Rym: It's Tuesday, October 18th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about Moonbreaker.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, we intended to experiment with, and then maybe start doing a Discord thing, because, you know, Discord recently announced and released a new feature, Discord Watch Together, where you can, like...
Scott: Well, it's Discord activities.
Scott: It's activities.
Scott: And one of the activities is watch YouTube together.
Rym: So we figured we'd try it.
Rym: So, uh, just before the show, Scott put on a video, happened to be a GeekNights panel, and, uh, feature just doesn't fucking work at all.
Scott: Well, okay, so it works, but here's the problem.
Rym: Well, it'll work for normal people who don't care if they see ads and also don't have good technology.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I, first of all, I have YouTube Premium.
Scott: And so I launched, I picked a GeekNights video, I put it in Watch Together, and we went to go watch it, and I didn't see anything.
Scott: I saw a black screen.
Scott: And the reason I saw a black screen, even though it said the video was playing, is because I have so much ad block in my house, there was an ad playing, and the ad was getting blocked.
Scott: And so I wasn't able to watch the YouTube video in Discord.
Scott: And then Rym saw the ad, I guess he has less ad block in his house.
Rym: Yep, so I don't have that level of ad block in the house.
Rym: Like, I don't use an IP hole or anything, I just, like, block ads in my browser because I use the browser for everything.
Scott: I have that also.
Rym: But I also pay for YouTube Premium, and it's my own fucking video that we were watching on my own account that I had uploaded.
Scott: Yeah, we both had YouTube Premium.
Scott: All the viewers and the person who selected the video had YouTube Premium.
Scott: And it was trying to show an ad.
Rym: Yep, and it showed me the ad.
Rym: So I saw an ad from YouTube in a YouTube stream, despite the fact that I pay YouTube to not show me ads.
Rym: So we are not going to use this feature.
Scott: Discord's implementation was not good.
Scott: So I was hoping that the activities, some of the activities are games, which have some potential to be fun, right?
Scott: Jackbox-ish kind of stuff.
Rym: I mean, if I were a product manager at Discord, I would be trying to make Jackbox-like experiences as hard and fast as possible.
Scott: Well, that's what they're doing.
Scott: And what they've done is, I think you get the YouTube watch together, and you get one other one for free.
Scott: But if you have Discord Nitro, which is not free, then you get all of them, basically.
Scott: And what they've added, a Discord Nitro mini plan, which is, I think the normal one is what, five bucks a month, ten bucks a month, something like that?
Rym: Yeah, I pay for it anyway.
Rym: I use Discord pretty heavily.
Scott: There's Discord Nitro.
Scott: So it's either ten bucks a month or a hundred bucks a year for regular old Nitro.
Scott: And the features you get if you pay for that are all the activities, right?
Scott: Fancier emojis, like animated ones, or make your own emojis.
Scott: You can fancy up your profile.
Scott: You get two server boosts every month, right?
Scott: And you get a discount if you want to buy more boosts.
Scott: You get some profile badges.
Scott: You can upload, the big one for me is you can upload larger files, right?
Scott: Just the iPhone, the default resolution of photos I take with the iPhone.
Rym: I mean, that's one of the reasons I pay for the big Discord, is that I upload full-on videos from like Overwatch games to Discord just fine.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I'll take a photo with my iPhone and try to upload a Discord channel.
Scott: And if you don't pay, it's like your photo's too big, right?
Scott: And then the last one is that if you go to a channel, and you try to stream video or webcam, it's not HD, right?
Scott: Unless the server is boosted so much that they're all HD.
Scott: So, and you can use emojis from one server in another server.
Rym: Oh my god, so the watch together is even worse.
Rym: It has a whole bunch of arbitrary restrictions.
Rym: It only works in the desktop app.
Rym: No other apps, probably because of licensing agreements with YouTube.
Rym: And it is limited to 180 minutes and then you're not allowed to watch anything else and it kicks everybody out and you have a cooldown before you're allowed to use it again.
Scott: Wow, alright, that's worse, that's even worse, yeah.
Rym: The same time it applies no matter what server or voice chat you're in.
Rym: And if you're watching by yourself, like no one joins your group, it cuts you off after 30 minutes.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I feel like a lot of this, the ads and everything, are all because of YouTube's monetization and embedding rules, is my guess.
Scott: So the other thing they've done is along with these new activities, the YouTube one which is the primary one, they've added this Nitro Basic plan, which is much cheaper, it's only $3 a month, which is a lot cheaper, right?
Scott: And what you get for this is you get the emoji features, right?
Scott: That I discussed.
Scott: You can upload bigger files but only up to 50 megs, not 100, but still much more than the default, right?
Scott: That'll probably get you and that's probably enough to upload photos from your iPhone without trouble, right?
Scott: You get the badge profile and on your whatever, badge on the profile and you get the custom video background thing when you're in a video chat, right?
Scott: Background's behind your head, right?
Scott: Which you also get with the regular Nitro.
Scott: You don't get any other Nitro feature.
Scott: You just get those features.
Scott: So I guess they figure, they must have calculated, that there are people who want just those features, but $10 is too much, but $3 will get them to pay, they'll pay the $3, especially if they don't have a lot of money, and they'll get money out of people who would otherwise pay $0.
Rym: It's not a bad strategy.
Rym: Plus in general, Discord generally makes good features and makes good decisions, which is why the weird ad situation with the watch together is interesting and that's why I'm pretty sure the problem is YouTube's rules as opposed to Discord knowing that that sucks.
Scott: Yeah, I guess the thing is we were trying to end around the fact that the Discord stages don't allow video in them.
Rym: Yeah, because if they did, we would absolutely stream gig nights into our own Discord, like why not?
Scott: I figured, well, what if we use the YouTube watch together, we could sort of end around, right?
Scott: We could just watch together the stream of ourself, right?
Scott: But I guess that won't work.
Rym: I guess I'll go back to.
Rym: if I want to watch a YouTube together, I will just stream my entire screen via OBS to Discord to all of my friends.
Rym: So in some gaming news, I have been playing a ton of Overwatch 2 and I actually have a lot I can say and share about it.
Rym: So there's a lot going on here because Overwatch 2 is basically just like an iterative advancement of Overwatch 1, like minor ruleset changes, the graphics look different.
Scott: And they've also, Overwatch 1 no longer exists, right?
Scott: They just replaced it with Overwatch 2, so Overwatch 2 is the only Overwatch.
Scott: No one can ever play Overwatch again, it is not preserved in history.
Rym: In the same way that pretty much all multiplayer games go these days.
Rym: It's still not good.
Rym: So Overwatch 2 would just be like an update, like the continuance of Overwatch.
Rym: I would have said it's basically the same as when Counter-Strike went to Counter-Strike Source and Counter-Strike GO.
Scott: Well, it's not a new engine, is it?
Rym: It's not a new engine, but it does graphically look different and they have radically changed the number of elements of how the game works.
Rym: But, they simultaneously also made the move to making Overwatch a free-to-play game, which has introduced a whole level of Fortnite evil monetization hellworld nonsense that was previously not in Overwatch.
Rym: Because remember, Overwatch previously was a game you paid money for and you got all of Overwatch, it just worked.
Rym: Now it's got battle passes and all that same kind of crap that Fortnite has, which increasingly seems to be the only way to monetize an online game enough to continue its existence.
Scott: I mean, the vast majority of players are gonna shell out a bunch of money, especially if they're not already playing.
Scott: It's like, "Hey, here's a game you might enjoy.
Scott: You can't even play it at all until you pay
Scott: $60.".
Scott: Even if people paid $60, it'd be like, "Here's $60.
Scott: That's the end of the income.
Scott: And now, why would you keep maintaining this game when no one else--".
Scott: It's like you're not gaining more players.
Scott: Now,
Rym: I would definitely, if there was a game I cared about, like I used to back in the day when I would pay for things because these other models didn't exist,
Scott: paying
Rym: a monthly fee to have access to a significant online game does make sense if the game--
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'm paying a monthly fee for Virtual Bicycle World.
Scott: -Yeah, but-- -Which is basically a video game.
Rym: In video games, you can't make enough money doing that.
Rym: There's basically no way to make money in video games unless you're evil.
Rym: So basically, most of the weird problems and the complaints and the interesting stuff that's happening around Overwatch 2 right now is directly and solely caused by the fact that it's also now free to play.
Rym: So in Overwatch 1, there were shitheads who would get banned pretty frequently, not hard to get banned from online games, and they were pretty aggressive about banning toxic people.
Rym: Like, it worked really well.
Rym: I'd say a high percentage of the people I reported, I got a notification that they were banned, like, pretty much within a couple of days.
Rym: So with Overwatch, when someone got banned, they had to buy the game again if they wanted to keep playing.
Rym: So there was a monetary cost to being a piece of shit in the game, which made a relatively stable ecosystem.
Rym: But if a game goes free to play, how do you handle that?
Rym: If a game is free, then people can just keep making an infinite number of free accounts to play the game.
Rym: So Overwatch tried a few ways, or Blizzard tried a few ways to get around this.
Rym: First, they tried to say, for the new Overwatch 2, you actually have to associate a real phone number with your Blizzard account to be able to play Overwatch 2.
Scott: Overwatch will steal someone's phone number, right?
Scott: Oh yeah, but even then-- Just open up the contacts on your phone and find a phone number and type it in.
Rym: Yeah, but then you have to verify with the texting.
Rym: Like, it basically becomes your two-factor.
Rym: So you have to prove it's your phone number, and they will ban you based on your phone number.
Rym: So they did this, and then a whole other set of stories came out because now a ton of people who wanted to play Overwatch couldn't because they didn't have legitimate phone numbers.
Rym: The only phone they have is the kinds of phone numbers-- Yeah, there's some kid who doesn't have a phone.
Rym: Yeah, but the kids who don't have phones and people who can't afford phones all have phone numbers from these throwaway, garbage-tier sites that are also used by scammers and trolls and criminals.
Rym: So if you let those phone numbers be used, the whole system's worthless because the toxic kid can get a hundred new phone numbers if they need to.
Rym: But when they block those services, suddenly a huge number of people who would otherwise play Overwatch 2 now can't because they do not have a phone.
Rym: So they walk that back a little bit, and they're still trying to sort out what to do, but it's even worse.
Rym: If you have not played Overwatch before and you start playing Overwatch 2 brand new from nothing, they actually-- On one hand, they did something good.
Rym: You can't play competitive until you win 50 games in the casual mode, which is a high number of games.
Scott: All right, so if you get banned and you make a new account for free, you have to play 50 casual games before you can interfere and troll some competitive games.
Scott: Not just play games.
Scott: And if you're a piece of shit, how are you going to win 50 casual games without getting banned again for being a piece of shit?
Scott: And that actually makes sense.
Scott: That should insulate the competitive play from shitty people.
Rym: Yep, because the competitive play of any free-to-play game is very easily ruined by the nature of free-to-play and the fact that if a game is free-- They care a lot less if casual play gets ruined.
Rym: Exactly, because casual play is casual play.
Rym: Like, just go in there and shoot people and stop shooting people when you're bored.
Rym: Whatever, I never play casual.
Scott: Well, didn't you have to win 50 games, though?
Rym: No, because you don't have to win 50 games.
Rym: One, if you had an Overwatch 1 account that was active when they made the switch to 2, if you were already playing, you're already in.
Rym: And you kept all your stuff.
Rym: Or you can buy a pack for, like, 20 bucks.
Rym: I don't know how often they'll have these packs, but it's a lot like Fortnite, and the pack is basically a "Get
Rym: everything!"
Rym: And it's just like you owned Overwatch 1.
Rym: You can "unlock" all the stuff almost immediately and being competitive really quickly.
Rym: So pay 20 bucks or win 50 games seems to be the way they're going.
Rym: In terms of player unlocking, because this is a game that has characters, normal players, people like me, people who have played the game, just have every character.
Rym: If you don't pay for a battle pass, you still get every character, but you have to win enough games to unlock them, and it's a lot of games.
Rym: You'll very slowly unlock characters.
Scott: Or is it like League of Legends where it rotates who's available?
Rym: There's no rotation.
Rym: That's not a thing in Overwatch.
Scott: So there's a few characters that everyone always has no matter what.
Rym: So a new player who does not pay any money gets a tiny selection of characters, not so much as part of a grindy experience, or an unlocking experience, or even to try to get those people to pay money.
Rym: The idea seems to be that it's a difficult, complex, competitive game, and there still are aiming that part of the game at people who want to play seriously.
Rym: And it seems like, and I've read a bunch of interviews where they said this pretty much openly, it is a better on-ramp to people learning how to play the game enough to hit this baseline level before you even let them into competitive.
Rym: So all the casual players who are brand new are playing in a very limited, it's almost like the easy mode of a game like Agricola before you play the real mode.
Scott: Alright, so if you started playing today, how many characters would you have?
Rym: No idea.
Rym: Some small set.
Rym: You get a limited set of characters of each type, and you'll unlock all of them.
Scott: Now how many are there total?
Rym: Uh, 10, 20, 20-ish?
Rym: 20-something?
Scott: 20-ish?
Scott: Okay, so if you wanted to unlock all of them from, you just started today, how much money would you have to spend if you did it only with money?
Rym: I think 20 bucks.
Scott: 20 bucks gets you all the characters?
Scott: Just all of them unlocked immediately?
Rym: All of them except one, the brand new character.
Rym: they just added for Overwatch 2, that if you have a battle pass, you will get it when you win like five games.
Scott: So you have to spend 20 bucks and then win, the only thing, you can't spend money to get that last character, you just have to win five games?
Rym: Well, and you have to spend money on the battle pass, which is separate from the pack I mentioned.
Scott: Like I said, they're doing the same- Oh, the battle pass is separate from the pack.
Rym: Yeah, they're doing the same thing that Fortnite and every other game does.
Scott: They have this obfuscated system with a bunch of different- So you end up with Overwatch 1 is 20 bucks and then the battle pass is how much?
Rym: I don't actually know because I refuse to buy battle passes in games.
Scott: So you don't have the one extra character?
Rym: No, I actually do not have the one extra character.
Rym: Now, I'm gonna get that character real quick because I play the game competitively and seriously.
Scott: So you can't just grind it out of nothing?
Rym: Yep, I can just grind it out of nothing and I can play the character in casual, I can play the character in the practice rooms, I can play the character in custom games, I only can't play the character in ranked competitive.
Scott: Oh, so even if you started today, you could use every character just not competitively?
Rym: In all the side modes, it looks like it, yeah.
Scott: Okay, so it's only in the competitive mode that you can't use every character to pay money?
Rym: Yeah, but to back up a little bit, all of this combined, the reason it sounds confusing is that it is confusing.
Scott: It is confusing to me- -to spend wrong amounts of money.
Rym: Yep, I have played Overwatch since the beta of Overwatch 1.
Scott: I have played Overwatch since the dawn of Overwatch.
Scott: An honest and open and clear casino doesn't make as much money as one.
Scott: that's a maze with all kinds of games with confusing rules.
Rym: Because an honest and open casino, you walk in, they would just like flash some lights in you and then steal your wallet and then kick you out with some booze.
Rym: It would be a lot more efficient.
Scott: But basically, it's in the same pay-to-win realm as League of Legends where it's debatable whether it's pay-to-win because not everyone is on a completely even footing.
Scott: It doesn't cost that much money to get all the competitive things.
Scott: It's characters, it's not like boosts, right?
Scott: Plus one damage costs a dollar.
Rym: There's no such thing as that because there's a whole other pile of nonsense with the battle passes and everything that I didn't talk about.
Rym: that's even more confusing.
Rym: But it's 100% cosmetic so it literally doesn't exist as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: But it's basically the same as that gray area that Netrunner was in where it's like, "Yeah, all the cards are available to everyone.
Scott: There's no collectible
Scott: bullshit.".
Scott: But some people went out and bought all the cards and some people didn't.
Rym: And what sucks is that weird edge case like that liminal zone between pay-to-win and just a game is blurred because it's a free-to-play game.
Rym: If this was not a free-to-play game and they used the same model they used in Overwatch 1, then none of this would exist.
Rym: This entire complex ecosystem of nonsense is solely there to obfuscate how they make money to allow the game to be free-to-play.
Rym: What sucks, because if it weren't for that capitalist pressure, the idea of the game is free for anyone to play and open so that people can try the game out and decide if they like it.
Rym: It's almost like having a minor league or a casual league that draws people in so that you can have people ascending to the serious competitive play.
Scott: I think we talked about this before when Richard Garfield wrote this article about tournaments being better than ladders.
Scott: And I completely 100% agree.
Scott: and no game that I know of has done this yet.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: all you gotta do is make a game where this free-to-play, whatever, nobody cares about that.
Scott: You can do whatever you want.
Scott: It's not competitive.
Scott: It's not serious.
Scott: So it doesn't matter.
Scott: Make it gambling.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: Do whatever the hell you need to do to make money in the non-competitive area of the game.
Scott: All you need to do is say, "This is the competitive area of the game.
Scott: The only competitive play are organized
Scott: tournaments.".
Scott: Just like when you play Magic at the local game store, it's a tournament.
Scott: You pay an entry fee to get into the tournament.
Scott: You gotta sit there and play all the matches.
Scott: It might be Swiss.
Scott: It might be elimination.
Scott: Whatever it is, you gotta sit there.
Scott: If you don't play all the matches, you forfeit.
Scott: You're out of the tournament.
Scott: You lose.
Rym: Now see, I take it different.
Rym: Personally, I just don't want to even play games with people who need that kind of structure to be able to not just be pieces of shit in the game.
Scott: No, this isn't about people being pieces of shit.
Scott: It's about creating a proper competitive structure.
Scott: It's like, the tournaments that anyone can play in at any time, you win those, and by winning those, now you can go to the next level of tournaments.
Rym: But the only reason to have those kinds of ladders in these kinds of games, really, is just so the matchmaking makes sense so you're not playing against people who are...
Scott: No, you don't need any matchmaking.
Scott: It's a tournament.
Scott: When you go to the local store to play Magic, it's not fucking matchmaking.
Rym: So instead of, "Well, I'm home from work.
Rym: I'll play Overwatch for an
Rym: hour."
Rym: It's, "Well, time to go see what tournaments are happening at 4 o'clock on
Rym: Thursday.".
Scott: No, there's no.
Scott: "see what tournaments are
Scott: happening.".
Scott: There's so many players, you just say, "Join tournament," and you join one.
Rym: Yeah, what if I only have 30 minutes to play?
Rym: What if I only have 20 minutes to play?
Scott: Then you're not ready for competitive... That's not a competitive thing.
Scott: But Scott, why?
Rym: Why?
Scott: You're gonna sit down and compete, right?
Scott: This is the time for playing series.
Rym: I agree with aspects of what Richard Garfield said, but I absolutely disagree with whatever nonsense you're on about because the whole point of competitive in a game like Overwatch, as opposed to casual, is just everyone here is trying their best to win.
Scott: That's just casual play, right?
Rym: Have you played an online FPS in the last five years, Scott?
Rym: If you play in casual, what I find is that in every game, the unranked mode, most of the players are not even trying to win at all.
Rym: They're just fucking around.
Scott: Listen, if you don't want to play in a tournament, then you're not playing competitively.
Rym: You're just playing against people.
Scott: That's going to the game store and playing against whoever happens to be sitting there.
Rym: But Scott, that's absolutely 100% not true because if I go to Overwatch and I click competitive, every single match, 100% of the time, everyone in there is trying super hard to win and taking the game super seriously.
Scott: Yeah, but that's because you're playing on some weird ladder nonsense.
Scott: No, what do you mean weird ladder nonsense?
Rym: All competitive means is we matchmake you based on some math.
Scott: That math is a ladder.
Scott: It's not a tournament.
Rym: Yeah, and that ladder is solely there to make sure you are playing against people of your same relative skill.
Scott: Right, but the ladders do not facilitate a greater overall competitive structure.
Rym: But what is your goal of that greater overall competitive structure?
Rym: Because the Overwatch structure actually very clearly and directly feeds people into the serious competitive, like the tournament scene, the money scene, the professional play.
Rym: Through this, the people who get to diamond tier and ascend to the three at the top, those are the people who get pulled up into the professional teams.
Scott: Yeah, sure, but doing it that way is not as good as doing it the tournament way.
Rym: How is it not as good?
Rym: Works fine.
Scott: Look at every single non-esport.
Scott: Even tennis where they have a world ranking, which could be considered a ladder, you only get points for the world ranking by playing at tournaments.
Scott: There are no just play games to get points.
Scott: That doesn't exist.
Scott: You enter competitive tournament events and those events are the things that matter for your overall ranking.
Rym: You just sound like a cranky old man.
Scott: You just play whatever the hell you want and go up and down.
Rym: You want weird things that nobody else wants.
Scott: No, I think this is, and then the other thing is that when you have these tournaments as being the only competitive mode of play, there's entry fees and prizes.
Scott: You can have prizes, right?
Scott: Because there's entry fees.
Rym: Yeah, that also exists, but that's separate because all this is for is matchmaking and they change that too.
Rym: Instead of showing people the number.
Scott: And do tournaments you don't need matchmaking?
Rym: Actually, yes you do.
Rym: The matchmaking just happens before the tournament starts.
Scott: When you go to the local store to play a Warhammer tournament, is there matchmaking?
Rym: If you're talking about that shit tier level, then no.
Rym: You're probably going to play with people who are radically outside of each other's skill sets.
Scott: Right, but if you use a Swiss structure, it's like yeah, the first couple rounds you might get randomly paired against someone who sucks, but then the rest of the tournament is automatically matchmade.
Rym: But in an online game, as opposed to a physical game where you actually have to go somewhere and schedule things with a large player base, instead the laddering system of matchmaking just ensures that no matter what, you are always playing every single game with people who are around your ability level.
Rym: No exceptions, which is way more fun than a random match where, "Well, now I'm playing against someone who literally can't play.
Rym: This is going to be really sad for ten
Rym: minutes.".
Scott: I do not agree.
Rym: I mean, you don't play games online, really, so...
Scott: Right, because they're all like these ladders.
Scott: Well, what do you mean?
Scott: What about the ladder?
Rym: Uh, okay.
Rym: I mean, you don't want to play any of the other games.
Rym: You didn't play Overwatch 1, which was up your alley when it wasn't free-to-play.
Scott: It's not a game I want to play.
Rym: You want to go play Counter-Strike right now?
Rym: No, that's not a game I want to play either.
Rym: You didn't play Netrunner.
Rym: Uh, because that was an in-person physical game that required me to pick a specific time to play, as opposed to I can just see who's online in my friend group, hit a button, and we're instantly playing a game 24/7, anytime.
Scott: But it was a much better game.
Scott: By like 10,000-fold.
Rym: I mean, you say that.
Rym: I honestly didn't enjoy Netrunner that much.
Rym: There's a reason I did not.
Scott: You played it for five minutes.
Rym: Yeah, and I didn't find it that fun.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: Kind of like the game we're going to review today.
Rym: So, you got any news?
Scott: Uh, there isn't.
Scott: Well, okay, so what was the news?
Rym: You were going to talk about that Gundam game.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the awful Gundam game.
Rym: That I assume you're not going to play, because it's not.
Scott: It was free.
Scott: I played it for 10 minutes, and then I saw what it was, you know.
Scott: So, it's a Gundam game.
Rym: Because I already see, I've got to say, I have it on the screen, I just went to the Steam store, and I see Gundam game.
Rym: All reviews, mixed.
Rym: All right, I scroll down a tiny bit, and it says, "Items available for this game.
Rym: Coins for $10.
Rym: More coins for $50.
Rym: More coins for
Rym: $100.".
Rym: The graphics that you can't see, that I'm showing the listener, I know exactly what this game is, and there's no way I'm ever going to play it.
Scott: No, I played it one time, and that's it.
Scott: So, the Gundam game, Gundam Evolution, is a free-to-play FPS, right?
Scott: It's on Steam.
Scott: You can play it right now.
Scott: And, it's basically Overwatch, right?
Scott: Only, all the character models are Gundam robots.
Rym: I question your, "It's just
Rym: Overwatch.".
Rym: I don't think you know- It is.
Scott: Everyone says it's basically just Overwatch, but a really shitty one.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't think you know what Overwatch is even like.
Scott: You have a team of, you know, what?
Scott: Five, six people.
Scott: You have these different roles.
Scott: You got your support guys, your tank guys, right?
Scott: You go try to, you know, different objectives on the map, right?
Rym: It's bullshit.
Scott: That's extremely facile, I mean- It's the same FPS nonsense, right?
Scott: Anyway, so, first of all, as a game, it's not even good at the game it is, right?
Scott: Even if this game was not free-to-play, pay-to-win, or anything like that, it's just not a good game.
Scott: The controls don't feel great.
Scott: You know, you just die really quickly.
Scott: The abilities are not fun.
Scott: The maps are actually the worst part of this game.
Rym: Ooh, 'cause that's actually one thing.
Rym: Overwatch has some of the best FPS maps I have ever seen.
Scott: These maps in this game, right, they look like, they're like the, if you were getting like some game dev tutorial, like how to make an FPS.
Scott: Like, these are like just the most generic maps, like a bunch of rocks and a building.
Scott: It's like, you know, they're so boring, these maps.
Scott: None of them are exciting.
Scott: They didn't make Space Colony the map, right?
Scott: They didn't make outer space or on the surface of a spaceship the map or anything cool Gundam-like.
Scott: It's just random places, you know, whatever.
Rym: They look like Halo maps.
Scott: They're not, they're not, they're really boring.
Scott: The other thing is that the game, even if it's good or not, does not, at least to me, feel Gundam-y, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, your characters are Gundams and some of their special moves are Gundam special moves, right?
Scott: But, you know, like you bring up the shield and whatnot, but it doesn't feel like the way it looks when you watch a Gundam anime.
Scott: If you watch a Gundam anime, Gundams are A) fast, B) they're jumping and flying all over the place.
Rym: It's got to be some combination of virtual on types gameplay.
Scott: Yeah, virtual on is more of a Gundam game than this.
Rym: But there's also got to be people's faces popping up on the screen yelling at me the entire time.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Gundams have all sorts of like...
Rym: You know, I got to tell you, I got to play the arcade Gundam game and other people in the pod.
Rym: I mean, I couldn't speak Japanese, so it was kind of a problem.
Rym: But other people could chat with you and their face would pop up from a camera in the other pod in your screen when they tried to communicate with you on the team.
Scott: Yeah, this game doesn't do any of that.
Scott: Gundam game, you know, Gundam when you watch an anime is like a, you know, it's an Itano circus.
Scott: There's a bullet hell.
Scott: There's just shit flying all over the place, right?
Scott: Meanwhile, when you play this game, you bring out like the, you know, the beam rifle.
Scott: It's like pew, pew.
Scott: It's not pew, pew, pew, pew, pew.
Scott: You know, I expect to be shooting lasers all over the fucking place, right?
Scott: That all do minimal damage and you need lots and lots of hits to actually hurt anybody.
Scott: There wasn't a beat.
Scott: There you have a beam saver or the machine guns in the Gundam's head or anything.
Scott: It's like, you know, it doesn't feel Gundam-y other than having some character models.
Scott: So that was a disappointment.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: Even the people who disagree with you and like the gameplay, all the reviews from the people who like it for gameplay are still saying, "Oh, the payment scheme is so toxic.
Rym: This game is dead.
Rym: COA.".
Scott: Correct.
Scott: So this game also, this, you know, in terms of pay to win, right?
Scott: Again, just like Overwatch, there's no, like, you can't pay for like a shield or armor or it's all, you know, cosmetic stuff, but there are some Gundams you have to unlock.
Scott: And to unlock them by grinding would be arduous.
Scott: Like, you're just not gonna.
Rym: I mean, again, considering that there is an option on the front page of the Steam page for this game to spend $99.99 on coins, that is extremely worrying.
Scott: Assuming you only spend your currencies on unlocking and not on cosmetic worthless crap, right?
Scott: You would still have to spend a small fortune, I didn't calculate it, to unlock all of the Gundams, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, but, you know, people have that same argument like we just talked about.
Scott: It's borderline pay to win, right?
Scott: Would Street Fighter be unfair if I only had Ryu?
Scott: Like, what if Ryu's my main?
Scott: Then it doesn't matter that I can't be, you know, M. Bison because I don't play M. Bison, right?
Scott: It's like, who cares?
Scott: But, you know, if you only play one Gundam, what does it matter if you didn't unlock the other ones?
Scott: Here's the problem.
Scott: This game, unlike, say, Overwatch, I presume, the Gundams that are not unlocked for free automatically are vastly superior.
Scott: Ah, see, Overwatch- They are- they did not- the ones that you have to grind or pay to unlock are just better.
Rym: Overwatch is set up such that- Every single character is on the Pareto Frontier at all times, and most of the design tweaks they make in the patches are making sure that Frontier remains constant.
Rym: Every character is viable, every character is equally useful.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, yeah, it's, uh, you know.
Rym: I mean, developed by Bandai Namco Online already does not give one confidence in this game.
Scott: You know, it's disappointing because we had an opportunity to have, like, a cool Gundam online multiplayer game, which, you know, just that alone, that concept is, like, S-tier, the execution, F-tier.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Maybe D-tier.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: But, anyway, things of the day!
Rym: Real quick, 'cause I have some really good stuff that I want to save for appropriate days for a reason.
Rym: So, if you don't do, like, outdoor sportsy stuff, a lot of people like to use the GoPros, but a lot of people lately, because they've gotten cheaper, like to use 360 action cams.
Rym: So, imagine, like, a GoPro- Oh, GoPro makes one.
Rym: Yeah, but other people make 'em too, but they're more common now.
Scott: There's a lot of companies making a lot of action cams these days of all kinds.
Rym: Which is interesting, because there's, uh, I don't know, I feel like there's actually a limited audience for them, because most people, by one, realize that they're not that good at whatever sport it is that they're videoing themselves doing, and then it collects dust.
Rym: But, uh, this person has shown the best possible use case for a non-super professional to, like, what you should do with a 360 action cam.
Rym: This is a 12-second video, and it is delightful.
Rym: It kind of reminds me of a Syriac animation.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, the, uh, the Steam Deck is out, and even though I don't really feel any desire to get one or need one, considering what I- the devices I already possess, I could see that clearly it is popular, uh, people like it, and, uh, someone who owns not the great multitude of devices that I own would probably, you know, especially some kid, you know, it's like this could be a great thing to have.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, one thing, the, uh, it, I guess, minor news, if you somehow miss this big news, uh, in one of the marketing materials for the Steam Deck, uh, a Switch emulator, a screenshot of a Switch emulator appeared.
Scott: So, someone at Valve who's making marketing materials had a Switch emulator installed on the Steam Deck, and they removed that.
Scott: Um, but anyway, uh, if you want to play, you know, some GBA games or whatever, right?
Scott: Yeah, sure, you could probably get a GBA emulator on there and all the ROMs, because it's just a PC, right?
Scott: Uh, but there's this device you can buy.
Scott: that's, uh, a GBA operator, right, which is like a little USB dock that you can put GBA cartridges into, and presumably, therefore, also Game Boy and Game Boy Color, because they're the same slot, kinda?
Scott: Maybe?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Um, and then, you install the software on the computer, and now you can play that game on that computer, and your, that's technically not illegal at all, in any way, shape, or form, um, because you have the cartridge, you didn't download ROMs, the software isn't illegal, you know, you can just do it.
Scott: So, somebody took this and plugged it in with a USB cable into their Steam Deck, and now that's, like, a really great way to play Game Boy games, except, uh, for the USB cable and thing flappin' around.
Rym: This might be a really good way to stream GBA games, which is currently a pain, or most people secretly use an emulator.
Scott: Yeah, well, GBA game streaming is actually not difficult, uh, what's difficult is DS game streaming.
Scott: That's the, that's the tough one, right?
Scott: Some people have managed it, but, I mean, I've done a ton of,
Rym: I did a ton of DS streams, uh, back in the day that actually weirdly have a lot of views, I should maybe start that up again, but, uh, I just used an emulator and it worked perfectly.
Scott: But I can see somebody just has to do a little modding here to sort of get this device into a different enclosure, sort of mount it on the back of the Steam Deck, you know, to make it not a cable flappin' around, and you got yourself a pretty good thing goin' here.
Rym: Yep, Steam Deck's not terrible hardware, it's just not somethin' Scott or I need for our current use cases.
Scott: Yeah, and, I mean, as good as my GBA that's upgraded is, that Steam Deck has a vastly superior screen, right?
Scott: And it's probably more comfortable to hold as well, so.
Rym: So, in the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book, Binti, it's actually, there are three books, we're gonna talk about all three because they're so short, it'll take you, like, a few hours to read them all, and we're gonna do this episode on Thursday.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Uh, it's about someone who goes to Space College, and, uh, it's got a lot of little twists and turns along the way, and, uh, wait 'til you meet the desert people.
Rym: I'll leave it at that.
Rym: There's good stuff goin' on in those books.
Rym: So, uh, this'll be the Book Club book, and then Scott's gonna reveal his choices, and, uh, the GeekNights Book Club will continue in its post-Genji life.
Rym: Also, we will be live at PAX Unplugged, maybe me and Scott, maybe just me, on Sunday, with an updated version of our Take Your Fuckin' Turn panel.
Rym: That's the one that PAX won.
Rym: Uh, whatever Sunday of PAX Unplugged.
Rym: Whenever PAX Unplugged is, on Sunday, of PAX Unplugged, that will be our panel.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I wanna say we're in the Crab God Theater this year, and I got, I don't have the email open, I just got it, so, uh, yeah, we will be there on Sunday doin' a panel.
Scott: Otherwise- Oh, there it is.
Scott: That would be December 4th.
Rym: So I imagine, uh, even if Scott and I both go and do the panel, we will only be at PAX Unplugged Sunday, because, while badges are not sold out, hotels are sold out on Saturday, it is a fully masked, and you have to prove vaccination event, uh, panelists have to wear masks, so we'll be on stage in masks, and, uh, yeah, we'll be around at most Sunday.
Rym: Don't expect to see us Friday or Saturday.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Uh, working on the website still.
Scott: I'm now past the part where I build the way to make it convenient for Rym to upload new episodes.
Rym: Hooray!
Rym: That's the part I'm most looking forward to.
Scott: And then I am now, well, it still has more features that could be added to it, but it is vastly superior, and now I am working on the import the data from our current website to the new website part.
Rym: We, uh, we got a lot of episodes, and, uh- That does, that doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, that doesn't matter.
Scott: Also, I did realize- It doesn't make it any harder or easier.
Rym: I was looking at, uh, the labels or the tags.
Rym: We have an extremely inconsistent tagging system of random nonsense in there.
Scott: It's gonna, it will remain.
Rym: Good.
Scott: Um, alright, so, today's episode is about a game called- Moonbreaker, which is another free-to-play online game.
Rym: Indeed.
Rym: Gonna come right out the gate by saying it is early access, so anything we say take with a grain of salt, but- Yep.
Scott: All of these problems could very well be addressed for when the game is fully released.
Scott: However, for something that's early access, it is quite impressive.
Scott: Like, you could have fooled me.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's, it's tough though, because on one hand, well, you know, it is, it is a really good idea that no one's ever done successfully before.
Rym: Like, I haven't seen someone try this hard.
Rym: Uh, two, they got a lot of the right people involved.
Rym: Three, uh, it, it's almost fun, but as the game is today, it is not actually fun to play.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, the story of this game.
Scott: This game is developed by Unknown Worlds, the people who made Natural Selection, Natural Selection 2, and Subnautica.
Scott: You know, Natural Selection, that's the real game, right?
Scott: It's like, let's just bring that back.
Rym: Scott, you wanna play NS2?
Scott: No, I wanna play NS1.
Rym: Uh, we could probably get that going.
Scott: With a bunch of gorgeous, a bop around on a RT, you know.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, those days are never coming back.
Scott: Alright, uh, and it's really, it's like literally, you know, Flaira, right, the internet name of the person who started it all, right?
Scott: It's like, I've been on Natural Selection servers, Natural Selection 1 servers playing with Flaira in 2000-something.
Scott: And today, go to the Moonbreaker Discord and it's like, Flaira is the same person.
Scott: At four, at four.
Scott: 20 years later.
Rym: Everybody at four.
Scott: Right, yeah.
Scott: So, it's the same exact team, basically.
Scott: Um, and what this game is, it is a tabletop miniatures game, like fucking Warhammer.
Scott: But a squad-based one, right?
Scott: Not too many, not a whole army, just a handful of units, right?
Scott: Uh, but recreated digitally.
Scott: So, it's, it's like, the units, it's like you put them down on the board and like, they actually, you know, they have a little base and they're a little miniature.
Scott: And they don't animate or anything, right?
Scott: Except when they attack, they spin around or whatever, you know, kinda.
Scott: But, you know, you move them around, it's like you're playing miniatures.
Scott: It's more like, you know, visually, it's like tabletop simulator, right?
Scott: You're moving miniatures around.
Rym: Or like a battle system, like the games where you would need to measure things, like a unit moves X inches and you gotta like deal with nonsense.
Scott: There's no grid, there's no hex grid or anything like that, right?
Scott: You even can paint the miniatures freely, as much as you want.
Scott: Digital painting, right?
Scott: So, you don't have to have an airbrush and all this mess and equipment in your house and spend money on paints.
Scott: You can paint miniatures to your heart's content.
Scott: Multiple paint schemes, you can run wild, there's so many paintings.
Rym: It's got like inking tools in there and washing and dry brushing, like automatic masking and it's going hard on this, which is cool.
Scott: Yeah, that's a great idea.
Scott: And then you can use your paint job when you play, right?
Scott: So, you know, it sort of makes up for the fact that you don't have that many, at least not right now, don't have that many units to choose from for your army, right?
Scott: So, how does the game actually work?
Scott: Well, the game itself is actually closer to a Hearthstone type card game than it is to a miniatures game, right?
Scott: There is the same sort of Magic the Gathering Hearthstone mana scaling, like on turn one, your commander is on the board, no matter what.
Scott: And then you have one cinder, which is basically mana, right?
Scott: And on turn two, you get two cinder and turn three, you get three cinder and so forth.
Scott: And you can bank, if you don't use all your cinder, you can bank up to three for the next turn.
Rym: Yup, so instead of like Magic the Gathering where you play a land, now you got one land out, you do your thing, next turn you play another land, next turn you play another land, now you got three land.
Rym: It just does this, this is just automatic.
Scott: So every unit that's on the board can move, right?
Scott: Its movement range, every turn, right?
Scott: No matter what, that's free.
Scott: Every unit can, if it has a base attack, not all of them do, some of them only have special abilities, but most of them have a base attack, can use its attack if it starts or ends its movement within range of an enemy.
Scott: So for a melee attack, it has to basically be right next to an enemy when it attacks, but it can attack and then run, or run then attack, the order is not constrained.
Scott: And for a ranged attack, it just has to have line of sight, and it can attempt to shoot, and if there's, you know, sort of partial cover, you'll sort of get a decrease on your accuracy, right?
Scott: But if you want, you can get really right up next to a guy and use a ranged attack in melee range, and it's very very likely to hit.
Scott: And then there's a random chance of crits, whatever, right?
Scott: And then, units have special abilities, special abilities cost cinder to use, right?
Rym: Yep, so you might have a guy who costs 3 cinder to put out on the board, like cool.
Rym: That guy might have a power spend 2 cinder to lob a bomb of some kind, independent of their other actions like moving.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Rym: So like a magic card or a hearthstone card, except a little miniature.
Scott: And the final aspect is that you have a hand of randomly selected units from your, you basically, when you build your army of dudes, there's all the dudes that are in the game, and you can only choose each dude once.
Scott: So you can't make an army with like two of the same dude in it, right?
Scott: So you choose a set of dudes, and you draw them, you draw them all, they're all unique, but obviously your opponent is going to have a lot of the same ones, because there's not that many.
Scott: And then you draw a hand at the start, and if you need to draw more units into your hand, it costs 3 cinder to draw a new unit into your hand.
Rym: Like El Grande, you've got people out in the hinterlands, and you have to pay or do something to bring them on deck, and then you have to pay or do something else to put them out on the board.
Scott: Yeah, on deck is in your hand, and then you know what's in your hand, but the deck, you don't know the order of what the dudes are in there, right?
Scott: And then you play them on the board, and when you play them on the board, you just have to play them within range of your main guy.
Scott: They can't drop anywhere on the board, they have to be within your main guy's area.
Scott: And the objective of the game is pretty simple, which is kill the other person's main guy.
Scott: Whoever's main guy dies first, loses.
Scott: That's it, that's all there is to it.
Rym: So, in terms of gameplay, it's a cool idea, the concept is great, and I wish them luck, but at this current stage, it's not that fun to play, partly because it is very hard to see what is going on.
Rym: Like, Scott very smartly painted all his guys just solid green, because that's the only way to actually differentiate anything.
Rym: Like, it's hard to tell the status of anything, all the things on the maps, all the models, everything, just kind of merge together into one big mess of pixels.
Rym: And even I play a guy, and it's hard to keep track of which guys I've moved, which guys I haven't, which guys are out there, which guys are like, the UX is just not even close to there yet.
Scott: I think a lot of it is that all the information about the status of the game state is there in the UI, but a lot of it, in order to see, you have to click on a guy or hover over a guy and read something, right?
Scott: There isn't just this immediate, clear visual clarity of what is up with everything on the board right now.
Rym: There's nothing as simple as, like, Advance Wars.
Rym: One of the buttons in Advance Wars, as in most games like that, is it'll cycle through all the units you have, in some sort of order, that have any actions.
Rym: they could still take this turn.
Rym: Like, one last sanity check.
Rym: The game has nothing like that.
Rym: I have forgotten to move units so frequently that that is, like, that is a part of the game.
Scott: And then you got a guy who all he can do is move and attack, no special abilities, right?
Scott: If you just look at the board, you can't tell by looking at the guy whether he's moved already or not, you have to click on him to see if the move button is lit up, and after you move him he doesn't look any different, and then has he attacked yet?
Scott: You can't tell just by looking at him, you have to hover over him or click on him to see has the guy attacked yet, right?
Rym: Even worse, there's no way to undo anything, so if you misclick, like, you click kind of fast on a guy and you accidentally move him when you just wanted to see if he could move, well, he moved, that's it, you're screwed, even though...
Scott: Yeah, a lot of times I'll move a guy, he'll just, like, bump into something and I'll be like, oops, and then that's it, can't move now, that was your move.
Rym: Now there are real world...
Scott: It would be nicer if it was, like, you have movement distance and you can keep moving until you use up all the distance.
Rym: There are real world wargames, I'll say battle system, because that's the system I know has this, I will be shocked if anyone listening to GeekNights even knows what battle system is, let alone has played it.
Rym: But it had rules like, if you move units, you declare their move first, then you pull out the measuring tape and see what actually happens, because you might have over-underestimated or messed something up along the way, and this game
Scott: arguably
Rym: could be trying to evoke that kind of feeling, but in effect, it just feels shitty, where you move a guy, and you're off by, like, one pixel, and then your next guy can't move past them, and you're just screwed, but there was no way to actually see that.
Rym: that would have been the outcome, because you're not physically there with tables, so the game doesn't give you any tools to figure this out, and that is frustrating enough to where I hesitate to play the game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, when you're clicking on a guy to move that unit, that's actually a really pretty good user interface, you can see the range of where they can move to, right, you can sort of try different positions, you know, you can tell sort of whether he's going to be in melee range or not, based on, like, this yellow border thing that groups around guys who are in melee range.
Scott: There's red lines showing you that, like, which ranged enemy units will be able to have line of sight to your guy, a lot of helpful things, but it's not, and there'll be, like, these vague white borders that show you, like, what the range of that guy's special abilities will be, so you can sort of say, "Ah, I'll move him, and he'll get in range for that other guy's special ability,".
Scott: like so, right, but what you can't do is sort of get combinations of information, right?
Scott: Like, okay, if I drop this guy here, like, when I'm dropping a guy from space out of my hand, I can see where I can drop him, but I can't tell, well, if I drop him there, will he then be able to move that far to get in melee range?
Scott: You can't, it doesn't let you measure a step ahead, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, I'll move, I can move this guy here, and I can see that there's a space between him and the wall, is that space big enough for yet this other unit to get through there if he moves second?
Scott: Maybe I should just move that second unit first to avoid having to ask that question.
Rym: This is actually, this is some of the stuff that worries me.
Scott: But I really want the other unit to do something else first, you know.
Rym: Because if this game were more like those bigger war games, then that would, all those kinds of micro, like, oh, he couldn't, that guy couldn't get through, I misjudged it, would kind of wash out over time due to the scale of the conflict, but this game, the battles, at least in early access, take place in very small, very simple maps, and as a result,
Scott: With very few guys?
Rym: A one pixel mis-move is just game over.
Rym: Like, GG, you've just lost, concede immediately.
Scott: It could be very, it could be very significant.
Rym: But, if you- Even worse, I don't think this game could ever support larger maps, because the mechanics, other than the special powers, are simplistic- No, this isn't, this isn't going to suddenly change into a big army game, that's what's happening.
Rym: This is a very small army game, and here is my fundamental worry.
Rym: All of the factors of how this game plays combined, I feel like in the end, it's just Naroshima Hex with extra steps.
Rym: It's Naroshima Hex with an infinite number of hexes on a tiny map.
Scott: I don't think it's Naroshima Hex, I think it's Hearthstone, except you actually position your dudes instead of just having them in a row, there's actually just complex positioning.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: but the problem is, because the maps are so small, and the movements are so low, and the rules for, like, ranged are extremely simplistic, I don't, like, I think
Scott: moving
Rym: and interacting on the map will be obvious and easy, and that will never, like, positioning and cleverness there will not be the factor.
Rym: The deck and, like, the macro is the only thing that's going to matter.
Scott: The card part of the game, right, which you guys, you draw, when do you play them, in what order, right, is going to matter a lot more than, the positioning is just, you know, making it a little bit more complex and interesting than a Hearthstone, right?
Scott: But it's not the primary thing, it's like, you can, you know, you can get over that, right, and what determines who wins and loses is going to be what order you draw your guys, what guys you selected, how you spend your cinder, right, that's the big, you know, decisions that matter the most.
Rym: But the problem is, I want the miniatures game.
Rym: If this, I want, like, moving the miniatures and fighting with the miniatures with simpler rules on the individual miniatures is more compelling to me than basically just playing Hearthstone that happens to have this map.
Rym: It almost feels like Magic the Conquering, which again, if any GeekNights listener played that game, like, let me know, because I'm not convinced that anyone played it except me.
Scott: I forgot it existed.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't even official, it was, like, published in Scryde as a variant to Magic where you would play your creatures onto a little map and it was just Magic with extra steps, like, it wasn't good.
Scott: No.
Scott: But yeah, so the thing is, you know, I think if they fix the user interface parts of this game and they increase the number of units to make it much more interesting, like, which guys you select, right?
Scott: And they fix the balance issues, which you haven't mentioned yet, there's a lot to fix here, a lot, that I would actually play the game if they could fix all these things, right?
Scott: But it's like, are they gonna fix all these things?
Scott: I'm not that confident.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, I'm also worried about the fact that you get new guys via buying booster packs that you unlock and grind.
Rym: There's this whole other mode that I refuse to even play.
Rym: that is literally just grind out cosmetic crap.
Scott: Yep, so let's talk about this.
Scott: other, what's going on, you know, with how you pay for the game.
Scott: This is not a free game.
Scott: You gotta pay for this game, right?
Scott: Pay real money, buy it, right?
Scott: It's not free to play.
Scott: So if you buy the game, that gets the expectation that people have as free, most people are free to play out there, right?
Scott: Is that if you pay for the game, you should be getting a ton of shit, right?
Scott: Of the consumable coins and whatnot, right?
Scott: And you kind of do, right?
Scott: It's like, basically you pay for the game.
Scott: It's like, you're going to unlock all, I unlocked all the units in like less than 30 minutes, like just with the stuff that came with the game, right?
Scott: So it's like, yes, it still has that question mark pay to win, but the only thing that will separate players is do you have all the units unlocked or not?
Scott: Everything else is cosmetic and unlocking them all is currently trivial.
Rym: Well just now, Scott picked a character that's in the meta and I have the default deck and you know what?
Rym: It would be, there is literally nothing I could do in the game to beat Scott's character with the deck that I have.
Scott: Well, that's a separate issue because that character's broken.
Rym: Yeah, that's sort of the fun.
Scott: The game balance.
Scott: They had a tournament and they bet they had the first tournament, they made people win with like two characters.
Rym: It's not just that the game balance is not great because it's early access.
Rym: Like that's, I would expect the game balance to not be there yet in a game like this.
Rym: It's that I don't think the kinds of powers they have introduced even in the first set are balanceable.
Rym: They have made the same mistake that Magic the Gathering made in Unlimited and Revised where there were cards that did game breaking kinds of things that you cannot do in games like this full stop.
Rym: These are like the hard rules of game design.
Rym: Moxes.
Scott: Every game messes this up.
Rym: You cannot have a thing like that.
Scott: Every game that has some sort of mana system messes this up.
Scott: It's like in Magic the Gathering, it's like every turn.
Scott: you can play a land if you got one.
Scott: And so your mana scales, hopefully, at one per turn unless you don't draw land.
Scott: Most of the newer games, they got rid of the random part and they just said one per turn.
Scott: Everyone is scaling up their power at the same rate.
Scott: And if you bring a guy into the field, you can't use him immediately.
Scott: You have to wait until next turn so that way you can't surprise your opponent with any bullshit.
Scott: And even in Magic the Gathering, the first game that did this kind of stuff, it's like if you want to surprise your opponent with bullshit on their turn, that means you're leaving mana untapped on your turn and your opponent can see that you have mana just sitting there waiting for a counterspell.
Scott: So, what did this game do?
Scott: Well, you have the Cinder, right?
Scott: One of the characters has an ability for one Cinder.
Scott: They can use this ability on the first turn.
Scott: They pick one at random, one of the units in their hand, and the cost of that unit goes down by two.
Rym: That is worse than a Mox Emerald in Magic.
Scott: That is right.
Rym: And then, wait, this character has... That's like a Sol Ring game breaker right there.
Scott: So, hold on.
Scott: This character also has two other abilities.
Scott: One other ability the character has is that if there is a unit within range of them that is stunned, which means it can't do anything.
Scott: It's a stunned unit.
Scott: And when you summon units, they're stunned.
Scott: And they can't do anything until next turn when the stun wears off.
Scott: For two Cinder, this character can un-stun a unit within range.
Scott: So, you can summon a guy that was discounted, immediately activate it, and then it can move and attack immediately and surprise your opponent.
Rym: That kind of thing in any game is absolutely unbeatable.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Wait.
Scott: And there is one more thing this character can do that is somewhat interesting but still bad and broken.
Scott: This character, to balance out the fact that they have these ridiculous abilities, their base attack is just a little one damage ranged attack.
Scott: It's really weak.
Scott: It doesn't do much, right?
Scott: However, if that little one damage ranged attack, right, which could be boosted by the way by other characters doing some, you know, whatever, enhancements or support abilities, right?
Scott: But anyway, if that main character kills and does the finishing blow, the last hit on an enemy, right, then that character will automatically draw a new guy from the deck to their hand, which typically costs three Cinder.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So, that's a way to basically eliminate a three Cinder cost by just last hitting a guy, which admittedly, that's sort of a nice mechanic, right?
Scott: If you do this clever thing that takes planning and consideration, get a bonus.
Scott: But that's a huge three, a three Cinder bonus.
Scott: Nothing, all the abilities should just be about damage or statuses or nothing should ever give you a free Cinder.
Scott: In Magic, nothing should ever give you a free mana.
Scott: In Hearthstone, nothing should ever give you a free mana.
Scott: Everyone, you had to lock in those hard rules of.
Scott: this is the pace and scale of the game, and you summon a unit, it can't do jack shit till next turn, no matter what.
Scott: You cannot make abilities to cancel those rules, right?
Scott: Yes, special abilities on units and cards should break the rules, but those rules should never be touched in every game ever that has messed with those rules, right, as resulted in brokenness.
Scott: In Netrunner, cards that let you get ridiculous numbers of credits, always, they broke the game every single time.
Scott: It's like, there's a pace at which you're supposed to be getting credits, do not exceed that pace ever, right?
Scott: It's like, the end, don't do it.
Scott: And every fucking game does it, including this one.
Rym: But I also worry that because the maps are so small, there's a lot of abilities that stun and block people from moving, but the map is so small, and your movement is so little, that those are extremely overpowered as well, and they lock the game up, and it's part of why I was thinking about Nurtium Hex, because the map is so small, and there's so many obstructive powers, and such little movement, that
Scott: the game- Well,
Rym: a lot of characters have a- that character can't move next round.
Scott: There's only one character that does that.
Rym: Nope, there's another character that, if it's standing next to someone, they can't move.
Rym: There's another character- That's the jail guy.
Rym: If they hit someone, that person can't move, and those two powers just kind of lock the movement up and make the map less interesting and the deck more important.
Scott: The last thing about this game- Well, they could also make more interesting maps that have all kinds of wacky Mario Kart shit going on.
Rym: I don't think they can, though, because the maps have to, by the nature of the core mechanics of the game, be very small.
Rym: There's very little you can do with maps that small.
Scott: Otherwise, melee is useless.
Scott: But they could fill the maps with all sorts of nonsense, right?
Scott: Like, rivers, and volcanoes, and shit.
Scott: that does stuff.
Rym: I don't think they could, though, because the map's too small relative to the size of the characters for that to matter.
Scott: It says, "Put all kinds of ridiculous nonsense on the
Scott: map.".
Scott: It's like, "Oops, you stood on the river, and then it came flowing, and it moved your
Scott: guy.".
Scott: Or, you know, do all kinds of stuff.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel like most of that would become random nonsense that you couldn't reasonably- You don't make it random.
Scott: You know when it's gonna happen.
Scott: It's a decision now.
Rym: But there's so little space on the map that you'd be taking off half the map with that stuff.
Scott: Make it smaller.
Scott: Not everything has to be big.
Rym: I think the entire map is like six of your biggest guy across, and I don't think they could be bigger mechanically.
Scott: Uh, maybe eight of your biggest guy across?
Rym: I'm imagining in my head, because I want his game open in front of me.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: The last thing about this game is a positive and a negative, right?
Scott: The positive is that I don't like games where people play slow.
Scott: You know us.
Scott: We don't like people playing slow and not taking their turn, right?
Scott: That's awful.
Scott: We want people to take their turn, right?
Scott: Move it along.
Rym: We're doing an entire panel on it and it PAX Unplugged.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And I've even considered, you know, one of the ideas that I always have in my shit-talk hopper is make a game where when the turn timer runs out, or you take damage.
Rym: Your computer explodes.
Rym: A spike comes out of your mouse.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or like a board game where the simultaneous turns and whoever finishes their turn first gets a benefit, or whoever finishes the turn last, right, gets a penalty.
Scott: Like just, you know, some direct effect of taking your turn faster to encourage quick play, right?
Scott: So I'm a person who really loves people to play fast, right?
Scott: In this game, the turn timer is too damn short.
Scott: It is too short.
Rym: Now you have to understand the enormity of Scott fucking Rubin saying these words.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's like every other game, I'm like, hurry it up, take your fucking turn.
Scott: And in this game, it's too short, right?
Scott: The decisions to make on the turn, right, can be done pretty quickly.
Scott: The big decisions.
Scott: Which guys do I play, right?
Scott: Who am I going to move?
Scott: But the thing is, because of the user interface, you can't at a glance figure out who's got what status is on them, right?
Scott: So it's like you got to sit there hovering over guys and clicking over guys and testing things out just to figure out what's possible.
Scott: That takes time, right?
Scott: You can't just see it all at a glance immediately and process it quickly.
Scott: And then you actually have to do execute all of these maneuvers, right?
Scott: And you want to position guys really carefully on this map.
Scott: that's not just a hex grid, right?
Scott: Everything's pixel perfect.
Scott: You know, like you'll move a guy.
Scott: It's like you'll try to move a guy a little bit just to get like an extra percentage chance to hit with a ranged attack, right?
Scott: You're like carefully positioning this circle.
Scott: And it's like, that takes time.
Scott: And if you summon a lot of units on the board, you know, if you only got two units on the board, no problem, right?
Scott: Three, still probably no problem.
Scott: Once you get to four or five, you do not have enough time, especially if you're going to be doing, maybe summoning more guys on your turn.
Scott: It's like, you don't have enough time.
Rym: This could be okay if, one, you've played the game enough to where you know what all the characters do, which, you know, that's a learny thing.
Rym: But two, if the UX of the game gave affordances to at a glance see the statuses of characters, see who moved, all these basic things that the game for some reason lacks.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it's really hard to actually, especially if you're new and you don't know all the abilities of all the units and you have to read stuff or whatever, you're going to get hit by the turn timer, which sucks because it's like your turn ends.
Scott: You didn't move all your dudes.
Rym: And you know what, if you have one turn, if you have one turn where you don't use all your dudes, you've lost.
Rym: It's over.
Rym: Like gate literally GG.
Scott: Unless the other person messes up too.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like, that is harsh.
Scott: Now, thankfully, I'll be sitting there on a turn and I will be doing things constantly.
Scott: Like I won't, I won't be sitting there thinking, wasting time.
Scott: Like I'm constantly looking at guys, moving them, trying out positions, attacking.
Scott: And then the turn timer comes up while I'm doing this and I'm still moving units.
Scott: And then the turn timer ends and it's like, really?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: That's too short, bro.
Rym: So the, if the UX were better and, and the things they need to change are so specific and obvious and easy that it'll be a big warning sign if those things don't get changed, like in the next six months of early access, like if they don't highlight statuses of characters better, highlight what characters have moved or not moved, let you cycle through characters quickly, then I worry about the future of this game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think there might be a keyboard shortcut for the cycling, but it's, it's clearly not obvious.
Rym: It was definitely not obvious.
Rym: Also, why can't I zoom out all the way?
Rym: The map's so tiny.
Rym: Why can't I just zoom out all the way?
Rym: Zooming in, I know that.
Scott: Just give me, give me the overhead strategic view that gets rid of all the graphics and all the paint jobs.
Scott: Like in Civ.
Scott: It's like, yeah, just like Civ, just show me icons.
Scott: That'll be easier.
Scott: I'll, I'll figure out everything really quickly with just a bunch of icons.
Scott: Cause
Rym: on one end I get that they want to focus on the models, but zooming in
Scott: zooms
Rym: in so far that it is worthless unless you're looking at the cool paint jobs and zooming out, you literally cannot zoom out far enough to like think about the entire map at any given time.
Scott: I think also if you could zoom out that you would, it would be hard to tell the different units apart.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Especially because the way, if you do good paint jobs, nothing in the environment of the map stands out from anything else.
Rym: So unless you hover over something, it's not clear if that's a game affecting thing or not.
Rym: Like everything's just a mess of pixels.
Rym: Uh, even to someone who's played the game a bunch and has a 4k monitor, it's just a mess of pixels.
Rym: It's hard to tell what's interacting.
Scott: I have to click on, other than your main guy who's huge and some other units that really stand out as different.
Scott: It's like most of the, just like the units that are just a humanoid, it's like you have to click on them and remember which one that is.
Scott: It's like, which one is that again?
Scott: Oh, the grenade one.
Scott: Which one is that again?
Scott: Oh, the fire guy.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And they all kind of look the same.
Rym: Like when I paint my units, I feel like I'm going to paint all my units like bright blue if they're range, bright yellow if they're melee.
Scott: That's the one thing you can tell between is range and melee.
Scott: Cause that's the only thing that's like a big symbol that's always on the UI no matter what.
Scott: So like everything should be a symbol just like that.
Scott: Like there should be a line of symbols at the top of each character just like that range melee symbol to show you all their statuses and whatnot.
Scott: Uh, and abilities so that you don't have to click on them or hover over them to see what the deal is.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So an interesting thing about this game too is of all people, they got Brendan Sanderson to create an original like universe for this game.
Rym: And uh, I'm going to read a terrifying sentence from you that I just learned by skimming through the Wikipedia.
Rym: I got to find it again.
Rym: It's too good because the listener asked in the chat, uh, which led me down this path, quote, have you listened to the audio drama stuff inside the game?
Scott: I started to listen to it and then I was just like, nah, nevermind.
Rym: So the game started and I was doing like the tutorial and that first audio drama starts playing and I was on my laptop and I was also working on some other stuff and I couldn't figure out how to skip it at first.
Scott: There's a button in the top right of the user interface that opens up a little media on the main menu at the top right and it opens up a little media player and you can use the media player to play the audio drama.
Scott: And I start, I listened to it for like 30 seconds and I was like, I got time for this.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, uh, I'm just going to read this, uh, due to the gay, this is a quoting from Wikipedia.
Rym: due to the game's large roster of characters and unknown worlds intention to support the game for years.
Rym: Moonbreaker will have a long form story that will last a decade or longer.
Rym: He compared the game storytelling to that of Canterbury tales, a story told from the perspectives of 30 different pilgrims.
Rym: I do not have time for that.
Rym: I do not care.
Scott: I mean, do you care about Warhammer's story either?
Scott: Some people do.
Rym: I care about knowing the name of whatever faction I would be playing at a really high level.
Rym: Uh, I don't know.
Rym: I just, I've never been super jazzed about people trying to cram novels and movies into video games directly that don't necessarily interact with the game mechanically in any way.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like Half-Life 2.
Scott: That's the right way to do it.
Rym: This game is just play a miniatures game.
Rym: And also there will be probably hundreds and hundreds and hours of audio drama you can skip.
Scott: It's like, here's a miniatures game.
Scott: And also this MP3 is on the side.
Scott: It's like, they're not integrated in any way.
Scott: You could just sell the MP3s by themselves.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: I guess the last thing is the, um, we got to talk about the, the pay to win part of it, right?
Scott: The, the currencies.
Rym: Oh, and also I got to note, underworlds has announced that they expect the game to last a decade or longer and it may potentially go free to play in the future.
Rym: So be warned.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, uh, you can get, there are currencies, you can get, there's different currencies, some, you know, whatever, right?
Scott: Um, and you can use the currencies to either get cosmetic shit or to unlock, get boosters to unlock dudes.
Scott: But once you unlock all the dudes, like you're good.
Scott: There's different rarities of dudes, but that's just different models.
Scott: It's just cosmetic, right?
Rym: I mean, I'm going to dunk them all in one color of paint anyway, so.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Uh, so then there, they had, they started off, when I started it, there was this cargo mode, right?
Scott: And I'm like, what the hell is this cargo mode that everyone is angry about?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because there's a bunch of people who weren't interested in competitive play.
Scott: They're just interested in like playing PvE and unlocking stuff.
Scott: Like that's all they want to do.
Rym: You know, it's funny.
Rym: The same thing happened with Overwatch.
Rym: Part of Overwatch 2 is to be able to support all these people who just don't want to play against other people at all, but yet still want to play the game because they care about the lore or the cosmetics.
Scott: I don't think they care about the lore.
Scott: I think people just like the, like this, like this feeling of unlocking stuff.
Rym: There are definitely people who play Overwatch solely to unlock the cosmetics and like listen to the in-game dialogue.
Scott: And I'm like, I'm like, don't you enjoy playing the game?
Scott: And they're like, no, it's like, I don't enjoy playing the game.
Scott: And I'm like, then why are you playing it?
Scott: It's like, it's like playing the game is its own reward.
Scott: It's like, if that part is not enjoyable, don't do it.
Rym: Which once again, never trust anything where the story is 100% disentangled from the mechanics of the game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like I told that to someone, I said, I just posted in the discord of like the Moonbreaker discord.
Scott: I'm like playing, I didn't like insult anyone.
Scott: I was just like playing.
Scott: the game is its own reward.
Scott: I don't care about unlocking stuff.
Scott: And someone was like, my brain doesn't work that way.
Scott: And I didn't type this, but I wanted to say seek help.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like that's, um, but anyway, so they had this cargo mode.
Scott: What is the cargo mode?
Scott: Well, when I started the game on the first day of early access, the way it worked is you would get cargo tickets and you get one cargo ticket for free every day, but you could buy more.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And because I bought the game, I got a few free ones.
Scott: Just like a handful.
Scott: I used one.
Scott: And you pay a cargo ticket and you can play cargo mode.
Scott: And what happens to cargo mode is you get an army of dudes and you fight the AI in a game.
Rym: So apparently they tried to make a campaign mode, but they found out they couldn't make it fun.
Rym: They tried to make a PV mode, but they also found they couldn't make it fun.
Rym: And they settled on this cargo mode.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the cargo mode, the way it works is you drop into a fight against some AI and they're really easy.
Scott: You beat them.
Scott: And then you go into a fight against some harder AI after you beat the first one.
Scott: And it's like, I think it's six or seven battles in a row.
Scott: If you never, if you never lose, but you're basically playing like the same deck.
Scott: So it's like, if your guy dies, it's like, you know, it's like that's, you have this one army to beat six or seven, however many enemies in a row.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Without losing.
Scott: And it's like, that's, it's pretty tough actually to beat all of them, especially because starting with like the third or fourth one to make up for the fact that the AI is not any good at the game, the AI is cheating.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It has units that are just like fire a laser and destroy all your dudes and shit, you know, ridiculous nonsense.
Scott: So you have to be really clever and perfect.
Scott: You know, always being out of range, using the right combination of abilities, et cetera, et cetera, in order to win.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if you win, what do you get?
Scott: Well, much like Hearthstone arenas, right?
Scott: The further you get you, the more rewards you get in terms of currencies and other bonuses.
Scott: So you're just basically spending this cargo ticket and then adding in some skill and strategy to get a payout of currencies and coins and other skins and cosmetic nonsense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, and so if you're a person who's only playing to unlock things and you don't enjoy playing, all you want to do is play this mode over and over again.
Rym: But you need those tickets to play that mode and you get like, what, one a day or something?
Scott: So you can play the game once a day without paying money for a game that you already paid money for because it's not a free game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So people got hella mad at that and they said, all right, we're gonna, you know, basically get rid of the tickets so you can play cargo mode all you want.
Scott: But we're gonna remove some of the rewards from the cargo mode so that you can't just play it forever and get a bunch of free, you know, shit that we're trying to charge money for.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, and so that's what they did so far.
Scott: And I'm like, why?
Scott: I don't even give a shit about the cargo mode.
Scott: I played it once to see what it was and I'll never play it again.
Rym: Yeah, which is another worrying sign that they tried to make an adventure mode and a campaign and all these other modes with their core mechanics.
Rym: But according to this article, they couldn't make any of them fun or replayable, which leads me to some worries about the fundamental mechanics of this game.
Scott: Well, I think that's just the problem.
Scott: You know, we talked about forever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, competitive and casual.
Scott: It's like they're trying to appeal to two audiences.
Scott: Right.
Scott: With the same game.
Rym: You know, we've only ever done that panel at Magfest in person.
Rym: It's one of our few like serious panels that's not on YouTube yet.
Rym: We haven't done the definitive version.
Scott: Interesting.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like, it's like they put two completely separate games in the same piece of software that share some rules together.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know, they have nothing to do with each other.
Scott: They're completely separate audiences who are at odds with each other.
Scott: One audience brings them a lot of money.
Scott: The other one doesn't bring a lot of money.
Scott: It just brings loyalty because they care about the game and want to win.
Rym: That second scene, the competitive scene for many games brings the esports and the alternative monetization streams if it gets big enough.
Rym: Like you can see a world where Overwatch competitive only makes money from like the live streams and the merchandising and the professional play.
Rym: And casual players, they make money from them because they buy stuff in the game.
Rym: So there is a way to monetize that, but that's difficult to monetize.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Scott: That's another good reason to go to tournaments with entry fees.
Scott: You make money that way.
Rym: The thesis of that panel that only people at Magfest have seen that we spent a lot of time on and I think we should do again someday with some tweaks was that you cannot, it is actually impossible to make a game that will appease competitive and casual players.
Scott: I also think that just regardless of what design decisions they make in this game in particular, that a miniatures game of this nature where there are two squads of units that fight until one of them is dead is that game is only going to be any good as a PvP one on one game.
Scott: It's not going to work as a co-op game.
Scott: It's not going to work as a PvE game.
Scott: It's only going to work as a competitive game.
Scott: No matter what you do without making something drastically different will only ever appeal to a competitive audience.
Scott: It's not going to appeal to a single player audience of grinding and all that nonsense.
Rym: If you did something which capitalism won't allow, if the game were like Advance Wars in that you had a campaign that was crafted so well to be fun to play with your deck against a long form campaign, they tried and failed to make a mode like that.
Scott: So yeah, so Moonbreaker as I guess the sum, the conclusion is that it's early access.
Scott: It could change.
Scott: The core concept is like gold almost platinum.
Rym: Somebody is going to make a game like this.
Rym: It might be them.
Rym: It might be someone else that is going to be the one.
Scott: This is something that has not been done before.
Scott: Painting your own miniatures genius.
Scott: It's like a miniatures squad based multiplayer genius.
Scott: The core concept is unbelievable.
Rym: But it's one poisoned by the capitalist need to monetize games in these toxic obfuscated randomized collectible exploitative ways.
Scott: And it needs a lot more.
Scott: It's surprisingly polished in many ways, but not polished enough.
Scott: This thing needs to be polished to Nintendo levels before it can be acceptable.
Rym: And remember, you know how Nintendo does that polish?
Rym: They hire an absolute army of experts to do it.
Rym: There's a reason they don't make that many games.
Scott: It's like, I know I used it as thing of the day before, right?
Scott: But what's his name?
Scott: Has the YouTube channel?
Rym: Oh yeah, I'll link to it again I guess.
Scott: Smash Brothers guy?
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: Let me find his actual channel.
Scott: Why can't I remember his name right now?
Scott: I'm going to feel real.
Rym: Masashiro Sakurai on Creating Games is the channel.
Scott: On Sakurai's YouTube channel, some of his videos have shown just some of these small details of polish that go into games.
Scott: For example, there was one video he talked about pauses.
Scott: He's like, look, here's a game where when you die, you just die instantly.
Scott: And here's a game where when an enemy bullet hits you, the game pauses for like a fraction of a second to emphasize each time you get hit.
Scott: He's like, see that?
Scott: It's like, if you're not a pro game developer, you don't know that, to do that in your games, right?
Scott: But it makes an enormous difference, and that's just one item of polish.
Scott: You have to know thousands of small details like that and incorporate them into your game to get it to the Nintendo level.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And right now, you know, it's early access, so maybe we'll get there, but the game lacks most of that kind of polish.
Rym: The mechanics are not polished, the UX is not polished, and like the graphics are not polished.
Scott: The graphics are polished in some ways.
Rym: They look great, they're just not functional as game graphics.
Scott: Yes, it is form over function polish, but some of the function is great, but there's function missing.
Scott: that is, you know.
Scott: So anyway, I remain hopeful because this is very close to my alley, you know.
Scott: It's not a strike, but it is, you know, it's maybe a spare, right?
Rym: I have to say, a game like this would be fantastic in VR as well, if you're just sitting at a table looking at it in VR and moving the pieces around with your hands.
Scott: Oh, you mean like an ARG kind of deal?
Scott: Where you have an actual table but no miniatures, and then you can actually move them?
Rym: That would be great.
Scott: What about ARG VR Paint the Miniatures?
Rym: Oh, see, well, uh, I don't think anyone's done anything like that, I gotta make sure.
Scott: There was that one where you could like paint a big blob in 3D in VR, right?
Rym: Oh yeah, you could definitely do something like that, I was trying to think if anyone has done anything even remotely like this.
Rym: There have been a handful of meh VR games that are like, here's a big miniature driven tabletop-y kind of game, but they're not, they're not this kind of game.
Scott: Yeah, I'm talking like, you know, actually like careful, slow painting of small things in VR.
Rym: Or never mind, like honestly, moving the guys, like the UX could almost be better in VR than it is on a desktop for a game like this, if done well.
Rym: Because then you avoid the problem of everything blends in with everything because it's almost rendered like they're real 3D components, but because of the angle you're looking- Yeah, you would see the unit sticking up out of the table better.
Rym: Yeah, because the problem is they designed it like that, but then when you look at it in game, you're looking from this angle that flattens everything out and everything's just a flat, just mess of pixels.
Rym: It's a little, I mean it's 3D, but it's- Yeah, but like look at it, like take the screen up, open your eyes, look at it for a few seconds, close your eyes and try to remember where fucking anything is.
Scott: I think what they, they would have just made a hex map instead of the free movement, you know?
Rym: Yeah, but the free movement is one of the few things I'm actually really interested in, like.
Rym: I feel like that's important to this game being worth playing at all.
Scott: It could be smaller, it doesn't have to be big ol' Battletech hexes, it can be smaller ones.
Rym: Nah.
Rym: Or just light highlighting of characters.
Scott: It's some sort of discreteness, such to give the movement discreteness, right?
Rym: You need some 2D aura highlighting on the 3D characters based on your angle of view to make them pop.
Rym: Nothing pops from the UI, that's one of the biggest problems.
Rym: Like nothing pops.
Rym: We beat this horse to death, so.
Scott: Hopefully, hopefully, you know, this game can, you know, it's come this far, it's still early access.
Rym: I'm not giving up on it, I'm gonna try to make the best deck I can and I'm gonna play it occasionally.
Scott: Yeah, I played in a tournament, I plan to try again, I lost obviously every match, I plan to try again.
Scott: You know, I'm gonna, when I get some time, right?
Rym: I'm gonna play this the way I played Magic as a kid, I'm gonna keep looking at who won tournaments, copy their decks.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I did.
Scott: And also, the, when it's, I think the line I'm gonna decide whether to go in on this game is gonna happen when it leaves early access.
Scott: We'll see what state it is in at that point, and if it's in a good state, then I'll go in on it, and if not, I'll be like, "Well, it was, it was a
Scott: try.".
Rym: And you know, if nothing else, Brendan Sanderson fans, even if this game is a complete flop, you'll probably be able to find an archive of the, probably hundreds of MP3s they're gonna record, that are the audio, like, story of this universe.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this particular episode of GeekNights are Alan Dreslin, Kijie, Dredlin, and Tinebrae on a bunch of Bepple who rarely don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Kasekare makes music, Chris of Dodd, Chris, Grimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Sherwin Von Horl.
Rym: Stop all the downloading.
Rym: The next station is Finch West, Finch West Station.
Rym: And a lot of people are very wisely giving us, like, less than $5 a month for the podcast that is just free on the internet.
Rym: So yeah, it's a shame that Discord's YouTube Together thing is just completely worthless.
Rym: We have discovered this, so spread the word, we'll see if they fix it.
Rym: But for now, I simply leave you with... He's saying he's like Short Circuit.
Rym: Mm-mm.
Rym: Nothing like Short Circuit.
Rym: Yeah, I was gonna say, he's nothing like Short Circuit.
Scott: I'm just like Short Circuit or Gremlins.
Scott: Hold on a second, let me look through this rulebook.
Rym: I wanna go to the bridge.
Scott: Why didn't you give me the book?
Scott: I only have one copy.
Scott: I wanna go to the bridge on the 15th Street.
Scott: Can you, like, copy the book and send it to me?
Scott: It's a big book, it'll take forever.
Scott: Take me to the bridge, please, at 15th and Olive.
Rym: No, do not take him to the bridge.
Scott: What do you mean no?
Scott: Uh, it says here he has a quest and you cannot let him complete it.
Rym: Do not let him complete the quest.
Scott: It has a quest!
Scott: I have a quest and I will complete it.
Rym: Tell me again how this is like a Gremlin.
Rym: It's like the one difference.
Rym: I have to fight the Mole Man.
Rym: What happens if he completes his quest?
Scott: He has my toothbrush.
Scott: As far as you know, there is no quest.
Scott: As far as I know, you told me he has a quest.
Scott: Now I'm not gonna stop thinking about his quest.
Scott: There's no quest, there's no Mole Man, there's no toothbrush.
Rym: I want an iPad.
Rym: Buy me an iPad.
Rym: He wants an iPad.
Scott: I don't have an iPad.
Scott: Oh, that's new.
Scott: I haven't heard that yet.
Rym: Get me an iPad, please.
Scott: I have, like, a second generation one somewhere, but it's, like, broken.
Scott: Let's watch Terms of Endearment.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: I need to find a plastic surgeon.
Rym: He wants surgery.
Rym: I'm one surgery away from perfection.
Scott: No, don't let him do that, actually, no.