Rym: It's Wednesday, July 27th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are reviewing Sonic X, the anime from 2003.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: And just to respond to the listener, this was not because either one of us lost a bet.
Rym: Uh, we just arbitrarily decided at the end of the last show that we would review something.
Rym: Scott doesn't pay for any streaming services anymore, and this happened to be free.
Rym: It just showed up.
Rym: I saw it at the top of my list.
Rym: I'm like,
Rym: "Amazon?".
Rym: And I was like, "All right, fuck it.
Scott: Sonic
Scott: time.".
Scott: The only streaming service I have is Amazon Prime Video because I have Amazon Prime.
Scott: And because it's a whole year, it's not like, you know, even if I decide to stop, it's like I still have it for quite a while.
Scott: And I'm using it.
Scott: I'm watching all the Bond movies on there.
Scott: And I'm like, "That's the only streaming service I got, Rym.
Scott: What anime do you want to
Scott: watch?".
Scott: And he just said, "Sonic
Scott: X.".
Scott: And I'm like, "Okay,
Scott: sure.".
Scott: He watched Amazon Prime.
Scott: He saw what anime was on there.
Scott: I guess that was the one he picked.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Because meanwhile, I switched everything.
Rym: Right now, Paramount is what we're doing because we're watching, like, every Star Trek.
Scott: I'm waiting for a, you know, there are things that I want to watch on some services.
Rym: Wait until there's a critical mass.
Rym: Then you, like, make a new Netflix account.
Scott: I'm waiting for a single service to have, you know, at least a month's worth of things to watch.
Rym: The time for you will be, I think, when Arcane Season 2 hits Netflix.
Rym: By then, there'll be enough of a backlog of good, short stuff on Netflix for it to be worth it for a month.
Rym: Arcane's still one of the best cartoons I've seen in a long, long time.
Scott: I think the other problem is that just, you know, I don't watch a lot of TV, period.
Scott: It's like, you know, 90% of the things that everyone is watching, I just have no interest in.
Scott: So it's like, it takes the streaming, you know, for someone else who watches, you know, I say the average American amount of television, you know, Netflix would fill up with enough stuff for them to watch in, like, a month or two, even if they had, you know, binged a ton of series.
Scott: Whereas for me, it could take several years for there to be enough things I actually want to see on Netflix.
Rym: This is the difference between Scott, who ignores 99% of everything, and me, who only ignores 98% of everything.
Rym: [Laughter].
Rym: So there's a bunch of anime and comic and manga-related news, and one to start with.
Rym: So this was a minor incident that shouldn't have been an incident, but it generated enough buzz.
Rym: It's worth talking about.
Rym: Mostly, I kind of want to just dunk on Japanese companies for continuing to not understand this.
Rym: So apparently, Anime Expo, there was a panel about Mob Psycho 100 season, like, there's a Mob Psycho panel.
Rym: And they had some sort of exclusive where, at the panel, they were going to show everyone the season 3 opener before other people got to see it.
Scott: And they were like-- And this happens at San Diego Comic-Con.
Scott: actually a lot, right, where there's trailers and previews and all kinds of things that they-- Right, it's not screenings like we had at Anime-Cons back in the day where we'd show whole shows and shit, right?
Scott: It's like, you come to a panel, they announce something, and then they show you some behind-the-scenes clip or a trailer or something, right, for the thing.
Scott: And that is the first time that thing has been shown to the public ever.
Scott: But, at least for as long as YouTube has been around, the past 5 to 10 years especially, those things end up on YouTube basically right after the panel's over, at the same time the panel starts.
Scott: And also remember, these aren't, like, leaks.
Scott: At least the same day, right?
Rym: These are things that will just be on TV when the show comes out.
Rym: Like, they'll be on YouTube officially, like, sometimes days after the convention anyway.
Scott: So, for example, San Diego Comic-Con just happened recently, right?
Scott: There was a John Wick panel, they showed a trailer for John Wick 4, and then it was on YouTube the same day, possibly within hours, or I don't know what the timing exactly was, but it was the same day as the panel, within 24 hours.
Scott: So, you know, that's just how things are these days, right?
Scott: That's just the way of doing things, right?
Scott: Some people, for some reason that I don't understand, find value and pleasure in, like, being in the panel room and seeing something, like, a few minutes before the rest of the world.
Scott: And it's like, if you, okay, sure, I don't understand it, there's no logical reason for enjoying that, but have fun, kids.
Rym: This is not, like, I don't know, the Denver Fenton Allen thing, where, like, it was this long shared experience, and being there was probably, like, being there was somewhat different and more engaging than seeing the YouTube video.
Scott: Right, it's not a concert where it's like, yeah, they're singing the same song you can hear on Spotify, but it's, you know, it's a live performance, it's not exactly the same as, right?
Scott: This is like, this is a video that is recorded.
Scott: Watching it elsewhere is going to be the exact same video.
Rym: It's a minute and 30 seconds of an anime opener that's going to be on TV.
Scott: Yes, you will see it, you can watch it to your heart's content at some point.
Rym: So, someone, of course, recorded it from the panel and put it on YouTube, and the Japanese company flipped out about it, and there's a big fight among attendees, and people were, like, people were getting into the whole fear that, well, leaks are serious, if you leak stuff like this, then the Japanese companies won't give us these things anymore.
Scott: Well, that may be true, because, you know, the Japanese, we've talked on and on, there's no point in talking again about how Japanese companies have the wrong attitude about, you know, sharing their creative works, right, and their artworks on the internet.
Rym: Someone commented on our Utena series today, asking when we'd start it up again.
Scott: Right, it's like, look at, K-pop is taking over the world.
Scott: Korea is a smaller country with a smaller economy, with, you know, basically less, it's smaller than Japan in every conceivable fashion, but yet, their cultural exports are dominating, not just the United States, right, the entire world, right?
Scott: South America, Middle East, you know, Europe, K-pop and other Korean television, Korean movies are dominating the world in, like, a Hollywood fashion, right?
Scott: BTS is, like, probably bigger than the Beatles ever were.
Scott: It could be, right?
Scott: And why?
Scott: Because they just, not only do they upload, like, the official music videos to YouTube, they upload extra shit, right?
Scott: Like, everything.
Scott: Behind the scenes, practice videos, interviews, right?
Scott: Every, like, there's, they just upload fucking everything to YouTube for free, right?
Scott: If Japan did that, Korea would actually, I don't think if Japan suddenly changed its attitude, I think Korea would actually be in big trouble, right?
Scott: Because, you know, like, if all Japanese television, just all of it, was translated and on YouTube for free, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, if all the mangas were in English, you could just read 'em, it's like, ah shit, it would be trouble for the entertainment, you know, media production of every country.
Scott: that wasn't Japan.
Scott: But they don't do that.
Scott: And I think the people who are saying, well, if you do these leaks, then the Japanese companies are gonna, you know, not, you know, they're gonna, they're gonna pull back even more.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: That's what they're gonna do.
Scott: That's how they are, right?
Scott: But that's not, that's not, I don't think that's a reason to not leak.
Scott: I think it's just, just deal with it, right?
Rym: I would say as, as like some random teen who's like hanging out in an anime con, that just makes the leaks funnier when they happen.
Rym: Because like I said, these are not leaks of like something that's actually exclusive.
Rym: That's just a little bit before everyone else will see it in a panel room that people probably lined up for hours for for some reason.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So even, it's like even the consequence that they're afraid of, right?
Scott: Oh, they won't show trailers at the cons early anymore, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, fine.
Rym: I will wait in line for a long time to see a panel that is like the creators I like talking about their thing.
Rym: That's the experience.
Rym: Showing me a clip from the show I'm already gonna watch.
Rym: The show that I care about so much that I waited in line just to see the people who make it that show?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If they stop showing things like this at the cons because they're worried about leaks, who gives a shit?
Rym: I think the cons would be healthier for it, to be honest.
Rym: The cons often mistakenly get too close to the industry where the industry is doing things that won't actually draw more people to the con or even make the con experience that much better, but they restrict what the con can do in many ways.
Rym: I remember where we really learned this lesson was at PAX's where I remember Civ 5, Civilization 5 was announced.
Rym: and I saw at PAX at a giant booth and you could play like five or ten minutes of it if you waited in this terrifying line.
Rym: I saw that booth and I thought, you know, I already preordered this game on Steam.
Rym: So why, why even engage with this booth?
Rym: I already threw my money down that hole.
Rym: I already threw those hours of my life away.
Scott: It was the time PAX East had the Portal thing and you could play Portal 2 for like a few, you know, some period of time.
Rym: I walked up behind someone else playing Portal 2 and said, oh, I think the thing that I am going to play when it comes out is going to be good based on what I see.
Scott: Portal 2 came out just like weeks after PAX East, right?
Scott: People waited all that line.
Scott: It's like I spent my time at PAX doing something else and then I went and played Portal 2 on my computer just shortly thereafter.
Scott: So yeah, it's like Japanese companies, they are the way they are.
Scott: They're wrong.
Scott: They should change.
Scott: But that doesn't mean that we shouldn't leak.
Scott: We should, you know, teach them, keep teaching them a lesson and if they don't, if they learn the wrong lesson, that's their problem and the consequences don't scare me at all.
Rym: I mean, you know, back when I was the director of like panels and workshops at a convention, remember occasionally there'd be a panel that had like weird like restrictions on like don't let anyone bring cameras or cell phones in and I remember very specifically how I addressed that.
Rym: I put up a one sign at the entrance that said like no cameras allowed and that was the extent of my intervention.
Rym: Whatever happened, happened.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And there's nothing, you know, you can't, if you're in a public place, it's like, it's like, you know, sure there are times where it's rude or wrong or inappropriate or privacy invading or abusive to photograph or videotape people and you shouldn't do it.
Scott: But at the same time, you, it's just a, you know, it's a reality of the world, right?
Scott: That like it's not all, you're not always going to be able to avoid it.
Rym: Well, case in point, you know what I'm not going to do?
Rym: Go to any concert.
Rym: that makes me put my cell phone in one of those secure bags until I leave.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Never would do that ever.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: I would not go to a concert that had that crap.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: We saw Hellsy at MSG.
Rym: They didn't give a shit.
Rym: Film the whole thing if you want.
Rym: They didn't care.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you know, it is somewhat annoying.
Scott: I go to, you know, concert.
Scott: I mean, when I was going to some concerts, right?
Scott: There's all these people.
Rym: Well, then there's the opposite problem.
Rym: I stand and there's a million people in front of me all holding their phone up, blocking my view, recording it.
Rym: That's a different problem.
Scott: That's slightly annoying.
Scott: And I don't understand that either.
Scott: Cause it's like only one person needs to do that, guys.
Scott: Just as long as that one person uploads it, we're all good.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Just link to that one YouTube video.
Rym: Every, draw lots on who gets to be the one every concert.
Scott: You know, but I guess it's like people, I don't know why people there's like, dude, do people who do that, watch those videos ever?
Scott: Do they go back and watch the video that they recorded at the concert?
Scott: I mean, they do.
Rym: I've never understood that.
Rym: Like, but you know, you see this a lot.
Rym: You see people who live their lives through their camera and don't actually stop and enjoy whatever it is that they're doing.
Scott: It's like, if I'm at a concert, will I re will I take a photo or a couple of photos and maybe a short video?
Scott: I would definitely take a short video cause that'll be in my short video clip and I'll like upload it.
Scott: I'll tweet it or something like that or post it on a discord or 10 seconds.
Rym: I might see that video and be like, Oh yeah, that was that concert I saw, you know, back before, uh, before the war.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like, if I really want to relive that exact concert, I know somebody else recorded the whole thing and uploaded it to YouTube.
Scott: So I'll search for it and there it is.
Scott: And it's like, why does you don't need that many people doing it?
Rym: So, uh, some other news, uh, the television show, well, the Netflix show stranger things.
Rym: Uh, there's an article about something happening with stranger things that is happening in a lot more places and has been happening in anime for a long time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I think the first occurrence of it that was really that I understood was star Wars, right?
Scott: Special edition.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that, you know, when the special editions came out, I was like, ah, you know, upgraded version, but we didn't understand until a little bit after that.
Scott: Like, Oh, they're trying to eliminate the original version.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like the most of the time and throughout history, it's like there was artwork.
Scott: And artwork that got modified would be like a painting that someone painted over, which happens and has happened throughout all of history.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: Or a sculpture that somebody would like modify.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, um, but when it came to like, you know, books, right, it's like books had additions that were printed, but because they were distributed, the old additions are still out there.
Rym: Or if, or many times too, when there were new additions or updates or changes to something, even film, anything, oftentimes they were restricted to like correcting an error.
Rym: Like if there's a typo in your book, you just correct the typo.
Rym: The typo was not intrinsic to the work.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But any form of art or, or publication, basically any publication, something that had a mass printing with multiple copies, right.
Scott: Where copies were made in the, you know, it's like, whether it was music or a newspaper, right.
Scott: It's like as every printing, every official printing was existing as long as someone preserved it right.
Scott: Video games that had patches.
Scott: It's like, you can load up any patch you want.
Scott: Cause they're all out there somewhere.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, you know, you can buy cartridges for SNES games of like every different version of, uh, links awakening.
Scott: Um, you know, they're really minor differences that most people will never notice, but there, there's some bug fixes in there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, but now with the streaming times, right, people aren't actually keeping copies.
Scott: Pirates are, but most people are not keeping copies of the originals.
Scott: And you know, as you know, we stopped buying physical medias or things aren't even released on physical media.
Scott: There aren't non pirate copies of things.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So if you're, if you make a TV, let's say you make a movie and you stream it and you decide you want to change, edit, you forgot an edit, but people have already watched the movie and you go and you, you can.
Scott: now, if you wanted to, you could just put up a second post, like, you know, director's cut.
Scott: And now people can choose.
Rym: Like what happened with the Blade Runner back in the day, there was the original cut, director's cut, The Abyss, movie cut, like home video cut.
Scott: You can watch all the cuts.
Scott: You can pick whichever one you want, but, uh, we have a situation here with Stranger Things.
Scott: They're going back and they're editing the episodes that are on there.
Scott: So if you were to watch Stranger Things now, you would not see it in the form in which it was originally streaming.
Scott: Unless you went and got a pirated copy somewhere.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's like, and it's sort of back to the olden days of painting over a painting and re chiseling a sculpture where it's like the original is gone.
Scott: ish.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Except for pirates.
Rym: And may or may not actually be a deep problem.
Rym: Like, for example, uh, Sailor Moon Crystal, a lot of anime airs on TV, just busted, just like bad animation errors everywhere.
Rym: And then they basically fix the whole thing.
Rym: And then they release it on other formats later.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, a lot of manga.
Scott: when it's published in its original, you know, magazine is not the same.
Scott: You know, it gets changed a lot when they go and republish it in the, the, the talk of on compilations.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Here's a totally separate example.
Rym: Say I have a website with some stuff on it.
Rym: Very few websites post a change log where you can look at every iteration of that website that they have ever had.
Rym: You can't go see Wikipedia has a log.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Wikipedia does have a log.
Rym: Not many websites do, nor would I expect them to.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Uh, but you know, newspapers, I think should, you know, all these big newspapers have some responsibility to show what the edits were.
Scott: There is a website that like tracks the edits to newspapers and such.
Rym: But I guess there's a lot going on here because there's no like hard pronouncement to make here.
Rym: Some aspects of this are good.
Rym: Like, you know, a show is out, someone notices a minor error, like you've like a compositing error and you fix it like cool.
Rym: Uh, someone changes the plot.
Rym: Someone like alters some dialogue that gets into different territory.
Rym: Uh, but it also starts edging into the opposite argument of fans almost get too entitled to the works to the point that a lot of fans freak out and demand access to all these like sub iterations for their own entitled enjoyment of the show and not for any archival purposes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, as if, you know, while we look at Star Wars and we're like, yeah, the original one is the, is the good one.
Scott: That's not a hard and fast rule at all.
Rym: No, that's, that's actually one of the rare cases.
Rym: Hillyman Crystal, the new version is what everyone intended.
Scott: The early version was just rushed out.
Scott: Just because this, this idea that people have that just because something was like the first published edition, that's somehow the real edition, the end, right?
Scott: It's like, it's like, actually that's not necessarily the case.
Scott: You know, I mean, if given a set of additions of something, yeah, one of them will be like better, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: People may be equal and different.
Scott: People may disagree.
Rym: Go ask a random person which Blade Runner cut they like and you might start a knife fight.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you know, sometimes it's more clear cut, right?
Scott: You know, the Aliens director's cut is the best.
Rym: Aliens is only the proper version of Aliens has those auto turrets and that full auto turret scene.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I didn't realize that until somewhat recently.
Rym: Oh, the Abyss.
Rym: Go look at that.
Rym: The Abyss was cut way more than I thought between theatrical and later releases.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But here's, so here's an example.
Scott: We'll go back to K-pop again.
Scott: This actually happens quite more often than you would think where they'll put out some video.
Scott: Usually it's usually happens more like the official music video has a problem and there'll be something in the video that is controversial or causes an uproar of some kind.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they are very responsive to up roars.
Scott: It's like they'll fire people for up roars.
Scott: They'll cancel people's contracts for up roars about small things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Unproven things, proven things, whatever.
Scott: So like for example, I've seen cases where like someone was wearing a shirt in a music video and they didn't speak English.
Scott: They didn't realize that the, what the shirt was saying, and then they'll go and they'll take the music video down, edit it, make a whole new one and upload it to different, the original one's gone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They'll upload a music video and one of the people they'll have a TV show and they'll record the whole show.
Scott: And they're going to put another episode, but in between the last episode and this episode, somebody was, uh, had a scandal, right.
Scott: Or at least what they would be would considered a scandal in Korea, not in the U S right.
Scott: Um, they'll edit, re edit the whole episode to remove that person as much as, as possible, blur them out.
Scott: And it's like completely.
Scott: And then, you know, it's like, they'll do all kinds of takedowns and re uploads.
Scott: And sometimes it's good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, Oh, we accidentally did a racist.
Scott: Let's remove it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Oh, there was some bad audio quality.
Scott: Let's fix it.
Scott: You know, take it down, put up a different one.
Scott: So sometimes it's good.
Scott: Sometimes it's bad.
Rym: Overwatch, how many versions of Overwatch have come out?
Rym: They just changed the game.
Rym: You can't play the old version.
Rym: The new versions Counter Strike.
Scott: They added a whole new gun.
Scott: True.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, this is just a space like, like, you know, usually GeekNights, we tend to bring up a topic and then be like, and here's the way.
Rym: But here, this is just a big messy space where there's a lot of room for discussion.
Scott: I think, you know, on the one hand, I think that if you are making a significant popular preservation worthy artwork, that all of your additions should at least be saved somewhere for archival historical purposes.
Rym: Obviously not necessarily any pre-release work.
Rym: You don't need to keep the changelog of the premiere project for the 10 years.
Scott: But it would be, it would be really nice for people to keep that.
Rym: It would be cool if people kept that.
Rym: That's the kind of stuff I think would really be interesting to society.
Scott: Especially people want to go back and, you know, someone needs to come and do a study on it, you know, years later and make a documentary.
Rym: So, for GeekNights, I actually do keep the raw recording session full, in full, for a year for every episode before I purge them.
Rym: And I keep the raw original audio forever.
Rym: But the actual session I get rid of after a year.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, it's like, you know, even just someone to do, like, you know, I go to see a museum exhibit at, you know, and it's like they have all these, you know, production, you know, art packs.
Rym: Or hell, look at what happens every time someone gets a hold of the original studio recording of any famous band's work with every individual track broken out.
Rym: That is always a recipe for someone doing something amazing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, but you should preserve these things, right?
Scott: But it's like sometimes there's good reasons to edit, sometimes not.
Scott: And we're going to have to judge on a case-by-case basis.
Scott: If somebody, you know, does paint over a painting or re-chisel a sculpture or, you know, edit something that's streaming only and now no one can see the old versions.
Scott: We're going to have to see what they changed and then judge that individually over whether it was good or not.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So speaking of leaks from before, a while ago, this was years ago, we talked about on GeekNights, there was an animation test for a Sony Pictures Popeye movie with Tartakovsky.
Rym: Like, Tartakovsky worked.
Rym: 3D, it looked amazing.
Rym: Like, this animation test looked phenomenal.
Rym: And nothing, we never heard of it again.
Rym: That movie just never went anywhere.
Scott: Yep, that shit, this happens a lot, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, something will be not, you know, made or partially made, right?
Scott: And sometimes announced.
Rym: Sometimes finished, sometimes a movie will be done.
Rym: Like, in the can, completely ready, and it just never gets released.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, you know, we've had cases like Mouse Guard Movie or, um, what was the other one I was thinking of?
Rym: I mean, Nothing Lasts Forever is like the archetypical example.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, that was released-ish.
Rym: Yeah, ish.
Rym: Ish.
Rym: So, this Popeye movie got way further than any of us realized.
Rym: Now, it's funny, this is a leak.
Rym: I watched a bunch of it.
Rym: I didn't think to save it.
Rym: I'm sure you'll find it somewhere, but it has now been taken down by Sony.
Rym: But someone uploaded to YouTube an entire 87 minute long animatic.
Rym: It is basically the entire movie.
Rym: An animatic, like, ready to rock.
Rym: They were basically one step before starting principal animation on this show.
Rym: And, or this movie.
Rym: And they just never made it.
Rym: And the worst part is, from what I watched, this movie would have been amazing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, people spent, Hollywood, you know, big people with lots of money, you know, spend a lot of money, you know, taking things pretty far, right?
Scott: You know, they spent, when they option scripts, it's like they're paying screenwriters for those scripts, even if they don't use them.
Scott: You know, they're not paying much, they're paying something, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, people are buying, licensing rights to make things based on properties, right?
Scott: And then they don't make them, right?
Scott: A Kira live action movie.
Scott: Someone paid for that and worked on it.
Scott: Evangelion live action.
Scott: Someone paid and worked on that.
Scott: It never happened, right?
Scott: It's still not out.
Scott: But it's like, there's money that goes into producing things and they just don't finish, right?
Scott: And so I think the lesson to learn here is, A, artifacts that are created from those unfinished things could still have value, entertainment value, because there is quality there.
Scott: There is artwork that someone put effort into.
Rym: Hell, I would say as a selfish capitalist.
Scott: If there are legal avenues to release those things, then the people who possess those legal rights should maybe consider doing it because you can, you know.
Rym: Well, case in point, take those assets, release them, and if they get a big response, now you've got market evidence that if you make the real movie, it'll sell.
Scott: That's if they actually cared, right?
Scott: And then I think B, though, is that if you have access to these things, you should, I encourage you to illegally release them for the good of the collective world culture.
Scott: And C, right, is that if you are a person who is making, you know, whether it's art or any kind of creation, right, crafting software, whatever it is you're working on, and it's like you start 10 things and you can't finish anything, right?
Scott: And it's like, and then, you know, it's like you never get anything published or done or whatever.
Scott: You just keep starting stuff and you can't get anything over the finish line like GeekNights' website.
Scott: Don't feel bad because for every movie that Hollywood fucking makes, there's like 10, 20 movies, however many that they just don't finish, right?
Scott: It's like you just don't see those.
Scott: So you think that like everything they start, they finish.
Scott: It's like, no, it's like, you know, they're, you know, big time authors start in 20 books.
Scott: that for every book that makes it to the shelf on the virtual shelf.
Scott: They started like a whole bunch of books that didn't get put, right?
Scott: It's like very few artists out there are finishing everything they start.
Rym: So one last little news.
Rym: I didn't think I'd ever talk to them in GeekNights, but, you know, one of the things I take a certain amount of perverse pleasure in is watching a fan convention implode.
Rym: Like big convention drama is something I, it entertains me from a distance, but at the same time, I never want to be involved in it.
Scott: I think it's definitely a privilege of having a relatively drama free existence that I can watch drama and read about drama that may or may not, I don't even care if the drama is true or not.
Scott: It doesn't really matter, right?
Scott: I basically, you know, like consider, I don't, you know, I assume it could be true or false.
Scott: It doesn't matter to me, but it's like I read it as I read about dramas as if they're stories.
Scott: And they're often very entertaining.
Scott: And if they're true, that much the better, as long as the drama goes the right way.
Scott: It's the same reason people watch like, you know, a Judge Judy or whatever.
Scott: It's like other people's drama, right?
Scott: Or that subreddit, am I the asshole?
Scott: Same thing, right?
Rym: I think part of it too is that we, we have pointedly really only, and COVID of course mess everything up.
Rym: We only go to very well run conventions and we have very strong opinions about how to run conventions as well.
Rym: And usually when there's big convention drama, it is the convention that is doing the kinds of things that we specifically say you should not do, pretty much across the board.
Rym: So there is an anime convention that you should all just be aware of.
Rym: It's called Anime Matsuri.
Rym: And it is the worst anime convention in the world.
Scott: It is like the worst that we know of.
Scott: It's in Houston, Texas, right?
Rym: It is.
Rym: It's pretty big.
Scott: It's been around for a while because that name seems like there could be other cons with that name.
Rym: I'll link to it.
Rym: I'll link to some stuff so no one confuses, but it, they've been sued like more than 10 times by their own guests.
Rym: They had at least one guest deported because they fucked up.
Rym: They, they're the con who not only kept inviting Vic Mignona and like the bad people around that whole sex pest situation after the court case, but they doubled down on featuring him prominently and supporting him and supporting his sexual harassment like openly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This wasn't a case of like, oh, we didn't know cause we don't pay attention to the internet, right?
Scott: We just said, wow, this guy, you know, cause there are cons out there that in good faith, right?
Scott: It's like they didn't know.
Scott: They just said, wow, this guy's a famous voice actor, right?
Scott: He actually did voice act all these, you know, big time roles.
Scott: Um, we're an anime con.
Scott: It's like, he's going to sell us tickets.
Scott: Why?
Scott: You know, they don't know anything about him.
Scott: They don't know any about the drama and they bring them in this con with pretty much no doubts, right?
Scott: They knew exactly what they were doing, right?
Scott: They are openly the bad people.
Rym: They invite like right wing YouTubers from the, uh, that movement that harasses the people that Vic Mignona was harassing himself.
Scott: Somebody who would be banned from a decent convention is likely to be a guest of honor at Anime Matsu.
Rym: It is amazing how most of their guests are people banned from other conventions.
Rym: Uh, but also like their lines are terrible.
Rym: Like everything about this con is bad.
Scott: And they're not managing the con well, right?
Scott: They're just focused on just being bad.
Rym: So this, this fucking con, uh, has spun up a company that is going to be a dubbing studio and they are collaborating with good old Vic Mignona.
Rym: And they're, they're basically, their take is we're going to take dubbing back from the SJWs who ruined it.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Rym: With hookers and blow, I assume.
Rym: Like this is just a shit show scam, obviously.
Rym: But, uh, I just really need to make sure nobody who listens to GeekNights accidentally goes to this fucking anime con.
Scott: Who, who that has an anime license is going to hire them to dub their anime?
Scott: Nobody.
Scott: Absolutely nobody.
Rym: This has got to be like an actual scam, but I can't prove it because I'm not close to the details.
Rym: I also don't want to get sued, but if they sued me, I'm pretty sure in discovery we would find out that this is not a healthy company.
Scott: You don't say.
Rym: That is my opinion.
Scott: But yeah, I think there, you know, it is a problem in that, you know, there are websites that like, you know, catalog all the different conventions out there.
Scott: Like animecons.com is like a terrific resource that shows you all the anime cons, all the info about them and everything.
Scott: But they're not reviewing the, they're not giving you the real scoop on the con.
Scott: Like, is it well run?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Etc.
Scott: They're just sort of giving you informational stuff.
Scott: This is when it is, these are who the guests are, this is when it started, this is how many years it ran, years it didn't run, attendance, etc.
Rym: Controversies!
Scott: Right?
Scott: We need, you know, for all the problems that get, arise when you have, you know, reviews online of things, right?
Scott: You know, fraudulent reviews, you know, bullshit reviews, etc.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Like Yelp and Amazon, you can see how much problems there are with their review systems.
Scott: But for all those problems, I think that those systems, at least when they're moderated sufficiently, which is not out of the realm of possibility, they are a net benefit to the greater, you know, population.
Scott: You know, you could tell it's like, yeah, there might be a bunch of fake Yelp reviews, but you can tell just by looking at them, whether it's a restaurant you want to go to.
Scott: We need some kind of review system for cons so that, not just for people who probably just know the cons in their area and aren't likely to go to any others, but for guests and vendors who are likely to go to many cons, right?
Scott: It's like they, you know, it would be very helpful to them, especially to have, you know, more detailed info about what a con is like so that when they get a letter that's like, hey, do you want to come to this con?
Scott: Or they're thinking about going to set up a booth at a con, whether it's a good idea or not, they'd have more to go on because there just isn't that much info on the internet to help you.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Of course, at the same time for PAX, you'd probably see tens of thousands of reviews where people say the expo hall isn't big enough.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you would see all kinds of, you know, but it's like you could, it's better than having no information.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Well, plus, you know, I would apply to that kind of review.
Rym: That would be a positive review in my eyes.
Rym: because one thing I do, this is such a reliable method.
Rym: If I'm trying to figure out if a restaurant is good to eat at, I will look at a few five star reviews, unlike Google Maps or whatever, and just see if they're talking about the food.
Rym: And if they are, and there's a lot of good reviews, I would then look at several one star reviews and I'm looking for something specific.
Rym: If all the one star reviews are complaining about the service as opposed to the food, the people doing those reviews are probably bad people and the restaurant is probably amazing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I'm only looking for good food, right?
Scott: I don't really care.
Scott: It's like there is a point at which service is so bad that it becomes a problem.
Rym: Like the one time you and I considered dining and dashing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it is quite rare.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, usually what I'm looking for specifically is there's a certain kind of like entitled, "I was here with my children and the wait staff didn't smile at them and they are
Rym: trying.".
Rym: That is a sign of a good restaurant if you see that kind of one star review.
Rym: Because the waiter who did not smile at that horrific child is the kind of waiter I want waiting at my table.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: A reasonable human being who doesn't take shit from assholes.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: I try to avoid doing the same YouTube channel like too often as a thing of the day, but Captain Disillusion does not upload videos that frequently.
Scott: Because he puts so much time and effort into them.
Scott: They can't make them that frequently.
Rym: He's the kind of guy who just disappears into a cave for what feels like a decade and he just staggers out and hands us a triumph on YouTube.
Rym: So last night.
Scott: But he was actually working on it the whole damn time.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Last night, I was sitting in front of the HDPC and I got a little ding because he uploaded a video.
Scott: You have the bell on.
Rym: I have the bell on.
Scott: It's actually an advantage actually I think to uploading rarely.
Scott: Captain Disillusion is probably the perfect example of this on YouTube.
Scott: It's like I don't give anyone the bell on YouTube.
Scott: There is no case in the world where I need to be immediately notified that a video has been uploaded to YouTube.
Scott: Like I'll go to YouTube on my own.
Scott: I'll click subscriptions and I'll see it when the time comes.
Scott: It's not something I need to be distracted from whatever I'm doing to know about.
Scott: But if the bell, I think the only time it would be acceptable is if somebody makes particularly high quality videos such that you want to see all of them and they upload videos rarely.
Scott: And Captain Disillusion, that's exactly what he is.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So this video is pretty amazing.
Rym: It's actually relevant to some of our news as well.
Rym: So he collaborated with a Japanese band, Atarashi Gako, like a girl group.
Scott: Who I had never heard of but they seem cool.
Rym: And he made three short music videos for them with his like quality.
Rym: Like good god.
Rym: And he broke down in detail exactly how to make them and it is a 22 minute case study in how trippy, modern, amazing music videos are made for real practically.
Rym: In detail.
Scott: Plus commentary on the YouTube copyright review.
Rym: Oh yeah, I was about to bring that up also.
Rym: He has the correct opinions on the way copyright is enforced on YouTube.
Scott: And also the correct opinions on what music videos are the best.
Rym: I was about to say, so he shows a lot of music videos in the background and like speaks to them and references them.
Rym: Literally, without exception, 100% of the videos he mentions or shows at any point are in my good music videos playlist on YouTube already.
Scott: Yup, pretty much.
Rym: So this video is a triumph.
Rym: and now we know how the correspondents made that ridiculous video with them running around in a circle.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So usually, you know, people, there's a hobby of making models, right?
Scott: Shipping a bottle, model rocket, model train, Gundam model, car model, military models.
Scott: It's a big, big hobby making models, but most people when they make models, all they're really doing is making a miniature look alike, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, so if like you make a model plane, it's like, it's not going to work.
Scott: It's not made of the same material.
Scott: It's probably just plastic in the same shape as the thing.
Scott: you're right.
Scott: You're making an object that looks like a much larger object on the surface, but is not actually structurally the same as that actual object, right?
Scott: If you were going to make a model, you know, space shuttle, the bottom would not be made out of heat proof tiles, right?
Scott: It would just be black plastic on the bottom.
Scott: and that's it, right?
Scott: So and if someone did make a model space shuttle at like 1/100 scale or something and the bottom was made of heat proof tiles, I want to see that because that's awesome.
Scott: So this dude in this video makes a model suspension bridge, which is cool.
Scott: And he makes that model suspension bridge out in the woods, which is extra cool, right?
Scott: Usually people are making models inside, right?
Scott: Who makes models like out in nature, right?
Scott: He found like a small stream to make the suspension bridge over.
Scott: I don't even know if it qualifies as stream, but you know, it's a small amount of water.
Rym: I would say this is a crick, maybe a creek, more like this is a crick.
Scott: A long puddle, whatever, I don't know.
Scott: But he's, you know, he's got a, has a body of water of some size to make a small suspension bridge over, but he constructs the suspension bridge much like a real suspension bridge with, you know, cement.
Scott: I don't know if it's concrete, concrete, but it's definitely cement, you know, metal reinforcement, like tiny rebar, I guess.
Scott: Your wires to, right?
Rym: It's like, that is what set me over the edge.
Rym: The tiny rebar is delightful like that.
Rym: That made this great, right?
Scott: Like tiny twisted cables for the suspension part.
Scott: It's like he's at, it's somewhat structurally similar to an actual full size suspension bridge.
Scott: So those two factors, the outside factor and the real like construction factor make this really unique and awesome.
Scott: And I'm sad it's only in like a Twitter video.
Scott: I wish I, if someone has a link to like a YouTube video or any, I don't even know if it's the original source, but like a better source anywhere.
Scott: Let me know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If I found this like out in the woods, that would be amazing.
Scott: That would be amazing.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book.
Rym: It's a short book.
Rym: We're probably going to show on it next week on Thursday.
Rym: It should not take you long to read.
Scott: Maybe Tim, maybe.
Scott: I didn't even buy it yet.
Rym: We could wait.
Rym: We'll do it either next Thursday or more likely the following Thursday episode.
Rym: But Binti by Nnedi Okorafor and Space University is always a thing that we are into.
Rym: So I think this would be a good read.
Rym: And we are very much considering.
Rym: Let us know if you think this is a good idea or a great idea.
Rym: Moving into a format where each book club book, whoever's turn it is to pick, presents two options.
Rym: And then the other of us chooses which of the two will be read.
Scott: Ah, would you like to read Poop or Diarrhea?
Scott: Ah, would you like to?
Scott: We could go the other way though, right?
Scott: Because it's like, you know, would you like to read the chocolate or the other chocolate?
Rym: There's going to be a lot of fun with this.
Rym: It's also another.
Rym: It's a good safety mechanism to prevent another Genji.
Rym: Though, I am more than willing to put a certain very long novel, which is not The Count of Mind and Crystal.
Rym: I actually have something.
Rym: I was about to say worse.
Rym: It's definitely a better book and I've never actually read it.
Rym: I don't know if you read.
Rym: I do not know if you've ever read it either.
Rym: So.
Scott: War and Peace?
Rym: Nah, nothing.
Rym: Well, I was about to say nothing like that.
Rym: But that's actually not 100% true.
Rym: I'm going to wait until we decide if it's my pick or not.
Rym: I've picked the two books I'm going to put before you and I'm really curious.
Scott: Of those large books that I just mentioned, the only one I've read the beginning of Crime and Punishment.
Rym: Oh, Crime and Punishment's not even that long.
Rym: He's got way longer books.
Scott: I know, but I'm just saying, of those ones that came to mind.
Rym: I've read Crime and Punishment twice.
Rym: It's actually my favorite of his works.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You think I've actually completely read any of his works?
Rym: You know what's the most called a cough?
Rym: Also, I will be live at PAX West 2022 on Sunday, September 4th, 1230 PM Pacific Time in the Sasquatch Theater.
Rym: That's the big one in the Sheraton.
Rym: With a panel.
Rym: I'm bringing back an old topic with a completely new lecture.
Rym: Losing.
Rym: Going to talk about losing.
Scott: It's probably not completely new.
Rym: It actually will be completely new because.
Scott: Probably just saying all kinds of stuff we've said ten times before.
Rym: Nah, you know what it's more like?
Rym: The other losing panel that I did by myself at PAX Australia because you didn't come.
Rym: It's a new version of that.
Scott: One thing I do want to say though about PAX West this year is that I saw some confirmations of some large industry returning.
Scott: And that's I guess a good sign for PAX.
Scott: And also I saw that Reggie, who I guess, I don't know what his job is now, but he's on a panel there.
Scott: It's like, it's a, you know, it's not a. obviously ask Reggie everything you wanted to know panel.
Scott: Even though some people will hijack the Q&A and try to make it that.
Scott: He's on a panel with some other people discussing like some other topic.
Scott: But it's like, that's still really cool to see someone like Reggie just out of PAX on a panel.
Scott: Even if it's not, you know, the things you want to hear him saying.
Scott: But I feel like he already had his, you know, sort of tell all that he's willing to tell interview that you can read.
Rym: Yeah, I think he's at the point where we're not going to learn any new bombshells until he's on his deathbed in distant future.
Scott: I don't think we're going to learn.
Scott: I don't think there's any bombshells left to know.
Rym: Nah, you never know.
Rym: There's always surprising bombshells.
Rym: But yeah, getting a little sick of COVID because I got to make it clear.
Rym: I'll be doing this panel.
Rym: I got some other work to do around PAX.
Rym: But if you were there, I will not be hanging out in the con playing board games.
Rym: I'll be in working and I'll be out like in Seattle doing outdoor things otherwise.
Scott: Yeah, and I got a new job.
Scott: And even though my new job, I never work on Friday.
Scott: I don't have, I basically have zero vacation days right now.
Scott: I actually used one.
Scott: So I'm in the negative.
Scott: Even though I only used one PTO day, then I'm not going to use another one for probably some months.
Scott: So, you know, but I will have enough for holiday times to take extra days.
Scott: You never know.
Rym: We might, uh, PAX Unplugged.
Scott: Plus, I only have to use four to get a whole week off, right?
Scott: Right.
Rym: I doubt.
Scott: And I still accrue as many, so.
Rym: I doubt we will go to PAX Unplugged and play games in the con because it's still going to be a mass event, which makes that difficult.
Rym: But not out of the realm.
Rym: We could do a joint panel again at PAX Unplugged.
Rym: We'll see how things look.
Scott: Yeah, I'm hopeful for PAX Unplugged, but I'm not locking anything in.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I will definitely be there doing a panel by myself if you don't come.
Scott: I would like to go, right?
Scott: But we had to see what the circumstances are, so, you know.
Rym: Yeah, we will see.
Rym: So, Sonic X.
Scott: I, uh, the only Sonic- Well, before we talk about Sonic X, right, I just gotta say, when I was a kid, right, there were two Sonic cartoons on TV, right?
Scott: And I think both of them were just called Sonic the Hedgehog.
Scott: I don't know how many other kids of the 90s remember this.
Scott: One of them was, like, syndicated on TV.
Scott: You could see it on all your local channels.
Scott: It was really easy to watch.
Scott: It was on all the time.
Scott: And it was mostly a poorly animated comedy episodic thing, right?
Scott: And it focused on Scratch and Grounder as, like, the bad guys.
Scott: They were sort of like a bebop and Rocksteady kind of deal, right?
Scott: And I did enjoy that as a kid.
Scott: I don't know how much it holds up now, but it had a charm to it, right?
Scott: It was much closer to, like, the Mario Brothers cartoon that was in the Mario Brothers Super Show, right?
Rym: I think that one was the Adventures of Sonic the Hedgehog.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I'm sure we could Google it and get the right answer.
Rym: I am trying to Google it.
Scott: There was another Sonic the Hedgehog cartoon that was on TV at literally the same time, like, concurrently on TV.
Scott: I could watch one one day.
Rym: Yeah, so that one was Adventures of Sonic, and it only ran for one year.
Rym: And at 1993, the one you're about to talk about ran for two years.
Rym: '93 to '94.
Rym: And it was just called Sonic the Hedgehog.
Scott: Right, so the one called Sonic the Hedgehog was, like, a special one.
Scott: It was, for the time, well animated, right?
Scott: It was on Saturday morning cartoons only at a special time.
Scott: Like, you couldn't see it otherwise.
Scott: It wasn't just on whenever, you know?
Scott: And it was, like, a serial plot with all kinds of characters, right?
Rym: It was, you know, much more akin to, I think- The hell?
Rym: They were both made by Deke?
Rym: Why were there two?
Rym: Now I don't know why there were two.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: But anyway, so that one was, like, the real deal one.
Scott: And I, you know, the thing with that one is, like, I wanted to watch it.
Scott: But because it was only on at, like, a certain time, and it was serial, it's, like, you would watch it, and I tried to watch it, and I didn't know what the hell was going on.
Scott: So I didn't enjoy it, and I didn't get to watch it from the start, and it's not like I was gonna, what was I gonna do in 1990, whatever.
Scott: Buy all of it on VHS if that was even possible, download it, get a DVD box set.
Scott: It's, like, I'm sure I could now.
Rym: Oh my god, this Wikipedia article, the second one, the better one, considered one of the darker incarnations of Sonic.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: It was a dark, like, serious serial adventure, you know, storyline.
Scott: Anyway, but, so, I knew, right, you know, I stopped watching television mostly around early 2000s, so I knew that there were more Sonic cartoons that had come out after those two.
Scott: But I didn't know which ones they were, I never watched any of them, I never, I didn't know their names.
Rym: So there aren't actually that many more, so you know what the next one after that was?
Rym: And it was way later.
Rym: Sonic X. No, 1999, Sonic Underground.
Scott: Oh right, but Sonic Underground was a continuation, that was a continuation of the dark one, basically.
Rym: So Sonic Underground was the third and final one made by Deke, and it also only ran for one year.
Rym: And then, in 1999, and then in 2003, the longest running Sonic the Hedgehog with three seasons was Sonic X that we just started watching.
Scott: Alright, what came after that?
Rym: Sonic Boom in 2014.
Scott: Oh, Sonic Boom.
Scott: Is there any more since then, or is that it?
Rym: No, that's it, there's only five Sonic cartoons.
Scott: So I had never heard of Sonic X or watched Sonic X until yesterday, I watched like three or four episodes, I forget how many.
Rym: I watched six.
Scott: That's a lot.
Scott: It is a lot.
Scott: I wouldn't have made it through six.
Scott: Yeah, I was right.
Scott: Spoilers on my opinion of Sonic X.
Rym: I will say this, before we, we'll talk about it at the end, some things we learned about the production.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: But my opinion is not, I guess, might not be the true opinion.
Rym: But what I will say is that, one, it's an anime.
Rym: Like, it is an anime, it aired in Tokyo first.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't know that.
Scott: I started, I thought it was just a US show, but it wasn't, it was an anime.
Rym: Yup, TMS Entertainment, like it fully produced in Japan, like there's a whole- It was a lot like Pokemon, right?
Scott: It's an anime.
Rym: It was on TV Tokyo, and if I have to say anything about it, one, it's a perfectly good kid's show.
Scott: Like, if I was a kid- Oh yeah, there's nothing offensive about it for kids.
Rym: Not just offensive, this was better than any fucking cartoon I watched as a kid.
Rym: In America.
Scott: I mean, it's not Thundercats good.
Rym: Ah, Thundercat, well, one, you said- You implied that Thundercats was good.
Rym: Thundercats is good by some definitions of the word good.
Scott: Thundercats is better than Sonic X.
Rym: Eh, I think they're similar.
Scott: It's better than American Sonic X. Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But, uh, the funny thing about it is I did not realize Sonic X is where that Gotta Go Fast song actually seems to come from.
Scott: I didn't know that either.
Rym: And I think that's only in the American release.
Scott: I didn't even know that Gotta Go Fast was a song, I thought it was just a thing being read in relation to Sonic the Hedgehog.
Rym: We have only watched the American release, which was for kids, so they called out all the drinking, and sex, and violence, and you might say, "Wait, were there drinking, sex, and
Rym: violence?".
Rym: And the answer is yes.
Rym: This Sonic takes place in modern day Earth.
Rym: Sonic and the crew and Dr.
Rym: Robotnik are transported to Earth, and it's just, they're fucking around with humans, and giant robots are fighting, and it's kind of violent.
Rym: It's, uh, not what I expected.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, according to the internet, this was heavily edited.
Scott: I don't know, I can't actually comment on the editing because I haven't seen the original, right?
Scott: So I'm sort of reviewing this sort of messed up, edited American version that's been censored, and dubbed, and whatever, because that's all I have access to easily, and all I'm willing to put the effort into.
Scott: But yeah, it's totally believable that the original anime version was probably way better, and darker, and superior in every way.
Scott: But I don't know how good that original one was, because I can't see it, or at least I'm not willing to go through the effort of seeing it.
Rym: I did realize that I don't know the names of most Sonic characters watching this.
Scott: I mean, I knew the names of Sonic, Knuckles, Tails, Eggman.
Rym: I knew Amy, and then there's the Annoying Rabbit, and the little pet.
Scott: I didn't know the cream cheese name until they said it in the show.
Rym: Also weird that Dr.
Rym: Robotnik calls himself Eggman, I always thought that was the pejorative.
Scott: Oh, you don't know the truth about that, do you?
Rym: I always assumed that that was the pejorative that his enemies used.
Scott: Oh, so here's the truth about Robotnik Eggman.
Scott: for anyone who doesn't know, because I looked this up a while ago, because I was also confused.
Scott: So, in Japan, his name was always Eggman.
Scott: It was never Robotnik.
Scott: Never.
Scott: His name was just Dr.
Scott: Eggman, that's the name, right?
Scott: In America, somebody, without permission from the Japanese, just decided to go with this Dr.
Scott: Robotnik name in the instruction manual, or for whatever, you know, they just did it.
Scott: Right?
Scott: I guess during localization, or who knows?
Rym: Well, think about what happened with M. Bison.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, M. Bison had some reasons, but yeah, someone just fucking did it, and for the release of Sonic 1, they just did it, and the release to the rest of the world.
Scott: So, Japan didn't even realize this happened, right?
Scott: And they were like, fuck, right?
Scott: And basically what happened is, they had this divergence where the whole world was calling him Dr.
Scott: Robotnik, and in Japan, he was Dr.
Scott: Eggman, and that was it.
Scott: And the Japanese were upset, and they wanted to fix it.
Scott: So, I think what happened is, around the time of Sonic Adventure on the Dreamcast or something, right?
Scott: They basically came up with a way to where they were like, look, his real name is Dr.
Scott: Robotnik, but basically his nickname is Eggman, and everyone calls him Eggman, no one calls him anything else, right?
Scott: It's like, we're just only gonna say Eggman from now on, and there's only maybe one or two properties out there that actually have both names used.
Scott: And afterwards, every Sonic property after that point only says Eggman, even though it's canon that his real name is Robotnik, whatever.
Scott: No one says anything except Eggman, the end.
Scott: But it's the same character, it's not like a different character.
Rym: I did not expect Scott to drop the deep Sonic lore in this episode.
Scott: It was something that bothered me a long time ago, and I looked it up a long time ago, and I somehow remembered it.
Rym: So, the plot is roughly, it's actually like, it's just a serial plot until it gets into sort of a monster of the week after that, but even the monster of the week always drives the plot forward.
Rym: The plot is basically, Eggman has all the Chaos Emeralds, like it's done, he won.
Rym: He's about to use them.
Rym: Sonic attacks the machine, very much like what happens in the first episode of The New He-Man.
Rym: And all of them get transported to modern-day Earth, reverse Isekai, and on one hand, if I had to summarize this show, it is just cops eating shit over and over and over again.
Rym: The cops are in every episode.
Rym: They're the AD police of this universe.
Rym: Sonic shows up, and immediately, a bunch of American cops surround him with guns, and are extremely aggressive, and also are constantly eating donuts, and being failures, and just disastrously handling the situation.
Scott: I mean, there's an episode I watched where Sonic had to make an E.T.-style rescue from what's basically Area 51.
Rym: Oh yeah, Area 99.
Scott: A military installation, right?
Scott: And my favorite part of that episode was the cop part, because this is where I was able to notice the edits most starkly.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: There was a scene in which there are multiple military soldiers with MP5s, like, straight up.
Scott: MP5s, right?
Scott: It's like, they're just guns.
Scott: And when they start shooting them, the sound effects are like lasers, like pew pew pew.
Scott: And it's like, you just know, I haven't seen it, but I'm like 90% confident that if I get the original Japanese, that those guns are going to be going bang bang bang, like MP5 noises, right?
Scott: And you know, it's like, yep, there it is.
Scott: So Sonic appears, so there's- But that's how hardcore the show is, is you have military people with MP5s trying to blast Sonic with submachine guns.
Rym: The president gets involved.
Rym: later, the military gets fully involved, there's spies, the plot, you know what this actually kind of is?
Rym: Take a Spider-Man-like story with a superhero, and it's just superheroes and supervillains fighting in this city, and that's kind of what the show is.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I do somewhat appreciate that, you know, you don't have this, because it sort of has a combination, right?
Scott: You get deeply involved with some random rich kid, right, who doesn't even need to be there.
Rym: Sonic almost just leaves the kid.
Rym: Well, because you need the annoying insert kid, that's the Wesley Crusher of this show.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But it's like, they do keep that part, which I don't like, but the fact that yes, the government recognizes it, that's a rarity, like Bocorano has that.
Rym: I was about to say, Bocorano is like one of the few shows where the weird shit happens, the first thing the kids do is basically call 911, and then the military shows up.
Scott: Right, there's too many things out there, or stories out there, where something happens, and the government and the institutions of the world take no notice, and it's like, what?
Rym: But I love how an anthropomorphic magic hedgehog appears on a city street, and immediately what happens, a bunch of cops show up and try to kill him.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, it's somewhat real, you know, it's not fully realistic, but at least there's some element of reality and common sense to it, despite still being a children's cartoon.
Scott: But what I don't like, though, is the whole transport to Earth thing to begin with, right?
Scott: It's like, I always feel like, you know, they do that in kids shows, if it's not taking place in Earth, they feel like they had to bring it to Earth, you know, or have human characters.
Rym: You know, in season three, they go back with the kids and some humans to the other world.
Scott: Well, we're going to talk about that, and I did research on that.
Scott: You know, and the example I want to use here is Transformers, right?
Scott: It's like, Transformers is fine with all the characters being transforming robots on Cybertron, right?
Scott: With, you know, it's like, that's all we need, that's the good part, right?
Scott: It's like the Earth part, it's like, we don't need that shit, but the people who make kids shows feel like they need to bring it to Earth to make it relatable to humans and have human characters.
Scott: Though at the same time, it was- Yeah, fucking don't, you can have all anthropomorphic characters on an alien planet, you don't fucking need Earth or humans or anything, get that, you know, we don't need it.
Rym: Of course, that is a trope that happens in other Sonic properties too, and it is fun to see- My Little Pony did it too!
Rym: Yeah, but it is fun to just see, you got, you know, basically you've got this handful of Sonic characters, otherwise they're just like, they're fighting with cops in the street.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, that part is, you know, there are, I'm not saying no one should tell that sort of reverse isekai story, that it's an invalid story, but if I get the vibe that it was done because the marketing.
Scott: people feel like they need to make something relatable to kids who live on Earth, and that's the reason for it, then it gives me a bad taste.
Rym: But what I really appreciated is in episode 1, the cops fail, so then the cops call the super cops- The cops drive Formula 1 cars.
Rym: Yep, and they go into weirdly specific detail about these Formula 1 cars to make sure this is a competition of speed, as the worst cops go after Sonic, and of course, they get crushed, Sonic just destroys them, basically.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But as this progresses, Dr.
Rym: Robot- well, Eggman does just try to take over the world, because frankly, the Sonic characters are more powerful than any human, and even Robotniks like shitty robots are way more powerful than any tanks the military can bring to bear.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, it is a problem, I do think, though, with the Sonic characters, right, in that, you know, the female Sonic characters are more useless.
Rym: Well, now Amy busts out her hammer and fucks some shit up in later episodes.
Scott: Oh, okay, the Amy I saw tried to hammer something pointlessly.
Rym: Yeah, she's more useful.
Rym: The one who's actually useless is Knuckles.
Scott: Well, Knuckles is very useful, it's just, he's got this sort of, like, at least the acting in the US version we saw was kind of meh, I'm imagining the acting of Knuckles in the original was better.
Rym: Eggman tricks Knuckles into portraying Sonic, like, four episodes in.
Scott: Yeah, but he's just got this, like, he's just got this attitude for, like, no reason.
Rym: But that's Knuckles' whole character, in every property I've ever known.
Rym: Attitude for no reason.
Scott: Right, it's like if you want to be the troubled loner who goes your own way, right, it's like, you know, like Shadow the Ninja or whatever, that's cool, that character, that trope, that cliche, that's out there, we can have that if you want it.
Scott: But Knuckles just has no reason for it.
Scott: Or at least they don't present a reason for it.
Rym: Eggman shows up, he's like, "Knuckles, Sonic is bad, and you should work with me,".
Rym: and the Knuckles is like, "Actually, that makes sense,".
Rym: and then he immediately attacks Sonic.
Scott: Right, it's like Knuckles is like, "I gotta go my own way,".
Scott: it's like, "Alright, you gotta go your own way, okay, where are you going?
Scott: What are you
Scott: doing?".
Rym: You know where he's going?
Rym: He just, he walks off-scene, and then just sits there, as far as I can tell.
Scott: Yeah, he just walks out, and then he's lonely.
Scott: It's like, he just doesn't, you know, he's just like, the only reason he walked away is because he's too insecure to act.
Rym: Meanwhile, that other, the other character.
Scott: He doesn't actually have anything else he's doing, or another plan.
Rym: I guess Cream, like the bunny character, it seems like she just moves from tube to tube.
Rym: She is, anytime she appears, she's just trapped in one of a series of tubes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, Eggman eventually starts attacking, like just brings robots to the city, but that's where the toys come in, because the first thing he does is bust out a robot that he calls Missile Wrist via some special trading cards that I learned are actually something that was being sold.
Rym: There was like a cross-promotion, and Missile Wrist, the toy, just looks like a blow-rent Zaku, basically.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: And yeah, they destroy a bunch of buildings, the mayor comes out, almost dies, and the show just seems to do nothing but escalate.
Rym: Every episode is just an escalation.
Rym: 6 in, it was still escalating.
Scott: Yeah, so about the third season you mentioned, right?
Scott: So the research I did suggests that when the show was made, they made 52 episodes, which is a lot.
Scott: That's two full seasons, right?
Scott: And at the end of episode 52, I looked at the episode descriptions on Wikipedia, there is an ending to this show.
Scott: It ends.
Rym: Oh yeah, it's a terrible secretive space.
Scott: Yeah, there is an ending on episode 52, but Japan was like, "Alright, we're done with
Scott: that.".
Scott: The show was, I guess, popular enough outside of Japan that the US sent money and ordered another season.
Scott: So the third season was made by the same studio, it had Japanese voice acting and everything, right?
Scott: But much like Big O season 2, I guess.
Rym: I was about to bring up Big O as another example of that.
Rym: Big O was more popular here than it was in Japan.
Scott: Right, it's like they wouldn't have made it, but they got paid to make more.
Scott: So that third season is really sort of a new show.
Scott: They come up with a new plot to carry forth.
Scott: You can see a similar thing if you watch the original Macross television show, right?
Scott: It's like after a certain number of, like 26 episodes, there's some number of episodes, there's like an ending.
Scott: I guess I shouldn't spoil that, I don't know.
Scott: It's as old as me, it's a 40 year old show.
Scott: But there's an ending, and then they sort of continue the plot for another 13 episodes or so with the characters who are still alive after the ending.
Scott: And then a second, less ridiculous ending, right?
Scott: Because the first ending was like the real climactic ending, right?
Scott: So it's sort of like that, right?
Scott: It's like there was an ending, and then okay, we'll just have another season, but the other season's really a new show, kinda.
Scott: Just picks up where the previous one left off.
Rym: But yeah, I don't really need to watch any more of this.
Rym: I will never fully understand the extreme nature of the Sonic the Hedgehog fandom, because there aren't that many properties or that many cartoons.
Scott: I think if I had been born 5 to 10 years later...
Rym: Yeah, I can see that.
Rym: If this was on TV when I was like 7, I would have been a Sonic kid instead of a masked kid.
Scott: If this was on TV at the right time, I would have been watching it and enjoying it and been all over it.
Scott: And then I would have become... It's like instead of growing up with an NES and then 16-bit consoles...
Rym: Oh, you might have been a Sega kid!
Scott: Right, if you were a kid who was old enough for this show to be on TV when you were 8 or something like that, that means that you were having a dreamcast in the prime of your life.
Scott: So, when we were in college or whatever, some kid was at home with a dreamcast as their main console, playing Sonic Adventure as the way we played Mario World or whatever.
Scott: And it's like, that's why.
Scott: That kid's gonna be a big-time Sonic kid in Sonic X, while it might not hold up so much the same way that He-Man doesn't hold up so much.
Scott: It's like, I can see why kids who grew up with this were way into it, and I can see why anime nerds who may have seen the real version of this that wasn't edited, like the one we saw, might actually have some reason to appreciate the quality of the show.
Rym: Well, you know, case in point, I saw the real Sailor Moon when I was pretty young, and I got fan subs of the stuff that wasn't on American TV, and I got way into it because it was way different from what they showed in America.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: It's a show.
Scott: It exists.
Scott: I don't think anyone who isn't a child should watch it.
Rym: It is worth watching the first episode just to watch basically the AD police eat shit over and over and over again.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, there are just some funny things that you can see.
Scott: I think this is a good show to- Oh, yeah.
Rym: And he's like eating donuts the entire time while he's yelling constantly.
Rym: The cops are just a tour de force in this show.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's definitely a treasure trove for making memes and other things of that nature.
Scott: If you have some nostalgia for it, and you can get the original, not-U.S.
Scott: version of the show, you might gain some enjoyment from rewatching.
Rym: You'd be better off watching this than watching either of the Sonic cartoons that came before it.
Scott: Probably, yeah.
Scott: But I think Pokemon's a better show than this, right?
Scott: Either edition, you know?
Rym: Pokemon's still going.
Scott: It is still going.
Scott: But, yeah.
Scott: This is a Sonic cartoon.
Scott: It's out there, I guess.
Scott: It's good for it to exist and to be available, but I don't see much reason for most people to watch it in either form.
Scott: In its entirety.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Linki G, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Anbuncho, Peppaloo, Riley, Don't Want Me to Say Ternaves, Chris Dodd, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Fink, Shia85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMadBull34, Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin von Horrell, Stop All the Downloading, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Yorkdale, Yorkdale Station, and a bunch of people whose names I will not say.
Rym: I don't know what you expect the Stinger to be on an episode like this.
Rym: I had many options, but I'm simply tonight going to leave you with...
Scott: [MUSIC] [LAUGHTER] [MUSIC] [MUSIC].