Rym: It's Tuesday January 18th 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: It's my birthday, and we're gonna review inscription.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I Don't know how you're how you're still here with such a birthday.
Scott: Are you supposed to like go off into the whatever the carousel or something?
Rym: so because I turned 40 what is the end?
Rym: I was planning it.
Scott: I gotta make a phone call.
Rym: we got At least so what I'm happy about is that as I turn 40 I am now better at DDR than I've ever been in my entire life.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: that on your tombstone got somehow got better at DDR when 40.
Rym: yep like you know You know how I know this profound difference.
Rym: get this nowadays.
Rym: when I think of fourth mix what I think of is It does.
Rym: the arrows are really simplistic like I've got a most of fourth mix generalized at this point.
Rym: and What fourth mix think of thinks of?
Rym: as a hard song?
Rym: it's just arrows in weird places like.
Rym: they're easy to do.
Rym: They're just hard to read, but I remember when we were deep playing DDR.
Rym: We really didn't like six mix like six mix was like the weird one We didn't like and then we didn't like the music yeah, so uh Revisiting six mix.
Rym: now that I'm crazy good.
Rym: I think those are the best DDR songs there ever were.
Scott: in terms of the arrows matching the music I mean maybe but I just don't like the music itself.
Scott: yeah, but these About the.
Scott: I didn't give a shit about the arrows right.
Scott: it was just if you took the fourth mix music and put you know The current mix arrow technology on there.
Scott: You know I would like that.
Rym: I think you could remake really good arrows for some of those songs that are gonna out proper 9-footer.
Scott: I think it's mostly Actual songs themselves even if they even if DDR fourth mix had first mix arrows which were garbage awful unplayable Didn't even match the music right.
Scott: I would still prefer that because for me I cared about what song it was more than I cared about.
Rym: but a lot of those fourth mix songs have updated versions and later DDRs with way better arrows - that's that's nice.
Rym: That's a lot of them.
Rym: that eighth mix and ninth mix.
Rym: really have that going on.
Scott: I'm just really disappointed.
Scott: They don't you know for obvious technical licensing reasons They don't release DDR everything which has every single song.
Rym: I mean it's that exists.
Rym: It's called step mania plus, but it's not.
Rym: you went to DDR Spain once.
Scott: It's not perfect right.
Scott: it's not the real ever you know.
Scott: It's like I have every NES ROM ever.
Scott: But if Nintendo's you know thing was like you know they have like a few measly games on the switch online.
Scott: right if they were Like?
Scott: no, this is actually every NES ROM ever for real this time Even though I have that already.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: You know I'll go in for it.
Scott: You know an official DDR that had every song ever would be preferable to The other thing.
Rym: I noticed that and then we'll get on to the rest of the show is that of all the mixes fifth mix.
Rym: Honestly despite the fact that I really liked the music in fifth mix I think it has the worst arrows of any like DDR after a third mix when everything changed.
Scott: What I liked about fifth mix you know it had some good songs.
Scott: You know it had the long songs.
Rym: I really like that.
Scott: Yeah, some of those are okay.
Scott: the thing I liked about fifth mix actually the most was just like the.
Scott: the interface Wasn't the last one to have the characters also.
Rym: I think I mean I don't know cuz I haven't played everything on step mania for so long And I don't have the characters or anything.
Scott: so yeah, I think fifth mix was the last one that had like the characters.
Scott: it was just like.
Scott: You know the aesthetic of it the you the UI.
Scott: you know the yeah the the menu music.
Rym: You know I mean even my DDR.
Rym: I've got to the point to where I Change the arrows to be like the fourth mix style arrows just with better color because I don't like the arrow styles from later mixes either.
Rym: Never mind that 1.5 X. that just sucks like I play.
Rym: you got to play in 1x speed anyway.
Rym: They're having fun with that, but what I actually did for my birthday is Basically I beat Zelda 2 again for the heck of it cuz I just have it on the switch And I can beat that game pretty quick at this point.
Rym: I mostly remember where everything is and I still like that game.
Rym: It holds up, okay Okay Enjoy.
Scott: yeah
Rym: I mean this really enjoy it more than Zelda 1, but I think that's just partly Because Zelda 1 is a game where I have memorized everything and execution doesn't really become Difficult in Zelda 1 until you get to like the final dungeons when there's like seven blue nights in the room.
Scott: Zelda 1 is not an execution game.
Scott: It's a.
Rym: you know it's a burn every bush game.
Scott: Yeah, that's why I well Hopefully you've already burned every bush and that into your memory so you don't have to burn them again.
Rym: You know I was playing Zelda 1 the other day just a little bit And it was scary to me how.
Rym: if I think now like where are all the secrets I'd be hard-pressed to list them all.
Rym: But if I'm in the game, I see a screen and my brain is just like burn that bush right there.
Rym: Yeah, that's the one.
Scott: There's a couple screens that look similar that like have two bushes, and it's like you want to burn the bottom one But I think on the other screen.
Scott: It's like yeah, there isn't a secret on the bottom bush on one of them.
Rym: Yeah, that really burns you.
Rym: in second quest though where every secret you think you remember is just a door charge.
Scott: Well second quest not only that but it also gets you because there's a lot of flute screens Or you flute and a secret appears instead of a tornado, and there's a lot of screen.
Scott: There's a lot of walk through the the the wall where it's you just walk And it this is.
Rym: I only learned about that from I want to say Nintendo Power.
Scott: Oh, I knew about the one.
Scott: well There was the one in the top right.
Scott: in The first quest you get the big money right and then in the second quest I Discovered one of those because I looked at the map.
Scott: you know the map you collect in the game Yeah, and I could see that there was obviously like some eyeballers You know on a map or something.
Scott: it was something like that you like try bombing and like you try all four entrances There's nothing was a corner or an eyeball or some part of a map that clearly had a secret room And I couldn't get into it and with bombing from every direction right.
Scott: so I Tried to walk through and sure enough it worked.
Scott: Just the same way.
Scott: the top right of the map worked, and then I said well.
Scott: I guess I have to walk into every Suspicious wall in every dungeon now.
Rym: So uh in the news there is basically one gigantic news.
Scott: Thank you news gods for bringing the biggest most giantest amazing news on a Tuesday So I don't gotta do any work.
Scott: so Activision Blizzard, which is already a ridiculous amalgam of Activision and Blizzard which yeah It shouldn't really exist in its current form as is But it does and it's been in the shit for a while.
Scott: Yeah, like they're like the reasons that we have discussed.
Rym: yep, but to give a really high-level summary Blizzard like Activision I like as an entity.
Rym: before it acquired Blizzard I Rarely liked their game, so I'm not gonna dwell on that.
Scott: but well I mean Activision went through a lot of stages.
Rym: are we going to go back to a pitfall?
Rym: pitfall to a Triumph of game design?
Scott: right and then that you had that and then you had the Activision that made mech warrior 2.
Scott: Yeah, there was that Activision.
Rym: But no the Activision of recent times is not the kind of gaming that Scott and I are particularly fans of ourselves.
Rym: So it was pretty much the Call of Duty company right yeah, or as my brain Just always thinks whenever I hear about Call of Duty.
Scott: Oh that Counter-Strike knockoff I Don't think it's anything like Counter-Strike.
Rym: It's not it's just.
Rym: it's the kind of FPS that I don't enjoy.
Scott: It's just a military FPS.
Scott: That's real popular.
Rym: Yep I I'm much more into either the like ridiculous quaky style FPS is or the like quote Hyper-realistic FPS is.
Rym: but I'm making quote marks here because neither Counter-Strike nor PUBG are particularly realistic.
Rym: It's just it's realism as game design and like a set aesthetic, but anyway Blizzard Have for a while Was doing very well in terms of having good game design and doing the right things in games.
Scott: But I think much like valve Blizzard, you know from its onset with the Warcraft 1 right.
Scott: you know Starcraft Yeah, it was a company that made PC games of high quality.
Scott: You know they made them slowly and carefully.
Rym: I trusted their game design.
Rym: like the game designers They had would say very interesting good things and make very good designs, right?
Scott: They weren't just cranking games out for money like other companies.
Scott: You know historically they had like these really top tier PC and even crossover PC Mac titles.
Scott: They didn't do a lot of console stuff.
Scott: There were a few console ports that were just kind of meh You know but yeah But they were huge worldwide these mega hit games.
Scott: Starcraft was the greatest biggest deal in RTS is ever you know You know World of Warcraft was the biggest MMO right?
Scott: It's like they were just the champs of these.
Scott: you know these games Yeah, basically they invented categories of games and other categories of games were invented as mods to gay.
Rym: Hey, it's like yeah, you know look at Boba's started off as Warcraft 3 mods Because I play it a lot I think about it a lot, but look at what they did with overwatch.
Rym: It basically said hey what Team Fortress 2 tried to be.
Rym: here's what that looks like if you Seriously polish it and for real dive into it.
Scott: Yeah, their games had a lot of polish.
Scott: so but yeah They combined with Activision and things started to.
Scott: you know go downhill right slowly.
Scott: Sure, you know carefully right it didn't just jump off a cliff, but I think I bit like game designers I knew of who worked in Blizzard.
Rym: We're just quitting like one by one very publicly and then like more behind the scenes.
Rym: there was a slow but steady increase in artists and Developers and other people quitting Blizzard.
Rym: all that I think it was people quitting.
Scott: there was the big layoffs They had.
Scott: there were a lot of disorganize.
Scott: you can see a lot of dysfunction right sort of like when you see a sports team Like doing really poorly.
Scott: yeah It's usually because this organizational dysfunction, and you could tell they weren't delivering games.
Scott: things are getting delayed Canceled right you know It's just.
Scott: you know.
Scott: they had like all kinds of messes in various categories.
Scott: They made their you know their MOBA.
Scott: What was it?
Scott: What's that thing called?
Rym: Oh god?
Rym: Oh and here's of the storm?
Scott: Yeah, right so that thing didn't do very well.
Scott: You know it's basically before heroes of the storm.
Scott: It's like did Blizzard ever have a stinker really now.
Scott: I'm not saying that's like a complete stinker Yeah, but it's like every single game.
Rym: They fucking ever put out was like S tier Even if it wasn't a game that we personally would play or like.
Rym: you can appreciate the level of polish and design.
Scott: Right it's like I wasn't.
Scott: I'm not great at RTS's I never.
Scott: I didn't play World of Warcraft.
Scott: I respect what Starcraft did, but it's like right.
Scott: But it's like every game They put out was S tier and like in Heroes of the Storm was not an S tier game right.
Rym: so It's like they stay were going downhill and that independent of that There was all the.
Rym: we've talked about this at length as has most of the industry because they are a triple-a game studio.
Rym: There is endemic widespread sexism sexual assault HR Shenanigans all sorts of crap.
Scott: I'm sure I have no evidence But I feel pretty confident and would not be surprised if similar things were exposed about other large game companies Which they have been.
Rym: Riot was the one getting most of the attention for that until the Blizzard Stories overshadowed it in public conversation for a hot minute.
Scott: Well, I think the evidence of the Blizzard ones and the tawdryness were oh, you know, well the Blizzard ones.
Rym: I think what they surprised everyone is that it it turned out that all the worst offenders in Blizzard were not Activision people who came in as part of the acquisition.
Rym: It was original Blizzard people.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, you know old PC gaming which from a triple-a game industry like that's just that you assume that's happening At any major studio, but I got to assume that's happening, you know Ubisoft.
Rym: Oh, yeah I mean Ubisoft had significant recent scandals of similar scale.
Scott: So right, but right.
Rym: but Blizzard got hit I think the hardest partly because Blizzard wouldn't fire Kotick like that's like a weird sticking point.
Scott: They are.
Scott: they have recently just in the past few, you know weeks months whatever they fight.
Scott: I think it said they fired 30 some odd people and then like reprimanded many more people.
Rym: There's already rumblings that Microsoft is Diving into that as part of the site, right?
Scott: Well, I think this was it was this was probably like leading up to that, right?
Scott: so, you know they were Basically going through their huge pile of unaddressed HR issues and addressing them to you know, too late But better late than never but also too little too late whichever one you want to choose but time.
Scott: So it's been obvious that a company that was so has so valuable and had such valuable IPs And was such a big deal That had hit a hard times.
Scott: Yeah was gonna get acquired.
Rym: that seemed well, especially because look what happened.
Rym: They lost so many of their best-known designers and the people who are Responsible for making these games this polished that they turned into effectively.
Rym: They weren't a husk yet, but the trajectory was to potentially become a husk that owns a lot of extremely popular IP But couldn't execute on that IP.
Scott: Yeah, they stopped being able to execute.
Scott: You know, I think after the the accurate the Activision combo I think really hurt their ex.
Rym: Oh even little stuff like when the changes happen in overwatch You could see because I play that game a lot.
Rym: I'm very.
Scott: I mean I saw what was going on with Hearthstone.
Rym: But overwatch you started to see that there used to be like when a patch came out The game balance was altered in like very interesting ways and like there was a lot of care Numerous patches started coming out that made minor updates to characters that radically rebalance the game in Unanticipated and annoying ways like over just recently like that little bit of polish fell away.
Scott: Well, that's that's a whole we could talk about, you know Troubles of maintaining a lifestyle game.
Rym: that could be a Tuesday I could be a not only an episode but that's a panel lifestyle.
Rym: Well, but not that.
Scott: but the thing is, you know We've never had to be never been in the spot of doing it.
Rym: So we only can talk about no, but I've been in the spot of being someone who plays a lifestyle game.
Scott: Yeah, me too several times Anyway, so what else is going on by Microsoft?
Rym: So what what's notable about this one?
Rym: Antitrust needs to be tearing the games industry apart, but we could say that about literally every industry.
Scott: So right this is this should be under normal antitrust circumstances not allowed.
Scott: But Activision blisters shouldn't have been allowed in the first place, but much worse things have been allowed recently.
Scott: Yeah, right, you know it's worse.
Rym: you know nerds defend this stuff.
Rym: nerds love to talk about how they love that.
Rym: Disney owns all the IP because they got all the Crossovers they want and they're getting what they wanted, but that is obviously a disaster For literally everyone.
Scott: but the fanboy who's excited about the MCU, it's just not it's not good You know, we're talking only now about the it, you know, the artistic industries the creative industries.
Scott: It's bad for you know culture and bad for art to have a few, you know Mega corpse right being the ones who decide, you know, what gets made.
Scott: I go is what and I mean obviously other things get made but they're choosing what gets made with a high budget.
Rym: Well, it's real simple.
Rym: your release the Tuesday episode of GeekNights.
Rym: You're all familiar with shadowrun the mega corpse of the bad guys, right?
Rym: Every mega Corp is bad without exception.
Rym: There's no good ones.
Rym: That is literally the reality of earth.
Scott: Yes, it is.
Rym: The only possible exception is a cooperative government nationalization.
Scott: Yeah, you know you got a lip if you're in a cyberpunk place.
Scott: He got his live in the weird no Corp area, right?
Scott: Yep, you know st.
Scott: Star Wars.
Scott: Oh, we're on the cloud city.
Scott: We were gonna avoid Imperial complications.
Rym: Instead you just have Lando complications obviously.
Rym: So what else is going on here?
Rym: So Wall Street people were once again surprised by this.
Rym: I am.
Rym: it is amazing to me how Generally Wall Street people will always come to me like clockwork.
Rym: Do you know how many people were messaging me today people?
Rym: I haven't talked to in like five or more years like oh, what's going on with Activision?
Rym: seventy billion dollars WTF?
Rym: What don't I know?
Rym: and it's just like did you ever listen to a word?
Scott: I've said at any point It's like I didn't see it coming.
Scott: But in retrospect I should have seen this.
Rym: I didn't see it coming today.
Rym: I literally I was what I woke up.
Rym: cuz I you know I wake up at 5 a.m.
Rym: To see if I can ski and I can't ski.
Rym: and then Emily's like happy birthday.
Rym: also Blizzard just got bought by Microsoft.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much those.
Rym: because full disclosure I own a lot of Activision stock that I bought when I Toward the end of that giant dip when I thought that it looked like they were firing P bad people one by one And I felt like the company would have been strong enough to come through and turn this ship around and at least become like less bad than the median in the game industry.
Rym: But instead they got bought and discussed.
Rym: the stock skyrocketed.
Rym: so full disclosure I own a bunch of Blizzard stock that just went up a lot because it's gonna turn into Microsoft.
Rym: Basically.
Scott: Yeah, basically, so Assuming assuming this passes, you know, this still has to pass the regular.
Rym: there is zero chance in my personal Non-professional opinion.
Rym: I just blocked or even looked at I think 1% chance.
Scott: It gets looked at and the only reason it
Rym: could possibly get looked at would be that Progressives in America have historically gone after the video game industry for the wrong reasons and it's an easy target for them, especially older Democrats, but to a bunch of people might give this a second look only because People who don't pay attention to games are shocked by the big numbers that come out of games.
Rym: Do you how many people literally did not believe me when I told them how much as modé sold for and who bought them and why?
Rym: They literally.
Rym: the response from professionals on Wall Street was what do you mean billion?
Scott: I Don't I don't for Just.
Scott: I don't think it's looked at because of the game part.
Scott: I think it gets looked at because the Microsoft part.
Rym: Ah, no, because this is a drop in the bucket for Microsoft even with the big number.
Scott: Anyway, so what is this right now?
Scott: Let's talk about why are the nerds excited when there's a mega?
Scott: well
Rym: Microsoft in this case Has been honestly a much better corporate citizen than other similar mega curves not saying they should exist but they have been a better corporate citizen partly because They constantly get attacked with antitrust stuff from non US sources to the point that they are always playing defense there.
Scott: Well, not just antitrust, but let's talk about what you know, the things that are actually gonna matter to you know, a gamer, right?
Scott: So what's gonna happen long term here?
Scott: Well first I think I've even seen news that already confirms that the games are gonna come to game pass Right, so you can buy the Xbox game pass and get all the fucking Activision Blizzard games and or whatever ones they put in Right, but also I could what I could see happening that again.
Scott: This is you know, we just said why do nerds, you know love the mega corp when the mega corp is the bad guy, right?
Scott: You know what Microsoft is probably gonna do all that shit that Blizzard refused to do all those years right give us You know, they're like, oh, we don't want to just make Warcraft for Microsoft's gonna be like what the fuck's wrong with you.
Scott: Just make fucking Warcraft for right.
Scott: It's gonna make us a fortune.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: Right World of Warcraft to do it Starcraft 3 just do it.
Scott: Don't be doing making this new garbage, right?
Scott: Just go all in on the obvious winners.
Scott: We bought you cuz we want money right and the nerds are gonna love it.
Scott: It's gonna work.
Scott: So I think and you know the get rid of stupid battle net they'll incorporate it with all the Xbox shit instead.
Scott: You know, you'll you'll use Microsoft store to buy those games or something, you know.
Scott: That's how it's gonna be.
Scott: Yeah, you get all the games.
Scott: look the work on the Xbox properly, right?
Scott: But yeah, think of it Microsoft owns fucking minecraft.
Scott: You're gonna get Wow minecraft shit going on, right?
Scott: Yeah, Microsoft owns old scrolls.
Scott: You don't think you're gonna get an old scroll
Rym: also
Scott: with a Wow theme common
Rym: absolutely not naming any names for a lot of reasons because these aren't like super big people but a few of the people I know who were at Blizzard went to Microsoft over the last couple of years.
Rym: like I suspect Microsoft actually has a Material number of ex Blizzard developers and designers on staff.
Scott: Yeah I mean that's all.
Scott: it's always a tough call with that one because it is a pattern that you see but I could be a Perceived company and then the better these company ends up buying their old company, right?
Scott: Well, well, the point is let's say you have a big company and a pile of people leave, right?
Scott: Well, those people are likely to go to other big companies in adjacent industries.
Scott: so even if Google bought Blizzard or I don't know Facebook bottom or You know literally no matter who bought them you could say that same thing.
Scott: you'd like Oh, I know Blizzard people who left and went to that.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I guess the difference is.
Rym: the Minor nuance to that is that these are people who are primarily game designers or game developers, not just general like engineering.
Scott: I'm sure game designers and game developers who left Blizzard in recent times have gone to a variety of companies that all could have been purchasers.
Scott: Right, you know, it's it's a so it's a you have to like.
Scott: actually, you know Get the records and see how many left because that is what I see that same pattern happening in small Businesses where there's no question about it, right?
Scott: It's like people left that company in a very small industry.
Scott: a lot of them went to that other company in the very small industry and then that Company acquired the company the people.
Rym: sometimes what happens is not quite corporate espionage But like say you run a company that does something and you get a few people who worked at a competitor to join you.
Rym: You'll learn a lot about your competitor as a result and sometimes what you learn is Oh, they're not doing well.
Rym: or yeah, guess what?
Rym: My awesome project got canceled.
Rym: I'd really like to do that project.
Rym: I'd like to do it.
Scott: It wasn't an intentional espionage.
Scott: It's that your industry is so small that it's like, you know, it's like.
Scott: okay the game industry isn't small But if you're a big biz Blizzard employee making a lot of money, there's only so many companies that can pay you that much money.
Scott: Yeah, you can't go.
Scott: unless you want to go and lose a bunch of money and work for a small place.
Scott: You're you're gonna work.
Rym: Yeah, you think I'm gonna go do fixed protocol work for a smaller company than where I work now, right?
Scott: It's you know that in the tech industry.
Scott: Does it?
Scott: they call it fang?
Scott: It's Facebook Amazon Apple Netflix, Google.
Scott: Yeah, it's like once you work for one of those, you know, you're probably gonna be working for one of those.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of my co-workers who have left my current company ended up at Facebook and a subset of them are currently at Microsoft.
Scott: I guess now it's called man But so I guess you could.
Scott: if you add Microsoft it would be mamang.
Rym: But I think what's gonna happen is we're gonna see a little more Wall Street attention toward gaming as an industry because there have been a number of big acquisitions like this recently where the dollar sides are big enough to where I suspect there is significant unethical untapped monetization and gaming that a lot of investors are going to be rabid for and I feel like I don't think this happened with Microsoft, but I think they're gonna see Similar acquisitions by companies that are going to go headfirst into NFTs as hard as possible.
Rym: I'm actually you know in terms of Actually take a much more healthy approach to this intellectual property, right?
Scott: If you know we've seen you know, Blizzard has been a little bit, you know less with the microtransactions.
Scott: then say, you know An Ubisoft right or an EA with it's basically Ubisoft I think is the worst company that you've all heard of in terms of making that kind of game You know and then you know.
Scott: and then after the after the really bad EA and the you know The Ubisoft's then you've got like epic which is sort of in this middle area and it's like, you know It's a little eh, but you know fortnight doesn't have any pay to win.
Scott: It's all cosmetic, right?
Scott: It's you know.
Rym: You know, I'm gonna save it but I've been playing a lot of fortnight lately And if any of you want to play with me once again Scott refuses to play any FPS is I would play fortnight.
Scott: I just don't want to install the epic store.
Scott: if fortnight was on steam.
Scott: I'd play it right now.
Scott: So the but then you basically if you go up a level again Right.
Scott: We're in the situation where like our only the only big companies I can think of that are making the triple-a games That are like still kosher is basically Microsoft and Nintendo.
Rym: Yep, right Because Sony is a too complex to talk about as a single entity.
Scott: Yeah, Sony and then you also got square over there there while Square Enix is going hard and NFTs, you know They're there, you know, they got other problems too.
Scott: But yeah, so It's pretty much Nintendo and Microsoft is like that.
Scott: Those are the the safe havens I guess of triple-a gaming right now, but if like any, you know, I think Nintendo is unassailable, but You know Microsoft isn't.
Scott: Microsoft could easily go down the You know micro transaction pay-to-win NFT hole.
Rym: I feel like Microsoft has a better play in the long run by continuing to make quality games and not over monetizing gaming but using that to grow the broader Microsoft ecosystem as a whole and Continue to cement windows as being literally the only operating system that did that exists.
Rym: if you're a gamer All right, so I'm looking forward to World of Halo and You're not looking forward to overwatch actually getting attention again from game designers?
Scott: If right, it's like.
Scott: on the one hand, right?
Scott: I talked about all these possibilities of like all the great things they could do.
Scott: I expect also chop chop.
Scott: right.
Scott: when you buy someone you always you always chop chop.
Scott: I'm not saying overwatch is getting the chop chop by saying something's getting the chop, right?
Rym: So considering overwatch has the nearly ready to launch overwatch - that is going after a deeply untapped segment of that market?
Rym: I feel like that is the least likely thing to get.
Scott: yeah, I'm not saying that's gonna get chopped.
Rym: I'm saying I'm not.
Rym: this is not Rym.
Rym: Hopefully wishing that overwatch gets investment.
Rym: This is Cynical Rym.
Rym: honestly believing that Microsoft sees overwatch specifically as a big part of their strategy.
Rym: Maybe It's got a. it's got a weirdly credible in sports presence like it does that Significant challenges.
Rym: it is it is far from the most significant part of the not the most significant it is But it is a key part as in in my me.
Scott: It's might not even be top five, right?
Rym: Five now.
Scott: Warcraft Call of Duty Wow Starcraft Diablo are the top five right.
Scott: overwatch is sixth at best.
Rym: It depends on what you're going after because those all go after terms of the value of the IP and the.
Scott: you know The size of the player base, right?
Scott: How much money you'll make from a game in that series?
Rym: What I'm saying is those all have an easy to project relatively steady Revenue stream.
Rym: it's easy to grow.
Rym: There's nothing new there.
Rym: It's hard to take those properties and go after a new Demographic Diablo.
Scott: could if you do Demographic with them because now you own so many IPS you can just cross them all over.
Rym: No, but here here's the thing.
Rym: What overwatch was doing with overwatch - I talked about this briefly years ago on GeekNights is specifically open up a demographic of the people who like FPS is For literally the opposite of the reasons you and I like them and that is a way bigger market than competitive FPS.
Scott: That's why for you know, it's you know, you know, it's a bit.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: You know makes that market look like nothing.
Scott: World of Minecraft.
Scott: Yeah But World of Minecraft is not World of Minecraft with halo skins.
Rym: Okay, that makes more money over but it doesn't get that demographic that demographic right now.
Scott: Basically, if you have world if you make World of Minecraft with halo skins, do you really need overwatch right?
Rym: now because one thing Microsoft historically has done which is similar to what Blizzard has done is Even if there are two or three areas that have the most revenue They will keep business units alive and invest in them if they are profitable.
Scott: Yeah, Microsoft has definitely not, you know been the biggest chopper, but something's gonna go.
Scott: Yeah, they're not So I will see the storm.
Scott: Yeah It.
Rym: So I had one brief little news before we get to the main bit.
Scott: just because it's it is is so big you need Nothing news.
Rym: It's just really funny because we brought up NFTs.
Rym: So Shonen jump Announced today.
Rym: quote soon.
Rym: You'll be able to show your show to jump love in a whole new way.
Rym: Exciting announcement tomorrow the most generic possible press release ever from any company.
Scott: Hey, it's not even a press release.
Scott: It's a release that is gonna be a release.
Rym: There is a press release that goes with it.
Rym: I have personally in my life issued press releases for real Where the sole announcement was.
Rym: there will be a future press release about X topic.
Rym: Okay, I have done that myself.
Scott: I guess marketing people just need you know to justify their jobs.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I was the marketing person in that company at the time as well as everything else.
Rym: So a pretty simple announcement right.
Rym: do nothing to even like like.
Rym: if you're trying to if you're trying to grab on to this tweet To like criticize or do anything you'd feel like it's just a slippery wall.
Rym: Yet Dateline right now.
Rym: There are 175 replies and 173 of them are People all saying this better not be fucking NFTs.
Rym: I will start pirating.
Rym: Shonen jumps so fast.
Scott: They tweeted that it's not NFTs.
Rym: Yes I Say this because we've been talking about this a lot on other nights of GeekNights where NFTs are just this toxic cancer That is invading every space and they are making inroads into gaming.
Rym: I just want to point out that sharp immediate and widespread anger in social media It doesn't necessarily stop companies from doing it But it forces them to take a stand and it forces them to reveal if you have any power over that over them or not.
Rym: Kickstarter basically said you have no power over us.
Rym: Fuck you discord said whoa, whoa, whoa.
Rym: back that up.
Rym: We're so sorry.
Rym: So Sharp immediate angry pressure has an impact do it every time.
Rym: when it comes to NFTs yeah, it's.
Scott: it's actually surprising to see, you know, I have not seen a lot of Positive responses on any NFT announcements.
Scott: their majority are like get the shit out of you But to the fact.
Rym: yet They got a big on a native NFT reaction when they didn't even say NFTs.
Rym: it forced them to go further and say oh shit It's not NFTs.
Rym: We're sorry.
Scott: You thought that Right, but you know, it's companies are still trying it and they're.
Scott: you know, there was just some Castlevania NFTs.
Scott: They made I guess a few hundred K off of it, right?
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: that seems like a lot of money But there's a lot of money.
Rym: the news I was gonna use that I'm gonna say for the next Tuesday show is about a bunch Of.
Rym: they've a bunch of reporters followed several gaming NFTs to see like who owns them where they ended up What happened to them and it's really enlightening and really funny and really sad.
Rym: but anyway things of the.
Rym: So check this out real simple.
Rym: There's a big discourse on Twitter for about 20 minutes a couple days ago Where someone pointed out that?
Rym: When Sesame Street in particular got more commercialized.
Rym: because you know, it's not just PBS anymore, you know the whole HBO thing.
Rym: Yeah, the show has actually continued to be like very progressive and like good like it's still doing its Sesame Street job to a big Like.
Rym: a lot of the fears that's good didn't come to pass.
Rym: still a fantastic show in fact.
Rym: it's gotten more aggressive on social justice causes and so and on social media, but One thing that has largely disappeared from Sesame Street are the long Atmospheric aspects of it that were a big part of the early show Like the segments that didn't really do anything in particular That honestly were a big part of what I liked about Sesame Street as a little kid.
Rym: so because of that conversation I thought back and I remembered there are exactly three Sesame Street skits that stood out in my like childhood as being formative to me that are just Constantly referenced by my brain to this day.
Rym: One of them is one two, three, four, five six seven eight nine ten eleven.
Rym: Another one is the count of course like but anyway But the one that was the most burned into my brain If I had to describe it, it's the one where a kid plays a trumpet and then a motorcycle leaves.
Rym: And I just found it on YouTube.
Rym: I'm gonna link to it as my thing of the day.
Rym: I think this Sesame Street segment more so than anything else I ever saw in that show in my entire childhood Shaped my brain in some way because I think about it all the time To this day.
Rym: and when this discourse came up my brain immediately said Oh like the trumpet one with the motorcycle and I googled for it.
Rym: I found it.
Rym: Apparently it was titled household sounds - Yeah So what you got?
Scott: Oh So apparently I found this video and it shows some kind of business in Japan.
Scott: I guess it looks like a garage of some sort And there was a big snow and this.
Scott: so there's like a few feet of snow on the roof of the Garage right and has a big metal slanted roof.
Scott: so the dude is like poking the roof for the long stick like banging on it and Eventually all the snow just slumps off.
Scott: this whole roof comes on all at once which is what you'd expect to happen But it's really fun and satisfying to see it happen.
Rym: So I love this video play and the next video was a very similar video on the same channel.
Scott: I was about to mention that so I Remember when I had a car.
Scott: the worst.
Scott: one of the worst things about having a car is having to scrape it when it snows.
Scott: I'm glad I never have to do that again.
Scott: But there was that one tiny bit of it where it was satisfying to have a sheet of ice just come off the windshield, right?
Scott: So here you can get all the satisfying parts of someone else knocking snow off a roof without having to go out in the cold or do any hard work, so I Realized thanks to YouTube recommendations that Rym also noticed.
Scott: There's apparently a trend of this Genre of video of the roof has too much snow on it and it comes off all at once in a big satisfying clump.
Rym: there is a genre like that and a trend of literally any action and For some reason most of these videos are from Japan.
Scott: So I think it must have something to do with the roofs there.
Rym: so Scott Here's how we make enough money to do GeekNights full-time.
Rym: We make a vtuber some cute anime girl.
Rym: Emily rigs it up for us and all we do is Watch videos and make videos of this with a cute anime girl.
Rym: love vtuber Reacting to them.
Scott: you can have a hard time finding enough roofs with that or this kind of roof that's slanted and can you can bang on it and There's enough snow.
Rym: so you know we do.
Rym: we hire climate.
Rym: we hire four people.
Rym: pay him up.
Rym: Hey, I'm something like pay him enough.
Rym: go around Filming these kinds of things causing these situations, and it's not.
Scott: you can't use the same roof twice.
Scott: You got to keep finding a new room.
Rym: We also if we have to we start cheating we start Setting up these situations.
Rym: change the colors use some Photoshop.
Scott: Does that doesn't seem profitable?
Scott: with how much it cost to run a snow machine to make that much?
Scott: And it has to be the right kind of snow Also artificial.
Rym: you only upload a video once we come off the roof.
Scott: No.
Rym: It's a real good video.
Rym: I like how the snow doesn't actually fall to the very very end of the video.
Scott:  yes Yeah, if you want to just get to the egg.
Rym: no no no no you need that foreplay.
Rym: You've got to watch them cuz they're.
Rym: I love the guys doing it cuz they're very clearly like they know how it's gonna go down.
Rym: They're obviously a little excited about it, but they're also really afraid they're gonna mess it up, and it's gonna fall on them.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's also you know while there are many videos in this genre.
Scott: This is the best one.
Rym: I thought this one's great whites.
Rym: I saw one from a ski resort.
Rym: I'll try to find it later and post it in the forum.
Rym: It is way more than this.
Rym: Like I think it would have killed people if it actually fell on them.
Scott: I mean this would have probably seriously.
Rym: I think you I think you would have easily broken it gotten a fracture from this hitting you.
Rym: Quite possibly yes, so in the meta moment the geeks not a book club book Which Scott is done with and I am steam rolling through to the end We're doing a show on this first week of February or second week whenever that Thursday falls at least one.
Scott: You know what I got.
Scott: it possibly know what I gotta say.
Scott: No, I gotta say I started reading the next book club.
Scott: Oh, I read.
Scott: I read two chapters in one sitting out this like lightning speed.
Scott: It was like you know how they talk about like how in baseball when you swing the heavy bag Doesn't really make it.
Scott: it doesn't actually help you.
Scott: right.
Scott: this might not actually help me read faster but after swinging the heavy Genji bat Reading a modern book from modern times of this century in English that was originally written in English.
Scott: It's like it feels like the bat is like a feather like I feel like I'm reading Faster that I've ever read in my entire life and the Kindle says oh, you'll finish the whole book in eight hours And I'm like holy shit.
Scott: That's like tomorrow This book is gonna be done in two seconds like it took me two years to read one book and like a week to read.
Scott: So I'm looking forward to reading many books now.
Rym: Yeah, I got a pile of nonfiction books piled up even at this point.
Scott: finish up that Genji so we can milk a few episodes.
Rym: I think we can get two episodes out of it easily.
Rym: We have to.
Scott: we have to do a Thursday episode this week.
Scott: Can you finish it tomorrow?
Scott: I Guess the bats still too heavy.
Rym: yeah, I'll definitely whatever the first Thursday is in February.
Rym: I'll do 100% be ready for that.
Rym: So otherwise no cons for a while.
Rym: PAX East has been announced.
Rym: looks like they just opened panel submissions.
Rym: very likely If I go to PAX East at all I'm just gonna go into a panel or two and then leave.
Rym: so Same deal is unplugged.
Scott: I think yeah, you know I'm not gonna just make any decision about PAX East until very close to the.
Scott: you know the time.
Rym: Well, I guess we know for a fact it's gonna require masks.
Rym: I can see no universe or that changes and I just don't feel like.
Scott: I mean, I don't really see myself You know, I gotta get to Boston and I gotta get a hotel and I you know, it's like yeah I would probably just know what the deadline is for enforcer or panel.
Rym: about veteran roll call was a while ago I mean, but I could still get.
Rym: oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I think any veteran could trivially enforce these.
Scott: yeah They're gonna be so desperate to get anyone to be like, yes, please come on.
Rym: But I imagine because the most fun I have at PAX East like I love like PAX is a great But it's playing board games with my friends and it's also like the long leisurely like dinner before we all go in force at LTK.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think yeah and without all my it's like even if I'm willing to go to the convention or whatever I put up with the hassle and if not enough of my people do the same thing.
Scott: Then it's like what am I doing there, right?
Scott: It'd be like when me and Rym used to go to anime Boston with no one else I was like, but at least in anime Boston there was no COVID.
Rym: So what did we do?
Rym: we could go hang out in Boston like go to a restaurant and like hang out there long enough to?
Rym: eat dessert.
Scott: Yeah, we did, you know, but you know nowadays Yeah, it'd be really weird if we had just the two of us went to a convention with no one else for a whole weekend Plus and we didn't have enough stuff to do with the convention.
Rym: I got a taste of it weren't staff at the convention?
Rym: the other thing I that is just a. this is a logistical problem that I thought about but I Experienced it when I went to PAX Unplugged for a few hours.
Rym: I did like walk around tabletop talk to people in there and what I noticed is that in an expo hall like space it is Extremely difficult to understand what people are saying through their masks because of the background.
Scott: roar Yeah, could be and I imagine maybe you should go check that you maybe should go to the ear doctor though.
Rym: Also, just now cuz no one can understand me there's like I'd like half my conversations were what what what until we got out of tabletop.
Scott: I mean, that's it.
Scott: That's a problem with tabletop conventions in general, especially for oh, yeah Even without masks like pre COVID times.
Rym: It is hard to understand people in that hall.
Scott: What I'm saying is I think that's why historically the RPG cons have been you know, mostly the smaller.
Scott: Right, it's very few big ones because it becomes very hard.
Rym: Incon was already reaching the upper limit and even then we had to cram like four games into a room and it was too much.
Rym: It was too loud.
Scott: Yep maybe we could make some sort of system though where Everyone's got a phone and everyone's got noise cancelling headphones and you put them on but you have a group chat.
Scott: Just but you know you I guess you could just open up discord on your phone.
Rym: You just do that with crisp.
Rym: I feel like you want to make an app that like makes it just work and you sell the app for a dollar.
Scott: We should just try it with discord.
Scott: one time.
Scott: just everyone put on a noise cancelling headphone in the same room With I guess the discord open but you have to use the microphone that's in your headphones that you don't pick up everyone else's.
Rym: None of my headphones have microphones.
Scott: Mind anyway, you get the idea there.
Scott: There could be something there.
Scott: I think the hardest part is if you talk and someone else's microphone picks up your voice.
Scott: Yeah, that's the biggest danger We should test cuz they're all sitting around a table all wearing mics and headsets.
Scott: now you want to hear.
Rym: you want to go not so mode.
Rym: I could It would so theoretically I could bring this audio device which I can power with from like.
Rym: I don't need to plug it in necessarily and I can rig us up.
Rym: I'd have.
Rym: I bought some more.
Rym: I am so we could have a local device.
Rym: that did it perfectly.
Scott: You got to make sure all the mics are super direction.
Rym: Oh, yeah, the thing is it would be it would take me about a half hour to set up meaning we just sit around.
Scott: That's not tenable.
Scott: No, that's not ten.
Rym: That's the kind of thing we would sit at a table for like all day at effects.
Scott: All right, so this game came out called Inscription with a Y in the middle and it looked like it was sort of a slay the spire Kind of game right where it's a little bit of roguelike situation, right where you explore a map And along the way you build your deck at various spots.
Scott: you stop on the map and then you have Encounters with enemies and you have to battle them using the deck that you've built.
Scott: you add cards to it along the way you remove Cards you upgrade cards modify cards, right and it was getting some really good reviews.
Scott: and also the aesthetic of it from the screenshots I saw was sort of It's not five nights at Freddy's but it's sort of.
Rym: it feels like.
Rym: it feels like every horror VR game that's out right now.
Scott: It's sort of it's.
Scott: it's creepy, but not scary creepy, but weird.
Scott: Oh, you know kind of it is.
Rym: it is very unnerving.
Rym: You're basically like first FPS style.
Scott: So it's it's in that same territory as like cards the cowardly dog, right?
Rym: Yeah, you're basically FPS.
Rym: I'll be in the woods locked in a cabin with Some what appears to be a person.
Rym: you can really only see their eyes or masks they put on and they are Vaguely threatening the entire time.
Rym: they like they're there.
Rym: There is always.
Rym: you feel like They're gonna stab you if you anger them like.
Rym: that's the feeling you have.
Scott: Yeah, but they're.
Scott: they have it yet and they're kind of just losing you.
Rym: They're kind of a weird that guy monster like entity and they're.
Rym: they're basically Getting you to play this board game with them.
Scott: Yeah, if you feel like you've been kidnapped by a potential serial killer, but they haven't killed you.
Scott: They let you roam around the room freely They don't let you leave though And all they want you to do is play this card game with them.
Scott: and the consequences for losing aren't really dire.
Scott: You just have to try again.
Scott: Yeah So you have no choice And you can run around and explore the room and mess up stuff.
Rym: There's another room nearby where there's something going on in there and you can't open it Yet.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: So basically what the element that this adds to slay the spire?
Scott: that slay the spire doesn't have is a plot.
Scott: There's a story going on here.
Scott: And also if you're it's an escape room actually.
Scott: Yeah This you know this very mist style classic escape room puzzle things going on in the room.
Scott: now You know items you can't grab, you know vaults you can't open, you know a clock.
Scott: you can turn the hands on the clock.
Scott: You don't got to figure out it's a it's a puzzle.
Scott: What time do you set the clock to unlock?
Scott: a secret?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Oh god do a thing to see the answer to that puzzle something kind of gross and disturbing.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: Yeah, I guess what I would say is it's a game where Using an item might do like it'll do the game effect that the game tells you it'll do but the fiction of what happened It might be extremely shocking to you.
Rym: Yeah, not spoiling anything.
Rym: is the game so short?
Rym: like you should just play it.
Rym: This game is fantastic, by the way, but I'm noticing something else.
Rym: I'm on the steam page.
Rym: Everything we've described is Literally all that is revealed about the game in any official channel.
Scott: Yeah, the game does not the I guess minor spoiler.
Scott: right the game has three acts.
Scott: Yep, right?
Scott: Everything we've told you about the game is all in act one After act one, it's basically like, you know It opens up and the game doesn't teach you anything about itself.
Scott: But the one thing it does do is when you first load the game It's got a main menu like games normally have.
Rym: yeah, I noticed that right away.
Rym: And for the first thing I thought was when you is oh Did I launch this on my laptop and make a save file and forget?
Scott: Right, your first instinct is to click new game, but you can't click new game.
Scott: It won't let you.
Scott: all you can do as soon as you have a fresh install of the game is Continue you're loading a save file.
Scott: when you start this game It's your only option besides the options menu or quitting, right?
Scott: so and that's yes, that's what you're supposed to do is you start by continuing the save game and then You sort of make sense later.
Scott: What's going on, right?
Scott: So yeah much is revealed Over the course of the game that is shocking and surprising and clever and meta Yeah interesting
Rym: clever met is something that stands out the most like this game evokes the feeling of Being a kid and playing a game You didn't know how to present read the rule book and you're kind of just trying to figure it out as you go like Kind of like that game we played on the 3ds where it was Like hey play these fake retro games and read the strategy guide Like when you're in the room with the dude.
Rym: the rule book to the game is there you can just read it But there's like ink spilled on some of the pages Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, so there is a Lot of commentary in this game social commentary specifically about you know CCG gaming Yeah You know and on various other similar, you know gaming world related topics.
Scott: So it's meta in that sense.
Scott: Yeah, it's just and whoever wrote this.
Scott: it's like, you know, there's some you know, minor polished things to criticize here and there.
Scott: Unlike slay the spire the card game itself doesn't really have a long replay value.
Rym: I mean it has more in the later act when There's a lot more going on then.
Rym: but it's more about that construction that about.
Rym: Yeah, the board the board is trivial.
Scott: I Made a really cheesy deck really quickly and then just dominated with it.
Scott: Oh, yeah until except for certain enemies that have a twist, you know Like slay the spire has the time boy right where it's like aha.
Scott: You made a shiv deck.
Scott: Well, yeah Good luck with that.
Scott: Oh you made a power.
Rym: I know it's random, but it always feels like slay the spire.
Rym: in the third act.
Rym: It's like oh you made the deck.
Rym: that's good against the two boys.
Rym: It's gonna be the time Lord.
Rym: Oh you took care of the time Lord.
Rym: It's the two boys in an inscription.
Scott: I made a deck that summons the big character right away the big monsters right away And then there was a playing a green dead.
Scott: basically There was an enemy that that did not work against at all Had to make a different day.
Rym: I guess Like to sell you on this game a little bit like part of the conceit in the first part of the game that we talked About.
Rym: the most is like you're playing the game, but then you draw a card and the animal on the card Talks to you and he's basically like yo, you gotta help us And like you find another card and then the guy who's running the game is mad.
Rym: like where'd that card come from?
Rym: well, I guess it's in the game so we got a roll with it, but I don't like that.
Rym: You have that card and stuff like that.
Scott: The game.
Scott: it's really, you know, the way they bring the meta and the story together is really out there.
Scott: But - but it's totally it's totally comprehensive.
Scott: It's like you can understand what the hell is going on, but - important.
Rym: if the game had ended when I beat that part I would have been perfectly happy with the game.
Rym: Like I would have been like, oh, yeah, I would 20 bucks.
Rym: it was worth one alone.
Scott: and then I got act two and three and I was like, oh bonus content.
Scott: great This is you know, so we're not gonna was actually somewhat disappointed that there was an act two and three.
Scott: I was like, oh I want a shorter game so I can move on with my life when I hit you.
Rym: good I have to continue when I hit the menu or you get to see six things.
Rym: I was like, oh, is this the clever ending?
Rym: Is this the framing story cool?
Rym: And then when I got into the ass the real second night of the game, I was like Guess this game's longer than I thought like looking at my watch like really like games to be short these days.
Rym: Yeah, exactly, but it pulled me in pretty hard.
Rym: So it's fine.
Rym: But so it.
Scott: one good thing I can say which I've discovered it since.
Scott: I beat it.
Scott: I don't know if Rym beat it, but I'm real near the end.
Rym: I didn't beat it beat it yet.
Scott: Yeah, there is only one ending for this game.
Scott: There is no Choose your own adventure aspect.
Scott: There's no chrono trigger, right?
Scott: Just don't worry if there are choices in the game that feel like oh no if I make a choice here, that's wrong.
Scott: I'm gonna have to play the game over to get a different ending.
Scott: Don't worry about it.
Scott: Just press onwards and Everything will be revealed no matter what decisions you made.
Scott: as long as you keep winning at the card game Right and keep going forward and then the game will end.
Scott: you'll know when it really ended It'll be obvious.
Scott: and the only things you might miss is there are a couple.
Scott: I don't want to say easter egg, but like.
Scott: It's like an escape room, right?
Scott: So imagine you're in an escape room and let's say there's like a vault in the escape room.
Scott: Sometimes you might need to open the vault to escape But what if you didn't?
Scott: what if the vault just had like bonus things in it, right?
Scott: There are a few things like that where it's like if you didn't completely solve everything You might have missed a little.
Scott: you know goodie here or there, but you won't stop you from beating the game.
Scott: and also There was an ARG for the game But the solution to the ARG led to a YouTube video that is like less than a minute long.
Scott: You can easily with a Google search find a link to that YouTube video.
Scott: Avoid playing the ARG or whatever.
Scott: It's probably too late to even do it now and just watch those 50 seconds as an epilogue after you beat the game.
Scott: It's not really that big a deal if you don't though.
Scott: It's like not that much happens in 50 seconds, right?
Rym: So so I guess if you haven't played this game like honestly this game is 100% worth playing.
Rym: I've never really played anything quite like it.
Rym: I enjoyed the hell out of it, and I highly encourage you to buy it.
Rym: I also highly encourage you to stop listening now.
Rym: We're not gonna like mega spoil everything, but I want to talk with Scott least a little bit about Some of the things that happen.
Scott: Did you beat it or not?
Rym: I didn't beat it beat it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You didn't beat it beat it.
Rym: All right, but Honestly, just go play this game.
Rym: It's great, and I guess I Was.
Scott: if it's on sale definitely go absolutely even at the full price.
Scott: It's a game that you can buy Play all the way through be done with Remember it leave an impression on you as a really good work of art And then you don't have to go back to it unless you really want to.
Scott: But if you did go back to it It'd be very easy to do so.
Rym: so because the way the game was made like rendered in the beginning I Was very surprised that there wasn't a VR Option because that could have been really easy to make and imagine how it would have added some immersion and some imagine how Absolutely cool.
Rym: It would be to play like that part of the game in VR.
Scott: But well did you get?
Scott: did you get to act three now?
Rym: I'm still an act two.
Rym: I think I'm gonna get into act three.
Scott: well act three might have some good VR awesome, but act two Would not work in VR.
Scott: act two would know you would act two.
Scott: VR is useless for act two.
Scott: yep But you could.
Scott: you could make a different game because remember right so spoilers right it's like You're a human playing a game, but your character in the game is a human who's sitting at a computer playing.
Rym: Yeah, I like.
Rym: I was reminded by that when I heard his voice in act two when something happens.
Scott: So you're a got you're a human in the real world sitting at a computer playing a game And in the game you're a human playing a sitting at a computer and then in the game the card game There's like yet another character.
Scott: That's like the avid right.
Scott: so you could make a VR experience.
Scott: Oh, yeah You are like that guy.
Scott: so like you're always adequate.
Scott: you just you know.
Rym: so here's the problem.
Rym: This is this is like that for that would only work with a high-end VR kit because a big problem in VR Is that without extreme resolution?
Rym: Anything that's like looking at screens or text inside of a game can be real dicey.
Rym: But like I could do a thing.
Scott: you could do a thing where when you sit down at like in VR You go to the chair next to the computer.
Scott: now when you sit at the chair It just take the.
Scott: it takes up your whole visor.
Scott: But you could do it with a high VR, and then you can get up whenever you want.
Rym: so yeah Yeah, you never played super hot in VR.
Rym: But the way it works is you put you sit down you stand there you put on the VR helmet Then it shows you in a realistic real-world apartment And there's a VR rig in there and then in the game you put on that VR set to play super hot.
Scott: I could definitely you could also make a sequel inscription to where The game is a VR game.
Scott: right and you do that same thing.
Rym: yep Ah that would be.
Scott: you could because basically you can make the game in the game.
Rym: You could play with that to such a ridiculous degree.
Rym: That's very adjacent to an idea chase, and I have been workshopping back and forth for years that we're never gonna do.
Rym: Yeah, we've been calling it the room for a while.
Scott: I mean you could.
Scott: I mean you know taking the old half-life elevator.
Rym: They you know mod and just Right it's basically that but with the twist, but anyway.
Scott: so uh else about inscription you want to say no other than like.
Rym: I was deeply impressed with this game in the how it Made a game within a game Just fun and engaging and difficult enough for me to play with But not difficult enough to where I had to seriously like Read that entire rule book in the game to figure out how to win.
Rym: like you could kind of play it fast and loose and still get through.
Rym: The escape room aspects were very true to escape rooms Which was good and bad in that.
Rym: yep, I solved every escape room puzzle with brute force.
Scott: Now some of them.
Rym: I even though I just like all the combination locks I just brute force because there were only three things.
Rym: So it was so quick for some of them.
Scott: cuz I had already cuz I found the codes or whatever.
Rym: I one point.
Rym: I saw what I thought was the code, but I and I put it in and it wasn't it.
Rym: I think it was a code for a different part.
Rym: So I just said fuck it, and I just clicked randomly and after like 30 seconds.
Rym: It just opened.
Scott: there was one really obtuse one That I googled out of impatience But actually the answer to it appeared in like the next segment of the game.
Scott: I just waited.
Scott: I would have had it.
Rym: you know what that is.
Rym: that's like Crystal Chronicles when you are.
Scott: it was.
Scott: it was one of The unnecessary ones.
Rym: never in Crystal Chronicles we encountered a puzzle.
Rym: We thought it was solvable.
Rym: you googled it to figure it out and determined that it was not actually Solvable.
Rym: at the point of the game we were at we just had encountered it early and were weird nerds who were obsessed with solving Something.
Scott: that was a good game design lesson.
Rym: You know if you don't reveal a puzzle that you can't solve without all that.
Scott: so so for example Super Metroid.
Scott: Right I got to show the player the super missile door before you give them the super missile.
Rym: otherwise the super missiles not that exciting.
Scott: Right, but you also have to make it absolutely clear to the player Unambiguously that there is no point in shooting this green door.
Scott: Just carry on.
Rym: that is why Metroid Dread was very clear.
Rym: do not use Being able to survive and attack by one of those things as a strategy.
Scott: We do not intend you to play this game this way, so if you're an escape room Don't put puzzles before You know answers.
Scott: right.
Rym: if the escape rooms love that because the red herring is a big part of why escape rooms are even remotely Challenging.
Rym: that's part of like the red.
Scott: make the red herring.
Scott: red herring clues Not red herring doors.
Scott: red herring keys are good.
Scott: red herring doors exactly Right not the greatest unless you do them really well, right so that it's clear.
Rym: Yeah, you can't do this yet But I guess that's sort of the secret sauce of this game that I appreciated.
Rym: Is that every puzzle or when you get to the stack - we have to make a deck like yeah?
Rym: There's a there's more skill there But it's not so hard that you have to think about it for more than a few minutes to figure out a cheesy enough deck That'll get you to the next part of the game.
Scott: Well, I think that's.
Scott: it's actually a good thing that the card game isn't so good.
Scott: right?
Scott: because you think about Slay the spire where the card game you can just yeah, it was just magic.
Rym: like this game would have been way too much.
Scott: Well, but imagine if you had a card game where they get but the game The card game was good and infinite really playable, but the game itself is this one-shot experience.
Scott: Well, it's like well.
Scott: I've beat the game and now there's this great card game.
Scott: I want to explore more But I have no avenue in which to explore that card game because the game itself is over.
Scott: So you don't want to put a good infinitely replayable deep card game in a one-shot experience.
Scott: Exactly because it'll be and likewise.
Scott: Let's say you had a crappy card game like this.
Scott: I mean, it's not crappy, but you know a card game That's not that deep.
Rym: it is less deep than like original magic with no expansions like there is not much going on.
Scott: It's a shallower game with a lot more luck involved.
Rym: right not very well cuz really it's not a game.
Rym: It's a series of puzzles.
Rym: the way the game actually works, but I digress exactly.
Scott: But let's say you put that game on the infinitely replayable roguelike slay the spire.
Scott: You would get bored.
Scott: You'd be like why would I climb the spire again?
Scott: This card game is.
Scott: no I'm already I've spent I've exhausted the.
Rym: why do I keep climbing the spire?
Rym: one because the ascensions are so hard Yeah, and two because that game has surprising depth.
Scott: Yep, see an inscription.
Scott: Yeah, also.
Rym: I watch this video the AGDQ and good lord.
Rym: I did not know about the room doubling.
Scott: glitch And Play it through.
Scott: beat it once then you'll be done with it.
Scott: Yeah, no more content after you beat it.
Scott: So don't worry about it.
Rym: Yeah, anytime you feel like you miss something just steamroll ahead.
Rym: It'll be fine like you don't just go forward You do not need to fully understand the cards And you are not going to fully understand why those three animals are talking to you in the first act.
Rym: just roll with it.
Scott: Yeah, just pay attention to everything, but just all you got to do is just try to progress forward right And you'll.
Scott: eventually you'll beat it trust me and it'll be worth the time it takes you to be up and I guess money that you paid for content warning if physical body horror bothers you be ready for.
Rym: there are two things in this game that do die.
Rym: very very Visceral body horror.
Scott: act one is the most horror.
Rym: Yeah, that's a in act one.
Rym: There's an item the pliers and you can use them to basically put weight on the scale like cheat at the game.
Rym: But the way if you actually click on this item what it does is your character rips one of their teeth out Like like right there doesn't warn you.
Rym: just happens and you put this bloody tooth on the scale The knife.
Rym: you gouge out one of your own eyes in first person.
Rym: Yep, so be ready for that.
Rym: the game in no way warns you.
Rym: but those are the only two things I encountered that were like like that VR eye gouging.
Rym: I mean I played some indie experiences where they had an eye focused jump-scare.
Rym: I would argue that that is Unethical game design when a VR is good enough.
Rym: You could really without consent.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah without forewarning.
Rym: I fully forewarned Slammed into the wall when that happened in a VR indie game that I played like literally bodied the wall.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patreons for this.
Rym: absurd GeekNights are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce Linky G drink Lily Tenebrae and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names Chris the dog Chris rhyme or Clinton waltz and text Finn Chi 85 Rebecca Dunn.
Rym: review mad bull 34 cowards Sam Erickson Shervin von Horrell Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Shepherd Young.
Rym: Shepherd Young station and several people whose patreon names I will not say due to their specific request.
Rym: So, uh, yeah Not much is going on.
Rym: do a show on Thursday on something but at least for tonight.
Rym: I leave you simply with
Media: just imagine a world where you will hold your entire Future
Scott: and
Media: when a tiny glowing crystal will guide you through an existence in which each day is more Wonderful than the last where it will be possible for you to obtain the fulfillment of every fantasy the satisfaction of every vanity the absolute attainment of every wish.
Media: a Metro-goldwyn-mayor presents the Saul David production of Logan's run a Fantastic journey through a world beyond imagination.
Media: Welcome to the 23rd century the perfect world of total pleasure.
Media: Imagine a world in which you need never be alone.
Media: You touch a switch turn a dial and the perfect lover steps into your arms.
Media: Every pleasure is yours to experience runner.
Media: There's just one catch When the tiny crystal in the palm of your hand flashes its final message your time is up.
Media: Michael.
Media: York is low.
Media: run Logan policeman in a perfect world trained to track down runners Until he is forced to run himself.
Rym: I'm your friend.
Media: I understand we all go crazy once in a while, but she's a runner and it's over Box an incredible being more than human more than machine Diabolical guardian of the gateway to freedom or Logan and the woman who loves him.