Rym: It's Thursday, August 4th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about vending machines.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: It's uh, it's warm today and I don't say that lightly.
Rym: It was uh, one of those days where you know the office is always crazy cold.
Rym: Like so cold that I'll shiver if I don't wear like a blazer.
Scott: Especially considering there's not a lot of people there I met.
Rym: Oh yeah, there's like no one there.
Rym: Especially on a Thursday.
Rym: Plus all my teams are overseas anyway.
Rym: Like I actually work with very few people in the US so going to the office is always extra funny.
Rym: Because everyone I'm meeting with is on a Zoom call like in Frankfurt or something.
Rym: But uh, and the office is freezing and outside is like 90 degrees.
Rym: But uh, it was a pleasant bike to and from work.
Rym: And uh, let's see what's going on.
Rym: We skipped a show Wednesday, Tuesday.
Rym: And as you the listener know, if anything that we thought we were going to talk about, any given GeekNights, once that episode's day passes it is forgotten.
Rym: So nothing else has happened in my life.
Scott: The uh, I mean, you know I tried to do, I tried to change my work up a bit this week, right.
Scott: And I took, you know, because I got the new work laptop.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: And I'm like alright, I really don't like working with just one screen, right.
Scott: But let me go try to work just out on the balcony.
Scott: Because at least, you know, it's trade off.
Rym: I've done that and the only time it's been pleasant and successful is when I'm doing training and not when I'm doing work.
Rym: Because there is no way to both avoid sun glare and avoid the sun being in my face directly.
Scott: Oh, neither of those was a problem.
Rym: The sun comes straight into our balcony, like head on.
Scott: Oh okay, I mean, anyway, I guess not at this time of year the sun is high enough that it goes straight down, kinda.
Scott: It doesn't get sunny in your face until like, you don't get, you will be in the shade until like noon or one.
Rym: Yeah, the other problem is now because the heatwave out on the balcony, there are like 4,000 air conditioners all going simultaneously.
Scott: Right, so I had to basically, you know, the air conditioner blows into the balcony.
Scott: So I had to, when I went out there, I had to turn off the air conditioner to not be Otherwise, not only is it blowing directly on me otherwise.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And, you know, having the one screen actually wasn't too bad.
Scott: I managed pretty well.
Scott: So that, you know, I think it helps that the last time, like every laptop I've ever owned personally did not have a high resolution screen.
Scott: Whereas this MacBook Air has like a retina screen on it, right?
Scott: And I was like, oh, I can actually get a lot of things on the one screen without issue.
Scott: Uh, and then I just finished working just now and, uh, that's it work again on Monday.
Rym: Four days.
Rym: I gotta figure out a way to get that.
Rym: I gotta get on that somehow.
Scott: Come work with this.
Scott: I don't know if this company needs you for anything.
Rym: I mean, if they ever need a senior like director product manager.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We make a database.
Scott: I don't know how much.
Rym: What's the comic?
Rym: I only know how to tell people to design complex alloys.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: Though in, uh, in minor, uh, openy bitty news.
Rym: So, you know, it's rollerblading season.
Rym: Uh, and also I've noticed skating like four wheel skating is on a huge upswing in New York city lately.
Scott: Like, oh yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's been on a huge, it's been an upswing for a few years, but it's like Excel this summer.
Rym: I feel like that upswing accelerated.
Rym: I see people everywhere.
Rym: I see a lot of people learning how to skate or blade for the first time clearly because I see how they're skating when I'm out.
Scott: So, uh, well, I think what's, I think what's happened is that, you know, it's been on the upswing for like quite a few years, right?
Scott: It started, you know, from the roller Derby then towards, you know, the, the old school retro disco day.
Rym: since around 2017, it's been on a big upswing.
Scott: But I think what's happened is maybe just the past year or two, right.
Scott: We've seen the capitalist response to the existing upswing.
Scott: It's like it was popular among the people.
Scott: Cause like, you know, it got popular just from like a, a sort of a grassroots popularity.
Scott: Like people.
Scott: just, you know, roll this, I seen a lot of people, like they would do like a, you know, they would dance in place on a vertical video on Tik TOK or YouTube or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know, it looks like fun.
Scott: People want to do it.
Scott: And I think enough people started doing it.
Scott: that there is now, you know, you see like in a fricking central park, they set up the huge roller rink where they usually an ice rink.
Scott: They've never done that before this year.
Scott: that I've seen.
Rym: Another consequence of this is there are a lot of knockoff bootleg adjacent brands now selling like shit ass rollerblades and roller skates.
Scott: The quality roller blades are.
Scott: roller skates are not cheap.
Scott: I mean, I have a pair of high quality styling ones are so, but now if you know that it's popular enough, it's like suddenly people are making cheap ones again, but the cheap ones are interesting.
Rym: I talked about when I got new rollerblades many years ago on GeekNights and how much the technology has advanced, but the cheap brands coming in.
Rym: So I wore out my last brake pad on my rollerblades.
Rym: So I went to buy a new one and I could buy the moderately expensive rollerblade branded standard universal brake pad, or there was an Amazon one that looked identical.
Rym: That seems like what all the cheapy people are buying.
Rym: That was like a dollar.
Rym: So I bought the dollar one.
Rym: See how it would go.
Rym: It disintegrated in the course of trying to use it once.
Scott: Yeah, it's probably just made of some random.
Rym: It was just random, right?
Rym: It's just way ground down to the screw.
Rym: One time when I tried to stop at speed, like it was amazing.
Rym: Just left this long black streak.
Rym: I basically bought a marker.
Scott: I mean, couldn't you tell that it was the wrong material when you took it?
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: But the thing is I don't use brakes that often.
Rym: You don't really need your brakes except when you're going across traffic.
Rym: Once you're out in the place you're going to be blading, you really don't need the brakes.
Rym: The brakes are just there as a safety mechanism.
Rym: So I don't hit them that often.
Rym: But going at speed and having to stop because there's a red light coming up, I had to break.
Rym: And I drew a 10 foot long black line on the sidewalk.
Rym: And then I scraped off the top of a screw trying to stop myself.
Scott: I wonder if the roller blade brand is really the S tier of inline skate.
Rym: Absolutely.
Rym: Right now I feel like the sweet spot is 90 millimeter wheels with the magnesium frames and the minimalist boots.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder what the most... There must be actual professional inline skate people, right?
Rym: So I'm already at the point where I have like... Instead of just buying blades you buy the frame and the boot and the tires and the bearings and all the pieces separately.
Rym: Like you choose what you want.
Rym: So I have this pretty complex rig.
Rym: The real scary ones are the speed skates.
Rym: Because 90 millimeters is already like double what I used to use when I was a kid.
Rym: And double was like standard back in the day.
Rym: I've seen 120s.
Rym: Those things are terrifying.
Rym: You can get those up to like 35, 40 miles an hour on a straightaway.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: There do seem to be a couple other brands though.
Scott: Is K2 brand.
Rym: K2 is like the second best.
Rym: They're pretty good.
Rym: I used to do... I only switched to roller blade after I moved to the city.
Rym: I was K2 my entire life before that.
Rym: And then there's a whole bunch of basically identical looking fake brands that all have different names but all are clearly the exact same skates that are for sale on Amazon.
Scott: Wow, this is freaky looking one.
Scott: It looks like a ski moon boot with tiny wheels.
Scott: Like four tiny wheels.
Scott: And it's called them 909.
Rym: That sounds like it's for parks and tricks.
Rym: Generally use smaller wheels for hockey.
Scott: For aggressive skating with grinds and jumps.
Rym: Yep, that's a park skates.
Rym: Park skates use basically the same wheels that skateboards do.
Rym: And speed skates and leisure skates use those.
Scott: Those don't look like skateboard wheels but they are tiny.
Rym: Yeah but they're the same material as skateboard wheels.
Rym: They're a lot harder.
Rym: They don't grip as much.
Rym: They're more rounded.
Rym: They'll survive like grinding.
Rym: If I jumped on a bar in my blades, they would instantly stop and flip me over sideways.
Rym: They would grip the bar like a brake and just flip me over.
Rym: Yeah, there's a ton of news.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Rym: We can talk about anything.
Rym: And the first one probably the biggest one.
Rym: And there's more.
Rym: There is a wave of consolidation.
Scott: There's a giant Wednesday news.
Scott: But let's save it for Wednesday.
Rym: We'll save it for Wednesday.
Scott: We don't usually have enough Wednesday news.
Scott: It's too big.
Rym: But basically this whole wave of news is all the same story.
Rym: Big companies in a variety of sectors are all merging all their crap and consolidating yet again.
Rym: Which in my personal opinion, but not the opinion of anyone I may work for, does not bode well for the economy for the next five to ten years.
Scott: We already knew the economy was fucked the fuck up.
Scott: Everybody knows that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So HBO Max is basically gone.
Rym: HBO Max is being merged into Discovery Plus.
Scott: That's really.
Scott: it's really interesting, because if you think about content wise, right, you got to, you know, think HBO Max is like one of the better content.
Rym: Not that is objective.
Rym: So industry surveys and studies have shown that HBO Max had the highest customer satisfaction far and away of any streaming service available in America.
Rym: Like they were the premium top tier offering, highest customer satisfaction, highest customer retention, highest everything.
Rym: Like they were the best one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You got to imagine, like, you know, if you think of if you just think brand wise, content wise, the ones that should go would be like Hulu.
Scott: She just is owned by Disney, right?
Scott: Just merge that shit into D plus.
Scott: Why do you got it separated?
Rym: Or the plebeian might think, oh, well, get rid of Discovery.
Rym: That's just like reality.
Rym: So who?
Scott: Well, Discovery, who even pays for that?
Rym: Ah, so here's the rub.
Rym: Discovery has so many more viewers than than HBO Max.
Rym: That keeping HBO Max around is a terrible idea.
Rym: Discovery.
Scott: No one like who is he?
Scott: Who is watching the?
Rym: who subscribes to the streaming service?
Rym: Basic people.
Scott: But how?
Scott: it's like no one talks about it.
Scott: Nobody.
Scott: Where are these people that are paying for this mass market?
Rym: And this is something that is always hard to express to people.
Scott: People who don't Internet and don't talk on Internet.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Ever.
Rym: People who aren't online and don't give a shit what they.
Rym: the most popular shows in America are things like naked and afraid or the British Bake Off.
Rym: They're all reality.
Scott: British Bake Off is on Netflix.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But shows like that unscripted content are the far majority popular content in America.
Scott: But I mean, that's been true.
Scott: That's not just the American thing.
Scott: That's a worldwide thing.
Scott: And that's been the case for like a very long time.
Scott: But the problem is late 90s.
Rym: People who care about movies and content, who care about quality, who are interested in these things.
Rym: We all have this perception that HBO Max, which was kind of warranted, was the premium offering.
Rym: It had high quality, high budget, like big productions on it.
Scott: So things had shows people were talking about the most.
Rym: But that's not how you make money, because, one, those shows cost a lot of money to make and not that many people care enough to pay to see them.
Rym: Meanwhile, direct unscripted shovelware like naked and afraid cost almost nothing to make.
Rym: You can crank out just hours and hours and hours and hours of content.
Rym: Doesn't have to be of any particular level of quality.
Rym: And people are happy to pay a pittance or watch an ad to see that kind of stuff.
Scott: Now, see, it'd be one thing, right?
Scott: It's like if you if you're going to make shovel content, that's just nothing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: At least have the decency to be like, you know, the K-pop industry and just give that shit away for free.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: With ads, because that's how they make their fucking money.
Scott: Well, they don't do it.
Scott: I mean, I guess this ad that I don't see.
Rym: So HBO Max was also the smallest of the major streaming services.
Rym: They had like 70 million subscribers.
Rym: Disney's like 130 million.
Rym: Netflix is like 220 million.
Rym: Even on Disney, a lot of their success and growth was around in other countries.
Rym: They offered a shitty tier of Disney Plus that was cheaper and full of ads.
Rym: And people are way more interested in that than the ad free tier.
Scott: Suppose they say that the Discovery one has 92 million subscribers.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So 92 million subscribers to Discovery Plus, but nobody talks about it on the Internet because the people...
Scott: It said that HBO Max only had 48.
Scott: It's like, wow, okay.
Rym: Well, 48.
Scott: So half as many.
Rym: The number I have from some industry sources was 70 million, but the difference might be between peak and current versus actual current.
Scott: Hulu might be 40 something.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But, uh, basically the big, like the funny thing is that best I can tell, HBO Max effectively cost HBO money because we actually look at where HBO generates its revenue.
Rym: Even now, almost all of it comes from regular old cable HBO Max.
Scott: People pay for the cable who aren't watching HBO.
Scott: This is something we've known about television for a long time, which is that if people had to only paid for the things they actually watched.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's a lot of just cable channels that are like ESPN was getting like multiple dollars per cable subscriber.
Rym: They just disappeared.
Scott: Even though a fraction of those people ever went to ESPN ever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They just were forced to pay.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Because it's all bundled together.
Scott: Like when you go to GameStop and you want to buy a new console, like a new PlayStation, and they bundle it with some accessories and it's like too bad.
Scott: You got to buy the accessories.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And now the accessory company makes money.
Scott: ESPN is the accessory company force.
Scott: People are forced to pay for their crap that they just didn't use.
Rym: Or even worse.
Rym: And this is something that I'll talk about in the thing of the day, but a lot of people, I'd say almost everyone who would listen to GeekNights is too young to remember when cable TV first appeared in the US outside of very limited rural market.
Scott: The whole point was no ads.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Cable TV was, Hey, pay for TV.
Rym: No ads.
Scott: It was well, even before that you could pay for HBO by itself, which we did.
Rym: We had a satellite dish that just had HBO.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: People had TVs that had a switch.
Scott: It's actually said HBO physically on the TV with a mechanical switch.
Scott: Not, you know, no remote controls yet.
Scott: It's like you turn a knob and it would say HBO physically on this dial.
Rym: So basically this consolidation, there's a lot going on here, but basically HBO max effectively costs HBO money because at best, even if it got subscribers, those are people who would either cancel the cable subscription who had never had it or who had never had a cable subscription.
Rym: They cannibalized their own much more profitable, at least in the short term.
Rym: business of just having stuff on regular cable TV, but also creating original content costs so much money and yet didn't actually attract enough users to matter in capitalism.
Rym: In fact, I was
Scott: one of those things that they, they invested too, you know, they could have made, you know, they're the, the, the budgets for the content were very high,
Rym: but if the budgets were low, then the content would have sucked and they wouldn't have even gotten the initial people.
Rym: Like I signed up to watch one show.
Rym: Our flag means death.
Rym: And when that show ended, I canceled my subscription and it looks like a lot of people did exactly that.
Scott: Well, I think the reason is that there's too many, you know, we all talk about this too many streaming services, right?
Scott: When there were just a few, right?
Scott: When it was like just Netflix by itself, you could subscribe to Netflix and you wouldn't really unsubscribe to it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like now when there's so many, it's like, well, I don't want to pay for so many at once, but I want to write, they're not bundled.
Scott: So it's actually now kind of worth it to subscribe and unsubscribe and switch around, you know, and watch different things that way.
Scott: When there weren't so many services, people might've just stuck with the one and kept paying it.
Scott: Even if they didn't watch anything that month, you wouldn't like turn Netflix off for a month and turn it back on the next month.
Scott: That's a pain in the ass.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So I suspect the end game of all this is a lot of streaming platforms are going to disappear and get acquired and merged into other streaming platforms.
Rym: They're going to be very few streaming platforms remaining.
Rym: I think a lot of existing content will disappear.
Scott: Fewer remaining is, you know, good and bad, right?
Rym: So I think a lot of existing content is going to disappear from all streaming services and be unavailable except via piracy or cable TV.
Rym: I also think we're going to see an absolute collapse of the scripted original content sector in America across the board.
Rym: I think fewer shows are going to be made.
Rym: Shows are going to have lower budgets and content is increasingly going to be focused.
Rym: It's going to be like what happened in the nineties when reality TV displaced like all of regular TV.
Rym: that's going to happen on the internet now at scale.
Scott: What I'd like to see is just, you know, the people who actually produce video content, right?
Scott: It's like some of them are on, you know, just YouTube, which is sort of direct, right?
Scott: Still YouTube middleman, but it's like, you know, historically we've had all these, you know, middlemen because of the technological nature and the production nature of Hollywood, right?
Scott: It's like, oh, you need distributors and you need producers and you need to get your shit into theaters and you need to get your shit into stores on discs, right?
Scott: It's like, you don't need that shit now.
Scott: You look a lot of authors, right?
Scott: Have been foregoing publishers, writing books and getting them up in the Kindle store or whatever, right?
Rym: You know, that is sustainable though, because discoverability is down across the board, coupled with the fact that with a bad economy, people can't afford to buy stuff.
Scott: So they're not gonna, it's a little bit more direct, right?
Scott: The point is what if I had enough money to make a movie and I wanted to make it right, but I wanted to at least come close to breaking even, right?
Scott: It's like, if you just want to make money and that's it, why would you in a movie is not the thing to invest in?
Scott: Well, that is the much more fundamental from the perspective of just a rich person who wants to get richer.
Scott: Art is not the way to get richer, right?
Scott: Whether it's big art or small art, right?
Scott: But you know, you want to make a movie and you want to at least break even, make some money, right?
Scott: You know, because you care about art and you're in that spot.
Scott: Why are you getting in with any Hollywood, right?
Scott: It's like, just go do everything directly, right?
Rym: It's like, I would argue that doing everything directly in that level of production probably doubles to triples your costs because you lose the economy of scale of the industry itself.
Scott: No, you still like, you know, you hire union people, right?
Rym: You know, you just- I think you underestimate how much that pipeline provides or what steps actually like a show like that goes through.
Scott: It's like, you need writers, you need camera people, you need sound people, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you can hire all those people.
Scott: Stop.
Scott: Spin up a company to produce one movie and that's all, that's it.
Scott: The end.
Scott: That company makes the one movie, it doesn't make any other movie.
Scott: That's it, right?
Scott: When the movie's done, everyone go buy another company.
Rym: Movies are also a separate phenomenon that are not as impacted by this.
Rym: What's being impacted is serials, shows and non-theatrical original content.
Scott: I don't, I think that, you know, video, whether it's, you know, a one video that happens to be two hours plus or, you know, a video that's broken up into several things.
Rym: For whatever reason, and it doesn't matter why, mass market consumers make a very, very clear distinction between the two.
Rym: and mass market consumers are willing to actually pay a lot to see a movie and are willing to pay basically nothing to see something that they don't consider to be a movie.
Rym: It doesn't matter why.
Rym: that's true, that is how they act.
Scott: Right, so it's just a completely arbitrary distinction though.
Scott: The production of them is the same.
Scott: So if you, you know, stop, don't produce, if you're making video, you have camera, people, writers, every video content.
Rym: I'm just saying that the, the fundamental problem is just that the industry, none of this is sustainable and unscripted content is going to take over everything.
Rym: because like you said, the fundamental root cause of all of this is that all things are made because someone who has money wants to have more money and money will go wherever the cheapest dollars are.
Rym: So never buy expensive dollars.
Rym: Don't spend 90 cents to make a dollar if you could spend 50 cents on something shittier to make a dollar.
Rym: In equally dire news, the worst and second worst airlines in America are merging to become the fifth largest and worst airline, worst airline in the US.
Scott: Well, worst, worst airline of note.
Scott: There's a lot of, it's surprising that there's so many like really, really tiny airlines that no one's ever heard of that like go make two stops.
Rym: Most people consider those shuttles or charters.
Rym: They call them something else.
Scott: Like when you're around though, but yeah, major airlines that you've heard of that you might actually buy a ticket from, right?
Scott: There's JetBlue and the other, it was Spirit.
Rym: So Spirit is one of the few airlines on earth, Rain Air is up there too, that I refuse to fly on under any circumstances.
Scott: Why do you always say Rain Air?
Scott: It's Ryan.
Scott: Like the guy's name is Ryan, right?
Rym: You ever talk to someone from the UK or Germany?
Scott: Ryan, like you don't have to.
Rym: My coworkers fly with them all the time.
Scott: Their name is Ryan.
Rym: So everyone I know at work who flies them all the time because it's the only way to get around a lot of places they live, that's how they pronounce it.
Scott: I wonder if the person, the Ryan, also I'm pretty sure the Ryan guy is like a piece of shit rich guy.
Rym: I mean, how do you pronounce Linux?
Scott: The guy's name is Linus Dorvalds.
Rym: Yeah, do you pronounce it Linux?
Scott: You're supposed to pronounce it the way his name is.
Scott: Are you?
Rym: Anyway, so Spirit was always on my never fly under any circumstances list.
Rym: The one time I flew with Spirit was such a just disastrous, ugly shit show.
Rym: I would never get on a Spirit plane no matter what.
Scott: JetBlue has an interesting history because JetBlue was run by like these Mormon type people, right?
Rym: When JetBlue was founded, they actually tried something that was a good idea for society, but a terrible business idea of making a budget airline that was nice enough, like this bare minimum of quality, didn't have classes.
Rym: There's no first class or business class, just all the seats are the same.
Rym: In-flight entertainment, which used to not be free back then.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, yeah.
Scott: Back in the day, like, you know, other airlines did not have, right, like TV, any kind of screen for the passengers and people did not yet have phones and tablets.
Scott: So it was early 2000s, no phones, no tablets yet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So a screen on the plane was like amazing.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And a lot of other airlines, if they had, yeah, most airlines, if they had a movie, it was more like a coach bus with like a few overhead screens here and there, all showing the same movie, not like individual personal screens.
Scott: JetBlue in the early 2000s, every seat had a screen.
Scott: All the seats were the same and it was satellite TV.
Scott: that was live and you could change the channels and you didn't have to pay extra for it.
Scott: It wasn't like pay for the in-flight movie and check the first class to get the check in a bag was free.
Rym: The terminals were like.
Rym: everything about JetBlue was great.
Rym: Like for a normal person who's not rich, JetBlue was.
Scott: JetBlue started.
Scott: It was like this, like the best possible airline.
Scott: Everything about it was great.
Scott: The only thing was it was early days for JetBlue.
Scott: They didn't go to that many places.
Scott: But the places they did go, it was just, you know, partly because their primary hub was New York City.
Rym: So if you lived in New York, you basically had like the cheapest, best flights everywhere in America.
Scott: I used to go back and forth to college like so many times.
Rym: Do you have any free flights?
Scott: I got 45 in 45 minutes instead of five hours of driving.
Rym: I think we flew JetBlue to almost every packs all around America for a long time.
Scott: Yeah, for a long time.
Scott: But then over time, right, JetBlue, they were making some money, I believe.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: As far as I can tell, they were profitable.
Rym: They were doing fine, but right.
Rym: They weren't making.
Scott: capitalism demands growth and they weren't making.
Scott: they couldn't make more money.
Scott: They added adding more flights didn't really make them enough more money.
Scott: So, you know, it wasn't good for stock prices and whatnot.
Scott: So they had to do things to make even more money.
Scott: And eventually everything that was nice about JetBlue went away.
Rym: I remember it was like four years ago, five years ago.
Rym: I think it was five years ago.
Rym: Covid.
Rym: I've always messed up how many years ago something was.
Rym: The last time I flew JetBlue, the flight was late taking off.
Rym: It was late landing.
Rym: The bags took forever to come.
Rym: The in-flight entertainment didn't work.
Rym: There was just problems the whole time.
Scott: And other airlines are bad.
Scott: Other airlines started doing the screens.
Scott: Also, every airline has that now.
Scott: Plus, everyone has phones and tablets.
Scott: So I just turn off the screen.
Scott: It's not a benefit.
Rym: But I remember the moment when I realized JetBlue might be going downhill was when they announced that they were introducing basically a first class cabin, like they added first class seats.
Rym: Then they added a basic fare where you didn't get to pick your seat, which is the kind of thing that shit tier airlines like Spirit do.
Rym: And it just got worse and worse and worse.
Rym: And that last year after I had this bad experience, I remember I looked online and I found out JetBlue that year was the worst performing airline in America in terms of on-time departures and arrivals by a wide margin.
Scott: I mean, they were the worst, but you got it.
Scott: The worst is basically like they're on time, like something like 70 to 80 percent of the time.
Scott: But it's like also everyone else is still doing better than that.
Rym: But also when they were not on time, it was by many, many, many hours.
Rym: Not like, oh, we're 15 minutes late or like four hours late.
Scott: So they're on time.
Scott: Performance is seventy three point four percent, which is like you think, oh, that's a pretty high number.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But actually out of major U.S.
Scott: Airlines, that's in tenth place.
Rym: So there's a lot of bad airlines doing better than JetBlue on that front.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Number one is Hawaiian Airlines at eighty nine point nine percent.
Scott: So if you take ten flights on Hawaiian Airlines, one of them is going to be delayed.
Scott: If you take ten flights on JetBlue, like two to three of them are going to be delayed.
Scott: So it's like, OK, you're still very it's still.
Scott: delays are still unlikely, but they're twice as likely.
Scott: So that's like.
Rym: but also they started doing the budget airline thing that Spirit also does, because that one time I took Spirit, they woke everybody up like in the middle of the flight with a with a loud announcement that came through every headset.
Rym: All the entertainment was paused and it was also in the air out of loudspeakers to give you this five minute pitch on their credit card.
Rym: And then they walked around and asked everyone yes or no individually.
Rym: And you had to answer them if you wanted to sign up for it.
Rym: It was awful.
Rym: There were ads playing on the screen or regardless of if you were using it, you couldn't turn the screen off.
Rym: Also, the staff were rude.
Rym: I saw a fight in the line like it was just everything was.
Scott: That's another thing when JetBlue started.
Scott: The food for the plane.
Rym: Oh, JetBlue had better food and coach than any other airline I'd ever flown in America.
Scott: Well, the whole the whole flight was the same seats.
Scott: There were no separation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So everyone got the same food and it was free.
Scott: They would just go down and they would be like, you know, you know, which snack do you want?
Scott: Here's the list.
Rym: It was nice.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, but more now, of course, get a lot of non free shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're like pay to get.
Scott: you want to pay to get a meal.
Scott: You want to, you know, just started doing all the money grabbing stuff that everyone does that they didn't do originally.
Rym: So we'll see what happens.
Rym: But basically now there are four sort of good ish, good or good ish carriers in America in North America.
Scott: Well, there's a lot of good ones that go to less places.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, you know, the Hawaiian Airlines, obviously.
Scott: You got your Alaska Airlines in the northwest.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, you can't fly Alaska Airlines in from like New York to like in Europe.
Rym: My favorite airline to fly was Turkish air because it was way cheap and the food was better.
Rym: Like the food was like restaurant quality on these flights, even in like premium economy, like regular old seats.
Rym: But obviously couldn't really fly anywhere but to and from Istanbul on Turkish air.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, this is something I really don't understand.
Scott: is what, you know, it's not like trains where we have, you know, we know why we can't have.
Rym: Scott, do you want me to explain airport slots?
Scott: No, no, no, no, no, not the slots, but it's like you look at, you know, some of the airlines from around the world, right?
Scott: Like, you know, especially like Etihad and, you know, Lufthansa and some of these, you know, airlines.
Scott: And they, you know, in the first class, at least, you know, they got some fancy.
Rym: Yeah, you are already here's that you were comparing international flights to domestic and pseudo domestic flights.
Scott: But like even what U.S.
Scott: Airlines international flights, Delta international flights from the U.S.
Scott: has the fancy shit.
Rym: Delta.
Rym: You ever flown Delta one fancy?
Scott: The fanciest Delta plane is not Etihad fancy.
Scott: Well, no.
Rym: So depending what you're talking about, because there's there is business in first class.
Rym: Like I've flown the Delta one, whatever class for work a bunch of times.
Rym: That is a private walled off cubicle with a bed that's completely lie flat and a real mattress and like a four star meal and all the booze you want.
Rym: And like a personal like a sommelier for your cabin.
Rym: Like that is already like that is Delta.
Rym: You can even get that flying to Seattle.
Rym: Not that you want to spend four thousand dollars on it, but no, what you're referring to that is a is like a special class of first class that only ridiculously dangerously rich people fly.
Rym: I experienced it once because of Lufthansa fucked up and they basically had to get me out of flight.
Rym: So they gave me that and I took a shower while I was flying home and it was amazing.
Scott: But there is no airline in the like.
Scott: no matter how rich you are in the US, if you want to take a shower on a US airline, you need a private jet.
Scott: You're not.
Scott: there's no US airline that you can buy a ticket to where you can take a shower.
Scott: It's just that level is just not there.
Rym: So though that level primarily only exists on international airlines that are propped by sovereign states as part of a kleptocratic regime of some kind.
Scott: Either that or so, so even if you're rich, if you're flying on that fancy airline, some other rich person is footing part of the bill.
Rym: Well, more like some of those airlines are prestige projects for governments.
Rym: Like you'll notice a lot of them are owned by their respective governments.
Scott: So they're not profiting.
Rym: Yeah, or that's what they're profiting, but in indirect and complicated.
Scott: So if I made a US based international airline and I tried to be as fancy as the fanciest planes on Earth and buy like the best possible planes with the people who would be the people who it wouldn't work is what you're saying.
Rym: The people who would be flying those tickets on your airline would be primarily at you don't want to stereotype here.
Rym: These would be oligarchs from a short list of countries.
Scott: Yeah, that's who would be flying.
Rym: And depending, you might be able to.
Rym: US has evil wealthy people, but they're not as wealthy is the thing.
Scott: They just all use private jets.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: There's a lot of complexity going on, but the end result of all this is not healthy.
Rym: Again, the economy is not great.
Rym: This race to the bottom of the fuck up.
Rym: Yeah, this race to the bottom.
Rym: You know, the two worst airlines that are upscale merging into one terrible airline that's not the biggest.
Rym: This is a symptom of the fact that nobody can afford anything.
Rym: And even just now.
Rym: I booked my flights to PAX last night and none of the flights are sold out with regular coach.
Rym: But Delta even offers now a shit tear where you don't get to pick your seat.
Rym: You can't check a bag every flight.
Rym: The shit tear is sold out.
Rym: That's all anyone can afford.
Scott: Well, also the price is going up.
Rym: Yeah, the fly the flights to PAX are about double what they were before covid.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, the demand is there.
Scott: People want to go places, right?
Scott: Clearly.
Scott: Otherwise, the shit tear wouldn't be sold out.
Scott: But the price is too high.
Scott: It's like, come on.
Scott: You know, it's like, bring the price down.
Scott: You know, that's the problem.
Rym: Capitalism drives that race to the bottom because the shit tear.
Rym: Those are cheap dollars to go after.
Scott: But I'm saying lower your prices on your other classes to fill those seats.
Rym: Now, why bother?
Rym: Someone will fly or sometimes there's tax reasons to not fill them.
Rym: They'll fill up later.
Rym: People who business travelers tend to buy tickets much closer to flight time.
Rym: So there's a lot of other factors going on.
Scott: That is an inherent problem.
Scott: I know, you know, that's just around.
Scott: our entire society is that there's.
Scott: there's too many benefits for people like having a storefront and not renting to anyone or or having empty seats or having a restaurant and throwing food out and not using all of going back to the HBO thing.
Rym: As part of that, Warner, they canceled a bunch of shows that were coming out, many of which were already like done with principal photography.
Rym: And they'll never release them now because they effectively make more money in terms of taxes by not releasing them than by releasing them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Any time that that's the case, we're like, you know, like basically wasting saves money.
Scott: We need to change.
Scott: Like I would say it should be whatever the system is to be illegal for Amazon to destroy unsold TV inventory.
Rym: They should have to sell them at a cut rate to the government and the government should be able to do whatever they want, including give them away for free to poor people.
Scott: Well, I don't know if it needs to be illegal.
Scott: I just think there needs to be like a waste penalty.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, oh, you know, you have a storefront and it's like, OK, you know, the rent is this, the property tax is this, you know, whatever.
Scott: But it's like you're not renting to anyone right now.
Scott: Well, it's like, are you completely like renovating it or something?
Scott: No, it's just sitting there empty more than a street baron.
Rym: Some more enlightened.
Scott: You have to pay for not having it rented out.
Scott: Some
Rym: more enlightened countries, obviously not the United States, do have laws around things like if you are the holder of an apartment or you own a townhouse or a condo in a major city and you don't live in it and you aren't renting it to someone else, you get charged extra taxes for life.
Scott: But it's like you have an airplane.
Scott: It's going to use all this jet fuel and harm the climate.
Rym: Those seats will fill up eventually.
Rym: It is, you know, a month and change before pack.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Scott: But it's like if you have an airplane and it's going to fly somewhere and do that much damage to the world, it better be full.
Scott: And if it's the airline should be penalized for empty seats, basically.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But simultaneously, airlines should be fucked the fuck over if they bump you nonconsensually from a flight you booked.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: So, yeah, one last little news.
Rym: We don't need to dwell on it because, frankly, just go watch the videos if you care.
Rym: But for those of you unaware, there is a fascist dipshit named Alex Jones, who is somewhat famous and infamous and terrifyingly has a huge fan following in the United States.
Scott: He's got some problems in his brain department.
Rym: He is a dangerous conspiratorial Nazi is.
Rym: those are some of the most charitable things I can say about this guy who causes a lot of harm.
Rym: One of the harms he perpetrated was after the Sandy Hook massacre, where autistic kids were murdered with guns in a school.
Rym: He, on his news quote news show, spent a lot of time claiming that the shootings were fake, that those kids weren't real and actually going after the parents of the dead kids, claiming that they were liars.
Rym: And of course, those parents sued for defamation and libel and slander and all sorts of emotional harm.
Rym: They're getting death threats from not just because he didn't.
Scott: he didn't necessarily commit a crime, or at least if he did, no prosecutor was going to do anything about it.
Rym: Well, the crimes he committed basically are boiling down to libel and slander.
Scott: Well, they may have committed crimes now.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there's a lot.
Scott: There's perjury is a crime.
Rym: So long story short, he eventually did eventually lose his lawsuit.
Rym: And you might be saying, lose his lawsuit.
Rym: But isn't the news that it's ongoing right now?
Rym: So here's the funny thing.
Rym: He lost the lawsuit by default at the start.
Rym: He was found guilty without the jury having to do anything because in the course of this ridiculously long trial, he never his lawyers and him never complied with discovery.
Rym: And eventually the judge issued a default ruling.
Rym: The trial was over.
Rym: All they're all they're deliberating is how much money he has to pay in punitive damages to the families he harms.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: And in the course of that trial, where all they're doing is figuring out how much money he owes, he has committed several additional crimes for which he will likely be prosecuted.
Rym: Some of them happened in the courtroom directly.
Rym: He threatened the lawyer of the parents.
Rym: He appears to have threatened the parents directly.
Rym: He committed so much perjury that you just got to watch some of those videos.
Rym: But the funniest thing that happened was this Phoenix Wright moment where he claimed he didn't have any text messages about Sandy Hook.
Rym: He never said anything about it.
Rym: Nothing on his phone.
Rym: The lawyer who's going after him was just showed him a whole bunch of his own text messages and you see him start to like squirm on the stand.
Rym: And they're like, do you recognize any of these?
Rym: He's like, no, I'm not a tech guy.
Rym: And they're like, would you believe that we have the contents of your entire fucking cell phone?
Rym: And he's like, what?
Rym: No, you don't.
Rym: And basically his lawyers accidentally sent the lawyers on the other side the entire contents of his cell phone, which he had claimed.
Scott: Even if I had a lawyer, I would not give my lawyer my phone.
Scott: I don't give your phone to anyone.
Scott: Not your lawyer, not the other person's lawyer, not the cops, not nobody.
Scott: But even worse, not your child, not your partner.
Rym: This data was dated that he testified under penalty of perjury did not exist and he did not have.
Rym: So now he's trying to.
Rym: now his lawyers tried to claw it back and saying you can't use that evidence against us.
Rym: And then the judge's response was basically, yeah, no, you're absolutely fucked.
Rym: And this is all on video and you can just watch it.
Rym: And it's only going to get better from here.
Scott: I do want to say this again, though, because it's I've seen a lot more recently, like I've been reading comments, just, you know, just not not on the specific topic, but people just casually online talking about like, oh, yeah, I was, you know, poking around my friend's phone or it's like what?
Rym: It's like, listen, though, we were out at dinner with our friends the other night and a Brando stranger needed help.
Rym: And one of our friends just handed them their cell phone to make a call.
Rym: I would never let someone touch my cell phone while it was unlocked, even in my presence.
Scott: Yeah, it's like absolutely under no circumstances.
Scott: If you have a smartphone, not just your smartphone, but your password to anything at all of any significance.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, your email, anything I don't care.
Scott: It could be, you know, your partner of 60 years.
Scott: You trust them with your entire life.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's there's no reason to distrust them in any way, shape or form.
Scott: Still, you do not tell them your password to anything.
Scott: You do not give them your phone.
Scott: You never touch anyone else's phone.
Scott: Absolutely not under any circumstance, not even in an emergency circumstance.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In an emergency, the phone has an emergency mode that they can use.
Rym: So even beyond that, I am not suggesting you commit crimes, but suppose you do.
Rym: If you're committing crimes, don't write text messages talking about the crimes.
Rym: Just don't.
Rym: There's a reason it was so hard to go after Al Capone back in the day because they didn't fucking write anything down.
Rym: Nobody wrote anything down.
Rym: And I saw an article.
Rym: This was on like CNN earlier this year.
Rym: And I think I just must have forgotten to use it on GeekNights.
Rym: But it was this mob guy doing an interview because he was like in jail and like he was going to get out soon and he was writing a book and he talked about how, yeah, young mobsters, they are stupid as shit.
Rym: They use their phones for everything and all the evidence is right there.
Rym: Like they're they're setting up slacks.
Rym: They're planning crimes in slacks.
Rym: And this is why they keep getting fingered.
Rym: And he's just like, these kids are fucked.
Rym: And it was really funny.
Rym: I got to find it again.
Rym: And we should use that as a thing of the day.
Scott: Oh, there is one more news, right?
Scott: After five years of K-pop news, right?
Scott: When it's enormous, enormous K-pop news.
Scott: After five years of waiting, right?
Scott: Girls Generation is coming back with an album, a full album from people who have people who have gone their separate ways and went to separate companies who come back single forever one.
Scott: No, it's a comeback entire album.
Scott: And, you know, as I said earlier, right, you know, K-pop people, you know, they love to make a lot of content and give it for free, right?
Scott: They basically, you know, they've been already been burying the world with free contents for like the past week.
Scott: And starting tomorrow, it's going to be like double buried.
Scott: Like there's like a whole schedule of like, we're releasing this then and this then and this then and ninety nine point nine percent of it is all free.
Scott: It's like, where does the money come from?
Scott: It's like, I guess, selling albums, streams.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: YouTube ads.
Rym: Well, I mean, the question of where does I mean, the question of where does money come from fundamentally is increasingly something that even in my professional job, I have difficulty actually saying, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: here's here's some examples of the contents that they've released from, you know, small stuff, right?
Scott: Like they had a photo shoot and they released a few photos each day, right?
Scott: A little tiny teaser video.
Scott: They have like these mood sampler videos, like we're not going to let you hear the album, but you know what?
Scott: We'll show you a short like one minute video to give you an idea of what the album feels like.
Scott: It's like a teaser for it out, you know, stuff like that.
Scott: Small stuff.
Scott: They have an entire like, you know, you said unscripted reality show like they've been doing in Korea for decades plus, right?
Scott: They just because they're coming back with an album, they produced a whole series like, you know, I don't know how many episodes it's going to be.
Scott: It's already up to like four or five of like hour plus long TV episodes of them.
Scott: just like we're in a house, you know, chilling, you know, whatever, right?
Scott: Just watching them waste time.
Scott: It's like, you know, well, we'll go to the beach.
Scott: Watch us go to the beach.
Scott: Yay, right?
Scott: An hour like that.
Scott: But just like, you know, they're just.
Scott: they're just burying everyone in in content right now.
Scott: And, you know, they've been.
Scott: it's you know, it's interesting in that, you know, we haven't seen, you know, K-pop groups, you know, even, you know, worldwide, right?
Scott: Boy bands, girl groups, whatever, right?
Scott: You know, teen pop stuff has always like come and gone, right?
Scott: Backstreet Boys.
Scott: I think they still they're somewhere, right?
Scott: I don't think they're broken up.
Rym: I have some name I haven't heard in a while.
Scott: I'm just saying like, you know, it's like.
Scott: maybe they do comebacks once in a while right here and there.
Scott: But it's like, you know, they're not like still a thing for real, right?
Rym: It's like they are still a thing for real.
Rym: The Backstreet Boys are still directly active.
Scott: Yeah, but they're not like, you know, making a huge splash with albums constantly, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, these groups, it's like they'll be like an like one more than one album per year, like constant releasing of new content in your face.
Scott: And then they get too old for that shit and they're done.
Scott: They go away.
Scott: You know, it's not like, you know, rock stars in the 70s who keep going until they're 100 years old.
Rym: Yeah, like if you ever go to Vegas, you'll see a lot of billboards where the first thing you will think is so-and-so is still alive.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And still working?
Scott: Why aren't they retired?
Rym: I'm still working.
Rym: I'm shocked.
Rym: they're alive.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But these girls' generation started, you know, 15 years ago, right?
Scott: When they were like in their late teens and now they're in their like early 30s, late 20s, and it's like, you know, how long are they going to go?
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: But they're going right now.
Scott: And it's pretty funny to see them next to like actual teenagers in the same, the same scene, you know?
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So speaking of HBO, my family, one of the, you know, we, we were, I was born in 1982 and our family got HBO.
Rym: Basically when it launched, we had this tiny little satellite dish and all it got was HBO.
Rym: And we would like the whole family would get together and watch movies on TV, which was a big deal back then.
Scott: And, you know, like we talked about, it used to be that you could only see a movie if you either went to a theater or rented a VHS tape, which even then was not like.
Rym: in the early eighties, VHS was not like a saturated market yet.
Scott: It was still coming in.
Rym: You know, like not everyone had had VCRs when I was a kid.
Scott: And what, you know, there weren't video rental places like maybe the mid or late eighties.
Rym: You know, I mean, we were going to video rental places, but we were going to the places that predated blockbuster video and predated like mammoth video.
Rym: I'm talking like a little shop that had a hundred VHS tapes and like 50 Betamax tapes and a weird old guy who would just like you to ask him, you basically ask him for like what kind of movie you wanted and he'd give you options and then you pick something.
Scott: I mean, we had Blockbuster didn't come to where we were.
Scott: Blockbuster, it says on the internet was founded in 85, but it wasn't.
Rym: It didn't open in our neighborhood till I think I remember when our mammoth video went under because the low blockbuster fucked it over.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like we had a tiny video place until then.
Scott: But it was, you know, like you said, a tiny video.
Rym: So one of the point is accent.
Scott: You couldn't just watch movies whenever the hell you wanted.
Scott: Even if you were pirating or whatever, it was an event to see a movie.
Scott: If a movie was on television, that was a big deal because it was rare.
Rym: I remember when they showed Alice in Wonderland, the Disney animated feature on TV as a big premiere, like one week night at prime time with ads and cut to shit.
Rym: And the next day, literally everyone in the elementary school had watched it the previous night, every single person, every teacher, every kid, everyone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Sometimes if something was really special on TV, right, that you like, you would never going to see again, you would get a blank VHS just to record.
Rym: Sometimes we recorded everything.
Scott: When the hell are you going to see that again?
Rym: So, uh, HBO.
Rym: My thing of the day is that they had their, their, uh, basically the eye catch or the sonic ID.
Rym: they'd like, Hey, you're about to watch a thing on HBO that they would show right before a movie started.
Scott: And same thing.
Scott: You know, everyone does that, right?
Scott: Like, you know, Cartoon Network has the thing at the end of the show where like, you know, the logo is there and it goes boing, boing, you know, and, uh, who else has one?
Rym: So I had watched, well, kind of like, uh, THX noise, right?
Rym: Or you watch it, you watch a certain movies animated in Japan and the, this is going to be a very good movie.
Rym: logo and icon and crashing waves.
Scott: College Schumer had the, had the, huh?
Scott: So, uh, I really want a GeekNights, one of those, but I can't find anyone to make one.
Rym: I can hire someone to make one.
Rym: We got, we got some money laying around.
Scott: I thought we spent most of the monies.
Rym: No, we still have plenty of GeekNights, money laying around.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Well then I'll spend more then.
Rym: Ah, absolutely can.
Rym: Let me know what you want to spend it on.
Rym: Just send me invoices.
Rym: We'll chat anyway.
Rym: So find somebody to make a, a Sonic before any of you get any, uh, GeekNights is technically profitable, but assuming Scott and I are not paid for our labor.
Rym: So just to give you a sense of GeekNights is not profitable if we are paid for our labor.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: HBO appears to have had four, maybe five, looks like four such openings in its history.
Rym: And I have actually only ever seen two of them, the 1982 one.
Rym: And then in 1983, they made their most iconic one, which if you watch this, it might not seem that impressive.
Rym: Uh, go look at what it took to make CG and special effects in the year 1983.
Rym: And this is actually pretty fucking impressive.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And as a kid, this was the holy shit.
Rym: We are about to watch a movie thing.
Rym: Like I watched this again, the HBO intro from 1983.
Rym: And, uh, I got this weird nostalgic excitement in the back of my brain.
Rym: I felt like a kid again, about to sit down and watch a movie, uh, which in the pre-internet era was, uh, a peak experience.
Scott: So what do you got?
Scott: So, uh, all nerds, right?
Scott: You know, you know, someone like me nerd, I just curious about anything that I don't know, right?
Scott: Anything that's a mystery.
Scott: I have a curiosity for it, right?
Scott: Even if I don't have an actual interest in it, it's just like, it's a land of mystery.
Scott: I got to know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And one of those things is obviously something that I think everyone who's a nerd finds fascinating, which is the power grid, right?
Scott: You've all around us is this electricity that we need to maintain our, you know, society for however long we can make it last.
Scott: And we see all this equipment around, right?
Scott: Like this in, in our neighborhoods everywhere.
Scott: And 90%, 99% of people have no idea what the fuck that shit is.
Scott: It's just shit.
Scott: They don't touch invisible.
Rym: Most people, like they don't even see it.
Rym: It's just like background.
Scott: Yeah, you either don't see it or you do see it, but you don't know what it is and you don't care.
Rym: Maybe you run into it because you got an umbrella in front of your face and you're walking at speed down a sidewalk.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: You know, but it's like, you know, something happens and people, you know, something happens wrong with it.
Scott: People like, ah, it's broken, fix it.
Scott: But it's like, well, you know, there's these big buckets up on the pole.
Scott: What are those buckets even do?
Scott: Why are they buckets?
Rym: What, you know, those are transformers filled with coils and oil.
Scott: Yeah, we know.
Scott: I know what they are.
Rym: I mean, I know what all this shit is, but I'm weird about the electric grid.
Scott: Yeah, we watch YouTube.
Scott: So if you wonder what some of this shit is, I actually found an amazing YouTube channel, There's this dude.
Scott: He's Canadian.
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: It's Bob's Decline, lineman blogger.
Scott: So this dude is a professional lineman.
Scott: His job is to go out and mess with all the dangerous power grid.
Scott: shit, right?
Scott: You know, repair it, maintain it, check on it that you're never going to go near or look at in your whole life.
Scott: And he is just showing you fucking everything.
Scott: He's like, this is what it is.
Scott: This is how it works.
Scott: This is what it's for.
Scott: He has all the parts of it.
Scott: It's like, I feel like if you watched all his videos, you it's like, and then you obviously should go to actual training before you try to do the job.
Rym: You know, there's a training yard for that right near our apartment.
Rym: Like they have fake houses and all this shit just there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like it would kind of half mostly prepare you for the job.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you watched all his videos and then went to get the actual training, it would probably be like a breeze because you would be hearing shit you've already known.
Scott: So in this one particular video, even though he's got a lot of cool ones, uh, he's got what's known as like a pad mounted transformer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So most of the transformers, you know, that we see in everyday life are those bucket ones.
Scott: But there's also ones that are pad mounted, which means there's a pad of concrete and it's just sitting on the ground.
Rym: You know, those green, those green metal boxes that don't have any signs on them other than stay away that you never touched, like, you know, in the front yard of a suburban house.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And it's like, Hey, it's a box.
Scott: It's not a bucket.
Scott: How is it doing the same thing as the bucket?
Scott: Well, you know, it's, it's taking the voltage that's, you know, ridiculously high voltage from the power lines and decreasing it to a lower voltage, the kind your house needs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And how does it work?
Scott: Well, he's going to open it up and show you in this video, right?
Scott: All the mysteries of inside the green box are now revealed.
Scott: It's now really boring.
Scott: Green box.
Rym: When I was in middle school, there was, we actually had one of these in the easement in our front yard and we'd kind of play on it.
Rym: Like it was just part of our, cause we couldn't get into it.
Rym: They're not dangerous unless something has gone horribly wrong.
Rym: Unless you go, go inside them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Just don't open it and you'll probably, you'll be all right.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And uh, when I was going near it, it's probably, it's not the greatest idea either.
Scott: It's not like, you know, as an adult, it's not that risky, but it's not necessary either.
Rym: Like I might like, I would consider if there wasn't anything else around sitting on one, like waiting for a bus, but uh, that's about the extent of it.
Rym: Don't get a piece of metal and try to wedge it into the door.
Rym: You don't say in the meta moment, the GeekNights book club book is Binti.
Rym: We will do the show two weeks from now.
Rym: Cause this book will not take you more than an hour to read.
Rym: It's a novella.
Rym: Just read it.
Rym: Space College.
Rym: We'll do a show on it.
Scott: And then Scott, uh, I think, did you update the old current GeekNights' website with the book club selection?
Rym: Of course I did.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: It's right there right now.
Rym: In fact, I've got it up on the live stream for everyone to see.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I also linked the episode we just did on non Fox gambit, uh, to the book club, uh, note on the website.
Rym: And I will tell all of you, the listener, I did read the rest of the books in the, after nine Fox gambit.
Rym: And all I will say is that there's three, there's three in total.
Rym: There's three in total.
Scott: They're a complete trilogy.
Scott: or is there good stuff?
Scott: There's not going to be any more.
Scott: There's a, there's a fourth book.
Rym: That's just a bunch of unrelated short stories set in that universe.
Scott: But those three people love to do that shit these days.
Rym: Tell a complete.
Rym: even E and M banks did a bunch of that.
Rym: And they're pretty good.
Rym: But those three books tell a complete contiguous story.
Rym: It ends in an absolutely satisfying way.
Rym: I have no complaints.
Rym: I love the shit out of them.
Rym: The second and third books are even better than the first one.
Rym: Uh, a lot of interesting things happen.
Rym: Uh, you learn some things about the moths, you learn some stuff about Judeo and what his real deal was.
Rym: Uh, those books are about democracy and revolution and how you design a society and where the hard work is.
Scott: We knew that from book one.
Rym: But book one barely scratches the tiniest edge of a tangent to the surface of that topic compared to the second and third books.
Rym: And also I will say in the third book, uh, basically you find out what, what piece of technology in that universe is actually the Evangelions, uh, among other things.
Rym: I absolutely recommend if you like Ninefox Gambit, read the other two books.
Rym: They are fantastic.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: And, uh, some of, some of the listener disagreed.
Rym: Yeah, I don't understand.
Rym: Cause the first book is actually less compelling to me than the second two because the second two are also way more relevant to the year 2022 in the real world and the kinds of problems we're going to face as a society.
Rym: Uh, anyway, uh, I will be at PAX West on Sunday, September 4th, 1230 PM Pacific time in the.
Scott: I'm still not getting on a plane to go anywhere.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And it looks like Magfest announced dates on time or otherwise.
Rym: There's a decent chance I will go to Magfest to do some panels, but, uh, it'll, it looks like they announced it'll still be a mass event.
Rym: We'll see how COVID goes.
Rym: I can't imagine I would go to Magfest to do anything other than do some panels and otherwise mostly avoid the crowds and the con, but, uh, stay tuned.
Rym: Same with PAX Unplugged.
Rym: We'll see what happens.
Rym: I guess we can get right into it.
Rym: Vending machines, a fantastic suggestion from the listener.
Rym: Uh, the one thing we're not going to do is cover the history of vending machines because I literally know nothing other than what I just read on Wikipedia right before I called Scott to do the show.
Rym: I pretty much only know about the modern era of vending machines.
Scott: So anything I don't know the specific history of vending machines, but the one, the only thing I do know historically is that, you know, when the vending machine was introduced, it was sort of like a wow deal, right?
Scott: Like, you know, Holy crap, you're selling things without people, right?
Scott: You had like the automats and things of that nature, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you could collect coin operated vending machines, go back to 1615.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's farther back than I thought.
Rym: And there is, there are multiple accounts of one in first century, Roman, Egypt.
Rym: It would accept a coin.
Rym: And if the, and based on the way to the coin, it would dispense Holy water from a fountain for a certain amount of time.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I was thinking, you know, like slot machines were.
Rym: so I was, I was thinking what 1800s, maybe like one weird thing.
Rym: And then I come to Wikipedia and it's like 1615.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Also 100.
Scott: I was thinking like, you know, slot machine would be like some of the oldest kind of sort of vending machine, right?
Scott: Just a coin operated mechanical machine.
Rym: There's a photo in the Wikipedia article of a stamp and postcard vending machine from Japan from 1904.
Scott: No, Japan loves the vending machine.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: So, um, I guess I mostly want to talk about vending machines on a high level in terms of, you know, my anecdotes, interactions, what purpose they serve in society.
Rym: Cause, uh, vending machines used to be way more important to me when I was a kid who didn't really have my own money or my own way to get around except biking.
Rym: So really the only things I could buy were things that my parents bought when I was in their presence for me or things I could get with like the quarters in my pocket when I was unattended.
Rym: So like going to school, there was one vending machine that had soda and it was an area students weren't supposed to go.
Rym: And I would sneak back there to like get a can of Dr Pepper with.
Scott: our schools just had vending machines.
Scott: Like these are here to get money out of you kids.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: Our school had all the schools I went to all the way, even through high school had rules.
Rym: The vending machines were not allowed to be on during school hours.
Rym: They were only on outside of school hours.
Rym: And in middle school, they weren't allowed to have allowed to have soda pop in high school.
Scott: My first year of high school, the high school was a Pepsi high school and all had all Pepsi vending machines.
Scott: And then they signed a deal, right?
Scott: It's a public high school.
Scott: They signed a deal with Coke to buy like a new scoreboard for the football field or some shit.
Scott: Obviously this is a bad deal.
Scott: It's like it was a good deal for Coke and a bad one for the school, but they did it because they're, you know, whatever capitalism, I don't know.
Scott: But Coke replaced all the vending machines and all the Pepsi vending machines in the school with different ones.
Scott: And then when a surge came out, it was like there was surge all over the school because they filled the vending machines with surge.
Rym: Yeah, basically no school I went to at any point had vending machines for soda pop that were accessible to the kids.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: I remember now the surge was all over the school.
Scott: Surge is the Pepsi drink.
Scott: It was everywhere at school.
Scott: And then when Coke came in, all the surge was gone.
Scott: That's what happened.
Rym: But the other place I remember vending machines in my childhood being very prominent were specifically when we went to amusement parks like Cedar Point, because I remember one year all these vending machines appeared all over the park and it was like Pepsi branded deal.
Rym: And those vending machines were way expensive, but they were way cheaper than getting soda pop from the fountains at the actual like restaurant stalls.
Rym: And as a result, our family would like get 20 ounce things a pop from the vending machines before we got in line for rides.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's you know, I think also when I was a kid, it's like there were only basically three kinds of vending machines.
Scott: There was the snack one with the coils.
Scott: You still see those around.
Scott: And the coil spins in the food and there's different snacks to choose from.
Rym: We got some anecdotes from RIT about those.
Scott: The big ones are at the bottom.
Scott: You had the soda can one, which got later got upgraded later in life to the bottle one, like in the in the late 90s.
Rym: Yeah, right around when Americans as they kept drinking more and more soda, we went from the 12 ounce can being the default to the 20 ounce being the default.
Scott: And the third kind of vending machine that thankfully is no more, at least not in the US, was the cigarette vending machine.
Rym: I remember there was a cigarette vending machine in every fucking restaurant I went to as a kid.
Scott: There was a fucking restaurant had one of those things and now they're all gone because they had a particular shape.
Rym: They worked differently from the other vending machines.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It was like a plunger or some shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I remember as a kid, I was always I didn't know how to use one.
Scott: I never used one myself.
Rym: Well, that same plunger mechanism is what most laundromats use, but I never encountered a laundromat in my life until college.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So those are like the three kinds.
Scott: But then I guess in the 2000s and going forward, right, I guess other countries.
Rym: Well, there were things we didn't think of as vending machines that maybe don't count here.
Rym: Like I wouldn't say the thing you used to pay for parking in a parking garage counts.
Rym: That's a different even though it's there's no person to be a vending machine.
Scott: It's you had to put money in some kind of payment mechanism and then it has to dispense a good, right?
Scott: Not a service or an actual good has to be in the machine and the machine dispenses the good to you.
Scott: Like, here you go.
Scott: It's like you're paying for parking or an ATM.
Scott: An ATM is not a vending machine.
Rym: I guess I'd follow that.
Scott: You're not buying the money.
Rym: So then the other vending machines I knew about as a kid were and these are gone now newspaper vending machines.
Scott: I would often throw a quarter into a newspaper vending machine, open a door and on your good faith, you don't take all the newspapers.
Rym: And weirdly, very rarely did someone just open it for a quarter and take all the newspapers because what are you going to do?
Rym: Sell them?
Scott: Like, yeah, they're not worth anything tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, but I also remember as a kid, those cigarette vending machines bother me because I hated cigarettes.
Rym: I hated cigarette smoke.
Rym: And I just remember asking my mom when I was really young, how do they check that you're an adult if you use the cigarette vending machine?
Rym: And my answer was they don't.
Rym: They should be banned.
Rym: And I was like, oh, that's right.
Scott: That's why they were bad eventually.
Scott: Oh, there was.
Scott: actually there was another kind of vending machine that I forgot about, which is the because, you know, they're different shape and size, which is the candy and toy kinds, right?
Scott: Where you put the corduroy in, you turn it and then either you gumball, basically gumball machine.
Scott: But, you know, then you got toys and balls, right?
Scott: Which I guess in other countries are much better than the ones we have.
Scott: We have really crappy ones.
Rym: I remember we would get a homie every other time we went to Wegmans at RIT.
Scott: Homies were a thing.
Scott: Yeah, I guess the homies didn't make enough money to carry on.
Rym: as a kid.
Rym: I was really into garbage here.
Rym: Candy from candy vending machines.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: Kid brain.
Scott: Yeah, no, I was not a fan of the vending.
Scott: Like when I saw the candy vending machine that had like especially the one with like all the sort of different fruit, like the bananas and that was disgusting.
Rym: That was the worst possible candy.
Scott: It's like I never ate it and I never had a desire to eat it like, you know, one gumball right.
Scott: Well, the ones I would get, for whatever reason.
Rym: as a kid, I like chiclets a lot.
Rym: So I would get chiclets out of the chiclet vending machine like all the time.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I would just buy chiclets in a package of chiclets.
Rym: Now I go to the vending machine, you pop a quarter in and a handful of chiclets would come out.
Scott: I would not do that.
Scott: That is what I did.
Scott: I would buy chiclets in the checkout aisle.
Rym: I mean, I was doing this like when I was like at the DMV with my parents.
Rym: So I guess the Secretary of State, because it was Michigan, there'd be a chiclet vending machine and I would go get some chiclets.
Rym: Like that was the thing.
Rym: So college is when vending machines actually became weirdly more important to me, which was partly that was the first time in our lives.
Rym: we were just completely independent, like just completely out of our own recognizance.
Rym: So we'd often stay out late.
Rym: And you know, RIT is not in Rochester.
Rym: It's actually in this small town called Henrietta.
Rym: So if it's after midnight there, especially back then when we were there, the campus is a lot bigger and more happening now.
Rym: There was nothing.
Rym: If you were hungry, if you were thirsty, there was no possible way to get anything unless you were willing to order a Papa John's pizza.
Rym: They delivered until 2
Rym: a.m.,
Rym: right?
Scott: Or you had a car and you could go to Wegmans.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So as a result, you weren't going to walk to Wegmans.
Rym: Also, I was deeply poor in college, so I had a lot of food just directly out of vending machines.
Scott: Also, RIT, we had these cards, right, with like college money, you know, which is now.
Scott: everyone has Apple Pay or, you know, whatnot.
Scott: But back in those days, that wasn't a thing, really.
Rym: Here, buy some Michigan Scratchy dollars.
Rym: They're just less useful than regular dollars, but you didn't pay for them directly.
Rym: They kind of came out of your student loan.
Rym: You're probably paying interest on that shit, but don't think about it.
Scott: Yeah, but RIT, it's like every student just had like this digital money on their student ID and they could swipe it and buy things right at food places and other places around campus.
Scott: So, you know, it's like sort of ahead of its time, but it was a closed network, right?
Scott: That money wasn't good anywhere else, really.
Rym: Yeah, but I many times was hungry enough to basically assemble a meal via a couple of vending machines.
Rym: And once I left college, honestly, I don't use vending machines at all for anything ever.
Scott: I use them on rare occasion, right?
Rym: They're a tool of desperation.
Scott: But yeah, I can say they're also positioned.
Scott: They're intentionally positioned for desperation, right?
Scott: It's like nobody puts, you know, a vending machine in a place where there's like a bunch of stores right there.
Scott: It's like, you know, why would I do that?
Scott: Just go with that.
Rym: But I see vending machines like that all the time.
Rym: Especially outside of the US, like fancy train station with fantastic food in London.
Rym: There will be a wall of vending machines that just has shittier food.
Rym: That's not actually cheaper.
Scott: No, I don't know why I see vending machines.
Scott: The most is places that are like inconveniently far from other places.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So like a truck stop, a rest stop that doesn't have an indoor area on a highway or like, you know, a motel, right?
Scott: The motel doesn't have food or the kitchen or the kitchen that it has isn't open all the time and the nearest food is like not close.
Rym: You just gave me a flashback to being a kid and sneaking out of our hotel room at Cedar Point in the middle of the night because I was hungry, finding a vending machine on the floor next to the ice machine and getting a bunch of snacks without my parents permission.
Rym: My mom is watching the stream right now, so now she knows.
Scott: It's like they'll have a vending machine there and it's like, there you go.
Scott: Now you have if you really need a food or a water or whatever it is, it's like it is available for you to buy money.
Rym: What I'm noticing is interesting for myself.
Rym: Just talking through this is that with other ways to avoid talking to a person like I don't need to talk to a human to buy groceries.
Rym: So I like just ordering stuff online.
Rym: But with vending machines, it's actually not.
Rym: I'm trying to avoid interacting with a human.
Rym: It's more I am desperate and vending machines are a tool that can exist in desperate places.
Scott: Yeah, I need a thing.
Scott: I'm in a I need the thing now and I'm in a place and the place I am in is far away from anywhere that I could conveniently acquire the thing the normal way of acquiring it.
Scott: And here it is right here.
Scott: It's just in a box and I can make it spit out the thing if I either hack the box, break the box open or put money in.
Rym: The last two times I tried to use a vending machine in any capacity, both failed and they were both at a PAX East.
Rym: The PAX East before Covid and the PAX East before the PAX East before Covid at both of those faxes.
Rym: I have clear memories of we're playing games in tabletop.
Rym: I'm really thirsty.
Rym: I didn't have a water bottle with me or I'm tired.
Rym: I wanted some sugar and I instead of walking all the way out of the convention center, I walked all the way to the edge near the bathroom.
Rym: So there's vending machines were just to get something, some sort of energy drink, don't even care what.
Rym: And every one of them was nonfunctional or out of beverages.
Rym: And I failed and I walked back empty handed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, so places I've used or attempted to use vending machines in recent memory at the top of Bear Mountain, right?
Scott: There's a vending machine up there.
Rym: I know exactly what vending machine you're talking about.
Scott: I think there's just vending machines up there on the top of this mountain.
Scott: There's no commerce.
Scott: What to speak of?
Scott: You're on the top of a mountain.
Scott: The closest place you could get any food or water is, I guess there's bathrooms up there, but it's like there is a trail that goes down to go all the way back down the mountain.
Scott: So there's a trail you can hike down.
Rym: It's an extremely steep trail, but it goes straight down the mountain and it ends near a small town that does have some restaurants.
Rym: Not going to help you on a bike, though.
Rym: It's not even mountain bike.
Scott: Or like you go to the town park, right?
Scott: It's like it could be a big ass part.
Scott: And it's like everyone's hanging out there in the middle of a grassy field.
Scott: It's like, oh, we didn't bring food with us or I forgot a food or whatever.
Scott: Or I'm only here for a short.
Scott: I'm walking through, but it's like this, you know, there's no restaurant in the middle of the park or the, you know, the other thing is that like a vending machine doesn't just extend over distance.
Scott: It also extends over time, right?
Scott: So consider a place where, you know, you know, hey, there's this road, right?
Scott: It's like if you tried to open up a restaurant on that road, it's like you need a certain number of customers per day to stay in business with the restaurant, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The vending machine, even if it might take a year for the vending machine to sell out, but it's like it doesn't fucking matter.
Rym: The only thing you're racing against is the expiration dates of the things in there, which reminds me, I remember as if you even care about that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's like if you're desperate, you're at a vending machine, you're already in a desperation mode, right?
Scott: It's like the cost to maintain the vending machine and the electricity is like, it's like the cost is so low.
Scott: It's like, yeah, you probably don't want to put one in somewhere where you're only refilling it once a year, but the, you can put it in a place with a lot less foot traffic.
Scott: And in fact, that's the better place you're going to want to put it right.
Scott: Enough foot traffic, but not too much because if it's a place with a lot of foot traffic, people don't use the vending machine.
Scott: They use something else instead.
Scott: We also do
Rym: have the privilege of having enough money to like, we are now we're rarely in the situations where we would even need a vending machine, but
Scott: you can make goods and serve goods available in a place where it would be otherwise unfeasible commercially to make those goods available because the population is too low.
Rym: Some of them are also basically lottery tickets for the people who own them or ads.
Rym: Like in airports, there's the vending machines like, Hey, Xbox 360 here, 300 bucks.
Rym: Swipe your credit card.
Rym: Like those exist.
Rym: Those are usually just silly.
Rym: But also if even one person buys one, but, uh, yeah, in terms of like, I really don't try to imagine when I would use a vending machine again, because especially the one use that I have is desperation at packs and they actually failed me.
Scott: I think the one, the other time I might use one.
Scott: besides, you know, the remote location scenario, uh, is the special location scenario.
Scott: Right?
Rym: So let's say, like captive audience in a shitty airport already behind security.
Rym: And that's the only thing.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Scott: So like in an airport, for example, right.
Scott: You do see those like, uh, vending machines that have like small electronics in them.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And it's like, if my etymotic died and I was on a long trip, I would consider just getting some sort of noise canceling headphone from that vending machine.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But another, another scenario, right?
Scott: You go to a bowling alley and they have a vending machine.
Scott: It's the spirally one, the normal, but instead of snacks, it's filled up with bowling specific needs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if you're bowling a lot, you're going to use that vending machine at least once sometime, you know, you go to, uh, don't really have that skiers or it's just have like staffed places.
Scott: Yeah, but laundromats, they have one that spits out detergents.
Scott: And other things, you know, dryer sheets, things of that nature.
Rym: Yeah, but you're being rough because I have never seen a laundromat detergent dispenser that had any type of detergent I would consider using on my own clothes.
Scott: I mean, sure, but yeah.
Rym: But also, like I said, I literally never saw a laundromat in person until I went to college.
Scott: No, I mean, I saw them.
Rym: I saw them on TV.
Rym: I didn't, I saw them on Seinfeld and in movies, but in real life.
Scott: A few times, like if we had to watch something really big or whatever, but you know, or the washing machine was broken.
Rym: And then I guess in RIT, we had the washer, but not the dryer.
Scott: Well, you mean in college, a beacon.
Rym: In RIT, I had, I barely had enough money to use the washing machines, which was its own problem.
Scott: But the point is, is that there are, there are certain kinds of businesses that will take some of their products, right.
Scott: And put them into a vending machine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So like I've seen, for example, like nerdy stores will put all of their like collectible cards into a vending machine.
Scott: So it's like, yeah, you know, everything else that we sell, right.
Scott: You know, board games, paintball guns, whatever.
Scott: We just sell normally.
Scott: But if you want to buy Pokmon cards, they're in the vending machine.
Rym: Partly because now your cashier doesn't have to deal with the punk kids.
Rym: They'll just deal with it on their own.
Rym: So it basically reduces your labor because the kids are going to buy the same number of Pokmon cards no matter how they do it.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Rym: Though I will say outside, like in the US, most vending machines are pretty shady.
Scott: Like part of it is a weed vending machines.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I've seen, I've also seen some vending machines that I think were forgotten, especially mechanical vending machines.
Rym: I remember several years ago, I encountered in the city, in the lobby of a building, a vending machine that had gumballs in it that looked like they had all faded to white over decades of sunlight.
Rym: Completely mechanical.
Rym: I am confident that vending machine is forgotten and woe betide anyone who puts anything in that vending machine in their mouth.
Rym: I think that was enough of an excuse to have a main bit for a show.
Rym: We can stop right there.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Link Egee, Dre, Lily Terrebray, a bunch of people who rarely don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Chris the Dog, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Kishaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Review Madbull34cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin von Horl, Stop All the Downloading, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Wilson, Wilson Station and several people whose names I will not say.
Rym: I will say that as much as unscripted content is probably going to destroy the ecosystem.
Rym: just like 90s reality TV destroyed TV, I also think that Taskmaster, which is an unscripted show, is actually pretty funny and I do watch it on occasion.
Rym: So make of that what you will.
Rym: But for now, I simply leave you with... This is where I make potato canishes.
Rym: The magic and the mystery of potato canishes.
Rym: Little black squash balls.
Rym: This machine creates little black squash balls.
Rym: It means potato pancakes.
Rym: Little black squash balls.
Rym: This is where I make centipedes.
Rym: I sure love to make centipedes.
Rym: I turn little black worms into centipedes.