Rym: It's Monday, August 8th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about vacuum cleaners.
Rym: Be sure to submit your show ideas to community.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Alright, so you know we like to get the food boxes, you know, to reduce, you know, so we can still cook, but reduce food effort, right?
Scott: And even though it's expensive, it's cheaper than ordering and whatnot, right?
Rym: Yeah, I think we're gonna stick with like purple carrot, like the two boxes a week, and mostly shut down the rest of them.
Scott: Anyway, the point is, is that one thing that those boxes do well, we've talked about, is they only give you, right, the exact amount of ingredients, so there's a lot less food waste, right?
Rym: Yeah, like, "Oh, you need something weird, like a demi-glace.
Rym: Here is just like, here is a little container.
Rym: that is exactly what you
Rym: need.".
Scott: Right, so, but, you know, they include ingredients, right, that aren't usually sometimes in the grocery store.
Scott: For example, they'll include like a spice mix, and it's like, you could try to recreate the spice mix, but that's their spice mix, you'll never be exactly right.
Scott: I guess that's fine a lot of times, right?
Rym: Yeah, I've never had a spice mix.
Scott: If it says Mexican spice mix, it's like, "Just do a chili powder based spice mix, you'll be
Scott: alright.".
Rym: Yeah, there's never been a food box that came where the spice mix was so notable that I had to recreate it.
Scott: Exactly, but sometimes they do include a rare or somewhat difficult to get ingredient, right, period.
Scott: You know, and living in New York City, that's obviously the case less often.
Scott: The groceries here have all kinds of fucking shit from all over the world, and very few things are difficult to find.
Scott: But, you know, I went and I picked out a food box recipe to go and redo, right?
Rym: Yeah, I've done that a few times, it usually works out really well.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: And one of the ingredients was indeed what Rym just pronounced incorrectly that I don't blame him for, because I also did not know how to pronounce "dumiglas," right?
Scott: It is French, obviously, right?
Scott: And basically, if you don't know what that is, it's sort of like you take stock and you take some wine, maybe, and you reduce that shit, but you don't reduce it to where it's thick, but it's obviously thicker than just watery stock, they call it.
Scott: And it's directly translated, it means "half glaze," right?
Scott: It's like you reduce stock halfway to being glazed.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it's basically it's in the family of what, like browns, like brown sauces, like there's different kinds of sauces.
Rym: It's orthogonally adjacent, it's in the class gravy in my brain.
Scott: And you could use different stocks, right?
Scott: Veal, beef, chicken, whatever, right?
Scott: But anyway, mushroom, whatever.
Scott: So I needed some for this recipe, but I need two fucking tablespoons.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: That's all I need.
Rym: I would say, unless this was an ultra-fancy recipe, I would just use some like thick stock instead.
Rym: I wouldn't even bother.
Scott: Right, but it's like, you'd have to still get some stock.
Scott: And like, I saw a recipe for it.
Rym: Oh, put a balloon cube in a cup of hot water, mix it up, reduce it a little bit, you're good to go.
Scott: No, they're like, they're like, "Oh, you want to make some?
Scott: Easy peasy, reduce it for 16
Scott: hours.".
Scott: And I'm like, "16 hours to get one minor
Scott: ingredient?".
Scott: It's like, I could probably just cook the dish without that ingredient.
Scott: It'd probably be fine.
Rym: That's basically what I would do.
Scott: But you know, I'm like, you know what?
Scott: Might as well go and look and see if I can just buy it in the grocery, because our groceries got all kinds of shit in them.
Scott: Let me see.
Rym: I wonder if Fresh Direct has it.
Rym: I bet not.
Rym: Hopefully we'll see.
Rym: I've been surprised by Fresh Direct before.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't look it there, but it's possible.
Scott: But yeah, I looked all the fuck over for it.
Scott: And it was not in like three different groceries.
Rym: Fresh Direct does not have it.
Scott: Despite being in New York City, it's not here.
Scott: So I heard some rumors it might be at Wegman or Whole Foods, but Costco is literally a block away.
Scott: But I don't have a membership, but I'm not paying a whole membership to get two tablespoons of liquid.
Scott: But maybe I'll check Wegman or Whole Foods, right?
Rym: Just, you know, maybe not.
Rym: Maybe it's an excuse to go to that Wegman anyway, which I've still never actually been inside of.
Scott: All I'm saying is like, you know, what's up with the grocery stores having every ingredient in the known universe, including stuff way weirder than dummy glass and not having it.
Scott: It's like, come on.
Rym: Of course, the alternative is outside of the city.
Rym: Like, you know, when you used to live upstate, there'll be the mega grocery store that has everything basic in the world.
Rym: But usually those don't have any of this kind of stuff either.
Scott: They don't have any.
Scott: Yeah, they have everything basic and nothing not basic.
Scott: Whereas here we have basic and not basic, but just not this other thing, right?
Rym: I wonder if it just doesn't keep well, or it's like not easy to, like there's probably a reason why it's not easy to just buy.
Scott: I mean, there was the time where I needed Lyle's Golden Syrup, which is a very UK ingredient.
Rym: I've used that to make cookies before.
Scott: But there was a UK specialty, you know, grocer in the Manhattan that I just went and walked over to from work.
Scott: During a time when I was still working in Manhattan, and I just picked some up, no problem.
Scott: But I don't know what specialty grocer is.
Scott: Is there, maybe I have to find a French specialty grocer?
Scott: Will they even have it?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, either they'll have it.
Scott: If anyone knows where to get it without making it.
Rym: I have a theory.
Rym: This is more like a supposition.
Rym: Possibly the specialty store for French cuisine would tell someone like us, "Why would you buy it?
Rym: Make it or go
Rym: home.".
Rym: I can see that happening.
Rym: Though, and some other, at least it's weird for something reasonably good to happen in American politics lately.
Rym: But that big bill, which actually kind of is almost a tech news, the big infrastructure inflation reduction bill, it actually passed.
Rym: And it has a few things that are actually going to be pretty good for the US technology sector around like, it's obviously not a perfect bill.
Rym: It's missing a lot.
Rym: I can get into that in a second, but it is going to...
Scott: Everything is missing a lot.
Rym: Yeah, but it is going to force...
Scott: If something happened that wasn't missing a lot, we'd be like,
Scott: "Whoa!".
Rym: But it does have some stuff around.
Rym: Basically, electric cars, to qualify for all these credits and things, will basically have to remove China from their production pipelines and supply chains for their batteries, which will probably be very good for the entire global battery ecosystem, which will itself be very good for the future of electrification and the reduction of fossil fuels.
Scott: Sure, but the fundamental thing is that electric cars won't save us.
Scott: Only less cars will save us.
Rym: Oh, no, but at least electric...
Scott: The switching over to electric cars is sort of like a...
Rym: It is a transition, just like nuclear power is a transition, just to get us off of the even more egregious problems.
Scott: I mean, common logic suggests that that would work, right?
Scott: It's like, "Ah, yes, just switch the electric car, then...".
Scott: But it's like, in reality, switching to the electric car is probably just not going to be good enough.
Rym: Switching to the electric car will, in theory, it will not fix all the other externalities of cars that we both know about.
Rym: But just in terms of climate change, it will, at best, not make particulate pollution worse, but more likely it'll cause more particulate pollution than current cars.
Rym: Because electric cars are heavier, they generate more particulates, which mostly come from diesel, which we're also getting rid of, or tires.
Rym: But...
Scott: They still have tires.
Scott: Tires are the...
Rym: But they will definitely, and there's a lot of studies, I've seen that back this up, reduce CO2 emissions because of the economy of scale of electricity generation.
Scott: Well, not if you're just burning the fossil fuels somewhere else.
Rym: Actually, yes, because burning the fossil fuels in large power plants generate way less CO2 per unit burned than poorly maintained machines distributed across the entire country.
Scott: We'll have to do the math on that.
Scott: There's a lot of studies that say that.
Scott: You lose a lot of power in transmission, too, right?
Scott: And then you lose power when charging up the batteries.
Rym: Yeah, but the economy of scale of scrubbers...
Scott: If you burn the fuel right there in the engine, it's like, yeah, okay, maybe less...
Rym: Because the fuel is heavy, and transporting the fuel to then be distributed is way worse than transporting the batteries.
Rym: But mining batteries sucks shit, at least currently.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know what doesn't cause any of these problems at all?
Scott: Is any vehicle that's not a car.
Scott: Anything that doesn't have a motor.
Rym: But way back when we were talking about how, like, nothing can change in the US, you know, that whole... Skateboard.
Rym: Because, you know, since basically 1992, our government's been paralyzed by the Senate filibuster.
Rym: What's interesting is you had actually asked a question on the show that derailed us for a while.
Rym: And that question was basically, "Why don't they just bribe the two dipshits who are blocking all
Rym: this?".
Scott: Yeah, I did ask that.
Rym: So, and the answer for a long time was, "We seem to have tried, and it didn't work
Rym: out.".
Rym: So basically what happened here, they bribed Manchin, like dipshit number one, in a weird way.
Rym: He seemed to be against this.
Rym: He was publicly against this.
Rym: And I suspect that dipshit actually colluded with Chuck Schumer, who's the head of the Senate right now, and the Democrats.
Rym: Like, he runs the Senate on a technicality.
Rym: They basically, like, orchestrated this.
Rym: So Manchin said, "Nope, I'm not on board.
Rym: Fuck this
Rym: thing.".
Rym: So the Republicans basically agreed to let this other bill pass, and then have a reconciliation bill, because the Democrats agreed to not pull shenanigans with the reconciliation bill.
Rym: And the evil Republicans basically believed that was true, because they thought Joe Manchin, since any one Democrat could ruin it, was going to block it anyway, so they'd won.
Rym: As soon as they passed that first bill, Joe Manchin literally, that evening, issues a statement saying, "I support the reconciliation to pass the Infrastructure
Rym: Act.".
Rym: And then the only things blocking it would have been Sinema, dipshit number two.
Rym: Without the cover of Joe Manchin, Sinema actually just took a pretty simple bribe.
Rym: They removed, like, one provision around venture capital companies that she's probably entangled with, and then she stepped aside because she couldn't take the heat by herself, and it passed, and the Republicans are pissed.
Rym: They can't do anything about it.
Rym: The saddest thing is, this bill is probably the largest, most impactful, and most important thing the U.S.
Rym: Senate has done since Obamacare.
Rym: As little as it is, it's the biggest bill we've passed since then.
Scott: That's how sad we are, right?
Scott: It's like, "Ah, yes, we must climb up this mountain that is 10,000 meters tall.
Scott: That's how far we have to go for success, and the most we've ever climbed is 10 feet.
Scott: Congratulations, we just climbed 15
Scott: feet.".
Scott: Good job, everybody, 15 feet.
Rym: I think about that scene.
Scott: Only 90,990 feet to go.
Scott: I
Rym: think about that scene in The Terror, which I think was a GeekNights Book Club book a long time ago, where they're gonna abandon the ships and head off to try to get rescue, and they send a party ahead with those sledges, and they sledge all day, and it's like the most grueling work in the world.
Rym: They've exhausted themselves and ruined themselves, and at the end of the day, they're still within sight of the ships.
Rym: And that's the end of the chapter.
Rym: It feels like that sometimes.
Rym: But the fact that this passed is kind of a big deal, because it means that at least one of those two dipshits was in fact bribeable, and for once, the Democrats were actually, for real, playing dirty with the tools that they had.
Rym: They were, and they did it, and it worked.
Scott: Yeah, so look, again, if you say that, that's only one conclusion, is that Scott was right.
Scott: Dipshits are still humans.
Scott: They have motivations of some kind.
Scott: They can be moved, right?
Scott: They're not robots.
Rym: But this is the interesting thing.
Scott: He can't be moved on most other things.
Rym: He moved on this one for probably some specific reason.
Scott: But there is some way to do it, right?
Scott: You just have to, you know, they're getting closer to figuring it out, because no one's going to tell you how to move them, right?
Scott: Oh yes, if you want to move me, you'll have to do it.
Scott: I mean, I do.
Rym: There's a price.
Rym: Anything that I'm willing to do for our price, I will state that price.
Scott: Sure, but not a lot of people do that.
Scott: It's very rare.
Rym: So in the news, I'm sure you saw that a lot of people were Googling the term "neck robotic" over the last few weeks, because we all saw that terrifying video of a spider robot.
Rym: And basically, this is legit, this is a real thing.
Rym: Turns out spiders...
Scott: Next week, haha, how I made everyone believe my hoax about spider robots.
Rym: But apparently, spiders only have muscles to basically curl their legs in, and they actually use pneumatic systems to extend their legs.
Scott: Okay, I didn't know that.
Rym: Yeah, as opposed to humans and like mammals.
Scott: Where does the air come from?
Scott: They'd like breathe it in somewhere?
Rym: Yeah, I don't know all the details, but I've read like two articles about this.
Rym: I got one on the Smithsonian.
Rym: And they figured out that if you just take a dead spider and hook it up to a machine that is basically a pneumatic machine, you can use the spider as a little gripper crane.
Rym: And it turns out that a little dead spider can lift a hundred times its own body weight in extremely delicate, extremely controllable way.
Rym: And these spider grippers are better than like any sensitive gripper we could build with like non-biological components today.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, if you think about it, it's like most things that we make that are, you know, like mechanical devices are, have a single, you know, mode of like, you know, like, you know, it's like, oh, it's a, it's a lever made of metal or it's an elastic or it's a, it's a hydraulic pipe, right?
Scott: It's like, there's not a lot of like, I've never seen a machine that's like, oh yes, in that direction, it's pneumatic.
Scott: And in the other direction, it's elastic or something.
Scott: You don't see that, right?
Rym: But also the efficiency of biological systems, because really all our bodies are like all the crazy interesting stuff our bodies do are literally just tiny little molecular nanomachines.
Scott: But they're not hooking up to the spider's nervous system.
Scott: They're just stimulating its limbs directly.
Rym: Imagine they did this with a human.
Scott: They basically put a human on a spike.
Scott: They could just move your arms and legs around with, you know, electricity directly on your muscles, right?
Scott: Or some shit.
Rym: But, uh, this type of thing, necrobatics is sort of a transitionary step to understand these machines better, but the future of machinery, especially extremely advanced machinery, is definitely going to be inspired heavily by the literal micromachines that are inside of animals' bodies today.
Scott: I mean, that was what the fictional technology in BattleTech was, right?
Scott: Even though the BattleTech mechs walked around all boring and lumbering, right?
Scott: They weren't like Gundams or Evangelions.
Scott: They still were, you know, technically full of like, you know, this, like, uh, I forget what the word for, like, uh, Mayamur.
Scott: That's what they called it.
Scott: Mayamur.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Right.
Scott: The clan had triple-strength Mayamur.
Scott: that was just better and lighter in every conceivable way.
Scott: But it was like, you know, that that's, you know, they weren't just like, uh, it's like if they had the triple-strength Mayamur, shouldn't they be moving like Gundams and Evas, right?
Scott: You know, but yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, but this stuff is actually like, this is not just scientists doing something weird to write a paper.
Rym: This is very important research that's only going to accelerate.
Rym: In some other news, uh, talking about all these mergers and acquisitions, Amazon, we got to talk about this today.
Scott: Well, yeah, last time we talked about Amazon buying the doctor, right?
Scott: Now they're buying the robot.
Scott: They're going to make a doctor robot?
Rym: Well, specifically the Roomba, the robotic vacuum cleaner.
Scott: Yeah, the iRobot company, basically the company that made robot vacuums a thing is now owned by Amazon.
Rym: Now, it's fascinating because, you know, there's a lot of angles on this.
Rym: One, I already am very suspicious of people who let Amazon put microphones that are always on all around their house and connect them to the Internet.
Scott: Yeah, or Google, right?
Scott: The Apple one is kind of trustworthy, but also useless.
Scott: It's like, I don't ever get any of those.
Rym: I have never told my iPhone to set a timer.
Rym: I just click on a timer on my watch and it just works.
Scott: I disable Siri and every voice activated thing on every device.
Rym: Yep, but here, so all right.
Rym: I imagine whatever privacy concerns this has is probably less than what the people who enable this have already led into their houses.
Rym: But it doesn't seem like it's a good idea to give Amazon access to data that is a literal map of your house, plus a map of like what areas are the dirtiest.
Rym: I feel like that data in aggregate will be used to drive even ever more terrifying advertising and products and such.
Scott: I mean, the vacuum detects pet hair and then starts, you know, and then Alexa tries to buy you some pet food and it's like, you know, it's like all that kind of shit.
Scott: You know, that's, you know, it's not like one medical where we had to like, you know, hypothesize like, what would Amazon do with this?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, no, it's obvious what they're going to do with this.
Scott: The iRobot directly integrates with their Alexa's and the Ring door knobs and all their other house shit.
Rym: And I am a big fan of the concept of advanced home automation.
Rym: I'm just not a big fan of the Internet of shit.
Rym: Norm, I'm a big fan of having remote services running all of this for me.
Rym: I want to run it in my own house.
Scott: Right.
Rym: The way like this kind of technology should be designed.
Scott: I'm not a fan of it.
Scott: I think part of it is I never lived, you know, I never owned a house large enough.
Scott: I guess the house I grew up in was large enough, but the technology didn't exist then.
Rym: But I mean, if my house was just like the Star Trek, like computer, lower the temperature in the podcasting room, computer, raise the blinds.
Scott: I mean, they have that.
Rym: Yeah, well, they have that operated via all these external Internet of shit things.
Scott: But I'm just saying is that like it's even if you have it set up and it was local, it's like, you know, it's easier than saying, you know, like, hey, hey, Google, turn off the lights, fucking turning off the lights at the switch.
Scott: It's not better.
Scott: It has to be.
Scott: It's not better than the switch that you have.
Scott: It's like it has to be an improvement.
Rym: Well, the switch to turn on and off the main lighting in our living room is there's only one switch and is by the entrance to the living room way on the other side of the room.
Scott: Well, it's not my fault you got bad switches.
Scott: But the point is, what would be an improvement?
Scott: Right.
Scott: This is what I would like for home automation.
Scott: It needs to be where I don't have to tell I could program it initially.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: That's that's a worthwhile effort.
Scott: But afterwards, I shouldn't have to program it, for example.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like if I if everyone leaves the house, it just turns all the lights and air conditioners off.
Scott: I don't have to say anything.
Scott: It's just do it right.
Scott: If I if it's around bedtime.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It should start cooling the bedroom.
Scott: When everyone wakes up and leaves the bedroom, it should close the door and stop cooling the bedroom and wait and just cooling that for no reason, because no one's going to be in there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All this that, you know, some of these some of these offerings do have some of those capabilities.
Rym: A lot of the smart thermostats were at least they claim to figure out your patterns and just adapt to that over time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the ones where I have to talk to it, it's like that's not an improvement over a switch or a button or.
Scott: But regardless, yeah, it's obvious that Amazon's going to do with these robots.
Scott: And but I think also, right, the robot technology could also probably be brought over to some of Amazon's other departments.
Scott: Like, you know, they keep trying to make delivery drones a thing.
Scott: I don't know if we'll see that in our lifetimes or if it'll just continue to be.
Rym: It's just fascinating how delivery drones are just a solution looking for a problem.
Scott: So just like coins.
Rym: Yeah, well, coins are just a money laundering scam and or a multilevel marketing scam.
Scott: They're also a solution looking for a problem.
Rym: Yeah, but I think the solution looking for a problem is actually just a thin veneer over what is directly a scam.
Scott: But also, you know, hey, you know, this this again, more buying is happening, more merging is happening.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Smaller companies, you know, someone who makes like robot vacuums.
Scott: It's like that's not really a necessity of life, even though they're pretty popular in an economic downturn.
Rym: I would definitely have robot vacuums because they do.
Scott: The only reason I don't have one is because, you know, it's a small place and the floor is not really conducive.
Scott: This is not going to really be able to clean very much.
Rym: It won't do better than I do.
Rym: Just sweeping once a day.
Scott: But the you know, it's like an economic downturn is not good for that kind of not necessary semi luxury product.
Scott: And that's what you're seeing get merged into some bigger company that can weather a storm.
Scott: It tires small.
Scott: Your small boat might survive normal times, but when there's a big storm coming, everyone ties the small boat to the cruise ship.
Scott: That'll be OK.
Rym: But that's the other problem with the, you know, a rapid descent towards cyber dystopia like Shadowrun without elves.
Rym: This is Amazon's fourth largest acquisition ever.
Scott: So it is a big, successful company.
Rym: So the the other three in order are one Whole Foods for thirteen or fourteen billion in twenty seven, obviously, MGM, the movie studio in twenty twenty one, like recently for nine billion and one medical for four billion last year.
Rym: They are accelerating their pace and the government is not keeping up with any sort of antitrust yet.
Scott: Well, there actually was some big tech antitrust bill that was making some progress, but it actually just faced some anti-progress like I saw the article about that like today or yesterday.
Scott: It was moving along and now it's not doing so well.
Rym: Part of what was happening and this is what sucks.
Rym: Tech companies, for all their other problems, tend to be more hostile to the Republicans and the conservatives than to progressives and liberals on most issues.
Rym: Obviously, there's a lot.
Rym: I'm not saying they're good companies.
Rym: do not in any way construe that.
Rym: But there was a big movement, especially during the presidency, the former guy that's slowly petering out where Republicans and conservatives see feel threatened by the power of these technology companies that are in some ways very liberal.
Rym: And they were trying to wield antitrust to do things like force Twitter down so their shitty social networks can come up or force net neutrality rules to make sure conservatives can't be banned when they say racist things on like major platforms like.
Rym: they had a lot of ulterior motives for supporting the antitrust.
Rym: And as that's not panning out, if you don't have their support, it's not like progressives can do real good antitrust.
Scott: So even the sort of more centrist Democrats were all in favor of, you know, the tech antitrust.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But they still need dipshit Republicans on board because the thing we did to pass that bill, the one we just talked about, you can only do that once a year, maybe twice a year if you pull extremely difficult shenanigans.
Scott: Let's see what this article says.
Scott: Legislative clock ticks down on bill that would block largest tech companies from favoring their own products and services.
Rym: Yeah, really?
Rym: We just got to break them all up.
Rym: In some more news.
Rym: So this is a thread and I think it's pretty interesting.
Rym: It's worth talking about a little bit, but it's some analysis of a bunch of stuff that goes on in Netflix and how they use machine learning, but specifically around a use case of machine learning that is actually machine learning.
Rym: It isn't just people saying they're doing machine learning and then doing like a linear regression or nothing.
Rym: The statistic is that most people, the average person when they go to Netflix, they'll scroll around for 90 seconds.
Rym: And if they don't see something that they're going to watch, they'll navigate away.
Rym: Like that was their attempt to watch something that day.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: I mean, people, I do it too.
Scott: I'm guilty as charged, right?
Scott: It's like when I had streaming services, right?
Scott: I'd be in the mood to watch something, but I don't know what.
Scott: And so, but you know, and it's like if I don't have it, if there isn't something on my mind that I want to watch, right?
Scott: That I, but I was still in a mood to watch, but it's not like the old days where your choices are limited on television.
Scott: So you would flip through channels until you found the best option.
Rym: Or even the Beacon days.
Rym: We have the three Netflix DVDs that we have checked out right now.
Rym: Which of the three will we watch?
Scott: It's instead, it's the paradox of choice there.
Scott: You turn on any, even if you only have one streaming service, there are so many choices, right?
Scott: If they only just showed you three things and said, that's it, pick one of these three, it would be easier to pick, just pick one.
Scott: But there's a thousand million things.
Scott: It's like, all right, so I keep flipping through them.
Scott: And, and sometimes there is one that's like, ah, yes, perfect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But then most of the time there isn't.
Scott: And you spend a lot of the amount of time you spend flipping, you could have spent watching a whole thing.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So it appears, well, even worse in the, there's sometimes we used to get into the rut of, we watch trailers and then we've watched basically a show's worth of trailers.
Rym: And then we just stop.
Rym: We watched a bunch of trailers.
Rym: That was all we watched.
Rym: So people seem to choose something.
Rym: If they watch anything on Netflix, the only thing that influences them on average is the thumbnails.
Scott: And unless you've heard of it, unless you know what it is, the thumbnail is giving you all the information, right?
Scott: And you're not, there's a description, but you don't read the description unless the thumbnail is good enough for you to click on.
Rym: And according to this thread, an average user will look at any given thumbnail for 1.8 seconds.
Scott: That's a longer than I thought.
Scott: That'd be like milliseconds.
Rym: So, I mean, I don't know if you and I are necessarily the median example of anything related to media consumption.
Scott: I guess, suppose the title also matters, but the title's in the thumbnail.
Rym: And this thread goes into all this ridiculous analysis.
Rym: for basically Netflix generates its own thumbnails using machine learning.
Rym: They don't use what the people who make shows like give them.
Rym: They don't use official art.
Rym: They generate thumbnails with machine learning algorithms based on the data they have over what kinds of thumbnails people click on.
Rym: And the terrifying thing is this appears to be like radically, extremely, almost deterministically effective.
Rym: Like kind of like that study that showed a YouTube thumbnail that is a white face making a extreme overreaction to something with big text objectively gets more clicks than any other type of thumbnail regardless of content.
Rym: Same thing on Netflix.
Rym: So the machine learning algorithm settled on some really interesting things.
Rym: And this thread talks about exactly what the algorithm is looking for, how it generates them, how it will give you a different thumbnail from someone else based on your past watching history with examples.
Rym: So like if I look at a show and you look at a show, it'll show us a different thumbnail if we've watched different stuff.
Rym: And the funniest one is the more characters there are on a thumbnail, the less likely it is that anyone will look at it.
Scott: And if there's something that everyone knows that everyone hates reading.
Rym: Yeah, but like a thumbnail has three characters or four characters, way fewer people will even look at that show than one that just has one character on it.
Rym: And the nuts example was they took two radically different viewer histories.
Rym: And if one set of people look at Pulp Fiction, they see the actual Pulp Fiction like movie poster that we all remember.
Rym: But someone who has watched like a bunch of other types of media, they will see a thumbnail that is weird and almost makes Pulp Fiction look like a completely different movie.
Rym: And you can read this thread to see all the details, but I still don't think this type of algorithmic manipulation of humans is particularly healthy, nor is this ecosystem necessarily not just a self-referencing and self-propagating thing.
Rym: I feel like the algorithms are driving people toward what the algorithms want people to watch.
Rym: I think that this is not just the passive discovery of habits.
Rym: I think this is driving behaviors.
Scott: The thing I never really understood is like if you're Netflix, you don't make more money when people watch more shit.
Scott: You just have to have someone watching enough that they don't unsubscribe.
Rym: And that's the goal of this.
Scott: So it's like you don't care what they watch.
Scott: There's no reason to drive someone watching one thing or another.
Rym: They do not care what you watch.
Rym: All they care about is, whatever you care about, how do we get you to click on something within 90 seconds?
Rym: And that's all the algorithms doing.
Rym: It looks at Scott and says, what would Scott click on in the next 90 seconds right now?
Rym: And that is what it's trying to figure out.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: I wonder what's going to happen if I get into a habit of canceling in my Netflix account, making a new one, canceling it.
Rym: Do they keep the data?
Rym: What if I give them a GDPR request every time?
Scott: If you reinstate your account quickly enough, they don't delete it yet.
Scott: You get it back.
Scott: You get everything back.
Scott: But if you let it go long enough, eventually they get rid of it completely and you have to start from nothing again.
Rym: You can also force them to start from nothing.
Scott: I forget what the time period is, but.
Rym: If you tell them that per the GDPR you want all your personal data removed, they have to remove it all.
Scott: Yeah, they do that.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: FTL, pretty good game.
Rym: Pretty old at this point, but it's out there.
Rym: Fun little rogue-like space game.
Rym: And this video, I just bumped into this randomly.
Rym: It's a cute little video.
Rym: It's like three minutes long.
Rym: And someone, it's sort of two things I like combined into one video.
Rym: One thing I like is when someone takes a video game and does something extreme in it and documents what that's like.
Rym: Kind of like a speed runner, like doing something crazy.
Rym: But the other thing I like is when someone tells a little story, almost like a machinima, like makes a narrative using the mechanics of a game.
Rym: And this is a cute little video that's animated and set to music.
Rym: That is, someone made a ship and all this ship does is start fires.
Rym: That's all it can do.
Rym: Their entire build is just, it starts fires.
Rym: And this ended up being actually really funny to watch.
Rym: That's what he got.
Scott: So, you know, when you watch movies, especially movies that are depicting an older time period in Eastern Asia, there's usually scenes of people planting rice, right?
Rym: Evangelion dwelled on that for like three hours in the middle.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's always that really stereotypical, sometimes racist scene of, you know, people and hats, in a muddy field, you know, on their backpack, they got a ton of rice, you know, seedlings hunched over, right?
Scott: They put one rice in the ground to take a step backwards.
Scott: They put a rice in the ground to take a step backwards, right?
Scott: And that is the way people planted rice for a long time.
Scott: And I'm sure some places on earth, people might still be planting rice that way, but clearly with the amount of rice that is eaten and by humans on the earth, that is not how all the rice can be planted.
Scott: It would not be enough rice.
Scott: How is it actually done?
Scott: Obviously, there's some sort of agricultural rice planting machine that does the work.
Scott: Have you ever seen this machine?
Scott: I haven't seen the machine yet until I saw this video.
Scott: I don't know if this is like the best possible machine.
Scott: There may be other ones that are better, newer, fancier, right?
Scott: This one's kind of small.
Scott: It's like just two people, but it is still an incredibly impressive machine.
Scott: And actually what's happening in the video is they have two rice fields, right?
Scott: The first rice field, they just sort of plant that, I presume, the way that you plant like grass where you just sort of toss seeds around and they just toss a lot of seeds around and you get them growing really dead
Rym: to that with rice
Scott: and you get lots.
Scott: That's right, right.
Scott: But you get the seedlings that way.
Scott: Then they roll up the seedlings like sod and like a little like little bundles, like little rolls.
Scott: And then the machine is actually they're sort of putting the rolls of densely packed rice in the machine, sort of like ammunition.
Scott: And then they take the machine to a separate muddy field where it then takes all those seedlings and plants them in a more spread out fashion so that they can grow to full size rice plants without crowding each other out.
Scott: So it's like there's a field for the first stage where it's dense and then big ass fields to transplant everything.
Scott: And the transplanting is very impressive machine.
Rym: Plus, apparently there's a big like.
Rym: I don't know all the details, but rice needs one type of environment to germinate.
Rym: But then it prefers to grow in a very different environment.
Rym: And there's lots.
Rym: How did rice grow without not in the not in anywhere near the quantity we need it to?
Rym: It also has a lot of other problems.
Rym: Some of this is to help it be free of disease and bacteria.
Rym: There's a lot of stuff going on here.
Rym: There's also a problem with rice.
Rym: Rice cultivation is increasingly pulling our stick out of the ground in increasingly bad like high quantities.
Rym: And rice is actually getting not quite dangerous to eat yet, but it's not great necessarily for young kids anywhere in the world.
Rym: There's nowhere you can grow it.
Rym: This isn't a problem, I guess.
Rym: So even if you buy the fair is still a lot more arsenic in rice than in pretty much any other cereal grain or like basically any grain.
Scott: Yeah, fascinating.
Rym: The Metamoment, the Geek God's Book Club book.
Rym: We will do the episode on Thursday next week.
Rym: This book will take you.
Rym: It's a novella.
Rym: Maybe a couple hours to read.
Scott: I didn't start reading it yet, though.
Scott: I did inspire you.
Scott: You'll probably read it.
Rym: Knowing you, you'll read it in one sitting.
Rym: You'll sit down.
Rym: You'll start reading it.
Rym: You'll be done.
Scott: Probably.
Rym: But when will that sitting rain coming up in the next week or two?
Rym: Week and a half?
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: I'll be alive at PAX West.
Rym: Sunday, September 4th, 1230 p.m.
Rym: Sasquatch Theater.
Scott: Losing.
Rym: TBD on other cons.
Rym: I saw Magfest drop their dates.
Rym: It's in January.
Rym: They said it'll be masked and require VAXes just like before.
Rym: We'll see how the world is.
Rym: We'll see if we got boosters by then.
Rym: You know, I'm key.
Rym: We're still continuing to not make commitments to things that are too far in the future because who knows what the future is going to be like.
Scott: Let me check the numbers.
Scott: They don't look good.
Rym: The worst part is the numbers don't even get tracked that well anymore.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, I just had a coworker at the new job just posted on Slack that their kid is at summer camp, but tested positive.
Scott: And now that's it.
Scott: Summer camp's over for them.
Scott: They're coming home.
Scott: And even though who knows if it's a mild or serious case or whatever, but it's like, shouldn't you just set the summer camp down if one person had it?
Rym: I have like more than 10 coworkers who tested positive like in the last week or two.
Rym: All of them definitely got it from their kids who were at camp.
Rym: That what worries me is that does not bode well for September when school starts.
Scott: There is a new coworker who started like.
Scott: I'm only been there a month, right?
Scott: But a coworker started like a week after me.
Scott: And they started the job with COVID and to even into even today, they're like, I'm 85% of the way to being, you know, they're like, they're still 15% sick.
Scott: It's like, really?
Scott: Uh, I'm going to continue being extremely cautious self that has gotten me, you know, other people look at me and they're like, oh, you're being too cautious.
Scott: But meanwhile, I've had zero COVID so far.
Rym: So I had my one COVID and that was when I went on a business trip to a convention in the UK that I, that I wouldn't do.
Rym: So yeah.
Rym: Otherwise just, you know, keep an eye on your internet stuff.
Rym: Websites coming along.
Rym: Other stuff's coming along.
Rym: I guess we can just get into the main bit.
Rym: Kirby's vacuum cleaners.
Rym: The listener suggested this back in like July and it's not the worst idea.
Scott: Uh, I mean, it's not the worst idea, but it's like, what do I got to say about the end?
Rym: So, uh, you know, so I was just at work, so we were planning some sort of big meeting and let's just say one person was trying to like put together a deck and like kick off the meeting.
Rym: and there they basically did the Homer Simpson, the, since the dawn of time, man has tried.
Rym: So I can almost start here is since the dawn of time, man has tried to clean up the floor in the place they live.
Rym: I don't think we're going to talk about the history of vacuum cleaners because you can literally go, you can go to Wikipedia and your cup overfloweth.
Scott: And I also don't know it.
Scott: I don't know anything about it.
Rym: What I can say is vacuum cleaners for me personally were very important and like just a thing that were a big deal in my life until I moved to New York city where now I don't have carpet, like wall to wall carpet.
Rym: And now vacuum cleaners are very much a like semi-specialty tool as opposed to something that is like looming large in my life being used nearly every day, like a utility, an appliance almost in the house.
Rym: Now it's just like a little thing to use sometimes to clean up a little mess.
Scott: I mean, I had vacuum, you know, wherever I lived, a vacuum was like an essential thing to own.
Scott: I had one and, you know, I used it more or less.
Scott: I changed the bag if it was a bag kind that got, if it got full and, you know, I used only some of the tools and most of those tools never really worked that well.
Rym: I use that corner edger, like the super point one for almost everything, unless I was just vacuum vacuuming.
Scott: I think a lot of them are for, you know, if you have a big house with lots of like, you curtains and all sorts of different things, then a lot of the tools suddenly make sense.
Scott: But it's like if you live in a more simple living place that doesn't have like this wide variety of things to be vacuumed, that a lot of those tools are just sort of unnecessary.
Rym: But a big part of this too is when I was a kid, you know, I grew up in the Midwest and there's a lot of interesting things about the Midwest.
Rym: But two things that are relevant to this conversation is one, the vast majority of people in the entire American Midwest generally wear their shoes in their own house and in other people's houses like that is just the default to the point that like as a kid we go to houses and if you started to take your shoes off, like the mom would come over and be like, no, no, no, do not take your shoes off like they would not let you take your shoes off in their house.
Rym: And two, most houses had a wall to wall carpet in nearly every room.
Rym: I even lived in a house at one point that had carpet in the downstairs bathroom, just full thick carpet.
Rym: And if you have carpet like that, like real carpet that has like the under layer and then like real carpet on the top, there's really no way to clean that except a vacuum cleaner.
Rym: Like you can't sweep that.
Rym: There's literally no way to get dirt out of that stuff except with a real big vacuum cleaner.
Rym: Kind of glad that I live in the city now where most people prefer hardwood or tile and there's no carpet.
Scott: Well, I think I think hardwood and tile are more popular even outside the city nowadays, you're only seeing, you know, at least in more contemporary homes, I think you're really just seeing carpet on like a bedroom, right?
Scott: Or maybe like a finished basement might have the thin carpet because no one wants to walk on a concrete floor, right?
Scott: But not necessarily could be some other kind of surface.
Rym: I always lived in houses where every room had carpet except like the kitchen and like the dirt rooms in the garage until I moved to the city.
Scott: I mean, I guess I mean, even in Beacon, other than the kitchen, the house that I grew up in, the house that I grew up in had carpet in the amount of carpet that was in there.
Scott: It wasn't every room, right?
Scott: There were basically.
Scott: there were hardwood floors that were nice ish underneath the carpet.
Scott: So it's basically when the house was built, the wood was in style, then carpet came in style and was installed on top.
Scott: And over at during the time we lived there, the carpet was removed, I think from all but two rooms, maybe.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like as we lived there, we changed carpet in a couple of times.
Scott: But yeah, there was carpet was removed from from rooms.
Rym: Yeah, I remember every time we moved, we would get a new vacuum cleaner and we would also replace all the carpet in any house we moved into, like no matter what, like we replace it all.
Scott: But you can't trust that.
Scott: You can't.
Rym: I mean, a decade of someone else's feet.
Rym: Not a big.
Scott: But you can.
Scott: you can vacuum hardwood floor to a degree.
Scott: You don't just vacuum.
Rym: You do need the right kind of vacuum, though.
Rym: That's where like the vacuums.
Scott: Yeah, my vacuum has multiple different heads.
Scott: It's got it right.
Scott: It has one with a spinny brush, one that I use on the rug.
Scott: And then it's got a spinny, you know, sort of softy like a roller.
Scott: It looks almost like a paint roller, but it's softer.
Scott: And I use that on the hardwood.
Scott: It's a hardwood floor thing.
Rym: When I was a kid, we basically we had giant, upright vacuums that had like all these different settings on them.
Rym: And you'd even set it to a different height, depending on how thick the carpet was in a given room.
Rym: At one point, my parents got a hold of.
Rym: I don't think they bought it from the company.
Rym: And I'm not going to say this company is a scam.
Rym: I'm not opening myself up to any libel or slander of any kind.
Rym: But I will just link to the fact that there is on.
Rym: the Kirby is a brand of vacuum cleaner, also a cute pink guy who is a vacuum.
Rym: And the Kirby's are let's just say kirby.com, the company that like sells these vacuum cleaners, which they mostly sell door to door, has an entire page on their official website whose URL is kirby.com/sellingkirbyvacuumsisnotascam.
Rym: Draw what conclusions you may from a business that has to tell you they're not a scam and has a fact about how they are not a scam.
Scott: But I was very suspicious when I was a kid.
Scott: There were TV commercials for a brand of vacuums.
Rym: Or I remember seeing those around.
Rym: I got some demonstrations of those.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So I never used one or right.
Scott: It was just.
Scott: I'm just a memorable TV commercial, right?
Scott: Because I was at an impressionable young brain and the commercials are on all the time, like watching Price is Right.
Scott: And so I'm trying to sell you vacuums.
Scott: But they basically they were marketed as these are the vacuums that hotels use.
Scott: They looked like they were, you know, commercial.
Scott: They didn't look like something that you would find in a home.
Scott: They look like something you would find in a commercial setting.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they you know, they're like, oh, it's the best vacuum.
Scott: Oh, so good.
Scott: Much better than the vacuum you're going to buy the you know, the department store.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Get one of these babies.
Scott: And the real expensive way more.
Scott: It's like and I never know anyone who owned one.
Scott: I didn't know if they were actually better.
Scott: I assume they were a scam because why were they trying so hard?
Scott: If they were so good, why do they need to buy all these ads?
Scott: The other vacuums.
Rym: But we ended up getting a hold of one of these things.
Rym: And these are way overpriced.
Rym: Like nobody needs a vacuum like that.
Rym: But I got to say a good if you have a big house, a good high quality vacuum is really important because crappy vacuums just don't work like cheap ones just don't work at all.
Rym: They might work in like a local area, but like vacuum all the entire living room and it just won't get stuff out of the carpet.
Rym: Like it just won't work on the hardwood.
Rym: My whole life, cheap vacuums are worse than no vacuum.
Scott: Yeah, there are a lot of things that can cause a vacuum to fail, right?
Scott: It's like even the highest quality vacuums.
Scott: It's like, you know, they're.
Scott: you know, they have lots of moving parts.
Scott: You know, it's a lot of power going in the motor, right?
Scott: You know, you got you got lots of opportunities for the filth coming into the vacuum to mess up the vacuum, right?
Scott: All kinds of pet hair being the worst offender.
Scott: You know, all kinds of other things might get sucked in there and then they, you know, it's not.
Scott: the vacuum is not immune to the things that it sucks in, right?
Scott: So it's like the higher quality the vacuum, the more the longer it's going to last, the better it's going to clean, et cetera.
Scott: It's just, you know, check your check a reliable source for knowing which ones are actually better.
Rym: And I have seen the difference.
Rym: Like I remember we like we vacuum the house every day because we had dogs and birds and hamsters and I was just full of animals.
Rym: So we had to vacuum literally every day.
Rym: My entire childhood, someone's chore every single day was to vacuum the entire house at least once.
Rym: And I remember when we got a new vacuum, I was in like elementary school and we vacuumed with it the first time and all the carpets like slightly changed color and the bag basically filled up and we were all like, oh, shit, that old vacuum just wasn't working.
Rym: It was it was gross and terrifying when we ran that new vacuum the first time.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I guess let's let's do the easy thing.
Rym: First, my favorite type you can alternate is the shop vac, the kind of vacuum that if I had a house, I wish I had a shop vac.
Rym: But living in an apartment, there is no way it is worth the space to keep a shop vac.
Rym: The deal is shop vacs.
Scott: A shop vac is a really unique kind of vacuum because it can.
Scott: basically the sucking is the vacuum is on the top part.
Scott: It's then the bottom part is just a bucket.
Scott: It's just a bucket.
Scott: There is nothing down there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you can suck anything with a shop vac.
Scott: Pretty much water, water, fire, anything like if it can fit in the hose and even better suck it in.
Scott: It's just a universal sucker until the bucket is better.
Rym: You can just unplug the sucker hose, stick it into the other side of the shop vac.
Rym: And now you got a blower.
Rym: In fact, you could use it blowing and sucking simultaneously if you have a fancy one.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: If you have a house
Scott: and the bucket is just like
Rym: a house or a garage, or if you do anything that you could do in a place bigger than a New York City apartment, a shop vac is an indispensable tool because even if you don't use it that often, if you're ever in a situation where a shop vac was the answer, the worst thing in the world is not having a shop vac right at that moment.
Rym: Because there is no way to get a shop vac in time to deal with a shop vac situation if you don't already have one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you only have a regular vacuum, there are certain situations.
Scott: you got to vacuum something and you can't vacuum it with a regular vacuum.
Rym: I do shop vacs to pump water out of basements.
Scott: Shop vacs can suck anything.
Scott: It's basically.
Scott: It's easy.
Rym: I do shop vacs to just like suck sawdust off of a project.
Rym: Like I'm cutting wood and the shop vacs just running with the hose pointed at the blade, sucking all the sawdust away so I don't breathe it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And because it's a bucket with just a long hose and a lot of sucking power, you can use it for a lot of say normal things that a normal vacuum could do.
Scott: But the the the shape and you know, the the ergonomics, I guess.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Vacuuming out the inside of a car or.
Rym: But it's especially things where you're not trying to pick up dust and normal dirt.
Rym: You're trying to pick up effectively liquid or debris.
Rym: Like it's not going to get the dust off of the things in your car, but it'll get all that schmutz that's built up in like the seams of your car seats.
Rym: See, what about?
Rym: so the crazy things.
Rym: I've used shop vacs for a bunch of pennies.
Rym: Once I spilled shit, I basically knocked over a bucket of small screws once in a workshop.
Rym: So I used a shop vac to vacuum them all up into a bucket to get them off the floor.
Rym: Water sawdust as.
Scott: It's good.
Scott: You know, like it usually if you break like a glass, right, you would have to pick up the big pieces of the normal vacuum, the small pieces.
Rym: But a shop vac and I have backed up broken glass many times in my life.
Rym: It just works.
Rym: But they will just spew dust into your house unless you have a very nice one with filters.
Scott: Even then, that's why it's a shop.
Scott: You don't use it to vac.
Scott: That's why it's a shop.
Scott: It's not a house.
Rym: So then there's the traditional upright vacuum that most American households have, which weren't super common outside of us.
Scott: I think the upright vacuum has gone out of style.
Scott: Personally, I haven't seen them lately around.
Scott: and the upright vacuum is basically on the one hand, it's a single unit, right?
Scott: And it's sort of straightforward, right?
Scott: You know, it's like you plug it in or it's battery powered, maybe, but usually plug in and it's going to handle along at.
Scott: the bag is big.
Scott: It's nice and long.
Scott: It's attached to the handle.
Rym: Upright vacuums are still very are predominantly.
Rym: They're the predominant type of vacuum.
Rym: And they're very popular in the US and Britain and pretty much nowhere else on Earth.
Rym: They coincide with places that historically mostly have wall to wall carpet.
Scott: So there you go.
Scott: But the thing I don't like about the upright vacuum is that you're moving.
Scott: You can only really vacuum like in place, you know, floors.
Scott: It can't vacuum really anything else.
Rym: Some of them might have never had an upright vacuum that did not have a hose hole built into it.
Rym: Never.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the thing is, is with the upright vacuum, you're pushing around all like the bag is filling and it's like, oh, you never use a nice around the one.
Rym: we had had a motor in it and it would drive forward and backward with a clutch.
Scott: Yeah, they could drive.
Scott: They can drive a little bit, but you're still pushing around the whole big fucking thing everywhere you go.
Scott: The canister vacuum.
Rym: I would disagree because I spent a lot of my childhood doing a lot of vacuuming in the Midwest.
Rym: The canisters were a pain in the ass because you had to roll the fucking thing around and it was getting heavy.
Rym: The upright kind of just drove itself.
Scott: You don't have to move.
Scott: You just move the canister into the room and the hose is a hose.
Scott: And you don't have my house just so big that you had to move that all around the fucking room.
Rym: The hoses are not that long on up on canisters.
Scott: It's not any heavier than the upright thing.
Scott: It's like you can vacuum all around within a great distance of the canister, which is holding light tools and getting into all kinds of places.
Rym: Canister vacuums are things are the predominant vacuum in Europe and nowhere else common in the US.
Scott: We had one in.
Scott: I mean, we had one in college and we brought it to a beacon.
Rym: No, but they seem to be not as common.
Rym: I'm reading like Wikipedia and things linked from Wikipedia, but Wikipedia says the listener can do that themselves.
Scott: But at the canister means you don't you only?
Scott: you know, you only have to pick it up and get it close to the place you're going to do vacuuming and then just hold the light holes on a hose.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And then there's the little ones like the little handheld ones.
Rym: Like as a kid, we had the Dustbuster and they were OK.
Rym: Those are actually.
Rym: that's the only vacuum you need.
Scott: We didn't have the Dustbuster, but my grandmother loved the Dustbuster.
Scott: Like she'd be you know, any time there were like crumbs from someone eating, she'd come with the Dustbuster.
Rym: like get the Dustbuster off like the dinner table after we ate before like we washed it.
Rym: Dog messes, all that kind of stuff.
Rym: The only problem with those things like they're great in an apartment, especially if it's the kind of place where you're not vacuuming the floor, like you sweep the floor and you only use it for like a specific spill or like vacuuming off the couch once a month, like that kind of thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: it's not for a general maintenance, like I need to vacuum now.
Scott: It's like there is a. there is a single thing I must vacuum right right now.
Scott: It just happened something like I spilled some sugar or something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like not shot back worthy.
Scott: The little tiny one can handle it.
Scott: You know, it's just sugar.
Scott: And that's what.
Scott: that's what the Dustbuster is for.
Rym: Then we got the Roombas like the robotic ones, topical, which.
Scott: Yeah, I never had one, but they are.
Scott: I have seen other.
Scott: I've been to places people have them and I've seen them in action and they're better than you.
Rym: They won't do a deep clean like like.
Rym: they're quite impressive house, like pretty clean, but they won't ever get as much dirt out of the carpet as a like full on canister upright.
Rym: But that's not their point.
Rym: Their point is, yeah, instead of like vacuuming every single day, you leave this thing going and maybe you do the real vacuuming like once every couple of months, depending on how dirty your house gets.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like I guess you have to.
Scott: I presume you have to empty the room at some point.
Scott: It might it must tell you when it's full or something.
Rym: But I've never had one.
Scott: Shake it out over the trash or it has.
Rym: But as I think back to houses, I've never had one either.
Rym: Like the house I lived in in high school, a Roomba would have been amazing.
Rym: Like it would have been perfect.
Rym: But like New York City apartment, that thing would not even be able to navigate this apartment.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you have too many things to close together, it's like it's really smart.
Scott: Like mapping your floor, you know, and I guess it can get over and under like slight bumps.
Scott: But if you have like a big step, it can't climb.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So like the house.
Scott: I grew up in the bottom floor right at the bottom of the stairs, the staircase, there's like a little landing that was like six, you know, one step high.
Scott: It's like so that Roomba would had to go around this whole horseshoe shape to get around.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the thing is, it's like, you know, there's so many obstacles.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it can.
Scott: it finds the obstacles, but some of them it's like it's I know the size of a Roomba.
Scott: It can't physically get in between those two things.
Scott: There isn't enough room for it to get past.
Scott: That's effectively a wall, even though you can walk through there and does.
Scott: It's like, say, between between a coffee table and a couch.
Scott: It's just like it can't get between those two things.
Scott: And that place is just going to be unroomed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Never, it's never going to.
Rym: So if I had a big house, definitely a small place.
Rym: They I think they'd just be more trouble than they're worth.
Rym: But they're not a bad technology.
Scott: The only bad thing about them, if you got a big if you have a big, flat place with a lot of open room, it's like I would get one of those, maybe even more than one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I don't think they can go upstairs either.
Rym: So you might need to get a lot of people on the floor from what I can tell.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then you got to keep doors open.
Scott: Otherwise, like even though it might get the whole floor, if you had doors, it's like, well, it can't open doors.
Scott: You're going to have to open them all up to the of course.
Rym: Then we got the central vacuum systems, which are interesting in that they have come in and out of fashion, at least in the US, several times.
Rym: And like this multi-decade cycle, like they're popular.
Rym: Then they're seen as like a bullshit nonsense that just breaks down or like a fad.
Rym: But then they come back again.
Rym: And right now they seem to be popular again, like they're coming back.
Scott: Yeah, my grandparents, one of the places they lived had one of those.
Scott: And it was slightly fascinating and interesting.
Scott: You know, I don't know if they actually used it, but the house had it.
Scott: And one time I went in the basement and I saw there was like a central machine and I was like, Oh, that's the vacuum machine.
Scott: It's like this, the thing in the basement that's doing.
Scott: it's basically ready to vacuum.
Scott: Whenever anyone opens one of these little flaps, they're like little flaps.
Scott: And if you opened a flap, suddenly the vacuum in the basement would detect it because you like broke the circuit or whatever, and then it would start vacuuming.
Scott: And there would be just a hole in the wall that has suction.
Scott: And you had a set of tools and you would attach the tools to the hole in the wall.
Scott: And you could vacuum anything within range of the hole in the wall.
Scott: So you didn't need to drag the canister around.
Scott: And it was like using a canister vac only with holes everywhere.
Scott: But if you didn't have enough holes, some places might be too far from a hole to vacuum.
Scott: Well, it's depending on the, you know, you had to really plan it out and get those.
Rym: The system has to be expensive and nice enough to have enough suction to even work.
Rym: And if it doesn't also provide either air-driven or electric power to run like the little roller brushes on the ends of the attachments, not all of them do, and the ones that don't are worthless.
Scott: But then the other thing is you got to, you know, that thing in the basement, it's like when it fills up, you got to go in the basement and empty out the big vacuum machine into the tray, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, all kinds of filth is building up downstairs.
Scott: You know, it's not like magically disappearing or anything like that.
Rym: So I don't know.
Rym: I feel like especially in a city, like in an apartment, those things are probably silly.
Rym: I don't know if there are any apartment buildings where they're offering like a central one for the whole building that just works.
Scott: Well, Roosevelt Island has one for the whole island.
Scott: To take trash is a giant pneumatic vacuum.
Rym: Istanbul has a somewhat similar system in a lot of the downtown areas where there's just like basically dumpsters that go into this big underground system that will collect garbage.
Rym: But yeah, not so in terms of there's other kinds of vacuums, but like they're not really materially different.
Scott: There are the electric stick ones, right?
Scott: Which we had, you know, like we had and we had both the regular vacuum, but also an electric stick vacuum that you would use for jobs that were like too big for a dust buster.
Scott: But like, you know, it would be good for the hard floor only.
Scott: Like you would really mostly be used kitchen only.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it was like it was just an electric stick vacuum for the kitchen because it was easier to just bust it out and just start using it right away than to go get the whole ass vacuum.
Scott: And the vacuum that I have now is, you know, Dyson one, all fancy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's effectively just a modern, you know, highly advanced version of the electric stick vacuum.
Scott: It has a lithium ion battery instead of having to be plugged into the wall.
Scott: It has a plastic canister instead of bags.
Scott: See, you just.
Rym: Alright, so it does a cyclonic separation instead of filtered separation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then it has all kinds of freaking attachments you can put on the end.
Scott: So you can actually use it on carpet, you know, as long as the battery doesn't run out and then just charge it up again.
Scott: So it's like, you know, I sort of, you know, I think that's sort of a perfectly fine solution for a small living place, right?
Scott: You're not getting something that's too weak, not too strong, you know, it's obviously too expensive because Dyson is, you know, a rip off.
Scott: But what are the alternatives out there?
Scott: There weren't a lot of.
Rym: the other big thing is how it actually filters, especially if they use filters or bags, because I remember as a kid, cheaper vacuums or the cheaper bags in the vacuums didn't actually catch all the dust.
Rym: So you'd be picking up the debris, but you'd be spitting the dust like right back out into the room and even agitating it.
Rym: Some percent, some percentage, but at the same time.
Scott: Well, this is also why you should never vacuum mercury, because you're going to be just breathing that right back into your lungs.
Rym: But if you.
Rym: but the problem is if you put like a full on HEPA filter on a vacuum, because we had a vacuum when I was a kid that you could put a HEPA filter in.
Rym: That thing would fill up and be clogged so quickly that you'd be spending so much money on bags that it wasn't worth it.
Rym: And I don't know what to do about that.
Rym: Like, I don't know of any solution.
Scott: There's.
Scott: Well, the the basement one, right, you can have a gigantic all that goes in.
Scott: It's and it's all filtering in the basement, so you're not really breathing it in.
Scott: by the time you go to the basement, the dust is settled, right?
Scott: Just don't kick it up too much.
Rym: I think we killed enough time.
Rym: I guess I could say vacuums still.
Rym: They're very loud.
Rym: Even very nice.
Rym: Modern vacuums are just very loud, partly because there isn't really a good way to make them quiet by the physical nature of what it is they're doing.
Scott: Yeah, they are at least a steady noise that active noise canceling headphones are very good at blocking or at least reducing greatly.
Scott: But, you know, you can't put those on like your pet or your baby or and, you know, sometimes they help.
Scott: a baby likes a vacuum.
Rym: You know, no dog, no dog I have ever had the pleasure of living with has enjoyed when the vacuum comes out.
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: But if someone could invent some way to to get, you know, vacuum pressure right enough to to, you know, because the other parts could just be like quiet electric motors.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's the vacuum pump part.
Scott: That is the loud part.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If someone can make a quiet one, you're rich.
Scott: Super.
Scott: You'd be rich forever.
Scott: So maybe worth working on.
Scott: if you're I don't know if it's probably not possible.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Just have some new paradigm, like instead of relying on suction.
Rym: What if you try to think of a Star Trek idea?
Rym: What if you use ultrasonic sound, quantum, quantum teleportation?
Rym: You superpositioned the ultrasonic sound to agitate the dust and then way lower suction to pull it up, coupled with ionizing to like charge the particles and then have them stick to stuff inside.
Rym: You could make some sort of fancy, over expensive vacuum that no one could ever afford.
Scott: I bet I wouldn't be very good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Linky G, Dread Lillie, each other by a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Chris Adon, Chris Reimer, Quinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Shai Aye, 85, Rebecca Dunn, Review Madboat, 34 Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl.
Rym: Stop all the downloading, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Wilson, Wilson Station and a bunch of people whose names I will not say at their specific request.
Rym: We will do that Book Club book.
Rym: It's a short read and I'll tell you, we'll see you listen to the singer.
Rym: I'm thinking either two books.
Rym: I'm thinking about putting forth for the next Book Club when it's my turn again for Scott to pick one of the two.
Rym: I think I'm going to choose between Umberto Eco's Foucault's Pendulum or some Star Trek novel written by the actor who played Garrick.
Rym: And Scott will get to pick which of those two he wants to read.
Rym: I think it's a 50/50 shot which one he'll take based on the length of the former versus the subject matter of the latter.
Rym: But for now, I simply leave you with...