Rym: It's Wednesday, August 10th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are reviewing E2O, directed by Masaaki Yuasa.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I was in the GeekNights forum, community.frontrowcrew.com, a little bit before this, 'cause I hadn't read it in a couple days.
Rym: Like, I'd actually been really busy, and I'd, like, I didn't read the entirety of the internet that I normally read, and I was catching up on it, and I noticed a comment from the listener, which, you know, when I see comments like this, I do react to them, because every now and then, I will fuck up an episode.
Rym: Like, I have left a main bit, like a thing-of-the-day sound in the wrong place.
Rym: I'd like it to happen.
Rym: It's rare, but it happens.
Scott: But, uh... I added, for the new website, I added a feature.
Scott: Not, it won't be one of those features that keeps me from releasing the new website, but it's one of those future features.
Rym: Oh, if you're gonna say what you're, I think you're about to say, that's gonna be great, because the process I have to follow now involves manually logging the Libsyn and fuckery.
Scott: Yeah, create some way for Rym to, you know, re-upload the MP3 if he fucks it up.
Rym: So I did look through some old stats, because, you know, I have my own production logs.
Rym: I have fucked up fewer than ten episodes in the history of GeekNights, which is actually pretty good.
Scott: That's why this is a distant feature and not a high-priority feature.
Rym: 'Cause I, when I fuck it up, so I thought, because the listener said, and I'm gonna quote here, "The audio tracks in the main bit of this episode are misaligned.
Rym: You are artificially talking over each other.
Rym: I don't care to listen about vacuum cleaners enough to listen this
Rym: way.".
Rym: Which, fair.
Scott: I don't care about, I don't, that's fair.
Scott: I don't want to listen about vacuum cleaners.
Scott: I didn't have much to say about them.
Rym: You already had to listen to it once.
Scott: I didn't have much knowledge about them either, so I'm not the one you should be listening to about vacuum cleaners.
Scott: Go find, there's probably some vacuum expert home appliance podcast you could listen to.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, but anyway, I, you know, I reacted to that.
Rym: So just before the show, I, uh, I went in and checked.
Rym: So, uh, first, I keep the raw session of every GeekNights episode for a year.
Rym: That's like my process, just in case.
Rym: And I keep the raw audio, but not the whole project forever, just in case.
Rym: Obviously reconstructing an episode from the raw audio would be more of a pain in the ass, but I have never needed to go more than a year in the past and fix an episode, except when I did all that commentary on the Patreon on the Beta GeekNights.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: So I go, I open the sequence first, because if you fuck that up, it's really obvious.
Rym: And it looked fine.
Rym: So I actually went deeper and did some analysis because I have to synchronize your audio recorded at home with a slightly different clock with my audio recorded here and the discord.
Rym: We have that whole process.
Rym: I talked about before, but no, that episode was within 50 milliseconds, uh, accuracy at any point as in 48 milliseconds, like difference between when you actually said the thing over the discord and when you said it in the audio that I lined up, because they're not exactly synchronized, uh, less than 50 milliseconds at the worst possible point in the entire episode, which a human could not even notice.
Rym: So then I, like, what if I exported and did something weird in the pipeline?
Rym: So I listened to the real episode on the actual Ibsen, it's also fine.
Rym: The only conclusion I can reach is that we did just talk over each other a bunch, but that's actually what we did.
Rym: That was what it sounded like when we did the show.
Scott: Such a high quality podcast.
Scott: I don't know why you listen to it.
Rym: Yeah, I think at this point it's just momentum.
Rym: We are literally one of the longest running podcasts on earth.
Scott: Uh, I looked up recently to see who else is still out there.
Scott: that's been running long.
Scott: We, uh, there's like the one I could find that was going.
Scott: the longest was in the girl one that I've heard of, but I don't know anything about other than that.
Scott: Presumed the hosts are a person named Keith and someone who's a girl who's named the girl.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know anything about their show, but it's, it's long.
Scott: I think it's longer and has older, longer, still going and has more episodes.
Rym: I didn't say where.
Rym: the number one, but we're, we're definitely in like, I don't know, the 50 or a hundred old.
Scott: But the other thing is if you go and Google, right, and you look for old podcasts, you'll find like these lists, but the lists mostly have really popular ones that are like, you know, big and well known that have run long or had a lot of episodes.
Scott: But for example, right.
Scott: I know that they're comic geek speak who we haven't talked about cause I haven't listened to them in years.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I listen to them back in the iPod days.
Rym: Memories just flooded back into my head.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They've been going longer than us.
Scott: They're still going, uh, and I don't know which of us has more episodes or more record time.
Scott: Uh, but that doesn't, who really cares?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the point is none of the pot, like podcast lists have them on there because they're, you know, not, they're an obscure, you know, little thing, right?
Scott: A little, just like us.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, and there must be out there.
Scott: How many others are there out there like us?
Scott: Like, you know, comic geek speak and my world order, right?
Scott: About some other topic that we're not thinking about.
Scott: There could be some horse podcast or some, I don't know, butterfly.
Scott: I think of the animals, but like this is a flower podcast.
Scott: What a flora, fauna, mineral.
Scott: So a geology podcast.
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where it's been going on for a long ass time since iPod nanos or iPod minis.
Scott: And it's got a lot of episodes.
Scott: They never gave up on it.
Scott: And just know if you, no one, only people who listen to it know about it.
Scott: And if you say, what's the longest podcast, the only way you'll know is if one of those a hundred listeners happens to be in the chat at this point, the only data, cause like you said, there's no way to find this out.
Rym: The only thing I can really go on there is that we started pretty early and we are still around.
Scott: I mean, if you go, if you go to a general podcast place and say, what's the longest running podcast or what are the top longest running podcasts?
Scott: You know, no one will say GeekNights cause no one knows about us.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So there must be others like us who also, no one knows about.
Rym: We got to go around and find like the oldest podcasts and then do an old podcasters convention.
Scott: The only way to do it would be, cause even if you were to scan, like if you, if you had access to like the iTunes podcast library, like backend, you could find all the podcasts that have like an episode that's old and an episode that's new.
Scott: You could narrow it down.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But the RSS feeds have a limit on how many episodes we're, and we are the weird ones and that we keep like everything up forever.
Rym: Almost every long running podcast tries to make money and they sell access to their archives like PNE or I seen a bunch do that, but not all of them, but they just take old stuff down.
Rym: Like we're kind of weird.
Scott: Or someone stops maintaining or the podcast ends and people stop paying for it to be hosted and it just disappears.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: We're also in a weird boat because of, because of our old Libsyn deal, I don't know that we could afford to keep that archive up if we were not using this service.
Scott: We could migrate to another service, but the redirect thing would be a problem.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Also the long tail of bandwidth.
Scott: Like it would be fine for anyone getting, you know, who wanted to like just go download episodes because the RSS would be updated.
Scott: The website would be updated to new URLs, but you know, it probably wouldn't matter that much for the listener, but if there was any like old URL hanging out there, linking directly to the old Libsyn, that it would fail, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: As soon as Libsyn closed our account.
Rym: So, but anyway, uh, I guess we'll just get right into it.
Rym: There is a bunch of news.
Rym: We, uh, I don't think we, I think we skipped a Wednesday show recently, uh, but we did do Sonic, but anyway, let's get right into it.
Rym: So in the news, there is a little bit of a tragedy.
Rym: Uh, so the voice actor of, uh, Jigen Daisuke, Kiyoshi Kobayashi has passed away at 89, which 89, good job.
Rym: I hope that I make it to 89.
Scott: You know, some years ago, you know, the Lupin, cause Lupin was one of these interesting things where no matter how many TV shows, movies, et cetera, that they made, they just kept using the same voice actors right over and over.
Scott: And it wasn't until just a few years ago, right?
Scott: I remember, I think we did it as a news that they all sort of retired and stopped doing it cause they were all way old, right?
Scott: They've been doing that shit for like 30, 40 years.
Rym: Kiyoshi Kobayashi has been playing Jigen Daisuke since 1969.
Rym: He played that character for 52 years.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I feel like if he had not gotten pneumonia and become an old human, uh, our meat sacks only last, you know, 80 to 120 years at most.
Rym: I feel like he would have kept doing it forever.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Scott: But yeah, much like, you know, at the Looney Tunes situation, right?
Scott: Or the Mickey Mouse situation.
Scott: It's like, yeah, they want to keep making cartoons with the same characters, but you know, the, the original goofy voice, like ain't around anymore.
Rym: Mel Blanc can't live forever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, but because it's such a huge, popular character, there are so many talented voice actors who can just do the character that it's, you know, they find they'll find the best person on earth who can get close enough.
Scott: And at the same time, it's, it's actually nice, you know, at least in my opinion, for the person to not just be a perfect imitation, um, bring their own thing, like a little bit of an update to the character.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If they use, if they get their own style in there a bit, they'll do a, they'll be actually more expressive, at least I think.
Rym: Well, kind of like how every bond, every bond is a little bit different.
Rym: They didn't just all try to be exactly like Sean Connery.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then, you know, you can get different stuff and you know what, there might be someone who does it even better.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And, but the cool, the other nuts thing is he was the last remaining original cast member in Lupin.
Rym: at this point, just prior to his retirement, he held out as long, longer than anyone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like I said, everyone else kind of retired.
Scott: But while they were all really old and they're like, all right, that's enough.
Scott: He's like, okay.
Rym: So in some huge and somewhat unnerving news, uh, we've talked about this.
Rym: half the news we've done for the last two weeks has been giant companies all merging together, like the consolidation of every industry.
Rym: And here we are again, Crunchyroll has closed a deal to acquire Right Stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, so if you don't know, there's a company called Right Stuff in the US, right?
Scott: And they're basically sort of like an anime retailer slash distributor slash licenser.
Scott: And they also had a side hidden brand for hentai stuff.
Rym: I mean, they've been around since what?
Rym: Like '87, '88, like they were around.
Scott: They've been around as long as anime has been around.
Scott: And like, if you were in the United States and you wanted to get anime, especially before the anime boom of the early two thousands, it's like, they had like mail order catalog.
Rym: They were still like, was that the one that had the separate hentai section that was like, you could remove it from the catalog.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, but like they also had a licensing arm.
Scott: They were licensing and subbing dubbing animes, right?
Scott: Releasing them on disc, you know, for themselves, I guess.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they were a big important deal in, you know, United States anime industry and, you know, Funimation and Crunchyroll, the two streaming services.
Scott: Funimation is also a licenser, right?
Scott: It's Crunchyroll kind of also, and, you know, they came together and now you're bringing right stuff into all of the same company.
Scott: It's like, that's it.
Scott: That's US anime monopoly, right?
Scott: Game over.
Rym: And I'm waiting for Amazon to just buy the whole thing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like, all I can think about is like those mid two thousands Otakons where there were like so many US anime companies, right?
Rym: You know, there was that brief period where the, the expo hall at an anime con looked a little bit like what a PAX expo hall looks like today with like the cars and the Pika girls and all the nonsense.
Scott: But it's like there were just so many different anime companies all going at it, you know, and, and now there's just a lot less.
Scott: It's that as one, basically does disco tech off to the side being awesome, right?
Scott: With their getting the old stuff.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Meanwhile, G kid and his G kids coming through with the movies and then this funimation with like everything else.
Scott: I
Rym: wonder what this will mean now for my streaming, because when I look back at what anime I've watched recently, pretty much every anime I've watched that has not been in the theater has been on Netflix or has been from the high seas because it was from like a streaming service I wasn't paying for.
Rym: I actually haven't, I actually canceled my crunchy roll because I haven't watched anything on it in a while.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Rym: Despite being deep into anime still like, I don't know.
Scott: I might, you know, there might be some stuff I'm going to watch on there soon.
Rym: Crunchy roll is the kind of service I think.
Rym: finally, let's just make sure if whatever either one of us is going to sign up for it.
Rym: We agree to do it at the same time and watch as many like four episodes of the show so we can do a gig nights episode on them as we can before we shut that off again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, we'll have to see what the pricing is like too.
Scott: Cause pricing on streaming services is going up everywhere.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, uh, we'll see.
Rym: This is not bode well for the anime industry in the longterm, but it'll probably be easier for fans of anime in the short term.
Scott: Well, it's, it's, you know, like we talked about it when funimation and crunchy roll merged, right?
Scott: It's like, it's good for fans because now you can just go to one streaming service, one stop shop.
Scott: There's everything is all there.
Scott: It's bad for fans cause.
Scott: well, it's like now you don't have a choice.
Scott: There's no competition.
Scott: They can drive prices up.
Scott: They can just control everything and you're not going to always like what they decide and then you're going to be stuck.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So in some other news, you may remember a cute little show that Natasha Allegri put out long time ago, being puppy cat that had like a pilot and then like a short series.
Rym: So the for real being puppy cat, like the remake, the full deal.
Rym: We just got our trailer drop.
Rym: It's coming on Netflix.
Rym: Cartoon Crave has got the trailer.
Scott: It's like we, we kickstarted this thing like a hundred years ago.
Rym: I went to the launch party.
Rym: Like I met Fred there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then they friggin, uh, you know, they released it and then they released it sort of again.
Scott: ish, right?
Scott: It was like a pilot and then it was a series, but it never really finished.
Scott: all the way kinda.
Scott: And it's like now they're giving it a third go or a fourth go.
Scott: I don't even know how many goes.
Scott: it's been at this point.
Rym: I'd say this would really just be the third go, but what's fascinating is if you watch the trailer comics, there's I'm pretty sure there's comics.
Scott: There's all kinds of merchandise.
Scott: It's like, it's like there's just so.
Scott: it's like this thing is already a thing.
Scott: It's like, they're just like, okay, with an even bigger budget, we're going to just make the show again for real, for real, for real this time.
Rym: It's almost like I've never seen anything do it that way.
Rym: It's an interesting process.
Rym: Cause you sort of like with Steven Universe, there was that pilot that we all saw.
Rym: And then there was the real show, which looked very different.
Rym: That's the normal process, but it's interesting to get a pilot.
Rym: Then like a pilot series, like a second pilot that's longer.
Rym: And then the main thing, though, I don't think, I think that, I don't know what, you know, what had a pilot series.
Scott: It was, that was the series.
Rym: Well, but it didn't like fully flesh out or like explore everything.
Rym: Like it almost like touched on everything that was going to happen, but then just kind of stopped.
Rym: Like it didn't follow the plot that it had clearly set up.
Rym: But the original Star Trek had a little bit of a process like that.
Rym: If you look at how they actually made, they got that show going originally.
Rym: Many shows do have multiple rounds of pilots, but rarely do we get to see those pilots.
Rym: This is fun because we almost see like the evolution of this idea into ever increasingly polished forms.
Rym: But the trailer both shows that there is a real like show here with a lot of content.
Rym: Like there's a lot of new stuff.
Rym: Clearly it's going to be like, there's going to be something going on, but it specifically shows you the scenes from the original, uh, to remind you that it is still the same.
Rym: V and Puppycat she is still going to in the first episode hit Deckard in the nuts with her umbrella.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Uh, I mean, yeah, there are, there, I think there have been series where they would start off with a pilot and then go to like a mini series that was so popular that they had to keep going.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's happened quite a few times.
Rym: I'm actually pretty excited about this, especially considering, I don't know, it's one of those shows that raised a lot of interesting ideas and allegories, but then didn't finish them.
Scott: And I just like the aesthetic of the show.
Rym: I like the aesthetic and I like the, uh, the, the deep, probably this is going somewhere, Blade Runner, uh, analogies and references that are everywhere.
Scott: I'll wait until it is 100% done and then watch it at this point, you know, you know how it goes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Uh, that all our news.
Rym: So, but anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, you know, I told my tale of how I bought a cheap roller blade break and it was basically just counterfeit.
Rym: It was basically like a marker.
Rym: So I got real breaks now and skating again.
Rym: And I, uh, I stumbled upon just randomly while I was looking at like different kinds of breaks.
Rym: I was debating whether or not I wanted to get like a different kind of break for my or upgrade or mess with them since I had them out and taken apart anyway.
Rym: And I found a good video that is basically, uh, it's 15 things to make you a better skater.
Rym: And it's just this guy.
Rym: And he walks you through, like basically the exercises you would do if you already know how to roller blade, like you're already a decent rollerblader, but you want to get better at rollerblading specifically.
Rym: And, uh, these are the kinds of videos that I watch a lot for skiing.
Rym: And I used to watch a lot for mountain biking.
Rym: And despite the fact that I've rollerbladed my whole life, I never got lessons.
Rym: I never learned any formal tech.
Rym: I just rollerbladed, like never thought about it.
Scott: Where, where were there rollerblading lessons?
Rym: Uh, there were rollerblading lessons.
Rym: In fact, there was a rollerblading class in my high school you could take.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: We didn't have that.
Scott: I mean, Michigan nineties, like it was, you could do at the roller rink, you could take roller skating class.
Scott: So that was it.
Scott: There are a lot of rollerblades at the roller rink.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Our roller rink banned regular roller skates.
Rym: Only rollerblades were allowed.
Scott: The roller rink was like, it's a place for dancing.
Scott: It's not a place for racing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That roller rink was people just skated in a circle.
Rym: Like no one wanted to dance.
Scott: And yeah, people would, I mean, yeah, you could, most people skated in a circle cause they couldn't dance, but it was not a place for ice.
Scott: It was not a place for hockey and not a place for racing.
Rym: No, the roller rink, the roller rink I used to go to as a kid.
Rym: So regular skaters kept getting hit by people.
Rym: And like so often that they banned them from the place and it was rollerbladers only.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But, um, I never thought about it.
Rym: I just thought by rollerblade.
Rym: So this video, it's not like a video.
Rym: The reason I'm making this my thing of the day is that one of the best ways to learn something is to do it.
Rym: Uh, and a lot of tutorials online, like here is how to bike better or here's how to ski better.
Rym: They almost just show you like the technique of how to do a thing.
Rym: This video does the more enlightened way of it shows you here are weird things to try that will force you to get better.
Rym: Like it's an exercise that if you do, it will teach you something by doing the exercise as opposed to emulate what you see in this video to learn how to do the thing you see in the video.
Rym: That's how actually ski instruction usually goes.
Rym: I just never seen this for rollerblading before.
Rym: And this video is actually pretty good.
Rym: And I'm going to try to do a bunch of these exercises because I'm an okay plater.
Rym: I'm not great.
Scott: So you got, uh, so one of these, uh, nerdy, you know, there's a nerdy thing that I don't do because I don't have a lot of space.
Scott: Uh, and that nerdy thing is jigsaw puzzles, right?
Scott: Have we done an episode on those?
Scott: We can make it.
Rym: If we haven't, that's going to be, I'm going to look that up right now.
Rym: That's a great episode.
Scott: We've done puzzles of other kinds.
Scott: I don't think we did jigsaw.
Rym: I think we can do a whole episode on jigsaw puzzles.
Scott: We might have.
Scott: It's possible.
Rym: We might have the backend while you explain your thing of the day.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: Uh, you know, the ones I did as a kid, you know, we did, we have never done any episode that includes the word to jig in any capacity puzzle though.
Rym: So if I look for pus, we have done the solitaire puzzles and versus puzzle games.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know, I've always, you know, it's like, it's a nice relaxing thing to just like have around, right?
Scott: It's like when you got nothing to do, right.
Scott: Instead of poking the internet, it would be much better to do, just go sit by your jigsaw puzzle.
Scott: That's a much better use of your time than reading Twitter again.
Scott: If you got nothing else to do, but sit around your apartment, have it a puzzle out.
Scott: Pretty good.
Scott: You know, it's not the best, but it's, it's good.
Scott: It's fun.
Scott: So, you know, but there are some puzzles.
Scott: It's like, I just don't have room to do them.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: Like I have to, I live in an apartment in New York city.
Rym: If we want a table, I unfold a big table and guess what?
Rym: That table has got to be folded back the fuck up before long.
Rym: Cause it is in the way.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know, you got to imagine in the year 2022 that there is some like, you know, really unique puzzles out there that didn't exist, you know, when my back in the day and sure enough, here's the YouTube video and a YouTube channel called Karen puzzles as a jigsaw puzzle specialist, YouTube channel and Karen puzzles gets the, uh, what is this?
Scott: 24,000 piece puzzle, 24,000.
Rym: I remember doing puzzles that were like, watch out.
Rym: This motherfucker's got 3000 pieces.
Scott: The short side is like five something feet long.
Scott: And the long side is like 14 feet long.
Scott: It's it's it's large.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, what's disappoint.
Scott: What's obviously this is, you know, no small feet that, uh, this puzzle is completed in six parts and comes in six bags.
Scott: But I am disappointed in the fact that the six bags it's really.
Scott: Uh, 24,000 divided by six, four.
Scott: It's basically like, you know, six, 4,000 piece puzzles really that you then combine because each bag is well, but I would argue, I would point out that that is interesting and that it is.
Rym: It is an affordance to allow people who do not have a puzzle room to do this puzzle at all.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: But really it would be so epic to just, I mean, I guess there's nothing stopping you from buying this and just mixing all the bags together.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: It's not forcing you to do the puzzle.
Rym: I mean, I knew a guy in high school who was he would do puzzles, but he'd do them upside down and not try not to see what the image was till the end.
Rym: Like you get someone else to buy them for him.
Scott: I mean, let's I'll save my story about that for when we do an episode on this topic.
Scott: But I just want to point out my epic six part YouTube video completing this thing.
Rym: I dug around and there seems to be some consensus.
Rym: So a five hundred piece jigsaw puzzle is expected to take an average person who is not like a jigsaw puzzle expert between two and seven hours.
Rym: A one thousand one, a one thousand piece puzzle will generally take someone five to twelve hours.
Rym: So one thousand five to twelve hours.
Rym: So twenty four times that times the complexity of it's probably not a linear progression as these get bigger.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, you know, I could see knowing those times now I could see myself like do without one good.
Scott: I guess I'll just save all these things or we do an episode on it.
Rym: But this video is great, especially the.
Rym: the top comment says everything you need to know about these videos, quote, find someone that hypes you as much as Karen hypes this puzzle.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: The sheer joy of this puzzle building.
Rym: I even if there is a hobby that I don't particularly enjoy myself, there is something infectious about watching someone who loves the shit out of their hobby no matter what it is, unless it's something evil like being a Nazi.
Scott: I mean, I like I you know, I hate cars.
Rym: I want to remove all cars from Earth, but I watch a channel that is just a mechanic being awesome about fucking with old cars.
Scott: Like I did a thing of the day on Transmission Guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: In the moment, the GeekNights Book Club book is Binti.
Rym: I expect we will do the show on Thursday unless Scott somehow has not read this book.
Rym: Scott, there is no way this will take you more than 45 minutes to read.
Scott: It's not about finishing.
Scott: It's about starting.
Rym: Well, we'll see what we do this weekend.
Rym: But I suspect you can finish this book.
Rym: We'll do it in the next.
Rym: If we don't do it Thursday, we got to absolutely do it the following Thursday.
Rym: Mostly, I just want you to pick your next book so then we can begin the gambit choice that we're going to do going forward.
Scott: I told no, I have no ideas right now, so I got to come up with a gambit.
Rym: I revealed somewhere.
Rym: I will not say where.
Rym: What the two choices I'm going to put forth for you are.
Rym: And the feedback I got was quotes.
Rym: That will be delightful.
Rym: I'll bet he picks X. Obviously, the book is not called X, though.
Rym: That would be funny.
Rym: I cannot reveal.
Rym: It'll be funny.
Rym: I do want to read both of these books, so I'm fine either way.
Rym: I'll be alive at PAX West Sunday, September 4th, 12 30 p.m.
Rym: Pacific Time in the Sasquatch Theater, which is on the second floor of the Sheraton.
Rym: Losing, there is a decent chance.
Rym: Scott and I will be at PAX Unplugged at least doing a panel or two, because that is that con is like an hour drive from here, even if we don't stay to do anything else.
Scott: We'll see what the state of the world is then.
Rym: I mean, I will pretty much definitely be there doing a panel unless I'm physically prevented from doing it.
Rym: But we'll see what the odds are at us with the world will be like that.
Rym: That's not that far away.
Rym: Well, and I'll see websites coming along.
Rym: I think we don't have any planned disruptions coming up for the foreseeable future and get right into the main bit.
Scott: The main bit is, you know, which all right.
Scott: So yeah, years ago, right, it was announced.
Rym: I got to find the episode where we like we found out there was a rumor he was making a new movie and we were like, oh, right.
Scott: It's like there was.
Scott: there was like, you know, Masaaki Yuasa, Saenzaru was making a new movie, or at least we knew they were going to make another movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the next movie was called Inuo, and we didn't know much about it at all, other than that's what it was called.
Scott: And there was like an image like, you know, a like a prototype of the movie poster.
Scott: And we knew absolutely nothing about it.
Scott: More recently.
Scott: Right.
Scott: An actual movie trailer came out very recently.
Rym: And I actually have that movie trailer up because I wanted to quote it right now because the trailer actually describes what genre this movie is in perfectly.
Rym: I'm just going to read this from William Bibbiani at the wrap.
Rym: The best feudal Japanese hair metal demonic curse serial killer political tragedy rock opera of the year.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much it is that that is what this movie is.
Scott: So yeah, that's when we saw the real trailer.
Scott: That's when he figured out what the movie was like, which is not at all what I expected.
Scott: But yeah, we got to see it because the Japan Center in New York City, a fine institution, got to have the East Coast premiere of the movie ahead of the more general G Kids release in the United States.
Scott: So everyone else is going to be able to see this movie, at least in the United States.
Scott: on G Kids website says August 12th, two days from now.
Scott: And I guess maybe one day if you're listening to this tomorrow.
Scott: Whereas we saw it like last week.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now what I will say before we go any further, we will avoid spoiling anything until the end of the episode, of course.
Scott: But I know we say I think there's not much I can say without spoil.
Rym: We'll argue when we're going to start like spoiling stuff because there are some things I want to discuss.
Rym: Yeah, but I'll say this.
Rym: We know we always say if there's an anime movie and we talk about it on GeekNights and it's not just a sequel to an existing long running anime franchise.
Rym: If you're even like partially an anime fan, just watch it.
Rym: There aren't that many.
Rym: They're usually.
Rym: they're usually very good.
Scott: I have even if it's not the best.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even if it's kind of so.
Scott: so if there is an anime movie with an original story, it's not just Pokemon, the movie, one piece, the movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's nothing like that that you just go see it because there aren't that many of them.
Scott: You can see them all.
Scott: There's only a handful a year.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And even if they're and they usually have some merit that makes it worth your 90 minutes.
Scott: It's not like investing in a whole TV series.
Scott: And so you know, just on that alone.
Scott: Yes, you should see it because of those same reasons, because it is also an original story anime movie.
Rym: So with this one, I'm going to go further and say, just go see it.
Rym: Don't even read anything else about it.
Rym: Just go see it, because it is a ride.
Rym: I haven't seen a movie like it.
Scott: I'm going to go even further than that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't want to I don't want to go too far.
Scott: But I will say of I went through and I looked at all the original, you know, full length feature anime movies that have come out over the years because I've seen almost most of them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The vast majority of them.
Scott: And I think in order to find one that I like more than Inoue based on only a one viewing judgment, I think you have to go back to Paprika and like two thousand whatever.
Rym: I mean, I'm going back to like Bell was in spittin.
Scott: distance is the night is short.
Rym: Walk on Girl is definitely close up there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Those are way up there.
Scott: But I think, you know, I Lou over the wall, you know, actually, you know, to the how many?
Rym: How many Masaki Yuasa's did I just list there?
Scott: One.
Scott: Well, Inoue was one and Walk on Girl is the other one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Ride your wave.
Scott: Bell is hosted.
Scott: So is there any hosted a movie that you like more than Inoue?
Scott: Do you like Summer Wars more than Inoue?
Rym: I don't think I do.
Rym: Bell.
Rym: I liked.
Rym: I liked a lot, though, where I was really good.
Scott: But but it's like I don't like.
Scott: I like.
Scott: those are great.
Scott: I don't like any of them more than that.
Scott: Like Inoue.
Scott: Is there any Makoto Shinkai thing you like more than Inoue?
Rym: You see, it's been a while.
Rym: I guess I'd have to watch the one that made me cry the hardest with you.
Rym: Place from his early days of all his works made me cry the hardest.
Rym: But that was a long time ago.
Rym: I got to see if Old Man Rym will still cry to that amount.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I'm saying is like, you know, of the of the newer anime directors that are active right now that are putting out the movies, the ones that get a G Kids release and a guaranteed night's episode, those right Miyazaki.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: what Miyazaki movie do you like better than Inoue?
Rym: Oh, I mean, I as a weirdo almost want to say The Wind Rises, but I very specifically like what that movie was doing.
Rym: But then I have to start differentiating movie.
Rym: I like on this intellectual allegorical level versus movie.
Scott: I enjoy watching and there are Miyazaki movies I like more than Inoue.
Scott: I like Lapita more than Inoue.
Rym: I like my favorite still.
Scott: I like Spirited Away more than I like Inoue.
Scott: It's easy, easy.
Scott: Totoro's better than Inoue.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was an easy call.
Scott: I guess what I'll say is this delivery service I like more than Inoue.
Rym: Those are all old.
Scott: Those are all older than Paprika.
Rym: But you know, that movies like it takes a really good movie to do this.
Rym: This movie just sucked me in and that I forgot.
Rym: I was in the theater.
Rym: I was completely immersed.
Rym: And when the movie ended, it was a moment of, oh, shit, I'm in the real world.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But also, right.
Scott: The point summary, I think this is my favorite anime movie since 2006 and maybe the best since 2006.
Scott: I can't say that for sure right now, but I'm leaning that way.
Rym: Go see this movie.
Rym: And if you can safely go see it in a theater because that bit in the trailer about it being a rock opera, it is a rock opera.
Rym: I want to go back and see how many minutes of screen time are a song versus not a song because I feel like that number is really high.
Rym: The movie didn't just suck me in like a good movie does in the movie.
Rym: It is you basically get characters telling an ancient tale to you via music in the context of the movie.
Rym: That is itself a tale.
Rym: And I wasn't just sucked into the movie.
Rym: I was sucked into the tale they were telling in the movie to the point that when we got home, I read the entire fucking Wikipedia article.
Rym: Unlike the Heike clan and what the hell happened in this battle.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, so, yeah, exactly.
Scott: I think that's really I was going to.
Scott: when we start talking about spoilers, I was going to talk about how this movie tells, like, several stories like that are all layered on top of each other.
Scott: But that element, I think, is the core element in that the plot is about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: These characters are trying to tell these ancient forgotten stories so that they are remembered within the movie.
Scott: But what's really happening is that exact same thing is happening in the meta.
Scott: Masaki Yuasa is the characters telling us the real audience, the stories.
Scott: So that they're remembered right via a story about someone trying to do what he is successfully doing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that meta element, which we've seen a lot of lately, or at least, you know, is in a lot of things.
Scott: Period is working in sort of a new way.
Scott: I haven't seen that exact layering element before where you depict somebody doing something to achieve a goal, while the artwork, the movie itself is somebody else achieving the goal that is depicted.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like if I'm it would be like if I was trying to stop climate change and somehow I succeeded by making a movie in which there is a person trying to stop climate change and the movie successfully stops climate change.
Rym: And it's like and especially with the end, like what happens in the very beginning and the very end of the movie.
Rym: And without spoilers, this movie does that thing.
Rym: And you picked up on it, too, where it shows you a scene and then the movie kind of starts and everyone watching the movie forgets about that scene.
Rym: And then the very end, just when you think, wait a minute, what it comes back to that scene and the movie, one of the big themes it has is the contiguous connection of humans telling their stories over the course of history and how that thread is still alive for things that are terrifyingly ancient and forgotten.
Rym: Like there's always this thread.
Rym: There's always this echo of memory that survives.
Rym: Even when memories and ideas are repressed, it's very hard to destroy human knowledge.
Rym: And even though we'll lose big swatches of it, like these pieces still remain.
Rym: So what is it like to watch this movie?
Rym: A little bit into it, and I would.
Rym: this is not really a spoiler, but the movie starts starts telling a pretty good story.
Rym: And then a song starts in the movie.
Rym: The character starts playing a song and then the movie almost turns into a sort of montage of songs being performed by those characters that span years and years and years and years and years.
Rym: And that song doesn't stop for a long time.
Rym: Very much like a rock opera.
Rym: Trying to think of what else I can say without, let's see, the music's great.
Rym: The music is varied to the point that every stage of the music in the show is a completely different style.
Rym: The animation is phenomenal.
Rym: The animation of the characters dancing is off the wall.
Rym: And I don't know what else I could really say other than go watch this movie unless we.
Scott: only other non-spoiler thing, right, is that you have the music.
Scott: Who are the two?
Scott: The two rock singers they got?
Rym: No, we got.
Rym: we got.
Rym: we got you know himself and we got the blind kid Tomona.
Scott: Well, no, but the actual the actual human being.
Rym: Oh, the band.
Rym: Oh, God.
Rym: I don't have any of that open.
Scott: Here we go.
Scott: Avu Chan and Mariah Moriyama.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So Avu Chan was the lead vocalist and songwriter of the band Queen B in 2009.
Scott: I'm reading this on Wikipedia, if you didn't know.
Scott: And the band Goku Monto Ika in 2015.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that's the person who is the the voice of Inuo.
Scott: And then Mariah Moriyama is.
Scott: it just says Japanese act.
Scott: Oh, they were like a musical person.
Scott: They were in the Japanese version of Rent and such.
Rym: So kind of like how in Carol and Tuesday you have a musical act that is also the actors like doing the show or doing them.
Rym: This is a very similar thing.
Rym: You've got these two musicians playing these like doing this music in the context of this story about two musicians making music.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Rym: So we're going to spoil stuff.
Rym: I feel like we have to to talk about this movie.
Rym: I honestly just go see it as soon as you can.
Rym: But Warren, we're going to start spoiling things as we go on.
Rym: There's a few shocking moments that happen that are worth addressing.
Rym: But I think this movie will be equally compelling, even if you know exactly what's going to happen.
Scott: So the thing like I was saying before, this movie is several stories.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All told, like on top of each other.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: On one story, there's a little bit of a of an Amadeus story, like a little bit.
Rym: There's there's a Mozart, Salieri, even though that is a very facile comparison.
Rym: It's more funny to say it that way than to actually line it up one to one.
Rym: But there's definitely the story of.
Rym: there is the senior respected musician, but then the world gravitates toward this upstart who he doesn't like because it's stealing his thunder and he wants revenge.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, and then the band, the upstart band, right, has its own story of, you know, the typical rock band story of, you know, people get together, form a rock band.
Scott: They're fucking legends.
Scott: They take the world by storm and one of them sells out and one of them is in it for the music and, you know, the true artist.
Scott: And it doesn't go well for them.
Scott: It's like that's a classic tale.
Rym: You've also got the tale of the music they make is new.
Rym: They have made a new scene and that scene threatens the existing political order to the point that the government represses it, which is also a tale that has happened in the real world time and time again.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You have the tale, the sort of folk tale of a someone who is cursed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And is, you know, disabled, disfigured in some way.
Scott: It's it's somewhat similar to a Tezuka's Dororo.
Rym: Ah, I was going to bring that up.
Scott: Where the guy's born with like nothing because because of a deal with like what was like a whole bunch of demons.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Same kind of deal.
Scott: There was a, you know, many, you know, there was a deal with demons that results in a person being born with not the greatest body.
Scott: And then by doing certain things, they are able to, you know, get their body to be, you know, quote, you know, normal.
Scott: But there's also it's a tale of, you know, disability and, you know.
Rym: Well, for both of them, because you have you have a disfigured social outcast and you have someone who is blinded in an incident when they were a child and they come together.
Rym: And these two disabled people form the greatest rock band in Japanese history.
Rym: But you've also got the story of two societal outcasts.
Scott: Also the common trope of, you know, the sort of disfigured person and the blind person.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They don't judge them because they can't see them.
Scott: kind of deal that happens a lot.
Rym: You have got a demon story where the current court musician made a deal with a demon to get the secret tales so he could have unique music and he could bring something to an existing music scene that no one else had.
Rym: But the deal he made was he gave up one of his sons and the demon took his son and made this son into the musical genius that would destroy him.
Rym: And there's a whole serial killer murder plot there that turns into an allegorical story of.
Rym: there was no demon.
Rym: He was just a fucking serial killer who was also trying to cover up anyone who could compete with his music for the court for his court job, basically.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Then you've got the political story of the Heike clan was destroyed.
Scott: And so we got to talk about the Heike clan here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, I think the movie does.
Scott: perhaps one of the only negative things I can say about it is that if you know absolutely nothing about the tale of the Heike, then you might be a little confused at the movie.
Scott: You have to at least know a tiny amount.
Scott: I know a tiny amount, even though a woodblock depicting a famous part of the tale of the Heike has been above my bed for like, you know, basically.
Scott: I think as also the Japan Society, ironically enough, just, I guess, coincidentally, I don't know, like 2010, we went to the Japan Society and there's a woodblock print exhibition.
Rym: That is where I learned everything that I know off the top of my head about this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so I'm looking at all the wood blocks and the one that I was drawn to the most was this one.
Scott: And in it is a depiction of a scene from the tale of the Heike.
Scott: And I ordered like, you know, an MFA fancy high quality print of it.
Scott: And I framed it and I put it up.
Scott: So the basic story is that in the thing about the tale, the Heike is that it's not completely fake and it's not completely real.
Scott: It's a thing that actually happened.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There is archaeological evidence.
Scott: This is real.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, there was that there we know there was a court drama.
Rym: There was a coup.
Rym: This was like late Hayen.
Scott: Like, so like this is like eleven hundreds, the 12th century.
Scott: This happened.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So towards the end of the era depicted in the tale of Genji, the tale is a real thing that happened.
Scott: But the stories surrounding it because of, you know, it's like how much real info do we have?
Scott: It's not like they had cameras then have become like a fantastic tale over time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Thanks to fictional retellings, you know, oral tradition, literary tradition, etc.
Scott: But what you need to know about the story is that at the time, Japan was split in two.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There was basically a Shogun in the north and a Shogun in the south.
Scott: And one of them, the north one, I think, was the Heike.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And Emily told me the reason that they have two names is because the Kanji, the character for Heike can also be read as Tyra.
Scott: So a lot of times you'll see the Tyra clan instead of the Heike, but they're the same thing.
Scott: And in the south was the Matsumoto, I think.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which also known as Genji, interestingly enough, was the other clan.
Scott: And so these two clans were at war.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, they weren't friendly with each other.
Scott: Little Hatfield McCoy situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because who was going to actually rule all of Japan?
Scott: It was split into.
Scott: there should be one emperor, one Shogun, whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, that kind of deal.
Scott: And I came to a head at this battle, the Battle of Dan-no-ura.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which was Dan-no-ura is basically, you know, the south island in Japan.
Scott: What's the name of that island?
Scott: But basically in between that island.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the big Japan island.
Scott: The long one is like a little straight.
Scott: And that's where they had a naval battle there.
Scott: And that naval battle was basically the decisive battle between the Heike and the other ones.
Scott: And the Heike did not win.
Scott: They were exterminated and they took their treasures down to the bottom of the sea.
Scott: Like the, you know, the right.
Scott: They were like, that's it.
Scott: And so it's not one of those stories where it's like, you know, one was evil and one was good.
Scott: It was like there were just two of them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And this one won and that one lost.
Scott: It's not like, ah, the evil Heike or the right.
Scott: And so that's right in over time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You had the sort of legendary status thing going on with the Heike crabs where in that area, because it was a naval battle, there are crabs because crabs live everywhere.
Scott: They're the ultimate evolutionary existence.
Rym: I think we both watched that video.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And some of the crabs looked like, uh, you know, the shape of the crab was somewhat similar to a, you know, a samurai face, you know, something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so the fishermen in that area believed that this is true.
Scott: They believed that those are like the dead Heike were, you know, coming back as crabs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So when the crabs looked like samurai too much, they would throw them over.
Scott: They wouldn't take those ones.
Rym: And so due to the evolution, I read up on that that night as well.
Rym: There is no possibility that there was any selection pressure.
Rym: They have always just looked like that.
Scott: Oh, they've always just looked like that.
Rym: Yeah, I read.
Rym: I read a lot at the night after we watched that movie, but it's, I guess it's interesting that the legend was still there.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: A bunch of samurai died here in a battle and their clan was dispersed.
Rym: And there are rumors of like Heike holdouts that we never found.
Scott: They literally call them Heike crabs.
Scott: That's the name of the crab.
Rym: You're some fishermen and you know, like this epic samurai battle happened here and they all died and there's probably ghosts.
Rym: And then you go fishing and a bunch of crab that looked like samurai come up.
Rym: You would definitely believe that there was a connection and it would be hard to follow you.
Scott: I zoomed in on Google maps and I can even see on Google maps here.
Scott: Dan Noura Battlefield.
Scott: So there's clearly his pictures, right?
Scott: It's like there's definitely some touristy shit you can see down there if you go.
Rym: But I guess the important thing you need to know in the movie, which is just simply that the Heike lost the battle and lost the war effectively.
Scott: So and now the other the other group, you know, now rules Japan.
Rym: So history was written by the winners and knowledge of what the Heike were about, what they're up to was generally suppressed.
Rym: So you basically in the movie, you have the situation where there's the one dude, the Salieri, who is the one who's allowed to tell tales about the Heike.
Rym: Nobody else is.
Rym: And depending on how you read the movie, either a demon told him those stories to tell or he's telling false tales or tales that he made up or collected in some way on his own, probably unethically, especially if you read into that thing with the regalia and the sword and why the kid was blinded in the beginning, which clearly was him sending people out to like find these artifacts and consolidate his victory and destroy knowledge of the Heike.
Rym: There's a lot going on there.
Rym: We'll get into in a minute.
Rym: So then suddenly, you know, and this up like this upstart band just start singing new stories about the Heike.
Scott: And yeah, there's these stories, right?
Scott: So there's Biwa monks, right?
Scott: And basically, you know, they're a real thing also, right?
Scott: They're monks who play the Biwa, an instrument that was also in the tale of Genji, right?
Scott: Once you see a Biwa or hear one, you'll know what it is.
Scott: Yeah, it's a musical instrument.
Scott: And so these monks who are blind would travel around playing the Biwa, telling stories to get money and survive, right?
Scott: Often together in groups for safety.
Scott: But like they were a thing.
Scott: And so in the movie, they're depicted going around, right?
Scott: To try to talk to people who were around in the Heike times or have been passed down.
Scott: You know, it's like they'll visit small villages and be like, Hey, has anyone here have any Heike stories that have been orally passed down?
Scott: Teach me them.
Scott: And then I'll take them around and teach them to other people so that they're not forgotten.
Rym: So it's interesting if I have this one reading, I think on the beginning is, you know, we see that they basically the imperial people come to the town and they hire local divers to go try to find artifacts from the battle because they're looking for the regalia and they find the cursed sword and the sword blinds the kid and kills the dead.
Rym: It is easy to read that literally if you take the demon that we see later as literal.
Rym: It's also easy to read that as an allegory.
Rym: And like, that's what the kid remembers.
Rym: Like, that's the last thing he saw.
Rym: But really, maybe the emperor saw, I guess, the Shogun in this case, because it was a as far as I can tell, I'm not super up on late.
Rym: Hey, there is a Shogun.
Rym: Yeah, but might have been sending imperial emissaries down to find that regalia because it is important to solidifying the rule and also maybe killing anyone who knows too much about exactly what happened in the Heike and suppressing the knowledge of the rival faction.
Rym: So maybe imperial troops came and just blinded the kid and murdered the dad and the kid remembered it as the cursed sword related to the Heike themselves.
Scott: Yeah, could be.
Scott: I mean, you know, if you think like, again, the wood block that I have, right, what it depicts is the sort of after the battle, right?
Scott: You know, Yoshitsune, who is in charge of the other clan, the one that's not the Minamoto.
Scott: That's what it is, right?
Scott: Did I say Matsumoto?
Rym: You did, I think.
Rym: I can go back and listen.
Scott: Minamoto clan is the one that's not.
Scott: the was the one that won, right?
Scott: And the leader was Yoshitsune, right?
Scott: And that the Shogun and then also Benkei, the warrior monk, was on that team as well.
Scott: Another legendary figure.
Scott: But it depicts after the battle, right?
Scott: They're sailing somewhere and it's like the ghosts of the Heike are coming to haunt their asses, right?
Scott: Like, you know, make it, fuck it up the water Poseidon style, being like, ooh.
Rym: I mean, part of what the Biwa priests were all about is placate all those angry ghosts.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So it's like every time I see a Heike story of some kind, it's like that theme is there somehow where it's like, it's not about the Heike.
Scott: You know, I mean, there is an anime tale of the Heike that's on crunchy roll right now.
Scott: that I presume tells.
Scott: Yeah, I'm going to watch it at some point, but I presume it tells the actual story.
Scott: But almost every time I've seen the Heike story come up in some other work, it's always about somehow relating to the Heike coming back to haunt, right?
Scott: Or, you know, revenge beyond the grave.
Scott: And Inoue is another example of that, right?
Rym: And think about everything we said earlier about what this movie is about, like all the different ways to read it, all the different stories it tells that all overlap with each other.
Rym: They all together are tied.
Rym: They're tied together specifically just by this root story of these people were real people who lived and died.
Rym: That not memory of them was suppressed like their clan, just like the kid with his dad, like his dad's ghost is telling him, man, tell my story.
Rym: Get revenge.
Rym: Don't let our line die.
Rym: Even though he's like, fuck you, Dad, I'll change my name as much as I want.
Rym: But all these ghosts want is for someone to know they existed.
Rym: Just hear their story.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's what they want.
Rym: And the way that is depicted in this movie to drive all those different readings and allegories is fantastic.
Rym: Those songs that get played, I was deeply invested in those tales of what happened to those soldiers on those ships.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's the meta thing that we talked about before the spoiler line, right?
Scott: It's like they're trying to sing music to get these people within the story.
Scott: They're trying to tell people the story of the Heike and make them care about it and remember it.
Scott: But actually me, the real person, right, is being told that story.
Scott: And now I care about it, right?
Rym: But the best part, they never show the battle that they're talking about.
Rym: They don't animate that directly.
Rym: You just see the band singing about it with the band's primitive late Han era, not historical special effects.
Scott: And that's the funny.
Scott: That was a really great thing.
Scott: It's like they're imagining how could somebody put on a rock concert in whatever year this is.
Rym: And it grows.
Rym: Like it starts with.
Rym: just they got the big guys just breathing fire, like constantly behind them while they're rocking out.
Rym: Like that was great.
Scott: It's like they make up like, well, how could it be done with the level of technology they had?
Scott: How could someone do a light show?
Scott: Well, they could do it like this.
Scott: So then not only do they draw this light show.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's all an animation, right?
Scott: They could draw whatever they want.
Scott: They draw a light show and then they draw pictures of somebody with a contrived theoretical means of doing a light show with ancient technology.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you didn't have to draw that, but you did.
Scott: And it's like, you know, when you think about the fact that that is something like someone drew that picture.
Rym: Storytelling as storytelling.
Rym: I think my favorite level, my favorite, especially as they're so different, my favorite of those effects like that bit, the song about the whale and the tie.
Scott: The whale is, I think, the best song in the whole.
Rym: Absolutely the best song, but also the best.
Rym: Well, there were the visuals.
Rym: I like the most like that set piece, but the the most luscious visuals are definitely the final set of songs that they do with a giant crane and the glam rock set.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, there's a lot of, you know, I'd say, you know, a lot of it is really just like a queen parody.
Rym: Well, there's.
Rym: it seems like it covers a lot of parody, but homage styles and types of music like you can like each of the set pieces of music is like a mishmash of references to a bunch of different bands and a bunch of different musical styles.
Rym: But it definitely gets extremely clean, especially toward the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The whale, you know, felt to me like it was directly referencing like Live Aid.
Scott: Because the whole focus, even if you listen to the soundtrack, right, it's on it's on all the streaming services is it's the whale?
Scott: song is all about the fact that like now the crowd is like at its peak.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The crowd is enormous.
Rym: The crowd is rising, just like the tide rose with the whole.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the whale song is just focused almost entirely on this huge call and response element where the crowd is like in unison.
Scott: And it's like you don't see that at concerts.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Other than right.
Scott: There was Live Aid and what other concert has that?
Scott: It's not that that goes down like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then the final song is so like not even not subtle at all.
Scott: Bohemian Rhapsody.
Scott: Oh, my gosh.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I got chills when that song starts off ballady and then it gets bouncy and then it gets right.
Scott: It's it's like they're not even trying to hide the fact.
Rym: I love how at the end of all that, that ridiculous visual in some of the final scenes, you do see in the background a giant crane that was clearly to let him swing across everything.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What else can we say about this thing?
Rym: So I do it.
Rym: I liked how they portrayed the jealous like the person who was taking the head details before, because like I said, you can read him as he's just a serial killer.
Rym: Like he's just going around killing the monk.
Scott: It wasn't serial.
Scott: He had an emotive.
Scott: serial killers have no motive.
Rym: Depends.
Rym: I mean, arguably serial killer just came out of the old terminology sequence killer, which just meant someone who kills many people over a span of time with the same methodology.
Scott: OK, the point is right.
Scott: He was clearly the murderer.
Rym: Yeah, but he was either the murderer directly because he was evil and crazy or he hired or he was working with that demon and the demon was responsible.
Rym: But really, he asked the demon for help.
Rym: It doesn't really matter.
Rym: I like, you know, my jam.
Rym: Same reason I like shows like your tenor.
Rym: Whenever the allegorical reading and the literal reading work equally well.
Rym: That is like the chef kiss of media for me.
Rym: The only thing that could get me harder is precursor technology mixed in.
Scott: Yeah, it honestly doesn't matter which way it goes.
Rym: But the moment where he like I thought he was going to go try to kill them and like ruin their performance, I did not expect him to just pop.
Rym: What's extra funny is the crowd did not react that strongly to like the eyeball bouncing like after he just popped when the demon killed him.
Rym: But when then you see the finger just like stuck to the wall, like slowly sliding at that moment, that's when the whole crowd went all at once.
Rym: There's like a shutter that went through the theater.
Scott: I mean, like for for for a movie that's actually pretty light on the, you know, anything that would be a content warning.
Scott: It's like that is like one brief scene was like, whoa, I read that as him committing suicide.
Rym: Yeah, probably, especially because you had the angry, you know, his sword is getting angrier and angrier every time they're succeeding.
Rym: And especially with the cultural sensibilities of the era.
Rym: He could not commit murder on that scale and get away with it.
Rym: He was consumed to the point they just had to destroy himself.
Rym: But if you read it with the demon, the demon is great because the demon is just like, you made a deal with me.
Rym: You said I could have your son.
Rym: I can do whatever I want with your son.
Rym: I did that.
Rym: So if you tell me to kill your son, you are taking away the thing that I like.
Scott: You're giving up telling me to destroy what's already mine.
Scott: Fuck you.
Rym: Like quit while you're ahead.
Rym: You're the court musician.
Rym: You're safe.
Rym: Like, don't?
Rym: what's wrong with you?
Scott: Well, he wasn't the court.
Scott: That was the whole thing.
Scott: So the the he should have been the court musician in his eyes.
Scott: Shogun slash emperor is the most popular.
Scott: no theater in town was by this dude.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What was his name?
Scott: The evil dude.
Rym: I forget his name.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But he had the most popular no theater in town.
Scott: It was popular with all the people and it was supposedly the best one.
Scott: And so he makes the deal with the demon, though, to sort of keep that position going.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so the demon gives him the, you know, you know, son.
Scott: So, you know, is his son.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But he also gives them all like new tales of the heck.
Scott: And so the, uh, what was I saying?
Rym: We were talking about Salieri.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, oh, so he's most popular in town, but the emperor does not have him perform for him.
Scott: Emperor has this other second no theater perform because like the emperor's daughter is a fan of this other one.
Scott: So even though everyone knows that sort of the Salieri guys, one is the best.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He doesn't get to perform for the emperor because the emperor's daughter likes a different one.
Rym: His daughter's fun.
Rym: I love, I love the crowd scenes of her and all the people in the crowd reacting to the performance too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so then, right, you know, when, when Inoue comes along, you know, with the, with the rock band and the new stories, right.
Scott: From all the spirits that he talks to, right.
Scott: He takes down sort of both, right.
Scott: It's like with their new rock and roll style, not only do they take down, you know, the no theater that was popular with the people, they also take down the no theater that was popular with the emperor and his daughter, right.
Scott: And they replace.
Scott: So it's like first they take out one.
Scott: Then when they take out both, that's what pushes the guy over the edge.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because it's like, you know.
Rym: You also had half the deal and now he's got nothing, which reminds me of yet another story had told.
Rym: There is the upper class performance arts that they portray, like what is acceptable, socially acceptable and popular.
Rym: And then great balls of fire style, some loud upstarts, making nonsense music outside.
Rym: And bit by bit, there's that great scene where the court, like the famous dancers performing the really, really slow upper high class, very special dance.
Rym: And then some dipshit just runs in.
Rym: He's like, Hey, the crazy guys by the water are doing something cool.
Rym: Everybody runs out to see that.
Rym: And there's only like six nobles sitting there watching this and everyone else goes to see the cool band.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, this is just.
Rym: you got that great bit where even the viewer like, what's up with him anyway?
Rym: Yeah, they got like long hair and makeup and WTF.
Rym: I thought they were monks.
Scott: I think it's just.
Scott: it's really like a genius, a genius work.
Scott: It spoke to me.
Rym: So I hope it speaks to you, too.
Rym: There is zero.
Rym: Just watch this movie.
Rym: I think people who have never seen an anime will enjoy this movie.
Rym: Just make just get in front of people and it's a ride.
Rym: And before you know it, it'll suddenly end.
Scott: I mean, I think I don't know if it's like.
Scott: it's like there are better anime movies, right?
Scott: It's like Akira is better than this.
Scott: Ghost in the Shell is better than this, right?
Scott: It's like that's it.
Scott: But that doesn't mean I'm going to still say it's S tier, even though it's not the essence of the S tier.
Scott: It's still in that same realm.
Rym: Absolutely.
Rym: If I could watch it right now and not regret those ninety eight minutes.
Rym: Just watch it again.
Scott: Yeah, I was so surprised it was only ninety eight minutes.
Scott: I was like, whoa, there's a lot worse ways to spend ninety eight minutes.
Scott: Most things you could do are a worse way to spend ninety eight minutes than watching this movie.
Scott: So I hope you are able to see it in the theater in a day or two when it is in theaters in the United States or who knows wherever you live.
Scott: It is getting some sort of distribution worldwide.
Scott: If you're in Japan, I'm sure you've had a chance to see it already plenty of times.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: You know, it'll eventually, I'm sure, be streaming in and Blu rays and all that business at some point.
Scott: So don't you know, you'll have your chance.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the GeekNights Patreon patrons for this episode are Alan Joyce, Linki G, Dread Lily, Tenebreyon, Bunch of Bepple who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Chris Hadad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Kishaya Yaw, 85, Rebecca Dunn, Review, Madbull34, Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horl, Stop All the Downloading, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Shepherd West, Shepherd West Station, and a bunch of people whose names I will not say.
Rym: I look forward to finding out if Scott is going to choose to read a book about the character Garak from Star Trek written by the actor or Foucault's Pendulum.
Rym: That will be the terrifying choice that sits before Scott.
Rym: This is the second time I've revealed it.
Rym: I don't think he will find out what the choice is going to be unless one of you tell him until the book club after the book club after Binti.
Rym: But anyway, tonight I'm really hungry so I'm just going to sign off and leave you with... I mean, I just heard the phone over and said take the stuff off.
Rym: Can I have you look in the very bottom below the very bottom left corner?
Scott: Is that the phone number?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you did get my text messages and said you didn't.
Scott: Nice trick.
Rym: Yes, Mr.
Rym: Jones.
Rym: Indeed.
Rym: You didn't give this text message to me.
Rym: You don't know where this came from.
Rym: Do you know where I got this?
Rym: No.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Jones, did you know that 12 days ago, 12 days ago, your attorneys met up and sent an entire digital copy of your entire cell phone with every text message you've sent for the past two years and when informed,
Scott: did not take any steps to
Rym: identify it as privileged or protected in any way.
Rym: And as of two days ago, it fell free and clear into my possession.
Rym: And that is how I know.
Rym: you lied to me when you said you didn't have a text message about saying it.