Rym: It's Monday, June 13th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights!
Rym: Tonight, AI and machine learning are a hot topic for a bunch of reasons, so we're gonna talk a little bit about that.
Rym: And know your chatbot is not sentient.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: This was one of the longer hiatus we've ever had in GeekNights, and it was only because the NHL couldn't do as a solid and scheduled the Stanley Cup playoffs opposite GeekNights.
Scott: They had to schedule them.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: So first of all, they scheduled it the best they've ever scheduled it.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: Every other night, right?
Scott: The problem was that A, we talked about this before.
Scott: We had tickets to every home game, which we've never had in our lives.
Scott: B, we kept fucking winning, which means we kept playing.
Scott: And C, two series go to seven and another one go to six.
Scott: So it's like we didn't have a break.
Scott: If they would have swept someone, we could have had a GeekNights time in there.
Rym: I mean, what I expected was the Rangers to crush the pens, get crushed by Carolina, and that's it.
Rym: And then instead, I got game seven, game seven, and then a 4-2 series.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then on top of that, other life shit was going on.
Scott: I think I discussed this on all the other platforms.
Scott: So basically, I unexpectedly got a new job.
Scott: I was not looking for a new job.
Scott: I was very happy with the job I had.
Scott: If you want to work at the place I was working, there's openings and it's a good place to work.
Scott: If the new job is a trap, which it very well could be, I would go back there, no question.
Scott: But yeah, so, you know, recruiters, you know, they come to me and it's like, you know, I'm very sort of, you know, professional, but also somewhat aggressive with them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In terms of like, you know, I'm like, look, you know, if your job is immoral, then I'm just I'm like, no, I won't work there.
Scott: Bye.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If the job is morally acceptable, I'm like, all right, well, is it better be better than the job I have?
Scott: The job I got is real good.
Rym: And there's two things I'll take.
Rym: Like, I would take better because it's engaging work.
Rym: better because it's better for the world.
Rym: Like it's activism or it pays so much more that I'll just take the money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, some months ago, someone did make me an offer for more engaging, more.
Scott: at least the product was, I guess, somewhat more interesting than music publishing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, it was it was cool.
Scott: And, you know, but when it came time to actually make me an offer, it was similar monies.
Scott: And I was like, you know, this is not better than the job I have.
Scott: And I demanded either 20 percent more monies or four days a week.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which would be 20 percent less time, I said, one or the other.
Scott: And they were like, too rich for our blood.
Scott: Thanks.
Scott: Have a nice day.
Scott: And I'm like, all right.
Scott: I still got a great job.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And also, I respect a recruiter who's up front and is like, oh, OK, never mind.
Scott: Like, well, that wasn't the recruiter.
Scott: That was actually.
Scott: I went through a whole interview process at the end.
Scott: And the recruiters always inflate.
Scott: They like to tell you it's going to be a lot of money because then they convince you to go through the interview process and then hoping that you'll feel bad and be bad at negotiating.
Rym: And I've always taken the exact opposite.
Rym: My strategy in interviewing my entire life is even if the salary is low, if I like the job, I would go for it anyway.
Rym: Make that like make sure I crush the interview.
Rym: So they love me.
Scott: And I mean, I try to walk away a lot.
Scott: I definitely crush the interviews and they love me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was just that, you know, while I would have taken that job in a heart attack, if I had no job, it wasn't significantly better than the job I had.
Scott: So why change?
Rym: Well, that's rule number two of my life is no lateral moves ever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So anyway, so another place comes along where I'm going to be working starting next month.
Scott: And, you know, it's like it's got positives, it's got negatives, but it's not evil.
Scott: The people are nice.
Scott: You know, I'm going through the interviews there.
Scott: Same deal, right?
Scott: I crush the interviews.
Scott: They're in love with me.
Scott: They want to hire me so badly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, and I'm like, you know, I get to.
Scott: finally I get to the negotiating part at the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I'm like, you know, I'd really like to work four days a week.
Scott: And I'm like, I know you're going to say no, but that's where I got to start my ask.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And somehow I don't know how, but the offer ended up being both four days a week and 20 percent more.
Rym: So all I got to say is if this works out, like if they're hiring and they need a product manager, just, you know, we'll see what happens.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, this could be a trap.
Scott: This could be too good to be true.
Scott: This could be who knows what's going to happen.
Scott: But I certainly say no.
Scott: It's like I didn't.
Scott: I didn't want to go.
Scott: I was like I didn't want to leave the job I had, but I had kind of no choice.
Rym: You know what it's like?
Rym: It's like a bidding.
Rym: It's like in a bidding game or even like a train game or something where I put for some sort of like ridiculous lowball offer like in sieve.
Rym: I'm like, hey, Scott, you gave me three luxury resources for like one nighter.
Rym: And then the other side says, OK.
Rym: And I'm like, wait, what?
Rym: What?
Rym: I didn't expect you to say yes.
Rym: Nobody says yes to that.
Rym: What's what's going on?
Scott: I needed that night.
Scott: I was the one nighter I needed to make a gun.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: Anyway, so, yeah, that's that took up some time and distracted from GeekNights.
Scott: But now now we're in we're in the opposite situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whereas I don't have to work for a whole month.
Scott: It's summertime.
Scott: I worked on the website most of the day to day doing lots of stuff, the GeekNights website.
Scott: And then what?
Scott: even when I start working next month, it won't be on Friday.
Scott: I know there's no GeekNights on Friday, but that still is going to give me time eventually to do some kind of content or something.
Scott: At least some of those Fridays once in a while will be spent doing something.
Scott: GeekNights Internet content production related.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's all I'm willing to say.
Scott: I'm not willing to talk any more than that.
Rym: So yes, the hockey will keep watching because honestly, this is going to be.
Scott: it's only a few games left.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also, I am very confident Colorado is going to win.
Scott: But I said that early in the regular season.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And when we say the whole thing, whoever came out of the Eastern Conference is just going to be sacrificed before the Nidhogg.
Rym: that is the Colorado avalanche.
Scott: That's what's going to happen.
Rym: We were just fighting over who gets to have the honor of being crushed by them in the finals.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Rym: But the one thing so I Emily and I ended up being at the last home game because that's like how our tickets broke down.
Scott: We were at.
Scott: we were at the last game at Madison Square Garden, but the game was being played in Florida.
Rym: But there is a technology angle here because something happened that I this happens.
Rym: It always happens in the playoffs, but maybe because I haven't paid attention to the playoffs or gone to games in a long time, but also it feels like it was more than like the last time I went to playoffs games.
Rym: The production value of the technology, the lighting and the sound and the stuff happening in the arena leveled up every round of the playoffs.
Rym: And every time it leveled up more than I expected it to.
Rym: So in the last round, the last game we went to, they had smoke, they had lasers.
Rym: So not just I got the lasers.
Rym: They had lasers that are if they hit a person in the eye would be fucking dangerous.
Rym: They were true.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So bright.
Scott: This is a laser that was like going across MSG from one end to the other.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And culminating to like a spot, maybe an inch, like inch and a half in diameter that was setting the building on fire.
Scott: But it's like they were like that hit you in the eye.
Rym: I think you would be insta blinded.
Rym: And it looks like they were hard.
Scott: And also they were bright enough to be visible just in the ambient air slightly, which well, they also combine them with the smoke machine that come out from under the scoreboard.
Rym: But some of them were occasionally touching briefly the bottom of the American flag that's hanging up there.
Rym: And it was like a sun every time it touched it.
Rym: So what's interesting is if you look at how they work, how they work this out, they were all aimed and I'm pretty there had better have been hardware controls, ensuring that they couldn't aim anywhere else.
Rym: They were flying around, but they were only aiming at the boundaries between the levels in the arena, like the little wall.
Scott: There was some that were aimed at the bottom of the boards on the ice.
Scott: And there were some that were aimed on like, you know, the flat where the score, the horizontal scoreboards are in between the one hundred two hundred level.
Scott: But yeah, they're basically not hitting anywhere.
Scott: There were seats and anywhere there could be a human body.
Rym: Right.
Scott: We were flying or something.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Which is just a fascinating use of technology, because if there weren't hardware lockouts, if they were relying solely on the programing of the controllers for those laser lights as someone who has done formal risk analysis professionally for more than a decade, that I cannot imagine what the risk assessment was of that situation.
Scott: I mean, they could have been doing it with software, just the software really good.
Scott: Yeah, I just know how that shit works.
Rym: I, I deeply distrust software interlocks on dangerous hardware.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, they had a lot of cool special effects going on.
Rym: So in some actual tech news, let's talk about Web Push for Safari.
Scott: Well, so Apple's WWDC happened, right?
Scott: This is where at the time of year where they have a big developer conference for Apple developers and they announce all their new Apple shit.
Scott: And usually it's all like what's going to be updated in iOS, what's going to be updated in Mac OS, all that kind of stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the big update they announced was this sort of something stage center stage something.
Scott: I forget what it's called.
Scott: Apple stage something main stage.
Scott: No, not that stage manager.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: Apple stage manager, which is basically, you know, we talk about a lot of how Apple will take something that someone else has already invented and sort of just polish it and make a new UI for it and act like they invented it.
Scott: Like when they came out with spaces or virtual desktops.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like virtual desktops have been on Unix and, you know, X11 Windows systems for decades.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And they acted like they invented it like it was even funnier because by the time that appeared was around the time when I had two giant monitors and didn't really use virtual desktops anymore.
Scott: But anyway, but they stage manager, which they just announced, is basically like it's effectively virtual desktops.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You group your windows by task and then you can sort of, you know, bring out.
Scott: That's how I use virtual desktops anyway.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like I'll have a virtual desktop for each task.
Scott: And then you just, you know, you swap out all your windows for a whole different set of windows to work on something else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like on the other virtual desktop that I'm not looking at right now, there's all the stuff to work on the GeekNights website.
Scott: But all that's hidden.
Scott: Because now I'm working on my desktop where I can do a GeekNights episode.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the stage manager is a new UI to effectively, you know, group applications by task and switch between tasks.
Scott: And it's actually really nice looking.
Scott: I kind of like it.
Scott: I wish my computer did that, but not enough to go get a Mac.
Scott: But they are bringing it to iPad, which is nice, but they're not bringing it to iPads that don't have M1 processors, which I think is actually a big problem.
Scott: And that, you know, Apple has always been known for the one thing they do.
Scott: I think the best thing Apple does is that they support really old hardware with new OS updates for a long time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: My iPhone 7 was which, you know, I guess I could have waited another year or two before updating it, you know, but I think I guess it was seven years before of lifetime.
Scott: If you bought an iPhone 7, the day it came out, you could have used it for seven years before it stopped getting iOS updates and you could have even kept using it longer than that.
Scott: You just eventually might run into situations where, you know, updates to iOS apps don't work because your iOS is too old.
Scott: Right now.
Scott: So, yeah, I only kept my iPhone 7 for five years and my Apple Watch 3.
Scott: I bought that.
Scott: I'm wearing it right now.
Scott: It's still good, but it looks like later this year it's not going to be good anymore.
Scott: They're going to have an iOS update that, you know, a watch OS update that finally puts the third watch.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Meanwhile, they're already on like Watch 8 or something or I forget what number they're on.
Rym: Yeah, I have the most recent one that's actually out and it's fine.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it'll last you many years.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whereas Android devices, they get maybe a handful of years of updates and then that's it.
Rym: In two years, I went through two and a half Android watches.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I used to update my Apple phone, my iPhone every two years because the contract would be every two years.
Scott: But and because the hardware updates were so significant, like what's iPhone 3G compared to iPhone 4, compared to iPhone 5, compared to six, compared to seven.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like those are big leaps.
Scott: But then after seven, like the leaps weren't there anymore.
Scott: You know, I went from seven to twelve mini, whatever the first mini one, whatever number that was.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So anyway.
Scott: So, yeah, that's the.
Scott: you know, they got their iOS updates and whatnot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the big one feature that they announced that really intrigued me was the sort of live notifications.
Scott: I forget what they called them.
Scott: But, you know, there are certain situations where let's say you order something like food to be delivered.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Right now, if you turn on all the notifications for your food delivery app of choice.
Scott: What they'll?
Scott: they'll?
Scott: they'll message you and be like, we got your order.
Scott: Then they'll give you another notification.
Scott: The restaurant started working on another notification.
Scott: They finished working on another one.
Scott: The delivery is coming.
Scott: Another one.
Scott: The delivery is close.
Scott: The delivery is here.
Scott: You like a pile of notifications for this one thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like your phone is going ding, ding, ding, ding.
Scott: And that's not a great user experience.
Scott: It's kind of a mess.
Scott: And you have to clear out a pile of notifications.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Really, that whole process should be one notification.
Scott: that sort of the notification itself live updates to tell you the current status when you look at it.
Scott: And that's they added that it's basically.
Scott: So when you if you were to now order food on a new, you know, once the new iOS comes out and the apps update themselves, you would get a note, you would order some food, a notification would come up and that notification would just stay there and always be displaying the current status of your food order.
Scott: And when it was done, that thing would go away and it would sort of be on your home screen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you could do the same thing for other similar like time gated events, like a sporting event.
Scott: It's like, OK, the sporting event started.
Scott: Now there's a thing on your on your lock screen showing you the live score.
Scott: And then when the game's over, it's gone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just one notification, one thing that knows when to come and when to go away and update itself rather than having multiple notifications.
Scott: So that's going to be a good thing.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: So the thing Rym talked about the Web push.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So speaking of notifications, as long as they've had notifications on iOS.
Scott: And the way it's worked is that, you know, you had to get an app in the App Store, get an Apple developer account.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Get your app approved.
Scott: Get someone to install your app.
Scott: Get someone to give your app notification permissions, and then the app can notify them within certain bounds.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A behavior that Apple deemed acceptable.
Scott: And then, you know, it's like, you know, in order to not ruin the battery life and annoy the users.
Scott: Right.
Scott: With lots of notifications.
Scott: So that's the way it's been, you might notice if you're anyone who uses a normal computer still that, like even today, desktop Web browsers do notifications.
Scott: Like you can go to a website and it'll pop up an annoying message like, hey, you want notifications from this website?
Scott: Huh?
Scott: And if you say yes, it's like your Web browser is basically going to be keeping open like a little thing in the background, like a little service in the background on your computer.
Scott: And the website, just any old website can send notifications and they'll show up like in Windows or Mac, like as OS level notifications, you know, and that's, you know, it's nice when you want to use it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Ninety nine percent of the time you don't want to use it like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When you want to use it, it's nice.
Scott: Like, you know, let's say at the game for the website for train games, you can close your tab for train games and still get a notification in OS level.
Scott: That's like, hey, it's your turn in the train game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's nice.
Scott: Or Gmail, like, hey, you got an email.
Scott: That's an important email.
Scott: OS level notification, even though your browser might be closed or, you know, whatever.
Scott: So it can be nice when you want to do it.
Scott: But what Apple is going to do is they're going to enable Web push right on Mac OS and iOS via Safari.
Scott: So this means that somebody with a Web page and no iOS app, no Mac app whatsoever can now send you notifications on iOS just from a website.
Scott: And so there's a video here that's actually targeted towards Web developers who want to implement this feature, but it's also useful because it tells users how the feature is going to work.
Scott: And the key here is that a they are not going to allow you to pop up a thing like, hey, you want notifications, the user must click or do some action in order to start the.
Scott: I want that is key.
Rym: That is very similar to how MailChimp dominated all the mailing services in the early days when they force either second verification or active subscription as opposed to opt out.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it's the example they give is like a website that has a bell icon and they're like, you can't ask the user for notification permission until they click the bell icon.
Scott: Then they can say, yes, I want notifications from this website.
Scott: And the second thing is that it is technically possible to do this the Web push and send messages to someone's Web browser and have JavaScript take action in response to those messages without displaying a notification to the user.
Scott: You could just sort of, you know, get the user's computer to do processing or whatever.
Scott: And Apple's like, yeah, you can, you know, a you can hurt someone's battery life like that.
Scott: Be you're using someone's CPU, possibly their phone CPU.
Scott: Hey, phone Bitcoin for me without them realizing you're doing it right.
Scott: So Apple has a system in place where if you don't display a notification to the user quickly enough.
Scott: after you send them a Web push and you do that like three times or something, then that's it.
Scott: They take away your Web push permission.
Scott: It's like you're done, right?
Scott: You can't do it anymore.
Scott: Your whole domain is just blocked.
Rym: I noticed this side thing in the article you link to around service worker APIs to that what it is service work that that seems to be exactly what this is.
Rym: This looks pretty good.
Scott: A service worker API is basically the JavaScript that's sitting on your computer that will leap into action once a notification comes in from the Internet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like, you know, it's like you leave instructions on the person's phone or on their computer of like what to do if they receive a message from Web site X. And then so when Web site X sends a message, the Safari browser says, oh, where did this message come from?
Scott: It came from Web site X. Send it.
Scott: Do I have a service worker for Web site X?
Scott: I do.
Scott: And it sends the message to the service worker for Web site.
Rym: What are the examples they give on like what is what it's supposed to do, what they expect you to use this for is actually a really good one.
Rym: I'm just going to quote the Web site receiving centralized updates to expensive to calculate data such as geolocation or gyroscope.
Rym: So multiple pages can make use of one set of data.
Scott: Yeah, you could go to a Web site, click on like do something, go away.
Scott: And then once the thing is done, you'll get a notification that's like, hey, thing is done.
Scott: You click on it and that will take you to the Web page with the results of the thing that is now done.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So anyway, yeah, they're now good.
Scott: You're now going to be able to send notifications to users of iOS devices without having to make an iOS app and get in the app store or give Apple money or make an Apple developer account or anything.
Scott: And that is kind of a big deal because, for example, front row crew dot com could make it so that you get a notification on your phone.
Scott: But it's a new GeekNights episode, even though that we don't have an official iPhone app whatsoever.
Scott: So and the notifications are much more useful on the phone than they are the desktop.
Scott: So I foresee do and a lot of people only have phones.
Scott: So I think what you're going to see is a lot more Web sites implementing notifications, implementing them in a way that is acceptable to Apple and won't annoy you by asking you to accept notifications just every just from visiting the Web.
Rym: This is where Apple often serves as a thought leader because they will implement and enforce design patterns that are pleasant to the user.
Rym: And then the rest of the ecosystem is usually forced to basically follow Apple's rules because people get used to like that's old flash.
Scott: That's how they killed flash.
Rym: I think that's a big part of why so many people perceive Apple products to be more pleasant to use, because there's usually at least one design pattern where Apple has said, nope, that sucks.
Rym: We're just going to ban it.
Scott: I mean, listen, you know, if I wasn't somebody who played games like, you know, with Steam.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And be developed software that was like Linux software.
Scott: I'll get a Mac.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's no reason for me to not have a Mac.
Scott: I've had an iPhone.
Scott: There'll be no reason to not have a Mac as like those are the two things.
Scott: And Mac will basically never do those things.
Scott: So, yeah, playing games and editing like extreme video with the real Mac can do that.
Scott: You can run all the Adobe software on there.
Scott: No problem.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: What you run into is you can't get you can't get a good GPU.
Scott: Well, I mean, if you're, you know, the GPU, if you get the Mac Studio, it's going to be for video editing.
Scott: You'll be fine.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So it's in some other news.
Rym: This is actually a big deal.
Rym: New York.
Rym: I think I think all this left is the governor has to sign this.
Rym: And we have a pretty OK governor right now in considering the span of what it is better than the last governor.
Scott: But that's not saying much.
Rym: We're going to primary around.
Scott: It could be a lot worse.
Scott: It could be a lot better.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But we have our state legislature has passed a right to repair law in New York for electronics.
Rym: And because New York is so big, this could have national ramifications.
Rym: Basically, this law, unfortunately, it doesn't actually cover agricultural equipment or cars or most hardware.
Rym: really only covers things like cell phones and like digital technology.
Rym: The definition is a little bit weird.
Scott: It's limited, but it's, you know, it's a start to nothing.
Rym: Kind of like that week sauce gun bill that looks like it might actually pass the Senate because they got 10 Republicans on board.
Rym: Yes, it's not.
Scott: But it's not nothing.
Rym: Yeah, not nothing is the best you can do sometimes.
Rym: So the bill better than nothing requires digital electronics manufacturers to make repair instructions and parts available, not just to technicians who are independent, but also directly to consumers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, Apple did make, you know, all this repair stuff available to everybody.
Scott: There are some articles out there of people who did it.
Scott: And the thing is, it's like, yeah, they'll send you all this ridiculous equipment to like fix your iPhone and you have to send it back within a limited time frame so you don't get charged for it.
Scott: Thousands of dollars of expensive equipment and instructions like.
Scott: you can do it yourself.
Scott: You can succeed at it.
Scott: But it's you know, it's still not for the faint of heart, right?
Scott: It's really.
Scott: it's like they do this.
Scott: They would satisfy the law and that, yes, they'll send it to just any old person, but it's really designed for somebody who is a professional.
Scott: You know, it's very much like they're running a repair shop.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, it's very much analogous to car repair and how you don't have to take your car to the dealership you brought it from to get it repaired.
Rym: Go to any fucking mechanic.
Rym: Some mechanics are good.
Rym: Some mechanics are bad.
Rym: Some mechanics are cheap.
Scott: Some people can do it themselves.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: But you can do that because of laws and regulations.
Rym: And now we're applying the same principle, at least to phones and laptops and a lot of digital or digital adjacent goods.
Scott: It's all my thing of the day from I think the last time we did shows, right?
Scott: Stas takes fix on YouTube.
Scott: I'm still loving that guy's channel.
Scott: He's just, you know, this guy who admits he doesn't know much about electronics, but somehow he orders some broken shit on eBay.
Scott: He fixes it and then he's real excited when it works.
Scott: He's like, yeah, it's like it's really fun.
Scott: It's like, but how did this get all about fixing stuff these days?
Rym: Like how did this come to pass?
Rym: Because with with any time a law passes anywhere in the US, the real question is, how did that good law make it through our government?
Rym: Like how did that happen?
Rym: Because if there's a pattern to that, you could make more good things happen theoretically.
Rym: So one, it happened in an extremely blue state like this is a state that is completely controlled by the Democrats to it's only within one state.
Rym: It just happens to be a very powerful state.
Rym: See also how California.
Rym: lot of companies follow California rules because they don't want to have trouble with.
Rym: the California market is too big to ignore.
Rym: And three, a number of companies.
Scott: don't put gay people in their movies.
Scott: that China market too big.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: So there were a number of public groups, advocacy groups that were aggressively fighting for this in New York state for at least five years now.
Rym: This is the culmination of years and years of constant letter writing, bothering random state senators like harassing government officials, donating money.
Rym: This is this was a lot of work to get this bill passed from a lot of very, very dedicated activists in this very tiny space.
Rym: So my advice to you is if you care about something about on this level, go harass like the state legislature in an important blue state.
Rym: That is probably the best for a long period of time.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of help, right?
Scott: That's how you can make it happen.
Rym: You've got to be annoying to the point to where a state government in the United States will would rather do what you want to make you go away than continue to listen to you.
Rym: It's a strategy in some other news, that's a good segue into the main bit.
Rym: We can't ignore Dolly because it is the new wordle in terms of completely filling my Twitter stream with.
Scott: Yeah, it's this little A.I.
Scott: ish right machine learning image generating model app that is available to the general public on some sort of throttled basis.
Scott: You can't, you know, just use it because it takes quite a bit of computing power to make it go.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And what we're playing with is the mini version, not the full on version, of course.
Scott: And it's free to try to use, though.
Scott: You just got to get through the throttling and yeah, you can type in any old text and it will search its database of images and it will try to combine those images into new images that match your description.
Scott: So you could write like, you know, Rym jumping up and down and it will try to make pictures of Rym jumping up and down.
Scott: Right.
Scott: For what?
Scott: However, it understands those words and you can have a lot of fun creating a lot of really interesting images by typing lots of pop culture combinations into this thing.
Rym: I just got it to make Shrek riding a bicycle through Penn Station and it pretty much nailed it.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know, you got to sort of learn you're in like what kind of things it does a good job with and what kinds of things it doesn't do.
Rym: I found and if you read their website for the full A.I.
Rym: model, it's interesting because it really focuses on natural language and detailed descriptions.
Rym: So you'd like an example of a good search would be a storefront that has the word open A.I.
Rym: written on it or an armchair in the shape of an avocado, the exact same cat on the top as a sketch on the bottom, like things like that.
Rym: The more specific you are, the better it is.
Rym: And it basically it seems like it's very similar.
Rym: Actually, now that I'm scrolling down to the website, they even call it out.
Rym: They say it's similar.
Rym: So it's not just me.
Rym: This is basically doing the same kind of thing that GPT-3 does, which is a natural language neural network where you can tell it things like write an article about this new cell phone.
Rym: It'll write a kind of shitty article about this new cell phone.
Rym: that's good enough, like it's enough to start with.
Rym: It gives you a starting point.
Scott: These it's a lot of fun and there's a lot of good memes people have generated with it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And we're going to edge into a little bit of people are talking about this.
Rym: I've seen people having such ridiculous takes as this will destroy jobs.
Rym: This A.I.
Rym: will take away my source of like it's people are.
Rym: no people are overreacting to the wrong.
Scott: Those are tongue in cheek.
Scott: This will take my job.
Scott: I don't think it's serious.
Rym: I've seen a few serious people, but it's more serious in the same way as the people who would complain that digital animation destroyed like my ability to make money painting cells.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I'm on a big Star Trek kick lately and my cup overflow it because there's a lot of new Star Trek, also a lot of old Star Trek that I never fully watched.
Rym: that I'm digging through currently near the end of a rewatch slash first watch of Deep Space Nine.
Rym: And my thing of the day is, if you're familiar in the original Star Trek or TOS, as nerds will call it, the original series, there was a parallel sort of sister show that was official.
Rym: It's canonical, but it was animated, filmation animation, like really limited animation.
Rym: It's a full on Star Trek.
Rym: You've seen it out there, but I've seen it.
Scott: But, you know, I don't a lot.
Scott: I know that many people like watch the whole thing.
Scott: I've definitely seen that it exists.
Rym: But what's notable about it, other than the fact that it is fully canonical, is that it has a distinctive style.
Rym: It is like it's hard to describe the style in full, but it uses a lot of like weird, almost Dutch angles.
Rym: It has a lot of close ups of a face just reacting to something and not saying anything while music plays for like five or six seconds at a time.
Rym: Clearly, it's a lot of the things they were doing to reduce how much animation they had to make in a Star Trek to crank this show out.
Rym: But it has a very distinctive style.
Scott: It was very super frenzy.
Scott: Yeah, I felt so.
Rym: This video is from some fans of this Grazelle Automations, and they have made a five and a half minute long video that is fully animated.
Rym: It is a basically an episode of Star Trek Voyager condensed into an animated in this style.
Rym: And what makes this sublime is they didn't just take the audio from this episode of Star Trek Voyager and just like animate it in the animation style.
Rym: They reworked it.
Rym: It has a soundtrack like the original animation instead of like Voyager.
Rym: They added all the weird pregnant pauses.
Rym: They moved the dialogue around.
Rym: It mimics completely everything that made that original animated show distinctive.
Rym: It's kind of amazing how like they hit it out of the park.
Scott: I mean, I do appreciate that, right?
Scott: I talk a lot about how like, hey, you know, why not make something new in the old style, right?
Scott: Why not just make, you know, a noir movie with some black and white film as it, you know, as if it was nineteen.
Rym: Scott, you ever see a movie called Brick?
Scott: No, really, it's a.
Rym: it's a straight up film noir and it's about a brick of cocaine, but it's set in like a dumpy high school, like earnestly.
Rym: And it's this film is I can't believe you've never seen it.
Scott: I'm sure there are people who do it, but it's not common.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it's not common.
Scott: Yeah, you know, old movies, they always open with like, you know, credits and like a classical music playing.
Scott: And it's like, you know, it's like what if you went to the movie theater today and a movie started like that?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no one does that.
Rym: Yeah, it is rare.
Rym: Case in point, Hateful Eight, like that movie, that's what it was like to go to an old timey four and a half hour long movie with an intermission a little bit.
Scott: Anyway, so the thing of the day.
Scott: So here's his book that's coming out.
Scott: The book is not actually coming out until September, September this year.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there is currently a free chapter one preview and you can get an early access e-book for thirty two dollars and you can preorder the print book and that will also include the early access e-book for forty dollars.
Scott: And the book is actually you might think, ah, it's an electronics book because it's called Open Circuits.
Scott: But actually this is a photography book.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's a. it's a book where basically they take electronic components.
Scott: The free chapter is passive components.
Scott: But then the other chapters, you have semiconductors, electromechanics, cables and connectors, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I each chapter is basically photographs of not just the components because like, you know, what a resistor looks like, but mostly cross sections of the components.
Scott: It's like you might know that like, yeah, a capacitor is like, you know, you like you know, in the theory and principle of what's in there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's maybe some oil in there or something.
Scott: But like if if I said, all right.
Scott: I'm about to cut open a capacitor right in half and show you the inside.
Scott: It's discharge.
Scott: Don't worry.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Would you know what you're about to see?
Rym: I would.
Rym: But most people wouldn't.
Rym: And I wouldn't for most electronic components, just I happen to.
Rym: I used to desolder and resolder capacitors as a job.
Scott: But did you cut a capacitor in half?
Rym: Yes, actually, because I had to prove that capacitors I was taking out of computer motherboards were defective because of the electrolyte solution inside of them.
Scott: Anyway, so the point is doing that at IBM, it's a book of photography and it's all.
Scott: the photographs are basically the insides and cross sections of electronic components.
Scott: You can see what the hell is actually in their school.
Scott: This is pretty fascinating.
Scott: I recommend you download the free first chapter.
Scott: And if you like what you see, well, there's the beef, not free options that will, you know, you can preorder for September.
Scott: Oh, and look, it says use coupon code preorder to get 25 percent off.
Scott: I never understood that.
Scott: It's like I'm on the purchasing page.
Scott: Why are you writing the coupon code right there?
Scott: Why not just lower the price by 25 percent?
Rym: I can explain that with modern pricing theory.
Rym: There is a very.
Rym: I talked to us in GeekNights a while ago, but this is a direct example of it.
Rym: This is a simple example.
Rym: But the idea is it's the same reason coupons exist in the modern world.
Rym: You do that.
Scott: Coupon is right on the page.
Rym: Here's what you're up.
Rym: So despite it being right on the page.
Rym: The data on how many people copy paste it right there when they buy it versus just don't bother is extremely useful data, because terrifyingly, that is how you generate lists of people who care more about time than money or more about money than time.
Scott: People who know how to read generate a list of people.
Rym: Not all I'm going to I'll put it diplomatically.
Rym: You can infer a lot about the future behavior of someone on an e-commerce site based on whether or not they will copy paste the word preorder and all caps from one part of a page into another part of a page to get 25 percent off.
Rym: You can also infer a lot about someone who will not do that.
Rym: I'll just leave it at that.
Rym: That is something they teach product managers.
Scott: Anyway, you took this one pricing like like training like one time and like you just keep going on and on.
Rym: I've taken away more than one training.
Rym: I've been this is something I've been studying for the last five years.
Scott: But anyway, uh huh.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: OK.
Scott: You went to a training five years ago.
Rym: But anyway, in the bad moment, the Geek Guys Book Club book, Nine Fox Gambit, the next Thursday episode, we are doing the show.
Rym: If you start reading it now, you can easily finish by next Thursday.
Rym: The book is not long, nor is it hard to read.
Rym: And if you bounce off of the first two paragraphs, that's a bunch of proper nouns and cylindrical heresy, you'll you'll figure out what's going on real quick.
Rym: And I'll leave it at that.
Rym: I already started the second book because that's how I roll.
Scott: I really met a moment.
Scott: Also, I guess I'm working on the website.
Scott: It's coming along very nicely.
Scott: I'm doing I'm basically right now.
Scott: I'm working on a thing for uploading new episodes, which is going to work a lot like the way, you know, you upload videos on YouTube, obviously less fancy, but, you know, drag an MP3 in, click, upload, type in a bunch of metadata, push, save that whole that whole thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: I also I got a little bit.
Rym: So I started this up again.
Rym: I had been doing it for a while because we hadn't really been reviewing a lot of tabletop games.
Rym: I guess something happened in the world over the last three years that prevented us from going to a bunch of conventions and playing a ton of tabletop games that we normally would.
Rym: that fuels a good chunk of GeekNights.
Rym: But it turns out, since we stopped playing a lot of board games, we had done five more episodes where we reviewed a tabletop game.
Rym: So I have now cut them out and put them on YouTube.
Rym: Just the main bits, just the reviews.
Rym: And I'm going to link to, if you don't know, there's a playlist out there that has 78 of our GeekNights tabletop game reviews with no news, no main bits, none of that other GeekNights crap.
Rym: It's just the review and nothing else.
Scott: What I think is really interesting and probably a mistake that we made.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, given that we don't really care about marketing, putting the main bit at the end.
Scott: And well, no, is that if you look around and say like the tabletop gaming community.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Nobody can sit.
Scott: Nobody like knows.
Scott: But you never see them saying like, oh, best you see.
Scott: I'll see occasionally threads like best.
Scott: tabletop podcasts were never mentioned ever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But 78 episodes is more episodes than most tabletop podcasts in total.
Rym: So it's only like not even 10 percent of we have more Wednesday episodes than most anime podcasts that have ever existed.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, I think I've been doing this for the tabletop content because I find that even more so than anything else we do, a succinct, deep review of a tabletop game is the kind of thing that someone will send to a friend to try to convince them to play a And they're useful to travel around independent of the rest of the GeekNights' crap.
Rym: You don't need to hear about us talking about biking to work for 20 minutes just to find out if Princess of Florence is worth playing.
Rym: So this is out there.
Rym: And before you ask, why aren't you doing this for the anime reviews?
Rym: I was.
Rym: I stopped because even a fucking anime review that had no screenshots, no content of any kind from the anime.
Rym: It's just the audio of me and Scott talking about it.
Rym: Got a copyright takedown on YouTube and I was just fucking done.
Rym: Anime is dead to me on YouTube.
Scott: OK, well, because they just look they're not.
Scott: they're just indiscriminately, you know, they're not actually checking for a copyright violation.
Scott: They just see the name of an anime in the title or description of the thing.
Scott: And then they just like, you know, they just send you a thing.
Scott: They just check.
Scott: It's amazing in your video.
Rym: My YouTube channel only gets this for anime content and literally nothing else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, that's because the anime we all know this.
Scott: How many times have we talked about this?
Scott: Japan is really wild with their copyright enforcement.
Scott: You know, like people in Japan are like going to actual criminal prison for like pirating some mangas or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They are super strict about it, you know, and obsessed with enforcing it.
Scott: Look at the way Nintendo, you know, what they did to the Bowser.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Not this.
Scott: Not the not the look what Nintendo did, not the fictional character and not the president of Nintendo of America, but the pirate guy, Bowser.
Rym: Well, we'll talk about that on the next Tuesday show, because there's that situation is kind of fucked up.
Rym: But anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so A.I.
Rym: has been in the news a bunch, not just because of, well, just the the industry moving fast and not just because of Dali, but because something a little bit.
Rym: I don't want to say silly, but the story we're about to talk about, there's a lot of facets to it, and we're not going to be able to cover,
Scott: you know, and there's so much we don't know, we can only talk about what we do know as, you know, people who read a couple articles and some blog posts.
Rym: But I'm going to head off before we get into it.
Rym: The
Rym: A.I.,
Rym: the chat bot that is at the center of this cluster of stories is is absolutely not sentience.
Rym: I want to be clear about that.
Scott: I mean, what is sentient?
Scott: You want to have a philosophy episode?
Rym: Oh, we could.
Rym: I am glad you.
Rym: if there's one argument that I am well prepared to have and go on forever about is something appears to be sentient.
Scott: Is it not sentient?
Scott: If no one can tell.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But there is a lot of hard evidence that this is not sentient in any meaningful way.
Rym: Basically, I'm going to super summarize this.
Rym: An engineer who works at Google believed and then claimed publicly that a Lambda chat bot is sentient and deserves sentient rights.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So my opinion on its sentience, because I can actually say why it's not sentient in my opinion.
Rym: I have a few articles queued up that also say in a hard science reason why even there's a there's a real simple reason that I alone, according to what I think, counts as sentient.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Do not consider it to be sentient.
Scott: is that this chat bot, the way it works, is you send some text to it and then it sends some text back.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It never just sends some text on its own.
Scott: It doesn't just say things out of nowhere.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just responding to an input.
Scott: It won't just say something.
Scott: And you might think, well, you could easily just sort of have some sort of clock hooked up to it so that it would say things on its own.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And there are humans who have particular kinds of executive dysfunctions where they are a human and no one's going to argue that a human is not sentient, but they will not take any action on their own.
Rym: But if you stimulate their brain in a specific way, they will spontaneously begin taking actions like a normal seeming person.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But regardless, even if you did that to this bot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, well, what are you going to?
Scott: you still have to like.
Scott: you can't just be like, hey, there's no way to be like, hey, say something you have to actually say something at it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It can.
Scott: it's.
Scott: all it's doing is processing text.
Scott: You give it.
Scott: if you don't give it any text, then it doesn't do anything.
Scott: It's just a text process.
Scott: I go even I go even though even though its responses to text may very well imitate thought, right, or give the illusion of thought, there is no thought on its own to happen there.
Rym: Well, case in point, imagine, imagine a Turing test, you know, in a chat room, the typical could chat with something and then decide if it is sentient or not or decide if it is human or not.
Rym: If you train a model with humans administering Turing tests and responding to Turing tests, you will get very human sounding responses, because a lot of humans will respond to the kinds of questions humans ask bots to see if they're human the way a human would like.
Rym: It's a self.
Rym: It's basically a self reinforcing model.
Scott: Well, no, but I think that, you know, let's say you did a Turing test.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The oldest test in the book.
Scott: What if you did a Turing test against this bot, no matter what text it sent back to you, no matter how convincing that text was, it would always be.
Scott: I send a sentence that sends back a sentence one, one, one, one.
Scott: It would never send back like two or three or send me back one when I didn't send it anything.
Scott: There are.
Rym: there are some chat bots that can do things like that, though.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But if I was conversing with a human, even if the human was very illiterate and bad at writing, there wouldn't be the sort of one one one one pattern going on.
Scott: And therefore that would be a strong indicator that it would be human compared to the one one one one where that even if the text was vastly superior.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So anyway, so there's this guy, this guy will just I don't.
Scott: there's too much.
Scott: I never heard of this person before this week.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And the person the research I did on the Internet indicates this is a very interesting person.
Scott: Have it a lot complicated with a complicated history.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: You know, it's not all positive.
Scott: It's not all negative, but congratulations on having a really interesting life.
Scott: This person.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What was their name?
Rym: Oh, their name is Blake Lemoine.
Scott: OK, so, yeah, very interesting individual who at least up until very recently was an employee at Google and was doing some sort of AI ethics type research.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the it is well known that Google has gotten rid of many of its ethics people, which is not great considering the AI stuff they're doing, even whether you want to argue it's actually AI or not.
Scott: You know, the point is machine learning type stuff.
Scott: There's still a lot of ethical issues that you need somebody to, you know, keep a watchful eye on.
Scott: That's not just Google.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: We'll talk about what those ethical issues actually are in a moment.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: So, yeah, this person was working there and they believe that this particular chat bot that I just said is not sentient, they believe otherwise.
Scott: And they went through all kinds of processes and H.R.
Scott: stuff and, you know, raising issues and getting help.
Rym: Looks like they tried to get a lawyer even to represent the AI.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're doing all kinds of stuff that they documented and also their newspapers reporting on it that they talk to and all kinds of stuff that, you know, we really don't know anything about other than what's been published to report it to Google.
Scott: And the end result was that Google put them on administrative leave, which means we're going to you're weird and we're going to fire you soon.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's what it means.
Scott: And you based on the available information and the checkered interesting history of the individual, it's kind of hard to, you know, not read it like both ways.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, well, this person is just, you know, losing it on the one hand.
Scott: But B, you know, you could ease easily also believe that, yeah, Google's up to no good, even while you don't necessarily have to agree that the chat bot is sent out to believe that Google's up to no good.
Rym: But I guess the situation here, like I'm going to actually quote the way article because it because this pretty much sums it up.
Rym: The reporting around this was this engineer thinks it's sentient and Google denies it.
Rym: But to quote WAPO, most academics and practitioners say the words and images generated by artificial intelligence systems such as Lambda produce responses based on what humans have already posted on Wikipedia, Reddit, message boards and every other corner of the Internet.
Rym: And that doesn't signify that the model understands meaning.
Rym: Quote, we now have machines that can mindlessly generate words, but we haven't learned how to stop imagining a mind behind them.
Rym: And it goes on, there's a lot of discussion around this, but basically this person seems to have now gone to the press.
Rym: There's a lot of public conversation around this and the public conversation is getting further and further away from the actual technology involved here and the reality.
Scott: And, you know, because there's so many blanks that are not filled in due to things that have not.
Scott: It's interesting because enough has been reported and enough has been blogged by the person in question that there's a lot of information available relative to what you would normally have in these sort of scenarios where someone's like, let go more than there were in the you know, the previous researchers who got let go from Google.
Scott: Yeah, but still plenty of unknowns and plenty of people talking who don't understand technology, like Rym's said.
Scott: So that empty space of knowledge gets filled with conspiracies, conjecture, rumors, nonsense,
Scott: B.S.,
Scott: et cetera, et cetera, that you all got to watch out for all that.
Rym: So first, let's talk about these like linguistic models and sort of how they work or what they mean, because basically what they do.
Rym: And again, we're super, super generalizing for a lot of reasons.
Rym: You feed in a ton of human language and then they will make predictions based on trends and relationships and statistics from that set of language so that if there is a set of text, generate more text.
Scott: that's like the text that I was given or related to the text or, you know, whatever.
Rym: Now, what these what these are
Scott: often
Rym: actually used for in the real world are things like when you try to get customer service and a human doesn't respond, a chat bot responds and it tries to get information out of you and get it get help you as much as possible before
Scott: those aren't even using that.
Scott: A lot of those just straight up scripted.
Rym: Yeah, they're scripted or they have extremely simplistic models, usually just looking for keywords.
Rym: Beyond that, they're often used.
Rym: There's a burgeoning industry of using them to prewrite simplistic articles, news articles, reviews, anything like low hanging fruit, press release nonsense.
Rym: Basically, you feed in the all the all the text around a situation into these models and they'll tell it what to write about and they'll spit out an article that clearly is unreadable, but it gets the broad strokes down.
Rym: It almost like it writes a crappy review of a phone.
Rym: And then you hire a person who's maybe way less skilled than someone who would write an entire article with research from nothing to clean it up and make it look like a human wrote it and publish it.
Rym: And that is a worrying and growing trend in journalism.
Rym: But that's a use for these things.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, the number one use is everybody knows is the series, Alexa's and OK, Google's.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Those are the that's the number one use consumers are aware of.
Scott: For all this nonsense,
Rym: a dangerous use that is coming more and more to the forefront, but already has existed in a practicable form for a long time with text is having something that is able to write novel content in the recognizable style of a known person, but without any input from said person.
Rym: You could get this to write an article.
Rym: that sounds a lot like how I write an article.
Rym: Look, if you read it, you think, wow, Rimm wrote that, but I didn't write it.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: If you just if you just take all the Stephen King books, throw them into this thing and then say, write a Stephen King book and you'll be surprised.
Rym: Yeah, it comes out, especially if you look at some later Stephen King books.
Rym: But I digress.
Scott: Maybe those were written by now.
Rym: The other ethical side of this coin is I absolutely believe we will build machine intelligences that are equivalent to superior that to or at least analogous to human intelligence.
Rym: Like we're not special.
Rym: We're just a biological machine, but I don't think we're anywhere near that point so far.
Scott: Not in our lifetime, probably.
Rym: And of course, at least not as we approach that point.
Rym: There are.
Rym: there is a huge body of ethics around what is ethical to do to and with such a intelligence.
Rym: But we are so, so impossibly far from that technology.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Then what we have now is basically just a giant spreadsheet and then fancy spreadsheet lookups.
Scott: It's like there's no moral or ethical problem with turning off the computer or deleting the spreadsheet or anything like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there are lots and lots and lots of ethical and moral issues regards to using the giant spreadsheet.
Scott: You know, you've seen plenty of people talking about how like image recognition is racist.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: You know, automatic like photo editing stuff racist.
Rym: Also true, because the data encodes the implicit biases and dimensionality of our existing flawed society.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This spreadsheet was filled with data from humanity and therefore the flaws of humanity.
Scott: And the systems we already have make their way into the system.
Scott: So it's like, you know, they don't just make their way into the system.
Rym: They define the system.
Rym: And then because of the scale of this computing, they amplify those flaws.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you could be like, you know, let's say you wanted to have something that like the computer helped you to, you know, find the like, you know, decide to give someone mortgages or not.
Scott: And it's like, well, the people who've been deciding to give mortgages or not all this time are racist.
Scott: So if you fill it with the history of all mortgages, hand it out forever.
Scott: And guess what?
Scott: It's going to keep being racist.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And only white people are going to get mortgage.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So and this leads into like you remember a way back, we barely talked about some geek guys.
Rym: It was a long time ago, but Google Assistant, they announced a feature long time ago where Google Assistant could if you like used an app or like clicked on a restaurant and Google Maps and you wanted to make a reservation or like put in an order.
Rym: And the only way you could interact with that business was via a phone number like they didn't have like a grubhub or like a web form to fill out or anything, then it would call that business and a human sounding voice would just interact with the person on the other end of the line to answer your question.
Rym: Like, are you open today?
Rym: It's Memorial Day and get the answer and give it back to you.
Rym: And that opened a whole shitstorm.
Rym: On one hand, businesses were afraid that they would be inundated with thousands and thousands of calls that were automated.
Rym: Luddites were afraid that this would replace human communication, even though I kind of wanted to.
Rym: Like, I don't want to waste a human's time calling them to make a dinner reservation.
Rym: Like, I don't I don't want to waste humans sorting that out.
Rym: We could sort that out easily with technology.
Rym: It could be an interesting.
Scott: Get a better website and it won't have to call you.
Scott: Yeah, come on.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: But most businesses don't have a better website.
Rym: I mean, that's why things like Grubhub exist in the first place, unfortunately.
Scott: Get your shit together.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But in the end, Google kind of backed away from a lot of this and they agreed to, among other things, if Google Assistant calls a business, it will tell you it's a robot.
Rym: It will like explicitly say what it is before it interacts with you.
Rym: And that opened a whole bunch of ethical concerns that are still not fully explored.
Rym: And that is like baby's first use of this kind of technology.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So regarding the actual news story guy, right, with the chatbot that is not sentient, but they believe it is.
Scott: the major ethical concern that I see with that particular thing is that, you know, even though this person involved is, you know, I guess we'll keep using the word interesting.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Unique individual.
Scott: They are convinced that it's sentient, right?
Rym: If it's all that, I would argue so.
Rym: This person may have failed what I'm going to now call the reverse Turing test.
Scott: Maybe, but regardless, this bot thing, right, that is not sentient is software that is capable of convincing some percentage of the world population that it is sentient.
Rym: So if I loaded up the history of everything I've ever typed into this thing, say someone else did it nefarious, they could probably make a discord bot that could talk like if Scott messaged it, it would respond and very plausibly seem like me.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, this that in and of itself could be used for nefarious things.
Rym: I mean, look at what.
Rym: look at.
Rym: look at the online discourse right now, the massive sea of disinformation, Russian bots everywhere.
Rym: There are a lot of people who are fooled by bots on social media.
Rym: already when other people will look at one sentence from one of those bots and their brain immediately says, wow, that's a bot.
Rym: But this technology makes more people susceptible to being fooled.
Scott: So here's a very you know, I think the I guess the saving grace is that it's very expensive to run this bot, at least for now.
Scott: Now, but but here's here's a really simple case that's just so obvious of how someone could use this for evil.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, there's all those people who call up old people and try to trick them into thinking, you know, tech support or something.
Scott: They see all their money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they have these call centers, you know, mostly in India.
Scott: You can watch on YouTube all those channels or they bust those people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like the call centers are full of real humans right in India, you know, calling up, you know, citizens of other countries trying to scam them.
Scott: And while this is effectively a mechanical bot, if you could get the bot to make those calls, you could get.
Scott: now one person could scam the whole world, keep all the money and not have to hire any call center people or rent any office space.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Same thing that happened with spam.
Rym: Spam appeared because you could just automate sending ridiculous emails to millions and millions of people.
Rym: And if only one percent of them fall for it, you still make a ton of money.
Rym: It costs you nothing.
Rym: It's way cheaper than mass mailers.
Rym: That used to be the way scams propagated.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then how are the anti scam people?
Scott: How are they?
Scott: what are they going to do?
Scott: How?
Scott: what can they do about it?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's going to be really hard.
Scott: It's not like you can call up, you know, the.
Scott: I can't really be intimidated.
Rym: Imagine these eyes start texting every old person in America pretending to be their son and saying that and I'm like, I'm in jail.
Rym: I need 50 bucks for bail.
Rym: Grandpa, help me.
Scott: And it actually believed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It actually talked like their grandchild.
Scott: Not just like a grandchild, but there's specifically like maybe new things about their grandchild.
Rym: I mean, I have already had to block people I otherwise liked on social media networks like Twitter because I would see them in my mentions arguing with bots like, how do you not see?
Rym: it's not a bot?
Rym: The better this technology gets, the more people will fail that reverse Turing test and interact with bots they think are people.
Scott: I think you could also see situations, right.
Scott: You know, how many online platforms, right, whether it's a game or a social network or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's like you have.
Scott: if you try to start something these days, it's really hard because like, you know, it's like I'll make a video platform.
Scott: It's like YouTube exists.
Scott: What are you going to do?
Scott: Right.
Scott: You need to.
Scott: you got to have the network effect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Get this user base up.
Scott: To then get your, you know, to have your platform be worth using.
Scott: You can make the best video site in the universe, but it's not the software that makes it great.
Scott: It's all the users and the content that they're uploading.
Scott: And YouTube already has that.
Scott: So it's like, you know, right.
Scott: Or it's not?
Scott: it's not the.
Scott: I can make a Twitter really easily, but it doesn't have all the people that are on Twitter.
Scott: So whatever.
Scott: But what if I artificially filled up my brand new app, right, with a bunch of AI generated garbage, but it was actually legitimate content that people found interesting and believed was real people.
Scott: And that caused I basically fake the network effect to give myself fake customers to defraud investors into thinking I have users and that I don't make a social media network.
Rym: Dolly version 2.0 is putting great illustrations on it.
Rym: And then your GPT 10,000 algorithm has a million people risk sharing and resharing and interacting with and responding to that original bot.
Scott: You got your Twitch channel and you're trying to get whatever status.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You don't have enough users, but you could do it.
Scott: The people do the botting.
Scott: But guess what?
Scott: The botting, you know, is kind of obvious.
Scott: But what if all those bots are chatting in Twitch chat in a human believable way and nobody can tell that those are not Twitch?
Rym: and we are already seeing this today.
Rym: It's just if you listen to GeekNights, you're probably the kind of person who recognizes when a bot comes into the chat.
Rym: But a lot of people already today don't.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: And so, yeah, the fact that the bot is now advanced to the level where the AI researcher person, whatever issues they may have, believes it's sentient, means it's too advanced to probably be safe for anyone to be using without oversight and regulation or at all.
Scott: Like, what do you what's even?
Scott: what's the legitimate use of this thing?
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like, yeah, I so I can so forget ethics.
Rym: Here are some fascinating uses.
Rym: One, scaling out various types of entrapment schemes from law enforcement at scale, like.
Rym: that's a way to do it.
Rym: They go out to find people who are prone to, say, engaging in right wing extremism and then basically act like you're basically pulling them into a fake network of similar minded people when actually it's all just bots until eventually they do something.
Scott: Why don't you do that then?
Rym: I mean, you could probably could.
Scott: I'm saying why don't you do that?
Rym: Because I got a day job.
Scott: Good idea.
Rym: I'm not saying it's a good idea.
Rym: I'm saying it's these are practicable ideas.
Rym: OK, an example of an app you could sell, sell an app where you load it with all your own information and you use it.
Rym: You pick people on your contact list, like, say, you're the kind of person who doesn't like to talk to your mom.
Rym: You tell it to maintain your relationship with your mom and just give you a feed of updates of what your mom's up to.
Rym: But it talks to your mom on a day to day basis and she doesn't realize it.
Scott: It seems like a bad idea.
Rym: I didn't say it's a good idea.
Rym: I said it's a practicable idea that I think you can make money selling such an app.
Rym: And I think a lot of people would buy it.
Scott: Yeah, and then it tells your mom something not great.
Rym: Yeah, well, that's when the person who wrote who made the app.
Rym: one starts deep faking you and all your friends and scams them for money and to blackmail you.
Scott: So this technology, you also have to realize that, like, you know, if you any such at least with the current levels of technology, performance wise, right.
Scott: Such a bot, if you were to use it in that way, would have to run in the cloud.
Scott: You could run the whole thing on someone's job.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you're going to have to send all your chats and all your mom's chats, all your full mom conversation to this cloud service unencrypted so that they can process it.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: And now you're basically right.
Scott: So now whoever runs this service, even if the service itself and what it does for the customer, we agree is legitimate and ethical, you now have a company that has access to all of these private conversations in an unencrypted fashion.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And even if they have a good privacy policy and abide by it, it is dangerous to have all of that data in a place.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And there are technological solutions to that problem.
Rym: But if the Internet of Things has taught us anything, no controls will ever be put on top of pretty much anything anyone builds.
Scott: Anyway, do we have anything else to say because I'm hungry?
Rym: I think we can wrap up there.
Rym: So we should be on our pretty much regular GeekNights schedule for the foreseeable future.
Rym: unless the Rangers make the Stanley Cup again in the foreseeable future.
Scott: It's not going to happen for another 12 months.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If it happens at all.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Link Eiji, Dread Loony, Tenebrae and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Chris Adon, Chris Reimer, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Kishaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Review Mad Bull, 34 Cowards, Sam Erickson, Sharon Von Hurl, Stop All the Downloading, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is DuPont, DuPont Station.
Rym: And several people whose names I will not say.
Rym: I simply leave you with an old classic.
Scott: Good afternoon and welcome to Brandy Park.
Scott: And you join us just as the competitors are running out onto the field on this lovely winter's afternoon with the going firm underfoot and very little sign of rain.
Rym: And it looks as though we're in for a splendid afternoon sport on this, the 127th Upper Class Twit of the Year show.
Scott: And there's a big crowd here today to see these prize idiots in action.
Scott: Vivian Smith by Smith.
Scott: He's in the Grenadier Guards and he can count up to four.
Scott: Simon Zink Trumpet Harris.
Scott: He's an old Etonian and married to a very attractive table lamp.
Scott: Nigel Incubator Jones, his best friend as a tree.
Scott: And in his spare time, he's a stockbroker.
Scott: Gervais Brooke-Hamster.
Scott: He's in the wine trade and his father uses him as a waste paper basket.
Scott: And finally, Oliver Singin-Mollusk, another old Etonian.
Scott: His father was a cabinet minister and his mother won the Derby.
Scott: And he's thought by many to be this year's Outstanding Twit.
Scott: And now the Twits are moving up to the starting line.
Scott: And any moment now, they'll be under starters orders.
Scott: I'm afraid they're facing the wrong way at the moment.
Scott: But the starter will soon sort this out.
Scott: And any moment now, we're going to have the big off.
Scott: This is always a tense moment.
Scott: And they're off!