Scott:
Rym: It's Thursday, March 17th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about St.
Rym: Patrick's Day.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: The holiday.
Rym: So yeah, we kind of had a sort of accidental GeekNights hiatus that's actually going to continue into next week due to a series of literally unrelated events that for each day we would have done a GeekNights, there was some reason why one of us couldn't.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't like, "Oh, let's take a week or two
Scott: off.".
Scott: It was like, "Oh, can't do the show tonight.
Scott: Oh, can't do the show tonight.
Scott: Oh, can't do the show
Scott: tonight.".
Rym: It was funny because I actually, like, I noticed that.
Rym: so I tweeted like, "Hey,
Rym: FYI.".
Scott: It wasn't even an out of idea situation like it sometimes is.
Rym: Many of these days we had a show queued up to do, meaning the next few weeks will be easy.
Rym: Actually, no, they won't because we're going to forget what those shows were.
Rym: I've already forgotten.
Rym: I remember the next Thursday show we're going to do, though.
Rym: See if I remember it two weeks from now.
Rym: But it's funny because I tweeted and a bunch of people were like, "Well, yeah, yeah, like, you've been doing this show for so long.
Rym: I'm surprised you never took a break
Rym: before.".
Rym: Because in retrospect, we've very rarely taken breaks from GeekNights, except at very specific times of year.
Rym: usually, like right around November, December, we've always taken a break.
Rym: We've always taken a break around March when there's a lot of conventions in a row.
Rym: But it's the first time we had a break just kind of in the middle of a random time.
Rym: I guess that is March.
Scott: I guess, but we're not going to the PAX East.
Scott: Well, you guess we're not going for real.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, all I will be at PAX East on Thursday doing a panel.
Rym: There is a non-zero but not high chance that Scott will be there.
Rym: Probably not.
Scott: I think it's zero.
Rym: You think?
Rym: So it's not technically zero yet, just like the Red Wings are not mathematically eliminated from the wildcard.
Scott: I suppose there could be some reason that could urge, but at the current time, I have absolutely no plan to go, and in fact, I plan to not go.
Rym: In fact, I would say the odds of Scott being with me live at PAX East are the same as the odds that the Red Wings make the wildcard slot in the Stanley Cup playoffs.
Scott: I don't know, I think the Red Wings have a better chance.
Rym: Uh, that does not appear true.
Rym: There's basically only, the teams that are going to get the wildcard slot are basically fighting over who has the last and second to last seed.
Rym: Like, there's a pretty big gap in the score, at least last I checked.
Scott: 55 points, and they need to catch up to...
Rym: 70-something?
Scott: Yeah, it's not looking good.
Rym: It's not looking good.
Rym: So yeah, on my side, I had a family emergency, which, 100% okay, like, it is resolved, but it was a medical scare that, you know, sometimes there's a, you get a phone call from a relative who doesn't call you.
Rym: often at a time, they don't tend to call you on the phone, and when you don't answer, they immediately call you again.
Scott: You just see the phone ringing, and it's a name of a relative you don't speak to.
Scott: It's like, you know, somebody's not doing good.
Rym: Or it's one you speak to kind of often, but you don't speak to, like, in the middle of a weekday.
Scott: Right, you can just tell by the person and the time that there's something wrong with that phone call before you pick up the phone.
Rym: Yup, better call James Randi.
Rym: But it was a situation, I'm not going to share details, obviously.
Scott: It's not a psychic thing, it's just, you know, a deduction based on...
Rym: But the situation ended up being, there was a chance this could have gone real bad, and it ended up being the best possible scenario for everyone involved, and the person involved is making a full recovery, and that's exciting.
Rym: I got to go to Florida and say hi to people once COVID is a little safer and it's a little warmer, but...
Scott: If I would go to Florida.
Rym: I mean, they live in Florida now, and it's like a zombie apocalypse still, like, avoid people at all costs.
Rym: I'm glad I live in the north.
Rym: But also, like, a hockey game came up, a friend we haven't seen in years was in town on one of the nights.
Rym: There's just been a lot happening, and guess what?
Rym: Next week, No GeekNights, because I'm going to be in London all week working out of my London office just for a work thing, so...
Scott: Coming to London.
Rym: Yeah, you're going to London.
Rym: It was very much, get this, it was very much a "we're going to London" situation.
Rym: Because, get this, I'm at work, you know, doing my thing, and someone messages me, and they're like, "Hey, so we should talk about the London
Rym: thing.".
Rym: And I was like, "What London
Rym: thing?".
Rym: And he's like, "You're going to be here, right?
Rym: For the
Rym: thing?".
Rym: And I had to go sort that out, but it turns out I am, in fact, going to London, so...
Scott: Well, good luck with that.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: At least the London weather there is better than it is here.
Rym: I biked home from work today, but it is not warm enough yet.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's hard to see, I think, today.
Rym: The good part of that is, it wasn't actively raining, but because it was so foggy and kind of damp, nobody else was biking.
Rym: I got home in like half the time I normally get home, because there's so much bike traffic normally that I actually run into, like, bike traffic on my way home from work when I bike home now.
Rym: Like, it's getting real dense.
Rym: Which is a good thing, but it means we need to take more lanes away from cars and make more bike lanes.
Scott: The congestion pricing might show up late next year, 2023, but it doesn't seem like it's going to be high enough to dissuade drivers from coming.
Scott: I think it seems like it's just going to try to get some revenues.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I increasingly see the most effective strategy with the least harm that's feasible in a country like America.
Rym: Because obviously there are ways to do this in a good way, but America is just incapable of that kind of thing.
Rym: But as to the primary thing you want to go after is reducing the number of lanes of travel, because that slows traffic, makes it more annoying to travel, so the people...
Scott: Inverse-induced demand, right?
Rym: But it does not remove the possibility.
Rym: That way, people who have another option are increasingly pushed to use that option, but people who literally do not have another option still have that option available.
Rym: And there's a lot of externalities of fucking with traffic, but that seems to be the safest, least harm way to make it better for everyone in America as America is today.
Scott: But also just charging what it costs, right?
Scott: I've seen studies saying that a car driving into Manhattan on a weekday causes about 80 to even... I've seen estimates as high as $160, and who knows inflation, right, when these studies were done, right, in externalities.
Scott: Meaning that, you know, basically, collectively as a society, we are subsidizing, right, anyone... Someone drives into Manhattan on a car on a weekday, they're costing society $160 in damage.
Scott: Pollution, road maintenance, the space they take up, right, you know, slowing everyone else down, just, you know, taking up a parking spot, you know, all these factors, right?
Scott: And if they had to pay for all of those things, they might have to pay $160 just for coming in, right?
Scott: Now, if someone comes in, and then let's say it's a tourist, and that tourist sees a Broadway show and goes to a hockey game and buys three meals and stays in a hotel for $500 a night, they're effectively going to be covering the damage they've done, you know, with the money they spend,
Rym: but
Scott: even if that's the case, what you have is sort of an indirect subsidizing of those businesses, right, by all of us, right?
Scott: So, you know, it's like, but if you go ahead and just charge someone, it's like, yeah, the toll to cross the bridge is 160 bucks now.
Scott: It's like, well, that, you know, that's not very fair to someone who needs to come and has no fucking money, right?
Scott: So you need to find a way, I think, you know, the fairest system would be find a way to charge that price, but then scale the price.
Scott: It's like if a rich guy wants to drive his car in, 1,000 bucks to cross the bridge.
Scott: Go fuck yourself, right?
Scott: And if a poor person drives the bridge, okay, zero dollars.
Rym: Yeah, until we can do things like build more buses.
Scott: The rich guy paid for you, don't worry about it.
Rym: Like build more bus lanes, build more trains, like do the stuff to make it easier for the poor person to travel.
Rym: The other way to go, like on a higher level, I always think about the fact that roads are so heavily subsidized, yet mass transit systems are expected to break even or be profitable.
Scott: Yes, they should all be zero dollars.
Rym: Yeah, either we pay the real cost for both of them, in which case mass transit will be so much cheaper that people would fight desperately to get more mass transit or mass transit should be free.
Rym: I still say anyone with a New York City ID should be able to ride the New York City subway an unlimited number of times free.
Scott: No, I think don't even don't even need to put any ifs, right?
Scott: Because think about this, if you just let everyone ride, everyone, any human being to get on a subway or a bus, right?
Scott: It should be zero dollars, right?
Scott: And not only is that just, you know, fairer for everybody, but you will actually save a ton of money because now you can just tear up the turnstiles.
Scott: You don't need to run this this omni system.
Scott: You don't need to have these MTA employees.
Scott: You know, cops can do something else besides, you know, arrest people trying to jump the turnstiles.
Scott: You know, it becomes more accessible.
Scott: People don't got to get the door open to get the wheelchair through.
Rym: The elevators could go directly to the platform without having to stop on a mezzanine, which is a big reason why a lot of old subway stations still don't have elevators.
Rym: There's physically nowhere to put elevators because you need two sets of elevators to handle the whole metro situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the savings, all those, there's a whole building near you, right, in a secret quote location where they count all the cash that comes in every day.
Scott: It's like if the cash is just tax money, then there is no cash coming into the transit system and they can just fire all those people.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: And but, you know, you get sell that building, right?
Scott: It's like this.
Scott: How much money is spent in order to collect money safely?
Scott: All those guards with armored armed cars filling up MetroCard machines, right?
Scott: All that infrastructure just poof, you know, how much did they invest to set up this whole omni thing?
Scott: They could have just not spent that money.
Rym: So here's the best way to do it.
Rym: Just make the subway free for everyone, just no tourist house or anything, but sell on, sell to tourists, passes and convince them that there's an RFID that gets checked.
Scott: Oh, you know that scammers will be doing that.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Well, just to this day, we should just let those scammers get away with it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Just like people sell tickets for that, the free ferries that go past the Statue of Liberty.
Rym: So you wanted to talk about Obsidian, not the Cardassian Obsidian order, but yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, so I've known a long time about, you know, this idea of personal wikis, right?
Scott: So think of like Wikipedia, but you just make one for yourself and you're the only one who ever writes in it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I've done this at every job I've ever had.
Rym: Like I had a wiki that I would like I ran a Twiggy wiki just for myself to organize my own work when I worked at both IBM and pipeline.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I've tried a bunch of those in the in the past, but they've always been kind of meh, you know, and like, you're not, you know, it's like it's hard to stick with them and hard to keep using them.
Rym: Well, especially because work is a is one thing because there's a certain structure to work and you can sort of mirror that structure in a wiki and the wiki only cares about like a certain domain.
Rym: But imagine trying to wiki your actual life.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So on the one hand, obviously, you know, even if you have a system that works for you and you use it, you have to like not document your entire life in text form because then what life are you living?
Scott: That's weird.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Don't go overboard.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: But I've used things like, you know, Google Keep, for example.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's you can't really keep everything in there.
Rym: Keep is just like a list of things.
Rym: I have to do in the near future is how I use Google.
Scott: I use Google tasks for that.
Scott: But, you know, but it's like, you know, there's no organization to a Google Keep or an Apple Notes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's no relation.
Scott: You know, the hyperlinking functionality is not there.
Scott: So Obsidian is this software?
Scott: that's free.
Scott: It's not 100 percent open source, I don't think.
Scott: But there are features you can pay for, like syncing.
Scott: But you don't actually need to pay for that because you could just use like some other underlying sync, like iCloud file sync or, you know, Dropbox or something to sync the files because you're just making markdown files.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're much easier to write.
Scott: And this little app runs on desktop and iOS and it runs on everything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you can get your, you know, to your notes about your life from anywhere.
Scott: And, you know, I think what's good about it is that the reason to do this, you know, it's like what.
Scott: what problem are you solving by doing this?
Scott: Right.
Scott: The problem that I was trying to solve was that there's often cases where I'm trying to recall information.
Scott: That is information that could never be Googled ever.
Scott: But also my memory is bad.
Scott: So, for example, I'm not recording everything I eat.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But like, what did you have for lunch last Thursday?
Scott: You would never.
Scott: It's not Googleable.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: Unless you remember, you're not going to know.
Scott: But if you were to record something like that, then this would be the way to do it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So but there are things.
Scott: For example, that you might want to remember for a conversation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So let's say I go to a hockey game.
Scott: And somebody scores their first NHL goal at that game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like now, if I was going to try to Google that later, like two years later, was I I think I was at the game where that guy scored his first NHL goal.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't remember, though.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You could go and find your ticket stub and then try to Google for like that person when they scored their first goal.
Scott: And right.
Scott: And that's going to take you a while.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you just leave a hockey game and then, you know, a relatively medium to significant event, you know, not an everyday occurrence.
Scott: And just make a quick note, like, was that hockey game?
Scott: Here's the two notable things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There was a DJ named.
Rym: This is remember all the all the stuff around the former guys, multiple impeachments and all these memos that keep coming up.
Rym: That is a really important concept of if anything notable happens.
Rym: It's not that by writing it down, you now have proof that it happened.
Rym: It's more that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Because you can write down a lie.
Scott: It's not proof at all, but it's metadata.
Rym: It's additional contributing information to remind you what happened.
Rym: So you have this artifact you can point to from the future about that incident or remember it or corroborate that with other memos and other information other people have written.
Scott: The other problem I'm trying to solve.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is that, you know, something happens, you know, when you're a person like me who talks on the Internet too much more than anyone should.
Scott: Conversations tend to repeat that.
Scott: They repeat themselves a lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Like a while ago in a private discord where someone accused me of raising a topic we had already discussed.
Scott: Not not not like that.
Scott: I'm saying there are certain discussion topics that keep coming up repeatedly month after month.
Rym: And you want to go back and find like this is all the things I would say.
Rym: I would have said these again in the same conversation.
Rym: So I already have a Google Doc bot that figures out if you're tweeting something you've already tweeted and just it'll auto complete the entire account like that.
Scott: But like I have a Google I have a Google Doc that has basically a list of like.
Scott: if someone is buying a bicycle, here are the things to say.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But here you can go.
Scott: if you use a wiki, you can go one further where like.
Scott: let's say we're talking about some game topic for a panel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like people playing games slowly.
Scott: And it's like, you know, there's all these things that we have to say about that topic.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if you have all those ideas and they're all tagged and linked in like a wiki.
Scott: Then it's like, ah.
Scott: And then as you think of new ideas, if they relate to that topic.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You put them in and over time, you're like developing your.
Scott: you know, you're not you're instead of repeating yourself over and over.
Scott: It's like you're actually a because you have the storage.
Scott: That's not your crappy memory.
Scott: Now you're developing your thoughts over time in a better way.
Scott: You're not like repeating thoughts you've already had.
Scott: If you've already had a thought, you'll see it there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, they're all interlinked.
Scott: You can you can like and if you say, you know, maybe one day I go in and I realize like, you know, I need a new panel idea.
Scott: You know, I go in and I see, wow, this particular note has like 20 things linked to it.
Scott: I could probably turn whatever that note is about into a panel.
Scott: And all those 20 linked ideas are going to be the slides.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or even though I was trying to do that intentionally.
Scott: Just the ideas and thoughts.
Scott: You know, anytime you have a thought that's like a new thought or a or a somewhat insightful thought, you just put it in and tag it appropriately.
Scott: And then you can go look at the Web when it's time to produce content and it's like it will give back to you.
Scott: And so I've you know, usually, you know, I'm sort of my whole life I was like and writing notes.
Scott: I don't take notes at school.
Scott: I remember I think I've told this story right where I was in a class and the teacher in high school and the teacher called out another student for not writing notes.
Scott: And the student said, Scott isn't writing notes.
Scott: And the teacher said, Scott's getting an A. Right.
Scott: So I never took notes ever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I didn't really study.
Scott: I just, you know, did projects and homework.
Scott: But, you know, now only after half my life is gone.
Scott: Why do I see some value in note taking?
Rym: Especially because right now we're at an interesting point where we've been socially isolated.
Rym: We being the royal we not like everybody because of covid.
Rym: So we've been socially isolated for a while, alone with our own thoughts in a much smaller circle of people.
Rym: And also, Scott and I, we've been doing panels and lectures for so long.
Rym: And every now and then we do hit this point of like, wait, what that?
Rym: what the hell new thing are we going to talk about?
Rym: And they're sort of coming to a head in that because we're isolated, we're not even playing like new games and doing a lot of new things.
Rym: Meaning I keep diving back into old topics deeper and deeper with like the panels I'm doing without Scott during this slow ramp up to going back to.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it's like this.
Scott: So, you know, this sort of an intellectual standstill.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Because the best thing is related to the major, you know, things that are related to major world events are advancing and everything else is sort of stuck.
Rym: All the things that happen when you get an eclectic or different group of people communicating or you revisit an idea and then expand from it instead of revisiting it to remember where you got it to last time.
Scott: Yeah, it seems there are some apparently there are some people who subscribe to like these various, you know, systems of note taking like this, the Zettelkasten stuff or whatever, based on something some old German dude did with note cards a long time ago.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, yeah, I'm not sticking to any of these like dogmatic systems of like.
Rym: you have to take notes a certain way, but it is certain kinds of people who have certain kinds of right.
Scott: But it is interesting.
Scott: So, you know, I did take some ideas because you do have to set up some sort of structure when you do this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I took ideas from that and I was like, oh, yeah, OK, I see what you're saying.
Scott: That makes sense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it sort of works.
Scott: So if you are a person who, you know, has either of those problems, I do recommend this.
Scott: Also, a lot of TTRPG people are using this software to take notes on their games.
Rym: I was thinking about that because one thing I'm starting to struggle with is we've been playing Blades in the Dark, an RPG for the entirety of Covid.
Rym: So I've been.
Rym: this is now like the fourth or fifth longest campaign I've ever played in a tabletop RPG in my life.
Rym: And there is a rich body of the history and the proper nouns and like the things that have happened in this world.
Rym: But I just have this really long Google Doc broken down by each session and what happens in that.
Scott: Imagine if instead of that Google Doc, you had a bunch of really tiny notes that were all linked.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, in like a wiki style.
Rym: Because then instead of like I've like, wait, like control F and like, wait, how many how many dealers did Bibi go through as she kept like getting them killed?
Rym: Like, no, I can click on Bibi and see a cluster of all the heroin dealers that Bibi is.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Well, and right.
Scott: Bibi would have the tag dealer.
Scott: You click on dealer and dealer would be a page.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That would link to all dealers.
Rym: And that was the guy who sold the magic ghost mushrooms that Bibi got him arrested.
Rym: No, the other guy was selling a magic ghost mushrooms would have a page.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Oh, magic ghost mushrooms are a big part of the plot right now.
Rym: We just stole a bunch from a military waste dump and we're going to make drugs out of it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But yeah, I've been using this software for a little while now and I'm still using it.
Scott: So now I can.
Scott: I can recommend it after.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I might try it out.
Scott: I wasn't going to say anything about it because, you know, it could have been like install it, say I'm going to use it and then not use it.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, this could be good, especially honestly, I might try it out to to start to crystallize our more like we've got to have it.
Rym: We've been talking a lot.
Rym: I guess we can say it on the show because I'm not shit talking.
Rym: I'm not promising we're going to do anything in particular.
Rym: But we've been talking a lot on our own about how to do another round of panels.
Rym: You know, guys over the years, we've had like sets of years where we do like a certain type of panel or a certain depth of a topic.
Rym: And we kind of want to do another round of old topics where we go way deeper and start to assume that people know some of these basics.
Rym: But that requires way more research and diligence than we have had time to do lately.
Rym: And this is a better way to organize those kinds of thoughts.
Rym: So we'll say I try this out.
Scott: So, yeah, obsidian note, I guess is what if you see like a purple gem, that's that's you found the right software.
Rym: Now, so what is plug ins and all kinds of stuff in some huge and surprising news?
Rym: Interestingly, surprising not only to us, but also to the senators who passed it, which I find utterly hilarious, but not in a way more in a ridiculous, sad way.
Rym: Daylight saving time switching back and forth in America might is about to end unless like the House fails to pass it or Biden vetoes it.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Scott: It's not it's not a done deal yet, but it's it's way close.
Scott: It passed the biggest hurdle.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Some hurdles remaining, but none of them are taller than the one it has already jumped.
Rym: So the funny thing is getting rid of the time change has been extremely popular in America for a long time.
Rym: Very few people actually like the changing of the time.
Rym: But America has always been extremely divided on what should we settle on the regular time or the daylight saving time?
Scott: Well, it also depends how close you live to the edge of a time zone.
Rym: Yeah, I live six hundred miles away from where I used to live, and yet I'm in the same time zone.
Rym: So I had way more daylight at night when I was young than I do in New York, despite living in the same time zone.
Rym: Sun went down in like July at like nine.
Scott: Even in Rochester was is farther west, right?
Rym: So Rochester is about halfway to where I lived.
Rym: A little more actually, a little more than halfway.
Rym: But I've always been an advocate of I don't care.
Rym: I can be pitch black when I wake up.
Rym: I just want as much daylight as possible when I'm not at work.
Scott: That's my all.
Rym: That's all I want.
Rym: I literally do not care about any other concern personally than that one.
Scott: Well, it has to be dark when I'm sleeping, too.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not healthy to sleep with the sun shining on you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it is healthy to be outside while the sun is out.
Scott: But during the winter, if I'm right, I want to maximize the amount of time I'm awake in the sun and also dark when asleep and minimize the asleep wake time and the asleep sun time and the awake dark time.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But the problem with living in the part of America we live in and many places have this problem in the winter, I wake up to go to work.
Rym: It's dark out.
Rym: I go to work.
Rym: I come home.
Rym: The sun is setting as I'm leaving work, basically, or dark when I leave work.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Though what's interesting is a lot of people.
Rym: Well, a lot of people who are very loud, but might not or not are definitely not actually a majority of people.
Rym: Their primary complaint about the plan that's going to happen, which is the one that's actually, as far as I can tell, majority popular of go to daylight saving time, meaning it gets light later and gets dark later and staying there.
Rym: The complaint against it that's primarily raised is either an archaic agricultural argument that's just not relevant to the modern era or parents complaining that kids will have to get up in the dark and that those.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So first of all, I even with the clocks that switch all the time, I got up in the dark a lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So elementary, middle and high school, I got up before the sun rose pretty much all all school year except like May and June.
Scott: That was not.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't like all the time, but it was it was almost all the time.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So but additionally, I guess what I'm saying is the only reason that happens.
Rym: That is not because of daylight saving time.
Rym: That is because America is so broken that parents need daycare and school to be the same thing.
Rym: And school has to start before parents have to be at work.
Rym: There's a lot of reasons why this is a problem.
Rym: that are not because of the time change.
Rym: They're because of society being broken.
Scott: Similarly, I feel like this is, you know, you should just if you need if whatever you're doing right requires some sort of, you know, difference of time, change your damn schedule.
Scott: Tell your school says your local school systems.
Scott: You be like, hey, make school start later.
Scott: Make tell your job.
Scott: I'm coming in later.
Scott: I'm coming in earlier.
Scott: You know, sort your shit out.
Rym: Yeah, but our society is incapable of that.
Rym: But the other complaint and I even found an article talking about the last because the US did this in the 70s during the oil crisis.
Rym: We went to DSC permanently for a while and then we went back and a lot of people hated it.
Rym: But even back then, the primary argument was that kids are going to get hit by cars in the morning because it's dark.
Scott: So studies actually show that there's less car accidents and basically daylight savings time is good for health and environment.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Less electric light usage.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You know, we're saving on energy if we stay in daylight savings time.
Rym: Well, they like saving time.
Rym: There's no S on the end of that.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: We also, you know, when the clocks regard, I guess it doesn't matter which one of the two clocks you go to, but the changing messes up a lot of changing of the clocks.
Scott: There are quite a lot of car crashes and other problems of like sleepy people in the morning after the clock rolls forward.
Rym: And when it rolls back, it happens in both time changes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And not to mention, you know, just the health impact.
Scott: People will live longer and be healthier by getting more sunlight.
Scott: It's going to add up.
Rym: But even worse, get this back then in the.
Scott: maybe they'll be more.
Scott: maybe there could be more skin cancer, but it's like that.
Scott: That's other things.
Rym: That's a problem that is also caused by other problems.
Rym: That is a much broader conversation.
Rym: But so even in the 70s, there was technically an uptick in kids being hit by cars on the way to school in the morning when it was dark.
Rym: But that uptick was statistically insignificant.
Rym: And furthermore, there was a statistically significant decrease in kids being hit by cars after school.
Rym: So it was better even then.
Rym: And the people who said it was dangerous were being disingenuous and lying to you.
Scott: So also in the 70s.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, kids were still walking to school.
Rym: Also in the 70s, America was still extremely lead poisoned.
Rym: There was a lot of things going on with cars in the 70s.
Scott: Never mind the fact that still are going on.
Rym: Well, never mind the final point I wanted to get to that I think you were about to get to unrelated to me.
Rym: The problem there is that cars are hitting kids regardless of the light.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: That's the problem.
Rym: So I'm really excited about this.
Rym: So the weirdest thing is that no one expected this to pass.
Rym: The U.S.
Rym: government has made motions to do this almost every term for as long as we've been alive.
Rym: This topic comes up every year.
Rym: It's majority popular and it doesn't pass for reasons because a handful of senators and lobbyists and interest groups will argue against it, mostly for ridiculous or capitalist based reasons.
Rym: It passed this time kind of by accident.
Rym: Basically, the Senate used a procedure known as unanimous consent, where basically the Senate says no.
Rym: OK, I guess the Senate has a really stupid rule about the filibuster needing 60 votes and all this nonsense.
Rym: But you can always say, hey, everybody, unanimous consent.
Rym: Does anyone disagree with this?
Rym: Because if no one does, we can just pass it right now.
Scott: And that never happens.
Scott: Common sense.
Rym: It never happens.
Scott: Because if someone says, hey, can we just have universal health care right now?
Scott: Someone's gonna be like, fuck, no, I'm not going to let that happen.
Rym: So noted piece of shit, Senator Tom Cotton discovered after this passed that it passed and was mad about it.
Rym: Apparently, his aides didn't bother telling him that this was going to come up for a fast track vote because they assumed that, one, nobody cares about this issue.
Rym: Two, there's no way it's going to pass.
Rym: And three, there's other stuff going on.
Rym: So we're not going to bother him about it.
Scott: So, yeah.
Rym: Fuck you, Senator Tom Cotton.
Scott: We won.
Scott: This is what I keep.
Scott: I've said this before, is that like these senators are a bunch of old people.
Scott: If you are willing to do dirty tricks, like make sure their aides don't even know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It just you could slip shit through.
Scott: You just got to be dirty and not care about being dirty.
Scott: It can happen.
Scott: It proof it happened once.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's going to be pretty hard.
Scott: It's going to be harder to slip something more meaningful.
Scott: You do like you announce a Taco Tuesdays, but you try to, I don't know, disband the U.S.
Scott: military completely.
Scott: It would be harder to slip that through.
Rym: You announce a Taco Tuesdays for all the staff and aides, and you only announce it to the Republican staff and aides, and then you lock them all in the Taco Tuesday long enough to pass universal health care and the new Voting Rights Act.
Scott: It could happen.
Scott: It really could.
Scott: They got their way.
Scott: The rules are so wacky.
Scott: It's like the good of success.
Scott: The consequences of failure are nothing.
Scott: Your status quo is maintained.
Scott: The consequences of success are enormous benefit to all society.
Scott: Why wouldn't you constantly try it every damn day?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: If there was a negative consequence, OK, stop trying.
Rym: So there is an example of that that was briefly attempted relatively recently, but they didn't go all the way because it wasn't going to succeed.
Rym: There is the concept of the reverse filibuster, where you bring something up for a vote, and of course, some Republican is going to filibuster it, and then you vote against your own bill, and then you bring it up for a vote again.
Rym: And you wait for them to filibuster it.
Rym: You vote against your own bill, and you just never stop.
Rym: But that's real hard to pull off.
Rym: It hasn't been done successfully for anything important, ever.
Scott: You can just make all your senators as endurance athletes, and you keep it going until some of those old dudes die because they're so old.
Scott: They'll literally die there, and you're young enough, you'll live, and then you can pass.
Scott: It's like, I'm just going to outlive you.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: I mean, if I was a younger endurance athlete type person, it's like, you're telling me all I've got to do is out-endurance an old guy, and I can do something that will have a significant beneficial impact on all of society?
Scott: Why would you not do that?
Rym: That's an easy one.
Rym: The other thing this is going to do for me personally is, you know, my day job is in capital markets, and daylight saving time.
Scott: You've got to set all your clocks, your favorite, your specialty.
Scott: Everyone's going to be looking to hire a Rym to get the clocks right.
Rym: So of all things, get this, I can't obviously share any details, but I am far, one, NTP, mostly obsolete.
Scott: Well, NTP isn't even a thing anymore.
Rym: I mean, it is, but it's not, like, I would use it at home because it's easy and it works, but it's not how...
Scott: There are newer, better things.
Rym: There are newer, better ways to do that.
Rym: That problem is way more solved.
Rym: But also, my job, I don't log into physical servers anymore.
Rym: Like, I'm not setting the clocks like I used to.
Rym: I'm not giving lectures on how to set clocks like I literally used to.
Rym: Today, literally, unrelatedly, someone messages me inside of the company and they're like, "Hey, we're having a problem.
Rym: We heard you could help us with
Rym: it.".
Rym: Long story short, it was about the nuances of all the different timestamps in the fix protocol related.
Rym: And it was basically, I was asked to fix a clock problem because even though I'm a senior product manager who, like, doesn't, like, I don't even see source code.
Rym: I don't have access to get, like, I'm not allowed to interact with that stuff.
Rym: Somehow, everybody knows, "Oh yeah, Rym, that's the clock guy.
Rym: He knows clocks.
Rym: He knows this shit.
Rym: Go bug
Rym: him.".
Scott: The fixed clock guy.
Scott: Oh, we have a fixed clock problem.
Scott: That's why they hired you, to do that.
Scott: That's what your job is.
Rym: It's just, it's the domino meme of Rym learns an archaic and obscure set of two unrelated protocols in 2003 at a job at IBM.
Rym: And now, to this day, he's the clock fixed guy forever.
Scott: Yeah, that's how it goes.
Rym: So, you have some news about our slightly better governor?
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, I was at the hockey game and it was Women's Empowerment Night, right?
Scott: Where they, you know, fake, you know, but it's still, you know, a fake corporate.
Scott: Oh, it's all performative.
Scott: Washing, yeah, performative, whatever.
Rym: Reputation laundering, performative nonsense.
Scott: Yes, but the governor was in attendance, the governor of New York, to drop the puck.
Rym: Who, you must remember, is not Governor Cuomo, who is a piece of shit.
Scott: Yeah, he did a bunch of pieces.
Scott: He made some piece of shit stuff going on today, but we're not going to talk about it.
Scott: Oh, no, fuck him.
Rym: We'll hope he just disappears from the limelight permanently.
Scott: He's trying to undisappear as of today.
Rym: But, because he basically was drum rolled out, the person who replaced him by procedure, Governor Hochul, not the best, pretty centrist, like, et cetera, right, but kind of a secret crypto progressive in that she has a way of saying very centrist things, but historically has done very progressive things.
Scott: Right, well, she's sort of like our mayor, where one minute the mayor will be like real progressive, and the next minute the mayor is like, let's bring, let's boost up the cops.
Rym: He's like, we're going to have bike lanes.
Rym: That's good.
Rym: And more cops.
Rym: That's bad.
Rym: The cops will be more diverse.
Rym: That's good.
Rym: The cops are still doing what the cops have always done.
Rym: That's bad.
Rym: The cops don't have guns.
Scott: We're going to cut money from the schools and the sanitation department, but not the cops.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the governor is a lot of the same thing, right?
Scott: We got one minute the governor will do something good.
Scott: The next minute the governor will do something bad, right?
Scott: So I was very, before I even sort of realized, because I wasn't paying that much attention, before I even realized that the governor was coming out to drop the puck, there were boos raining down from all over the garden.
Scott: Now, nobody quite knows why the boos are raining down.
Scott: Now, clearly some of the boos were from Republicans in attendance, right?
Scott: Even though New York is very progressive, I got to say that's probably like 30%.
Rym: No, two of the recent hockey games I've gone to, a Trumpy MAGA chant started in the...
Scott: No, that's one guy who's like in the section behind us.
Scott: He's usually doing it by himself.
Scott: He's just a loud, obnoxious dude.
Rym: No, there was a big one happening outside MSG a few weeks ago.
Scott: I think it's that one guy who tries to start it.
Rym: Luckily he has mixed levels of success, but not zero, which is the point.
Scott: The couple times he's done that, I've seen also people yell back at him.
Rym: I think I yelled back at him the last time we were at a game together.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But anyway, there are clearly people there who are just right-wing people at a hockey game.
Scott: There's also, you're at a sporting event, I think it's probably going to skew more right than left, even in New York.
Scott: More right than the society surrounding the sport.
Rym: Well, New York City is very progressive as an entity.
Scott: The heat outside Madison Square Garden is 70/30.
Scott: Inside the garden is going to probably be more like 60/40, because you've got people from Jersey, Connecticut, other people coming in.
Rym: But also it's expensive, so you're over-representing wealthier people and tech pros.
Scott: You're over-representing white people, because it's ice hockey.
Scott: And you're over-representing men, and you're over-representing people who are toxic masculinity, representing misogynist people who are like, "Ugh, sports!
Scott: Ugh!".
Scott: So, you know, those people were booing, for sure.
Scott: And I think that the other factor was that even people, they're progressive people at the garden, because it's New York.
Scott: And they're going to boo, too.
Rym: It's like our old mayor, de Blasio, he was way more on-paper progressive than our current mayor.
Rym: But at the same time, he was so ineffectual that he would be booed by, like, the cops would turn their backs on him because they'd say he hates cops, yet we would boo him because he didn't defund the cops and in fact was singing their praises.
Scott: I heard one person yell at the governor, "Go back
Scott: upstate.".
Scott: So that was clearly a city person, right?
Rym: One thing I should point out about Hochul, because a lot of people don't realize this, she's from western New York, which is an interesting place because the cities there, deeper blue than New York City, like, for real.
Scott: That's like labor union town.
Rym: But the areas around those cities, they're not the deepest red in the state, but they're like the third deepest red areas in the state.
Rym: But that area also has a lot of relatively pragmatic politics, more so than, like, the parts north of Albany that just go crazy.
Rym: So you get a weird situation where western New York, where she's from, she's very popular there because she toes a very centrist line, but has actually pushed a lot of progressive stuff through.
Scott: Anyway, so she was booed, mightily, in that one of the major issues that's going on, that's been going on in New York for a while, that we haven't talked about on the show, but I don't think really needs a whole episode, which might have related to the booing, is this bail reform issue.
Rym: If you're not from the US, in America, we have a really fucked up system where if you commit a crime, or you are accused of a crime, and you're gonna have a trial, the judge will decide if you stay in jail until your trial,
Scott: or if you're
Rym: allowed to leave and come back for your trial.
Scott: You're still presumed innocent, right?
Scott: You haven't gone to trial and been found guilty, so you're an innocent person, but there's a concern.
Scott: It's A, you were at least suspected enough of a crime that you were arrested, right?
Scott: And presumably some evidence that it was enough to arrest you and bring you to a court.
Rym: Presumably because of a news we'll talk about next Thursday.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So there's that.
Scott: And so now it's like, okay, well, if we let you go, because your trial isn't gonna be today, so we have two choices.
Scott: We can let you go, and it's like, are you gonna come back to your trial, or are you gonna run?
Scott: Even if you're innocent, you might run.
Scott: You have good reason to run, even if you're innocent.
Scott: And so there's that question.
Scott: That's question one.
Rym: That's also the question, are you likely a danger to yourself or others during this period?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So for example, there might be someone who is a mass shooter, a common occurrence in the United States, sadly.
Scott: And it's like, you see the cops, see the person mass shooting, and they arrest them somehow without killing them.
Scott: And it's like, okay, this person didn't have a trial yet, but it's like, there they are on video, mass shooting.
Scott: It's like, even if we know this person 100% will come back for their trial somehow, I don't know why.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, are you just gonna let this person walk around the street until their trial?
Scott: They're gonna mass shoot again, probably.
Scott: So it's in our interest and it's common sense.
Scott: But the way this system works is you put this person somewhere, do something such that this person is not free until the time of their trial.
Rym: But our system is really weird in that you basically, the judge will define an amount of money.
Rym: Sometimes they set no bail, but they set an amount of money, meaning you have to put this cash up and you get it back if you show up for your court date, giving you another incentive to show up other than if you don't show up for a court date, you're literally a fugitive and you're kind of fucked anyway.
Scott: And if you can't afford that amount of money, you have this private system of bail bondsmen who will, basically, they'll pay your bail, you pay them some of the bail, like a fee, like 10%.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They pay the bail.
Scott: And then when you show up to court, well, they get their money back.
Scott: But they've made a profit because you don't get your money back.
Scott: So it's like if Rym had a million dollar bail because he was evil and then Rym would pay the bail bondsman a hundred K and then the bail bondsman would pay a million to the court.
Scott: And then when Rym shows up to trial, the bail bondsman gets back their million so that all they got was a free hundred K.
Rym: But if I don't show up, the bail bondsman literally becomes a bounty hunter with no small support from the US legal system.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that bail bondsman is now Rym, that bail bondsman is like, well, I have to go get Rym and drag him to court to get a million dollars.
Scott: They're going to fucking do it.
Rym: Now, if you need to know how obviously unfair racist broken the system is, I'm sure like John Oliver has done a very long episode about it.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Scott: But yeah, it's all kinds of fucked up.
Scott: And the problem is, is that people in New York are making all of these either ignorant or bad faith arguments that somehow like rising crime is related to the fact that we reformed our bail system.
Scott: We made it slightly better.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A year or two ago.
Rym: What else could be causing rising crime?
Rym: Extreme depression caused by social isolation, a global pandemic, a war, a crushed economy, the failing of basic social services, the collapsing infrastructure.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But basically, we know why the crime is going up, but they're basically like, it's like, what the fuck does?
Scott: bail has nothing?
Scott: Even if there wasn't all those other things that we knew, even if what was making crime go up was a mystery.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And even if crime was actually going up a lot, which it isn't, it's inflated and it's going.
Rym: it's gone up and is going up.
Scott: But that's from those statistics are reported by cops themselves.
Rym: But also more to the point, technically going up is really misleading when you remember that it's going up from some of the lowest crime rates in like recorded history.
Scott: It's like, oh, the crime went down, you know, a thousand percent since ten years ago.
Rym: And then it doubled last year because there were two murders instead of one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like it's actually way low.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But really, bail is stupid.
Rym: A judge should just decide, is this person going to show up to court or not?
Rym: Are they dangerous or not?
Rym: That should be the sole decision that gets made.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It should either be yes or no.
Scott: There should be no bail whatsoever.
Scott: And there's people in New York basically blaming the, you know, thinking that because we got rid of bail, that somehow crime is a problem.
Scott: And it's like if if there really is a crime committed by some repeat offender that is out on the street, then why they shouldn't have been there.
Scott: What?
Scott: Why did the judge let them out?
Scott: Why should we let that person out on a bail?
Scott: It's like they'll commit, you know, it's like they shouldn't be.
Scott: any circumstance, no matter no amount of money that should allow them to go.
Rym: If Roberto comes back to prison a second time for a stabbing, you don't let him out until you have a trial.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like no period.
Scott: You can't go back out, not even for a million or 10 million or 100 million, guaranteeing that you'll come back.
Scott: It's like there should be no circumstance that you get out and then until your trial is done.
Scott: You know, B, it's like if there isn't a reason to if we're pretty sure you're going to come back and regardless of guilt or innocence.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All you did was like, I don't know, Rob.
Scott: You know, you're you're accused of, I don't know if I can rob in a convenience store.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You weren't even armed or anything.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like, is that person really?
Scott: it's like what they could do, rob another convenience store.
Rym: It's like if they do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Don't let him out a second time until they have their first.
Rym: Like human judges.
Rym: The point of a judge is to make someone was smoking weed.
Scott: It's someone was smoking, you know, not someone who was caught with a bunch of cocaine.
Scott: Were they hurting anybody?
Scott: You know, they were just smoking cocaine, sorting it.
Rym: What's the worst case scenario?
Rym: if we let them out?
Rym: They're going to do a bunch more cocaine before their court date.
Rym: Like, sure.
Rym: I mean, cocaine shouldn't even be illegal, but that's a separate situation.
Scott: Some guy had some meth and you arrested him.
Scott: It's like, why?
Scott: Why are we paying money to put that person in jail?
Scott: I should clarify, cocaine should not be cause money to lock that person up.
Scott: Why are we spending that money for no reason?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Anyway, so Hoekel did something.
Rym: We didn't actually talk about the news.
Scott: We just talked about bail.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So basically, you know, the governor basically sort of does things secretly.
Scott: We don't know what she's going to do until she does it.
Scott: She's a very backroom kind of dealer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But yeah, they're basically she's going the bad route on this one and is trying to support undoing some of the bail reforms.
Rym: Probably because bail reform is very popular in the cities and very unpopular.
Scott: There's this big, you know, message.
Scott: that's, you know, completely false of like, you know, scare mongering people about crime.
Scott: You open up a newspaper or a news TV thing.
Scott: It's just constantly crime and fear mongering, you know, all the time.
Scott: That's the only news story they report is like murder in your neighborhood.
Scott: Someone got mugged.
Scott: It's like, you know, don't go outside.
Scott: It's dangerous in a house.
Scott: Gave out.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know, it's more dangerous.
Rym: All the fires happening from our people.
Scott: I don't even know what.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: People don't even know what the fuck bail is or like, oh, they got rid of bail.
Scott: That means they're letting dangerous people roam around the street instead of keeping them locked up because of the bail reform.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like that.
Scott: None of that is true.
Scott: It's safer to let your kids walk around the street now than it probably was in the in the fifties when all this people who are currently scared walked around the street.
Rym: Also, when everyone was lead addled from leaded gasoline.
Rym: I'm terrified to decide.
Rym: I was saving this for Monday.
Rym: But just so remember, I always talked about that idea that lead poisoning was a primary cause of violence.
Scott: It's not an idea.
Scott: It's it's known.
Rym: So a recent study actually went way further and like proved it more thoroughly.
Rym: And the cutoff line for measurable effects is anyone born after 1981 is below the level on the cutoff.
Rym: We are we are according to that large study, we are just past the cutoff on no cognitive impairment from lead.
Scott: So basically any United States inhabitant from who was born prior to 1981.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, this isn't an insult to them, but it's like there was lead in the atmosphere.
Scott: I think they should be able to claim, right.
Scott: Increase your disability and get reparations from the auto industry.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, I got a real simple one.
Rym: This is a video or not.
Rym: Technically, it's a film reel that has been turned into a video from 1943, produced by the Signal Corps for the commanding general of the United States Army Ground Forces.
Rym: It was it was a restricted, classified video that, of course, is now just public domain.
Rym: And it is called Crack That Tank.
Rym: Might be a little on the nose considering the current global situation, but it's basically a training video aimed at U.S.
Rym: soldiers that tells them in 1943 exactly how, as infantry, to take out extremely advanced tanks of that era.
Scott: But there is that era with but with equipment of that era.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: We have better equipment now, but we also have better tanks.
Rym: What's interesting is anti-tank equipment advanced far more than tank equipment did.
Rym: But that's a topic for another show if you're curious.
Rym: Tanks always lose against anti-tanks in the modern world.
Rym: So the reason I'm making this my thing of the day is not just because of the Ukraine situation, but this video is interesting because when you watch it, a lot of training videos have this sort of training video sensibility.
Rym: They're almost like a little too bland.
Rym: They get a little boring.
Rym: This video is basically this army guy sitting down speaking in plain colloquial language to his audience.
Rym: Like, look, this tank's going to F you up.
Rym: So here's the ways to deal with it.
Rym: You got to make sure they can't see you.
Rym: How do you do that?
Rym: Do that.
Rym: It's very like it almost sounds like a mobster.
Scott: How not to be seen.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But military training materials in the US and around the world, but especially in the US are the ones I'm the most familiar with.
Rym: This is something a lot of people don't realize.
Rym: If you're making training material for anything, make it in the colloquial language of the people you're trying to train.
Rym: That includes potentially swearing or using folksy wisdom, like whatever would reach your audience.
Rym: Don't make vanilla, generic, like...
Scott: Everyone's just going to go to sleep if you do the formalized shit.
Rym: This one's more like you try to run away from the tank.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: It's going to get you.
Rym: You're better off standing your ground.
Rym: Here's why.
Rym: Do this.
Rym: Do that.
Rym: You can learn a lot from how the US trained soldiers during World War Two, when you're making...
Scott: And you get some of those annual required sexual harassment training videos to be good.
Rym: Right?
Rym: You just need to smart like someone, like the kind of person who would be giving a talk about that kind of topic at like a video game convention.
Rym: Just like, look, here's the deal.
Rym: Don't fucking do this.
Rym: Don't fucking do that.
Rym: Anyway, what do you got?
Scott: So I got this really short video.
Scott: It's actually a YouTube short, like from the YouTube short section.
Scott: I don't know where this dam is or what water it's holding back, but this person, Evan, because that's the YouTube channel, they were visiting a dam and, you know, dams have gates and you can open the gates to let the water through.
Scott: That's how a dam works, right?
Scott: Apparently this dam's gate had been closed for years and it was a kind of dam where on one side, obviously water, on the other side, the ground was very, very long way down.
Scott: Way down.
Scott: Because the water had been held back so long, right?
Scott: The riverbed or whatever, it was like a long ass way down.
Scott: And after all that time, like they opened the dam gate and they captured it on video.
Scott: And it's like, it's pretty amazing to see that water eventually come out of there.
Rym: This is my kind of thing.
Scott: Yeah, you don't see this very often and therefore it's worth seeing.
Rym: In the meta moment, gig nights, possibly just Rym, likely not Scott, maybe rimming someone else.
Rym: Atari game designed Thursday, April 21st, 7 p.m.
Rym: Bumblebee Theater.
Rym: This will be pretty much all new content.
Rym: I'll be playing Atari games live for the audience.
Rym: If Paxil let me, depending on the COVID protocols, I might take a volunteer from the audience to try some of these games.
Rym: We'll see what happens.
Rym: It'll be a fun time.
Rym: The book club book is The City We Became.
Rym: I think I'll be done with this book by the end of next week, considering that I'm going to be in London during COVID.
Rym: Spent a lot of time sitting in parks and sitting at outdoor pubs.
Scott: We'll give the listener maybe a few weeks after you come back.
Rym: Yeah, so I'd say first or second week of April, like whatever the next Thursday episode is that lines up, we're going to do the gig nights book club book episode on The City We Became.
Scott: Then I'll probably, I'll probably then select a book that I have already read because I've read many books recently.
Rym: This book is just fucking great.
Rym: It is so up the gig nights alley.
Rym: Every time you, I mean, the premise of the book, like cities or living things, every borough of New York kind of has its own avatar.
Rym: There's a bunch going on.
Rym: Every one of the borough's avatars that I have encountered so far in this book is just a chef kiss.
Rym: This book is so good.
Rym: Otherwise, catch our stuff slowly.
Rym: Content is appearing at conventions.
Rym: We'll see how things go.
Rym: Gig nights will keep doing its thing, but there will be no gig nights next week, except possibly I'm thinking about doing some live streams from London because I'm going to have a lot of downtime stuck in my hotel room.
Rym: So you might see a couple of live streams on the gig nights feed.
Rym: I'll talk about things Scott doesn't like to talk about.
Rym: Maybe I'll talk about time and fix.
Scott: Have fun.
Rym: I'll do some fixed training for you all.
Rym: That'll be fun.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I want to be very clear before we get into this main bit.
Rym: This topic, we mean no malign thoughts or intentions toward Ireland or the Irish people.
Rym: Our ire is solely and specifically at the manner in which the average American celebrates what we are about to discuss.
Rym: We are talking about St.
Rym: Patrick's Day or as we referred to it in gig nights in the old forum back in 2010, National Get Wasted Day.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, as someone who grew up as, you know, a Jew, a non-Irish Jew in the United States, St.
Scott: Patrick's Day was something I didn't know about at all until I was in like kindergarten or first grade.
Scott: And they had like, you know, some green bagels or some shit.
Scott: And they were like, you know, this party is something.
Rym: Meanwhile, me growing up in Detroit, surrounded by Irish people, partly because my dad was a fireman.
Rym: A lot of firefighters are Irish.
Rym: I spent a lot of time around Irish friends, Irish family, Irish parties, Irish funerals.
Rym: So I already had a pretty good idea of St.
Rym: Patrick's Day.
Rym: But when I was very young, it was my second favorite holiday for one and only one reason.
Rym: The color green.
Rym: Because in preschool, I do like the color green.
Rym: It was the day of wear green or people hit you.
Rym: Wear green.
Rym: And if someone's not wearing green, go get them.
Rym: You go to the preschool, the water tank with all the pump toys had green food coloring in it.
Rym: And it was basically just green day as far as I was concerned as a little kid.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: As a little kid, it was, you know, pretty much green stuff and shamrock day.
Scott: But also because it was called St.
Scott: Patrick's Day, I understood that like, yeah, that's a holiday we don't, we're not going to have anything to do with us Jews.
Rym: The other thing, I went to a private Catholic school for first through fourth grade.
Rym: So saints were a big deal.
Rym: And even though even then I was an atheist, I had to pretend to be Catholic or they would kick me out of the school.
Scott: I mean, even to this day, I don't, you know, it's like, yeah, I understand there's a saint named St.
Scott: Patrick.
Scott: I couldn't tell you which saint it was or what he did or why he's got a date.
Rym: That's which one he is.
Scott: I know there's a St.
Scott: Patrick's Cathedral in Manhattan.
Scott: It's the same saint, but not to St.
Scott: Patrick's.
Rym: But let's skip all that.
Rym: If you want to know the history of St.
Rym: Patrick's Day, read the Wikipedia article I linked to.
Rym: We're going to talk about how it gets celebrated in contemporary America, because poorly my perception of St.
Rym: Patrick's Day up until like high school was it's the green holiday and the adults have a bad day the day after.
Scott: Mine was it's a green holiday that I have nothing to do with and I don't care about it and I ignore it and whatever.
Scott: And maybe there'll be something on TV.
Scott: There's.
Scott: no we have.
Scott: no there's.
Rym: there was never any evidence that there's any Irish lineage in either like either side of my family.
Rym: So we didn't celebrate it per se.
Rym: Like, I wouldn't be like Irish.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I knew of, you know, there were some people in school who were like, you know, clearly Irish people.
Scott: But I don't think I didn't have that many, you know, I wasn't super close to many Irish people, you know, whatever.
Rym: I was close to a lot of Irish people when I was a kid for all those reasons.
Scott: I think I had Irish friend in middle school, but that was only in middle school.
Rym: The Simpsons really like crystallized some of my young thoughts around it being the drunken holiday because I didn't experience that part as much.
Rym: Mostly the adults would disappear, like parents would go out on a pub crawl or something and a babysitter would be there.
Rym: Parents are cranky the next day.
Scott: None of that for us.
Rym: But my perception of St.
Rym: Patrick's Day changed rapidly and suddenly around the year 2006.
Scott: 2000s.
Rym: 2000s.
Rym: When particularly when Scott and I moved to Beacon, New York.
Scott: And I remember at RIT there was still, you know.
Rym: At RIT it was a problem, but there were a lot of other similar days that happened.
Rym: Like St.
Rym: Patrick's Day was not the worst of it even.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Scott: Even at RIT it didn't, actually I think at RIT I sort of forgot when it was.
Scott: It's like I forgot it existed almost.
Rym: It's like, oh, all the frat guys are like passed out in their airsoft hot tubs.
Rym: What day is it?
Rym: It's not St.
Rym: Patrick's Day, it's just Tuesday.
Rym: But it was when we lived in Beacon, because I remember we moved into Beacon and that first year we were there.
Rym: I was woken up by a lot of noise outside.
Scott: There's probably GeekNights episodes where we talked about this as it was happening.
Rym: Oh, there are definitely GeekNights episodes because this was the thing.
Scott: Look for a March GeekNights episode from 2005, 6, 7, 8, 9.
Rym: So in the city of Beacon in upstate New York on St.
Rym: Patrick's Day there was a Beacon City tradition where a bunch of people would get together and do a pub crawl.
Rym: And that pub crawl basically was a, it was just a ruinous mob that would march through the city pissing everything.
Scott: We weren't even in the downtown main street area.
Scott: People would come all the way up the street.
Rym: Yeah, we lived on the edge, edge of town, like way, like right on the edge of the next town over.
Rym: But there was a bar, the Barking Frog, that was like actually at the edge of town.
Rym: And the pub crawl ended at that bar.
Rym: So every year, St.
Rym: Patrick's Day was a lot of cops and a lot of fistfights and a lot of screaming.
Rym: And then the next day just a sea of garbage, broken mailboxes and piss everywhere.
Rym: Like you think I'm exaggerating.
Rym: It was awful.
Rym: It was such a, like every year the whole city would be like, "We should ban it.
Rym: We can't ban
Rym: it.".
Rym: I think the city did ban it.
Rym: It happened anyway.
Rym: Like it was a problem.
Scott: It's very Santa Con-esque.
Scott: In addition to that, right, this was a time when I was taking the commuter train to the city.
Scott: So if St.
Scott: Patrick's Day was during the week, right, there would be a parade like there was today in the city.
Scott: And many, many college-aged people usually, but also other people would, you know, they're not going to drive.
Scott: They took the train into and out of the city, you know, specifically to get wasted.
Scott: And they would be unpleasantly on the train mixed in with the commuters, making everyone else's life miserable just with their presence and loudness and, you know, some occasional vomiting and loud noises.
Rym: When we were living in Beacon, once I got a job downtown, I would wake up at 4.40 in the fucking morning to get on the 5.24 a.m.
Rym: express train to Manhattan to be at work on time because I had to be at work at 7.
Rym: On the 5.24 a.m.
Rym: express on St.
Rym: Patrick's Day, there would be passed out in vomit people.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now, I don't begrudge anyone, you know, their partying and their celebrating of the thing they care about.
Rym: I mean, go to a bank fest.
Rym: You might find me, at least in non-COVID times, extremely drunk wandering around making a ruckus.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like it's the same thing.
Scott: Like, I don't really begrudge people their fart car.
Scott: The problem is, is that, you know, swing your fist until it hits another man's face.
Scott: Your partying has become so rowdy.
Scott: And so, you know, it is.
Scott: it is crossed over into the realms of, you know, vandalism and, you know, it's like harming other people.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: Now we got a problem.
Rym: I found a post.
Rym: So I posted this on in March of 2010, which was right after we'd moved to New York to the city proper from upstate.
Rym: I posted this in the GigKnives forum.
Rym: This is a memo that I wrote.
Rym: So this is what I thought was notable on that day.
Rym: Quote, I will be spending this day avoiding the drunken yelling idiots who are clogging the streets outside of work.
Rym: I will then lock myself indoors till the mayhem has ended.
Rym: I literally tripped over a passed out guy walking out of a Starbucks at eleven thirty.
Rym: He passed out and vomited all over himself just outside the door.
Rym: Nearby, the police were writing citations for underage drinking and open containers to a crowd of at least 20.
Rym: There was vomit everywhere.
Rym: Full disclosure, I worked right outside of Grand Central, which is basically ground zero for this shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, today.
Scott: So we have on our hockey ticket plan, one of the games that was canceled because the Islanders had too much covid was rescheduled to today.
Scott: So today there is a hockey game between the New York Rangers and New York Island.
Rym: That is already like brewing for a drunken fistfight.
Scott: We sold.
Scott: we sold the fuck out of those tickets.
Scott: There's like there was no way I was going there today.
Rym: That's like when two waves intersect and become twice as powerful for a brief moment.
Scott: You've got the existing rowdiness of just a Rangers, Islanders game on top of it.
Scott: St.
Scott: Patrick's Day.
Scott: It's like, no, thank you.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'll be watching that game from the safety of my own home.
Rym: Thank you very much.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: But it's interesting how this this phenomenon of St.
Rym: Patrick's Day just being a goddamn disaster is mostly confined to large cities.
Rym: Also college towns.
Rym: Yeah, but college towns tend to have this happen on a frequent basis to where St.
Rym: Patrick's Day, in my experience in college towns, doesn't really get worse than whenever there's a big kind of party.
Scott: I wonder if it's really bad at like, you know, Notre Dame University.
Scott: I wonder.
Scott: The fighting Irish.
Scott: They're probably, you know, I don't know what their tradition is, but I can imagine they're going wild today.
Rym: But New York is really just a place where I have like pointedly avoided being out during St.
Rym: Patrick's Day and Santa Con.
Rym: Those are actually the only two things that cause other than covid now that caused me to avoid going into Manhattan because I'm afraid of running into trouble.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there are many, many holidays on the calendar celebrated by different people for different reasons.
Scott: And I celebrate some of those holidays and I don't celebrate most of them.
Scott: But St.
Scott: Patrick's Day is the only holiday that I anti celebrate the only one.
Scott: I can't think of a single other holiday where I'm like, you know, I don't know, unless white supremacists have holidays I don't know about.
Rym: Those aren't holidays.
Scott: Yeah, but, you know, St.
Scott: Patrick's Day is the only day where I'm like, get this shit the fuck out of here.
Rym: Like, have your drunken parties, but don't be vomiting actively on a 5 a.m.
Rym: train into Manhattan because you pregame too hard at 3 a.m Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: So I don't know.
Scott: if anyone else out there, you know, I don't have, you know, too much else to talk about a holiday that I don't just simply not celebrate, but I anti celebrate.
Rym: Also, we've gone kind of long because we skipped a bunch of episodes and I think we had a lot of pent up talking into the microphone.
Scott: Intentionally, that was intentional because it's Thursday.
Scott: But yeah, but if you have any St.
Scott: Patrick's Day anecdotes or experiences or memories of your own, why don't you come over to our communities and share them with the class?
Scott: Yeah, and I will link to maybe you're one of the drunken vomitors and you want to defend yourself.
Rym: I would love to hear your accounts of why you do what you do on that day.
Scott: Maybe you're a bartender who serves them.
Scott: Maybe you are just like us and you want to commiserate about hating drunken vomitors.
Rym: But I will link to...
Scott: Maybe you celebrate St.
Scott: Patrick's Day in a non-vomitous good way with some Irish soda bread and whatnot.
Scott: And you want to talk about that.
Scott: That's cool, too.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this particular episode of GeekNights on March 17th are... Heidi McNichol, Ellen Joyce, Lynn Kije, Dred Lilly, Tenebrae, and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Kristin Dodd, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, Help Computer, Kishaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Revue Medville, 34 Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Blore Young, Blore Young Station.
Rym: And several people who have contributed money to GeekNights that have chosen not to have me say their names out loud on the show.
Rym: So yeah, stay safe out there.
Rym: If any of you are in London and would like to get together next week, I will very likely be more than happy to meet you outdoors for a pint.
Rym: I'm not really going to go into a bar or anything.
Rym: Like, it is way too soon for that COVID-wise.
Rym: But the weather's going to be pretty nice, so I would gladly grab a pint with you.
Rym: I know a couple places that are open late that are right on the Timbs that are very much outdoor and pleasant, so let me know.
Rym: I know there's a lot of listeners out there in London, and I haven't been to London since before COVID, so maybe I'll see some of you.
Rym: But anyway, for tonight, I leave you with a very important song.
Scott: Everything's gonna be okay.
Rym: Bad stuff happens in the bathroom.
Rym: I'm just glad that it happens in a vacuum.
Rym: Can't let them see me with my pants down.
Scott: Coasters Magazine is gonna be my big chance now, but I'll be out of here in no time.
Rym: I'll be doing interviews and feeling just fine.
Rym: Today is gonna be a great day.
Scott: I'll do Coasters Magazine and blow everyone away.
Rym: Let's be clear.
Rym: I did absolutely nothing wrong.
Rym: I'm not to blame.
Rym: It's not my fault.
Rym: This is just to say.
Rym: If Jean had pooped like every day, this would have all just blown away.
Rym: But he'll be honest.
Rym: No one's gonna blame me.
Rym: I'll be doing just fine.
Rym: Today is gonna be a great day.
Rym: If Teddy can't unstick my bat, I'll find another way.
Rym: Hey, where's Bob?
Rym: I wanna tell him I can smell him from across the street.
Rym: Yeah, Linda, where is Bob?
Rym: I gotta do his hair for the big interview.
Scott: Interview?
Scott: What interview?
Scott: Bob's got a big magazine interview.
Scott: What, are they writing an article on guys with mustaches you wanna punch?
Scott: Zoom!
Scott: I say zoom now.
Rym: You like it.
Scott: Yeah, it's okay.
Rym: Bad stuff happens in the bathroom.
Scott: I did absolutely nothing wrong.
Rym: I'm not to blame.
Rym: It's not my fault.
Rym: This is just to say.
Rym: Coasters Magazine is gonna be my big chance.
Scott: Because I'll be out of here in no time.
Scott: No one's gonna blame me.
Rym: I'll be feeling just fine.
Rym: Today is gonna be a great day.
Scott: If Teddy can't unstick my bat, I'll find another way.
Rym: Bad stuff happens in the bathroom.
Scott: I did absolutely nothing wrong.
Rym: I'm not to blame.
Rym: It's not my fault.
Rym: This is just to say.
Rym: Coasters Magazine is gonna be my big chance.