Rym: It's Thursday, January 6th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We are talking about sports commentating, sportscasting, and possibly even shoutcasting.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yep, it's a weird feeling to know that there's a magfest happening that I'm not at, and I'm very glad I'm not there.
Rym: It started today.
Rym: It's like, kind of just kicking off right now-ish.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Have fun getting sick, magfest people.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I mean, I hope you don't.
Scott: That would be actually great.
Scott: But, you know, it's like if I see someone walking into a fire, it's like, wow, I sure hope they don't get horrible burns, but I expect them to get horrible burns and I can't stop them.
Scott: So that's how it is.
Scott: The end.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I hope people don't get sick.
Rym: I kind of just assume that like 20 to 40 percent of everyone who shows up there is going to get COVID, but we'll see.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: Have fun with that.
Rym: At least a much more safe to attend event is coming up very soon.
Rym: The old AGDQ.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Schedule's looking pretty good.
Scott: We got, you know, some cool kid Mega Man 2 going on.
Rym: Ooh.
Scott: You know, you got some, you got one of the best links in the past.
Rym: I did not even look at the schedule yet, actually.
Scott: One of the best link to the past.
Scott: You know, Japanese runners is going to be on there because that's the benefit of doing the digital one, right?
Scott: Suddenly you get runners from a wider area there instead of a geographic area.
Scott: You know, that person probably would never have been able to appear.
Scott: Ooh, Hitman.
Rym: I don't super enjoy Hitman games, but speed runs are real funny usually.
Scott: Speed runs of a lot of games that I don't like are real good.
Scott: You know, I don't like to play any of them Souls games, but I watch some Souls speed runs.
Rym: Yep, for sure.
Rym: Oh, they got Geoguessr again.
Rym: Okay, I'm excited about that.
Scott: Geoguessr's always good.
Scott: That's a new... The Tetris is back again also.
Scott: They got some fan favorites in there.
Rym: What?
Rym: The Sailor Moon R game?
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway, you can look at the schedule.
Rym: We'll talk about this more on a Tuesday, but AGDQ's coming.
Rym: I'm ready.
Rym: It starts on... What's the actual date?
Rym: It starts officially the 9th.
Scott: Two or three days the 9th.
Scott: So Sunday.
Scott: Three days.
Rym: This coming Sunday it starts.
Rym: Oops, I got right into the news.
Rym: If you... I hope you're aware of this, but it's the one-year anniversary of when in America the Republican Party, one of our political parties, staged a violent coup attempt, tried to murder the Vice President and the Speaker of the House.
Rym: A whole shitstorm went down, and on the anniversary of it, the President of the United States, Joe Biden, just gave a speech.
Rym: And I highly encourage you all watch it because it's not long.
Rym: It's only, like, 30 minutes long.
Rym: And that includes the preamble and Kamala Harris giving, like, a pre-speech.
Rym: Like, it's not a super long speech.
Rym: And for those of us who are super, super wired into politics, it might not seem like this speech is that big a deal.
Rym: Like, we know it was an insurrection.
Rym: The President saying it was for the first time doesn't, like, change anything.
Rym: But you gotta remember, most people in America, they don't actually pay attention to politics except around every two to four years during an election or when there's a big news about it.
Rym: And it's easy to underestimate the importance to regular, inattentive people.
Rym: When the President says out loud there was a violent coup attempt, like, for real, directly blames Trump for it.
Rym: It's a speech that is a big deal to the kind of people who we really need to pay attention and vote in the upcoming election.
Scott: I mean, it's nice to hear, you know, the elected people actually, you know, believing the same thing that we believe, right?
Scott: Which is, you know, that shit is not great.
Scott: So that's nice.
Scott: But I still don't, you know, it's like, okay, you agree with me, right, that we're in a desperate time.
Scott: That's actually nice to hear because you haven't said that before.
Scott: So A plus, right?
Scott: But if I'm in your position, you know, desperate time calls to the desperate measure.
Scott: Where's the desperate measure?
Scott: You're the President.
Scott: Have you taken a desperate measure?
Scott: I haven't seen one, right?
Scott: You know, my anxiety will not go away until you take a desperate measure or attempt to take a desperate measure.
Scott: At least attempt and fail at the desperate measure.
Scott: That would still reduce my anxiety.
Rym: To a degree, though, because actually studies have shown that previous failed, like, try a big thing, like an EO that immediately gets shut down, not only doesn't move the needle at all, but in many cases it builds antipathy and resistance to the President who fails.
Scott: You have to do it in such a way, right, where even if it doesn't succeed, it has a chance to partially succeed or at least causes the opposite side to have to spend energy and resources fighting it in order to make it fail and then you can tire them out by making them fight and, you know, basically That
Rym: is actually kind of what's going on because the thing that the President is doing is through the DOJ, the one place where the executive branch has a huge amount of power.
Rym: And Garland gave a speech, what, yesterday or two days ago and talked a lot about how the charges from January 6th that have happened so far and the prosecution that happened so far is typical of significant investigations where they bring very small charges first while they're gathering information for the coming big charges.
Scott: That's how our justice system works, yes, that's how it works.
Rym: But more importantly...
Scott: You know, you find someone who's, you know, because a lot of our justice system was built on fighting mafias, right, especially the FBI.
Rym: I mean, that's how they investigated Watergate.
Scott: Right, so a lot of our laws are struck and the way our law enforcement operates is around that same kind of ideas, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, find some henchmen, right, give the henchmen a cut them a deal if they spill the beans on the boss, right?
Scott: And then, even if the boss did all these loopholes, you get Al Capone on tax evasion or some shit, right?
Scott: So, that's still the playbook, mostly.
Scott: They have other playbooks, but that's still playbook number one as far as federal prosecutors go.
Scott: So, they're following that playbook.
Rym: Yeah, and the other thing you can do if independent of the real courts is the court of public spectacle.
Rym: Not public opinion, because a public opinion in America is sadly simple.
Rym: Like, you can literally look at metrics like gas prices go up, current president unpopular.
Rym: Like, Americans are just kind of particularly bad at this, but...
Scott: I mean, you know, population density directly correlates to who wins elections where.
Rym: Yup, but... So, with the January 6th committee, the House of the United States is the other entity that actually has a lot of power, and they're moving into, now, for basically the rest of this year, public hearings as opposed to private hearings.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So, that's actually a pretty big one, too.
Rym: But I do encourage all of you out there, if you don't pay attention to politics, watch this speech because it is a subtle change in tone, similar to when his earlier speeches around the COVID response shifted to addressing the anger at the unvaccinated and how justified it is.
Rym: It's a similar tone shift because, really, if you went to American high schools or middle schools, even, you learned that the primary power of the president in America is the bully pulpit.
Rym: You can go Google that and figure out what that means if you've never encountered that term before.
Scott: Not enough bullying going on.
Scott: Too much speaking softly, not enough big stick.
Rym: I'm trying to think of the last non-insane fascist president who actually used the bully pulpit strongly, and I think we're already going back to, like, FDR era.
Rym: Carter tried, but America hated him for no good reason.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: You got any news?
Scott: Do we have news?
Scott: Well, the reason we thought to do this show is because the legendary John Madden passed away at the age of 85, right?
Rym: Not a bad run.
Scott: I think everyone knows the name Madden because it's on the number one football game there is, but I don't know how many of our listeners are, A, old enough to have ever seen John Madden broadcast a football game, from the United States, or even if they are the age, did they ever watch fucking football?
Scott: There are plenty of nerds who are my age who could have seen John Madden, but were nerds and they didn't watch football, so they never saw him, right?
Scott: But I guess I don't want to talk too much about sport casting and ruin the main bit, but John Madden, for whatever else you want to see, there's a lot of things to say about him.
Scott: He was a very interesting character.
Scott: He had a lot of good and bad things going on in his life, but as far as his job of sport casting, he was basically legendary and revolutionary in that he did something that most sport casters even today don't do and before him didn't do very much either in that he was extremely knowledgeable about football, having been a football coach, right?
Scott: And so he knew everything that was going on, especially since the game was simpler then, right?
Scott: But it was still more complex and if you watched football and you weren't a football coach or player, you didn't know what the hell was going on, right?
Scott: And he didn't necessarily try to speak simply and try to dumb things down for the audience.
Rym: He kind of explained what the hell was going on in a way I could understand.
Scott: Right, but he wasn't thinking like, "Ah, people at home don't know what the hell's going on, so I can't talk in a complicated and use big fancy football words that they won't
Scott: understand.".
Scott: But rather than just lower the level of discourse, he actively attempted to elevate the viewer and teach you football, right?
Scott: He was the first one to use the telestrator, maybe period, but definitely the first one to use it a lot to draw on the screen.
Scott: Oh, he basically made the telestrator a thing.
Rym: I don't know if any sportscaster had used the telestrator in any significant degree before Madden started using it.
Scott: Well, it wasn't really useful for anything other than football, maybe hockey or soccer.
Scott: Something where it's not on a big field is not useful, right?
Scott: But what are you going to telestrate in baseball?
Scott: First or second?
Rym: Just keep circling the picture like, "This guy's going to throw the
Rym: ball.".
Scott: Tennis!
Scott: He hit the ball that way.
Scott: What are you going to draw on tennis?
Rym: In a replay on tennis, you could show, "Look, this person is running in this direction at this critical moment, and you see the...".
Scott: There are other visualizations that are better.
Scott: But regardless, John Madden did that.
Scott: He tried to elevate the audience's football knowledge actively, which is not done... I think Tony Romo is coming a little bit close.
Scott: The other thing that he did, which is something
Rym: that
Scott: you see from a lot of local radio broadcasters and like one team, like home broadcast teams, broadcasters, but you don't see this very
Rym: often at
Scott: all from national broadcasts, like almost ever, which is why people tend to love their local broadcasts and hate the national ones, is because even though he was neutral, he wasn't necessarily being a homer for one team or the other, even if the game was like a fucking blowout, John Madden just fucking loved football.
Scott: So he was excited.
Scott: He would nerd out about some football thing that someone did in the fourth quarter when they were losing by 20.
Scott: And he would be excited about football all the time.
Scott: He'd be like, "Oh, check out what they did on this play.
Scott: Oh, yeah, look at this.
Scott: Exciting.".
Scott: And that is sort of a contagious enthusiasm that you get from broadcasters who are also fans, but you don't get... If you watch NBC Sunday Night Football today, I don't know who's still doing those games.
Scott: I haven't watched them in a few years.
Scott: Collinsworth and whatever his name is, I forget.
Scott: It's like those guys were not excited about football.
Scott: It was a blowout.
Scott: They were like...
Rym: That's where his magic was.
Rym: It's not necessarily the specific things he did.
Rym: It's that his goal in doing all those things was not even necessarily directly to educate the viewer, because you could have a really educational, really terrible sportscast of a football game.
Rym: It's that his goal was to increase the capacity of the audience to enjoy whatever was happening in football.
Scott: Right, but also to make his own enjoyment of football to pass it on to you.
Scott: He's like, "I fucking love football, and I'm going to make you love football,
Scott: too.".
Scott: And that's really the GeekNights' thing.
Scott: Even if there is some nerdery that I don't give a fucking shit about, look at how many things of the day, how many newses are just like, "Here's a YouTube channel with somebody who's fucking incredible at this thing I don't give a shit
Scott: about.".
Scott: A lock-picking lawyer comes to mind.
Scott: "I'm never going to pick a lock in my goddamn
Scott: life.".
Scott: The dude is enthusiastic about lock-picking and educational, and so it's like I'm watching his videos and enjoying them, even though I'm never going to do that hobby in my whole life ever.
Scott: Maybe when I'm an old man, if I really finish every other hobby, I build every Gundam or something.
Rym: Including playing Pendragon.
Scott: Yeah, and playing every TTRPG, then I'll try to pick a lock or something, right?
Scott: But that's the John Madden thing.
Rym: John Madden, the first honorary GeekNights, spreading the joy of your hobby and nerding out about it and giving zero fucks about the people who didn't understand you.
Rym: Granted, he did a good job, and there's a reason he's a legend.
Rym: He appealed to such a wide audience.
Scott: Whatever other weird things there are to say about John Madden.
Scott: You know, he's always riding on a bus to go everywhere.
Scott: I can at least say this.
Rym: He is the rare person who is a public figure, lived a long time, and does not have a "controversies" main title on his Wikipedia page.
Rym: Not that he was uncontroversial, but he does not have a whole section dedicated to that.
Scott: I'll just end this news on one funny John Madden story that I happen to know.
Scott: I'm sure there are many, right?
Scott: As everyone knows, John Madden was afraid of flying, or he just used a bus to go everywhere.
Rym: There is an entire section on his Wikipedia about his aversion to flying.
Rym: It's long.
Scott: Yes, he used a bus to go everywhere, because he had to go to football games all over the country.
Scott: He had his own coach bus.
Scott: It took him everywhere.
Rym: There was a rule.
Scott: No shitting on the bus.
Rym: Oh, that's a rule in hockey, too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He didn't like it if someone took, even though he had a toilet on the bus, he didn't like it if someone took a shit in there, right?
Scott: I think there was a time where someone did shit in there, and actually he got extra mad, because they were like close to a hotel.
Scott: They could have held it, and they went in there anyway.
Scott: And the story is that he made a comment, something like, "I had to carry your shit all over two states," or whatever, something like that.
Scott: But the interesting story is someone was permitted to take a shit on the bus.
Scott: Do you know who took a shit on John Madden's bus with permission?
Rym: Ooh, that's a hard one.
Rym: The easy answer would be the bus driver, but I feel like that's too easy.
Rym: I don't know the story, actually.
Scott: There was one person specifically who was allowed to take a shit on John Madden's bus, and that person was Wayne Gretzky.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I would let Wayne Gretzky shit on a bus I was on, too.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Scott: That's real interesting.
Rym: That is real interesting.
Rym: So speaking of other sports news, it's a sports news day.
Rym: The Athletic is basically the best sports journalism out there in the English language.
Scott: So if you don't know the deal with The Athletic, because if you're not a sports nerd, you won't know what the hell that is, some years ago, somebody used the Silicon Valley business model, the same business model, the evil one, the exploitative one that Amazon and Uber use.
Scott: They got a bunch of VC investment money, and they went and spent all of it to basically hire all the best sports journalists away from all the newspapers and consolidate them into one journalistic outfit.
Scott: And they write really the highest quality sports journalism that there is.
Scott: And they're covering every team and every sport and most teams in most sports in most places, obscure stuff, giving you lots of detailed coverage, way better than you're going to get in a regular newspaper, because regular newspaper is just giving you the big stories.
Scott: There was a trade, there was a game, there was a big rumor, big drama happened.
Scott: The Athletic is like, "Hey, here's some analysis.
Scott: We're going to break down.
Scott: Here's all the analytics.
Scott: Which
Scott: one?".
Rym: Let's look at these five lines across these four hockey teams and do a big analysis infographic thing.
Scott: Even stuff that would never be too insider stuff for Sports Illustrated.
Scott: They're giving you even more in-depth stuff, because now these sports journalists have nothing to do but write articles constantly.
Scott: So they're just constantly researching, putting stuff out.
Scott: So if you are someone who's interested in even just a small area of sport, it suddenly actually becomes worth it to you to buy a subscription to The Athletic.
Scott: It's so inexpensive relative to what you get.
Scott: And you get access to the best sports journalism in the world for every sport in every place.
Rym: Now, of course, the problem with this is that they're not profitable.
Scott: You can't make money with quality.
Scott: No, they've never been profitable.
Scott: They spend so much money hiring all the sports journalists.
Scott: And then they only get money from these heavily discounted subscriptions, and they don't run ads, which is nice.
Scott: These are not ads that I can see.
Rym: I've been a professional product manager for over a decade, and guess what?
Rym: Quality does not make money anywhere on earth.
Scott: They've also got to pay all the tech people to keep the site up, and they've got to pay how many podcasts they're making.
Scott: They're paying audio engineers.
Scott: They've got so many people they're paying.
Scott: Labor has to be pretty much their biggest cost.
Rym: So the news is The New York Times is buying them for the paltry sum of $550 million.
Scott: Right, now usually you see your Silicon Valley places go for billions.
Scott: $550 billion isn't paltry relative to money, but relative to basically the best sports.
Rym: A journalistic M&A.
Rym: That's a small amount of money.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: usually you see other tech companies of the same business model going for way more, especially when they're this successful.
Scott: So it's like, all right.
Scott: It's like, well, what's The New York Times going to do?
Scott: Because The New York Times isn't going to run it on the Silicon Valley business model of get investors, try to get a monopoly by taking losses, right?
Scott: And then profit on item three after some question marks.
Scott: So what the hell is The New York Times going to do?
Scott: Are they going to merge it?
Scott: Are they going to make cuts until it's profitable?
Scott: Are they going to raise the subscription?
Scott: There's a few ways they could go.
Rym: professional, like.
Rym: in my professional opinion, the ways a company like this could go would be the best possible course would be to try to make it profitable, not by reducing its quality and cost, but by leveraging its quality to cross promote and cross monetize with all the other New York Times properties, integrate it more fully with The New York Times and use it to drive New York Times subscriptions.
Scott: I mean, if you think about it, I'm paying for the athletic.
Scott: If you, you know, you can basically, it's like what I pay for The New York Times?
Scott: No, it's not worth it.
Rym: I pay for WAPO.
Rym: Well, Washington Post.
Scott: I don't pay for either one.
Rym: WAPO is the best journalism I can pay for, honestly.
Scott: If you increased the price a very small amount and that included New York Times plus Crossword Puzzles plus athletic, then it suddenly sort of becomes worth it.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: You could squeeze out a few dollars from the extra, but not that many more dollars.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So I have to imagine they're going to try something like that because the Silicon Valley way of water it down, make it profitable, fully integrated, and then eventually destroy it.
Rym: There's no reason to buy a company like this.
Rym: And I don't think the athletic competes with The New York Times because like the athletic is for sports nerds.
Scott: The New York Times.
Scott: New York Times is not known for its sports section.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now, we'll see how this goes.
Rym: If I can get access to the athletic via a New York Times subscription in the future, I'll probably just pay for a New York Times subscription because then I also won't have to hit escape at the right moment between when I click on a New York Times link and the page pops up and then the monetization anti-ad blocker thing pops
Scott: up.
Scott: You should be introduced to this Firefox extension called No More Paywall, whatever it's called.
Rym: I click on New York Times links so rarely because I pay for Waypo and Waypo is fantastic.
Scott: Right, but this gets rid of all paywalls.
Scott: All of them.
Rym: And anyway, some other news that leads even more closely into our main bit today.
Rym: Wizards, this is basketball now, broadcaster.
Scott: Washington Wizards.
Rym: Said something that is highly plausible and likely.
Rym: This was an honest mistake.
Rym: But it so happens that what he said on the broadcast because two different people shared the same name and one of those people had a father who was involved in multiple gun-related incidents used the word, basically used the word trigger as part of a commentary in a game.
Rym: Quote, Kevin Porter
Rym: Jr.,
Rym: like his dad, pulled that trigger right at the right time when Kevin Porter basically made a buzzer beater.
Rym: And it was amazing.
Scott: Right, because there was a different Kevin Porter who was a basketball player.
Scott: And the commentator said, and if you believe, you know, good faith, whatever, that they thought that the other basketball player, Kevin Porter, was this Kevin Porter
Scott: Jr.'
Scott: 's father, which is not the case.
Scott: Kevin Porter, who scored this buzzer beater, their father was a Kevin Porter who had gun-related incidents and he just used the unfortunate wording of pulled the trigger.
Scott: If he'd used any other wording, it would have also been weird because it would have been like his father, you know, because he saw the father part in there.
Rym: But even weirder as a coincidence, the other Kevin Porter, the one who's not...
Scott: He was like, like his dad, you know, was clutch, right?
Scott: It didn't use the trigger wording.
Scott: It's like, what do you mean, his dad was clutch?
Rym: It was clearly a mistake.
Rym: But just to point out, that other Kevin Porter played the NBA in the 70s and 80s, so the timing was plausible, and he was drafted by the Baltimore Bullets.
Scott: Yeah, the Washington Wizards used to be the Washington Bullets.
Rym: And previously before that, the Baltimore Bullets.
Rym: Yep, that's correct.
Scott: And this is not the first gun-related incident on that team.
Scott: There was the infamous Gilbert Arenas gun in the locker room incident on the Washington Wizards, like in late 2000s, I think.
Rym: And you might think, if no one was shot, how bad was a gun in the locker room?
Rym: Read this story.
Rym: This is a weird gun.
Scott: If you don't know about the Gilbert Arenas gun in the locker room story, it's a famous one.
Rym: It is not just, "Oops, I had my gun with me.
Rym: Sorry about
Rym: that.".
Rym: It is way worse than that.
Scott: Why is it that the team that used to be called the Bullets has now had two gun-related incidents since changing its name to the Wizards?
Scott: I hope it's the last one.
Rym: Nominative determinism, I'm telling you.
Rym: But the reason we bring this news up, and we're not going to talk about it too deeply because it'll be covered in the main bit, is that sports commentating is an extremely difficult job, and there is an army of people behind the people who do professional, national-level sports commentary to ensure that the facts they say about the game, about other players, are correct, and mistakes, even relatively minor and excusable or understandable ones, get immediate, massive attention, even if they're not as extra as this one.
Rym: Saying the wrong thing as a sports commentator will be in the news for weeks afterward, in many cases.
Scott: Depends.
Rym: Yeah, it depends on the title.
Rym: It'll be in the local news.
Scott: Nowadays, it'll be in the news for a day.
Rym: Yeah, the local news, like the local team stuff, like in New York.
Rym: Like if Sam Rosen said it's really fucked up, we'd be talking about it for a few weeks at least, but off and on.
Rym: Depends on the level of the fuck up.
Rym: But, uh, think about that.
Rym: Someone played the same sport, had the same name, in the same time frame, and possibly even someone was like gathering stats, or maybe you're sitting there with all the screens with stats, and you eyeball it and don't double-check enough, you can easily just make a mistake like that.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, as you all know, I like mountain biking.
Rym: I used to mountain bike a lot.
Rym: I rarely mountain bike anymore, and I've largely given it up, because as much as I, you know, I like skiing.
Rym: Scott makes fun of me for skiing, but skiing's really not dangerous.
Rym: Mountain biking, I like mountain biking.
Rym: Mountain biking is dangerous as fuck.
Scott: Yeah, I don't do that.
Rym: There's a reason I don't mountain bike much anymore.
Scott: I mean, like, I would, you know, I'm not saying, like, I would ride a mountain bike on a mountain, but I would not do, like, the sort of downhill, narrow track going fast mountain biking.
Rym: Remember that one time in Poughkeepsie?
Scott: I would just bike up a mountain, like, weka, weka, weka.
Rym: Early in Poughkeepsie, you and I took our bikes on that mountain bike trail that one time in Red Oaks Mill together.
Scott: That was like trail ride.
Scott: Okay, I'll just bike in the woods.
Scott: Is there a hill in the woods?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You know, off-road biking, it's like, okay.
Rym: And that's fun, and honestly, that's the kind of mountain biking I prefer to do over the crazy stuff as I get older.
Rym: But anyway, one of the, there's two big things you need to know before I explain this video about mountain biking.
Rym: Is that one, if it's a serious mountain biking course, especially a technical one, a primary safety measure you're expected to take when you are doing that kind of mountain biking is to walk the trail once before you do it at speed.
Rym: Now, maybe you just walk it by riding slowly, but you do it real slow at least once to learn what's out there before you take it at speed.
Scott: Biking it slowly, you have to make sure that no one else is riding it quickly because they're narrow little tracks, right?
Scott: So if someone catches up to you when you're just sort of going real slow and careful, they'll just plow right into you.
Rym: Yeah, and there's all sorts of different trails and groups have different procedures, now they handle that.
Rym: But, you know, part of that is just know how the local trails are run and do what the locals do.
Rym: And don't do something weird and ask people what you should do if you're not sure.
Rym: You can apply that advice to almost anything in your life, to be honest.
Rym: But two, mountain biking trails have to be designed well.
Rym: So this is a video where the people riding did not do the walkthrough, which like I have often even not done the walkthrough, like not everyone does it every time.
Rym: They're obviously professionals who know what they're doing and they're wearing a significant degree of armor, so they're definitely taking safety seriously to a degree.
Rym: The trail has, what I would say, an egregious flaw.
Rym: Like, you want to talk about bad user experiences?
Scott: The worst possible.
Rym: So there is a segment after a high-speed downhill where there is clearly a technical jump, like there's a little wooden ramp that goes up in a jump.
Rym: So I as a mountain biker, who has mountain biked a lot and I'm honestly very good at it, when I watched this video, I was shocked by what happened over that trail or over that hill.
Scott: If you see a ramp that has a cutoff and is clearly a jump, you pick up speed and try to hit it and go straight, and then you trust that it was well designed that you're going to land on the other side, Evil Knievel style.
Rym: So you come up, so if you're watching this video, you come up over, you see the first person hits this jump and flies off like you'd expect them to with a very well executed jump.
Rym: The person behind them, wearing the GoPro, hits the same jump and it is immediately apparent that the first person is in deep shit and is falling off a cliff, the second person is now following them off the cliff, and like five mountain bikers follow all of them off the cliff, one after another, just one by one by one.
Scott: Thankfully it was not a very, you know, huge cliff.
Rym: Yeah, no one dies or gets seriously injured, but they do get hurt.
Rym: And they're mostly laughing and pissed on the ground afterward.
Rym: So you get to see what a mountain biking cliff bail looks like.
Rym: for one, and two, what's actually there over this ramp is an immediate hard left turn around back the way you came.
Scott: It's not a jump, it's a drop.
Scott: I guess they were intending you to just not jump, but go down and to the left.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So whoever designed this mountain biking trail, one, should be shot.
Rym: Two...
Scott: Sued, sued for sure.
Rym: That is the kind of mountain bike trail that warrants multiple warning signs leading up to that feature if they insist on having that feature there.
Rym: Granted, I would say it's unethical to even have that feature.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: Put a net out there.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: You can put a net.
Rym: I've bounced off of nets before.
Rym: That at least needs a net and a sign.
Scott: But you could just get rid of the jump, just make it a downhill slope.
Rym: Make it a bank turn around to the left like a normal mountain bike trail designer would do.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So yeah, that's my thing of the day.
Scott: Uh, oh, so, uh, Reddit board games, the subreddit board games is a place that I, one of the few subreddits I still subscribe to.
Scott: However, I can't recommend it.
Rym: Most of the comment content there- I do not subscribe to it anymore.
Scott: Most of the content there, the overwhelming majority of the content there is not, you know, even though it's about board games, it is about peop- I enjoy them and they enjoy the games in entirely different ways than I enjoy them.
Scott: Almost all the discussions are like about collecting, kickstarting, fancy miniatures, sleeving cards, right?
Scott: There's almost no talk about the actual rules of games, you know, how to win, strategies, uh, you know, even basic things that we talk about in our, in our panels and lectures and, and podcasts all the time.
Scott: Like any game with more than two players isn't a pure race, is a political game.
Scott: Like they don't, you know, basic facts like that are not established there, you know, so you get questions that just like fly in the face of, of fundamental truths.
Scott: And there's not a lot of good content there, but no, occasionally there is amazing content there.
Scott: And that happened, uh, you know, right on schedule, you know, once every couple of weeks or whatever.
Scott: Um, this person went and reboxed some of their games and specifically they reboxed some of their games that are just card games, right?
Scott: Cause you know, these days, and I guess it's been true for a long time, but if you make a card game and want to sell it in the game store, you can't just put a pack of cards and charge 20 bucks for it.
Scott: Who's going to pay 20 bucks for a pack of cards?
Rym: I mean, PC games used to be this way.
Scott: Go, go find a photo of a PC gaming store from the era when that was, that was to get more shelf space so people would see your game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But yeah, big cardboard box and inside the big cardboard box is a jewel case with a CD in it.
Scott: Um, but anyway, so this person reboxed their card games.
Scott: Uh, now for reboxing card games, you know, you could get, you know, card boxes, like, you know, what bicycle decks come in, assuming the cards are the right size.
Scott: Uh, that's not a bad option, but what do you do with the bicycle deck?
Scott: Maybe someone out there sells empty card boxes.
Scott: That's not a bad idea.
Rym: But then, you know, they're just going to be what white, I guess, or, and usually what people do is they get, they get big card boxes, like a magic type one, and they put a bunch of card games in the same box with dividers.
Scott: That's what I do, but that's not very portable.
Scott: because now it's like, you know, you want to, you go in there, you're going to get this big giant box, right?
Scott: It's heavy, full of a zillion card games.
Scott: You know, you want to take one game out, you got to find where it starts and ends, little separators, right?
Scott: Um, and also let's say you've got, you know, a big board game that has a deck of cards in it.
Scott: Well, you know, something like, uh, you know, oath has a lot of cards, right?
Scott: I guess oath comes with ways to store the cards, but not every game does.
Scott: So in those cases, you're using what rubber bands or you're getting the magic bondage, non-adhesive tape or something.
Scott: Um, this person, I guess, I don't know if they originated this idea, but they had the idea or got it from somewhere to use boxes from cassette tapes to put the cards in.
Scott: They're the exact right size.
Scott: As long as the deck isn't too big.
Scott: Uh, if the cards are too big, okay, find another solution.
Scott: Uh, if you got too many cards, just get more cassette boxes.
Scott: Um, they open nicely.
Scott: They protect the cards.
Scott: You don't have to worry about getting any tape or adhesive or any kind of rubber bands ruining your cards.
Scott: The cards are, you know, physically protected, right?
Scott: They're not going to like bang and dent in there.
Scott: Uh, so I guess less reason to sleeve them.
Scott: Also, you know that if someone's doing this, they're not sleeving cause the sleeves wouldn't fit in there.
Scott: Uh, and lastly, because it's just a cassette case, you can easily with your printer at home, if you have one of those print out using like a template, a piece of paper and insert it in there to get the box art onto the plastic, you know, onto a cassette paper, whatever it's called, right?
Rym: The only, the only danger to you is some games have cards that are too big to fit into a standard cassette case, but there are standard size.
Scott: cards will fit in there perfectly.
Rym: But you can get other kinds of cases for older formats of cassettes and professional formats.
Scott: Similarly, maybe you might be able to find one that matches up with the cards in a particular game.
Scott: But this makes me want to go and buy blank, you know, empty, just plastic cassette shells in bulk, and then find every game I've got that's got cards and do this to all of them to save space and also increase convenience.
Rym: I foresee one of the two of us buying like a bulk box of these and splitting them up.
Scott: Go buy like 50 of them.
Rym: I probably will.
Rym: I'm pretty into this cause I've been planning to rebox most of my games for some time, but mine won't look as nice as this person cause my printer isn't color.
Rym: Oh, you want to use my printer?
Rym: I have an office full color laser printer.
Scott: Oh, you paid for the color printer.
Rym: I have a full on for real.
Scott: Honestly, when this printer dies, I'm not buying another printer ever.
Rym: I use this printer just enough to where.
Rym: every time I use it, I think, God damn, I'm glad I own this thing.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, in the meta moment, the geek size book club book, which we're going to do an episode on probably in the first week of February is the tale of Genji.
Rym: It's not just a novel.
Scott: I'm getting real close to finishing, like way close.
Scott: I can see the end.
Rym: Yup, I think you sprinted past me.
Scott: I'm on chapter 40 something and there's only 50 something chapters, there's only like 54 chapters maybe.
Scott: I got maybe less than 10 chapters to go.
Rym: You're like 8 chapters, 8 or 9 chapters past me, I think.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Well, you better catch up.
Rym: Yeah, but chapters aren't that long.
Rym: I read a chapter pretty quick, usually.
Scott: Some of those chapters like in the late 30s were like mega chapters.
Rym: Ah, yeah.
Rym: There were a few chapters I remember like when he's conspiring to actually, like early on, the longest chapter I bumped into is when his wife dies and all that nonsense happens.
Rym: and like that one was longer than others.
Scott: There were a couple of mega chapters in the 30s somewhere.
Rym: Yup, passing that Sakaki branch back and forth forever.
Rym: Anyway, that was a while ago.
Rym: Anyway, it's not just a novel, it's the first novel.
Rym: We're gonna talk about it.
Scott: The first novel ever written by any human ever.
Scott: There were clearly writings by humans before this, but they weren't novels.
Scott: They were poems or other forms of literature that were not novels.
Rym: Yup, and it's both a novel where I'm learning a lot about a culture I didn't actually know that much about.
Rym: I had bare superficial knowledge of Heian era.
Scott: When I came up with the idea to make this the book club book years ago, it was because I had A) heard about it a lot and then B) went to a museum exhibit about it and was like, "Oh, I should read
Scott: this.".
Rym: Someone in the forum I want to say, or maybe it was on Twitter way back, replied when we announced the book, I think it was on Twitter, and said something like, "What, the thing from Final Fantasy
Rym: VI?".
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: Otherwise, we're not going to any cons anytime soon.
Rym: Our last panel from PAX Unplugged is on YouTubey as are tons of other panels.
Rym: And I'm working on a few panels that we might just do as panels for no con.
Rym: Just do them on YouTube.
Rym: I feel like that'll be fun.
Scott: Tonight's website is coming along very well.
Scott: We are making a lot of significant progress.
Scott: So, basically what my plan is, is that I have a long list of features I want to get in there, but I'm not going to hold off on getting all of them.
Scott: As soon as I have every feature that the current website has, and all the URLs work, and all the data is in there, and we have the ability to upload a new episode, which I guess counts as features the current website has.
Scott: So, as soon as it achieves parity, I'll just switch it over, and then because I've set it up in such a nice way, I put all this effort into the auto-deployment stuff, I can just continue to add features.
Scott: Whereas adding features to the current website is very difficult, because the stack is so old.
Scott: Once we launch the new website, I can start doing all sorts of fancy things.
Rym: About once every six months, I'll try to upload the show, and it'll fuck up in a weird way, and then it's a pain in the ass to deal with today.
Scott: So, it's going to be pretty nice.
Rym: Also, we can finally, you know what we've got to do?
Rym: We have to update the closer.
Rym: We have to re-record the closer.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: It still says, "Web designed by BrandoK," or, "Logos by BrandoK," "Web designed by Kat
Rym: Lee.".
Rym: It says a bunch of stuff that we've since changed.
Rym: We've got to update our accreditation.
Rym: We've got to say some different things.
Rym: We'll do that at some point.
Rym: We'll do that as part of the launch.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: I think that's the last thing in the old branding.
Rym: It's actually recorded.
Rym: At night.
Rym: It's true.
Rym: Yeah, it is true.
Rym: Also, I'm excited that we'll finally get away from the blue, because at this point, everything looks as our new style, but then if we link to our website, I know people come here and are like, "What is this 2001-looking website that I'm
Rym: on?".
Scott: It's also going to be mobile-friendly, and more accessible, and load faster, and I'm going to make the search better, and all that stuff, so you'll actually be able to search properly.
Scott: That's going to be super nice.
Rym: It's pretty exciting.
Rym: I'm just glad we're still doing this since, you know, coming out 2022.
Scott: Well, this is hopefully going to be the last ever GeekNights website.
Scott: I don't want to make it any more exciting.
Rym: Until Web 4.0.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: But right now, we're trying to revert back to Web 1.0, because Web 2.0 kind of sucks shit.
Rym: I guess Web 3.0 is the real danger.
Rym: That's all NFTs, and there's only eight websites, but I digress.
Rym: Let's get into the main bit.
Rym: Sports commentators are honestly, like, it's funny, when we thought about doing this show, I was thinking back, like, preparing for this show.
Rym: And it's really fascinating to me that, without even thinking, like, just, if I think about sports commentators, my brain says, "Yeah, like Mickey
Rym: Redman.".
Rym: Because I grew up in Detroit, and Mickey Redman has been the color commentator for the Detroit Red Wings for my entire life.
Rym: Like, Mickey Redman is just an institution that will never go away, and I just looked up, he is still doing home games and even some away games to this day.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's a job you can keep doing, and people at home want you to keep doing it.
Rym: Yeah, well, because he gets a comfortable patter, which means we got to step back and say, "What are we...".
Scott: If you have a team that you're following, you hear this person, and suddenly there's a national game, and you hear this other voice, you're like, "Hey, you're upset,
Scott: right?".
Rym: What was the one NHL game, the Rangers game, where the in-stadium person was different one day, and everyone's like, "Whoa, that's
Rym: weird.".
Scott: Oh, the PA announcer, yeah.
Scott: I mean, you know, my family constantly, my whole life, whenever, you know, any holiday gathering or any non-holiday gathering for watching sporting events or whatever, who was casting what was always, you know, a topic, who was on the radio, right, for the drive home, and you had opinions of, "That guy's good, that guy sucks," right?
Scott: It's like, we don't like that, "Ah, damn it, why's it gotta be this
Scott: guy?".
Rym: We got Sam Rosen, John Giannone, Joe Micheletti.
Scott: Right, but it's like you watch, you know, some, even if you go into, you know, sports communities on the internet, you'll always see people be upset of like, "Oh, this announcer's on,
Scott: right?".
Scott: It's like a thing.
Rym: So why is that?
Rym: We gotta back up a little bit, 'cause sports commentary, like, what it came from, the reason it exists, is a big part of why it is the way it is today.
Scott: Well, I know a little bit about the history, so I believe that the first sports, like, live sportscasts ever, I think, I could be wrong about this, were boxing in the UK, like boxing matches.
Rym: I wanna say you're correct based on a cursory amount of research I did.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it was boxing matches in the UK somewhere that were on the radio, and then I think the first televised sports, if I'm not mistaken, were college, maybe college football in the US, I think?
Rym: But the first part you said is the more important part.
Rym: It existed, it wasn't like we got sports on live TV or in arenas or stadiums and people said, "Oh, we need someone to explain what's going
Rym: on.".
Rym: If you're somehow a nerd who's never been to a sports game, those people talking are not talking inside of the arena.
Rym: Like, you can't hear them if you're just sitting in the bleachers of a baseball game.
Rym: But, I remember being surprised by that when I went to my first hockey game as a kid.
Rym: I was like, "Where's, what's going on?
Rym: Where's Mickey Redman?
Rym: How do I know what's going
Rym: on?".
Scott: Some people go to sporting events and bring a radio and wear headphones and hear the radio guy.
Scott: We did that at Tiger's Games.
Rym: Every kid had a little headset and their little box score thing and were listening to the commentary in the bleacher seats.
Scott: When I went to the US Open, even for the first time last year, you could buy a little radio thing, or I think there may be an app.
Scott: I think it was updated for the 20th century in some manner.
Scott: Yeah, but you would be able to, you know, you could pay and get a thing at this booth and then be able to hear commentary, announcements, news of some kind.
Scott: I didn't pay for it.
Rym: But, that's also why, like, hockey is the sport I like the most.
Rym: So, my whole life, I know all the ref's signals because in the arena, you'll know right away, "Oh, he got called for
Rym: hooking.".
Rym: You don't have to wait for the ref to come and explain what happened.
Rym: But, where did this all come from?
Rym: The reason it exists is because radio was the first, like, real way you could broadcast a sporting event other than tele-tape for, like, horse races prior.
Rym: So, as a result, radio was the way.
Rym: You had to somehow come up with a way to convey to someone who can only hear sounds from you what is happening in a relatively complex sport in a way to where you understand it and appreciate it and are excited by it.
Scott: That's really fucking hard to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's this thing happening live in real time and you're watching it and you have to describe it, right?
Scott: It's easy to make, like, a radio drama where you can write it and prepare and get sound effects, but it's like you're watching something live and you have to describe the events that are happening right before your eyes, right?
Scott: In a correct way so that the listener can draw a picture of what is happening in their mind as if they were at the stadium, right, enjoying the event directly.
Rym: And to really underlie how hard this is, when I was a kid, I went to some Red Wings, like, pre-season event long ago because I really wanted autographs because I thought I could make money off of them.
Rym: That's all I cared about in that regard.
Rym: But also I wanted to meet the goalie and a couple other things, like, it was fun.
Rym: But they had a fun little, like, exhibit set up where first they would play the audio commentary from, like, a historic Red Wings game and you were supposed to, like, take a quiz on what happened based on the commentary, like, not down, like, what happened, what happened, like, draw a little thing and, like, fill out this little worksheet and then they would show it to you and you could see how right or wrong you are.
Rym: And I was pretty right.
Rym: Like, I didn't, I got wrong, like, which side of the puck the ice was on, but I was never wrong about which zone it was in or who had it or, like, roughly what went down.
Scott: Yeah, the way you would know which side of the ice was on from radio only is, like...
Rym: If you know, like, the left wing versus right wing...
Scott: If you know which player plays the left and they told you that that player was in deep, well, now you know they're in deep on the left.
Scott: But if you don't know that that player plays on the left, well, then it could be either side.
Rym: But if you listen to the radio, that's not as important as knowing, you know, the things I got perfectly accurately.
Rym: Who's, like, on offense right now?
Rym: Who's got the puck?
Rym: Is there a shooting attempt?
Rym: Like, what's going on?
Rym: Like, are they in the zone?
Rym: Like, that was important.
Rym: But then the second part of the exhibit was they would play a short clip and it was for kids.
Rym: and there's a little microphone and there's an audience of people waiting in line watching you fuck this up and you had to do a live commentary of, like, a minute of hockey.
Rym: And I failed utterly to convey basically anything.
Rym: And I love this shit out of hockey.
Rym: I know the rules, like, to a weird degree even as a kid.
Rym: And yet I could not for the life of me give meaningful commentary live on a hockey game I was watching.
Scott: No, you have to know all the players.
Scott: You have to go real fast, right?
Scott: You have to be able to, any action that someone takes, you need a very brief way to accurately describe what that action was.
Scott: You need to have the right level of excitement, you know, that matches the flow of the game.
Scott: There's so much going on.
Rym: So this evolved as a profession and it's definitely a mix of science and art.
Rym: There's an art to it and a science to it.
Rym: And as the science came in, you saw it sort of separate into different roles.
Rym: Multiple commentators, armies of support staff providing information, screens and notes, telecastrators, not telecasters, telestrators, all these different things.
Rym: So, you know, you might hear of, there's the play-by-play commentator and the color commentator splitting up the roles.
Scott: The color commentary is much, you know, I don't want to like downplay the importance or skill of color commentators.
Scott: It's way easier.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They are extremely important, talented, knowledgeable, right?
Scott: I can't do that job either, but it is an easier job than play-by-play commentary.
Rym: Basically give color like the play-by-play commentator says, I don't know.
Scott: It's usually during breaks in the action, right?
Scott: Because when this action, the play-by-play person has to describe everything that's happening.
Scott: As soon as play stops, that person needs to catch your breath and you don't want dead air time.
Scott: So the color commentator is basically someone for them to converse with, right, about what happened, like, ah, on that play.
Scott: You know, let's say someone just gets a penalty, right.
Scott: You know, and it's like, ah, that was a real bad penalty to take because such, you know, you start, that's where you can fill in, you know, with your John Madden type.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, explain what just the hell just happened.
Scott: Nothing's going on right now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, you know, you do a little back and forth, whatnot.
Scott: And also the color commentator often is actually much more knowledgeable about the game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The play-by-play person, you know, obviously still has to know a shit ton, but they don't have to know, like, you know, people's like stats and stuff.
Rym: But also they can focus kind of like how in hockey you have refs and linesmen because the linesmen are paying attention to one specific, very important thing.
Rym: Now, the play-by-play commentator can focus on that very important role and not have to worry about any of that other stuff, regardless of if they know it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And the, the color commentator also serves to look at the, what players are doing often like away from the action.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, it's like the, the play-by-play person has to really focus on like one part of the game where the most important thing is happening that the viewer needs to know about and hear.
Rym: Um, and the color commentator can look.
Rym: Panarin's got the Pockys in deep, uh, passing to, to Crider.
Scott: The color commentator can see and talk about things that are happening away from the play.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Oh, did you see what's going on over on the bench?
Scott: I noticed this other thing, right?
Scott: They give you this depth into specific areas rather than having to constantly pay attention to what's happening at this moment.
Scott: They could, right.
Rym: And also the, the, the banter, the bouncing back and forth.
Scott: Another set of eyes on the field.
Rym: That banter and back and forth part is extremely important too.
Rym: Much like, you know, Scott and I are doing this show way harder if it's just one of us doing a panel twice as hard to do a panel by myself, uh, than with, instead of having Scott with me to bounce off of.
Rym: And then there's a bunch of other roles.
Rym: We're not going to like get, you can just read a Wikipedia article if you care about the details.
Scott: Just to go back to the history aspect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it definitely started with radio and then went to, right.
Scott: But when television came, it's like, you might think it's like, well, you're seeing the game now.
Rym: Well, so when television came, you remember we were watching, like I was watching hockey on a 13 inch black and white TV.
Rym: There's a reason the home jersey and the away jerseys were dark and light.
Rym: And they used to be flipped actually back then.
Rym: And the refs were black and white because you couldn't see shit.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So they kept the commentators for television, you know, for a variety of reasons, just, I mean, like you don't even really need, you know, it's like, it wasn't some genius idea someone had.
Scott: It's just like this common sense thing.
Scott: If you were, if you try muting a sporting event and watching it, it's kind of like eerie and weird.
Scott: And even with an HDTV and amazing cameras, like you can't necessarily follow everything that's going on.
Rym: And especially you're not getting that color commentary.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, you're not, you know, can you read the names of the players backs if you don't know them?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I know players, but even I'll like flub a number or forget, or can't quite seize the number because someone's standing in a weird way or like is under a pile of people like who got hit.
Rym: Can't quite tell color.
Scott: If you're watching a football game and it's like, you know, okay, so you could, you, if you turn on mute, it's like you see the ref through a yellow flag and you're not using closed captions either.
Scott: So they throw the yellow flag.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: There must've been a penalty.
Scott: What penalty was it?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you couldn't really see all the action.
Scott: You got a TiVo, what are you going to do?
Scott: Rewind and watch it.
Scott: It's like, you know, try to find the penalty yourself.
Scott: The game is still going on meanwhile.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, but the person, the caster can be like, ah, that was a holding penalty.
Scott: I saw so-and-so do it because they're at the game.
Scott: They can see.
Scott: if you're at the game, then you don't need the commentating as much, even though you could have it with the, like I said, with the radio, but if you're at the game, now you can see with enough resolution.
Scott: And you know, you get your PA announcer, you got your scoreboards, right?
Rym: Also, sometimes you get the players yelling at each other.
Rym: I can look at the bench and see what's going on with the bench if I care.
Scott: But not only were the early televisions, like Rym said, so low graph, so weak graphically so that you still needed commentary to know what the hell was going on.
Scott: But also it was a long time before they invented like those onscreen overlay things to show you the score.
Rym: And even after they did invent, they did have the score pretty early, way earlier than you're applying.
Scott: No, but even when they had them, like, for example, I remember watching football in the eighties and it's like, yes, they had onscreen graphics, but those onscreen graphics, like during while play was happening was literally just the clock only.
Scott: And the clock was actually another camera that was aimed at the clock.
Rym: I remember that era, right?
Scott: And the scores would come up on the screen, like before and after commercial breaks, they didn't have the score pill, like always there all the time with updating graphics.
Scott: You know, you know, now they have so many more great.
Scott: They invent, you know, they have a whole NFL games.
Scott: They have a whole truck of people just for the yellow line.
Scott: That's the whole job.
Scott: Several people just put in the yellow first down line on the screen for everybody.
Scott: That's all they do.
Scott: It takes like six people, humans.
Rym: But another thing this does, there's two things that this did in the end is the fact that this stayed with TV, like technology forced the commentary to be there, but then the commentary sort of grew into becoming an integral part of the game.
Rym: So now we had basically accessibility by accident in that the TV broadcast is literally like accessible to a blind person because it's the same commentary you'd get on the radio.
Scott: It's not exactly the same as the radio.
Scott: Radio commentary is different from TV commentary.
Rym: Nowadays it did diverge in that radio commentary is primarily just the play by play.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Radio commentary doesn't usually have a color person.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, also it's, you know, it's nonstop.
Scott: It's much more descriptive because they know you can't see anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The TV commentary is a little bit more relaxed.
Scott: Um, but, but it also knows some people, there are some people out there who still will like, you know, you watch the video and then turn on the radio.
Scott: And do you know, uh, use some sort of offset to make sure that they sync up because they won't sync up.
Scott: The radio is always going to be ahead of the television.
Rym: But the other thing it did is the primary purpose of this today is to increase the enjoyment of the, of the people watching.
Rym: that is, you know, the design of sports played professionally is that they're designed.
Scott: So the spectator will enjoy themselves and conveying to the spectator, all the information that is not communicated by some other means.
Scott: I mean, if you ever watch the radio is all the information.
Scott: And in the case of TV is everything you can't see.
Rym: If you don't believe this, go watch a sporting event that is not in a language you understand and listen to the commentary with like, close your eyes.
Rym: Just listen to the commentary.
Rym: You can tell when they're about to score a goal, like.
Rym: you can feel the tension rising due to the skill of the commentators.
Scott: You might not know which team or you might not know exactly what's happening because you don't understand the language.
Scott: And I guess, you know, you could, I guess, like, you, you know, even if you wanted to replay, if you want it to only have that audio for the feeling part and not for the information part.
Scott: So you put a bunch of cameras in the crowd, uh, mics in the crowd for that purpose.
Scott: It's like, well, first of all, you know, eh, you got to know which crowd is home and away.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And also, you know, some nights it's like, you know, the crowd isn't there or the crowd isn't into it.
Rym: during the last court, the previous lockdowns where the NHL was playing in empty arenas before they piped in fake crowd noise.
Rym: One, the players were unnerved by how quiet it was.
Rym: And two, watching it at home.
Rym: It was weird, like super weird.
Scott: And it could be, you know, it's, it's hard.
Scott: It, I guess it might be impossible to say for sure that it's weird because we've only, we've, you know, not experienced that.
Rym: I think it's partly because sports, spectating sports is prime is more, I think more people enjoy it for the communal aspect than watching sports by themselves solely and specifically because they care about the sport.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I would say that I have an one, one piece of evidence to submit suggesting that, no, it's not because we're used to it.
Scott: And that's why it's weird.
Scott: Is that laugh tracks, right?
Scott: Laugh tracks.
Scott: I got used to, and now they're weird.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because I noticed them.
Scott: So, but this is the thing where it's like, I'm used to a commentator and crowd noise.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I'm still used to them.
Scott: Even after I recognize their existence, where I recognize the existence of the laugh track and it's unnaturalness makes it now awful.
Scott: But they also never became awful.
Rym: Even though I recognize, I think of the crowd, like a Greek chorus, they are one of the commentators because you'll be watching a game.
Rym: Commentators are doing their thing back and forth and say, there's a bad call by a ref in the middle of play.
Rym: You'll hear the crowd reacting to it.
Rym: You'll hear like this chorus of boos or like the disgruntled crowd getting less and less gruntled.
Rym: Like that'll happen.
Rym: And then usually by that point, one of the commentators would be like, oh, the refs in the crowd are starting to respond to that hook.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, I guess the, uh, the last thing is, you know, the, in, in this necessity for the sportscaster, right?
Scott: The sportscasting has like this next level to where it actually becomes an art and a part of the game itself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, there's so many like famous calls, right?
Scott: It's like when a big sporting thing happened, of course the thing that happened was a big deal, but it, the thing the sportscaster said when it happened also it becomes part of the event, right?
Scott: It's like, so Ali knocks out Frazier in its own as a legendary sporting event.
Rym: I can hear in my head, like to this day, the call when the red wings won the Stanley cup, when they got the goal, like the, just the words and like the way he said it and the crowd going nuts, like it becomes part of history.
Scott: But, but Howard Cosell going down goes Frazier, right?
Scott: It's like, that's like, that is right.
Scott: It's part of the, you know, it's inseparable from the thing that happened, right?
Scott: The same thing.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, uh, and you know, being able to say the legendary, you know, seeing a legendary thing happened before you and immediately saying a legendary description of it, that will remain, that will basically becomes a part of history with the thing that happened.
Rym: Case in point, case in point.
Rym: Oh, the humanity.
Rym: You all know exactly what I'm talking about.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Oh, the humanity, right?
Scott: A commentary of not a sport, but still, uh, you know, same deal.
Scott: So I have a lot of respect for sportscasting.
Scott: It's real important.
Scott: Uh, you know, sports fans, especially people who are, you know, not just getting drunk, watching sports, but actually paying attention to the sports, uh, pay attention to it a lot.
Scott: And you know, I think that in the nerd realms, right?
Rym: Well, look at e-sports, a big part of the rise in e-sports was the professionalization of e-sports commentators.
Rym: And they're, they're doing what we said they should do.
Rym: They're all modeling themselves on traditional sports, but they're changing things where it makes sense.
Rym: They're pushing the boundaries.
Rym: And I think you're going to, you're starting to see sports commentators pulling in some of the techniques that the prominent e-sports people are doing again, where they make sense.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, yeah, it's, you know, there's a lot of nerdy things, not just e-sports, but also like, you know, board games, especially with the ability to broadcast anything, even small time things, right?
Scott: You know, your local magic tournament is getting a broadcast.
Scott: It's like, you know, so if you're broadcasted, uh, you know, we did, we, we started doing this kind of stuff with net runner.
Scott: We had commentaries.
Rym: How fun would that be?
Rym: If I, I think we could both, honestly, we could learn to be very good tabletop game, play by play and color.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You got, you know, this chess commentary going on nowadays, right?
Rym: There's always been chess commentary.
Scott: There has been, but now it's getting bigger.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, because all the, any, any sport that ends up on Twitch, you got to have commentary.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: So, uh, you know, it's a field that's, you know, still growing and it's going to be with us for a very long time.
Rym: And it's a career.
Rym: Like this is something like you, if you're young, like you listen to GeekNights and you're in high school.
Rym: One of the things that I'm most mad about in my childhood is that nobody told me about all the jobs I could totally have tried to get sports commentator.
Scott: Oh, my friend.
Scott: Oh, this was not one of the jobs actually that falls into that category.
Scott: I have friends who tried to become commentators and went to school for this.
Scott: They didn't succeed.
Scott: But you know, like I had a friend who was doing like a college hockey at the college down the street, but you can get degrees on the real radio, right?
Rym: Sports.
Rym: Commentation is its own specific field of study.
Rym: There's different majors, different aspects.
Rym: There's a lot of ways to approach it, but it's out there.
Rym: You can go to school for it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So and I think it's going to grow as a profession as these sports grows.
Scott: I think I get more things that need commentating than there are people with common skill.
Scott: You don't even have to commentating skill.
Scott: The commentating skill is more important than the sports knowledge.
Scott: If you this is why you'll see people who are, you know, like who work for like, you know, a TV network.
Scott: And that same person will be.
Scott: it's not that they obviously have to have a high level of knowledge to be able to do it in the first place.
Scott: But you'll see like the football commentator will also be commentating some baseball and some Olympics.
Scott: And so it's like, but like they'll be commentating like some biathlons, like what the fuck do they know about that?
Scott: Well, it's more important to have someone who knows how to commentate than it is to have someone who's expert on biathlon because you can pipe into their ear, biathlon info, and you can have some a color commentator who's next to them.
Rym: In fact, what you usually see the pattern I think is growing more and more is the play by play is a professional play by play person.
Rym: And the color commentator is a former professional who played the thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Often.
Rym: Or if it's not, it's either it's a former coach it's or it's someone who just has encyclopedic knowledge of that sport.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, yeah, I don't know.
Scott: There's not much else to say other than pay attention.
Scott: If you watch sports and you aren't paying attention to and respecting the commentating or poor commentating based on who you got.
Scott: Pay attention.
Scott: It's important.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the GeekNights Patreon Patrons for this sports commentary episode of GeekNights are... And a bunch of people who do not want me to say their Patreon screen names.
Rym: And now I leave you with something you really should have seen coming.
Rym: Rest in peace to a legend.
Scott: John Madden.
Scott: Football.