Scott: It's Wednesday November 2nd.
Scott: This is GeekNights with Rym and Scott mostly Scott.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah, so I Got to the train station this morning looked at my cell phone and it said one voicemail.
Scott: My cell phone really sucks at telling me when this voicemail doesn't make noise or anything.
Rym: Ah, I've told my phone to make a noise and it makes a noise.
Scott: I tried then I immediately looked to see how I could tell my phone to make a noise.
Scott: I couldn't find how to tell it to make a noise in a voicemail.
Scott: I don't think it can.
Scott: So the voicemails my dad.
Scott: so I check it and he says call me which is real informative.
Rym: yeah, I hate it when people do that because that always means either something bad happened and they didn't want to tell you in voicemail or They're just stupid and they're not informative enough in their voicemails.
Scott: It's the second one anyway.
Scott: So I go and I try to call him and he he doesn't turn his cell phone on or keep it on his person.
Scott: Great, so I got immediately dumped to his voicemail.
Rym: Did you leave a?
Rym: No, you should have no.
Scott: so Eventually later in the day.
Scott: He picked up the phone right and he's like, oh you call me now I'm like Supposed to know that it was a timely call, you know, what the hell he's like.
Scott: apparently He got locked out of the house And I have a key to his house and he would have wanted me to come open it.
Scott: Now just the other day, yeah I do distinctly recall.
Scott: now it made me realize that I would have had to go and Open the house because I expect them to come open this house if by some Terrible accident we lock ourselves out because I did notice that the other day we were talking about just this.
Rym: Yeah, and I said, what would you do if you locked yourself out?
Rym: And you said I just call my daddy and he'd come and open the door.
Scott: Yep But now I guess I have to do the same thing the other way.
Rym: Yeah, it's great that I don't have to do.
Scott: I should have said I didn't have a key to his house But no, I do.
Rym: Yeah, I do, but he probably knows you have it.
Scott: Well, he wasn't 100% sure you.
Scott: that's why he asked me if I had one But I wasn't gonna lie and I lie.
Rym: Yeah, so if you had accidentally answered your phone You would have been stuck driving to Connecticut instead of going to work.
Scott: No, it would have been last night.
Scott: The voicemail was last night.
Scott: Ah, I just didn't see it till this morning.
Rym: cuz the phone sucks How do you lock himself out?
Rym: what was your mom or your sister?
Scott: my mom isn't the stupid basket tour thing or me.
Scott: Maybe she got back already.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know the story with that your mom in those baskets But her birthday's next week.
Scott: So I said like go there.
Scott: I'll just take the train there after work.
Scott: All right, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, nothing interesting happened to me today Awesome.
Rym: Yeah, I sat at work.
Rym: I Didn't do a lot of work and then I came home.
Scott: Awesome Yeah, I did work.
Rym: I did work but it was a lot of like install a thing on a server.
Rym: So I'd state do the install do all the configs and then I wait for like 20 minutes while it firefight.
Rym: So anyway, there's actually a lot of fairly interesting big news today, oh really oh, yes, really really Oh, really?
Rym: Yeah, really?
Rym: So apparently the CIA is running gulags in Eastern Europe.
Scott: We knew that Yeah, but now the government knows that And now the government international knows it.
Rym: now the government admits that it knows it.
Scott: Well, if you admit you're doing bad.
Scott: doesn't that also kind of also mean we're gonna stop doing it.
Rym: I Don't think so.
Rym: That's not what I was led to believe by these Articles about.
Scott: it can't say you're doing something.
Scott: You know is bad.
Rym: Not only did they not stop doing it They refer to them as quote black sites Because that's not an evil name at all.
Rym: They don't call them anything like the puppy factory.
Scott: What do you what if I'm a company and and all of a sudden I come out and I say, yeah, we've got these death camps?
Scott: And then they say oh, I guess you you've come out and you're gonna stop death camping.
Scott: No, actually we're gonna keep them going.
Rym: Oh It isn't better.
Rym: the Washington Post Knows where all these camps are located.
Rym: They have chosen not to reveal this information to the public at the request of a senior US official Because the disclosure might quote disrupt counterterrorism efforts in those countries and elsewhere.
Scott: Well, we just know now not to read the Washington Post cuz they're a bunch of pussies.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, though, uh from all the rumor-mongering it seems like Most of them are in former Soviet territories and they're actually former gulags like really Old abandoned prisons and stuff.
Scott: How can you do something bad?
Scott: Usually you admit it and then you stop Keep doing it because they didn't really admit it.
Rym: It's other people found out and they don't know what to do about that.
Rym: You close them and you at the minimum you can't close them cuz.
Scott: uh at the minimum You say you closed them and you keep them open.
Rym: Come on You gotta at least look like you're trying because if they say they closed them, that's admitting that they had him.
Scott: They already admitted they had him or beyond that.
Rym: not really.
Rym: they just said don't talk about it.
Scott: Right then you don't you do?
Scott: you say they don't exist and you move them.
Rym: yeah, see the thing is the CIA will not acknowledge the details of its system and They acknowledge the existence of the system.
Rym: It's not really.
Rym: it's complicated and no one's really everyone's kind of just going.
Scott: But if they didn't acknowledge the existence of the system, how do we know?
Scott: It's not just some bullshit made up by the newspaper.
Rym: Uh Don't know.
Scott: Oh, that's great.
Rym: Oh Apparently they were.
Rym: well this may much have admitted it because apparently they were conceived in the couple months after September 11.
Rym: Oh fine, if they admitted it then everything I said before yeah, but they're oh, oh They're claiming that they aren't illegal and that they're part of the war on terror and that they need him.
Scott: I'm killing this guy.
Scott: It's all right.
Scott: It's part of the war on terror.
Scott: I thought he was a terrorist.
Rym: Britain got away with that dude.
Scott: The police will come here one morning and be like you killed your roommate of like his terrorist.
Rym: That might work.
Scott: it's kind of scary.
Rym: Yeah the fact that I'm more afraid of being shot or harassed by my own police department or my own government that I am of Actual terrorists.
Scott: and it's not even that I'm afraid that they'll get me because I do something terrorist like.
Rym: no It's just.
Rym: I'm afraid they'll just get me I'll be walking.
Scott: I'm afraid that they'll just you know, think of a terrorist randomly just by accident or whatever.
Scott: They know.
Scott: I'm not doing anything terrorist for real.
Rym: yeah, no not everything bad is happening in the u.s.
Rym: This time there's riots in multiple countries that most people don't know about.
Scott: I can't believe it didn't know that there were riots in Paris for like a week like a week and no There's no one burned.
Scott: I read Google News.
Rym: Yeah, Google News had a blurb at the bottom.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: I didn't even see it because I have a like European Union Google News section and this came and menacing.
Rym: youths have been Rioting in the poor areas of Paris.
Scott: see I wonder how big this ride is if it didn't get to the top of news.
Rym: In one night over 180 vehicles were torched.
Rym: a bunch of arrests riot police The city the city is generally in a state of panic at least the outer like poor boroughs of the city.
Scott: Wow, it's the Rodney King Ferris.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there been a couple bunch of deaths But nothing like no huge massacre or anything yet yet.
Rym: Well, it's still going on and no one knows how to deal with it.
Rym: some of the right-wingers in the government are calling for Various military groups to just kind of storm through the suburbs and subdue anyone on the street.
Scott: It's what you get for being racist Yeah, and what's the other word Zeno folks anaphobia?
Rym: Yeah, something like that little xenophobia.
Scott: Oh, we are these enough.
Rym: Oh, I mean France has the largest Muslim population of any Western nation yet They seem to be the one of the most racist about Muslims, well, you know Germany.
Scott: they had a ton of Jews there And they didn't like them because the Jews are doing good BAM Goodwin.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So where else was there rioting?
Rym: Ethiopia Ethiopia that wonderful paragon of civilization.
Scott: Ethiopia is pretty good compared to some other African countries like Rwanda.
Rym: Ethiopia was very nice until various things screwed it up.
Scott: It's still.
Scott: it's still okay.
Scott: it's okay, but what happened was at an election and this guy won the guy who was favored by Bush and such and favored by Blair and So all the people were like it was rigged.
Scott: It was rigged.
Rym: All right, was it rigged?
Scott: We don't know.
Scott: probably not great But anyway, what did the people do?
Scott: Unlike fat-ass Americans who sit around when it's obviously rigged and do nothing.
Scott: They rioted and they're still rioting and I Think whether it was rigged or not the guy who's in charge who won the election.
Scott: He put the opposition party in jail.
Rym: Oh See up until you said that I was thinking alright, so the people are rioting but it might not be rigged.
Rym: They might just not just be overreacting but damn Yeah, imagine if after the 2004 election Bush has been like, alright, Terry Dean jail.
Rym: Yeah Way to kill the momentum by getting a call on your cell phone and making me pause it.
Rym: Yeah You know, you could have just ignored the cell phone.
Rym: I don't want to but uh Why we were doing something?
Scott: cell phones more important than doing something because I didn't know who was calling.
Scott: Yeah, I did.
Rym: How could you've known?
Scott: my mom just called and then she called again.
Rym: How about when your mom called and you cut off the podcast?
Rym: They don't need to know that there were two phone calls in the interim.
Scott: Well now they do so.
Scott: now there won't be any deception by you Uh-huh, as to the number of phone calls there were Because I could really benefit from falsifying such a wonderful and useful information you do all the time.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, so, uh, yeah, Ethiopia.
Rym: Oh Wonderful, though.
Rym: There was some cool news.
Scott: apparently Denver, Colorado Legalized marijuana, did they actually pass a law that says so?
Rym: Passed a measure that makes it legal for residents over the age of 21 to possess up to an option or ounce of marijuana To possess.
Scott: Yeah, what about to sell?
Rym: They can sell less than an ounce so they can still get dealers, but they can't get people who just have some marijuana.
Rym: hmm and Oregon isn't.
Scott: if they doesn't someone just have to say hey your town law can't conflict with state law because it can conflict.
Rym: All this means that now it's only a violation of state and federal law.
Rym: So Denver told the state police that yeah, if the state police of Colorado want to enforce their stupid drug laws.
Rym: They're gonna have to send state troopers down here and do it themselves Because our cops aren't gonna.
Scott: but isn't it also?
Scott: but I mean if you're gonna do it that way Right, if you look at like look at a state like Connecticut, right?
Scott: Yeah, the town of Trumbull that I lived in doesn't have a law that says murders is illegal.
Scott: The state has a law that says murder.
Scott: is you know all the murder crap, right?
Scott: Yeah, so if you murder someone in, Connecticut It's a violation of state law.
Scott: It is indeed a violation of state law and state law only.
Scott: but the town cops arrest you because you broke a state law.
Scott: They don't have to send state troopers to get you.
Rym: the town cops don't have to though and they won't know.
Rym: Well, they don't have to and they won't know.
Rym: they don't Really?
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: Yeah, really?
Scott: Yeah, I did not know this.
Scott: I thought that pretty much, you know, it's like federalism federal law state law town law all above laws apply below.
Rym: Yeah, but apparently the town is gonna say screw you we did something.
Scott: but I mean is right town a beacon doesn't have a no marijuana law.
Rym: Yeah, what if it did?
Scott: Oh if it did you'd go to jail for breaking town law and breaking state law and then whatever.
Rym: but yeah No, they passed a law of saying specifically it is not illegal and specific.
Scott: But then but then doesn't that conflict with the state law?
Scott: yes, and this isn't the law illegal?
Rym: no, it's stupid.
Scott: Basically if your law in a town conflicts it does state law is.
Rym: it's a political move Because they believe that marijuana shouldn't be illegal.
Scott: Oh, that's a political move is fine.
Scott: But and the law is gonna be thrown out real soon.
Rym: Maybe maybe not.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: Maybe not.
Scott: if a state makes a law that directly conflicts of the federal law.
Scott: Yeah, it just goes away.
Rym: Not Always it has to get to a federal court first.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but I mean this will go to a state court.
Scott: What do you think's gonna win in the state court?
Scott: for they win the state involved?
Scott: It's their court.
Rym: Well, the state hasn't said they're gonna do anything at all.
Scott: Well, if the state lets it fly then that basically invalidates the state law.
Rym: I mean the most is it's not the state laws not enforced can do because you can't.
Rym: it's not against the law to not Enforce the law.
Scott: no, that's correct.
Rym: so the only thing the state can do is send state troopers in to go after people with an ounce of marijuana and Get them and that's fine.
Rym: But the local cops in Denver don't have to do jack anymore and they won't.
Rym: that's fine Yeah, so it's never gonna hit the courts because there's no chance for it to hit the courts.
Rym: It's not illegal for the local cops to not enforce a law that isn't on their books.
Scott: But some guy can just go make file some papers in court and then there'll be a thing about it.
Rym: You can't file in court unless there has been a damage to you.
Scott: Well, you can.
Scott: you can file suit against the.
Scott: the state can try to sue the town for what.
Rym: there has to be a damage And they have to prove for damaging the state's laws.
Rym: That's tricky.
Rym: You have to prove tort and it's not that easy.
Rym: People do this kind of crap all the time Yeah, and they usually get thrown out immediately.
Rym: if you don't have tort you can't even sue they just yeah But you know what?
Scott: There are lawyers who know what they're talking about who are smarter than us that are working on it right now Yeah, and you know what the town's probably gonna win because no one cares.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean if the state doesn't enforce it you can then you can argue in court They didn't enforce the law might as well not exist.
Rym: Yeah, that might be their goal.
Scott: We don't know I like that kind of thing but I Really don't think we should start a trend of town laws overriding state laws because you know next lot Nazi town You know what?
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Cuz I'll just move on a Nazi town and the Nazi people can live in their crappy little Nazi town.
Rym: Yeah federalism Godwin, too We're on a roll.
Scott: I'm going for Godwin like five.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right Godwin this one.
Scott: So, uh the Microsoft Live debut Windows wouldn't exist if IBM didn't make computers and sell the Nazis.
Rym: IBM didn't make computers to sell the Nazis.
Scott: They did way back in the day.
Rym: There weren't computers?
Scott: Yeah, there were.
Scott: there were like enigma and there are machines of international business.
Scott: There were computers, yeah, they're just really crappy and they're real big.
Rym: But anyway, so this is real reminiscent of the other famous Microsoft demo that failed in front of millions of people.
Scott: Yeah, but see the thing is this one.
Scott: actually while it's hilarious that it failed and Microsoft was very crap Oh and failing it failed because the internet connection they were using died and Also everyone who was there watching their wireless died.
Rym: so it obviously wasn't though two of the reporters who were there say that they think the demo died and then Microsoft made the wireless die so they couldn't blog about it right away.
Scott: The only two things that could be true that I could think of are number one Microsoft actually just lost the connection and those reporters are all Linux II and awesome maybe or they're right, which means aha Linux II and awesome either way.
Rym: No one's gonna remember why it failed.
Rym: They're just gonna remember that it failed.
Scott: Yeah, they're also gonna remember.
Scott: I read one guy who actually you I think that's the article the one you're looking at.
Scott: One of those guys is talking about actual Microsoft Live and not about the fact that it went down and he's like, yeah It's cool after you customize it a whole bunch.
Scott: It's not immediately useful And it basically compared to Google's stuffs.
Scott: That is equivalent.
Scott: It's poop Aha.
Scott: So yeah They finally come through on the.
Scott: oh, we're gonna make it a web service instead of an application and it sucks All right, Nostradamus.
Scott: I thought it was gonna be good if they actually did it.
Scott: No, I pretty much assumed it wouldn't be Because I thought it would be just like an application only on the web.
Rym: But no people have been trying to do that for ever and they've done it successfully.
Rym: Not for office suites.
Scott: that is a word processor and there's a spreadsheet and they're both really good.
Rym: They're not as good from a business perspective and by business I mean what people in businesses use word processors and spreadsheets for.
Scott: if you slightly modified these things they would be.
Scott: you just had to Make it so it.
Scott: you know.
Rym: customize a little bit for your business Yeah, but keep in mind a lot of businesses use office suites in stupid ways.
Scott: Oh, we're gonna use a spreadsheet to do something.
Scott: We should use Microsoft Access for but Microsoft Access sucks.
Scott: You should never use it.
Scott: They're using.
Scott: they're basically using Excel for something that is supposed to be using MySQL for.
Rym: yeah Yeah, something like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh I need to make a poster.
Scott: I'm gonna use Microsoft Word instead of I guess the modern equivalent of publisher.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So my thing of the day Isn't so much?
Rym: it's really just a Wikipedia article, but I thought it was cool and it amused me greatly at work.
Scott: Wikipedia.
Rym: it is a list of unusual deaths and it is just people who have died in unusual funny or interesting ways Throughout history, how unusual could it be?
Scott: I can't imagine a death.
Scott: That's so strange.
Rym: All right This one may not be true, but according to may not be true.
Scott: then what's the point?
Rym: because accordingly in 207 BC?
Scott: How do we if it's 207 BC what the hell precipice.
Rym: some Greek philosopher died of laughter after seeing a donkey eating figs?
Scott: That's that's.
Rym: I move to ones that are definitely verified.
Rym: King Bela the first of Hungary died when his tall wooden throne collapsed because it was sabotaged by an assassin.
Scott: He's an eye-chair And I got the legs out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh another one of the figs Matthew Corvin is a king of Hungary.
Rym: He died after eating a poisoned fig.
Scott: I think someone sabotaged this thread this page with fig stories And I have a theory every theory hypothesis if you will.
Scott: it's a hypothesis.
Rym: Here's a good one.
Rym: this conquistador was killed by having molten gold poured down his throat.
Scott: He probably wanted it to happen that way.
Scott: He's probably pull the gold down my throat then I can eat the hottest peppers.
Rym: Tycho Brahe died of a bladder infection after refusing to leave for the bathroom during a banquet for the sake of good manners.
Rym: Oh No, no, no, it says that they've figured out later that.
Rym: no he just died of mercury poisoning?
Scott: Never but he made he's still alive.
Scott: He makes comics and they're funny.
Scott: Yeah Yeah.
Rym: So yeah, it's a funny list and I could just sit here and read them all day.
Scott: So let's not do that.
Scott: so my funny thing of awesome of the day was a case.
Scott: Western is a video floating around the net of A chemistry lecture.
Scott: All right I think it was a Halloween chemistry lecture, but I don't think that matters and visit his teacher up front showing something about Chemical equilibrium.
Scott: woman some reaction whatever.
Scott: Uh-huh and all of a sudden.
Scott: Um, I don't know which ghost it is pinky blinky Pac-man.
Scott: the blue pac-man ghost is about to be eaten the blue one.
Scott: Oh, they're all blue when they're about to be eaten.
Scott: so yeah, what about to be eaten?
Scott: one of unknown name comes in and Tells the teacher he's coming.
Scott: He's coming to get me.
Scott: Oh my god You know, he ate the big pill.
Scott: What am I gonna do?
Scott: Right and The teachers just like haha leave you're you're funny with your pac-man ghost.
Scott: All right, get out of here.
Scott: Yeah, and the pac-man comes and I was like, oh my god, and then pac-man chases him around of it and then chase him out of the room and Everyone there was.
Scott: it was very entertained man.
Rym: I miss college and I miss hijinks like that.
Scott: I miss that type of college hijinks.
Rym: Nothing like that happens at work.
Rym: There's no way I'd be sitting at work and someone dressed like pac-man would run through the car.
Scott: It's a pretty good pac-man costume - nice and solid good shape Better than some of the ones I saw at Otakon.
Rym: Well, even some of those were good though I saw one really good one at Otakon because it was going up the escalator look like it was eating people.
Scott: Oh, yeah That was a good one.
Scott: This is a lot like that one, but it's not the round ones.
Scott: I don't like and the round ones are - Anyway, yep Do you know?
Scott: it's anime day anime manga and comics?
Rym: Yeah are all that stuff?
Scott: web comics All those sorts of things.
Rym: Yep, though.
Rym: We did watch a episode one and two of a newish anime.
Scott: It's very new.
Rym: Yeah, it's very good to mushishi mushishi.
Rym: It's about these little things called mushi.
Scott: Well, they're not all little.
Scott: they're all summer big.
Rym: at first I thought they were all little.
Scott: they look like little like protists or little bacteria But you know the big ones were seem to be a bunch of little ones combined.
Scott: Yeah other times not.
Scott: it's sort of an ambiguous spiritual thing.
Rym: It's neat because the show starts and there's what looks like a main character and this like peripheral character character who comes in and Then through the episode You realize at the end that the peripheral guy who came in is the main character and the guy who thought was the main character Is just this one episode.
Rym: throwaway side plot Yep, but I like.
Scott: it seems like every episode is it is a one episode plot Which is good because the order doesn't matter so much.
Scott: But I'm sure that over time that more about the mushishi guy with one eye is revealed Was an episode two and his mushishi pin and his mushi pin.
Scott: mushi pin because the creatures are mushi.
Scott: Yes, he is a mushishi because he chases mushi, but it's not like Pokemon which is you know It's.
Scott: it's cool because it's like creatures but not Pokemon though.
Rym: He has at least one of these mushi.
Scott: That is his own personal I'm sure he has more and he uses their powers.
Rym: But whatever it's a good show and it's worth watching.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: it's not an a a plus plus plus show, but it's the best show this season so far.
Scott: Yeah, if you like like shadow star Naruto, it's similar to that but that had a little more fighting Pokemon leanings Yeah, but it's like it's like Pokemon plus mushishi equals.
Rym: it is Strange and cool unexplained creatures in an episodic kind of deal.
Scott: It's more in the genre of You know nice happy little Spiritual story kind of thing.
Rym: It wasn't all happy though.
Rym: Luckily.
Rym: There were some happy endings in the early parts.
Scott: Well, okay, they're not perfectly happy endings Which is good though because perfectly happy endings make for bad drag in the first episode.
Rym: You see all these mushi You're like, oh the mushi are cool and cute and whatever.
Rym: They're happy.
Rym: Then the second one.
Rym: There's the bad mushi.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: not all mushis are good or bad.
Scott: They're just mushi.
Rym: They're just these creature things I like the way they look.
Rym: they're really funny looking.
Scott: some of them are cute and happy.
Scott: I like the ones that are all like translucent protozoa thingies and they fly around and I'm very glad that unlike cluster edge Nobody got the gay on them.
Rym: There was no No, no Unexpected random gay god.
Rym: I still can't get over that scene and freakin cluster edge.
Scott: Yeah, we just we don't want anyone listening to this to think that we're homophobes or no.
Rym: We're not in fact considering that we have a tradition in our group known as the yaoi couch.
Scott: Yeah, but we can't take it when there's even an allusion to a yaoi in something.
Rym: We're actually watching Mainly because we have a friend who we were over hanging out at her house one day and we discovered her yaoi dungeon.
Scott: Oh, yeah, she ate.
Scott: In fact, we were talking about making molds of penises Randomly.
Rym: don't ask why we were talking about that.
Rym: Yeah You don't want to know.
Scott: but all of a sudden she had a relevant yaoi manga Sephiroth yeah making a mold of his penis and then impregnating himself with it.
Rym: and This one manga came out of a sea of manga under her bed and it was cool and creepy at the same time.
Scott: all of which Yeah, yeah, yep All right, mushishi to yaoi.
Rym: So, how do we get from yaoi to something else?
Scott: Well, let's talk about something that we really don't mind yaoi mixing with.
Scott: didn't you watch?
Rym: gone kotsuo.
Scott: It's not so yaoi.
Rym: No, it's not shamanic princess.
Scott: You can talk about shamanic princess.
Scott: We can get yaoi on that all we want.
Rym: Yeah, there's no yaoi in it though.
Rym: No, it's old.
Rym: It's real, but it still looks kind of like it was animated Really well for when it was made and it's really wasn't made in the 90s.
Rym: Yeah early 90s early 90s early mid 90s.
Scott: Are you sure to take the year on it?
Scott: Looks like a 96 or 97 to me early mid 90s.
Scott: It's pretty.
Scott: let's go check the year.
Rym: I saw it a long long time ago All right and I watched it again because I hadn't seen it in a while when I first seen it.
Rym: it was a show that I had Seen one of my early my anime that I'd seen.
Rym: so it was kind of uh, I saw it through the eyes of someone Thinks all anime is perfect and awesome and I loved it all and I watched it again.
Rym: I still really like the show but it's definitely not a anime.
Scott: Yeah, I remember when I was getting into anime and like anything was great.
Scott: now not so much.
Rym: So I gotta say if you like pretty shows shamanic princess is definitely worth watching.
Rym: It is definitely a Pretty people standing on top of tall spirey buildings saying poetic things than fighting with each other with magical things.
Scott: So it's so it's X.
Rym: yeah, it's a lot like X. it's that stylish 1996.
Rym: I'm the win.
Scott: Yeah mid 90s whatever.
Scott: What is it?
Scott: 99?
Scott: You've been like mid 90s.
Scott: It's between 90 and 2000.
Scott: It's in the mid.
Rym: Yeah, 96.
Rym: I was a freshman in high school.
Scott: that links up actually from when I saw it, all right Well, I guess that's good that you saw one is brand new.
Rym: then I saw it was fairly new.
Rym: Hey, I saw a crappy fan sub of it.
Rym: In fact And I got to say the dub is The worst dub ever worse than you ten of them worse than the you ten of them I can't be.
Rym: I should play some clips from.
Scott: I think is if you haven't seen terrible dubs in a while.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Just just for one example.
Rym: There's this cute little fairy thing named Japolo and he has a funny like normal voice and in the American dub instead of having like a funny little guy kind of voice it has like the voice of an old carny and Everyone speaks in such a stilted way.
Rym: an old carny like it like a carny from a carnival.
Rym: only who she was old and She was a gypsy she or he I couldn't tell.
Scott: So we did get the alley all over this.
Rym: Ah Yeah, because the ferret was getting it on with yeah.
Rym: Oh my god It was prime over Yuri show because it's all the main characters are girls and they all seem to like each other a lot in a very non yuri way.
Rym: This was before yaoi and yuri became mainstream like they are now.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think I'll be watching this show.
Scott: Let's send it back to Netflix.
Scott: Yeah So, uh, I went to the comic-book store today and I see you picked up a rocket.
Scott: Oh, I got a rocket.
Rym: Oh, I see you picked up a death note.
Scott: You know this death note the phone.
Scott: I went there to get death note.
Scott: volume one day came out.
Scott: Yeah There wasn't any.
Scott: let there's a little manga rack cuz they're the big wall full of comic books in a little rack of new manga.
Scott: Then they have a wall of the old manga, but they have a rack of new manga, uh-huh There were no death notes on the rack of new manga when I went to get volume one when it came out.
Scott: And I asked and they said oh, I guess we're sold out Today.
Scott: I went and I go to the rack death note volume two not on the rack And I'm like damn it.
Scott: I don't want to come here like next week again because they to go the next week to get volume one.
Scott: It was so ah, oh, no, I went to the other Branch of the story by every death note a week off from when it comes out.
Scott: Yeah, but it's still a pain.
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: you haven't already read it all Haven't read it all.
Scott: the plane took off and I don't have this.
Rym: next, you know Who?
Rym: you know what happens in the only part of the plot that I really care about.
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: So I asked the guy I was like, alright this guy was running around the store like a nut.
Scott: I think they were short on employees.
Scott: cuz one guy I always see there wasn't there, you know and stuff.
Scott: And I'm like got death note, so he looks on the rack.
Scott: it's not on the rack.
Scott: the rack actually was really empty.
Scott: So he goes and he's like, where's the overstock?
Scott: I got the last one in the overstock awesome.
Scott: Then he took the overstock and he started filling up the manga shelf again.
Scott: I was like, yes Death note is awesome.
Scott: Yeah, and I read it again.
Scott: It's still awesome.
Rym: If you haven't read death note read it.
Scott: Oh my god They're two volumes out now by them all.
Rym: Oh my god, cuz I must say Ryuku is probably the best character in any manga ever with the possible exception of major kusanagi yourself.
Scott: He's cool Thing is the coolest.
Rym: He's the only person I've ever seen in any manga who got both upside downy and inside outy at the same time for not eating Apples.
Scott: Oh, oh, oh my god when you read it again.
Scott: There's great stuff in here like when he makes the prisoners who commit suicide write notes before they die.
Scott: Yeah, and he reads down the left-hand columns.
Scott: L looks at the notes and he reads down the left-hand columns like the first letters and the first words of each sentence.
Scott: Yeah, and it says like L. Do you know?
Scott: it said that in Japanese - yeah, and the next one says gods of death.
Scott: and the last one says eat apples or like apples.
Rym: I Don't remember that.
Scott: Yeah I don't remember that kind of stuff either.
Scott: cuz I reminded me of when you were talking.
Scott: you were like Remember when L was all freaking about about the gods of death.
Scott: That's why he was freaking out about the gods of death because he talked about it in the stupid notes.
Scott: Maybe that was it.
Scott: No before then L didn't even know about guys.
Rym: Look at L's eyes.
Rym: There's no way that there's not some connection between Ellen, but look he's like.
Scott: are you saying that?
Scott: what do they call him?
Rym: Shinigami?
Scott: Shinigami exists question mark, that's when he started getting on it and then after it.
Scott: whenever he hears gods of death again He's like, uh-huh Because it was written in those notes that Kira made him write down.
Rym: See we'll see.
Rym: cuz look at his eyes.
Rym: There's something there.
Rym: I'll bet money now.
Scott: look before he was talking about gods of death and he was all freaking out about it and Just disagree you didn't have the manga.
Scott: I read it more recent, you know what you know what?
Rym: Look at his eyes.
Scott: His eyes aren't like that until after he's read those notes from Kira.
Rym: No, his eyes are always that way.
Scott: his eyes aren't like that.
Scott: Oh god, you're such a nut.
Scott: You always try to look into it.
Scott: so much to the point.
Scott: You know what assume we're looking in is right and it's never right because it worked with Gundam seed.
Rym: I was right about almost everything except the one unpredictable.
Scott: He doesn't like this completely different.
Scott: It does not logically follow that because you can predict one anime you can predict every anime and manga there is.
Rym: Well, I'm still waiting for one character in Death Note who left And I figured they would come back and they didn't and I'm curious about that.
Rym: Yeah, we can't really talk anymore because I'd a lot of people haven't read this and I don't want to spoil it because it's one Of the best manga I've read in a long time.
Scott: It's you know, I'm sure there's tons and tons of manga that are really awesome.
Scott: We haven't read but I've read lots and lots of awesome.
Scott: Manga is at least all the English ones.
Scott: Yeah, it was really awesome.
Scott: Very good, and it sells out.
Scott: So it's not just me.
Rym: They have raws of it at Walden books, so Yeah, and they sell.
Scott: I guess kind of yeah, they sell well enough to keep having them, but something no one knows about.
Scott: Yeah, rocket.
Scott: Oh rocket.
Scott: Oh is so And no one knows about.
Scott: a few people know about it.
Scott: it might be the most popular indie comic right now.
Rym: Yeah, read rocket.
Scott: Oh, it's pretty Sideways, so you'll see it and you'll know it looks like a comic book But it opens at the bottom instead of the side.
Scott: Well, I guess stapled at the top.
Scott: so you flip it up, but you rotate the whole thing 90 degrees to read it.
Rym: So it's why it's like a land.
Scott: It's a landscape.
Scott: Yeah landscape comic book and it's awesome.
Rym: It's got this cool style of drawing.
Scott: Well, it's like painting kind of and the characters are very Awesome.
Rym: There's not much I can say.
Rym: you just got to read it.
Scott: It's about this guy and like this other universe or world or ever and he's a navigator or mapper Yeah, and he has like a compass in his hand and the mapper is the only people who can know where they're going.
Scott: and there's only different races like cat people and dog people and Lizard, but I still like that tiger guy from the first.
Scott: tiger guy was definitely awesome But in this one, there's a new kind of guy in issue three is very awesome.
Scott: Is that the guy?
Rym: you showed me a glimpse of the guy I showed you glimpse of guy I think is a bad guy.
Scott: He's not a bad guy.
Rym: He's got to be a bad guy.
Rym: No, no one good looks that evil.
Scott: Yeah, oh he's kind of good.
Scott: he's pretty good.
Scott: He's definitely not a villain.
Scott: Anyway, the whole thing is is made by Frank Espinosa.
Scott: at least he does all the art and I think he writes it.
Scott: but there's a co-writer Mary Taylor and as a logo designer And let's see this presented whatever.
Scott: president you didn't do anything.
Scott: creative director Chris stone, I guess he did something.
Scott: But those it's really weird for an American comic to have so few people working on it Usually a manga like even Death Note, which is crazy.
Scott: It's made by two people the story and the art guy.
Scott: That's that's and that's unusual.
Scott: A lot of times is one guy story and art, you know, like Akira.
Scott: It's so huge one guy.
Scott: Yeah, American comics.
Scott: It's usually like writer penciler inker Tracer trace it.
Scott: Yeah Actually, they're not really traces but it's like they separate all these things out because they have to produce it so fast.
Scott: Yeah, and it's so with the crazy colors and the high productions.
Scott: They need a lot of people to do it the American way.
Scott: But you know to do them black and white, I guess you don't need so many people.
Rym: but yeah Well, I know a lot of mangaka just kind of work at their own pace and they come out whenever they finish them.
Scott: Yeah, well they come up with very few pages like weekly when in America They need to come out with like like 20 high quality pages monthly, you know.
Scott: And it's not easy because they have editors like telling them what to do.
Rym: Yeah The manga guys just do whatever they want really plus that comics used to have the things like the comics code kind of crippling them.
Scott: Well, but that's gone now.
Scott: Yeah, except for Archie comics and uh-huh DC Comics still do the comics code.
Scott: No one else there don't cares anymore.
Scott: Yeah, but Rockit.
Scott: Oh, it's.
Scott: it's like kind of a watercolor type of thing.
Rym: It reminds me a lot of like 50s type sci-fi Only kind of like only samurai jack with less colors and less hard edges Kinda, it's very soft and there aren't many hard edges at all.
Scott: Yeah, but it's very awesome It is.
Rym: it is if you're not gonna read Death Note at least read Rockit.
Scott: Oh, if you just go to the comic book store near you or an online comic book store or something I mean even if you don't want to buy how many comic books is it gonna be?
Scott: Doesn't know.
Rym: I don't know how many it's gonna be by the first one and read it You'll get enough out of that to make it worth it.
Scott: Yeah Actually like the first volume the best Right, you know, even though volume three is real good and two is real good.
Scott: It's it's all real good.
Scott: They'll be.
Scott: I'm sure there'll be a trade paperback one day.
Scott: I'll buy and then give that to people.
Scott: Yeah, Rockit Oh rules, yep, no one knows about it except for really awesome people.
Scott: but now everyone should know about it and read it.
Rym: and Tomorrow in our Netflix comes the final DVD of ghost in the shell standalone complex Which we had yet to see the end of.
Scott: yeah I think the episodes that I hadn't seen yet were the ones that we just watched and I love that show.
Scott: It's a great show.
Rym: It's a real good show.
Scott: compared to you and when you've been in such a drought of anime It's good to have shows that were great that you didn't watch that you can fall back on.
Rym: Yep, if nothing good comes out in the next few months We're gonna have to watch like Nadesha Co which neither one of us have seen strangely.
Rym: Yeah, it's really weird.
Rym: You've seen like every anime.
Rym: so I ran a freaking anime Club.
Rym: You remember like the biggest anime Club we hung out We spent whole weekends marathoning shows never saw Nadesha Co.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: We saw everything else.
Scott: Yeah, but there's a lot of old shows that are great that we didn't see what else you have in our queue at the Zee Gundam Zee Gundam, yep Last exile isn't that old but I was wanted lost exile.
Scott: last Knows, I don't remember.
Scott: but yeah, we should see that.
Rym: Yeah, Akino's journey looks cool.
Scott: Yeah, it looks like a little girly show.
Rym: Yeah, of course gone could suppose coming out.
Rym: I'm gonna buy all the DVDs because I love that show.
Scott: Good you only watch like a few episodes.
Rym: I watched the first seven and I loved.
Scott: I think I watch like a little over half of the show and then Stopped cuz I don't know what happened.
Rym: if you've read the book the unabridged penguin classics count of Monte Cristo Gone could suppose a thousand times better to watch.
Scott: Yeah, yeah things like that.
Scott: But whatever.
Scott: It's still a fun show.
Scott: it is It's not the greatest greatest show but it was the part that I got to is really cool.
Scott: And then I stopped watching.
Scott: I think cuz they stopped being available or it left r.i.t.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, most of what makes the show great is that it's very pretty and it's very stylized.
Scott: Well, all the people that are important have those like magic clothes that they put on.
Scott: Yeah It's what doesn't have.
Scott: the gonzo spends a lot of money on a show plus shows like that are right up my alley.
Rym: I mean my favorite friggin show is still utenna which is the same kind of deal of stylized pretty people.
Scott: But it was so cheap to make and gotten good.
Scott: So it was so expensive.
Scott: It's completely different.
Rym: Yeah, imagine if you tenor were made as high production value as Gonkatsu.
Scott: Oh was he would be the same thing.
Scott: It would just be better color in terms of like Looking like 2000 and not like 91 when it was.
Rym: maybe the fights wouldn't just be like utenna and toga standing there with like a silhouette of their swords going All right, all right, maybe that would change.
Rym: yeah, they're probably more - - That would be good.
Scott: Who could potentially be the only one Akio did not have sex with?
Rym: yeah, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but we don't know that for sure But that's the only one.
Scott: there's a chance.
Scott: He's the only chance All right.
Scott: Are we done?
Rym: I got nothing.
Scott: Oh We're gonna keep our bit of telling a story.
Rym: Oh, we should tell the story.
Rym: What story should we tell today?
Rym: Ron Jeremy Ron Jeremy All right.
Rym: This is your story.
Rym: So take it away Scott.
Scott: So so my mom went.
Scott: you turned your microphone off in the middle of podcast.
Rym: I bumped it by accident.
Rym: I turned it back on.
Scott: Whoo stupid click whoo It's bad.
Rym: So tell the story about Ron Jeremy and how you're his illegitimate son.
Scott: I'm not his illegitimate son You know, are you sure?
Scott: I'm a hundred percent sure.
Scott: Okay, do we get?
Scott: I will do a DNA test if you really want to.
Scott: I Mean, sorry, am I fat or look like Mario to you.
Scott: I mean a penis might might throw you off but But I can assure you that is not the case.
Scott: Anyway, so one day I'm sitting with my mom for watching.
Scott: Um, what was that movie?
Scott: boondock saints?
Scott: I think he was the bad guy.
Scott: yeah, yeah, it was boondock saints.
Scott: he's in it for like.
Scott: he's a bad guy who gets killed and My mom's like.
Scott: you see that guy.
Scott: I'm like what guy?
Scott: And I'm like, well, you know like the cop Detective guy William Defoe.
Scott: I thought to will him without the foe.
Scott: Yeah He's really good actor by the way Even though he's got the gay Come over here.
Rym: I'll give you the gay.
Scott: Oh knows Too much gay in today's podcast.
Rym: It's cluster Edges fault.
Rym: I'm telling you or it's um You know what?
Rym: It is.
Rym: We haven't had a yaoi couch in a Long time.
Scott: So anyway, my mom's like no the other guy and I'm like Ron Jeremy.
Scott: And she's like, yeah She's like laughing and like what about him.
Scott: and she's like.
Scott: she's like I went out with him.
Rym: I'm like, what the hell was he still fat back then?
Scott: I know I didn't get those details, but apparently He went to Queens College.
Scott: She went to Queens College.
Scott: All right, I think Seinfeld also went to Queens College I don't know if at the same time.
Scott: But anyway, my mom was on vacation in Florida.
Scott: He was on vacation in Florida.
Scott: They were on the same beach.
Scott: So she went out with him like twice and then broke up with him.
Scott: cuz he was a sleazy guy And he's still a sleazy guy.
Scott: and now that was that.
Scott: but Apparently my mom didn't even realize any of this until like her friend Judy knew that he became Ron Jeremy.
Scott: Apparently his name was William Hyatt, but that's what he.
Scott: oh, no, his.
Scott: he says his name is Ron Hyatt and not Ron Jeremy.
Scott: Uh-huh, but he says that's what his real name is.
Scott: But my mom said that his name was like Ron something Jewish like gold something ski, who knows but I don't know.
Scott: I can't I don't know.
Scott: Uh-huh but anyway, it was him and Outstanding.
Scott: the funny part was that my mom told me the story and then I told everyone.
Scott: I knew I got a story And I didn't tell what the story was.
Scott: and then I came and they were all in the same place at the same time And I told the story to everyone at once And it created a lot of suspense.
Rym: you did.
Rym: I remember that I remember being pissed because you kept saying I got a story but it's gotta wait.
Rym: It's gotta wait It's gotta wait and it worked.
Rym: it did.
Rym: I'm you're lucky.
Rym: You're damn lucky that that story lived up to the expectation.
Scott: What kind of story you think I was gonna tell?
Rym: we expected you to be like nothing.
Rym: Nothing happened.
Scott: I'm just screwing with you guys or you would have told one of your stories like so Now sitting around there waiting for me to show up thinking of what the story could be and not even coming close Not even close.
Rym: I Mean never would have suspected Ron Jeremy.
Scott: No, that's why it was great.
Scott: Yeah, if I would have thought you would have figured it out I wouldn't given you any time to figure it out because that would have ruined it.
Scott: Imagine if I came and I told it right and whether it was a good story or not.
Scott: It was something you would thought of.
Scott: You would have been like oh we thought of that.
Scott: you suck I feel like but it was still good.
Scott: Just cuz you thought of that.
Scott: now, I'm the suck.
Scott: It could only be something you couldn't have thought of and also not the suck.
Rym: So I will wait for the results of that DNA test, right?
Rym: Yeah, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the music and promotional consideration was provided by no one.