Scott: It's Thursday, November 10th, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, we'll be talking about awesome webcomics!
Rym: Dun dun dun!
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: So, I get on the train to go home today, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And there's always these two guys, I sometimes pass them, and they have like a little tiny wooden chess portable thingy, and they kind of put it on their laps, and they sit in the seats facing each other, and they play chess.
Rym: Is it magnetic?
Scott: I don't know, it could be.
Scott: If it is, it's like, secretly magnetic.
Scott: But they keep it balanced pretty well.
Scott: It's not an unstable set.
Rym: Yeah, it's not that bad of a train, so.
Scott: But anyway, that's not the point.
Scott: The point is, is that when I got on the train today, I sat in the little thing across from them.
Scott: You know.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: And I heard one guy talking, and he was talking, I think, I didn't hear the whole thing, about the the pick-three lottery.
Scott: So, where you pick three numbers, and then you win a prize.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And he was saying, "If one day, it's like 3-5-4, and the next day, it's like 3-5-6, and the next day, it's 3-5-8, what are the odds?
Scott: it's gonna be 3-5-9 on the fourth
Scott: day?".
Scott: It's, it, I'm like, I'm just sitting there like, the same, one out of 999.
Scott: The same it is every single day.
Scott: It doesn't, oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Someone needs to take a statistics class.
Rym: So, your story is basically that a lot of people are real bad at statistics.
Rym: That's the reason the lottery exists.
Scott: We need to fix, oh my god.
Scott: You should be sent immediately back to elementary school, if anyone hears you saying those sorts of things in public.
Rym: Here's the problem with that.
Rym: If people all knew statistics, there wouldn't be any more lottery, and then there wouldn't be any more money for schools, because we all pay for our schools through the lottery taxes.
Scott: Well, you know, with all these people that we'd send back to school, because they were too dumb, and they, you know, join the lottery, or play the lottery.
Rym: So the schools would need even more money.
Scott: Well, no, they would get the money from all these dumb people who had to go there, because they would go there, and it would suck for them, and they would put money into it.
Rym: What do you mean they would put money into it?
Rym: They wouldn't.
Rym: They'd coast through, and then they'd leave.
Scott: How about this?
Scott: If we make an enlightened despotism, we have a lottery.
Scott: And there's a law.
Scott: If you ever buy a lottery ticket, you are sentenced to school that you must pay for, double price.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: So that way you have to pay for your own re-schooling, as well as the schooling of someone else, for being dumb.
Rym: Or, you know, we could just reform the public school system, so these things don't happen anymore.
Scott: But what about the people who are already dumb?
Scott: Like this guy.
Scott: I mean, he seemed like a smart guy, you know, he's playing chess, and all the other things he was saying, he seemed like a cool, happening kind of guy, except he just didn't understand statistics.
Rym: Well, why didn't you do your part and fix that right then?
Scott: Because I was busy playing with my new digital camera.
Rym: So Sony's been doing some good, but I don't know if it outweighed the bad.
Scott: Wait, wait, hasn't Sony been doing just all bad lately?
Rym: No, they did one good, they did one good.
Rym: They joined this Linux alliance with IBM.
Scott: Wait, wait, every Linux alliance so far has been poop.
Rym: Well, let's see, this is IBM, Sony, and Philips.
Rym: It's a Linux adoption group, and they're trying to get people to use Linux.
Scott: Huh.
Scott: Oh yeah, those are three companies that don't like Microsoft.
Rym: It's mostly a legal protection racket, as in, don't worry, we vouch for the stuff being legal so you won't get sued.
Rym: You can use OSS.
Scott: That's like IBM saying, don't worry, we've already won the SEO case, give us your money and we'll give you nothing.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: IBM's already won the SEO case, as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: That's the point, but they're, you know, because the SEO, that's probably why IBM's keeping the SEO case not done yet, is so that they can get money out of people and basically sell them nothing.
Rym: But we don't need to give them money, this group just is vouching for Linux, basically.
Scott: They'll do it whether you give them money or not?
Rym: As best I can tell, it's one of those vague industry initiatives that doesn't actually do anything.
Scott: And so it's just an excuse to make a press release with the words Linux, IBM, Sony, and Philips in it.
Rym: Something like that.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Because it didn't really take away from the fact that not only did Sony release a horrible rootkit, not only does it also infect Macs, not only do if you call them to get the uninstaller, does the uninstaller install an even worse one, but someone has already exploited this thing in the wild and there's now a Trojan.
Scott: Well, they exploited it to cheat at World of Warcraft.
Rym: Not that there's anything wrong with that.
Scott: I can't really blame you for avoiding the grind and beating the Chinese gold farmers.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: I wonder how many people are going to be selling some level 60 characters on eBay right now.
Scott: I heard that the next Diablo is going to be an MMO, wait till we see what goes on there.
Rym: Oh god, remember Battle.net?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: It's actually still Battle.net is what they call all the Blizzard online stuff.
Rym: I thought it'd be really cool and I logged on.
Rym: It's kind of like Steam of Blizzard.
Rym: And the guy had every item in the game and I asked him if I could have some and he gave me every item in the game.
Rym: And then I realized that I could just make copies of every item in the game and I'd never play it again.
Scott: Yep, yep, yep.
Rym: But this Trojan, it's kind of cool because it preys on the vanity of idiots.
Rym: It comes as an email attachment in an email that says, "We're some sports magazine" or "We're some business magazine and we want to use your picture.
Rym: So could you please confirm that this is a picture of
Rym: you?".
Scott: Oh great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They open the attachment and then BAM!
Rym: BAM!
Rym: Uh, dollar sis dollars files all over your system.
Scott: Ah, that's how it goes, eh?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It doesn't use the Trojan that's already installed.
Rym: They must have bought the CD, gotten the Trojan out of it, and now they're using it in their own malware.
Scott: Ugh.
Scott: See the thing is, Sony didn't make the Trojan.
Scott: They just kind of bought it from this British company.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder, I mean- The Mac one is actually a different one that they also bought and they put them both on all the CDs.
Rym: Who thought this was a good idea?
Scott: Some company that was making DRM.
Rym: No, I mean, who in Sony thought it was a good idea to poison the only legitimate paying customers they had?
Scott: Well, the thing is, they didn't, they didn't, I don't think they knew.
Scott: I think they were just saying, "Hey, let's buy DRM.
Scott: Let's look at the DRM
Scott: solutions.".
Scott: And this company came to them and said, "Our DRM is pretty much
Scott: unbeatable.".
Scott: And Sony said,
Scott: "Okay.".
Rym: Yeah, they probably didn't look at it too hard.
Scott: And probably, even if they looked at it too hard, do you think they know what they're looking at?
Scott: You think anyone at Sony that was looking at this is as competent as we are?
Rym: Someone at Sony has to know how to code.
Rym: Someone at Sony had to have said, "Hey, hey, this is a bad
Rym: idea.".
Scott: Even so, this thing has been in the wild for like months and months and months, and no one found it until very recently when the rootkit revealer guy, the guy who makes rootkit revealer, the expert on rootkits found it randomly.
Rym: You know why I think that was?
Rym: No one who knows about computers buys CDs anymore.
Scott: Could be.
Rym: So, no, anyone who bought, I mean, the list of CDs includes such wonderful hits as Ricky Martin.
Scott: Who's that?
Rym: Livin' La Vida Loca.
Scott: What's that?
Rym: Wow, you're more divorced from pop culture than I am.
Rym: I didn't think that could be.
Scott: I have no idea what you're talking about.
Rym: Hot, hot, hot or cold?
Scott: It's hot, hot, hot.
Scott: That was from SNL, wasn't it?
Rym: Yeah, that was a spoof on Ricky Martin.
Scott: Oh, alrighty then.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Pop Culture there.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: I just thought it was funny because the guy said, "Hot, hot,
Scott: hot.".
Scott: I didn't know they were making fun of anybody.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: So, you know that video game law in Michigan that was like, "Oh, if you sell, you know, bad video games, we'll fine you and stuff, and maybe even send you to
Scott: prison.".
Rym: Yeah, the law that made me kind of ashamed of my home state.
Scott: So, some judge came around and said, "Hey, I think there'd be some chilling effects up
Scott: there.".
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: And, uh, put a stop to that.
Scott: He didn't get rid of the law, but he said, "We can't be enforcing this law yet until we see some court
Scott: lookings.".
Rym: So, uh, he basically isn't letting the law get passed until they come up with a way to get rid of the law.
Scott: Well, it's passed, but he basically said this law can't be enforced, and it's kind of like a hold.
Scott: Like, you put someone on hold on the phone.
Rym: Huh.
Rym: I wonder if he's just gonna hang up when no one's looking.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I got a theory.
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: I think this judge is a gamer.
Rym: You know, I wouldn't put it that far out.
Rym: We're getting to the point where the first gamers, I mean the real gamers, the hardcore gamers, are in industries and are, uh, doing things other than gaming.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You know, there's gonna be a day someday when someone from the Nintendo generation is president of the United States of America.
Scott: There has to be, because you can only be president for eight years, and, uh, you know, eventually someone who was born between, you know, 1980 and 1990 will, uh, will be up for election, and your choice will be between Nintendo Player and Nintendo Player.
Rym: Ah, maybe Sega Kid.
Scott: No, who had a Sega Master System.
Scott: He'd have to be, like, a Brazilian import, because that's what they had the Sega Master System.
Rym: Man, I remember when I was in parochial school way, way back when I was a little kid, and everyone had a Nintendo, but all the dumb kids had Sagas.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: In my town it wasn't that way.
Rym: I mean, one kid had a Nintendo jacket, and he was the coolest kid.
Scott: Where'd he get a Nintendo jacket from in those days?
Rym: I think his mom made it.
Scott: Oh, okay, that's all right.
Scott: But in the 8-bit era, everyone had NES, and some cool kids had Ataris, but they also had NESes.
Rym: Yep, yep.
Scott: I had an Atari 2600, but it broke.
Rym: I had an Atari 7800, and I had an Intellivision 2 that my grandma bought.
Scott: Oh, but, you know, after the NES, it was either SNES or Genesis, because no one could afford both of them, and, you know, no one was smart enough to hook up both to the TV.
Scott: So, you know, some kids bought SNES, and some kids bought Genesis, and, you know, there were some kids, you know, they would fight.
Scott: They'd be like, "Oh, this one's better.
Scott: This one's
Scott: better.".
Scott: But everyone played both of them pretty much equally.
Rym: See, I didn't know anyone who had a Genesis, and I didn't know anyone who knew anyone who had a Genesis.
Rym: The kids who had Genesises were kids on the other side of the school that none of us ever talked to.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: We would, you know, you'd see if you had a bunch of friends with SNESes, you would usually buy a Genesis.
Scott: That way, you could get more games going on.
Rym: Yeah, but we had enough with the NES.
Scott: Sometimes the logic was different.
Scott: Sometimes the logic was if your friends have SNES, your close friends have SNESes, the ones you trust, you get the same, so you could trade games, and the semi-distant friends, you would get different, so that you could play the other games at parties.
Rym: You know, one time, I traded Hydlide for Mega Man 3.
Scott: You just ripped someone off real bad.
Rym: Yeah, he came to my door, like, 15 minutes later, and I want my game back!
Rym: Give it back!
Rym: And I wouldn't open the door, and I kept it.
Scott: Yeah, one time, I traded this kid, Prince of Persia, for the Sega Genesis for, I think, Urban Strike, the helicopter game.
Scott: You know, and Prince of Persia was on a bunch of different systems, so I didn't really care, but we were supposed to trade back.
Scott: I never saw that kid again.
Scott: You know, I didn't beat Urban Strike.
Rym: Wasn't that good a game?
Scott: No, but I think I also got an NHL game out of the deal, but who needed that?
Scott: It wasn't as good as ice hockey or anything else.
Rym: Blades of Steel.
Scott: And then we eventually got NHL 99 for the N64, which is really good.
Rym: We had that for the PC.
Rym: Barely ran on our computer, oh my god.
Scott: I had the demo for the PC.
Scott: It ran on my Pentium 3450.
Scott: See, everyone always says, "Oh, put on your tinfoil
Scott: hat!".
Rym: Wrap tinfoil around your house.
Scott: Yeah, it'll prevent the government from spying on you and the radio signals getting in and out and blah.
Rym: Too bad.
Rym: it'll actually, uh, what, magnify?
Scott: Yeah, they tested some tinfoil hats, and they sent some, you know, I think 2.4 gigahertz frequency signals at you, and apparently the tinfoil hat increased the signals and did not protect you at all.
Rym: Outstanding.
Scott: I think you would actually need, like, a real Faraday cage helmet to, uh...
Rym: But a Faraday cage has to be a complete sphere.
Scott: Yeah, so if it comes in through your neck, you're not doing too well.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I guess you just roll around in a ball like in American Gladiators for the rest of your life.
Scott: Dude, that'd be freaking sweet.
Rym: I wonder if we could make a market for those.
Rym: We could sell them to those consumers.
Scott: I wonder what happens if the American Gladiators set.
Scott: It should totally be on eBay.
Scott: I would buy the freaking, uh, the one where they shoot the tennis balls.
Scott: I would buy all the equipment from that.
Rym: You know what, I would play that every day.
Scott: I screw paintball and airsoft.
Rym: You know what, I get to be the guy in the tower.
Scott: No, I think we have to take turns.
Rym: No, I think I always get to be the guy in the tower.
Scott: All right, that's fine.
Scott: 'Cause you know what, every time I watch that show, the guy who was on the ground, you knew he could win so easily.
Scott: He was just always dumb when he lost.
Rym: Yeah, like, he'd always, like, he'd miss with every gun until he got right up to the end.
Rym: You have to throw the tennis balls at it.
Scott: And he would actually throw all three tennis balls.
Scott: I'd be like, you're not gonna win with the tennis balls.
Scott: Just run for the exit.
Scott: You'll get some points.
Scott: And the thing is, they had the one weapon, the rocket, with the little guard bit.
Scott: That rocket can hit so easily.
Scott: These people sucked.
Rym: 'Cause they were so afraid of getting hit by the ball, but the rocket had a shield on it.
Scott: The other thing is, one time a guy kept popping out and made the gladiator shoot all the tennis balls.
Scott: And then he was just like, he walked right up and shot the rocket at the target.
Rym: 'Cause most of the time, they got eliminated.
Rym: And I remember if you got eliminated, you got no points.
Rym: If you made it to the end, even if it took you the maximum time, you got some points.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So you'd just make it to the end.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I would have been great on that show, except for all the other events that require speed, strength, and stamina.
Scott: You know what definitely won't protect you from those tennis balls?
Rym: Uh, tin foil hat?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Maybe we should start a market in saran wrap face masks.
Rym: That'll solve the conspiracy theory problem.
Scott: That'll solve the guy who don't know the statistics problem.
Rym: So it's time for the thing of the day.
Scott: I thought we were going to make a little music for that.
Rym: Well, we haven't done it yet.
Scott: We're so lazy.
Rym: So what is your thing of the day?
Scott: So I went onto the internet this morning and I saw--.
Rym: Oh, you went on the internet this morning.
Scott: I saw Doom running on the iPod Nano.
Rym: Now-- Wait, Doom.
Rym: Doom or Doom 2?
Scott: Doom 1.
Rym: Doom 1.
Scott: The whole thing.
Rym: How do you, uh, control it on the iPod Nano?
Scott: Well, I guess you steer left and right with the wheel.
Rym: And then I guess you, uh-- So how do I strafe, change weapons, shoot, and open doors?
Scott: You can't-- I don't think you can do all those things easily.
Scott: I think there's no strafing.
Scott: You pretty much turn left and right by going left and right.
Scott: And I think you, uh, go forward by pushing up.
Scott: You shoot by pushing the middle button.
Rym: And you open doors, I think, maybe-- You realize without being able to strafe, it's pretty much impossible to get more than two and a half levels into Doom.
Scott: I think you play it on, uh, you know, Don't Hurt Me.
Rym: Uh, uh.
Scott: I guess you could play it on Nightmare, but the idea isn't the cool, awesome controls.
Scott: The idea is that you're playing Doom on an iPod Nano.
Rym: So, uh, did you install it on your iPod Nano?
Scott: Well, the way it works is you have to install iPod Linux and then Doom, right?
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Now, um, see, the directions seem pretty easy.
Scott: It was get this executable Windows thing, run it, and it installs Linux on your Nano.
Scott: And then just put Doom folder on your Nano.
Rym: So, uh, that didn't work?
Scott: Well, I read and I thought I read the whole thing.
Scott: And I mean, they had a picture of Doom running on the Nano.
Scott: And the directions on the Doom for Nano website was install iPod Linux, copy Doom.
Scott: So I went and I got the executable to install iPod Linux and ran it.
Scott: But little did I realize that the latest stable version does not support the Nano.
Scott: They must use a nightly build or done something else tricky that they didn't explain at all.
Scott: So I found out what happens when you screw up the firmware on your Nano.
Rym: It doesn't work?
Scott: Well, it turns on.
Scott: You get the little black apple that says I'm booting, right?
Scott: And then you get the, uh, this folder with an exclamation point that says www.apple.com/ipod/support.
Scott: That is awesome.
Scott: It tells you this URL for the support site.
Scott: So then I'm like, all right, I broke it.
Scott: I'll just use the iPod updater to restore the firmware.
Scott: Apparently, because the firmware was somewhat borked that I had put on there, it wasn't so easy to replace it.
Scott: I eventually had to like restart the computer, restart the iPod service, run the updater, then plug in the iPod, then wait as the computer went crazy, then click the restore button, then wait as it went crazy again.
Rym: So, uh, did you figure this out on your own?
Rym: or was there some forum somewhere where someone said I borked my iPod?
Scott: No, I had to figure it out.
Scott: I knew to restore.
Scott: That was obvious because he just restores to the real Apple firmware.
Rym: Restore didn't work.
Scott: Restore didn't work like five times.
Scott: I just had to keep messing with it.
Scott: And if that didn't work, I would have had to go to the Apple store.
Rym: Don't you do a work at work?
Scott: This was during my little breaky bit.
Rym: Yeah, your breaky bit.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, well.
Rym: My thing of the day, usually I'm not one to say this, is so much cooler than your thing of the day.
Scott: What could be cooler than doom on a music player?
Rym: This is one of the coolest things I've seen on the internet in a long time.
Scott: Can't be that cool.
Rym: So, uh, humans haven't made anything like the great pyramids in a long time.
Scott: Ever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you're saying aliens made the great pyramids?
Scott: No, I guess, but not, you know what I mean?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We have not really undertaken such massive, uh, works.
Scott: Well, we made Rome.
Rym: Rome wasn't really a large semi-useless thing to convey information.
Rym: It was more of a city full of people.
Scott: We made, uh, big buildings.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: Rockets.
Rym: Consider how would we, as a civilization, convey culturally independent information that can be understood and experienced by possibly unknown or primitive cultures five, ten, fifteen thousand years from now, and why would we want to?
Scott: Well, I don't know why we'd want to, but we could use HD Rosetta.
Rym: Yeah, but we're talking about technologically primitive.
Rym: Possibly.
Scott: We could make a box that has some audio recorded and a speaker and- Audio!
Rym: Audio!
Rym: Because they'll speak the same language as ten thousand years from now.
Scott: Who says it has to be language?
Scott: It could just be noises.
Rym: All right, so we have a moo, and then a bark, and then some noise.
Scott: You know those things where you turn it upside down and it goes "meh"?
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure that'll convey the, uh, gestalt of our civilization.
Scott: How about, you know, a self-powered video player where, you know, if anyone comes near it, it plays video?
Rym: Self-powered that'll somehow not be taken apart and sold for scrap sometime during those ten or twenty thousand years.
Scott: Well, hide it with like a projector.
Rym: All right, all right.
Rym: So anyway, back to the other point you made of why would we want to.
Rym: Well, uh, say we start using nuclear power more than we do now, and we start generating a lot of nuclear waste.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So we're gonna have to start building deep underground storage facilities to contain it.
Scott: Well, you already determined that that would be perfectly safe.
Rym: Yeah, unless someone drills there, or digs it up, or starts like tapping into the well water that goes right through it.
Scott: Yeah, that would be bad.
Rym: So this is an actual study, and there's a lot more to this document than I have in my link today,
Scott: but
Rym: basically it's a bunch of scientists and researchers talking about how can you convey universally to intelligent beings that there is something bad here that you don't want to unearth.
Rym: Like think about in the movies where there, or in D&D, when there's a demon that some ancient civilization buried somewhere, and they put up like the crazy warnings and the spell barriers and all the stuff to keep you out and to warn you that something's bad's here, until the main character of a movie wanders in and accidentally releases it.
Scott: It's so obvious, you just put some traps and you put some things that are ominous.
Rym: No, because traps don't work.
Rym: Traps tell people there's something valuable here.
Rym: I'm going to bypass the traps and try to get to it.
Rym: And traps don't work forever.
Scott: You put things that are all too enticing.
Rym: See, actually the conclusions, I mean this paper is really interesting, and I can't really get into all the details without making a whole podcast about it.
Rym: So you're really gonna have to follow this link because it's really neat.
Rym: But basically they talk about how you could do this, how you could make this gestalt, this system of information that as a whole will let people know that this is a bad place and you don't want to be here, while at the same time propagating itself and being resistant to people, say scavenging it for spare parts or masonry, or making a monument to it because they think it's something like the pyramids.
Rym: And it talks about different things, like they break up the types of different information you can convey to people into four levels.
Rym: Level one is there is something man-made here.
Rym: Probably the simplest message in the world.
Rym: What is here is not natural.
Rym: Level two is whatever is here is dangerous.
Rym: It was repulsive to us as a society and you do not want it.
Rym: There is no item of value here.
Rym: This is a non-place.
Scott: A non-place?
Rym: A non-place.
Rym: A place that you should not be.
Scott: It's not a place.
Rym: Level three should be an explanation in some sort of language, probably whatever language is most common, maybe multiple languages, that would hopefully be translated by people in the future, that explains exactly what it is.
Rym: This is a horrible nuclear waste burial site.
Rym: It was built in the year blah blah blah.
Rym: It is this big.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: Level four information is here are the schematics and technical diagrams of all the crap we buried under here and exactly how dangerous it is and when we think it won't be dangerous anymore.
Rym: And to skip a bit, because I could talk about this forever, I read the whole thing and it's really cool.
Rym: They came up with a lot of ideas on how to convey these messages and the basic concept is that in addition to having bits of information around, they want the area to be inhabitable and ominous.
Rym: So these architects came up with ways to have like horrible non-euclidean looking jagged spikes coming out of the ground made of like basalt or horrible Cthulhu looking cities that just make you feel bad.
Rym: Like something's bad here and I shouldn't be here.
Rym: These are like things out of movies.
Scott: See but that makes people feel bad.
Scott: How do we know that some aliens won't feel good?
Scott: Like hey look this is the obviously the only inhabitable part of this damn planet.
Rym: Well actually they get into that because they show such things as you can't just have a big warning that says warning radiation because a civilization might be standing there and to whip out a Geiger counter and hey there's no radiation.
Rym: that signs BS.
Rym: They don't know that the radiation is buried very deep.
Rym: and then five thousand years later they dig down to get something and the horrible radiation comes out.
Rym: So they tried to come up with universal ideas of.
Rym: this is a dangerous place.
Rym: Menacing earthworks.
Rym: Not using like obelisks or pyramids or anything that looks good.
Rym: They want things to be pretty but not good looking.
Rym: They want to convey the message that this is something repulsive.
Rym: And yeah I really shouldn't talk more about it because other than there's a funny picture of a guy getting radiation on him and then falling over dying and there's happy trees next to him.
Scott: Why don't they just put some poison gas there like.
Rym: See that's one of the one of the things they said is that you can't keep people out because we can guarantee like the pyramids.
Rym: The pyramids were designed to keep people out.
Rym: then technology improved.
Rym: People found the pyramids and they broke themselves in and saw what was out.
Rym: Just put something that smells bad that'll last ten thousand years.
Rym: Yeah yeah because we have that technology.
Rym: Unless we got to get working on what we made a giant pyramid of dead dogs and skunks.
Scott: I'll tell you what if we did that it'd be a lot cooler than this story.
Rym: Really read the article because the pictures are neat the conclusions they make are neat and this is probably one of the most forward thinking projects I've ever seen mankind in recent history engage upon.
Scott: It's neat and it's forward thinking but I don't think it's that cool.
Rym: If you read this article I think you'll think it is.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This is the closest to a real yeah we're ever gonna get.
Scott: But you know what's good about these kind of things is like when you run out of stuff to talk about.
Scott: that's the kind of stuff you could just keep talking about for like hours if you're a bunch of nerds.
Rym: Yeah like when we debate the various uh ways magic works in Dungeons and Dragons games.
Scott: No it's nothing like that.
Rym: Yeah because that's what Pete and Katsu and I were doing not too long ago mostly Pete and Katsu.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: So web comics.
Scott: Oh yeah read them every day.
Rym: Yeah every morning I get up and I read about 12 different web comics.
Scott: I read like seven because I have standards too high.
Rym: Well also because a lot of web comics we used to read have fallen by the wayside because their authors stopped updating them.
Scott: And a lot of them we used to read are not funny and it just took so long to finally delete the bookmark.
Rym: See I'm sorry but Bob and George was never funny.
Scott: It was funny.
Rym: It was never funny.
Scott: It was Flash Man and the joke was that he flashed people.
Scott: He had a trench coat.
Scott: It was funny.
Rym: That wasn't funny at all.
Scott: That was funny.
Rym: That was perhaps one of the lamest jokes I've ever heard in my life.
Scott: I like it.
Rym: That speaks very highly of your character and sense of humor.
Scott: I like flashing.
Rym: Flash.
Rym: Oh god.
Scott: So you know over time we've you know added and removed a whole lot of web comics.
Rym: Yep one web comic we read for a long time and then the author stopped writing it and disappeared and then he reappeared and asked for money and he said if you got enough money you'd start the comic again.
Rym: So we both gave him money and he wrote three more strips and then he disappeared again.
Scott: You know I was thinking about the exact same comic like two seconds ago.
Rym: Yeah so uh Nick Yu of Bad Boys of Computer Science if you're listening I want my five dollars back.
Scott: Not only don't I want my one dollar back that I gave you.
Scott: and uh you know you were supposed to make a comic for that one dollar and you didn't.
Scott: So yeah get working.
Rym: So probably our favorite web comic just hands down is Penny Arcade.
Scott: I don't know VVOCS could have lived up if it would have kept going.
Scott: Yeah it could have.
Scott: Despite its much much much less artisticness.
Rym: But Penny Arcade is I mean this is undisputed by and large by orders of magnitude or at one order of magnitude the most read webcomic in the world.
Rym: It is the number one webcomic.
Rym: More people read it than any other webcomic.
Scott: With good reason.
Rym: Yeah and you know what it's probably one of my favorites.
Scott: It's my favorite webcomic.
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: I mean it's very simple.
Rym: The humor is often very uh strange or violent or revolving around the use of bad words.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: The thing about Penny Arcade is that it's just the only comic of all the comics.
Scott: every single one of them is funny.
Scott: Every single.
Scott: there isn't one that is unfunny.
Scott: Some are better than others.
Scott: Not gonna deny that.
Scott: And some you know are about something that you care about more or a game you care about less or something you're in touch with more.
Rym: They're often multiple layers to the jokes.
Rym: Like there'll be a joke about or there's one with a snowman.
Rym: There's a joke about something some video game The Sims that if you don't play video games you wouldn't get.
Rym: But there was also a very obvious blatant look.
Rym: he put a penis on the snowman joke.
Rym: It's scary.
Rym: that I mean as we both started reading this along with all of our friends right about as we were freshmen in college.
Scott: You mean when the comic was pretty almost brand new.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I think it was maybe six months to a year old at that point.
Rym: And I can think back to a Penny Arcade comic and I can correlate it with a period in my college life.
Scott: It's hard to match the times of exactly like.
Scott: sometimes you look and you're like that comic so recent.
Scott: Oh my God it's two years old.
Scott: Oh my God.
Rym: But some are like they're making fun of tribes too.
Rym: We bought that when it came out.
Scott: Oh and I remember playing it and I remember it was the best game ever.
Scott: And that comic is so right.
Scott: All their comics are so right.
Scott: One thing about Penny Arcade comics is that it was like a newspaper comic right.
Scott: It's like they have like an introduction at the beginning.
Scott: Then there's like a setup and then there's a punch line.
Scott: A Penny Arcade comic like doesn't have a beginning or an end.
Scott: It's just the middle.
Scott: You know like you'll see like violence about to happen in the final frame or like you'll see constant violence throughout the three frames.
Scott: And there'll be a joke in each one.
Scott: So like it'll be like joke joke joke.
Scott: But the third one somehow also includes the first two.
Scott: So it's like instead of say something normal say something normal.
Scott: Something funny because of the first two things.
Scott: It's two funny things and then a third thing that incorporates the first two things.
Rym: It's like each frame stands on its own as a joke.
Rym: But the three of them together are greater than the sum of the three.
Scott: Yeah and even and most of the time you'll see that the thing they say in the third frame.
Scott: The joke is actually in the non-existent fourth frame.
Scott: Or somehow in the non-existent first frame.
Scott: Like you'll see Gabe come walking in with something stupid that already happened to him.
Scott: You know like he'll already be chewed up by a dog and it's like what happened to you.
Rym: Yep or also you can't forget the ones where they show the end of the joke.
Rym: and then the last frame is like Gabe and Tycho staring at each other in an awkward moment.
Scott: Yeah when the facial expressions especially on Gabe whenever something funny happens.
Rym: There's the one when the hobo spiders came out.
Scott: The hobo spider and he had a spider in his mouth and one in his eye.
Scott: And the way his mouth was just this oval.
Scott: It's just this oval like he drew it.
Scott: I don't know he probably drew it with his hand but yeah it looked like it was a perfect oval drawn in illustrator with two rows of like flat teeth in this tongue and it was like it was covered in spiders.
Scott: Just looking at it.
Scott: Just cut the face out and put it somewhere with no text.
Rym: Now the other one that we started reading at right about the same time which used to be the most popular web comic in the world.
Rym: Mega Tokyo.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: Which was absolutely hilarious back when it was a four panel comic about gaming.
Scott: You mean when it was Largo's comic?
Rym: Yeah back when Largo was still on the comics.
Rym: He was done by Fred Gallagher and Rodney Caston.
Scott: Rodney Caston.
Rym: And they had a falling out and now it's just done by Fred Gallagher.
Scott: I think his site is like TypeRcaston.com.
Rym: Something like that.
Scott: Because he thinks he's cool with the Type R.
Rym: And I still read it and it's a good comic.
Rym: It's really well drawn.
Rym: I mean hands off to Fred for being an amazing artist.
Scott: You know actually it's like it looks really cool.
Scott: but a lot of people I know that like it looks really cool to me.
Scott: You know he draws like pencils and like you know crazy detail as compared to like you know a lot of manga that's in pencil.
Scott: I mean like Death Note has better art but you know maybe you know random Tokyo Pop.
Scott: manga number three doesn't.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But lots of art people I know always say bad things about it.
Scott: All the girls look the same and he doesn't do backgrounds very high quality.
Scott: And a lot of times like the sizes of things are all off.
Scott: Things you don't notice unless you're like an artist person.
Scott: Unless they're way way off.
Rym: I mean I still like the comic.
Rym: but the only thing that bothers me is that it's not about gaming anymore and it's kind of following this like stereotypical show Joey kind of.
Rym: oh girls and fanboys plot that.
Scott: The thing that bothers me is not so much the is it.
Scott: Number one the plot moves slowly right.
Scott: It's not the worst plot in the world.
Scott: I mean in terms of itself but it is very slow and they don't fill in a lot of details.
Scott: and like if you don't know stuff like I didn't even know what was going on for the first half because they were never really character introductions or developments or anything.
Scott: You know.
Scott: and then the other thing that bothers me is like the plot itself is okay but the message of the plot is it's okay to be a fanboy and it's very fanboy fanboys.
Rym: Don't be mean to them.
Scott: Yeah it's like it should be fanboy get off your ass and stop being a stupid fanboy shower.
Scott: Yeah take a shower or else girls won't go with you.
Scott: Girls should be all oh and liking fanboys.
Scott: and you know it's like oh just fanboy fan service of the most direct kind.
Rym: Now see I can always hope that he's not gonna like.
Rym: that's the direction he's going in but then it'll kind of turn into a. oh that was wrong.
Rym: here's how it should be.
Scott: There's no chance because he's a fanboy and he makes you know he's drawing like his own fantasy world and it's also the fantasy world of fanboys.
Rym: Possibly I mean I don't know him too well.
Scott: No remember he likes that canon stuff.
Scott: I mean come on come on.
Scott: it's obvious everyone knows it.
Rym: Well also the fact that we have a personal grudge with Megatokio because they stole the joke mosh mosh revolution from us.
Scott: I don't think he actually stole the idea.
Rym: Not him specifically.
Rym: this sounds silly but this really happened.
Scott: Well we we were talking about this idea of mosh mosh revolution and some guy who thought he was all cool because he knew Fred.
Rym: Ken Hashimoto aka the blur.
Scott: The blur according to Largo who called him the blur.
Scott: Her overheard us you know making this random joke of mosh mosh revolution.
Rym: And then sure enough next week mosh mosh revolution was in Megatokio.
Scott: Yeah so I think it's pretty obvious that what happened was we were talking about it and then Ken heard it and told it to Fred maybe said it was his own idea or just told it as a joke or who even knows yeah but communicated that idea to him and then Fred turned it into a comic.
Rym: Though even still you can't deny the Megatokio phenomena.
Rym: Remember what the first Otakon they went to the sheer number of people trying to get into that room to get a glimpse of those two guys.
Scott: Because the number of people that the type people are at Otakon are the type of people read that comic.
Rym: Imagine if Gabe and Taiko went to Otakon.
Scott: Yeah they were gonna once and they didn't.
Scott: Yeah instead they went to the Baltimore Comic-Con this year where like no one went and it was all quiet.
Rym: Yeah I mean I guess two Gabe and Taiko even though you're probably not listening.
Rym: Imagine the Baltimore Comic-Con where that entire convention center is filled to the brim with geeks.
Scott: Every you were in just.
Scott: I think the Baltimore Comic-Con was in just one room of that convention center.
Scott: Otakon is the only thing that uses the entire convention center.
Scott: Every room in both buildings is absolutely full of geeks geeks geeks everywhere.
Rym: And that's not enough.
Rym: they're making Baltimore build another convention center next to it to house more Otakon.
Scott: And if you had come that one year you probably would have packed the largest room in that convention center.
Rym: Which seats what 9,000 people?
Scott: Something crazy like that.
Scott: just to look at your ugly asses.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Of course to move on I don't have a segue here.
Rym: 8-bit theater.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: 8-bit theater when it started was really dumb.
Rym: Like the first six or seven comics were just this stupid sprite comic where a guy took pictures from Final Fantasy 1 and put speech bubbles on.
Scott: You know I was never the biggest fan of Final Fantasy and like when I was a freshman everyone was like oh I read 8-bit theater and I was like oh that's crap.
Rym: So I read the first few and I was like this is crap.
Rym: And then I came back a month later and there were a whole bunch more.
Rym: And it evolved from crap sprite comic to probably one of the funniest things I've ever read in my life shortly.
Scott: I mean I came back when like Black Mage was cutting up like people in town.
Scott: And it's like he.
Scott: just you know he the guy always complains or at least I've seen writing of his that says man I kind of don't like the sprite thing because I'm so limited.
Scott: But he stretches.
Scott: he's the only person of all the sprite comics who actually you know does things to the sprites to like stretch out their artistic possibilities.
Scott: He throws in like pictures in the background and you know he makes things all like shiny or you know all kinds of crazy stuff.
Rym: Yeah the other thing is I don't know how he did it but he took these very inanimate sprites and gave each one of them such a unique and obvious personality that it's gotten to the point where if I play Final Fantasy 1 I see Fighter from the comic.
Rym: I don't see Fighter from Final Fantasy 1.
Rym: I don't see whatever I used to come up with when I played that game.
Scott: I mean I used to play.
Scott: I used to play with a freaking black belt but I can't do that now.
Scott: you know speaking of black belt he's in today's guy.
Rym: Yeah he is.
Scott: The other thing though I've noticed about 8-bit theater is that it used to be where there would be like a zing in the final panel right.
Scott: ever since the vernacular zing comic there seem to be more zings per comic.
Rym: I like zing.
Scott: It's just he's gotten better and better at coming up with these great like one line hilarious things and he just loads every comic up with them and they're still funny even if they might be repetitive.
Scott: I hope that lasts.
Rym: Yep plus I went to UberCon last year and I actually had the privilege of meeting Brian Clevenger and he's a cool guy.
Scott: Yeah imagine he's a cool guy.
Scott: I've seen some stuff about him.
Rym: Yep I thought when I first met him like I should ask him for a sketch and I realized he does a sprite comic.
Scott: I don't know if he.
Scott: I don't remember if he had drawing skills or not.
Scott: I'm pretty sure he does.
Scott: Going to get drawing skills and then didn't because he went with the sprite comic and he's lazy.
Rym: You know what though I like the sprite comic.
Scott: Yeah and you need at least something that's you know different from the other stuff.
Rym: Now we're in real life and it's not the best comic in the world but I like it.
Scott: Yeah it's definitely.
Scott: uh the content matter is important.
Scott: The subject matter.
Scott: It's very geeky.
Scott: Yeah and you know the guy comes up with just a geek joke and you know but he's a really cool guy even though I never met him.
Scott: Yeah it's like you read the comic and you know all about this guy and that's kind of the point.
Scott: It's like ah he's a cool geek somewhere and now I know all his stuff.
Scott: Yeah and all his stuff is kind of like my stuff.
Rym: It flows a lot like a newspaper comic a good newspaper comic.
Rym: Yeah I don't know what else.
Rym: what else more I can say about it.
Rym: I mean it's just a generally good comic that I read every day.
Rym: Yeah every day it updates.
Scott: You know what it's not as good as?
Rym: Huh?
Scott: Boases.
Rym: Oh god Boases.
Scott: Boases if Penny Arcade is the number one comic.
Scott: Boases is the number two comic with with no argument at all.
Rym: Boases seems weird because you look at it.
Rym: it's called boy on a stick and slither.
Rym: Boases.
Rym: A boy on a stick and a little snake.
Scott: I like how it comes out where it's boa snake get it?
Scott: I don't think that was intended.
Rym: Uh might have been you don't know.
Scott: Nah.
Rym: It's just a very half the time it's very metaphorical and poignant and half the time it's just silly.
Scott: You know I think even when it's being just silly it's still trying to say something.
Scott: It's just trying to say something less important.
Rym: I gotta tell you though I would have voted for Frickles Mudcat.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Frickles Mudcat for president.
Rym: Several chances.
Scott: Several chances.
Scott: You know Boases is just like instead of drawing.
Scott: it's totally different from every other kind.
Scott: He doesn't draw panels he doesn't you know.
Scott: all he does is he has the stick and the snake standing next to each other saying stuff.
Rym: And random surreal backgrounds and sometimes God appears he's a little uh.
Scott: God is a cloud with a bottle of beer and a cigarette and a lightning for a hand.
Scott: And whenever God appears you know that's a great comic because.
Rym: I don't know I'm a fan of the Florida Cracker.
Scott: I don't like the Florida Cracker.
Rym: I don't like the Florida Cracker but I know people like the Florida Cracker.
Scott: The Florida Cracker could be more funny if he was if he used him a little differently each time instead of using him this kind of the same way.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So every time the Florida Cracker appears all he does is say Florida Cracker people are stupid.
Scott: Doesn't actually.
Rym: Of course he did the same thing with that uh hippie character that he kind of hasn't used in a while.
Scott: You mean Nancy the Tooth?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Nancy the Tooth is never funny.
Scott: That's why Nancy the Tooth doesn't appear anymore.
Rym: Though since we're moving toward the weird comics we move toward probably the weirdest comic.
Rym: A lesson is learned but the damage is irreversible.
Scott: It's not the weirdest comic.
Rym: I think it's probably the weirdest comic I read.
Scott: Okay maybe the weirdest one you read but it's.
Scott: it's not the weirdest comic at all.
Scott: There's plenty of weird freaking comics out there.
Rym: It's very odd and very interestingly drawn and I never would have found it except a friend of mine who is actually also a webcomic artist pointed it to us one day.
Scott: Well they draw it.
Scott: he draws it differently every time.
Rym: Yeah like every comic it updates randomly as far as I can tell.
Rym: Every comic is completely different.
Scott: Yep it's like sometimes they'll have like this really nice painted art and then they'll have this kind of splotchy kind of thing going on that looks like it was like.
Scott: uh you know I don't know the word for it.
Scott: Sometimes they'll have like very few colors.
Scott: Sometimes it'll be crazy colors all over the place.
Scott: Sometimes we panel.
Scott: Sometimes it's just like this kind of like swooshy kind of shape going on.
Rym: And sometimes it's funny.
Rym: Sometimes it's very uh metaphorical.
Rym: Sometimes it's nothing.
Rym: Sometimes the comic will just go and then it ends and you're just left hanging with the sense of why did I read that?
Rym: Nothing happened.
Rym: Yeah but it was still very pretty and you still feel good about reading it.
Scott: Eh some of them I just didn't really feel anything.
Scott: I was like.
Scott: what was that?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah I like it though.
Scott: Yeah it's it's not something that I. uh I check but if there's a new one it's worth the 10 seconds it takes to read the page.
Rym: Yeah of course there's always the Perry Bible Fellowship.
Rym: Which is absolutely hilarious.
Rym: Imagine the far side only a little bit darker in terms of what it's about.
Scott: And like three or four panels.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's still always good.
Rym: Everyone's different and it also updates randomly but.
Scott: I think it updates semi-weekly.
Scott: I think was the the rule.
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: His site has very little text and a lot of pictures.
Scott: The site's very badly designed as a site.
Scott: The comics make it worth suffering.
Rym: It's very creative though.
Rym: It seems like he knew what he was doing HTML wise.
Rym: He just made it weird on purpose.
Scott: I think he's just more of an artist and not a web guy.
Scott: You know what.
Rym: that's excusable because his comic is great.
Scott: I would definitely agree.
Scott: Weaboo.
Rym: Weaboo.
Scott: I mean his comic made like you know the 100 coolest internet things ever list.
Scott: That why I did it a couple podcasts ago.
Scott: It was my thing of the day.
Scott: His comic Weaboo was on there.
Rym: It is.
Scott: Hey.
Rym: So there's one I read and you don't read it called College Roomies from Hell.
Scott: Isn't that just some dumb drama crap?
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: It's been going on for freaking ever.
Rym: And I've been reading it since before I really knew about web comics.
Rym: I've been reading this comic.
Scott: Yeah well Bob and George has been going on for freaking ever.
Scott: That doesn't make any better.
Rym: So you're admitting that Bob and George wasn't funny.
Scott: It was funny at some point.
Rym: See College Roomies from Hell is just.
Rym: it's neat.
Rym: Partly because it's a very dialogue driven character driven comic.
Rym: And the plot it's kind of hard to explain.
Rym: It's just weird.
Rym: And it's been going on for so long that the only way to really understand it is to start from the beginning and read until you catch up.
Rym: And then read it because updates every day.
Rym: And just a couple of panels of character driven comedy drama.
Rym: But the main thing that is going for it is the.
Rym: you know the zings in 8-bit theater times a million.
Rym: And that's what almost all the dialogue is in this comic.
Scott: It seems like all the plot isn't really like an intelligent thoughtful plot.
Scott: It's like a waste of time to read plot.
Rym: No the plot is silly.
Rym: And it doesn't matter because all that matters are the characters.
Rym: And the characters are fantastic.
Rym: Well you don't like anything good so.
Rym: Yeah okay.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: I've got a lot of emotional investment in these characters.
Rym: Just because I've been reading for so long and the characters are so well developed.
Rym: Kind of like 8-bit theater how the characters are so well defined and well developed.
Scott: I read at least one more webcomic.
Scott: Perhaps one of the most recently discovered and most hilarious webcomics there is.
Rym: Oh god there's the new comic we just discovered.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: McNinja.
Scott: That's not it but that's a good one.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: McNinja is about a ninja doctor and that sounds stupid.
Rym: You know what it is stupid.
Rym: But you know what else?
Rym: It's still awesome.
Scott: It's very awesome.
Scott: It's like it's kind of like a space ghost humor going on.
Rym: That's the best way to describe it.
Scott: I think it is exactly space ghost humor which I like.
Scott: Some people don't like it.
Scott: If you don't like space ghost you probably won't like Dr.
Scott: McNinja but.
Rym: It's probably the only space ghost humor I get anymore.
Rym: I don't see space ghost anymore.
Scott: I don't think space goes on anymore but there's.
Scott: I think there's still at least one or two shows on like Adult Swim and some random time that are like it.
Scott: I don't know I don't watch TV.
Scott: It's just a guess.
Rym: Are there DVDs of space ghosts?
Scott: Yeah they put spaces.
Scott: I think the first and second seasons might be out on DVD.
Rym: I think we should uh get all on that.
Scott: Get all Netflix in that house.
Rym: Yeah if we get if we put in our Netflix queue now we'll see him two years from now.
Scott: Of course that's not the comic that I was originally referring to but you did.
Scott: you were correct that it was the most recently discovered one.
Scott: The second most recently discovered one.
Rym: Order of the stick.
Scott: Is infinitely more hilarious than.
Rym: It is a comic about a Dungeons and Dragons campaign and it is full of jokes about Dungeons and Dragons and rules and Dungeons and Dragons.
Rym: However even if you have never played Dungeons and Dragons it's still just as funny.
Scott: Yet my favorite comic is still the one where they walk into the town and it's like adventures are coming.
Scott: adventures are coming and they start boarding up the town like the adventures are going to blow it up which you know is what you would normally think.
Scott: and then oh they're trying to sell things to the adventures at inflated prices because they're loaded with gold.
Scott: but the adventurers love the small towns and it implies that all the small towns do this and it's hilarious.
Scott: But the thing about that the best part jokes in order to the stick that I like is unlike red maid she was just like this kind of blatant I am tweaking guy is like they met a game in the comic.
Scott: but since you never see that the piece you never see the actual people playing these characters.
Scott: you just see the characters the whole time.
Scott: it's like you know or like you'll see this like bard like oh I know I'll use my song to distract them out.
Scott: and then he you know he sings a song like you know bash down the door bash down the door.
Scott: you can do it.
Scott: bash down the door and it doesn't actually help him bash.
Rym: that was the greatest.
Rym: I think the only really funny one with that kind of joke was when he's singing the song to help the other guy move stealthily sneak sneak sneak past the garbs.
Rym: hope they don't hear you sneaking.
Rym: yeah it's a good comic.
Scott: it's very excellent.
Scott: I definitely anticipate it greatly every three times a week but I don't know.
Scott: the guy seems to update later in the day now.
Rym: recently now one comic I used to read of all the old huge comics but it ended quite a while ago was exploitation now which was insanely popular and it was just funny and gooey and it was really good.
Scott: that was not a fan yeah but it was too dirty and it was dirty.
Scott: I'm not a fan.
Rym: it wasn't as dirty as uh thin h line but it was dirty.
Scott: I'm not a fan of the dirty comics.
Rym: but then Michael Poe ended it ended it and now he's doing a new comic called errant story which is a semi-manga styling uh fantasy and it's comedy slash drama and it's not dirty like exploitation.
Rym: I was and you know what it's just a really good solid uh story and the art is most excellent and that was GeekNights with Rym and scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: thanks for listening.
Scott: please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds dot.
Scott: feed burner dot com.
Scott: slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: also please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion.
Scott: and whether you love or hate our podcast we won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.