Rym: It's Monday December 5th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about money, and how not to suck with it.
Rym: Let's do this Yeah, so we had a weekend of super geek up in Albany.
Scott: Super geek played all them board games.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't play a Moisture yeah, and turns out whatever it looks like it could have been the most fun.
Rym: We played a bad board game, and we feel sorry for our friend who bought it.
Scott: Yeah It always.
Scott: it always kind of hurts when you buy something and then you're not gonna use it or someone buys you something and you Don't want it.
Scott: It's it's kind of an ad.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: Now I got a couple of board games.
Rym: I bought that.
Rym: we haven't played in years, so I really can't hate on him too much.
Scott: Yeah, I'm all smart piling my spiel disjars.
Scott: I think I've only got one board game now that no one wants to play hellas hellas.
Rym: We'll be talking about hellas tomorrow because one I broke that game into the games broken independently of me.
Scott: Yeah, it's just busted up.
Scott: Yeah, I can see why.
Scott: now on board game geek There's lots of trading and selling and buying of games You know, but I think I'll stick to you know because I'm into more than just.
Scott: I can see if you're into just games That you would buy and trade and sell all different types of games.
Scott: But when you're someone like me who does a bunch of other stuff and board games You just get the best of the best and screw the rest.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Yeah, so I didn't go to work today.
Rym: Oh, yeah I noticed cuz I woke up and I was about to go through my normal morning routine And then I heard a grumbly noise and lo and behold your home.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you know.
Scott: some people live Maybe you know half-hour from work.
Scott: So if they wake up, you know a little bit late They can still go to work late.
Rym: I show up to work anytime between 7 and like 11.
Scott: Yeah, I wake up at 5 30 in the morning.
Scott: And if I wake up at 7 or later I might as well not go to work because the train ride I'd get to work.
Scott: I'd be there for about three hours and they can know the train ride home and it's not worth it at all.
Scott: It's easier to just work from home.
Rym: I guess it's good though.
Rym: It forces you to wake up.
Rym: I mean, I know I can lay in bed another hour and I often do and then I have to stay at work another hour.
Scott: Yeah, I only messed up a couple times and sometimes there's gotten that 726 train, you know, and I Think you're just a little ill and you seem kind of tired.
Rym: We were trying to watch a ninja movie up in Albany, but you kept falling asleep.
Scott: Well, cuz it was.
Scott: I wouldn't I would have made it if I would have sat up but I laid down and that was it.
Rym: This ninja movie was fantastic.
Rym: We'll have to talk about it.
Scott: All right We saw barely any of it so I can't really talk to him.
Rym: I think we'll have to do a whole podcast on bad ninja movies Mm-hmm, because we have several.
Scott: but anyway during my day at home today.
Scott: I made an Awesome little demo combining some technologies.
Rym: Okay, I take it you use canvas.
Scott: I use the little Firefox canvas and I combined it.
Scott: Well, it's not the Firefox canvas is the HTML canvas element and I combined it with the Ajax HTML HTTP request whatever the hell it's called thing so I can Lively update a drawing surface on a web page from a web application without reloading or anything.
Rym: Did you did you draw a penis?
Scott: No, but I'm sure The point is is that what I can basically do using this technology is if I spend more than a couple hours on it Is I can make an MMO in 3d in a web browser That requires no downloading.
Scott: No installing and no plugins.
Rym: You know, not bad because we've always been bouncing around that idea of an awesome MMO.
Scott: Yeah, basically, I'm just gonna not go that far and make like a board game or something.
Scott: Yeah for now, but if we ever get any more coders to live near us Yeah, because he before you were just restricted to drawing on the web page whatever you could draw with pings and gifs and CSS and HTML.
Scott: now I can draw Anything.
Scott: So it's like oh, yeah My day was great.
Rym: I had to set up a secondary DNS server somewhere and I discovered that the routing path between My network and the network where the real DNS server is is blocking DNS traffic specifically and only DNS traffic Thus present preventing me from doing my job.
Scott: Wait, but if you block DNS traffic right and the DNS traffic on the blocked side if the DNS server on the block side goes Down won't they lose DNS?
Rym: They don't get DNS where I am anyway, because it's blocked.
Scott: Oh There is no DNS server in there.
Rym: No, it's my own private network that I'm using to build some cool thing I can't really talk about but I have to deal with people who don't particularly care if I complete my job.
Rym: Ah It's awesome.
Scott: Totally awesome.
Rym: I just found it great that they blocked only that the one thing I needed.
Rym: everything else is fine.
Scott: Yeah, maybe they knew that was the thing you need and they want to get rid of you.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so it's strike two for Bell South.
Scott: You mean strike three?
Rym: They had a first strike.
Scott: Yeah, they suck.
Rym: I Mean First they do.
Rym: they're crazy, you know Ruined the internet ideas and now They did something really kind of.
Rym: I guess asshole is the only word that can be used to describe this Mm-hmm.
Rym: So they promised New Orleans they were gonna just as a donation rebuild a police station or some building for him.
Rym: Okay, it was a donation.
Rym: They can pick up the tab.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: independent of that New Orleans is offering all the flood victims free Wi-Fi.
Rym: They're trying to build a Wi-Fi network to get people back in touch.
Rym: since the phone lines are all still down.
Rym: Bell South found out about this decided they didn't like the unfair competition Had an wrote an angry letter to New Orleans and rescinded their donation.
Scott: Well, what were they donating?
Rym: They I just said they were gonna repair a building.
Scott: now See I could understand if you're donating some Wi-Fi and they said screw you we have our own that you would rescind your donation.
Scott: maybe donating a building to be nice and then it's like You know.
Scott: the image to the public is that we're donating because we're good people.
Scott: But really the the truth apparently is we're donating because we're basically buying business.
Scott: We're giving you something that we don't need in exchange for business and we don't get the business.
Scott: We're not gonna donate to you.
Rym: even better They rescinded the donation about a couple hours after the city announced his Wi-Fi plans.
Rym: They called him and angrily told them why like just girl you bastards.
Rym: We're not gonna give you our donation now.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Rym: So, uh, I guess Bell South is on the list of things for boycotting.
Scott: yeah Bell South this is a bunch of asshats.
Rym: Yeah, Bell South is right up there.
Rym: But let's see.
Rym: We're boycotting American Greetings still the RA RIA Walmart Target.
Scott: Yeah, except for that whole pharmacy thing, yeah, it's nice but it could be a worse pharmacy thing than their policy.
Scott: Their policy is like the borderline.
Rym: Yeah problem is if we boycott all those stores We can't buy things like floor mats or yeah, and all the stores pretty much have the same deal.
Rym: Yeah, and Walmart is definitely above and beyond in the worst department though Apparently according to my mom who lives in Arizona someone's running these like super anti Walmart ads on television.
Rym: good for them.
Scott: Yeah Now people freaking know but they're gonna still gonna go there because they're freaking dumbasses.
Scott: Okay, or because it's a town where there's no more Stores or because they're so poor they can't afford to go anywhere else.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So Adobe, you know bought macromedia a long time ago.
Scott: Yeah today they finished buying them.
Scott: So now if you go to macromedia.com, you see the red a up in the top left and it's kind of scary Great.
Rym: So what's flash called now?
Scott: It's still called macromedia flash, but we can look forward to in the future is a Single plug-in type thing that encompasses the HTML and the PDFs in the flash and everything.
Scott: It's a one one plug-in to rule them all and in the darkness bind them and you can look forward to like You know getting Photoshop and flash in like a bundle and stuff like that.
Rym: I think we can look forward to paying more money, too.
Scott: You're definitely gonna be looking forward to paying more money because this company.
Scott: basically You know, this is basically three categories of software that I see in all four.
Scott: There's four categories of software in terms of price.
Scott: There's open source free stuff.
Scott: There's the little cheapy bits like, you know, you buy five dollars.
Scott: it you know staples right $50 at staples.
Scott: Then is the big packages like Adobe and macromedia and stuff.
Scott: and then there's the enterprise stuff Which doesn't have a price cuz you
Rym: yeah,
Scott: it's like Oracle you pay a zillion dollars doesn't matter Adobe pretty much that was a monopoly on that third level of software
Rym: Yep, and they seem to buy up things that are in the category down and then put them in that high category and run the old company out of business.
Scott: Yeah, that's always easy because one way to put these guys out of business is you know Photoshop.
Scott: you have the gimp.
Scott: the gimp is free But Photoshop is like $500.
Scott: Yeah, the gimp can almost do everything Photoshop does.
Rym: there's no free flash.
Scott: Yeah A lot of people.
Scott: what they do is they make a program that does almost everything or everything that Photoshop does and as good as the third level software.
Scott: But it only cost them a little bit and they sell it on the second level.
Rym: So Adobe of course goes around and buys them up and yep, I don't know if any of you remember a program called cool edit.
Scott: Yeah, there were a bunch of other ones too.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, there's an awesome awesome program.
Rym: It was cheap and it did a good job of manipulating audio.
Rym: They bought it and they're selling the same product for almost an order of magnitude more money Though someone in the forum pointed out today or yesterday or whenever there was posted that uh My diet or what I eat is scientifically back to be the healthy way to live.
Scott: So there's a New York Times article that you know supported this a long time ago.
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: I just knew it like intuitively.
Scott: In fact, it's called intuitive dieting, isn't it?
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Scott: and then the New York Times came out with an article I love it because like there are things that I kind of know.
Scott: You know and I know because I know the stuff that contradicts it is wrong.
Scott: But I don't.
Scott: I never have evidence that I'm right except for the fact that everything else anyone has said I know is wrong.
Scott: And then I'll find an article on Google News that says Scott was right and I'll be like, yeah They see I was right again and it happened in the New York Times, but now it happened again double-plus
Rym: yep, basically all that all the studies say is that the best way to be healthy and to not be obese and or to lose Weight is to eat everything you crave whenever you crave it and if you're not hungry don't eat.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty confident that anyone who's not fat because of genetic reasons or glandular problems is Simply they eat when they're not hungry.
Rym: or actually a lot of people really really underestimate the number of calories They eat all but some of them don't even think about.
Scott: they don't even have a good like number in their head.
Scott: They don't understand how many calories equals how much fatness is.
Scott: how many you're supposed to eat is how many is in the food?
Scott: They just it just to see your numbers.
Scott: They don't understand it.
Scott: They don't even think about it.
Rym: Well, I did see a study a while ago of people who were obese and who were dieting and counting calories.
Rym: And they were supposed to they eat they eat but they catalog what they eat and then they calculate the calories and they keep it To you know, fifteen hundred two thousand calories a day, whatever and they were still gaining weight.
Rym: So then the scientists had observers follow them around and independently And properly count how many calories they were eating and they were underestimating by an order of magnitude.
Rym: They were eating thousands upon thousands more calories than they thought they were just because they didn't calculate properly.
Rym: They said no idea.
Scott: Well, I mean if you're dumb enough to eat when you're not hungry, you're dumb enough to not be able to do math.
Scott: Yeah, I Don't know.
Scott: I was always cuz.
Scott: I knew that you know.
Scott: my whole life I've been eating all kinds of crap foods and every healthy foods ate like steaks and chocolates and whatever the hell.
Scott: I never thought about health food and health food always tasted bad and I said screw that crap It's not see whatever I crave.
Rym: I mean when I was a kid I craved dr.
Rym: Pepper and I drank, you know Eat whatever.
Scott: I wanted then to live long and eat health food.
Scott: I didn't want.
Scott: so then, you know, I never turned fat.
Scott: So I was like and then I saw fat people and I was like, huh?
Scott: Other than like eating McDonald's or something.
Scott: That's crazy makes you fat.
Scott: What the hell's going on here?
Rym: Well, you know, it's scary.
Rym: when I was in like elementary school I remember there was there was one fat kid in the whole school Like one and ever ever made fun of him and it was kind of sad.
Rym: I felt bad for him.
Rym: There was like the token fat kid.
Rym: Now I walk past elementary school and they're all fat.
Rym: Yeah, like every other kid.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: I see when I was in elementary school There was one kid who was large, but he was generic genetically large like we could sit on his lap.
Scott: He was so large and there was another kid who was it was like fat, but he wasn't fat like Blob you fat he was blood.
Scott: He was like a big guy like hey, what's up?
Scott: Jolly kind of fat.
Scott: There weren't any really like slobbily fat guys in my school But like, you know in high school, there were a few of them that walked around the building.
Scott: I guess I'm not from a big fat area You know, but I see these people in the street.
Scott: No, I see them all over the place.
Rym: I gotta get by him in the tiny hallways in the factory at work.
Scott: Yeah, they're no fat.
Scott: Is there any fat people at my work?
Scott: I Don't think we really hire fat people.
Rym: You hired the chain chomp.
Scott: That's an old lady.
Scott: I think she's been there for a long time.
Scott: Yeah, she has scary teeth.
Scott: That's why they call it the chain chomp.
Scott: so Tomorrow Google is expected to release Google Calendar.
Scott: Ooh No, you know Okay, cool.
Scott: Google new thing, whatever.
Scott: I don't understand the whole calendar thing.
Rym: Some people use calendars.
Rym: I don't I don't.
Scott: what would he would?
Scott: can you not remember what you're doing?
Scott: Are you doing?
Scott: if you're a guy who does so many things that you need a calendar to keep track of like every hour every day because you have a meeting and then a Presentation and then a trip and then an office and then who knows if you need to do that?
Scott: You're big enough and important enough to have someone who does it for you.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: I can see it from a business sense.
Rym: I mean I use my calendar at work exclusive extensively Because people will.
Rym: just I have meetings scheduled all the time all over the place in weird places with weird people And I don't even care enough to remember where to go.
Rym: Yeah, so it's just every day I look in my calendar and says oh I have to meet this guy this time this guy this time.
Rym: But every company that does that gives you some sort of calendaring thing.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I really like Yahoo calendar.
Rym: a lot of people use it.
Rym: I don't yeah.
Scott: I mean like I could see calendar.
Scott: the only use I would have for a calendar is like some sort of event notification like a Page I could go to to look at.
Scott: that would say Here are the things that are.
Scott: I could click on a day or a time and it would tell me if there's anything cool happening.
Scott: It's like I could turn on my blackberry and be like, is there anything cool I can go to?
Scott: right now?
Scott: Here's where I'm at and it would say yeah, there's a cool happening.
Scott: You might like over here, but I don't need a whole calendar application for that.
Rym: Yeah, we don't.
Scott: I just need something where I put in the position and the date and time and it gives me a list of events.
Rym: Like we don't need something to tell us Otakon's coming up because we're thinking about Otakon now.
Scott: yeah, and I don't need something to tell me how to do my everyday stuff because Every day is pretty much almost the same, you know, and I do whatever I want, you know I just go to work do work come home.
Scott: Do what I want go back to work.
Rym: Yeah, well that takes me off.
Rym: I miss the college days where I did crazy difference every day.
Scott: I did a different crazy thing Yeah, but even then I learned my schedule I memorized it and like inside of the week and then nine weeks I had it memorized.
Rym: Like every day was different and it was real easy to skip classes.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I can't skip work But I don't know why.
Scott: can't people remember what they're supposed to do?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe the life hackers should help them out.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: a lot of those life hackers.
Scott: half the stuff they do is Randy.
Rym: Yeah, it's just kind of silly Mm-hmm.
Scott: Oh, I'm sure a lot of people use the Google Calendar.
Scott: It'll let people.
Scott: at least let people share what they're doing so you could look and see what your friends doing.
Rym: But yeah, but I don't like that for the same reason.
Rym: I don't like LiveJournal, but I'm not hating on it because a lot of people we know use LiveJournal, but basically, what I've seen is that a lot of people I know who have a LiveJournal if You like if you fall out of contact with them and you don't talk to them every day like you used to Instead of talking to them to find out what they're doing They just they post everything their LiveJournal and you can be friends with someone for years after you stop talking to them And you'll still know exactly what they're up to and they'll know what you're up to.
Rym: but you never talk anymore And when you talk to each other you have nothing to say Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't like that.
Scott: I'm not a fan of LiveJournal.
Rym: In fact, I make a point of not reading people's LiveJournals.
Scott: I won't read.
Scott: Oh, it's not LiveJournal the system.
Scott: That's a problem, but I won't read a LiveJournal.
Scott: if there's a thing that happens to be on the LiveJournal system I don't care, but I won't read a LiveJournal the way other people do though.
Rym: Actually, it leaves a lot of interesting conversations.
Rym: I call a friend I haven't talked to in a long time like hey, what's up?
Rym: And they say oh Read my LiveJournal and I say I don't what even up to.
Rym: and then they talk to me for an hour instead of just you Know, I don't know hanging up Sending me a link to their LiveJournal.
Scott: Yeah, I just don't call people unless I have something to say to them.
Rym: Hey there quagmire.
Rym: Hey, what you doing?
Scott: Nothing you called me Mm-hmm.
Rym: Granted I do that a lot.
Rym: I actually talk on the phone quite a bit woman.
Rym: Yeah, what can I say?
Rym: I'm very European woman.
Rym: I'm very continental European guys.
Scott: Don't do that.
Scott: Hey there hate to tell you.
Rym: Actually according to a lot of studies they have tests of you know masculinity and femininity and the American idea of masculinity is Far different from the European idea.
Scott: Oh, of course, of course.
Scott: But European guys still don't just call other European guys and say hey what you doing?
Rym: Actually, they do not a lot but more often than Americans who seem to avoid any contact with other males.
Rym: That doesn't involve drinking or sports.
Scott: Yeah, that's some but you know, not all and we're seeing that change.
Scott: a Lot of people are hanging it out doing all kinds of other stuff.
Scott: Well, at least geeks are well At least the Internet's bringing them together.
Rym: Yeah, but all the people who aren't on the internet boat Yep, all right.
Rym: So my thing of the day.
Rym: I found this last week and I've been keeping it until now.
Rym: I Found this video of a dancing puppet skeleton.
Rym: It's some good puppeting it's just it's a little puppet and it's really really emotive and realistic.
Rym: and the funniest part is when he looks into the little Donation hat and doesn't see any money in there and starts crying and then some lady gives him some money and then he's a little dance Whoo There's really not much more I can say about it.
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: Follow the link.
Scott: Mm-hmm my thing of the day.
Scott: So remember you were looking for some slippers recently.
Scott: I was eventually were complaining that every store only had one type of slippery.
Rym: Yeah, every store had like 50 million kinds of slippers for women and in the men's section of one ugly moccasin looking thing.
Scott: Yeah, you finally found some though.
Rym: Yeah, I paid too much actually.
Rym: No, I didn't find some.
Rym: no My girlfriend's father gave me some That he happened to have lying around.
Scott: awesome, but well if you would have waited until today you would have found out that that company that makes the Cthulhu plushie toys.
Rym: No way plushie slipper HP Lovecraft is spinning in his grave tentacles to keep your feet warm.
Rym: How much are they?
Rym: 30 bucks?
Rym: That's pretty badass.
Scott: Oh, oh, it's out of stock.
Rym: Great I guess I think today didn't beat park slash dot whoever the hell found it before we did.
Scott: Yeah Well, I'm sure you'll see them at your next gaming convention game store where they sell your Plushie products.
Rym: Yeah, probably overpriced as those things tend to be.
Rym: but what are you gonna do?
Rym: Yeah Considering that we have a kid.
Scott: It looks like to be the same quality as the actual plushie toy, which is high quality.
Scott: Yeah, only I think the plushie toy was 40 bucks.
Scott: So this being 30 and you get two of them.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: But we have a lot of high quality weird plushies like that.
Rym: You wouldn't expect us.
Rym: We got the Cactuar.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, it's it's all about the high quality plushie.
Rym: So moving on from our main bit.
Scott: It's time for another edition of how not to suck.
Scott: how not to suck at money.
Rym: Oh the greens the gold the Platinum's the doubloons the rupees Yeah, so Scott found an article that he'll talk about in a minute.
Rym: and Basically, we discovered that despite the fact that from my perception I piss money away on stupid things on a regular basis
Scott: and I buy freaking every video game I see
Rym: I just head down to the city on a train like all the time and eat food out constantly.
Scott: I drive places when I know it'd be cheaper to take a train or vice versa and Buy food.
Scott: just yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I know that vending machines a ripoff, but I don't care.
Rym: We had two expensive dinners in two days over the weekend, and I'm still just fine Yep, but apparently a lot of people really really suck at dealing with money.
Scott: Uh Just about everybody.
Scott: So I read this article.
Scott: I think it was business week or some other one of those magazines I don't really remember because I didn't go to work today where it was in the bathroom.
Rym: Yeah, you found it in the bathroom in the bathroom.
Scott: They replaced the nice Forza magazine with the Ferraris in it.
Scott: I'm kind of upset, but anyway Hey, we're talking about how.
Scott: you know people are having a hard time these days with debt.
Scott: You know they go to school they get these student loans.
Scott: You know then they have to pay 200 $300 a month.
Scott: You know their jobs don't pay so much They're just pay more than ours.
Scott: And You know and and these people?
Scott: it said that the average credit card debt For people between the ages of 24 and 34 25 and 35 or something around there was fifty four hundred dollars.
Scott: good god now They gave examples of people and the first example was a lady who made sixty thirty year old lady who made sixty thousand dollars a year.
Scott: She had to be three hundred dollars a month for student loans.
Scott: her loan was the same size as mine But mine is two hundred a month.
Scott: But I I'll be paid off before I'm 30 if I just make the payments and don't do anything else.
Scott: Yeah, right, and it was like oh if you get a master's degree.
Scott: You're screwed even more, but you know not so much.
Scott: and Somehow her making let's see 33% more money than me.
Scott: and Oh my money plus 50% is how much he makes.
Scott: and then Paying less.
Scott: you know about the same amount for student loans and things.
Scott: she has fifty four hundred dollars of credit card debt.
Scott: Where'd that come from?
Rym: yeah like what do people spend their money on?
Rym: I buy stupid crap?
Rym: I buy anime and just garbage constantly, and I still have plenty of money, and I make far less money than these people.
Scott: yeah Well the number one rule of how not to suck with money Don't live above the means.
Rym: Yeah, yep, yep, yep.
Scott: too many people.
Scott: they decide on what their level of living is.
Scott: you know they say I am a person who lives in a car in a house with four bedrooms in a two-car garage and two SUVs Regardless of how much money they make.
Scott: if you do it that way Unless you happen to be making more money than that you know then you're in a big pooper.
Scott: Yeah, you got to look at how much money you make and then decide how well you're gonna live.
Scott: You know based on the money.
Scott: if you only make 30 G's you got to live a 30 G lifestyle or else you're gonna be poor real real soon Plus just poor decisions in general like say you want an Xbox 360.
Rym: If you buy it now you pretty much have to buy the full-on bundle and you're out a whole shit ton of money.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: if you wait till like February and you buy one You'll probably be better off.
Scott: Yeah, and what are you gonna gain by buying it now?
Scott: if you buy it now You'll gain a tiny bit of social currency for like maybe a week or two.
Scott: You know people coming to your house to go ooh and a bunch of crap launch games.
Scott: of course It might backfire on you.
Scott: people might go out.
Scott: Here's the poser trying to get one real quick.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: what are you really paying if you buy it on eBay for $1,000?
Scott: What is that really doing for you?
Rym: You mean you know how many were sold on eBay.
Scott: you're paying 800.
Scott: You know maybe $600 more than you know what the thing normally costs or what you could buy it for.
Scott: You know in a couple months from now Dollars or $800 worth of stuff out of that.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I mean for 800 bucks.
Rym: I could live it up.
Scott: Oh man for 800 bucks.
Scott: Wow Wow, I could buy.
Rym: I'd buy every anime box that I've been waiting for for a long time and every board game I've ever wanted and I'd have a lot money left.
Scott: Yeah, I'd gain interest on it in the bank.
Scott: What else?
Scott: one of the mistakes do people make with money uh?
Rym: Don't buy a car if you don't need one.
Scott: don't buy an SUV.
Scott: well Don't buy a car that uses more gas than you can afford or cost more than you can afford And don't drive it if you don't have to.
Scott: Like.
Scott: you know just because it might be convenient don't drive up and down the road ten times a day.
Scott: go all out at once.
Scott: You know cuz gas is a lot a lot of money that adds up if you keep using the car.
Scott: and You know no matter how much fun you might think the SUV is or how trendy you think you'll be.
Scott: guess what you're not gonna Stand out in a sea of SUVs.
Scott: It's cheaper to buy a freaking like Ford Mustang sports car and more fuel-efficient than to buy a Ford Explorer.
Rym: You can get a freaking Lotus Elis a for not that much money.
Scott: Yeah, you can get a Lotus Elis a is 40 G's.
Scott: a Ford Explorer I think is 40 G's or maybe 30, but you know it's only like five to ten thousand dollars more.
Scott: But you'll save that money in gas in a year.
Scott: if you use the car free Lotus as just a Toyota Celica engine and it weighs nothing You use barely any gas it goes really fast, and you can turn on a dime.
Scott: You can't take anything with you besides you and maybe a passenger Maybe you and a grocery that has more space into the friggin mr.
Rym: 2 spider.
Scott: yeah, and if you got a big family You know you can get a minivan even though you'll be uncool.
Scott: Yeah, okay sure you'll be slightly uncool.
Scott: is being Uncool is being cooler worth ten thousand dollars.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: yeah I'll tell you what I could buy a ten thousand dollars worth of cool.
Rym: That wouldn't include a big car.
Scott: Yeah, think about this.
Scott: if you buy a minivan instead of an SUV right you can get all those fancy minivan features like.
Scott: it Has little TV players in there and stuff right.
Scott: you'll still save 10 G's.
Scott: You can use the 10 G's to buy a projector in your house in a home theater, and then you'll be wicked cool.
Rym: Like our friend Alex he drives a minivan around and we're always glad when he comes cuz we can all pile into it and go Do geekery.
Scott: yeah, don't be you know a stupid fashion type person buying like you know the $300 jeans or anything.
Scott: You know.
Scott: you pay for labels you pay for cool.
Scott: You're gonna pay.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: one big big thing you can do is you know not have cable TV anymore?
Rym: Yeah, that costs a lot of money.
Scott: cable TV does cost a lot of money.
Scott: I mean the family.
Scott: a lot of you have the family basic basic plan Which is still $40 a month you know but?
Scott: Anyone who gets more channels than that?
Scott: I see people paying a hundred two hundred a month doesn't matter satellite or cable either Yep, and they only watch maybe like one or two channels or they TiVo a bunch of stuff.
Scott: You just get a myth TV.
Rym: You don't have to pay the TiVo bill yeah, and Netflix is like less than 20 bucks a month and It's more movies than we'll ever have time to watch.
Scott: and the other thing is if you're not spending all your time watching TV Maybe you can spend your time doing other things You know.
Scott: maybe make some money or learn some skills that might get you a raise at your job, or you know.
Rym: granted I don't think many of our listeners watch much TV anyway.
Rym: That's good You know.
Rym: at least I would assume you know when we were kids.
Rym: we watch a lot of TV.
Scott: That's kind of why you know I stopped watching TV when I got to college.
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of why podcasts are so great.
Scott: so I can still get some sort of push programmed media But it's interesting and targeted to me And I don't have to actually stop doing what I'm doing on the computer to do it.
Scott: like if I have to visit a web Page I have to stop working.
Scott: podcast goes right through work simultaneous.
Scott: I like it.
Scott: TV can't do anything.
Scott: while you're watching TV I can play like Mario Kart yeah But then you're not really getting the TV at all.
Rym: you're just playing Mario Kart because there's so much to get ever since.
Rym: uh You know every good show was cancelled.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, the Simpsons is still going.
Scott: something else You can get rid of is your home telephone.
Scott: Haha, just go for the cell phone alone, and don't have a phone line in your house.
Scott: You don't need it.
Rym: Yeah, right we haven't had a phone line since college And that's just because they gave us one.
Rym: we didn't pay for it.
Scott: sure even if you had one Have you used it for years and years and years?
Scott: It's only a slight pain in the ass to change it you know and then once you change it You're changed and now you can use your cell phone for everything.
Scott: yeah Cell phones definitely cheaper also for the long distance.
Scott: if you call anyone far away No gouging.
Rym: I don't think I've ever paid long distance on a phone ever.
Rym: I've had a cell phone pretty much as long as I've used phones for things.
Rym: My first cell phone was one of those giant bricks that lasted about 45 minutes if you actually tried to talk on it.
Rym: My mom got it for me because she thought it would keep me secure or safe or something in case I ever got in a car accident.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I still have it laying around somewhere Mmm.
Scott: Oh oh the number one way to save money when you do have to buy things even though they may be expensive is To do lots and lots of research and not be dumb.
Rym: Yeah, well that just boils down to.
Rym: don't listen to the guy at Best Buy He doesn't know what he's talking about.
Scott: yeah like when you go to buy a car Don't buy a car cuz it's cool.
Scott: Don't buy a car because the dealer tells you to do your own Research on the internet and in books and things and what is good for you and decide based on that.
Scott: Completely ignore anything superficial like brand and color and whatever.
Rym: And well I care about matters.
Scott: well, okay, yeah, but You know what I'm saying?
Rym: More importantly be an asshole.
Rym: once you find what you want go and get that and don't settle for less.
Rym: Yeah, walk into the car.
Rym: dealer pointed a car and say give me that one for this price.
Rym: if they say no walk away.
Scott: Yep, no one had.
Scott: you don't have to do what anyone says.
Scott: you're the guy with the money.
Scott: You're buying stuff.
Scott: if they don't want to sell it to you give them the finger.
Scott: You know when you go to buy.
Scott: what else is a big purchase?
Scott: if you're gonna buy a computer Don't buy a computer from Dell.
Scott: don't get the little insurance plans.
Scott: don't buy the accessories.
Scott: Just figure you know.
Scott: go online Figure out what kind of computer you need and buy the cheapest one you can get.
Scott: If you can't build one your own you can still get someone to build one for you, or you know I mean you're geeks.
Rym: you got to know a geek who can build a computer.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like I look on Dell comm and I see a computer for like a thousand dollars.
Scott: I could build it for three hundred dollars And it would be better and faster, and you'd never need to upgrade it ever.
Scott: you know that thousand dollar Dell is missing pieces never upgraded ever.
Scott: eh Well, I guess if you didn't want to play games.
Scott: You wouldn't have to upgrade it ever.
Rym: Grant I'm still running a freaking Thunderbird gigahertz.
Scott: yeah see there you go.
Rym: is the last game I cared about?
Rym: they came out was counter-strike.
Scott: Oh speaking of games don't play a game with any sort of subscription service or get addicted to anything.
Scott: well specifically Yeah, well those are the games you can get addicted to.
Scott: don't do drugs either.
Scott: drugs will take away all your money.
Rym: Yeah, I remember the the geeky fable about Duane.
Rym: Yeah, I don't want to be Duane.
Scott: Yeah Anything that addicts people I mean even like Farc.
Scott: well FARC doesn't cost money.
Rym: well as it does you pay or cost money if you lose your job because all you do is Read FARC.
Scott: Yeah, well don't pay for FARC.
Scott: I guess you're not paying for it.
Rym: That's a lot of people pay for total FARC.
Rym: Yeah, it's probably not a good idea Now if you have trouble Closing your web browser now.
Rym: Don't get total FARC He'll just sit there until you starve.
Scott: He has a good example of when to know to pay for something and when not to let.
Scott: I played puzzle pirates when it was Like beta and free.
Scott: cuz I hear free and I like pirates.
Scott: Yeah, it was a good game And I had some funny fun puzzles in.
Scott: it wasn't like an MMO where you level up.
Scott: It was just puzzles all right and money collection, but you can get money so easily.
Scott: it wasn't even like a contest.
Scott: And then it was.
Scott: they said pay 50 bucks for like two three years.
Scott: So I'm like all right.
Scott: 50 bucks is what I usually pay for a video game And I usually play a video game for maybe a year.
Scott: if not if not even like a few months all right.
Scott: So 50 bucks for three years.
Scott: That's like a freaking deal.
Scott: It's I paid for it And then it ran out and I stopped playing long before it ran out as I expected and I stopped playing.
Scott: If an MMO was like pay $50 a year.
Scott: I'd be like no Because the formula of that is a dick to you.
Scott: and take your money.
Scott: take your money take your money take your money take your Money.
Rym: yep, they do that with talk with total FARC - cuz I had FARC.
Rym: I read FARC a lot more than I should I post on it a lot and one day someone sponsored me for total FARC.
Rym: some Total Farker must have liked me enough or hated me enough to spend money to give me total FARC for a month.
Rym: Wow oh my god There were just a million.
Rym: I basically was infinite entertainment Infinite news constantly.
Rym: it was a sea of updating.
Scott: So not only will that take away your job, but and your money Hey, it just ruined you.
Scott: yeah Wow No really yeah really Volcano look yeah, don't spend your time making photoshops, and you're supposed to be working anything.
Rym: Yeah quiet I thought my Asian bird flu haha guy was hilarious.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: oh Another good way not to lose money is It's okay to have like you know a hobby, but don't get into a hobby.
Scott: That's like collecting Expensive useless things.
Scott: I know a lot of people.
Scott: you know where.
Scott: otherwise They're just perfectly good people, but they have an infinite number of like PVC robots Yeah, or they'll spend their time collecting comic books, and they'll go and they'll spend like a thousand dollars for comic book.
Scott: You know it's like all right.
Scott: I understand You know collecting you want to have a nice collection, and you know show it off, and it makes you feel good.
Scott: But when it comes to something like you know a statue Well you can just get the replica of the statue or the look thing that looks the same and does the same things But isn't the original?
Scott: for much less you know and no one will know or care except you Just get over it and you can save yourself a freaking fortune.
Rym: Yeah, or be like our friend Scott Johnson.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you a video game.
Rym: some of them are good enough.
Rym: you buy them on opening day like they come out and you Immediately take how many beat it.
Scott: that's usually just cuz.
Scott: I have no other games left and when a new one comes out I can go get it, but most games wait and buy him in the discount bin for like five bucks.
Rym: Say with anime our friend Scott Johnson every time we go to a convention We we all leave with you know we go to the dealer's room.
Rym: We buy crap.
Rym: He'll leave with like 50 DVDs and a giant sack of crap.
Rym: And then we ask him how much he spent and it's almost nothing because he pretty much just rooted around in bargain bins and bought Yesterday's hotness.
Scott: yep, I mean he gets you know.
Scott: you look at the individual deals there And it's like you know get five for the price of three, and you're like all right.
Scott: But when he keeps going around getting every single deal starting from the best going to like you know like a limit And then when you look at the sum total, it's like he got 60% off the total price of things.
Rym: It's like wow granted the drawback of that is we were subjected to some bad anime as a result of him.
Scott: Yeah What was that one called?
Scott: Oh?
Scott: God Super Atrogan, I was okay Was he?
Scott: definitely I could have done without it.
Scott: Yes wasn't a bad anime though.
Scott: anyway Don't give your money to homeless people on the street.
Rym: don't give your money to a Scientologists.
Scott: Yeah, don't join a cult.
Scott: Don't give your money to wacky religion.
Scott: Don't give your money to pretty much anything unless You you're getting something out of it, or you know it's you know a charity.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: Yeah, like if you're gonna give to a charity give to like the Red Cross.
Rym: Yeah, don't give to the United Way.
Rym: Yeah, well actually get into that some other podcast, but Red Cross good United Way bad.
Rym: You don't deserve.
Rym: okay UNICEF's all right.
Scott: if you're gonna give money to like something like Child's Play, right?
Scott: You know it's good to give the Child's Play or Red Cross, but don't give more than you got.
Rym: yeah You know like actually the worst thing to give your money to is the Salvation Army.
Scott: Yeah, Salvation Army very bad.
Rym: They spend most of their money on administrative garbage and paying their own employees And they spend the rest buying various religious implements to convert people Like they'll go to a starving African village and bring Bibles instead of food.
Rym: That's not cool not cool at all and there's nothing to do with the fact that it's Christian.
Rym: I mean they could be bringing anything other than food, and I'd be equally pissed.
Scott: yep Let's See what all the things do people spend their money on.
Scott: that's dumb.
Rym: Yeah, do I just turn them to a list of things that are dumb to spend money on because that's pretty much everything.
Scott: yeah Oh, well, here's here's a good thing.
Scott: Don't get a loan for something.
Scott: That's just like stupid.
Rym: Okay, great advice there.
Scott: Well.
Scott: You know a lot of people.
Scott: they go and like you know they've already got a loan here And they've already got a mortgage there And you know and then they want to make like addition to their house.
Scott: So they get another loan.
Scott: just leave without the freaking addition.
Scott: you can't afford it.
Rym: You've already got a loan or maybe you can't afford it, and then you get it.
Rym: It's just live within your means.
Scott: It's that simple yeah, but specifically with loans because they have the big interest.
Scott: if you get a lot of money You know you want to pay off that.
Scott: you know the loan real quick Faster if you know than it's supposed to be.
Scott: if you don't pay a crap ton of interest a lot of times They'll trick you with those payments.
Scott: You know and a lot of people aren't quick enough to realize oh The interest adds up to like you know $5,000 over.
Rym: well the worst thing you can do.
Rym: or like there are lower loans And then there are negative amortization loans, and then there are balloon loans.
Rym: And basically these are loans.
Rym: well you'll owe more at the end than you did at the start.
Rym: Loans where you have a low monthly payment, and then after two years you suddenly owe a one-time payment of like 20 grand.
Rym: Yeah, because you weren't paying down the interest.
Rym: Mm-hmm Money-making schemes are all BS, but you know that.
Rym: yeah if anyone says you know you can get rich quick You'd think oh, that's obvious don't fall for a money-making scheme, but we've had a lot of Fairly smart friends put money into stupid stupid things.
Scott: Mm-hmm I fell for a money-making scheme in middle school once.
Scott: oh really well It was just.
Scott: it was contest to win a bunch of games called pandemonium.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: and they put an advertisement in the video game magazine That was that showed like a giant TV and every video game system and a giant stereo And it looked freaking out and a satellite dish and everything and all you had to do to enter the contest Was send in this little puzzle that was in the magazine, and it was the simplest puzzle ever.
Scott: and I said all right I sent it in with free.
Scott: then they sent me a thing back and said fill out this puzzle and send us a dollar.
Scott: and I said and they're like there are five puzzles And I calculated the increase in difficulty of the puzzle that this one wasn't so much more difficult than the previous one.
Scott: So I'm like all right.
Scott: It's only a dollar.
Scott: if the next one sucks.
Scott: I won't send it again, right What's it gonna cost?
Scott: five bucks?
Scott: Yeah, the next one came and these people were so good and I was such an impressionable middle school kid that It was.
Scott: it was harder, and I felt like it was harder.
Scott: But I was smart enough to figure it out because I was a smart guy and it was five bucks.
Scott: So I'm like yeah five bucks whatever who cares all right?
Scott: What?
Scott: I didn't have anything to spend five bucks on in those days except like a pack of Magic cards Which were also a ripoff?
Scott: It wasn't safe.
Scott: It wasn't waste any money.
Scott: those other waste money.
Scott: They're wasting money somewhere else.
Scott: So they sent me the fourth one which is really freaking hard But I finally got it after like many hours and help from people and they said send ten bucks.
Scott: So I'm like there's only one more.
Scott: how much could the last one be?
Rym: was the last one a hundred dollars?
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: the last one is 15 bucks, right?
Scott: So they got 15 plus 10 plus 5 plus 1 so 25 30 31 dollars.
Scott: I sent them which is not so bad, but the last puzzle pretty much.
Scott: they said they had a big open square.
Scott: it was just a grid and They had point values assigned to letters of the alphabet all the letters of the alphabet And you had to completely fill this grid right with words in every single possible direction filling every single square and I think it was like a 10 by 10 grid and you also had to get the highest possible score.
Scott: and Oh, so I filled out the whole thing using as many Z words as I could because I think it was.
Scott: I think Z was A big one and like Q is a big one, you know I take it.
Rym: you didn't win the amazing pile of awesome.
Scott: Do I have an amazing pile of awesome?
Rym: No, you do not.
Scott: Do I have a neogeo?
Scott: Have an original game boy to have a Sega Saturn to have an original game boy.
Scott: Do I have a 3do?
Scott: I have?
Scott: no I have never known anyone who had none of these things are things that I have?
Scott: I don't have a 50 inch rear projection TV in a satellite dish and a 5,000 watt stereo or anything because it was a scam.
Rym: good game.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I never fell for a scam again.
Rym: I had a couple of friends in high school who fell for this Amway scam.
Rym: We did one of those thick abs where you sell crap on a website that you buy from someone else.
Rym: It's not really a pyramid scheme.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's a direct marketing crap.
Scott: Yeah, anyone who says that you can make money by selling their stuff.
Scott: That's a scam.
Rym: Anyone who says you can make money and doesn't offer you an hourly wage is a scam.
Scott: Yeah, you know those pieces of paper you see hanging there like, you know big money work from home You know Thousands of dollars.
Scott: that's all scams.
Scott: every single last one of them.
Scott: There's not a single one.
Scott: That is not a scam.
Rym: Don't forget Nigerian scams.
Scott: Oh, I don't think anyone's gonna fall for a Nigerian scam.
Rym: a lot of people still fall for them.
Scott: That's like the obvious scam.
Scott: chop your dollar.
Scott: I had to get that in real quick the dollar chopping.
Rym: Yeah, so we're sorry if this uh, all this talk of money and Responsibility and crap was boring, but we were just really kind of pissed off about that article.
Rym: Yeah, because there's someone who's just like us.
Rym: They make more money.
Scott: They're not geeks though.
Rym: Yeah, they're not geeks, but they don't have any dependents.
Rym: No kids No family to take care of.
Rym: they're making a lot more money than us and yet they're somehow Struggling and can't make ends meet.
Rym: that's really an insult to the people in the world who really can't make ends meet.
Scott: I know it's like I can't buy food.
Scott: Are you so Greedy and and whatnot that you have to have all these fancy things.
Scott: They're whatever you're spending your money on that God.
Rym: yeah, God course.
Rym: then we have like our one friend who couldn't afford to eat and Then he got all his student loan money and he bought a drum set And then he didn't have any money to eat.
Rym: Yeah, and then a friend of his felt sorry told the story before we did.
Rym: we told that story told that story.
Rym: Ah, did we actually tell her?
Rym: do we tell her one of the beta podcast?
Scott: It might have been in a beta podcast.
Scott: Oh, yeah Don't be that guy either.
Rym: Yeah Well onto a meta bit We do have a bunch of old terrible podcasts that we might publish someday if you guys want to hear them.
Rym: Yeah, like when we decided to do a podcast and we took this crap logitech like microphone and stuck it in the middle of The room and real sad on opposite sides of the room.
Scott: It sounds like everyone else's podcast.
Scott: Yeah Doesn't have a mixer or anything fancy completely unedited.
Rym: We screw up a lot.
Scott: It's basically just.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's raw the raw deal.
Scott: Yeah, the rawest raw raw Like meat that's uncooked.
Scott: Remember the other raw meat analogy that went too far Huh?
Scott: No, there's like a raw steak analogy.
Scott: I used for something.
Rym: No, I don't remember that at all.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Oh remember is about arguing like I'm trying to cook this steak.
Scott: You don't let me finish.
Scott: Then I throw this raw steak at you.
Rym: Yeah, you know people who can't make analogies shouldn't?
Scott: Yeah?
Scott: Yeah Don't make an analogy book.
Scott: if you don't whatever god damn it.
Scott: I tried to tie that into money and I fucked up.
Rym: Yeah, don't worry tomorrow be all good cuz it's a gaming day and we got a lot of gaming to talk about.
Scott: Oh, we got so much gaming.
Scott: It might float over next week.
Rym: Yeah, we I mean I I had to really check myself from talking about the gaming today.
Rym: Oh Yeah.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we played some games.
Scott: We got some.
Scott: We're gonna talk about tomorrow.
Scott: they look forward to us talking about the card game Varetha Yep, and more terror my turn what we still have to play.
Scott: that.
Scott: so we'll probably talk about that again.
Rym: But we at least know how it works.
Scott: We definitely know how it works.
Rym: We got Hellas Hellas.
Rym: We hate it.
Rym: I'm undefeated at it.
Rym: I still hate it as Tower of Babel.
Rym: Yeah, these are all German games.
Scott: so far I got Mario Luigi.
Scott: Oh Mario and Luigi what other video we have another video game that came.
Rym: No, no new video game.
Scott: yet, I guess that's the new video game is Mario and Luigi Super.
Scott: it's not Superstar Saga.
Scott: It's partners in time, which I didn't play at all today cuz I was home from work.
Rym: Huh get some playing tomorrow on the train All right, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds dot feed burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: Also, please visit our website at www.front row crew comm for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.