Scott: It's Wednesday December 28th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We talk about Lupin's essay Galaxy Express 999 the first original movie and Samurai Champloo.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So no one's really in my office.
Rym: this week everyone took vacation except me and one Indian guy is pretty cool.
Scott: People are in my office, but the train is kind of empty Except for this morning when one of the trains didn't show and then we had twice as many people on the next train And it was kind of sucky Though my co-worker.
Rym: He uh he gave me a gift.
Rym: That's either going to kill me or be awesome And I won't know until New Year's when I actually try to use this gift.
Scott: It's probably some sort of poison alcohol or something.
Rym: well the thing is I I very much enjoy my wine, and I very much enjoyed port.
Rym: Scott doesn't but I'm not Scott and This guy had this old old old bottle.
Rym: It's about seven years old since he got it and it aged for many years before that and it's a South African port wine.
Rym: tawny and Basically, it's an only port wine is weird because there's sediment and crap in it like floating around.
Rym: it looks like there's dirt floating around and you got a decanted all this weird stuff to drink it and This is an old expensive cool bottle of port and I'm gonna open it on the new year And if it doesn't kill me I'll have something to say about it next Monday.
Scott: It'll be pretty hilarious if you know you like.
Scott: you open it And then you barf and then you try to drink it in your barf, and it's just poison Can't be worse than whatever that spoiled liquor was.
Rym: your parents had those on.
Scott: my grandpa had it was.
Scott: I don't know what it the hell.
Scott: They called it, but it's his weird yellow stuff, and it's just wow.
Rym: what do they say?
Scott: There's only one drink you can make with it, but my dad said there's only one drink You can make with it, and he's probably right cuz he knows a lot about that.
Rym: It Yeah, so in real news You know a while ago.
Rym: We made a big deal about this Windows exploit where Internet Explorer you could get screwed.
Rym: There's another one that's Worse.
Scott: how could it be worse than visit a website?
Scott: your computer is rooted.
Scott: nothing you can do about it.
Rym: It's visit a website your computer is rooted, and it's harder to patch it or work around it.
Rym: great Basically windows, there's this file format a Wmf a Windows metafile.
Scott: I thought those are Windows media files.
Rym: I heard when the Schlosshauer says Windows metafile whatever and they can contain media.
Rym: they can also contain viruses and Firefox won't protect you nor will opera.
Rym: no well it nor will anything.
Scott: so it's in the code in Windows that that processes these files No matter what program opens the files.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: There is no patch.
Rym: There is really nothing you can do about it.
Rym: So if you're running Windows Don't go to suspicious websites for at least the next month until a patch comes out.
Rym: You're kind of hosed.
Scott: So remind me why people use Windows again.
Rym: They don't know better.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I Mean unless you play games you have no reason to use Windows anymore.
Rym: Because I mean like just the other day when we over New Year's We had our Scott's grandma had an old lady friend who needed help with her computer And we went over there to try to you know fix it or whatever was wrong with it and It just had viruses and there's really no way to fix it.
Scott: Yeah, and the virus is a disabled Norton so he couldn't use Norton We.
Scott: she was on dial-up so he couldn't really download any tools to help us.
Scott: We didn't have any tools with us and It changed her home page, which kind of confused her but really there was nothing protecting her from getting more viruses at this point.
Scott: and And Then we couldn't clean them up short of formatting the hard drive installing windows again Yeah, and for what she did which is like visit one website do email and word process.
Scott: Linux would have been more than enough 10,000 times more than enough.
Rym: in fact in January most likely we're gonna head back down there Give her Linux and we'll probably have a full report on us converting two cool old ladies to Linux.
Scott: Yeah, my other grandma uses Linux already because I just gave her a computer but They don't know how to use it, but this grandma would know how to use a computer better, so we'll see.
Rym: yeah But I'm starting to see.
Rym: I mean a lot of people like whenever there's a big exploit I a lot of apologists seem to always say things like oh Yeah, this was just one bad thing and then Microsoft patches it.
Rym: you haven't noticed.
Rym: This has been happening on a regular basis for the last couple of years with increasing frequency.
Scott: yeah, the other thing is that people like okay, they've patched most of the exploits or whatever but That's only if you're like a company or something and you maintain your windows And you put a lot of effort into it and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, you can get it to be usable and Relatively perfect or even perfect as perfect as windows can be.
Scott: but Linux.
Scott: You don't have to do Anything.
Scott: it just is even a shitty.
Scott: old Linux might be shitty But he won't fuck up.
Rym: I mean there are a few exploits for old versions of Linux like Red Hat 5 had a bunch of exploits But you're not flying around the net crazily.
Scott: you won't get them just visiting websites.
Scott: Not that I'm you know Planning on using blu-rays or HD DVDs or anything anytime soon because you know I don't have an HDTV and I probably won't get one.
Scott: and You know I'm probably not gonna get a PlayStation 3.
Scott: So It's not like I care, but if one of the formats has to win out.
Scott: It looks like it's gonna be blu-ray.
Scott: now.
Scott: blu-ray supposedly has more space to store more stuff which I guess is good and Supposedly it has DRM, but HD DVD also has DRM.
Rym: So they're both bad, and we're really rooting for DVD John to on DRM it real quick DVD on become blu-ray on.
Scott: but Apparently the reason I think blu-ray is gonna win is because today we found out that it's gonna have regioning which you know I guess is some sort of necessary evil nowadays, but no it's not a necessary evil.
Rym: That's horseshit.
Scott: Well.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah It's just an evil.
Rym: Yeah exists solely to limit supply Segment markets and make profits for the company.
Rym: It has no benefit other than to the company that designed it and implemented it.
Scott: Yeah pretty much, but Japan and the US on blu-ray will both be region one Which means really?
Scott: That a lot of things.
Scott: I mean how are they gonna sell Japanese anime DVDs for 40 bucks and American ones for 20?
Scott: Well, I guess they'll be blu-ray, so there might be more money across the board.
Rym: Well the way they do that now is they delay the American releases several months hoping that the people in Japan Just won't be able to wait and they'll buy the expensive job.
Scott: That's not gonna work.
Scott: now.
Scott: if the blu-rays are all region one across because people just start Buying blu-rays anime fans will get blu-ray players and get Japanese DVDs Which plays right into the.
Rym: basically it'll only screw the American Anime publishers.
Rym: yeah, but actually if the Japanese start doing what they seem to be doing a lot more Which is putting English subtitles on their internal releases yep?
Scott: But at the same time if the Americans keep putting their blu-rays out cheaper than the Japanese blu-rays Then it'll screw the Japanese public.
Scott: eventually what you're gonna Get is you're gonna get the Americans who want stuff right away And don't care about the cost Buying from Japan and the Japanese who care about cost and don't need it as soon as it comes out buying from America And it's gonna be all screwed up.
Rym: Yeah But it also kind of I mean American and Japanese culture at least as far as geeks are concerned are moving toward each other.
Scott: mm-hmm Definitely the geek arena Japan US merging.
Rym: of course if you step back from geekery you realize that most Americans Don't even really know where Japan is or what it does.
Scott: yeah, they know nothing about it other than cars come from there and You know the people look different.
Rym: I mean I feel bad cuz there's a cool Korean guy in my office, and I sit my Sharon office with him.
Rym: He's a really cool guy.
Rym: He's into video games.
Rym: He has a wife kid all that stuff and The rest of the people in the office don't seem to realize that there's a difference between you know All the different Asian countries in the Korea Japan China.
Rym: They're all different.
Scott: yep very different.
Scott: I mean I used to not be able to tell the difference But I knew there was a difference, and I would.
Scott: I would be like so which one are you?
Scott: but now?
Scott: But now I can mostly know the difference.
Scott: I mean I probably couldn't tell you the difference between a Cambodian or a Vietnamese guy But I could tell you difference between a Chinese a Korean and Japanese guy which are the major ones You know and I can't expect people to you know be able to recognize You know which country people are from just by looking at him and talking.
Rym: I don't expect that but I expect no one's to not.
Rym: I mean like say where we are.
Rym: company was looking into hiring us.
Rym: some guy who happened to have the same last name as The Korean guy in my department just because it's a common Korean name mm-hmm.
Rym: so someone asked him seriously.
Rym: Do you know him?
Rym: And The guy looked and he's like that.
Rym: names like Smith.
Rym: Yeah, you want Yep, and they actually seriously suggested that he should interview the guy to make him feel more at home Mmm.
Scott: Yeah, yeah It's kind of like that Seinfeld episode.
Scott: It was a Barbara Chang or something like that.
Scott: Yeah, Donna Chang Donna Chang By the name.
Scott: they were like oh Asian, and it wasn't Asian It was just Donna Chang.
Scott: Steen change her name to Chang and was yeah Seinfeld is funny.
Rym: my co-workers are off.
Rym: I mean they all.
Rym: they know that I like Japanese Animation because I have my office is full of wall scrolls and little figurines and pencil board.
Scott: the only thing I have is a little Mario.
Rym: the background and all my pcs are anime things and all the servers I built.
Rym: I'm putting anime themed backgrounds on them and all This stuff.
Rym: awesome, but every now and then when they're looking for some sort of support online They'll run afoul of a Chinese website because we do a lot of business with China, and they always come in like.
Rym: You know Japanese come and read this and I walk in and like that's Chinese And I don't know Japanese to begin with.
Rym: so I don't know what you want.
Scott: Yeah, what are they thinking?
Rym: I don't know what they're thinking.
Scott: the same thing that people who are running windows are thinking yeah, nothing.
Rym: Yeah, don't run windows, okay?
Scott: Alright, so one of my favorite kinds of music is the the nerdcore hip-hop.
Scott: You know optimist run MC front a lot.
Scott: so there's these guys and I'll admit that their rap skills are not the greatest but their lyrics are very good and their music video is very good, and they are called 64k and They're elite.
Scott: Let me tell you Yeah, only one of them really had the rapping skills, and it wasn't that great skills to be.
Scott: anyway You know it was.
Scott: he was better than the other two, but he still wasn't great.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: it was amusing video to watch.
Rym: it went a little long And I probably stopped watching except for the fact that While it was kind of corny the lyrics if you listen to the words were very clever very very clever.
Rym: That's mostly what they got going for themselves.
Scott: Yep, so you know and definitely we love the part where the.
Scott: It's great because they go through like all the history of gaming all the way from Commodore up to like stuff That's not even out yet, and if you are also leet a lot of this stuff will just like ring true with you Like the one piece he guy he goes in and he's like.
Scott: he's talking about the PC games He played and how he was so great.
Scott: He's like the best is still mech warrior, and I'm like yeah You know just Gauss.
Scott: Yeah, so you know if you listen to this then I'm sure one of the guys will say some things that ring true with you If you're a gamer, and you'll enjoy it.
Rym: So my thing I ran into.
Rym: well first of all you all know there's a pruder film the film of JFK being shot by some guy named a pruder who just happened to be there and happened to be filming at the time.
Scott: yep, and
Rym: first of all whenever you've seen it a lot of people have seen it in documentaries or on TV or whatever and It looks like it's the zoomed in thing of like Kennedy, and it's real short and
Scott: a lot of times He's shown in black and white -
Rym: yeah, which I don't get.
Rym: it was filmed in color.
Rym: Yep, but Basically if you ever watch the real Zapruder film It's zoom way out.
Rym: you can see a lot more than they show you on TV - it's real shaky and hard to see anything Mmm.
Rym: So someone is taking it and Stabilized the image.
Rym: so instead of the JFK shaking around on the screen the edge of the screen shakes around.
Rym: they did a whole bunch of Optimization things and the end result is a very watchable very creepy film of JFK being murdered.
Rym: Snuff yeah, basically it is well.
Rym: it also very nicely disproves the Somewhat silly theory.
Rym: a lot of people have had that the Secret Service guy sitting in the front seat turned around and shot him.
Scott: Yeah, like you.
Rym: I just said it because I had a high school AP US history yeah, but when you said it you sounded pretty convinced.
Rym: I said it that way because that's the way he presented it.
Rym: It was funny.
Rym: that way One day we had a class and he shut the door and he's like so I'm gonna show you all who really shot JFK, and it was just kind of funny.
Rym: one time We got a Secret Service guy in class To talk about stuff, and he shut the door and he showed the guy the video and he was like Explain that.
Rym: and the Secret Service guy was like what the fuck What the hell I'm here to talk about not this?
Rym: Hmm crazy crazy teachers, but if you watch this video which is nice and cleaned up you see that the guy turns around.
Rym: it has this look of oh shit on his face and He's not really pointing anything at JFK.
Scott: Yeah, definitely not pointing anything.
Scott: I mean you don't even see bullets coming from anywhere or anyone shooting anything in the video.
Scott: It's just oh there He is.
Scott: oh my god.
Scott: He shot.
Rym: It's kind of eerie because he's like he's shot and His wife is leaning over like are you okay?
Rym: And the guy in front is like what the hell's going on and it looks like everyone's just like trying to figure out what happened And then suddenly his head explodes.
Scott: Yeah, it's funny because if you look at the grassy and all this this guy He was like falling over himself.
Rym: Yeah, like he falls over and rolls.
Scott: Yeah, like like he heard the shots.
Scott: He must have heard the shots.
Scott: He was probably like ducking and stumbling and it was really funny looking at that guy.
Rym: No, he was the third gunman.
Scott: He was running from the scene.
Scott: No, I'm pretty sure he's just some dumb guy.
Rym: Yeah Cuz we all know that.
Rym: the truth was that Chuck Norris went back in time and roundhouse kicked him to death.
Scott: You can see it right in the video He's just in between frames cuz.
Rym: he roundhouse kicks so fast cuz remember if you can't see Chuck Norris your seconds from death.
Scott: Yep So it's anime day Yeah, and it would be also comic book day except on holiday weeks when there's no Monday.
Scott: diamond ships comic books on Thursday Which means I get them tomorrow and next week.
Scott: I'll also get them on Thursday.
Scott: So But you're gonna have to wait but it's me a good weight because Every great comic is coming out.
Rym: Yeah in this week, so fair Plus we had a chance to go through some other stuff.
Rym: We've got lying around and we watched three shows we can talk about.
Scott: Yeah, it's good to have anime on the computer.
Rym: Yep So we got some Lupin the third action, but not the Lupin the third action that you're probably gonna expect.
Rym: Got some Galaxy Express 999 because we're really on a kick with that guy's works now yep, and samurai Champloo, which Rym hadn't seen no cuz I was on co-op when they showed it in Club and Never got around to watching it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So you watch the first episode of that.
Rym: So Lupin the third.
Rym: we love.
Scott: Lupin is like the awesomest dude, even though once you watch it enough It's just the same thing over and over for some reason.
Scott: It's still entertaining every time and I mean Especially great in a group because just you sit there you watch it and everyone's yelling and screaming when the same things happen.
Scott: It's just hilarious.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: He shot him.
Scott: That guy was the one in disguise.
Scott: Oh my god, that guy was upon in disguise.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: He escaped in a miracle.
Scott: Oh my god He escaped in another miracle G gun shot someone going on cut someone.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Well, we got a hold of as far as we know the first Lupin Animation ever.
Scott: Yep, the Lupin pilot.
Rym: It was the pilot for the first anime of Lupin.
Rym: I mean, yeah, if you've seen Lupin on the Cartoon Network, that's actually the second TV show.
Scott: Yeah, they don't tell you that the first TV show the theme song is like Lupin.
Rym: Yeah And this was the pilot for that.
Rym: it's old old old school, but you know what it's the same action it was.
Scott: it was so weird because even though there was just some dumb guy being the voice of Lupin and What was happening was really kind of weird.
Rym: It was just a Excuse to introduce a bunch of characters.
Scott: Yeah, like half of the stuff was just like every time you saw a new character Which wasn't really new to us because we knew the characters.
Scott: Well, most of them.
Scott: it just you know, it explained who they were.
Scott: So it starts out.
Scott: It's like Zenigata the guy who chases Lupin Lupin the great thief.
Scott: Yep Jigen his sidekick the great shot Fujiko their arch-nemesis.
Scott: But then it was all weird because in all the Lupin I've ever seen a red go him on the ninja Samurai guy is helping Lupin and me, you know, even
Rym: first episode of the second TV their best friends
Scott: Yep, but in this one They were like going on the guy who was sworn to kill Lupin and wasn't.
Scott: we were like What is this?
Rym: some kind of one of Lupin's tricks, but now he tries to kill him.
Scott: Yeah, it was kind of weird.
Scott: so now I kind of want to read some like old Lupin manga because that's obviously I think the way it originally was and There must have been at some point where it turned around.
Scott: Yeah, and I want to read the story of how that turned around, you know, cuz that'd be pretty interesting.
Rym: Plus the old Lupin he's a lot less careful with the lives of others.
Scott: Well in the manga he's just he just kills people.
Scott: Yeah, right cuz he's a bad dude like.
Rym: one of the examples in this pilot of how cool Lupin is is He's in a plane and it lands on top of a car and then he jumps out out of the car and the plane flies Away, then he throws a stick of dynamite through the window of the car and he jumps off the car And then the car explodes and goes off a cliff.
Scott: Yep He's a he when you're when you're a thief like that I mean, I guess I don't know.
Scott: just easier to just kill all the guys in your way and then later when they made Lupin I guess more The hero kind of guy.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: maybe They wanted Lupin to be like you like him even though he's a bastard and then later They wanted to make him not a bastard and you like him because he's cool I mean still kind of a bastard kind of.
Scott: but he steals things.
Scott: but then like You always see like when he steals crazy stuff.
Scott: He'll always give it back or he'll drop it or yeah He doesn't actually steal like where you go.
Scott: Hey, you stole that.
Rym: you'll never see the TV show the TV show.
Rym: He steals things from people and keeps them.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: The movies are really where it's different.
Rym: It's like every movie he tries to steal something but then he ends up helping someone out and doing the right thing every time.
Scott: yeah, even if he doesn't want to I Guess that's just what they you know need to do in a movie to sell it I guess because people wouldn't go see it.
Rym: Otherwise, I don't know There are more Lupin movies than I have seen and I have seen a lot of Lupin movies.
Scott: I think we've almost actually seen all the movies except for like a few of the TV Ones and even a lot of those we've seen.
Scott: We need to see more the TV and we need to read manga because we haven't written any manga at all Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the other thing we watch you watch the the first Galaxy Express 999 movie which I've only seen one other time in my life.
Rym: Yep, I saw parts of it on the sci-fi channel when I was in like sixth grade.
Scott: I saw the whole thing on the sci-fi channel sometime in middle school or high school or I don't even remember but Watching it again.
Scott: I Saw it, but that's probably just because I've seen a thousand hundred anime since then But it was still really really good.
Rym: Yeah, it was most excellent.
Rym: I'm very much starting to become a fan of this whole my tell Harlock Arcadia Story the emeraldus.
Scott: Yeah queen emeraldus Galaxy Express all that stuff is in the same universe even though it's like a bunch of separate stuff, but it's way cool.
Scott: and You know, I remember that I There were some things that I remember that didn't happen and some things that happen that I didn't remember.
Scott: You know whenever you watch something and then watch it again like a hundred years later.
Scott: that always happens Like.
Scott: I remember there being more explanation about like the mystery of the train But in fact, there was none of that when I watched it again.
Rym: Well, there was one quick explanation Why does it look like an old train?
Rym: Oh, they made it to look like an old train.
Rym: It's actually an advanced spaceship
Scott: No but I remember there being like explanations about like how the train worked and like what was going on inside of it and why it was the way it was and Where it came from and all that kind of stuff, uh-huh That might have been one of the other movies.
Scott: I don't know but I'm Obviously, I remembered wrong because there was none of that in this movie.
Rym: Regardless, it's an excellent movie though.
Rym: It tries to cover a lot in less time than it probably should have spent.
Scott: Yeah That's the one problem I had with it is that it started out where he's going to get the the count right at the at The time castle.
Rym: Yeah, there's this count Mecca who murdered his mother for fun.
Scott: And he's the movie is about him seeking vengeance and You know that wraps up Like before the end of the movie.
Scott: and then there's this added on bit and the added on bit is like the actual.
Scott: I guess The message of the movie is like, you know, kind of they say it for sure at the end there.
Scott: but it felt like You know something ended and you were ready for the movie to end and then there was more.
Rym: but see I like that because to Me I got the feeling of a lot of movies just end and they ended like the cloud right after the climax when the plot is Resolved but they never really deal with the aftermath.
Rym: and I really like this movie really goes into Wow You've completed this goal that you've been searching for most of your cognizant life to complete now.
Rym: What yeah, what do you do now?
Scott: I guess it's okay because it's not so bad.
Scott: It's kind of like a square boss You know, like you beat the final boss and there's another boss.
Scott: Oh my god secret boss You know, it's that kind of thing which can be fun as long as it's not overdone.
Rym: Final Fantasy 4 advanced there are like five square boss.
Rym: It's like a square boss of a square boss of a square boss.
Scott: great Not like Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles with the Oh God.
Scott: Yeah enough square boss is there.
Rym: But Yeah, if you haven't seen Galaxy Express movie highly recommended and moving right along We watched the first episode of samurai Champloo, which is the only samurai Champloo I've actually seen.
Scott: I've seen the whole show and let me say I love the show.
Rym: I gotta say now that I've actually seen it.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: It pulls it seems to pull a lot of tricks like they'll start to show something.
Rym: They'll be like up wait No, no, never mind or wait back that up now And it jumps around a lot and it's a new.
Rym: it's a style I haven't seen much before and I really like it.
Scott: Well, that's really just.
Scott: the first episode is like that.
Scott: but the thing is is that each episode has its own different kind of style like and Each episode is like about a different thing altogether even though there is a contiguous plot.
Scott: So this one had the cut back and forth kind of action going on.
Scott: Other episodes will kind of have like this, you know, like a weird kind of feeling.
Scott: Others will have more like this fun kind of jovial bouncing around kind of action going on, you know It's always different which is which is what I think makes the show great, huh?
Scott: Like and the the greatest part is like they have this great like I don't know if anachronism is the right word thing going on Where it's kind of.
Scott: you know stuff from now at times, but it's all displaced in the past.
Scott: But in the past is also kind of messed up like you've got like hip-hop graffiti spray in.
Rym: you know punks back in the ancient times of samurai and You know, the thing is a lot of people seem to forget that in the real world There were punk kids back in Rome.
Rym: There are punk kids in the mice nice civilization.
Rym: punk kids have always been around being punks.
Scott: Yeah, but they're doing specifically punk things like.
Rym: what graffiti?
Rym: there's graffiti all over in Rome.
Scott: No, but you should wait.
Scott: Do you see these episodes?
Scott: It's like a direct clashing of set of ancient samurai culture and modern hip-hop culture.
Scott: That is very fun.
Scott: And of course there is a real actual Plot that gets resolved in the 26th episode.
Rym: Oh, yeah the wanting to find the samurai who smells like sunflowers.
Scott: Yeah, that is the actual plot of the show that that does end I like.
Rym: it's actually a typical mysterious anime plot that lets the show go on while being vague enough to not constrain it.
Scott: Yep, it is a typical Anime plot and when it gets resolved, it's pretty much like you don't even realize that that they've come across it.
Scott: well, I guess he kind of do but not really.
Scott: and Pretty good wrap-up, you know, it's nothing like crazy.
Scott: It's not like other animes where you know, you have this great buildup and it's like oh my god.
Scott: Here it is.
Scott: Oh my god, it's like they've been looking for the thing.
Scott: They've been looking for the thing.
Scott: There it is and we're done.
Scott: that was great.
Rym: I Really like the characters.
Rym: from what I've seen.
Rym: the two main samurai guys just have this edgy Adversarial funny dialogue kind of vibe that I enjoy.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it's spike Spiegel and a serious guy.
Scott: Yeah, basically like an avid Costello kind of thing though.
Rym: It seems like a slightly less Intelligent spike Spiegel.
Scott: No, he's pretty smart and he actually has some history that's revealed and stuff.
Scott: But you know, it's like actually you could think of it isn't like spike Spiegel split in half Like there's the crazy kind of one guy looks just like him.
Scott: That's the guy we're talking about Mugen and He's the kind of crazy fun loose guy.
Scott: and the other guy is like the serious samurai You know.
Scott: and spike Spiegel is like Mugen with more seriousness and intelligence.
Scott: So if you take that seriousness out and you put that in the gin character.
Scott: It's kind of like that because it is made by the cowboy bebop guy
Rym: Yeah, which is really really evident whenever there's a fight scene because they fight just like how we bebop people fight Yep, jumping around kind of hip-hop Kicking their feet around like a monkey Kung-fu action
Scott: and the animation is all the same style and everything.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, and But the the main care I guess she's the main character.
Scott: foo is really cute and funny.
Rym: Yeah, she's also.
Rym: what I like.
Rym: is I like the fact that while she's a typical cute funny female lead in an anime You even from the first episode you can tell that one she's smart And two she does think she does the right thing.
Rym: in a situation like two guys are fighting with swords She gets the hell out of that room Yep.
Scott: Or like later when she's like I have to free those guys and then she goes and gets some fireworks from the firework maker.
Scott: She can't fight with a sword.
Scott: she goes to buy some fireworks.
Scott: boom crazy stuff happens.
Rym: Yeah, I like her.
Rym: Yeah, very cool All right, so that was kind of a short anime episode But we're kind of in the middle of watching a bunch of new anime so we can talk about it.
Scott: Yep, and not only that but it's the week in between Christmas and New Year's which means not much is going on.
Scott: And you know, we got less listeners less action, but that's to be expected.
Scott: Yeah ring a week like this.
Rym: Also.
Rym: We've been rather busy planning a crazy New Year's bash for all our friends.
Scott: Yep, it's gonna be pretty crazy.
Rym: all our friends who don't freakin RSVP and we don't know have no idea how many people are Actually coming.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, hey, you know RSVP you get what you get.
Rym: One thing we've learned is when we were in college We always wanted to throw big parties, but we never.
Rym: none of us had money and all the apartments We had were small like college apartments.
Rym: So parties were always just us sitting around and then we'd all like scrounge up money to get some cheap Chinese food.
Rym: Now we're actually throwing a party as in we're providing food like catered food and drinks and all that sort of thing.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Parties cost money.
Rym: They sure do good God.
Rym: I was trying to figure out how much food my friends could eat in a day and I realized that the answer is indeed All of it.
Rym: Well, they're beating up the two-year-old five-year-olds five-year-olds All right, that might have been a little bit of an inside joke.
Rym: So in lieu of being chastised for it I'll explain very quickly.
Rym: There was a debate on the internet and it has been Immortalized as the longest and yet at the same time most trivial debate that has ever taken place.
Rym: Wow, it went on for tens of thousands of posts across multiple forums over the course of like six months.
Scott: Holy crap I didn't realize it was that big.
Rym: Oh, it was on Fark.
Rym: He was everywhere.
Rym: and basically, the argument was Say you were attacked by a mob of five-year-olds Fearless five-year-olds, so they're just saying someone with the physical power of a five-year-old and Those five-year-olds were given one hour of instruction from some sort of martial arts master.
Rym: You are also given one hour of instruction from martial arts master.
Rym: you're put in a gym and the debate was how many of them could you take out before they took you out?
Rym: and They started defining this very explicitly like well taken out means knocked unconscious and blah blah blah.
Rym: no weapons into the do The bodies have knocked out ones disappear.
Rym: Would you eventually drown in five-year-olds?
Rym: Yeah, and That there's nothing more I can really say about that.
Scott: People just argued about this to a crazy degree and the only funny thing you have to remember is the one guy's answer How many five-year-olds could you take out all of them?
Scott: That that's the right answer.
Scott: so as always Go to the forums and hang out.
Scott: There's people there actually talking a lot about cool stuff.
Scott: If you go and hang out there, that's cool, too.
Rym: Yep, and we've been working a lot on the audio.
Rym: I don't know how much people notice this or not because I think we notice changes in audio a lot more than other people listening Do because we do it.
Rym: but every podcast last week has been different.
Rym: I've been playing around with a lot of different methods of cleaning up and different Normalization crap.
Rym: once I figure out what I'm doing really well I'm gonna do a show on it and tell you all how to do it.
Rym: But for now if one episode sounds particularly good or particularly bad let us know.
Scott: Yeah, let us know all kinds of stuff because really no one lets us know anything about this podcast.
Rym: Yeah, nice at gmail.com or call that phone number the phone number.
Scott: We forgot again great.
Scott: I'm gonna write it down.
Rym: Don't worry It's on the website.
Rym: Yeah But really let us know because while I test.
Rym: I test on small samples because these filters take a long time to run.
Rym: so I'll get like a two-minute wave of us talking and I'll fiddle with and try to see what I can do and Then I have to end up applying these things to very long wave files and it takes a long time to do.
Rym: and I don't Have time every night to sit there and listen to every podcast to see how it sounds in its entirety.
Rym: So it might like what a filter I come up with might work really well in one spot But then it breaks later on when we're both talking at the same time or Scott breathes into the mic again.
Rym: That happens Darth Scott.
Rym: Oh Um your Podcaster that was not funny.
Scott: No kidding.
Rym: You know what have been funny if this is a diplomatic podcast.
Rym: Where is the ambassador?
Scott: I'm the ambassador Whatever.
Rym: yeah, but stay tuned tomorrow because we watched Star Wars four or five and six over the past week and we're gonna do a show on Star Wars and That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussions and whether you love or hate our podcast.
Scott: We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.