Rym: It's Monday December 26th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We finish our ongoing series on how to build a new computer talking about video cards cases power supplies that sort of thing.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we're back from the holidays.
Scott: It's not like we went anywhere.
Rym: Yeah, it was a fairly uneventful Christmas Festivus Hanukkah Kwanzaa Etc.
Rym: etc.
Scott: is it actually Kwanzaa yet or isn't Kwanzaa like some different day?
Rym: I don't know when Kwanzaa is.
Rym: all I know is they made us they told us about it And we celebrated it in Catholic school of all places.
Scott: really yeah the guy who invented the holiday came to RIT once.
Scott: I didn't go see him, but the fact that there was a guy who invented the holiday That's still alive tells you a lot.
Scott: Yeah, not insulting Kwanzaa or anything.
Rym: Though uh we had some nice Hanukkah food just today.
Rym: We just got home Christmas Eve.
Rym: we had some excitement.
Rym: You know we're doing our typical lay around play video games and relax type holiday, and we're gonna go out to eat.
Rym: and Scott in his infinite wisdom while I'm putting on my shoes is Poking at our security system now.
Scott: It's not a security system that we use or have it's just.
Scott: this house has an alarm and Sensors and motion detectors and things and a control pad from the previous Occupants.
Rym: yeah two nuns who were paranoid.
Rym: we'll talk about them some right, but we didn't.
Scott: we don't pay for the contract So they don't provide us a service or anything.
Scott: It's there not doing anything.
Rym: I wouldn't even know the code for the thing.
Scott: Yeah, it just sits there.
Rym: so Scott is poking at it and He must have hit some combination of buttons because the fucker went off.
Scott: I can't believe it went off.
Scott: It's we're not paying for it.
Scott: How the hell does it supposed to work?
Rym: It was so loud.
Rym: We screamed.
Rym: It was painful like ah oh god.
Rym: Yeah, usually.
Scott: I'm the one who will always avoid using the telephone But I opted for the job of calling the security company in the telephone rather than go near the alarm.
Rym: Yeah, so I go into the kitchen And I see the box where this painful noise is coming from and I cover one ear And I got like my shoulder on the other ear and I get on a chair And I pull the thing off the wall and unscrew it.
Rym: I look inside and it's blasting sound at me.
Rym: There's all these wires and circuits.
Rym: So I just grabbed the circuit and ripped it until all the wires came out and it stopped making noise.
Scott: That was a great relief.
Rym: Yeah until we heard that there was another noise.
Scott: Yeah, there's a siren on the side of the house like an air raid siren.
Rym: this thing was loud.
Rym: It was louder than the one in the house, and I couldn't just go outside and cut the wires.
Rym: I didn't want to go outside and hear that sound let alone try to find a wire on the side of the house.
Rym: that wouldn't Kill me hmm, so I go and find the like metal control box to the alarm system.
Rym: I unscrew it and I pry it open and there's all these wires and circuits in there And I'm not thinking so I grab a screwdriver And I go to just start unscrewing all the contacts and I feel a little shock.
Rym: I pull back and then I realized there's 120 volts in there.
Rym: mmm dangerous Yeah, and we didn't have any implements and the noise is loud, and we're look running around.
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: and Scott has failed to call the security company?
Scott: Yeah, they weren't there.
Scott: I mean it was Christmas freaking Eve and obviously they're not a real security company like ADT Whatever that has people on call 24/7.
Scott: This is just some schmoes local So there was no one there and leaving a message wouldn't have really helped because I needed someone that second.
Rym: So I took an oven mitt and then I took some scissors And I cut wires in this control box one by one until the noise stopped and the control box went dead.
Scott: And it worked.
Rym: and then the police knocked on the door.
Scott: I guess it's still.
Scott: the security system was somehow active.
Rym: Yeah, well what we learned is that we I mean there's a phone line in the house.
Rym: every house has a phone line.
Rym: We don't pay for it.
Rym: We don't care.
Rym: There's nothing plugged into it.
Rym: We all have cell phones But no matter what even if you don't pay a dime to the phone company by law if you call an emergency number Like if you just plug a phone into a deadline and call 9-1-1 by law the phone call will get through yep.
Rym: So our security system to fight it being inactive or whatever called 9-1-1 and the police came to see what was up.
Scott: Well at least they came.
Scott: that's cool.
Rym: Yeah, finally they came real quick.
Scott: Yeah quicker than I ever expected.
Rym: so he comes in.
Rym: well He's at the door, and I explained what happened, and I offered to let him look around.
Rym: I'm like here's where I cut all the wires on the alarm system.
Rym: Here's the speaker.
Rym: I pulled out of the wall, and he's like yeah, this happens, and then he left.
Rym: yeah He was pretty cool, so if we had been robbers We just got away with the crime of the century.
Rym: because this cop came into a house the alarm stopped going off while he was Standing on the porch.
Rym: He sees two guys.
Scott: They've cut the one of them wearing a coat.
Rym: Yeah, we were both like dressed in coats because we were like right and then as soon as he left He was writing his report in his car.
Scott: We drove away to go eat out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you're running away with loot or anything.
Scott: It kind of pissed though because I mean we had.
Scott: we don't have a telephone and 9-1-1 and a cell phone isn't so great because you have to kind of like talk to people and so you get the local Guys.
Scott: if I would have known that we had you know a 9-1-1 button in the house Like I would have liked to know that and I would have liked to keep it.
Scott: now It's just dead and we lost the 9-1-1, but yeah I'm afraid that we never knew we had.
Rym: I'm really afraid to reconnect all the wires cuz I'm afraid it might just start going Off as soon as I reconnect it.
Scott: yeah I'm afraid it might shock us.
Rym: like just to get you the the Scope of this I cut the power and it kept going off because it had a battery backup inside of it.
Scott: mmm At least it's really secure.
Scott: I mean it has a phone line.
Scott: That's pretty much always there.
Scott: It has a battery so if you cut the power you still can't break into the house.
Scott: You know that's a pretty good security system as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: Yeah, so these paranoid nuns.
Rym: They they got the best.
Rym: yep And we're not.
Rym: they're not like joking or calling nuns.
Rym: our house was actually occupied by two Like super Catholic something nuns before we got here.
Scott: Yeah, it's a renting house.
Scott: You know they don't own the house or anything.
Scott: They just they were renters, and then they left.
Scott: so now we're the renters.
Scott: Yeah, which is pretty good Because they didn't really mess up the house or anything.
Rym: yeah That was beautiful except for one mysterious stain that we kind of hide with furniture.
Scott: Hey, whatever Purchase the nuns with their candles.
Rym: But other than that that was our main Christmas story.
Scott: Yeah, and it sounds like Christmas to me.
Rym: Yeah Elizabeth shade better than my previous Christmas last year when I tried to fly back home to Detroit for the holidays And I failed to do so
Scott: Mmm
Rym: through no fault of my own you know I got a flight home, and I went to Stewart Airport and They first they call me the night I'm gonna go to the airport at night, and then they call me they're like your flight was canceled.
Rym: come in tomorrow We've got a flight for you.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I show up the next day.
Rym: They're like yeah your flights late You're gonna miss your connection.
Rym: Great tell you what.
Rym: we'll put you on a cab for free and send you to Newark Airport Which is like an hour and a half away, and that's like a hundred dollar cab ride.
Rym: Whatever they send me in a cab.
Rym: it gets stuck in traffic.
Rym: I missed that flight.
Rym: They put me on two more flights.
Rym: The one the one comes late, and I would have missed the standby.
Rym: the next one comes And then there's a blizzard and it's grounded and then they sent me in a cab all the way back to Stewart.
Rym: I had to pay $12 in parking and then I went home to my box my little studio apartment and went to sleep.
Scott: It can't be worse.
Scott: I don't know which Christmas it was but I was basically in Rochester in colony all low and everyone else had gone You know to their homes for the holidays, and I didn't go anywhere.
Scott: And I think I just went to like the Chinese restaurant alone sat at home playing games.
Scott: Wasn't so bad, but yeah, it's worse than at least you had some excitement even it was terrible.
Rym: Yeah, it was actually cool because when an airport screws you the airline well if an airline screws you the airport's real sympathetic.
Rym: So they put me in the lounge.
Rym: They gave me free drinks pretty much all day, so I spent my Christmas sitting in Newark Airport's executive lounge drinking gin and tonic.
Rym: Wasn't so bad.
Scott: No you know I never got in those lounges, but this is jet blue really doesn't have a lounge.
Rym: Yeah, well I would never go into a lounge if I had to pay for it because I looked and those drinks are like eight Bucks each.
Scott: yeah, well, it's usually the lounge isn't like something you go in.
Scott: it's like Special travelers can go in there.
Scott: usually yeah like depends on which airline and what the lounge is and whatnot yeah?
Rym: They're mostly for business travelers and like pilots and all that crap.
Scott: yep But yeah, I've never actually had a problem flying ever.
Scott: I've never had a delay.
Scott: I've never had a cancellation.
Scott: I've never had anything.
Scott: I've arrived early in some occasions.
Scott: I'm just real good at flying and I always fly only when it's good to fly.
Rym: well that you also fly between like major Easy airports for nice airlines like jet blue go.
Rym: yeah, I'm flying from anywhere in the East Coast to Michigan.
Rym: No one freaking flies there, there's all the direct ride, it's like 500 bucks to fly from our airport to Detroit.
Rym: yeah Luckily my family is bit by bit moving out of Detroit.
Rym: It's actually cheaper and faster to fly to Arizona to visit my mom than it is to fly to Detroit to visit my dad.
Scott: Well to Arizona you go.
Rym: Yeah in January.
Scott: I'm gonna go there then bring in Michigan.
Rym: Hey.
Rym: I like Michigan.
Scott: Arizona warm Michigan cold.
Rym: Michigan's real hot in the summer.
Rym: just real cold in the way.
Scott: everywhere is real hot in the summer.
Rym: ah No, there's some places where it's not hot in the summer.
Scott: all right, Antarctica, you know Quebec isn't so hot In the southern Quebec.
Rym: It's not that it's not as hot as it could be.
Rym: you know uh Newfoundland the Territories up north in Canada those aren't places people live.
Scott: people live out there Eskimo Canadians not real people.
Rym: yeah, so we don't really have any news.
Rym: we figured you guys read news Yeah, and care.
Scott: It's the holidays, so there isn't too much big news going on.
Scott: You know the big news will start again probably in the new year when you know People have done releasing all the holiday stuff and whatnot.
Scott: then the new year will come around and then People will get back to work, and then news will happen again.
Rym: I mean news happen.
Rym: It's just there wasn't anything.
Rym: we really the only thing we really had planned to talk about anyway that we saw was the fact that Jack Thompson's in the news yet again.
Rym: Yeah, well really yeah the whole Take two stock incident.
Scott: Oh that was like a week ago.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't talk about it Did?
Rym: we were gonna talk about it on the show that got canceled last week.
Rym: Oh, we're gonna talk about Jack Thompson.
Rym: We were gonna talk about something.
Rym: I can't read my writing and something else.
Rym: I can't read my writing.
Rym: oh and speed limits.
Scott: Oh good.
Scott: We can all we can have a whole show on speed limits.
Scott: It just yeah, we'll hold that off until later, but I actually I made a news story But I'll talk about it.
Scott: Maybe tomorrow cuz it's video game day.
Rym: Yeah, it's definitely a video game news video game day.
Rym: Yep and Coming up what we were gonna do, but we missed it.
Rym: Just didn't do an episode.
Rym: is we've recently watched Four or five and six of Star Wars again.
Rym: Oh, yeah And I got to say the blood is boiling for Star Wars all over again, and we're gonna have a lot to say.
Rym: We're gonna do a whole show.
Scott: There's nothing I like better than a whole bunch of spaceships in space shooting at each other really.
Rym: oh, yeah, all right It's a trap trap trap.
Rym: That's no moon.
Rym: It's a trap trap.
Scott: You know if you watch those again, and you actually like pay the freaking attention.
Scott: There's so many just traps.
Scott: all though.
Scott: It's just really the thing is just a trap trap.
Rym: pretty much.
Rym: Oh Star Wars over and over again.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: It's a trap.
Rym: someone is our only hope.
Rym: oh There's another trap.
Rym: well someone is our only hope.
Scott: I mean look let's go to that cloud city.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: It's a trap.
Rym: You hear the words.
Rym: You're our only hope.
Rym: at least seven times in the three movies.
Scott: Yeah, we should count all six movies.
Scott: how many times someone says hope?
Scott: How many times someone says trap or a trap is set or a trap is triggered?
Scott: You know.
Rym: so the one benefit of the fact that we didn't do a show for one extra day is that we've got quality things of the day.
Rym: Because every time the equality things the day yeah I mean Scott's thing is kind of weird and just go with it.
Rym: Just trust us on this.
Rym: and my thing is just I just thought it was funny.
Rym: So we'll do Scott's first.
Scott: all right, so There've been flash games before.
Scott: I mean everyone plays the flash games right, but there's one kind of game Where you don't really win or lose, or you know it's not like you don't have to pay money.
Scott: even It's pretty much just like this sandbox.
Scott: You know we're kind of like.
Scott: you can just do whatever you want here and there and yeah like games are like Oh, there's a village.
Rym: You can poke at it.
Scott: Yeah, and This one in particular is just Really really great for some reason.
Scott: I can't explain.
Scott: It's in Java.
Scott: actually it's not flash, but it might as well be flash.
Scott: and basically you have sand water salt and oil and They're pixels, and they kind of fall down from the top of the screen, and there's also the name Kuji Which is a little baldy guy?
Rym: I usually get rid of him.
Scott: I usually get rid of him.
Scott: He's not so interesting, but basically you can change the rate at which these things fall from the sky.
Scott: You can speed or slow down time, and you can also draw other things.
Scott: you can make walls Which are pretty much?
Scott: Invincible and you just draw walls and you can change the size of your pen that you draw with from one pixel two pixels four pixels 64 pixels like you draw a little light copy wall, and then the sand falling down fills it up and then overflows.
Scott: yep and You can use a spout.
Scott: if you use a spout It's like drawing water, but it stays there and water comes off of it.
Scott: So it's kind of like a. just you draw something and water just comes out of it like whoa.
Rym: Or you can draw a plant and a plants like a wall, but it grows into water.
Scott: Yeah, so if you have a plant it's just as green stuff, and if water touches it it pretty much turns into plant.
Scott: You can draw Sarah Cera Which is kind of like this ceramic wall.
Rym: right, but it'll burn, but it'll burn slow.
Scott: Yeah, the wall isn't.
Scott: walls are invincible But ceramic.
Scott: if you set it on fire with the fire hit that I will scoot soon.
Scott: explain.
Rym: Yeah, fire is great.
Scott: fire is the most fun in this whole thing.
Scott: It'll slowly slowly burn so you can do interesting things with it as opposed to oil which burns quickly.
Scott: Yeah, oil if fire gets near oil it just goes crazy with fire.
Scott: Fire obviously is fire.
Scott: you just draw fire, and then if it catches on to things that are flammable It'll ignite.
Rym: now this game is basically just a physics engine a very simple one sitting there, and you can poke at it.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically pixel based.
Scott: I think it actually you know goes across all the pixels and figures out.
Scott: Okay, this pixel touch that.
Scott: now this you know it's just.
Rym: I don't know why it's just so utterly amusing.
Rym: I sat there for like an hour just playing with.
Scott: I made a system where The there would be.
Scott: I set the oil there's an oil falling from the top of the screen And there's fire at the top of the oil right and there's some Spouts of water under it right and there's a wall and closing the whole system.
Scott: So you have is you have oil that falls down, but some of the oil sets on fire and some of it keeps going down.
Scott: Then you have water just filling up slowly and then I start some plant.
Scott: So you have this thing just filling up with plant because the water turns into plant and Eventually the plant gets all the way to the top where the fire is At the top of the oil.
Scott: so all the plant just sets on fire and turns to nothing and it fills up with water again But the fire doesn't get all the plant.
Scott: so the plant grows back and sets on fire.
Scott: It's just perpetual motion.
Scott: I met something that's just one of the great things you can do with it.
Rym: Yep I made a bunch of walls and I basically made an oil lamp where there's fire burning at the end of this lamp and Like at the top and then there's a little loopy like a reservoir where oil collects and then the like oil is constantly refilling the lamp So it never runs out.
Scott: It's pretty fun.
Scott: You can just do crazy stuff.
Rym: I mean the salt really doesn't do anything But it's still fun to watch it flow around.
Scott: Yeah, the sand couldn't put out fires and the water can put out fires.
Scott: It's like I would make like a ceramic thing and have fire come up under it And then when the fire burnt through the ceramic the sand and the water would fall out and put the fire out But then that water would touch some plant that would grow and hit some oil that was on fire.
Scott: Oh my god Do it again?
Scott: Okay, oh.
Scott: and the one other thing in this game is an eraser.
Scott: you can just erase things and There's the question mark.
Scott: if you use the question mark, it just makes the game go crazy But like this fractal all over the place.
Scott: I don't know the point of it.
Scott: It's kind of silly.
Rym: Yeah So just seriously go to this site try it.
Rym: it'll look weird.
Rym: Trust us if you're not amused within 30 seconds, then you'll get your money back.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's not even a game.
Scott: just start playing with it and see what happens.
Scott: You know be way cool is that they made this for the DS of the stylus man.
Scott: That would rock.
Rym: Ooh Yeah, that'd be real good if I was just bored like on a train for five minutes.
Rym: Yep So my thing this is just someone's blog and I just thought it was cool because it's basically this Russian guy as far as I can tell writing about how Russians actually drink vodka and How to drink vodka without getting drunk.
Scott: Because yeah Russians actually do drink a shit ton of vodka.
Scott: That's not like some stereotype.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I mean a long time ago The tradition was that a lot of times the water supply wasn't that safe and vodka was safe.
Rym: So you drank vodka to get your water, but you didn't want to get drunk because you had to do work.
Rym: So Russians came up with a lot of ways to not get drunk but still drink a lot of vodka.
Scott: now Does this work with non vodka?
Scott: or is it vodka specific?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean part of it is that there are genetic predispositions and that people who drink a lot tend to have high Resistances to drunkenness.
Scott: Well, that's the same thing with anything I mean if you eat a lot of percocet eventually doesn't work and you have to take more and more.
Rym: I mean some of this stuff is kind of yeah, and some of it's silly and some of it's pretty officious But basically it's just.
Rym: it's a really cool.
Rym: here's how to not get drunk and It also talks a lot about the traditions around vodka.
Rym: and like if you go to a Russian party and the Russians are drinking vodka It's it not only tells you how much vodka you're expected to drink socially But how to politely not drink too much vodka and get drunk and sick.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: No one ever wants to get sick.
Scott: I at least I don't want to get sick.
Rym: I don't know many people who drink specifically to get sick.
Rym: Mmm, I know I want to drink to get drunk, which I'm not a big fan of.
Scott: Yeah It would be pretty interesting to see what of the things the Russians do which ones are scientifically actually helping you not get drunk and which ones aren't and if there was a way to learn from that.
Scott: to like just Make like a thing you drink and then you could.
Scott: you know You like.
Scott: drink one of these things we invent and then drink a drink of vodka and then drink one of these things We invent and you won't get drunk.
Rym: a lot of it's just common sense.
Rym: They say like drink shots, but always eat things between every shot and that's why I'd like a traditional Russian drinking party.
Rym: They'll have these.
Rym: I can't pronounce the word.
Rym: It's a Russian word.
Rym: that kind of means appetizer.
Rym: There's a little salty things or caviar things and between every shot.
Rym: You're supposed to eat a whole bunch of appetizers And you're supposed to eat while you're drinking.
Scott: and now what do you get full though?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't think you ever do Mmm, it's a Russian party.
Rym: What do you want?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Oh Those the Russians In Soviet Russia Yakov Smirnoff makes you Yeah, oh, we're supposed to like, you know say something of an inside joke.
Scott: Does that count as an inside joke?
Scott: Yeah, I try to think about it.
Rym: in Soviet Russia something something's you is not an inside joke.
Rym: That is a far cliche that grew out of a terrible Terrible terrible Soviet comedian like.
Scott: there's a guy called Yakov Smirnoff and he is a comedian and he has his own Like place that he does comedy at.
Scott: he doesn't do comedy at other places and you can go to the place.
Scott: There's a website.
Scott: just search for it.
Scott: It's not hard to find.
Rym: his jokes are all of the same format.
Rym: in America Something something's you or something you something something in Soviet Russia something something you Yep, like in America you eat beef or beef but in Soviet Russia beef eats you.
Scott: Yeah Only they're actually somewhat funny because they relate to Soviet Russia and their things that in Soviet Russia actually happened to you.
Rym: Yeah, basically he is the Jeff Fox worthy of Soviet Russia?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Jeff Fox worthy is but I'll let that Fox worthy was the ya might be a redneck if bla bla bla bla.
Scott: I know that guy.
Scott: Yeah The other the previous joke where I said, oh those Russians.
Scott: Yeah, there's a. there's a song called Ra ra Rasputin, you know Rasputin the Russian guy who you know did the Queen and well allegedly Yeah, but anyway There's a song and at the end of the song the the guy goes, oh those are.
Scott: We'll talk more about that in the future.
Rym: Yeah, because it's it's part we've been searching for a Russian song that we can't find for a long time.
Scott: Yeah, we'll let that one stay a mystery for a little while longer.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah in the meantime, but you know what that Rasputin He was Russia's greatest love machine.
Scott: All right for the past two Mondays We've done our how to build a computer and how to properly purchase a computer and now we're going to continue.
Rym: This is part three of three Of three.
Scott: well probably of three.
Rym: Yeah I don't think we're gonna need to do another one on this because every other topic beyond building a computer is Really another series like networking.
Rym: Yeah building servers and all that.
Scott: Yeah, this bit is really all the parts and which ones to buy and what they do.
Scott: Maybe we could do one in like actual construction instructions, but you can get that on the internet It's not yeah I mean seriously.
Rym: you plug the things that fit into the holes and you can't plug things in wrong because they won't let you.
Scott: yeah, the hardest part is the BIOS and then you just take the book that comes with the motherboard and you read each item and You say do it tells you you should set this to this.
Scott: if you have this you should set this to this.
Rym: if you have This and you call the direct the BIOS is when in doubt don't touch it.
Rym: Yeah, if you don't know what something does leave it alone.
Rym: It'll work fine.
Scott: Yep, you only read that you really have to.
Rym: change is make it work faster, but that's a topic for another day.
Rym: That's really not a big part of this.
Rym: That's like post building the computer.
Scott: Of course today the first thing that talk about is what video card do you get?
Rym: and There are basically four broad broad broad arbitrary categories of video cards From bottom to top.
Rym: They are no name.
Rym: video cards Middle of the road what?
Rym: basically no name.
Rym: crap video cards normal video cards gaming video cards and professional video cards And those are very broad obtuse.
Rym: Don't worry about them categories.
Rym: That's just how I like to think about it.
Rym: Yep Don't buy a no name video card.
Scott: well, all right a No-name video card is something like it only can do 2d graphics or it Doesn't even have a 3d chip or it has a 3d chip in it.
Scott: You've never heard of like one of those.
Scott: like it's not Nvidia.
Scott: It's not ATI.
Scott: It has something else on it.
Rym: Yeah like it's a video card that came with like a Dell dimension and it has a weird name and It's not an Nvidia and it's not ATI.
Rym: It's just something weird.
Scott: All those video cards are really good for our Computers that don't really need a display like a server doesn't really need to show anything on the screen.
Scott: maybe it'll show some text on the screen, you know, or You just use the terminal and at the most it might have a 2d gooey But it doesn't have any fancy graphics or anything like.
Scott: then you can use one of those.
Scott: you don't care You just need a video card to boot the computer.
Scott: But if you actually want a hat a desktop computer, you need another.
Scott: you need something better.
Rym: yeah, and Honestly, there's a. there's a. basically there's a big war going on between ATI and Nvidia when it comes to the two middle categories Of video cards, which is all you're really looking for here.
Rym: Yep, and To not be partisan by an Nvidia don't buy an ATI.
Scott: Well, see the thing is is hardware wise?
Scott: looking only at the chips themselves it's kind of a tough call because The ATI chip is pretty powerful and pretty cheap and the Nvidia with its wide array of chips are pretty powerful and pretty cheap.
Scott: And you can compare them on any given day.
Scott: and one guy will have a better Top of the line and one guy will have a better middle of the line.
Scott: and you know Just considering how many pixels it can push without in optimum conditions and how good the graphics it can do.
Scott: You know, you really have to look at a whole bunch of different, you know Stats and charts to figure out which one is the best and they're pretty much equal.
Scott: Yeah It's just don't even think about it because it doesn't matter.
Scott: The reason you should get Nvidia is because it works in Linux and ATI doesn't work in Linux for crap.
Rym: Not only that ATI has trouble in Windows sometimes.
Scott: Yeah, the ATI drivers are really really really really really had more really shitty as fuck.
Rym: Yeah that we can't stress enough how poorly written and poorly executed the ATI drivers are.
Scott: I mean that's like Nvidia is kind of a good company like they.
Scott: they want them.
Scott: They they're putting stuff out for Linux.
Scott: that is really good.
Scott: But they won't open source the driver which makes a lot of the crazy open source zealots mad at them.
Rym: But at the same time they make it easy to incorporate their driver into a Linux distribution.
Scott: Yep And the thing is is they the only reason they don't open source the driver?
Scott: at least some people at Nvidia have said the only Reason they don't open source the driver.
Scott: So ATI doesn't see it.
Scott: because if ATI sees it then ATI and video be pretty much equal as long as ATI doesn't see that.
Scott: Well, how?
Scott: what makes the Nvidia driver so fucking awesome.
Rym: I use the word fucking a lot here But I guess we can't stress it enough, yeah, I mean seriously Nvidia has a unified driver.
Rym: They have one driver for every card.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There are rare rare rare exceptions to that and you won't run into them Yep, because they don't make those cards anymore.
Rym: Yeah, like I ran into it my computer I'm recording this show on now has a GeForce 2 GTS Which is this it was the $400 top-of-the-line awesome video card in the year 2000.
Rym: Mm-hmm Now it's a piece of crap and Nvidia's dropped support for it.
Rym: So I had to use an old version of the driver because they just dropped it from the new driver.
Rym: Mmm, I guarantee this won't happen to you anytime soon if at all.
Scott: The other thing you have to realize is that Nvidia is just a chip maker and they make drivers to support their chips.
Scott: ATI makes chips and cards and drivers and the only way you can get an ATI chip is if you buy a card that is made by ATI.
Scott: you won't find like a bit or aces or Who else gain word or light on or any of those companies making a video card with an ATI chip on it?
Scott: There's only ATI makes cars of ATI chips on it.
Rym: But my g-force 3d labs made that and before that some other company made my Nvidia.
Scott: Anyone who wants to make a video card with an Nvidia chip on it can do so.
Scott: So that just helps you out because now you have all these different people competing on price and Nvidia just doesn't care.
Scott: They make plenty of money because they're selling chips to all these people.
Scott: It's just you have to you can you know get people to fight over which is gonna be the cheaper cheapest?
Scott: geforce fx 9000 which what you know is it gonna be this company this company who's gonna make a better card Don't want to get a card that has more RAM less RAM.
Scott: you know you have so much more choice more competition better for the consumer and It's just great.
Rym: Yeah, and even though there's all these different kinds once again You don't need to worry about the driver Because some companies put out their own driver for like say 3d labs.
Rym: when I got my video card They put out their own driver for my geforce car.
Rym: Yep, however the geforce Nvidia driver the one that Nvidia puts out worked just fine.
Rym: In fact was better.
Scott: Well, actually the thing is is I had a diamond viper v770, which is the first tnt2 card that didn't suck.
Scott: Well, it was that really the first tnt2 card that was worth buying at all.
Scott: Yeah, and it came with a diamond driver.
Scott: But I realized later that all those drivers that have the same brand as the as the card manufacturer are really just the Nvidia driver in disguise.
Scott: and it's the Nvidia driver from whatever time they released your card.
Scott: and If you use the Nvidia driver from the Nvidia website, not only does it work better Because it is definitely absent of any buggy code that the video card manufacturer might have put in But it's more updated because the one from the video card manufacturer is never gonna really update.
Scott: The Nvidia one is updated and while they have no guarantee and there's all this fine print It's great and you can use it no matter who made your card and it'll work perfectly.
Rym: Yep, and They're often putting out improvements.
Rym: They whenever they release a new Nvidia driver They always add stuff like this card is now faster or the drivers now smaller or something cool.
Scott: Mm-hmm and while you may be thinking and What do they know?
Scott: my ATI driver works fine, I'm never gonna use Linux.
Scott: what do I care?
Scott: Windows Vista is cut right now.
Scott: You gotta look at the situation at this point in time.
Scott: XP is the current windows.
Scott: Vista is coming out.
Scott: Vista is gonna have DRM and other stuff that won't let you pirate it.
Scott: It'll be really hard to pirate probably not impossible.
Scott: I don't think that'll ever happen.
Rym: Yeah, but even if you pirate it's gonna be hard to get updates.
Rym: You're gonna have trouble.
Scott: You're gonna have trouble downloading and listening to your own mp3 collection Like if you thought XP was hard to pirate.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yes Vista is not gonna be this great thing.
Scott: It's probably gonna be like the first windows.
Scott: That isn't monopoly.
Scott: So you're probably not gonna want to upgrade to that Which me.
Scott: and eventually one day they'll stop supporting XP and it'll just be impossible to use it without getting a million viruses.
Rym: I mean Windows 2000 is already barely supported.
Scott: Yeah, and we're talking years down the road because computers last five six years at least mine do you know?
Scott: You're gonna probably go to Linux or Mac or something.
Scott: and if you're planning and going to Linux Unless ATI all of a sudden comes out with a working good Linux driver sometime between now and then You can't go wrong buying an Nvidia.
Scott: You can always jump to Linux in case something happens.
Scott: if you want to throw a Linux live CD in to fix your computer It'll work a lot better.
Rym: Yeah, if you want a dual boot you have to use Nvidia.
Scott: Yeah and people were talking about things like game CDs that would just boot off the CD and play and If those are based on Linux, you're gonna need an Nvidia or you know it.
Scott: Cuz I'm a video card.
Rym: We're not kidding ATI's drivers.
Rym: Just half of them just won't even work in Linux.
Rym: They're buggy They're huge.
Rym: upgrading them can just prevent your computer from booting.
Scott: Yep I mean I have an ATI in my laptop from work and I don't do 3d with it at all.
Scott: I mean, sometimes you play Quake 3 at work and it works.
Scott: fine Sure But the actual interface of doing things in the driver like setting up multiple monitors It's just painful and it doesn't work, right?
Rym: I mean we had a computer downstairs We call it div affectionately and it's connected to our TV.
Rym: and we had this ATI pretty good video card with an S video out on it and we just stuck it in the box belt Linux on it.
Rym: and Then we discover that in Linux There is actually no way in the world to make that computer output video on the S video.
Scott: Wait, so then I plug my laptop from ATI into the TV and it kind of worked kind of shiddly Like.
Scott: I really couldn't make it go.
Scott: and this is with the ATI video card.
Scott: So then we bought like a $30 geforce 4 crap video card popped it in.
Rym: it worked immediately.
Scott: We didn't have to do anything It just it worked properly and it wasn't because of who made the video card It was because it was an Nvidia video card.
Rym: now you hear a lot of things like steam and all these valve games.
Rym: They they say they're back in ATI and they always see things like oh ATI.
Rym: It'll work right here on ATI.
Rym: Yep, don't worry about that.
Rym: The cards are the same.
Rym: You're not gonna notice a significant difference.
Scott: Yeah, you'll see sites that you know, the sites with all the benchmarks for all the gamers.
Scott: They compare like how fast it is and sure if you have a game that was written for DirectX and for ATI If you have an ATI and it's working Well, it's gonna be.
Scott: you're gonna get a few more FPS with the ATI card then with the equivalent Nvidia card It's gonna be that way.
Rym: but they love a lot of times they imply that it's not gonna really work if you don't have an ATI card.
Scott: Yes, it works just fine.
Scott: with the Nvidia You'll just have a few FPS less and if you really care about those FPS extra you got a problem.
Scott: I Mean, is it really worth the you know, the extra trouble and the self-limiting just to get you know a few extra Frames in a game that you don't even notice because they're above your vertical sync and because
Rym: a long time ago it mattered I mean back in the day when you would want 20 frames per second was good.
Rym: You could like overclock your video card and get 25 and it was a huge improvement huge improve.
Rym: But if you're getting a hundred and now you get a hundred and eight That doesn't mean.
Scott: and even if you're getting a hundred if all of a sudden you get two hundred It doesn't mean anything.
Scott: you never.
Scott: you don't see that.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, usually you can't.
Rym: I don't know how many of you realize but in most games There is something called a vertical sync.
Rym: you want to turn vertical sync on if we can Yeah, though you usually in old games like in the quake two days.
Rym: Most people turn it off because you couldn't handle it.
Rym: Basically all it does is your monitor refreshes a certain number of times per second and a certain time.
Rym: Yes Vertical sync ensures that the video card updates in tune with your monitor, right?
Rym: It's more complicated than that But that's basically what it is.
Scott: So basically my monitor will update the picture on itself 75 times every second right now.
Scott: Normally my video card will just churn out a billion billion frames and When the monitor updates it'll just display whatever frame happens to be there at the time.
Scott: and the other frames You know, they kind of get displayed.
Scott: It's complicated but if you set vertical sync The video card will display one frame for every time the monitor updates and it'll be perfect and in sync and there's no flickering.
Rym: and it's all the other half of this that really meant that.
Rym: that just the part that makes the Performance difference is that vertical sync.
Rym: when you don't have it the game itself will not sync itself up vertically because it's just updating as fast As it can.
Rym: so if you like say it's quick and you look up really quick.
Rym: The textures might tear so it's hard to you have to see a picture of it.
Rym: Maybe I'll find a googling but basically the Horizontally because it's called vertical sync, but it affects how things look horizontally.
Rym: You'll see things kind of like jaggy like they won't be lined up for a second while you're looking around.
Rym: Yep But the thing is regardless of that You can't see FPS greater than your monitor can display.
Rym: Your monitor is probably not refreshing more than maybe 120 times a second at most if you have a really really good monitor.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So what it comes down to is if your monitor is a 75 frame a second monitor If you're putting out more than 75 frames a second on your video card Those frames are basically useless and your video card is better than you need it to be and you could probably just turn up The graphic image quality to lower the frames a bit and you would have a better experience.
Rym: Now to wrap up just because we've been talking about video cards a lot.
Rym: We've thrown a lot of information at you.
Rym: Mm-hmm basically, if you're a multimedia designer or 3d designer or something for your job buy a professional video card if you can like an Oxygen or whatever matrix.
Rym: Yeah matrix is good.
Rym: If you do 2d matrix is King.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They're still King.
Rym: I haven't looked at the last time I checked but that was over a year ago as many years ago.
Scott: Yeah, but if you're doing like if you're working at like a 3d animation place You're gonna need some one of these crazy like quadro something something cards that are just insane.
Scott: I mean you could use them for gaming, but they're not made for that.
Rym: They're may really won't help you out.
Scott: Yeah, they're made to just render videos really really quick and make model, you know All that kind of stuff.
Rym: but for normal use a general rule of thumb Even if you're a gamer even if you're a fairly hardcore gamer if you're the hardest core gamer You're just gonna spend 800 bucks and buy the newest video card.
Rym: Whatever if you're smart buy the second best video card on the market.
Rym: Yeah Like literally look at what the most expensive awesome normal video card is.
Rym: go back one or maybe two steps and you'll save four or five Hundred dollars and it'll be almost as good.
Scott: Mm-hmm I'm always.
Scott: it's kind of like video cards seem to follow the same price scale as CPUs.
Scott: Like the number one g-force will be crazy out of control.
Scott: The one under it would be like half that price.
Scott: the one under it will be half that price and then it starts to taper Off.
Scott: like the next one will only be 20 bucks cheaper.
Scott: The next one will only be five bucks cheaper.
Scott: The next one is only a dollar cheaper.
Scott: So that's the point at which okay It's worth it to spend 25 bucks and go up three steps.
Scott: the one last thing though is Nowadays you can get.
Scott: I don't know how common it is, but a while ago you could get Nvidia Enforce motherboards that had video cards in them.
Scott: That's what I have for my parents and it's a great way to save a crap ton of money.
Rym: Yes, remember you can always add a video card later if you need a fast one.
Scott: Yeah And basically you have a video card in the motherboard.
Scott: that is a geforce 4 and it works just fine.
Scott: for normal computing.
Scott: You have to sacrifice you have to get more RAM because you're gonna use your RAM as the video card RAM and this kind of configuration.
Scott: But you can save a lot of money if you don't actually want to do 3d games really much at all.
Scott: You know, if you maybe you're gonna do a tiny 3d game like the Sims or something, you know Then it'll work just fine.
Rym: And for this point in time again once again You might notice we tried to avoid saying specific video cards because that a month from now would be completely different.
Rym: Yep, but if you don't play the new games like half-life 2 basically, that's really the only game.
Rym: Mm-hmm crap $30.
Rym: geforce 4 MX whatever will be more than you need.
Scott: Yeah, like counter-strike Yeah That'll play the crap out of counter-strike 1. if you want to play counter-strike source You might need a geforce FX.
Scott: maybe at least sixty.
Scott: six hundred seems right at this point in time.
Scott: Yeah, sixty six hundred is probably.
Scott: is it the normal great card that you can play?
Scott: half-life 2?
Rym: just fine Just buy the second or third best card and you'll be fine.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Don't buy the number one card You really really don't need it.
Rym: You're not gonna get that much out of it.
Rym: a month from now You'll see that card for $200 less.
Scott: Oh, there's also something now that's become popular again called SLI.
Scott: Or you combine two video cards together to sort of double whatever.
Rym: It's silly.
Scott: Don't do it.
Scott: I mean the.
Scott: the logic is that you can buy a card now and then later When you know the new card.
Scott: to get a new card would be so expensive.
Scott: Instead you can just buy another one just like your old card and tie them together.
Scott: It doesn't really work.
Rym: Yeah two video cards are not twice as fast as one video card.
Scott: in reality this system if you Do just normal 3d stuff is actually slower because the overhead of the two cards communicating with each other is Makes it slower than just having one card.
Scott: But if you are doing crazy 3d stuff like an ultra super awesome brand new game It will help you out.
Scott: But it doesn't help you out at all when you compare it to how much more it costs to buy two video cards.
Scott: So just forget about it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there's.
Rym: even if you're a program just don't even consider it.
Rym: Don't just pretend it doesn't exist.
Rym: anyone who does it We're just gonna make fun of you.
Scott: buy it if you play.
Scott: only if you play PC games all day every day all night.
Scott: And the newest PC games maybe if you do play PC games for a living buy this.
Scott: Yeah, otherwise forget about it All right.
Rym: the end of video cards, yep No, since we talked about video cards so much we'll do a quick bit on displays, you know monitor Splat screen CRT, whatever Because a lot of people neglect it and we don't consider it when we consider the price of a computer.
Rym: because generally you buy a new Computer you don't need a new monitor monitors.
Rym: Don't go bad.
Scott: as long as they have a monitor You might not have one you might not have any computer or you might have an old crap monitor.
Rym: You gotta buy a new one.
Scott: Yeah, and the monitor goes in a separate upgrade scale from the computer.
Rym: Yes I mean I've upgraded my computer once in the last five years.
Rym: I upgraded the motherboard whatever.
Rym: I've had the same monitor since the year 2000 and it's kicking strong and I'll probably use another five years.
Scott: Yep, I had the same 17 inch CRT longer than the first computer that I bought with it But I used it for like one or two more years into the newer computer.
Scott: Then I got an LCD screen, but I didn't get rid of the CRT.
Scott: I just had two monitors and then eventually when I got a job and real money I replaced the CRT.
Scott: now I have two LCDs, but they're real nice.
Rym: LCDs They're real nice.
Rym: But we're not gonna go into depth on all the different statistics and numbers that are associated with all the different kinds of displays Because that would be a show in itself and we'll do a show on that one day.
Rym: But we just want to do a quick overview of like.
Rym: basically your choices are a CRT or a cathode ray tube.
Rym: You know, that's a normal monitor a monitor with a big glass and it's huge and heavy or an LCD liquid crystal display the little flat screens Yep, just like laptops, but not because they sit on your desk.
Rym: Now basically unless you have a reason to or if you're really trying to save money You can get a 17 or a 19 inch CRT
Scott: for like a hundred bucks real
Rym: cheap and we're talking a good one Mm-hmm, and the only real downsides of them are that they're big and they're heavy
Scott: if you had a lot of desk space and you don't really care and You know you want to save a lot of money.
Scott: get like a 19 inch CRT 17 inches a little small these days.
Scott: get a 19 inch CRT run it at 1280 by 1024 and you're good to go.
Rym: Yeah, and if you want to get an LCD Basically, you have to consider right now.
Rym: Are you a gamer or not?
Rym: Mm-hmm, if you want to play games, you have to get a low latency.
Rym: CL this LCD.
Scott: Yeah You want it.
Scott: they visit you'll see a number called the refresh rate and it'll be measured in milliseconds.
Scott: if you're gaming You need at least 12 milliseconds or less.
Rym: Otherwise, you'll get ghosting.
Scott: Yeah ghosting mate basically means that when you're playing the game you things will like kind of not disappear Immediately and you'll see like kind of like this shadow when things move kind of like a motion blur.
Scott: That's nice.
Rym: You have an old Gameboy like the original Gameboy or an old game gear.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's ghosting.
Scott: Yeah, cuz those were very very low refresh rate LCD screens where you know a pixel would move.
Scott: Let's say in Tetris the block would move down, but you'd still kind of see the old block because it didn't disappear.
Scott: yet There's a ghost of the old block where it used to be.
Scott: So that's what why it's called ghosting.
Rym: and the only other main factor is there's active matrix and passive matrix.
Rym: Mm-hmm You want active matrix?
Scott: No one really pays attention to that anymore because all the monitors are the good kind.
Rym: Yeah But watch out if you see a monitor that looks too good to be true and it's huge and has a low latency and it's Cheap.
Rym: check and see if it's a passive matrix.
Rym: Yeah somewhere You don't want that passive matrix is what is on old crappy laptops.
Scott: Yep Now if you don't really care what your screen looks like you can get lots like I got my grandma this I had no name brand like Southeast Asian random crap LCD screen and you know what?
Scott: It didn't have any dead pixels and it works and I had speakers built in which is good for my grandma and it was.
Scott: it Was just great.
Scott: But if you actually care get a name brand get.
Scott: it'll be a brand You've heard of like viewsonic sony samsung L I guess LG Phillips.
Scott: I think you know.
Scott: don't get like Rose will or CTX or random guy Cuz.
Scott: yeah odds are you're not gonna have a nice warranty and there might be dead pixels and all kinds of bad things.
Rym: Just don't skimp on the monitor because that's the primary way you enjoy your computer.
Rym: Mm-hmm and a bad monitor I mean if you like if you sit down a computer that has a crappy worn-out monitor and it doesn't look right The computer feels slower.
Rym: just it does not actually slower, but it feels crappier to use.
Scott: And don't hurt your eyes and don't underestimate the importance of the monitor.
Scott: I had a computer and I was using that 17 inch CRT.
Scott: and sure, I used that 17 inch CRT with my old crap video card and I upgraded to the new a whole new computer.
Scott: and You know, it didn't really make that much of a difference graphically Even though I had upgraded from a TNT to to an FX 5900, which is just huge.
Scott: That's like three or four generations of video card upgraded and sure I had more FPS But it wasn't that much better as soon as I bought that new LCD That made more difference than all the video card in the world could have.
Scott: so don't underestimate how important the monitor is.
Rym: All right, we're running long as we tend to on this topic.
Rym: great but uh burners Peripheral drives floppy drives we can do this real quick because it's real simple.
Rym: Yep back in the day used to have to buy a Plex store because Plex store made the best burners in the world and Other burners would fail to burn CDs you to throw them out coasters.
Scott: It was bad.
Rym: nowadays It doesn't matter buy a cheap one.
Rym: They all work.
Scott: You can just go on Newegg and for like 30 40 bucks.
Scott: You can get a DVD burner.
Scott: Just make sure that it supports DVD DL which is a dual layer DVDs.
Scott: That means you can burn like these super big DVDs.
Scott: They can hold a whole movie on them.
Rym: Yep, if it does DL odds are 90% of the time.
Rym: Well 99% of the time it supports everything else you want to.
Scott: yeah plus minus RW CDs CD RW you can put CDs DVDs whatever.
Rym: just make sure it says DL dual layer.
Scott: Yep Oh and one note is that all DVD burners?
Scott: Technically usually start out region-free and they will set themselves to a DVD region.
Scott: You know once you put a DVD in them or Windows does something.
Scott: if you use Linux or if you do things properly Or you have a piece of software you can keep your DVD burner set to region zero to watch any movie you want.
Scott: So if you want like to watch foreign movies pay attention to that before you make your DVD burner work.
Rym: Yeah, and In regards to other drives, I mean External hard drives.
Rym: Yeah, if you use them you use them.
Rym: If you don't you don't that's not really something we care to talk about but floppy drives.
Scott: You don't need them.
Scott: Don't bother You just don't need a floppy drive anymore.
Scott: It's completely useless.
Rym: Floppy drives are really just completely useless drivers.
Rym: you get on the internet now you save files So you have absolutely no reason to get a floppy drive.
Scott: if you really need something that does what a floppy drive does Which is read and write to something without wasting a bunch of CDs and move files around physically get one little USB keys.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there you can get a 512 megabyte one for like 10 bucks 20 bucks.
Scott: I got a 512 megabyte one for 20 bucks on sale at Staples and that's about dropping rapidly.
Scott: Yeah, they're dropping pretty quickly as flash gets cheaper All right.
Rym: Now we're getting to two components the last two main components and these may seem like afterthoughts But as particularly one of these is perhaps the most important decision you'll make And one of the most difficult.
Rym: Yes the most difficult.
Rym: the case in the power supply.
Scott: Now the case is that box that your computer goes in.
Scott: I mean you could if you wanted to just have a computer sit out on your desk on like a static-free mat.
Scott: You know, we've had one.
Scott: all did that Yeah, and plug all the pieces together and just have it wide open sitting there.
Scott: but you really probably want to put the computer in a box to make it look like a computer.
Rym: and Basically, you want to look online.
Rym: you want a case that'll hold.
Rym: first of all You probably got an ATX motherboard.
Scott: if you didn't what the hell you got a mini.
Rym: you might have gotten a mini ATX.
Scott: Mini ATX are the ones that are designed for those tiny tiny cases that are all cute and small.
Rym: So look at the motherboard you picked out and then see if it says mini ATX or ATX.
Rym: Make sure the case you buy says mini ATX or ATX.
Rym: Otherwise, it won't fit.
Rym: Yep But if it says that it'll fit guaranteed that is an industry standard that no one deviates from except old broken bells.
Scott: And if it doesn't fit then you probably bought a really crap case.
Rym: Yeah Now basically just look online.
Rym: look at Newegg.
Rym: look at the case.
Rym: Make sure it looks nice because the ones that look nice don't cost that much more than the cheap crap ones.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can get the really crazy riced out ones, which I don't think are so pretty but they're like Really cheap.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: Yeah But you have to look.
Scott: when I look at a case the first thing I look at is what material it's made out of.
Scott: Plastic cases usually really cheap and crappy.
Scott: They're gonna break.
Scott: Steel cases are usually real heavy real quality.
Scott: Usually not all the time, but they might have sharp edges that'll cut you.
Scott: Yeah, they're unpleasant to work with and they're heavy.
Rym: I mean, I have a three foot tall.
Rym: It's a little over three feet.
Rym: old-school steel reinforced gray Full tower case.
Rym: it weighs like 60 pounds.
Rym: Yeah, not full of sharp bits.
Rym: It's painful to maneuver in there.
Rym: My cables are a mess.
Scott: Mm-hmm What I look at is I always want to buy an aluminum case because aluminum is light.
Scott: those cases usually cost a little more but it's worth it and You want to if it's not like a crap.
Scott: Oh weird brand aluminum case.
Scott: It probably won't cut you.
Scott: It's well made.
Scott: You know this.
Scott: it comes with all the right screws quality parts, you know, aluminum is good get aluminum.
Rym: I mean basically just look on Newegg.
Rym: It's pretty obvious what cases are crap and which ones are good just by looking at him.
Scott: Yeah, you can look at something and be like hey that looks like you know something from the weird crap gamer rice store And you can look at something else and go.
Scott: Wow, that looks real slick.
Scott: Look at that.
Rym: your main choice is do you want a mini tower a mid tower or a full tower?
Rym: Mm-hmm, and basically if you don't know you want a mid tower.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: There's really no reason to get anything else mini tower.
Rym: You probably have room for everything you need unless space is a huge consideration for some reason.
Scott: Well, if you have if you know that the only thing you're gonna have in this computer is like one DVD ROM and one hard Drive and you know just the normal basic computer then a mini tower is all you need.
Scott: But if you ever think that you might add something to it, the mini tower might not hold it all.
Scott: So a mid tower is probably a better choice.
Rym: if you're not sure about your future and don't bother with a full tower I have one because back I mean I have a lot of hard drives in this computer because it's old and I do weird stuff Unless you're building a file server or something.
Rym: You don't need a full stop full tower.
Rym: You'll never fill it.
Rym: It'll have all these empty space.
Rym: You'll have long cables stretched to their limit.
Rym: You'll never be able to move the thing around.
Rym: It'll weigh a ton Mm-hmm.
Scott: and anyone who talks about air circulation with the full tower being better or whatever Don't don't listen to whatever they're saying though.
Rym: Cooling is key.
Rym: Make sure going is important with fans.
Scott: Yes, it has to be case that comes with the fans But I recommend you get a case with big fans.
Scott: Big fans are better than little fans or better than more little fans.
Scott: Yes You'll often see a case that has like in the back like two normal fan holes.
Scott: You're better off getting one giant fan.
Scott: The giant fans are rare, but they spin slower and they push more air per spin.
Scott: So you end up getting is you get something quieter that keeps your computer just as cool if not cooler?
Rym: and Despite all the crazy things you see you basically just need one intake fan in the front One exhaust fan in the back and your power supply will have an exhaust fan inside of it.
Scott: Yeah, and your CPU will come with a fan if you buy a retail CPU.
Rym: Yep, if you add your video card will have a little tiny fan on it.
Rym: Mm-hmm If you buy a crazy crazy fast computer like and you overclock it or something stupid You might get the blowhole on the side.
Rym: That is not necessary in any situation that any of you will probably ever be in.
Scott: there might be a hole in the top a Hole in the top.
Scott: that exhaust is sometimes good, too.
Rym: Yeah, they're not always because then that might draw exhaust away from the power supply Yep.
Rym: And the other rule of thumb is that you want more exhaust if you either want the fans to be equal meaning you want the same Amount of air being pushed in as is pulled out.
Rym: But if there's gonna be a discrepancy you always want more air being pulled out than being pushed in.
Scott: Yep, because basically all the parts of your computer make heat and the air in your computer case gets hot.
Scott: now If you just take the panel off the side of your computer and leave it wide open You know, you don't have to worry about that because the air just comes right out Which is in some cases worse because you get less optimal airflow Yep.
Scott: but if you have fans that work properly the hot air will be pulled out of the computer pretty easily and new cool air from your room or cooler air from your room will be pulled in and That keeps your computer running nicely.
Rym: So just remember always at least equal or more exhaust than intake Mm-hmm.
Rym: That is the primary rule of cooling and it'll serve you well.
Rym: Yep If you want liquid cooling or something Buy a case that has it and get people to do it for you because it's actually very difficult to do without ruining everything.
Rym: Yeah, it's not really worth the effort and my opinion and as you're crazy We're gonna do one final bit here because I know that we've gone long.
Rym: but the power supply Mmm, I know I've said I can't stress this enough too many times in the show.
Rym: I cannot stress enough.
Rym: do not skimp on the power supply.
Rym: a bad power supply can destroy your entire Computer and it won't be covered by warranty.
Scott: Yep Well is the thing about a power supply?
Scott: What it is?
Scott: is there's the electricity from the wall and there's a wire that goes from the wall to your computer.
Rym: The power coming in is AC and it's often dirty or at least not perfect.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, that wire goes not.
Scott: where does it go?
Scott: It goes into your power supply Which is this little metal box and then on the other end on the inside of your computer?
Scott: Coming out of this little metal box are a bunch of crazy wires and those wires go to your motherboard They go to your CD roms.
Scott: They go to your hard drives.
Scott: They go to your video cards.
Scott: sometimes they go to each part of your computer to provide power to make things go.
Scott: and that power supply box converts the power from the wall into the power your computer gets.
Scott: and If you have a lot of things in your computer, you need a power supply that can provide a lot of power.
Rym: Now the other.
Rym: the problem with this is that almost every power supply manufacturer in the world lies.
Rym: They lie outright and the wattage you see on a power supply is bullshit.
Scott: Pretty much almost all the time.
Scott: the wattage on the power supply really doesn't mean so much.
Rym: Now they would be fine if the industry was good and the wattage on the power supply meant how much power it can output Because then you would just buy what you needed.
Rym: and most computers don't need more than about 300 watts of actual power.
Scott: Yep, or 350 really?
Rym: You need like a 500 watt power supply to cover your 400 watts of use or your 300 watts of use.
Scott: It's always good to have even if it they're not lying because sometimes they're not.
Scott: it's good to have Power supply that can put out more power than you're using.
Scott: because then if you decide you want to add three hard drives You won't have to buy a new power supply.
Rym: not only that but the failure mode of a power supply.
Rym: the way it happens is basically the more the closer you are to the Peak output of the power supply the more it wears out the more likely it is to fail and the dirtier power It's gonna send to your motherboard a power.
Rym: And the more power supply fails the more it's gonna send spurious voltages to the motherboard which will cause your computer to crash Reboot randomly.
Rym: It'll destroy RAM sticks.
Rym: It might destroy a hard drive.
Scott: Yep There is one saving grace and that is if you try to take more power out of a power supply modern
Rym: power a
Scott: modern power supply meaning the past ten years or so Yeah, then if you try to take more out of it, then it can put out Let's say I plug in ten hard drives into an old 300 watt power supply.
Scott: It just won't turn on it won't work and It won't.
Scott: it's really hard to figure this out because it never tells you what's going on because it doesn't really have that ability.
Rym: Yeah, you basically have to sit there with a voltimeter to find out Yeah But you're on you don't?
Scott: you check over the inside of your computer and everything looks just fine?
Scott: And if you push the power button and nothing happens It's probably the power supply is either dead or it's refusing to turn on and what you should try to do is unplug as many things as you can.
Scott: Just run the bare minimum parts of your PC and see if it turns on.
Rym: or if you work with a lot of computers I recommend buying a power supply tester.
Rym: You can buy it like Circuit City or an tech.
Rym: They're like ten bucks.
Rym: They're just a thing.
Rym: you plug into that wire coming out of the power supply and you unplug everything else and you turn it on And it applies a load between two pins.
Rym: Well, you don't care.
Rym: basically if the light turns on the power supply works.
Rym: if the light doesn't turn on your power supply is dead.
Scott: Yep, I really didn't care about the power supply.
Scott: It wasn't an important part of the computer for me.
Scott: I just took whatever came with the case Because you can get cases that include power supplies and usually that might be a good idea, you know.
Scott: But anyway, I had one that came with the case and I didn't even think about it.
Scott: It worked.
Scott: and then one day I pushed the power button on my computer wouldn't turn on and it took me forever to realize Oh, the power supply is just bad it died And it just.
Scott: that was not something I thought about.
Scott: but now I think about it a lot and I bought this crazy power supply In my current computer, it's like blue and shiny and has fans and it's like 400 something watts.
Rym: Yep Now having way too much Having way too many things that your power supply can't power is fine because it won't start.
Rym: the most dangerous Situation you can be in is if you have just enough power because then every time the power supply burps it's sending bad voltage to your motherboard which stresses the capacitors and the power regulation circuits on the Motherboard and it's gonna ruin your computer.
Rym: Yeah, like really we're not kidding.
Scott: Mm-hmm So you want to have more power supply than you need and you don't want to buy something cheap and crappy.
Rym: So buy a name brand that comes in a nice box.
Rym: We're not gonna name brands because actually good brands come and go and the markets pretty volatile.
Scott: Mm-hmm You can always kind of trust actually the ones that you get in a box at like CompUSA.
Rym: Yep, those are usually pretty reliable even like the crap CompUSA brand ones are pretty good.
Scott: Yep, and Usually what you can tell is if you try to turn your.
Scott: another thing you can tell is I remember I had a computer where I thought that all you needed was a 300 watt because I still didn't realize what was going on.
Scott: and You know, I would push the button on the computer and it would just be like deep deep, but it wasn't a RAM error It was just some other beep error that I didn't know anything about.
Scott: That was because they didn't have enough power supply to turn the computer on and the motherboard was like hey I'm getting power but not enough.
Rym: Now there are crazy things you can do.
Rym: you can get multiple power supplies modular power supplies redundant power supplies But that's very difficult to do in consumer PCs.
Rym: So we really can't talk about it.
Scott: You don't really need that.
Scott: Anyway, just get one good power supply.
Rym: Yes And if you work it like if you're one of those people who has a million computers around the house and you're always fiddling with Old computers have an extra power supply around Mmm.
Scott: extra power supplies are very good to have.
Rym: Yes, because if your computer dies and you're panicking It's very nice to plug in a different power supply and see your computer boot because then you know It's just my power supply.
Rym: My computer's okay.
Rym: Thank the gods.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's.
Scott: one good thing about the power supply is if the power supply dies your data is still safe.
Rym: most likely I mean worst case scenario.
Rym: if a power supply dies, it usually destroys itself physically so that it can't hurt your computer.
Rym: Yep, but cheap power supplies or if they fail spectacularly will probably destroy your motherboard or processor.
Rym: Usually they destroy RAM before they destroy anything else or CPUs sometimes.
Rym: Yeah, CPU is actually the last thing to go because I deal with this a lot at work.
Rym: It'll destroy the RAM and the power regulation things on the motherboard before it does anything else.
Rym: Mmm, if it destroys the CPU you were fucked anyway.
Rym: Yeah But even if it destroys a hard drive the data is probably still there and it's really rare for a power supply to actually hurt a hard drive.
Rym: But still don't skimp Don't skimp don't skimp.
Scott: If you're not sure how much why did you need go look online and see what other people with similarly powerful computers are getting?
Scott: and If you can't find that out just call the people who make your motherboard on the phone and be like, hey What kind of?
Scott: or call whoever you're buying the parts from and say hey, what kind of?
Scott: uh, you know?
Scott: How much power supply do I need for all this stuff?
Scott: and someone will probably be able to make you a good recommendation.
Scott: Because Seriously, like the 600 watt power supplies the crazy ones You really only need those if you're like the crazy gamer with the two video cards and the five hard drives and the two burners And whatnot.
Rym: Yep, and if you really want to get crazy and build a computer with a ton of hard drives or something weird You can just have two power supplies and there are ways to do that It's I'm not gonna explain how to do it now because you have to do some wiring But you can do things like that if you really want.
Scott: Yeah, the trick is to find a case in a motherboard that support that and usually those are like the server motherboards that take two Processors and all that.
Scott: but yeah, that's not a desktop computer.
Scott: Who cares?
Rym: so That those are basically all the main components and we've gone long.
Rym: So we're just gonna stop here.
Scott: Yeah, Joe just one last sentence.
Scott: You need a keyboard and a mouse.
Scott: Get a keyboard you like a USB keyboard Wireless if you really want to.
Rym: probably QWERTY because we were gonna do a whole show on this.
Rym: but don't bother with Dvorak.
Scott: Well, you know unless you're already a Dvorak guy.
Rym: Yeah, but there are there issues.
Rym: Yeah, I am very Sour.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I thought I was only say one sentence.
Scott: Then buy a mouse that feels comfortable on your hand and is also USB wireless if you want to yep, and make sure it has all the buttons you like to use and then plug everything in and turn your computer on and It'll work if you do it, right?
Rym: Yeah, we really got to work on these ending the podcast gracefully.
Scott: Well, that would be a graceful ending wouldn't it?
Rym: Oh it would but too late.
Scott: I ruined it.
Rym: Haha And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds dot be burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.