Rym: It's Tuesday, December 20th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we talk about Final Fantasy Advance 4.
Rym: Alright, let's do this.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: So, I have, you know, normal $10 Sony earbud headphones.
Rym: Yep, yep, and they're kinda crappy.
Scott: In fact, they broke.
Scott: My brother, in fact, had the same ones.
Scott: They also broke in the same manner.
Scott: And not to mention that they damage hearing.
Rym: Yes, significantly so, in fact.
Rym: More so than you might think.
Scott: Like, I didn't know it, but then I checked up, and apparently, because they don't block out any external sound, people tend to turn them way, way up.
Scott: And having things with all those extra decibels for extended periods of time damages hearing a lot.
Rym: And it used to be not a big issue, back in the days of, you know, Walkmans and Discmen.
Rym: And there's a very simple reason for that.
Rym: People didn't listen to their Discman 24 hours a frickin' day.
Scott: Yeah, but my iPod Nano can hold 4 gigs of music, and the battery lasts 8+ hours.
Rym: Fantastic.
Scott: And it's really small, and I can take it with me anywhere, and I can jog with it, and who knows.
Scott: So, there's really potential to damage my hearing significantly.
Scott: Like, we're talking multiple rock concerts per day significantly.
Scott: So, I wanted to get new headphones, and the obvious solution was to get those big ones to cover your ear, and maybe have noise cancelling, and all that good stuff to save my hearing.
Scott: But, those really aren't portable.
Scott: And I go on a train, and I go to work, and- What's wrong with wearing giant frickin' headphones on the train?
Scott: There's nothing wrong with wearing giant frickin' headphones on the train, other than if you try to lean on something to get in the way, but it's transporting the giant headphones that is a problem.
Rym: You just wear 'em around your neck and be all cool.
Scott: No, it's not cool.
Scott: And it's not comfortable, either.
Scott: You can do it if you want, but it's not my preference.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: So, a co-worker informed me of a solution.
Scott: There are headphones that you stick in your ear.
Scott: Like, all the way in.
Scott: Like, you jam 'em in there.
Scott: And they block out external sounds.
Rym: Yeah, these things are like a vacuum seal.
Rym: I tried 'em on, and it's like, going in, going in, suddenly there's this suction, and there you go.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You know how, like, when you put your finger in your ear, and all of a sudden all the noises are in your head, and you can hear, like, things touching you, or things in your mouth get really loud, but anything outside your head is like, you can't hear it at all?
Scott: That's what it's like.
Scott: It's like the headphones are not only headphones, but are fingers that are in your ear.
Rym: So, uh, you used to make fun of people, like our friend Ken, who bought the crazy expensive awesome headphones.
Rym: But, uh, I think you see the light now?
Scott: Well, those were, you know, his were a little more than mine were.
Rym: Well, his headphones are insane.
Rym: We got a friend who's got, like, these multi-hundred dollar velvet-lined, like, monitor headphones of the gods.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like, they're better than our stereo.
Scott: Yeah, well, the point is that these headphones are pretty much as good as headphones need to be, unless you're a DJ.
Rym: Yeah, and, you know, they'll save your hearing, so, uh...
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The other thing was, I didn't get them at, like, a normal store.
Scott: I went, and, 'cause I was worried that they were gonna be, like, when she told me about them, I thought it was gonna be an audiophile place with all kinds of bull- Yeah, wasn't it called Audio Lab?
Scott: No, it's called Scientific Plastics.
Rym: Ah.
Scott: So I went over there, and it was just a lab with, like, three old guys in it, and they had the headphones, and they sold them to me, and I paid them my credit card like a store, but these were guys who, uh, made hearing aids, and ear plugs for musicians, and all kinds of custom things in the shape of the hole in your ear, for you.
Rym: They definitely know what they're doing.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely was science, and not BS, and if a guy makes a hearing aid, I trust him to sell me something that doesn't damage my hearing.
Rym: Though, actually, a lot of hearing aids, there are problems where they'll damage people's hearing over time, and it's a trade-off between hearing things now and not hearing things later.
Scott: Well, as if you're really deaf, then they have to put- the only way you can hear with a hearing aid is make it really loud, and there's no way around that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But these guys definitely knew what was up, and it was a cool place.
Rym: I like how your receipt looked more like a prescription than it did a receipt.
Scott: Yeah, it was a handwritten deal, you know, it wasn't a store, so what do you expect?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Though, in real news, most of you probably don't care if you don't live in New York, but there's this transit strike going on.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: So all the subways and buses and everything aren't running?
Scott: Nope, not at all.
Rym: And it doesn't affect us at all, because the train that goes between here and the city, while it's part of MTA, the workers on the train aren't striking.
Scott: Yeah, the strike is a transit union strike, not an MTA strike.
Scott: So the MTA is actually pissed at the transit union.
Scott: Like, "Get to work, you
Scott: asshats!".
Scott: But the transit union, which is the buses and subways, are not working.
Scott: And they're going to be in big trouble.
Rym: Yep, they're being fined a million dollars per day.
Scott: So, and if you're a worker, and let's say you make ten bucks a day, I'm just, no one makes ten bucks a day, but I'm just picking a number.
Rym: Well, in the West.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But I'm just picking a number, just to make the math easier.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They're fined twenty dollars a day.
Rym: So not only do they not get their ten bucks, but they owe the government twenty dollars.
Scott: Well, they owe the government ten bucks.
Scott: Because they take away the ten bucks you would have made, well...
Rym: No, they're not making money because they're not working.
Scott: Ah, that's true.
Scott: If they were, well, I guess if they...
Rym: If they were working, there wouldn't be an issue.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like, even though it sounds like double-suck, it's really triple-suck, because you don't make the ten dollars you would have made, unless you're a salary, I guess, unless you get a paid vacation, who knows?
Rym: Well, strike is a weird situation, because the transit union, public workers, in New York, at least, don't have the legal right to strike.
Rym: But they have the legal right to unionize.
Rym: Which is kind of weird, because the primary power of a union is its ability to strike.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So it was kind of like this union existed, but couldn't really do anything, and they said they were going to strike, and the mayor said, "If you strike, I'll destroy you, and you'll all go to jail,".
Rym: and they struck anyway, and no one knows what to do, and the city's grinding to a halt.
Scott: Well, it's not grinding to a halt for me.
Scott: I'm just fine.
Rym: Yeah, because you take Metro North, which isn't striking, and then you walk a few blocks.
Rym: That's great.
Rym: What about the people living in Brooklyn?
Rym: We gotta get to Queens.
Scott: They can walk over the Brooklyn Bridge.
Scott: If you live in Queens, don't go to work.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There were a lot of private buses driving around.
Scott: There were a lot of cabs going around.
Rym: The funny thing is, they're not letting anyone drive into Manhattan in the morning, unless they have four or more people in their car.
Rym: So, there were funny scenes.
Rym: If you look around on Flickr, on the internet, you'll find pictures of this.
Rym: Expensive, expensive luxury SUVs with cardboard signs in the windows, let's say like Bowery trying to pick up bums or people to sit with them so they can drive into the city.
Rym: It was hilarious.
Scott: Great.
Scott: That's cool.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Though, there's actually a whole bunch of big news today, but this one made us very happy, and so we really want to talk about it, and the forums, I put a thing about it already, and people were talking about it.
Rym: Intelligent Design lost to science, logic, and reason.
Scott: Gee, I could have told you that was going to happen.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I was worried about what would happen, but I was worried that maybe the judge was going to rule on a technicality, or skirt around the issue, or say something like, "Yeah, Intelligent Design might have been valid, but this case specifically,
Rym: blah.".
Rym: Because this case specifically was kind of blah.
Rym: The people involved were actually trying to push creationism, and just using Intelligent Design as a cover.
Scott: I hate it when that happens, when you want the judge to say something about an issue in general, but all he does is say something about that case, which leaves all the other cases up in the air.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or the Supreme Court does that a lot.
Rym: Like, when there was the case of the guy who didn't want Under God to be in the Pledge of Allegiance, they threw the lawsuit out, no contest, on a technicality, because they didn't want to worry about it right now.
Scott: It also is kind of stupid, but...
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But they threw the case out, they didn't rule.
Rym: either way, they just kind of said, "Ehh, technicality, go
Rym: away.".
Scott: See, but in a perfect, if our country was good, and not all broken, then you do want judges to just rule on the case at hand, and not in general, because it's really Congress's job to rule in general.
Rym: The problem is, there are some cases lately that we really need an actual ruling, because Congress isn't stepping up.
Scott: No, they're sucking, because they don't want to lose votes, so they end up not doing anything, because that would mean, responsibility.
Scott: Illities!
Rym: People don't like abilities.
Scott: Congress has no illities, and they need some.
Scott: They have no abilities, no responsibilities, nothing.
Rym: Though, not only did the judge rule against the school board, and not only did he rule pretty much exactly the way intelligent people around the world wanted him to, he went about as far as I would have gone had I been the judge in this case.
Rym: He had such choice quotes as, "Our conclusion today is that it is unconstitutional to teach intelligent design as an alternative to evolution in a public
Rym: school.".
Rym: And my favorite quote, the judge actually said this in his decision, "It is ironic that several of these individuals who so staunchly and so proudly touted their religious convictions in public, would time and time again lie in my courtroom to cover their tracks and disguise the real purpose behind this ID
Rym: policy.".
Scott: Wow.
Scott: I don't know why he didn't perjury them if you thought they were lying.
Rym: He said he could have.
Scott: He should have contempted them, at least.
Rym: Yeah, he could have been contempted and perjured almost every one of the defendants in this case.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, but this is a far-reaching ruling, and due to a technicality, there can't be an appeal.
Scott: You know, what do you do if you're in a court case and a scientist comes up as a witness, as an expert witness, and he says, "Evolution is bullshit.
Scott: Is that perjury?
Scott: Can you jail
Scott: him?"?
Rym: No, because you can't be perjured for what you believe to be true.
Rym: So if you're crazy, and you say something that you think is true, or it can be shown that you thought it was true, they can't get you for perjury.
Scott: What if I just go in and be like, "The sky is green!
Rym: La la la la la la la
Rym: la!"?
Rym: They'll probably just get you for contempt for being an idiot.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Things like that don't come up often, though actually it's come up a lot recently with, not to get into it, but you know the whole Catholic church, little boys, scandals that have been going around for the last, I don't know, 20 years?
Rym: Apparently, and I remember learning about this in Catholic school, because I went to Catholic school in my younger days, but there is an idea in the Catholic church called "mental
Rym: reservation."
Rym: Because I don't know how much any of you know about Catholicism, but you have to regularly confess all your sins to a priest or you'll go to hell.
Scott: Great.
Rym: So you confess your sins to priests.
Rym: Fine.
Rym: Priests, supposedly, will listen to you, but will not ever tell anyone, no matter what, what you've told them.
Rym: Even if, say, a priest, say you confess that you murdered a bunch of people to a priest, and then you get caught, and the police find out that you confessed to this priest, and they want the priest to testify.
Rym: He won't.
Rym: And technically, it'd be perjury if he didn't testify, or if he lied.
Scott: Well, no, it's only perjury if he goes on the stand and lies.
Scott: They can't force him to testify.
Rym: Well, if he wouldn't testify, then it would be obstruction of justice.
Scott: Well, they need a summons or a subpoena or one of those things that makes him be a witness no matter what.
Rym: Yes, and if they got him in and he still wouldn't testify, obstruction of justice.
Scott: But... Is it really obstruction of justice if you don't say anything?
Rym: It depends.
Rym: It can be.
Rym: It's kind of... Do you have to answer?
Rym: You only don't have to answer if you might incriminate yourself.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: So if you're not incriminating yourself, like if I saw you kill someone and I just don't want to say it, I have to?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Or they can make me say it?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know that.
Rym: Which is a good thing because theoretically our courts are supposed to get to the truth of matters and find justice.
Rym: But you don't have to testify if it'll screw you.
Scott: See, but here's the thing, here's the thing.
Scott: Let's say I see you kill someone, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they bring me in and they try to make me talk, right?
Scott: Now, all they're doing is asking me a question and I have to provide an answer.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now, if I say I saw you kill them, well then everything just goes nicely.
Scott: But if I say no, then they have to have evidence that says I'm lying.
Scott: And if they have evidence that says I'm lying, why do they even need me for anyway?
Rym: See, things like that, I don't know, I never, I mean, I've seen one murder trial, like one actual real trial ever.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: I was in the courtroom for it.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: And things never turn out the way you might think they turn out in a trial like that.
Rym: Everyone's real.
Rym: in eloquence, the judge is usually kind of eh, no one really knows what's going on.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: The witnesses usually just say whatever.
Rym: A lot of times they just they just, you don't, like you can't even understand what they're talking about.
Rym: They go off on tangents.
Rym: Nothing makes sense.
Scott: Oh, okay, because I did listen to an audio of a, on this lawyer podcast of a lawyer making a really bad argument in court.
Scott: Like, it was just hilarious.
Scott: And it sounded like real, and what the judge said sounded like real TV quality court drama, but it was a real court.
Rym: I think it's real hit or miss, because the trial I saw was a. it was a federal trial in Detroit.
Rym: I went to watch it for a. there was some class project.
Rym: I had to go watch a trial.
Rym: And we saw there was this murder trial, so we watched it.
Rym: We were the only people in the audience.
Scott: Oh, cool.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, they have this doctrine called mental reservation, which is an internal church thing where basically a priest can say to himself, it's okay for me to lie and say that he never confessed anything, because I would be violating church rules to say anything because he confessed it in confidence.
Scott: Well, they're going to perjury him right away, aren't they?
Rym: Not because they usually can't prove that the guy said anything.
Scott: Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Scott: Doesn't the priest, like, swear on, like, a Bible before he sucks?
Rym: Yes, yes.
Scott: So isn't he going to hell?
Scott: Isn't he catch-22ing himself?
Rym: No, no, you didn't even listen to me.
Rym: That's what mental reservation is.
Rym: It's okay to lie if it serves the greater good.
Rym: That is the doctrine of Catholicism.
Scott: So even though he swears to God that he's going to tell the truth, the whole truth, nothing but the truth, so help him God.
Scott: And he thinks he's a god.
Rym: Well, you realize you don't have to say so.
Rym: help you God.
Scott: Oh, that's good.
Scott: But at least he swears.
Rym: Or you have to swear on a Bible.
Scott: Well, you still have to swear.
Rym: Yeah, you have to swear.
Rym: I'm not going to, unless you're a Mormon.
Rym: They can't make you take an oath, really.
Rym: But you're still, you're still on the, you can still be perjured.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's all complicated.
Rym: Don't worry about it.
Rym: We got off on a tangent.
Scott: Yeah, but I still see a catch-22 where they swear, and then they don't.
Rym: That's what the mental reservation doctrine is.
Rym: It states that it's okay to lie.
Rym: It is not a sin to lie.
Scott: Even if you swear that you're not going to lie?
Rym: Yes, because you're lying to serve the greater good by not revealing something that was told to you in the confidence of a church ritual.
Scott: But you see, then there's a question of isn't putting the murderer in jail the greater good, not letting him walk the streets?
Rym: No, because you're supposed to be able to confess no matter what without any fear of retribution down the earth.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm not saying I agree with it.
Rym: I'm not a Catholic, but I grew up and I went to a Catholic school, and I still remember all that interesting stuff we learned.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I just thought of the guy in Les Mis where he lets the thief go and he gives him all the silver.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: See, that's a cool priest.
Rym: We need more priests like that.
Scott: Yeah, but I totally would have let him take the silver and then have the cops grab him.
Rym: You ass.
Scott: He's a fucking thief, man.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, give a guy a chance.
Scott: He had his chance.
Scott: He still stole from me.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, um...
Rym: So basically, intelligent design was smacked down with no chance of appeal.
Scott: Fair.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Alright, so, Google Google, Google, Google, Google.
Scott: They have this thing called the zeitgeist which they put out once a month or whatever.
Scott: it updates semi-infrequently.
Scott: I think it's a manual update they do.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And it gives you statistics like here's the most popular search, here's the most popular sports search, here's the most popular famous people searches, right?
Rym: It's usually really surprising.
Rym: It reminds me that most people on the internet are not geeks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And, uh, because it's almost the end of the year, they've released the 2005 year-end Google zeitgeist and it's like six pages of stats and graphs and lists.
Scott: And it's really freaking cool and interesting to see what shows up here.
Rym: Yeah, apparently Ares the God of War is the number two gainer in terms of search terms.
Scott: Yeah, it's actually a peer-to-peer network.
Rym: Yeah, and a company and a bunch of other stuff but I'm pretty sure the peer-to-peer network is the primary.
Scott: The number one gaining search is Myspace.
Rym: Not HiSpace?
Scott: No, not HiSpace, sadly.
Scott: Uh, Baidu, which is a Chinese search engine that's number three but because it lets you search for MP3s and such.
Rym: Yep, it's basically Google only Chinese.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Then you've got Wikipedia, Orcutt, iTunes, Sky News which is a, I think it's a European TV channel, World of Warcraft, Green Day.
Rym: Yeah, I want Green Day is like having this resurgence in popularity.
Scott: I'll have to go see if their new music is any good or not.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: And then, DaVinci.
Scott: Hey, what do you know, number ten.
Rym: I have a feeling that's because of the DaVinci code and not so much because of anyone's actual interest in history.
Scott: Oh, that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: Though something scary.
Rym: remember the Janet Jackson boob thing way way back?
Rym: Mhm.
Rym: That's still the top search in Google News.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: More people searched for Janet Jackson in Google News than any other thing.
Scott: Number two was Katrina which is understandable.
Rym: Number three was Tsunami.
Scott: Yeah, Tsunami, which is a bigger disaster than Katrina, was one less.
Scott: And then you have Xbox 360, Brad Pitt, Michael Jackson, famous people, famous people, whatever.
Scott: Frugal, which is where you can search to buy things and it gives you the lowest prices.
Rym: It's almost all Apple products.
Scott: It's all iPod, iPod, iPod, four of the top ten are iPod.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Digital camera is number two.
Scott: MP3 player, which is kind of like one half of iPod, so four and a half iPod.
Scott: Computer desk, not bad.
Scott: Xbox, PSP, laptop.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Rym: You know, Apple is doing real well with this whole iPod thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The other areas of statistics are world affairs, nature, movies, celebrities and phenomena.
Rym: They have cool graphs.
Rym: Like, you can see spikes, like when something happens, what people are looking for.
Scott: Since I'm not really interested in nature or celebrities, I'm only gonna look at the other three.
Scott: Gonna look at the world affairs.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Oh, this shows you, there's a graph and it shows you that when the search, how how much people search for London.
Scott: And you can see that during the week, searches for London go up and each week end, it goes down.
Scott: So it's like up, down, up, down, up, down, up, down, right?
Rym: Luckily, more people search for the force than the dark side.
Rym: Though the dark side had a couple of spikes, but they didn't beat out the force.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You can also see when the pope died, searches for John Paul jumped up a little bit.
Scott: Then it went, you know, it kind of went down a bit.
Scott: And then when Ratzinger was elected, searches for him went way up, way higher than searches for the previous pope.
Scott: But then they dropped down to nothing.
Scott: But the John Paul still gets a, you know, a significant amount of searches, even to this day.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Despite all the Harry Potter phenomena, Hogwarts is searched for very little compared to Middle Earth.
Scott: Hooray!
Rym: And surprisingly, March of the Penguins had this like crazy, crazy search spike.
Scott: I don't even know what that is.
Rym: It's that documentary about penguins.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: All of our friends went to see it.
Rym: And they all said it was awesome.
Rym: Lisa in particular pretty much just bugged about it for like a week straight.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, here's some interesting ones.
Scott: Wikipedia, you can see it jumping up and down, you know, with it coming down on the weekends, has been going up a whole lot since August.
Scott: It was kind of like,
Scott: "Oh!"
Scott: And it's really getting crazy now.
Rym: I think part of that has to do with, it's been in the mainstream news a lot.
Scott: Yeah, Wikipedia is getting a little, uh...
Rym: A lot of bad press.
Scott: Yeah, but I like it.
Scott: It's going up, and that can only be good for Wikipedia.
Rym: I think Penny Arcade's comic about it was probably all we need to see.
Scott: Flawless.
Scott: There's a little Black Friday searching.
Scott: You can see people looking for the sails.
Scott: Oh, here's one.
Scott: It has skateboarding, snowboarding, and surfing, right?
Scott: Apparently surfing is more than skateboarding.
Rym: Um, I know that that's probably because surfing also includes the web.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one thing that I want to know.
Scott: I'm pretty sure Google is smart, you know, and they know these things, but how can they tell the difference between someone searching for web surfing and surfing surfing?
Rym: They probably can't.
Rym: They probably just throw these statistics up like, "Hey, here you
Rym: go.".
Rym: Ah.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: That kind of makes some of these a little silly.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What do you want?
Scott: Well, the last graph I want to talk about is this one has a squiggle for MP3, which is way up there, right?
Scott: Then there's a squiggle for iPod, which is much, much lower, but it had a huge jump when the Nano came out, and another little spike when the video one was announced, and since the Nano came out, iPod searches went to a new level and kind of stayed there.
Scott: Podcast searches have been increasing, and at some point, which isn't labeled, I think it was when, but it looks like the middle of the year when podcasts became on iTunes, it jumped up a little bit, and it's kind of slowly increasing.
Scott: It's like an unstable, very small bit, which means there's a lot of room for growth there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, seriously, we look at our statistics.
Rym: Almost none of you use the RSS feed or iTunes.
Rym: You're all just coming to the site, clicking on the link every day.
Scott: Yeah, use the RSS feed.
Rym: Be the new wave.
Rym: Be cool.
Rym: Be geeky.
Scott: It's much easier.
Scott: Imagine you just wake up, and you go to your computer, and well, there it is.
Scott: You didn't even have to push a button.
Scott: You don't have to visit our site.
Scott: You don't have to do anything.
Scott: You just automatically, the podcast will be on your computer whenever there's a new one.
Scott: Of course!
Scott: I mean, what do you do?
Scott: What if one day, we release a special episode on a Saturday, and you don't check?
Scott: If you use the feed, you'll get it on the Saturday.
Rym: Of course!
Rym: Not to sabotage ourselves.
Rym: Still go to the site and check out the forums.
Scott: Oh yeah, of course.
Scott: The forums are very important.
Scott: What you want to do is you want to subscribe to the feed and bookmark the forums, and then forget about the site, because the feed has everything that's on the site.
Rym: Ah, the site has the links.
Rym: So if you don't know what we're talking about.
Scott: If you need the links, you can go to the site, but the links are also in the feed if you use a feed reader that supports that.
Rym: See, I was just saying, because honestly, I don't use the RSS feeds, and anything I listen to, I go to the site and click.
Scott: Well, that's because you're no good.
Rym: I don't even have an iPod.
Scott: You don't need an iPod to do podcasting.
Rym: I don't have any sort of portable music whatsoever.
Scott: You should get some.
Rym: I will eventually.
Rym: I'm buying a new computer first.
Scott: That's probably a good idea.
Rym: So, my thing of the day.
Rym: I will say right now that I saw, I see one reference to my thing of the day, so while I'm going to present it as my thing of the day, I do not endorse 100% that.
Rym: I believe this is factual.
Scott: Great, so it might be a false thing of the day.
Rym: Well, it might be, but Joseph Stalin was crazy enough to where I really don't put it past him.
Scott: Oh, Stalin?
Scott: Yeah, he was crazy.
Rym: Yeah, basically, this is an article on The Scotsman, talking about how... The Scotsman?
Rym: Yeah, it's actually a fairly well-known, pretty good news source.
Scott: Of Scottish?
Rym: No, just called The Scotsman.
Rym: I don't know if it's from Scotland or what.
Rym: It's on Fark all the time.
Scott: Willy must read it.
Scott: Ugh.
Scott: Bagpipes, golf.
Rym: If this is to be believed, then Stalin said the following, "I want a new, invincible human being, insensitive to pain, resistant, and indifferent about the quality of food they
Rym: eat.".
Rym: He wanted a, quote, "living war
Rym: machine.".
Rym: So in 1926, he got the Politburo to pass a request to the Academy of Science to try to make a monkey-man hybrid soldier-type creature.
Rym: So they tried, supposedly, experiments of breeding humans and monkeys, artificial types, not, you know, bestial ways.
Rym: Ew.
Rym: Yeah, and they tried to impregnate a bunch of women with monkey sperm.
Rym: Didn't work.
Rym: Tried to impregnate a bunch of monkeys with women, with men's sperm, or, like, fertilized human eggs, and nothing worked.
Rym: Monkey, monkey!
Rym: And eventually, the scientist who was in charge of it was sent to jail for failing.
Scott: Oh.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, God shmud, I want my monkey-man.
Scott: [laughter] The thing is, the one question I have about that is, why do they think a monkey-man would be impervious to pain and not care about what food you give it, and all those things?
Rym: I think they just wanted an animal that was smart enough to use a gun or dig a trench, but not smart enough to want anything more than food at the end of the day.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: 'Cause the Soviet army had a lot of trouble in those days feeding its army.
Scott: You could've just trained monkeys.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know, but they wanted to make some sort of monkey-man.
Rym: And they failed.
Scott: Great.
Rym: And that's the end of that.
Rym: And there's a picture of Stalin.
Scott: You know, if you'd just waited, like, a thousand years, some of those monkeys might evolve into, like, Cro-Magnums or something.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Zayas, Dr.
Rym: Zayas!
Scott: Ohhhhh, Dr.
Scott: Zayas.
Rym: So what's your thing?
Scott: Well, you know what the best airplane ever is?
Rym: Uh, to me, would be the F-22.
Scott: No, it's not the best airplane ever.
Rym: Or the F-117A 'cause I think it's cool-looking.
Scott: Oh, the triangle-pointy one?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's cool, but it's not--.
Rym: I'm partial to the F-16 because it's so widespread, and I actually sat in one once.
Scott: Isn't that the pointy bit at the front?
Rym: It's the basic fighter jet.
Scott: It has that, like, pointy needle in the front.
Rym: Oh yeah, with a hole in the end of it.
Scott: Yeah, that one.
Scott: But no, none of those are quite as cool as the SR-71 Blackbird.
Rym: Ah, the SR-71 Blackbird.
Scott: Completely useless, and completely scary.
Rym: It was actually really, really useful back in the day.
Rym: It's just not useful now.
Rym: It was fast.
Rym: It's real fast.
Rym: In fact, it's still one of the fastest planes ever made.
Rym: Not counting the X-Series, which aren't really planes.
Rym: They're just rockets that go sideways.
Scott: Like the scram jets and whatnot, but the X-Men got more use out of the Blackbird than the US military.
Rym: Yeah, yet they could somehow fit people.
Rym: You realize there's no cargo space in a Blackbird?
Scott: Yeah, yet somehow they have, like, tons of people in it, and it goes into space, and God knows what they do with this thing.
Rym: Yeah, I remember in the cartoon, because they skipped a lot in the cartoon, and at one point, like, suddenly they're all sitting on the Blackbird going into space, and then they crash.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And then, you know, the Dark Phoenix side.
Scott: I think they just have a really big SR-71 Blackbird on X-Men.
Rym: Because that works.
Scott: But anyway, I found all of the diagrams of the SR-71 Blackbird online.
Rym: Let's learn how to fly one.
Scott: I don't think we can learn how to fly one from the diagrams, but there is the best diagram that shows the instrument panels, which is every button and display and gadget and dial that the pilot sees and has access to.
Rym: Whoa, that's complicated.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: With, uh, labels.
Scott: Let's see if I can read any of these labels.
Scott: Temperature indicator.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It indicates temperature.
Scott: Fuel and something control panel.
Rym: Alright, great.
Rym: Let's not read the labels.
Rym: You're not getting anywhere with this.
Scott: Throttle one something.
Rym: Anyway...
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of freakin' knobs on this fucker.
Scott: God, I couldn't fly one without, like, weeks and weeks and weeks of training.
Scott: God.
Scott: So, if you ever see one flying, just know that if you look at this, you'll appreciate how skilled the person flying it is.
Rym: You know, you do realize that there aren't any anymore.
Rym: They were decommissioned quite some time ago.
Scott: There are still some.
Rym: Not that are flyable.
Rym: They're all pretty much dismantled in museums.
Scott: Oh, you can get it out of a museum and make it work.
Rym: Probably not.
Rym: Not easily.
Scott: Well, you know what I'm gonna do when I'm a rich man?
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: Of course, who knows if there'll be anyone left who knows how to fly it by then.
Rym: So, moving on, today is Tuesday.
Scott: Tuesday.
Rym: Which is video game day.
Scott: Video games.
Rym: And, well, it's not just video games.
Rym: It's also board games and, you know, gaming in general.
Scott: But we haven't played any other games.
Rym: Yeah, and we only have one new video game, even though I'm very pleased with it.
Rym: I've almost beaten it, even though I've only had it for a few days.
Rym: I picked up Final Fantasy IV Advance for the GBA.
Rym: Now, Final Fantasy IV.
Scott: Oh, wait, wait, wait, sorry, sorry, wait.
Rym: Final Fantasy IV was released in the US as Final Fantasy II.
Rym: Now, we are going to use the Japanese numbering system because it makes more sense.
Scott: Because anyone who is using the American numbering system is an idiot who doesn't know dick about Final Fantasy.
Rym: Well, basically, there's Final Fantasy I, which was supposed.
Rym: basically, it's actually, a lot of people think this is an urban myth, but it's true.
Rym: The company that made Final Fantasy I was going out of business.
Rym: Also, a guy was retiring.
Rym: It was called Final Fantasy because it was going to quite literally be the Final Fantasy and then they were shutting their doors.
Rym: And it did so well, they stayed in business and made eleven, twelve, fifteen more games.
Rym: And they're still making them.
Scott: Fifteen more games?
Rym: Well, think, there's Final Fantasy I through XII.
Rym: There's, uh, Final Fantasy Legends 13, 14, 15.
Rym: There's Final Fantasy Adventure, though those weren't really Final Fantasy.
Rym: That doesn't count.
Scott: That doesn't count.
Rym: There's Mystic Quest, which was made by, like, Square USA or something.
Rym: It wasn't actually made by them.
Scott: 16.
Scott: Final Fantasy X2.
Scott: 17.
Rym: Ah, yeah.
Scott: 17 Final Fantasy games?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, Final Fantasy II and Final Fantasy III were released in Japan on the NES, and they were just sequels to Final Fantasy I. Yep.
Rym: They were never released in the United States on the Nintendo.
Scott: Never.
Rym: II was recently released on Dawn of Souls, which contains Final Fantasy I and II for the GBA.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I recommend checking that out if you want.
Rym: I recommend, honestly, not bothering with playing Final Fantasy II or III on the NES, because while they're cool games, I guess, "tease" and "arbitrary" are the two words I would use.
Scott: You know, I think we can apply those words to all Final Fantasies, but especially II and III.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And I, actually.
Rym: No, not I so much.
Rym: Not compared to II, III, and V. Yeah.
Rym: V, I think, is probably the worst when it comes to tediousness.
Scott: Mm, the tediousness is the number one reason I don't play these games so much anymore.
Rym: Yep, but that's why you're really gonna like these re-releases, because they fix that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, III is gonna be re-released for the DS in 3D.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: And that looks like it might be cool.
Rym: III was basically like I in terms of, it's just an "explore this cool world,".
Rym: blah blah blah, whatever, there's no real backstory to your characters, but it was a fun game.
Rym: Mm.
Rym: IV was released as II for the Super Nintendo.
Scott: But it's really IV.
Rym: Yep, and IV Advance is what I have.
Rym: Now, there's a funny story regarding IV, for those of you who don't know.
Rym: Final Fantasy IV was released in Japan in two versions.
Rym: Easy Type and Hard Type.
Scott: Hard Type is what Japanese people play.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Hard Type is the actual game, and Final Fantasy IV Advance is essentially Hard Type.
Rym: Final Fantasy II, as it was called in the US, was the children's version of the game that took out most of the special abilities, most of the secrets, made the monsters ten times easier, and took out a bunch of plot.
Scott: This is because Japanese people thought Americans were stupid and we wouldn't play the game if it was as hard as Japanese people had it, so they sold us the easy one.
Rym: Yeah, that's quite literally what happened.
Scott: Yep, so if you have only played Final Fantasy II for the, you know, American number two for the SNES, which is Final Fantasy IV, you should get this GBA version so you can, you know, play the game for real, instead of playing whatever crap game you played.
Rym: And I'll go into it in great detail in a minute.
Rym: Final Fantasy V for the Super Nintendo was not released in the US because it was incredibly difficult and strange.
Rym: It was just a fucker.
Rym: Yeah, it's real hard, and I had a lot of trouble with it.
Scott: And the plot really wasn't so interesting.
Rym: Yeah, IV, I mean, for those of you who played IV, that plot was kind of cool.
Rym: I think it would make a good movie.
Rym: V's plot was kind of silly.
Scott: I don't even remember anything, or any character, because it was just...
Rym: You don't remember The Pirate Girl?
Scott: You know, I played, the non-American games I played in poorly translated ROMs during, like, one year of my life, when, uh, I think maybe, like, eight years ago.
Scott: So, they don't exactly stick in my memory so much, considering some of them I didn't even finish, because it wasn't worth it.
Scott: But VI, however...
Rym: Yep, VI, AKA Final Fantasy III in the United States, is considered by many to be the pinnacle of Final Fantasy gaming.
Scott: It is the pinnacle of Final Fantasy gaming.
Rym: I don't know, I like IV more, but I still respect VI as awesome.
Scott: VI is the bestest.
Rym: Yep, and then there was VII.
Scott: Everybody knows it.
Rym: VII was actually really good, too.
Rym: I mean, honestly, I hate to sound like an old crotchety man, but I really consider Final Fantasy VII to be the last true Final Fantasy.
Scott: I don't even consider VII to be the true Final Fantasy.
Rym: I think it is.
Rym: I think it's a logical extension of VI.
Scott: Ehh, kinda, maybe.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, the gameplay, the way it worked out, it was basically just an extension of VI.
Rym: Ehh.
Rym: Just with better technology.
Rym: And then Final Fantasy went, well, the thing is, after VII, Final Fantasy went in this completely other direction.
Rym: And I can't stand any of them.
Rym: Final Fantasy VIII was painful.
Rym: I loved the plot.
Rym: It would have been a great movie.
Rym: I ended up watching someone else beat it so I could see what happens.
Rym: I just couldn't deal with that stupid game.
Scott: Man, I played the demo of VIII for the PC, 'cause I didn't have a Playstation, right?
Scott: And I was playing, and I was doing alright, and I didn't understand really what was going on, but I didn't care.
Scott: And then it said I had to use this junction to combine magics.
Rym: And I couldn't figure out how the hell to do it.
Scott: It told me exactly what to do.
Scott: It was like go to this menu and do this and then push this button.
Scott: And I couldn't make this thing happen.
Scott: The menus were just so complicated.
Scott: In about five minutes, I gave up and I said, screw this game, it's not worth it.
Scott: Nine, I actually, someone else got nine the day it came out and I watched them play it.
Scott: And it would look better than VIII, you know, and it seemed to hearken back to previous Final Fantasies with, you know, like, the character who looked like a black mage and that sort of thing.
Scott: But it still had a lot of this tedious kind of stuff and, you know, you had to really like walk around.
Scott: And it wasn't like exploring like Metroid where it's interesting to find new things.
Scott: It was like a giant place of tedious exploring, you know, and they even had stupid stuff like this card game.
Scott: you would have to play with all these people if you wanted to get these cards that gave you power or something like that.
Scott: Just, you know, eh.
Rym: And then, you know, 10, 11 the MMO, 12 is coming out now, and apparently 12 I mean, I haven't seen much about it, but there's basically three generations of Final Fantasy fans.
Rym: There are the people like us who are like one through six, old school woot.
Rym: Then there are people who love, you know, 7, 8, 9, 10, which is fine because people are entitled to their opinions.
Scott: That's only because they were born when a Playstation was the thing and they got a Playstation as their first real system and we got an NES as our first system.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Think there's gonna be kids who get the Xbox 360 as their first system.
Scott: Scary.
Scott: Very scary.
Rym: But apparently these people are looking at 12 the way we looked at 8 as this, it's a departure that they don't like.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: I'm ambivalent.
Rym: We'll see when it comes out.
Scott: I'm ambivalent because I haven't played Final Fantasy in years and years and years.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see if it can bring me back into the fold.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if it's gonna bring me back in any fold, especially if I need a system.
Scott: I don't have to play it.
Scott: But, um, they'd really have to do something crazy you know, to make it a game I'd wanna play.
Scott: 'Cause at this point I don't really care if they make, like, an into a dancing game or like a girly game or...
Rym: Well there was Chocobo Racing.
Scott: There was?
Rym: Yeah, it's not that bad.
Rym: And Chocobo's Dungeon.
Scott: There was?
Scott: Yeah!
Scott: Chocobo's Dungeon sounds like some might be fun.
Scott: Is it fun?
Rym: I actually haven't played it, but Chocobo Racing I kinda liked.
Scott: I have to go find those.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But, uh, basically, to not get off on a longer tangent about Final Fantasy, the last Final Fantasy game we really played was Crystal Chronicles.
Scott: Oh, I guess that kinda counts.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So that ups the count of Final Fantasy games, doesn't it?
Rym: And, just now, you know, Final Fantasy 4 Advance came out and I bought it, and I am now going to go into great detail on it, because it's the only new game we have.
Rym: And actually, I gotta say, this is well worth buying.
Rym: Final Fantasy 4 Advance is fantastic.
Rym: One, it is the Japanese version.
Rym: It has all the complexity and all the coolness of the Japanese version.
Rym: Nothing is spared.
Rym: In fact, the only thing that has changed between the original Japanese one and this one is that the pornography book that you can find in the developer room is called the magazine, but it still does the funny thing where the screen goes red and your character says like, "Whoa, that's my kinda
Rym: book.".
Scott: It doesn't say pornography book?
Rym: No, but it didn't say that in the American version either.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, like, they changed so much in Final Fantasy 2 America for the US.
Rym: And silly things.
Rym: Like, they took out some of the romantic things, they removed a bed because they didn't want to imply the two characters were sleeping together, and in perhaps the silliest censorship ever, there's a part where Rosa, the white mage and protagonist's lover, is kidnapped by the evil guy, and she's in a chair, and there's a scythe above her head that's gonna come down and crush or kill her if you don't get to her in time.
Rym: In the American version, they decided that a scythe was too violent and they replaced it with a giant weight instead.
Scott: So it turns from serious to slapstick.
Rym: Yeah, the weight would have still killed her.
Rym: It was just a different form of violence.
Scott: Okay, great.
Scott: Who thinks up these things?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: But this is not only, I mean, this is really pure.
Rym: Final Fantasy 4 Advance is pretty much the real deal.
Scott: Real deal is good.
Scott: We don't get the real deal too often.
Rym: It's also a slightly updated translation, and they've added plot.
Rym: Not, like, new plot, but they've added a lot of exposition and explanations and things are a lot more clear.
Rym: Like, some of the plot points, if you played through the original American version, didn't make any sense.
Rym: Like, why are we suddenly going to this place to do this thing?
Rym: This is just silly.
Rym: It suddenly all makes sense.
Rym: Like, "Oh!
Rym: Because of this and
Rym: this!".
Rym: I'm purposely avoiding spoilers, because I don't know how many people have actually played this game, but suffice to say, this translation makes the game make about a thousand percent more sense.
Scott: Because a lot of things in that game was just like, "Oh, that's the next place to go,".
Scott: and then something happens.
Scott: And I didn't really know the characters so well when I played 2.
Scott: You know, US2.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Because, you know, it's like, "Okay, he's the that guy.
Scott: He's the that...".
Scott: You know, and they're just kind of like these stereotype shells of characters.
Scott: Not like 6, where the characters were full and you knew who they were and what they were about and all that kind of thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This one, you actually know a lot about the characters.
Rym: It really gets into it.
Rym: You're, like, you're... I felt somewhat, like, there's a... It's pretty early in the game.
Rym: Basically, you are... you commit genocide.
Scott: Way to go, you...
Rym: You're a character.
Rym: You start this game as a dark frickin' knight and you're the head of the Red Wings, which is this imperial air force for the nation of Baron, and you go around killing people and you're just pretty much a bad dude.
Scott: And... Kidnapping the president by ninjas?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rym: That was terrible.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: And in this game, it really goes into how bad the guy feels as he starts realizing what he's done and... I mean, I'm really trying not to spoil much, but it's a really good translation.
Scott: Yeah, the other one, the guy didn't really feel bad till after.
Scott: He would just kinda... It was implied, even.
Scott: He didn't say anything.
Scott: He was just like, "Oh,
Scott: oops.".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The dialogue is much expanded.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: And there's also a lot of other nice little changes.
Rym: I mean, while it's Final Fantasy 4 hard version with all the hard stuff in it, they nerfed all the bosses.
Scott: Hooray!
Scott: Now I won't be pissed off all the time.
Rym: Which you might think, "Oh, that sucks,".
Rym: until you realize that the way the game is set up, you do not ever need to level.
Rym: Unless you're a nut at the end of the game when you just want to level to get all the crazy extra Uber stuff, which they've added.
Rym: You don't ever need to level.
Rym: As long as you fight monsters as you walk around, which is kinda fun, you'll always be able to beat a boss unless you suck.
Rym: Unless you don't know how to heal or how to use ice magic on a fire guy.
Rym: That sort of thing.
Scott: That's good, because I always hate leveling.
Scott: As soon as I have to level, I'll just drop a game.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I leveled a little bit because it's just kinda for nostalgia's sake, but you really don't need to.
Scott: I would probably level until I got pissed just to get ahead in the game, so it'd make the rest of it easier.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now also, they've added a lot of other cool nice things.
Rym: Like, every character has a headshot.
Rym: They redid them, and all the characters look a lot better.
Scott: That's good, because all the headshots always look weird, like they didn't match the character sprites.
Rym: Yeah, they've smashed a lot better.
Rym: And two, the thing that I thought was really cool, they only changed one character's sprites.
Scott: Oh, they changed a sprite on someone?
Rym: Yes, one person.
Rym: Not the combat sprite, just the world map sprite.
Rym: Rosa, the love interest of the main character Cecil.
Rym: Now, in the original game, she's billed as she's supposed to be this incredibly beautiful woman, like known throughout the land for her beauty and grace.
Rym: Her headshot in the original game was kinda ugly and pale, and creepy looking, and her sprite was also pale and creepy looking.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Her sprite is really cute.
Rym: I'll see if I can find a picture online to post, but they changed her sprite, and it's a which I'm not gonna complain about, because I think it's a welcome change.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I always hated how some of the Final Fantasy headshots in the menus look kinda weird, and freaky, like they shouldn't be.
Rym: Have you ever looked at the art in the original Final Fantasy manuals?
Rym: They're all that way.
Scott: Yeah, it's kinda freaky.
Rym: Final Fantasy 4 is just the only one that went with that in the game, too.
Scott: Well, 6 kinda had it in the headshots.
Rym: Yeah, but it was the same artist.
Rym: 4 really, really went with it, though, like hardcore, but they changed it a lot in this one.
Rym: Also, there's some new content in terms of playing the game.
Rym: One of which is there's this dungeon you can go into, and you can get like special new weapons they've added for all the characters, whatever.
Scott: Is the dungeon part of the plot, or otherwise can you just skip it?
Rym: You can skip it, just like there's a bunch of things you can skip in the game.
Rym: There are caves on the moon, and there are caves... oh, yeah, I just foiled something.
Rym: You can go to the moon.
Rym: But there are things you can skip in the game.
Rym: There's a point at which the game stops being linear, and there's a whole period where you can pretty much do whatever you want and go all over the place and explore.
Rym: And they just added a couple more things to explore.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: But they also added something big.
Rym: One part of Final Fantasy is that more than 50% of the characters in your party sacrifice their lives to save you at some point.
Rym: Like, seriously, left and right, characters are like, "Oh, go ahead, don't wait for me,".
Rym: or, "Oh, I'll stop that bomb, you guys stand on that other side of the door,".
Rym: and then they die, just like left and right.
Scott: Happens all the time.
Rym: But some of the people who die, they come back later for various plot reasons.
Rym: Not like silly reasons, but actual reasons.
Rym: It's not just completely silly and arbitrary.
Rym: But the thing is, you find them again in the game, but all you do in the game originally was talk to them again.
Rym: Maybe you get an item from them.
Rym: In this game, once you find a guy again, you can swap people in and out of your party.
Scott: Oh, so someone dies, but you really like having them in your party?
Scott: Well, you can get them back.
Rym: Only if there's someone who doesn't die permanently.
Rym: Some people die permanently.
Scott: Ah.
Rym: So you can use those twins from Mesidia.
Rym: if you don't like using Cain or Rydia or whatever.
Rym: You can swap people out.
Rym: That's good.
Rym: Which I thought was neat.
Rym: It adds kind of a fun element to the end of the game.
Rym: Like, can you beat the game with that crappy bard?
Scott: No.
Scott: He's crappy.
Rym: Oh, and while the translation is very, very, very accurate and cool now, they left one of the inaccuracies from the original English translation in on purpose.
Rym: Tella still calls Edward a "spoony
Rym: bard."
Rym: That was, uh... That was a gross mistranslation that was left in because it's so well known.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Uh... What was the original translation say?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Don't even ask me that.
Scott: 'Cause that sounds right to me.
Rym: Yeah, it was something in Japanese, and they translate... They took a lot of liberties in the English translation.
Scott: Well, they kind of have to when they're limited by, you know, the number of characters they can write.
Rym: Yeah, 'cause you gotta understand, a lot of these old translations for NES and SNES games, especially the ROMs, even more than, like, the official releases, you couldn't just translate into different texts because you were limited as to how many characters you could have in any given conversation.
Scott: So the original Japanese, someone said, like, a hundred, you know, characters' worth of text, then in English, all you had was a hundred characters' worth of text for them to say something.
Rym: And they could, like, they could use tricks and add more or less characters sometimes, but they were still limited, so it was very difficult to translate things so they would fit.
Rym: This version of the game doesn't have that problem, so the translation is very good.
Rym: And I guess one last thing, this might bother some people, or you might not notice, I only notice because it's my favorite Final Fantasy, I'm kind of a nut, but the GBA, for whatever reason, they didn't, they removed a lot of the 3D effects from the game.
Rym: There were just a lot of, like, 3D missed effects over certain areas of maps, or there'd be a 3D, like, crevice in holes that you'd walk by and it would scale as you walked around them.
Rym: They took all that out.
Scott: See, I don't get that, because Golden Sun has all that kind of crazy stuff going on all over the place, and that's a GBA game, it doesn't have a problem.
Rym: See, I think it's because Golden Sun was made for the GBA.
Rym: So they used all the GBA tricks.
Rym: This game was made for the Super Nintendo, used all the Super Nintendo tricks.
Scott: Do you really think they just put an SNES emulator on the cartridge and put the ROM in there and then modified the ROM and that was that?
Scott: You really don't think that they recoded it for the GBA?
Rym: I don't know, if they recoded it for the GBA they didn't do it crazily.
Rym: Maybe they were limited by memory, I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, maybe they tried to make the game cheaper by putting it on a less memory GBA cartridge.
Rym: Because Final Fantasy IV and Final Fantasy VI did push the SNES in a number of ways.
Scott: Well, anything that used Mode 7 was pushing it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mode 7 is kind of like when people use that brand new feature on the video card.
Scott: that's only in the newest DirectX.
Scott: You know, and no one can get a good frame rate no matter what card they have.
Scott: That's what Mode 7 was.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But I guess, kind of to wrap this up, in conclusion, blah blah blah.
Rym: One, if you've never played an old school Final Fantasy pick this game up.
Scott: Oh yeah, if you're one of those people where the first system you had was like PlayStation, and the first Final Fantasy you remember was Final Fantasy VII, and you think that's like the best game ever and whatever, you gotta play this right now.
Scott: Get a GBA SP or DS or something and play this.
Scott: Because then you'll realize "Oh!
Scott: I was wrong!
Scott: I've been living in a
Scott: dreamland!".
Rym: Or maybe, in the very least, you can see kind of where these games came from.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like this, I mean, this is one of the classic Final Fantasy games, and this is a very very good implementation of it.
Rym: that removes a lot of the tedium that early, early Final Fantasy games had.
Scott: Yeah, because I notice a lot of people might, you know, a lot of people like VII will go back and they'll try to play VI or IV or something, you know, and someone tells them that that's the real deal.
Scott: But then, things that, gameplay things that have been fixed in the newer ones like VII, VIII, IX, that still existed back then will piss the people off to no end, and no matter how good the game is otherwise they'll still be all "eh" on it.
Scott: So this GBA one can help fix that, and you'll realize, you know, that the games didn't suck.
Rym: And two, if you've played all those old games and you like Final Fantasy IV you have no excuse not to pick this up.
Rym: This is fantastic.
Rym: I am reliving my childhood through this game.
Scott: Uh, good for you.
Scott: Let
Rym: me put it this way, for those of you who have actually played the game I picked it up last Friday, and I didn't play it that much over the weekend because I was busy doing various things and we had a friend over and we were doing all this stuff.
Rym: But basically, I am already at the point where I'm going to go into the sealed cave and get that last crystal.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's quite a ways.
Rym: So, that's all we got for today.
Rym: Kind of peter out here, we only had one game.
Scott: It was the Final Fantasy.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at thieves.feedburner.com/geeknights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: Also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion.
Scott: And whether you love or hate our podcast, we won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geeknights@gmail.com.