Rym: It's Tuesday, December 9th, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, Wizard.
Rym: Behold his power.
Scott: Nah.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: AKA the breakout game for GeekNights at PAX Australia, but we'll get to that.
Rym: So, I've been, you know, it's been mostly animation season for me, so I've been watching a lot of cartoons and things lately, and I have been playing a lot of games, but I've mostly just been playing Smash Bros.
Rym: and Counter-Strike.
Scott: I've been playing a lot of games.
Rym: And a lot of tabletop.
Scott: I played the South Park game, which I gotta finish that.
Rym: Oh yeah, I keep forgetting to get that and play it.
Scott: Well, you missed the sale.
Scott: I don't know if it's worth paying full price.
Rym: Yeah, I'll get it somehow.
Scott: I got a lot of 3DS action going on.
Rym: I got a lot of 3DS action going on, a lot of Smash Bros.
Rym: going on.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of stuff, so.
Rym: No, just Smash Bros.
Scott: There's NES Remix.
Scott: P-Cross E5.
Rym: P-Cross.
Scott: P-Cross.
Rym: Those games, my feelings about them are the same way you feel about Myst in terms of, like, how much fun it is as a game.
Scott: Myst isn't that bad.
Rym: No, Myst is okay.
Rym: You're fine with Myst.
Rym: I mean, this Myst has- Are you fine with Sudoku and crossword puzzles?
Scott: I mean, P-Cross is just better Sudoku.
Rym: So, you're fine with Sudoku.
Scott: You're fine with that- Well, Sudoku's just really bad compared to P-Cross.
Rym: How so?
Scott: It's way, way easier and less fun.
Scott: So, how is- But it's basically the same.
Scott: Mathematically, it's the same deal.
Rym: But you have fun playing P-Cross?
Scott: Yeah, when you do P-Cross, like, at the end.
Scott: See, when you finish a crossword puzzle, right?
Scott: Crossword puzzles at least have some trivia and maybe you learn some knowledge, right?
Scott: Knowledge-based.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Sort of like Scrabble, right?
Scott: Sudoku, it's like, okay, Sudoku's like, you know, brain exercise.
Scott: But when you finish a Sudoku, what do you have?
Scott: A box full of numbers.
Scott: P-Cross is also sort of a math exercise just like Sudoku is.
Scott: Except when you finish a P-Cross, first of all, P-Cross is better.
Scott: Especially because you get really big, crazy ones that are way more complicated and harder than any Sudoku.
Scott: But when you finish a P-Cross, there's a picture that is revealed.
Scott: It's like, "Yay, it's Turtle.
Scott: Yay, it's
Scott: Mario.".
Rym: Great, a pixelated monochromatic turtle.
Scott: Yay, but if you play it in the DS, it turns into a color turtle.
Rym: But you didn't make that color playing P-Cross.
Scott: There is actually, the 3DS version doesn't have it, but there are color P-Crosses.
Rym: No, why don't you play those?
Scott: Because they're not in the 3DS.
Rym: Yeah, but honestly, lately, I've been pretty much playing Counter-Strike.
Rym: And while there is definitely an old man limit to my ability to click heads, I am getting better again.
Scott: You clicked one head.
Rym: I'm doing okay.
Rym: It's interesting because I'm getting to the point where when I play on puppies, occasionally someone good will join.
Rym: But usually now, I'm either the best person on the server, or at least I'm the best person on my team.
Rym: However, Valve, this isn't my news, this is kind of a thing I've noticed.
Rym: Basically, they've done these packs where you can pay money to basically get priority access to different kinds of loot drops and different new maps that are in rotation.
Scott: Operation Vanguard or some shit?
Rym: Operation fucking bullshit.
Scott: Pay money for nothing.
Scott: The same shit they have in Dota.
Scott: Buy the Dota Compendium, get a bunch of digital nothing.
Rym: I paid for the first one because the way it was framed was that the money was distributed among the people, the fans, who made the crazy awesome new maps.
Scott: Yep, that's true.
Scott: And in Dota 2, when you pay money, it goes into the pot for the world champions.
Rym: And unlike Dota, where it's just skins and stuff, this was actual maps, like really good maps, like CS Thunder quality maps.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Yeah, but also it lets you- Can you just get those maps by joining a server that's playing those maps?
Rym: Yes, and basically what happened was- And you don't have to pay for them?
Rym: Well, what happened was, one, the money just went to those people, which is cool.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: It's like tipping.
Scott: But two- I'll tip people who make Counter-Strike maps.
Rym: For the month or two or whatever that the past thing was active, basically anyone who paid for it had priority access to a whole bunch of servers they spun up and ran that were only running those maps.
Scott: Official Valve servers?
Rym: Because very few people run their own Counter-Strike servers anymore.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Because Valve is running a bunch of them, no one needs to run their own?
Rym: Yeah, like the people who run them now either run default ones that don't do anything special, and most people don't go to a name of a server, like they don't join.
Scott: Yeah, they don't use the server browser, they just say, "Play
Scott: Counter-Strike.".
Rym: But here's what happened now, because of the loot drops and the missions, and it's all just cosmetic bullshit, people are getting really invested in this, and it has ruined the casual mode of Counter-Strike.
Scott: So when you join a casual game of Counter-Strike, people aren't playing Counter-Strike?
Rym: People are literally like, "No,
Rym: man.".
Scott: They're just trying to get loot.
Rym: "No, man.
Rym: No, man.
Rym: I just need eight more kills.
Rym: I don't give a fuck about the
Rym: bomb.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: This is what TF2 did, too, with the hats.
Rym: Yeah, so you know what?
Rym: I can't play Casual mode anymore.
Scott: It makes a lot of money for Valve, but it makes the game garbage, because everyone's griefing.
Rym: So I can't play Casual Counter-Strike anymore.
Rym: I can play Demolition mode, because at least that mode, because it starts so close to the action, and is so quick, it's not as fucked as the casual mode is.
Scott: Well, gun game is okay.
Rym: But here's my problem.
Rym: What I really need is the server- Because the server I ran, the only reason I got rid of the Geeknight server, like, people used it occasionally, and I would use it a lot.
Rym: But it was a pain in the ass to administer, because administering Counter-Strike servers- Maybe that's why there's so few servers out there.
Rym: Yes, it's a fucking pain in the ass.
Scott: If I worked for Valve, that's the one thing.
Scott: In Valve, they say you're allowed to work on whatever you want there, right?
Rym: I would work on, yeah, the interface to run a Counter-Strike server.
Scott: I would work on making it easier to run servers, starting with Counter-Strike, and then moving over to the other one.
Scott: Because
Rym: basically what I want is a server that follows most of the game rules of, like, competitive mode servers, but with half as many rounds, so you can go through maps quicker, and switching teams, and the right number of player limits, and cool map rotations, and basically having a server that's cool, and I don't want to actually run it in any capacity.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, there's been this history of any game where you run your own server, you then have to get a bunch of community hacks and mods, and they're really hard to install, because there's no official way to do it, and you just put a bunch of files in folders, and hope stuff works, and edit text configuration files-
Rym: Well, and the documentation is just like, there is no
Scott: real documentation.
Scott: And the documentation is garbage, right?
Scott: Anything that the community feels should be put in, like, NS2 even had this.
Scott: You had NS2, and then there were all these mods you had to make to your NS2 server.
Scott: They should have just changed the official NS2 server to include every single one of these features that the community was adding.
Scott: that was good, right?
Scott: So that you never had to mod the server.
Scott: You just push the buttons and start server, and then there'd be a nice, gooey configuration, that had all the advanced crazy shit that everyone needed to configure the perfect server exactly the way they wanted.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And then, if you do that, a lot of people will be able to run servers really easily.
Rym: So, basically what I'm thinking is, I'm not going to run a server, because, guys, I'm an IT professional.
Rym: Like, I'm a senior, serious IT guy.
Scott: The only thing harder than configuring a game server like this is configuring an email server.
Rym: I was about to say, email is the only, like, good email is the only thing I've ever failed to successfully run.
Rym: I don't think anyone has successfully run good email.
Rym: Except maybe Google, Microsoft, yeah, anyway.
Rym: So, if any listeners out there run a Counter-Strike server or want to run one just on your own, I'm not saying I'll pay for it, but I might just give you a bunch of money.
Rym: I don't care, really.
Rym: Because they're not expensive to get the hosting, but if you'll manage it...
Scott: It is if you want a lot of players and you want it to be fast.
Rym: Yeah, even then, it's not.
Rym: Scott, by our standards, it's not.
Scott: And public ones are more money, too.
Rym: It's still not.
Rym: The amount of money I was paying for that Counter-Strike server, which was, like, a pretty high-performance server, you spend more than that on lunch, like, by Wednesday for a month.
Rym: It was not a lot of money.
Rym: I just don't want to deal with all the bullshit, but if someone has a server and you just want more people on it, I will happily make that also the, "Hey, if you're playing Counter-Strike, that's the semi-official, all GeekNights fans, go play there,".
Rym: so we have our community thing.
Scott: And then you have that problem where everyone's online and everyone's looking at the empty server, not joining it.
Rym: Yep, but then I will do what I did on the other server, which every time I join, I'll just go to the server and invite a bunch of people, and if no one joins me, then fuck you.
Rym: That's what I do.
Rym: Anyway, so in the news, there's some Counter-Strike news.
Scott: Oh, boy.
Rym: There's a good forum thread talking about this.
Rym: Basically, what happened is at DreamHack, big tournament.
Scott: Yeah, big-time gaming tournament.
Scott: Has Hearthstone, has everything.
Rym: Yeah, but we're not talking about the tournament.
Rym: We're talking about the Counter-Strike tournament at the tournament.
Rym: The best Counter-Strike players in the world, the competitive, awesome, whatever.
Rym: And a team was disqualified for "g".
Scott: Well, they quit.
Rym: Well, they quit.
Scott: They forfeited.
Rym: They forfeited/quit, but arguably that might have been to avoid getting an official censure and all that.
Rym: There's a lot of drama around this, and there's even conflicting reports.
Rym: But the gist of it is that there was a team in the final round.
Scott: So they made it to the final round without doing anything shady, so they were really good.
Scott: They're also reportedly a bunch of assholes.
Rym: Which I'm fine with.
Rym: I'm always a fan of the evil team.
Rym: I mean, Mighty Ducks, I'm a fan of the not-Mighty Ducks team.
Scott: Yes, you would be.
Scott: Are you a Yankees fan, too?
Rym: I'm more of a Yankees fan than a Mets fan.
Scott: You can go dine if you want.
Rym: I don't care.
Rym: I'm actually a Tigers fan, so I either want the Tigers to win or a team near where I live that's not Boston to win.
Scott: I like Boston more than the Yankees.
Rym: I think I dislike Boston the most, but that might just be because I have more than once in my life experienced Red Sox fans in person.
Scott: Yeah, at least they don't actually say stuff to you and be drunk, unlike, say, Philadelphia fans.
Rym: Well, I've never experienced Philadelphia fans.
Scott: Why don't you go to Philly without me and see what it's like?
Scott: Go to an Eagles game or two.
Rym: So basically, they, in their spawn, or near their spawn, were able to jump up onto a crate that no one knew you could jump up onto due to what appears to be a transparent pixel or some little edge somewhere on this model that you could just get your character's foot just on it, your little detection box.
Scott: So these guys discovered this.
Scott: No one else knew about it.
Scott: And they must have practiced it in secret.
Scott: And then they didn't whip it out until the final, final round.
Scott: they started using this trick that they discovered.
Scott: The first half was won.
Scott: So the final round, first of all, this only worked because, A, the final round happened to be on this map.
Scott: There wasn't a guarantee of that, I don't think.
Scott: Two, they happened to be playing on the side of the map where you could access this thing in the second half of that final round.
Scott: If they had to play that side of the map in the first half of the round and they whipped out their secret, the other team would have seen it and would have been able to use it against them.
Rym: So the first half was won 12-3 by LDLC.
Rym: That's one of the teams.
Scott: The good team?
Scott: The team that didn't lose?
Rym: The second half, Fnatic, which was down, the evil team, lost the pistol round.
Scott: So clearly, I mean, they were down, right?
Scott: They were clearly, you know, by all accounts, they were the second best team there, right?
Scott: Discounting this trick that they used.
Rym: So they lost the pistol round, and then they revealed a new trick.
Rym: I'm quoting this article.
Rym: It involves a boost from a counter-terrorist spawn.
Rym: that should be impossible.
Rym: Nothing to stand on, road pixel, blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: So basically, once you get up there, you can see the entire map, including the terrorist spawn location.
Scott: Woah.
Rym: So, quote, "Fnatic used this spot to enormous effect, turned the score around from losing 12-3 to win the
Rym: match.".
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Nobody knew what to do about this.
Scott: So apparently in the year before, in 2013, there was a rule, like, in the tournament rules specifically, like no pixel standing or whatever, you know.
Scott: This year, that was not in the rules.
Scott: It was not in the written rules this year.
Rym: So you know what that'd be like?
Rym: What if the rules of football, American football, like, someone messed up and the official published rules left off something about lateral passes.
Rym: And no one noticed.
Rym: And then in the Super Bowl, one team that noticed did it.
Rym: Should they win the Super Bowl?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes, exactly.
Rym: They're playing by the rules.
Rym: If no one else read the rules, tough.
Rym: If something awesome and crazy happens, it's sports.
Rym: It's awesome and crazy.
Rym: I mean, sports is ideally about the best team winning, but at the same time, I don't care if anyone- The best team is whoever got victory by using everything they could within the rules.
Scott: If the rules are broken, that's the game's fault.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Now, a lot of people were saying that this was actually against the rules, but like Scott said, it turns out it technically wasn't.
Scott: Now, I think I agree with Scott- They didn't make a decision on whether to disqualify them or not.
Scott: They just forfeited and let the other team win.
Scott: Which, I mean, good on them for- I mean, even though they were supposedly the jerks.
Scott: You know, I mean, within the spirit of Counter-Strike, yeah, that other team was clearly- Wow, this article is great.
Rym: I'm going to quote the article I was reading from.
Rym: "There is no doubt that Fanatics players can be unpleasant
Rym: people.".
Scott: Yeah, there you go.
Scott: They probably play Heroes of Newerth as their second game of the Counter-Strike.
Rym: That's the full story of this thing, but here's my take on it.
Rym: One, there's nothing wrong with what they did, because two, the rules of a video game are the code of that video game.
Scott: Yes, unlike any real world game, like a board game or a sport, where you need to have referees or some sort of human watching and administering and enforcing rules that are just known.
Scott: A video game and a piece of software, everything that happens in the game is within that software, and so- Well, well, well, see, I already- because here's the thing.
Rym: The tournament is a structure built on top of and around the video game that has its own rules, like where people sit, what equipment you're allowed to use.
Scott: Sure, you can do stuff like that, sure.
Scott: But at least things that happen within the game can and should be administered and refereed totally by that software, and if the software is flawed in some way, you should fucking fix that shit before the tournament happens.
Rym: Basically, in this situation, what you could do is do it like sports ball.
Rym: There's referees, and if there's a call that's extremely complicated, they discuss it, figure out how the rules should be interpreted.
Rym: Then they immediately explain how they interpreted the rule and how it's all going to go down, and then the game continues.
Rym: They address it immediately.
Scott: Well, the other problem is that if you look at a mature sport, like football, basketball, hockey, baseball, no matter what happens on that field of play, there is something in the rule book that you could somehow interpret and help you out.
Scott: The real world law, no matter what a human being does, there is some law that we can use to determine whether it's legal or illegal, but the rules for this tournament were so immature that even if you were judging, you could say, "Okay, that's what
Scott: happened.".
Scott: You might just look through that whole rule book and be like, "I don't
Scott: know.".
Scott: There might be nothing that you can interpret.
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: What if the rule said that you're not allowed to use a single pixel glitch?
Rym: What if that was two pixels?
Rym: We don't know.
Rym: Who's going to figure that out?
Rym: That rule is bullshit.
Rym: Maybe the rule could be something relatively vague but verbose enough to cover obvious unintended glitches to be decided at the moment of the infraction by a panel of referees based on the following guidelines.
Rym: That would have been fine, but they clearly did not have that and didn't have a real way to address this.
Scott: Why didn't they just say, "Hey, look, this map is obviously fucked.
Scott: Let's play it again in a different
Scott: map.".
Rym: There's a million different things they could have done, but e-sports is still baby's first attempt at this.
Rym: They're not learning from sports ball, which probably has the most comprehensive and well-written rules in the history of sports.
Scott: Hockey is the best, really.
Rym: If you didn't, you couldn't guess.
Scott: Tennis, the sport of tennis is just so perfect, it doesn't need help.
Scott: But in terms of the officiating technology, hockey, if there's any issue, they fucking call Toronto on the phone.
Scott: They're watching every hockey game in this one room, the same team of people, and they will make any kind of hard decision that the ref at the hockey game can't make is made at this one place.
Rym: And look, they make it immediately.
Scott: For every game.
Rym: And then they change the rules every year.
Scott: You just call them on the fucking phone like, "Hey, Toronto, was that a
Scott: goal?".
Scott: "Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Cool.
Scott: They said it's a goal.
Rym: It's a
Rym: goal.".
Rym: "Hey, Toronto, they have a goalie who's literally so fat that they shoved him into the goal and he's blocking the entire goal.
Rym: What do we do about that?
Rym: Is that
Rym: okay?".
Rym: And then they'll decide.
Scott: Yeah, I think part of the problem also is that a lot of the e-sports that happen around the world, there's so many different leagues.
Scott: And you look, sports, each individual sport, physical sport, didn't really become mature and big until its leagues unified into a single deal.
Scott: The other thing is that every sport in the real world, the people who make the sport and the people who run the league are one and the same.
Rym: So thus...
Scott: The people who make Valve should be running every... All the Counter-Strike leagues should unify and they should be owned by Valve.
Rym: Or in the very least, they should have a base set of guidelines for how tournaments go that Valve administers, but then they get whatever they want.
Scott: But if you look, the kings right now of competitive gaming is League of Legends and that is what they're doing.
Scott: There are League of Legends tournaments besides the one, but the big ones are all run by Riot Games.
Scott: They run the show, they make the game.
Scott: The biggest, most important tournaments around the world, they run them.
Scott: They got it unified, mostly.
Scott: And it's like, yeah, you can have the same thing with the NFL, right?
Scott: The biggest, most important football is the NFL.
Scott: There are other footballs, right?
Scott: There are other League of Legendses.
Scott: But the one that matters is made by the same people who run the show.
Rym: There is, in fact, international football and one year Japan won.
Scott: Well, Japan won, I think, every year until the US started participating.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because the US wasn't...
Scott: Basically, the team that goes to play in that is all the college football players who didn't make the NFL, like the best of those.
Rym: And they're better the entire rest of the world combined.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Well, I mean, we're not very good at soccer.
Rym: No, we're not.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: We're not the worst at soccer.
Scott: No.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: So, yeah, you got any news?
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: So Tekken, which is, in my opinion, a not that good fighting game.
Scott: But it's been around for a long time and it's really popular.
Rym: I mean, it's not as bad as Primal Rage or...
Scott: No, it's especially popular in Japan, right?
Scott: You know, and Tekken has always been known for not being as good as Soul Calibur.
Scott: Besides that, it's been known because it has a lot of crazy characters in it.
Scott: It's like a really good arcade game because, you know, you're not really good at fighting games.
Scott: No one you know knows how to play Tekken.
Scott: So even if your friend is really good at fighting games and you're not, you can both go to a Tekken machine to mash buttons.
Scott: And you get to pick the bear.
Scott: And he gets to pick the block of wood or whatever characters are in there, right?
Scott: It's like some, you know, samurai guy.
Scott: So crazy characters.
Scott: So you have a lot of fun just watching how the crazy characters move and interact, even if you can't play fighting games for shit.
Scott: So Tekken 7 is coming soon.
Scott: And there's a new character in it that got revealed called Lucky Chloe.
Scott: And she's just sort of like a cute kind of like pink Hatsune Miku hair.
Scott: Well, her hair is blonde.
Scott: She's wearing cat ears.
Rym: She's wearing an admittedly pretty adorable like weird sort of cat shawl?
Rym: Sort of explain what that thing is.
Scott: It's like paws, right?
Scott: They cover whole arms, but it also goes across the back.
Scott: So it's like, you know what she looks like?
Scott: It's like a shirt that only covers the back of you and completely covers your arms and has paws at the end of it.
Rym: She looks like a lot of the people I see at anime conventions.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically anime convention girl, right?
Scott: Like roller derby, like knee pads and shoes, but without skates.
Scott: And then, you know, obviously kind of cheesecake-ish because it's a Japanese game, right?
Scott: You can't have some covered up woman.
Scott: That would be no.
Scott: So apparently there are a lot of U.S.
Scott: people who are complaining.
Scott: They're like, we don't want no cute girl in this game.
Scott: It's like, why not?
Rym: You've got to block up on the seriousness of my bear.
Scott: You've got a block of wood and a bear and whatever other panda and mother nonsense in here.
Scott: You don't want this girl because you're why?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, I'm not sure if they're trying to be if they're being sexist by not wanting the girl or if they're being anti sexist because they don't want a perverted naked girl.
Scott: I don't know why.
Rym: I don't get the impression.
Rym: I was just flipping through a lot of comments and a lot of people who were actually like the people are actually mad about this.
Rym: They're not mad because that is a bad representation of a woman.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Rym: They're mad because it's not serious.
Rym: And because it's like Japanese moe crap, anime crap getting into my tech, playing a Japanese playing a Japanese fighting game.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: What the fuck do you think this is?
Rym: So, yeah, those people.
Scott: So the guy who makes the game or the primary guy who's in charge of the game, Katsuhiro Harada, he said something along the lines of hello, small world.
Scott: I'll make muscular and skinhead character for you.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: He tweeted, I'm always serious.
Scott: If you don't need equal, I don't release them.
Scott: If you need equal, I'll release.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: He commented again.
Scott: It's your community's choice.
Scott: I'm just hearing the demand and request.
Scott: Anyway, we are so busy because Tekken 7 development is not finished.
Scott: We are working on arcade version first.
Scott: I think we have planning time for this issue after development.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I wish more people who are in the position to speak officially on matters would answer in the way that he answered that.
Scott: I think what's going to be hilarious is, you know, he'll be like, OK, US version of game.
Scott: I know put in character, you know, like, OK, oh, you are all importing Japanese version because it's missing character.
Scott: Oh, you're paying too much money because Japanese version twenty dollars more.
Scott: Oh, I so sad.
Scott: No, I'm not sad.
Scott: I sell many more copy.
Scott: Thank you.
Scott: We always give American bad version anyway.
Scott: We continue that trend, if that what you want.
Rym: So it's interesting because we used to complain like tribes to was ruined because those guys bet for bad reasons, listen to their fans and did the things they requested.
Rym: But they I think we always say ignore your fans or pretend to listen to them, but don't do what they ask for.
Rym: I like this response of your morons for wanting that.
Rym: And here's why.
Scott: Oh, you want me to make game worse?
Scott: OK, I do that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, what happened?
Scott: I remember last year when we reveal character, you said, you know what?
Rym: Now you want to get the first post in this article, I found just a picture of what guy would get guy.
Rym: This dumb squabble about a Tekken character makes it clear to me why this character exists in the game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I don't get the the the the feeling that the people who play Tekken, right, the Tekken community is among like the high brow fighting game communities.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, I bet the people who play Marvel vs.
Scott: Capcom are probably better than the people who play Tekken.
Rym: Where where's my Bushido blade?
Scott: Yeah, that's like the net runner fighting game.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I want that coming back.
Scott: You make it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I got time for that.
Rym: Right alongside that Twitter idea that we've been throwing around.
Rym: So I don't know if you've seen all those tweets, but the idea is what you've got an RPG where your character, she does nothing more but a list of things you can do.
Rym: You can only ever do any of those things once ever.
Scott: So what happens when you run out of things?
Rym: Well, one of the things is die.
Scott: So eventually you just die no matter what.
Scott: So.
Scott: But you could only do the things on that list and then the game be over.
Scott: So every game be pretty much the same.
Rym: You've got like the list, like one hundred things.
Rym: You play like four sessions with these characters.
Scott: That's your four sessions with only one hundred things.
Rym: Maybe it depends on.
Rym: I mean, how many how many times you roll the dice and average burning will game.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And it's a weird vague idea that, yeah, that that's even higher priority in the hopper than remaking Bushido blade.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: This is relevant to later in the show.
Rym: But this is just a video of Daffy Duck as a wizard in a slayers style.
Rym: And it's pretty cool.
Rym: And you should learn the lyrics to parts of this song for future reference.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So this is really awesome.
Scott: Shapeways, the people who do all the 3D printing, whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Partnered with this people called nervous system who, I guess, design 3D printed and or clothing fashion stuff.
Scott: They're like a design firm, I guess.
Scott: And they designed a dress that you could 3D print at first.
Scott: They were just trying to design a bracelet.
Scott: You could 3D print.
Scott: And, you know, there's a lot of problems involved with that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, how do you get something that sort of moves and bends but is printed firmly?
Scott: And basically the idea they came up with is, well, you print the thing to be a bunch of pieces that are all linked.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's small pieces that are linked together.
Scott: So they're all individually.
Scott: Every piece is firm plastic.
Scott: But once you take it out, it's like, oh, OK.
Scott: So instead of just, you know, shoot aiming low and making this bracelet, they made a whole dress.
Scott: Now, the other problem is the volume of the dress is bigger than the box of the 3D printer.
Scott: So they had to.
Scott: they took it in the 3D model on the computer.
Scott: They crumpled the dress up so that it fit in the area of the 3D printer.
Scott: So it prints crumpled up and then you sort of take it out and uncrumpled it and it becomes, you know, the full size.
Scott: And despite being 100 percent solid plastic, it was actually really kind of awesome.
Scott: You just got to see this.
Rym: fully expect to see someone wearing this at PAX South.
Rym: No, I don't think you'll see that someone's going to wear it at a convention and we'll see.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: It's not that kind of thing.
Scott: This is like it went to the MoMA or whatever.
Scott: It's not the kind of thing that just a normal person can get.
Rym: So there's OK.
Rym: So they didn't release.
Rym: I haven't looked at this thing at all.
Rym: I've seen similar attempts at things, but they've always been relatively small, like a shawl kind of thing made out of plastic.
Scott: This is like a work of art that one person made.
Scott: I don't it's not something that I don't think.
Scott: you went to Shapeways and said, hey, can you print me that dress?
Scott: Yeah, it might cost a bit.
Scott: And, you know, I don't know.
Rym: Anyway, so in the meta moment, we're going to be appearing at the Penny Arcade Expo South, the inaugural in San Antonio, Texas.
Rym: So on Sunday, January 25th at four thirty p.m.
Rym: in the Armadillo Theater.
Scott: You mean an armadillo?
Rym: Depends on where you live.
Scott: You are not Mexican.
Rym: We are presenting a new and updated version of Bad Games.
Rym: If you've seen us present bad games before, you probably don't need to go to it.
Rym: We're hoping that people who don't know who we are go and see it.
Scott: And hopefully there'll be a lot of those people in the south.
Rym: And otherwise, we're pretty much just going to eat barbecue, play tabletop games and make fun of the south.
Scott: And the Tejas.
Rym: Yeah, Texas.
Scott: Let's play.
Rym: You're giving me shit for Armadillo and you say Tejas.
Scott: Well, you know, the titans that live there.
Rym: Yeah, here's coyotes out in that territory.
Scott: We should bring and play Outlaw in Tejas.
Rym: Actually, we should.
Rym: Actually, we should set it up on a laptop with two controllers and video people playing it and get their reactions and then run a tournament.
Scott: Outlaw tournament.
Rym: Yeah, I had spare time.
Scott: As it's properly known, Pretzel Cowboy.
Rym: Yeah, if I'm going to remake a video game, that's what I'm remaking first.
Scott: Pretzel Cowboy.
Rym: Otherwise, the Book Club book is Watership Down.
Rym: I read it a long time ago.
Rym: You should read it.
Rym: It's an awesome book.
Scott: Other meta things.
Scott: Come find us on the internet.
Scott: I mean, I'm pretty sure if you found this podcast and you're listening right now, you've already found us on the internet.
Rym: But at the same time, many people who follow us on YouTube did not realize somehow that we obviously think Gamergate is stupid like anyone who's smart.
Rym: And they were shocked when they realized through YouTube that that was our opinion.
Rym: Because they only followed us on YouTube and it literally never interacted with us in any other way.
Rym: So you should interact with us in multiple ways.
Rym: That way you can find out what important thing we think that you will be offended by and leave.
Scott: Yeah, you should also internet more because internetting is what cool people like us do.
Scott: If you internet enough, you won't need to listen to this show.
Rym: I've also uploaded a whole bunch of video from PAX Australia, which was one of the rare times outside of Kineticons and weird conventions where one of us gave a lecture without the other one.
Rym: It was just me.
Rym: Because Scott didn't want to fly to Australia again.
Scott: We also recorded another episode of GeekNights presents you tennis.
Rym: Yeah, we did.
Scott: Upload that.
Rym: I gotta edit it together and do stuff to it to hide the fact that because it's in 4K, you can literally see my pores.
Scott: Alright, well, do that.
Rym: Yeah, but it'll be up soon.
Rym: As soon as I get a chance to put it up.
Rym: And the last meta thing, just because people asked me a lot about this last year.
Rym: I'm going to go skiing at Hunter Mountain on Saturday.
Rym: If you want to go meet me and hang out and go skiing, let me know.
Rym: I'm going to be there all day.
Scott: I don't think I'm doing anything this weekend, but if anyone wants to play Netrunner in New York, I mean, I probably already played Netrunner with you.
Rym: So, Wizard.
Rym: The Wizard.
Rym: Scott and I met two awesome, smart people at the previous PAX Australia.
Scott: The first PAX Australia.
Rym: Yes, we went to it.
Rym: We were walking around and we were like, "We gotta find some smart people to play a game
Rym: with.".
Rym: We saw two people and they were looking for a game and we were like, "Hey, you want to play a
Rym: game?".
Rym: And one thing led to another.
Scott: We played Hanavi.
Rym: We played Hanavi, which is Smart Person Detector Alpha.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And they were smart.
Scott: Yep, the Smart Person Detector went bing, bing, bing.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's almost like a dowsing rod, but it works.
Rym: So, I have to give props to them because Jess and Bain, these two people who were smart and we hung out with them, I hung out with them again at the next PAX OZ.
Rym: Because, like we do, we form PAX-specific posses in every region of the world where there's a PAX.
Rym: And they brought out a game and, as is the Rym and Scott style, I did what we always do.
Rym: Really, I've never heard of this game and you want me to play it?
Rym: Watch how enthused I am.
Rym: Watch me try to avoid learning this game because I actually just want to play this game that I brought.
Rym: And I played Wizard, and it was great.
Scott: Wizard.
Scott: So, Wizard is actually a mad old game.
Scott: It's published in 1984.
Scott: It is two years younger than us.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It received a nomination for the 2011 Netherlands Spelenpriz, which I guess is the Netherlands Game Prize.
Rym: Nederlander das Spiel des Jahrs.
Scott: Right, basically, in 2011.
Scott: So, it took that long for the game to be recognized.
Rym: It wasn't even published commercially until like 1986.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then we only discovered it in 2014.
Scott: So, this game is like a game that I guess has just been sitting in the dark and suddenly popped out of nowhere.
Scott: It's designed by a guy named Ken Fisher.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Who I never heard of, but I'm going to look him up.
Scott: Alright, in his board game geek picture, he has a hood on that has a gold lining.
Scott: I think Wizard is the only thing that he makes.
Scott: It's WizardCards.com.
Scott: Well, you know what, guy?
Scott: It's an official website.
Rym: If you've only ever made one game, you're batting a thousand.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: He's made Isaac Asimov's super quiz one, two, and three.
Rym: Okay, I think your batting average is dropping.
Scott: Or maybe this is just part of his wish.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Alright, alright.
Scott: Wizard's the only thing we care about.
Scott: Sorry, Ken Fisher.
Rym: Wizard is interesting.
Scott: He actually has the username Wizard on BoardGameGeek.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, remember our review of Pendante.
Rym: Pendante is like if poker were designed today to be fun, it's Pendante.
Scott: It's like they take poker and you soup it up with some Euro game skills and some modern design.
Rym: And write rules to it like it's a modern game and all that.
Scott: And put some theme on there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Pendante gives you 90 percent of the fun of actual poker without any of the tedium of actual poker.
Scott: So, Wizard is, well, Pendante is to poker as Wizard is to wist.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Slash heart, slash huker, slash every trick-taking.
Rym: Trick-taking games.
Rym: Wizard is just a Trump food suit following trick-taking game.
Scott: Now, most people who are in the board game nerd community who are looking to play a trick-taking game go straight to teach you.
Scott: I have teach you.
Scott: I play teach you.
Scott: Teach you is not good.
Rym: Teach you is not.
Scott: I would rather play hearts than play.
Scott: teach you, but I would rather play Wizard than any other trick-taking game I've ever seen.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Scott: And Bridge is for old people.
Rym: So, I grew up in the Midwest where everyone plays trick-taking games.
Rym: Everyone.
Rym: Everyone knows those kinds of games.
Rym: You grow up playing Euchre and Wist and Hearts and P-Nuckle and all these kinds of games.
Rym: I hate Bridge.
Rym: I hate P-Nuckle.
Rym: I like Euchre, but if you play Euchre enough, it's a solved game that comes down to cheating.
Rym: Hearts is a fantastic game.
Scott: Hearts is the best.
Rym: I fucking love Hearts.
Rym: I will play Hearts almost any time.
Scott: Hearts is great.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: But, much like how when we taught Pen Dante, especially when I tried to teach Pen Dante to a bunch of our friends, I learned that a lot of our friends had never played poker.
Rym: They didn't know what a flush was.
Scott: They knew what a flush was.
Rym: They were extra surprised by a flush.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And, this was the same deal.
Rym: It was interesting to read the rules to trick-taking because I had never in my life thought about the rules to trick-taking.
Scott: Yeah, if I had to teach him this game, I would say, "Look, all you have to do in this game is...".
Rym: Trick-taking.
Scott: It's trick-taking game.
Scott: Trump is the top card that gets revealed from the deck after we deal the cards.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: What I'll do right now for you guys?
Rym: I'm going to teach you the entire game the way I would teach it to Scott.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But, I already know how to play.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: This is for the listener.
Rym: So, this is basically just a trick-taking game, but the way you're going to do it is you bid how many tricks you're going to take, and then you play a hand of one.
Rym: Then, you bid how many tricks you're going to take, and you play a hand of two.
Rym: Then, a hand of three.
Scott: So, obviously, in the hand of one, I would only bid one or zero because it would be impossible for me to take two tricks.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Am I allowed to bid two even though there's only one trick to take?
Rym: Well, yes, but that's going to fuck you because the scoring is you get one point for every trick you take if you bid the correct number, and then you get two points because you bid correctly.
Rym: So, if I bid one, I get one.
Rym: I get three points.
Scott: So, you want to take more tricks and bid correctly, but if bidding correctly is more important because if you're even one off from the correct bid, you lose a point for every one you're off by.
Rym: So, if I bid eight and I take nine or seven, I lose a point.
Scott: But if I bid one and take one and you bid five and take five, you're doing way better than me.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: That way, you can't just be like zero, zero, always taking zero, ducking under.
Scott: Even if you always take zero, you're going to play a trump card at some point because you're going to have it in your hand and you're going to take one.
Scott: Maybe, maybe not.
Scott: And then you're going to be off.
Rym: Yeah, because someone else will play the fucking A's and you just duck your trump under.
Rym: That is fine.
Rym: So, that's the game with one trick to it.
Scott: All three tricks.
Rym: Three tricks?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I was just going to say there are super trump weird cards.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There's only four of each type.
Rym: There are jesters and there are wizards.
Scott: I didn't, I don't know any jesters.
Rym: So, the problem is the game is in German, at least the copy of it that we got.
Rym: So, it's Zauberers and Nars, Zs and Ns because that's not in any way visually confusing.
Scott: Yeah, because a Z is just a sideways N.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Well, I mean six and nine upside down.
Rym: So, anyway.
Scott: That's why you draw a line on one side of it so you know.
Rym: A wizard is, it is trump and it is infinity.
Rym: So, it always wins the trick.
Scott: What if two people play wizards at the same hand?
Rym: If multiple wizards are played, whichever wizard was placed first wins the trick.
Scott: So, if I get the first play because I took the last trick and I play a wizard, I get the next trick and everyone else can dump a card?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So, if you lead a wizard.
Scott: And clear out a suit or whatever?
Rym: There is no suit for that hand.
Scott: So, wouldn't I want to play my wizards later in the round?
Scott: Because I mean I'm going to take a trick with a wizard anyway.
Scott: Possibly.
Scott: So, if I play it later in the round, I'm basically preventing people from dumping suit early.
Rym: But you don't want to be in a situation where you don't have the lead anymore and then the last three people all lead wizard and then your fourth wizard is just fucked.
Scott: Ah.
Rym: That could happen.
Rym: Or you might accidentally take a trick in the mid and now you don't want to take a trick with that wizard.
Rym: Ah.
Rym: And then the jesters.
Rym: They are negative infinity and are not Trump.
Rym: They have no suits.
Scott: So, obviously, even if two people play gnar, one of the other players is going to take the trick.
Scott: But what if all players play gnar?
Rym: Whoever led that gnar gets fucked.
Rym: Oh no.
Rym: I've never seen it happen.
Scott: I doubt that would ever happen.
Rym: The day it happens, I'm going to yell and scream because it's just going to be so beautiful.
Scott: Well, so it says here on board game you can play with three to six players but there's only four gnars.
Scott: So, it can only happen with three or four players.
Scott: It can only happen with four or fewer players.
Rym: I think the game is best with four players, like all trick taking games are.
Scott: If you play with five or six, I mean, obviously, the all wizard or all gnar situation can't happen.
Rym: So, if a gnar is led, then the next player to play sets the suit for the trick.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, that's pretty much the whole game.
Rym: Now, if you don't know, if that doesn't mean anything to you, the way trick taking games work, fundamentally, one, you should go back and listen to our episode on hearts.
Scott: Everyone who is in the game has a hand of cards.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Someone goes first.
Scott: That person plays a card.
Scott: Any of the cards.
Scott: Cards have a suit and a value.
Rym: So, whatever suit was played is now the suit for that hand, that trick.
Scott: So, the next person now has to play one card from their hand.
Scott: If they have a card matching the suit of the already played card, they must follow suit.
Scott: That's why you ever heard the phrase follow suit?
Scott: That's what that means.
Scott: So, if Rym goes first and he plays a spade, and I have a spade in my hand, I must play a spade.
Scott: I may not play one of the other cards in my hand and people, if I cheat, people can figure it out easily and ruin me.
Scott: Pointing out, so, I have to play a spade.
Scott: If I don't have a spade, I may play any of the other cards in my hand.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So, one suit will be determined by some fashion.
Rym: In some games, players can kind of decide through a process.
Rym: In this game and in many games, it's just random.
Rym: And not all trick-taking games have this.
Rym: But one suit will be determined to be Trump.
Rym: That suit will trump any other suits.
Rym: So, if I played the ten and Scott played the four and someone else played the two of the suit that was the trick, then I would get it.
Rym: I have the highest number.
Scott: And if someone else plays a card from some other suit because they didn't have the appropriate suit in hand, they don't get to take the trick.
Scott: Because it's only, you have to follow suit for your card to count as taking the trick.
Rym: But a two of Trump beats the highest number of non-Trump.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, it's like if I want to take tricks, a lot of them, I want to have a lot of Trump cards in my hand and dump a suit.
Scott: So, let's say I get rid of all the spades in my hand.
Scott: But I have a bunch of Trump cards.
Scott: Hearts are Trump.
Scott: Then other people still have a ton of spades.
Scott: And they play them.
Scott: And on my turn, I don't have to play a spade because I don't have one.
Scott: So, I play my heart cards that are Trump.
Scott: And I get to take those tricks.
Scott: Regardless of the value of my heart cards.
Scott: Unless someone else.
Scott: As long as someone else also ran out of spades and plays heart cards that are higher value than mine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, because the hearts are the Trump.
Scott: If someone just starts the hand with the hearts, well.
Rym: That's awesome sometimes.
Scott: But you have to follow suit.
Scott: You have to follow suit.
Rym: So, in like a state, like in hearts.
Rym: Well, the hearts is an example.
Rym: So, in Euchre, if I play, Euchre's not a good example because then I have to explain fucking, whatever.
Rym: So, in Wist, if I play the ace of Trump.
Rym: And I lead that.
Rym: And Scott only has a king of the Trump suit.
Rym: He's got to just throw it down and lose it.
Scott: And he doesn't do anything.
Scott: Even though that is an extremely powerful card.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I was forced to play it and lose it.
Rym: So, the final rub in Wizard is that you may play a Gnar or a Zauber-er.
Rym: Regardless of following suit at any time.
Rym: You can always play one.
Scott: So, even if I can follow suit, I can Wizard or Gnar instead.
Scott: So, if I was in a situation like Rym just said where I have a really powerful card.
Scott: But I'm going to be forced to lose it.
Scott: I can just Gnar or Wizard instead and keep that powerful card in my hand.
Scott: And then play it later and get the value from it.
Rym: So, the game is great.
Rym: You can play it with a normal deck of cards as long as you have eight cards beyond the deck of cards that can be labeled Zauber-er and Gnar.
Scott: So, usually if you buy a deck of playing cards at the drug store, it's going to have two learn to play cards and two jokers.
Scott: You might need to get two decks of cards at the same back and take the aces and doodle on them and write Zauber-er and then take some deuces and write Gnar on them or something.
Rym: Do something like that.
Rym: Or you can just buy.
Rym: There's a lot of people that make pre-made decks.
Rym: The one we bought has the- The official one?
Rym: Has the best worst art ever.
Scott: Yeah, so the artist is Franz Vowinkel and the art is simultaneously good and bad.
Scott: I mean, it's not the worst art I've seen.
Scott: It's not Sentinels of the Multiverse, which looks like a child drew it.
Scott: Sorry, whoever did that, but yeah, it's bad.
Rym: The art's special and if you play with this deck, your players will comment on the art.
Scott: Yeah, it's noteworthy, which I think is actually a positive, right?
Scott: It doesn't really matter for the game, you know, a lot.
Scott: This is the way it does for a collectible or living game.
Rym: Oh my god, I just realized what it says on the back.
Rym: Game contents, 60 character cards, one score pad of truth, one set of instructions.
Rym: I love how it's not even branded as a card game.
Rym: It's the character cards.
Rym: It has this whole story and the story in the game is amazingly succinct.
Scott: What's the story?
Rym: The story is we unearthed Stonehenge and found the game that Wizards used to play back when Wizards existed.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: Here are the rules.
Scott: Dude, that sounds true to me.
Scott: I believe it.
Rym: So, if you have never played a trick-taking game ever, get this game and play it.
Scott: It says on Board Game Geek that Wizard originated from Oh Hell or also known as Up and Down the River, which are played with a standard deck of 52 cards with a proprietary 60 card deck comprising a standard deck plus four wizards and four jesters in the first hand, one card and so on and so on.
Scott: So apparently there was another trick-taking game called Oh Hell, also known as Up and Down the River, which was the game that came before Wizard but did not have the wizards and Nars in it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But then you're getting close to Wist or Gops or all those other kinds of games.
Rym: But seriously, if you've never played a trick-taking game, get Wizard somehow.
Rym: And this is the best way to learn trick-taking games, to learn to get good at them, and then it'll be really easy to play Hearts and Euchre and all these other kinds of games.
Scott: I think you should just play Hearts first on your Windows PC.
Rym: Well, so it's tricky because...
Scott: Or Yahoo Games.
Rym: What's interesting is that...
Scott: And then you'll be able to play Wizard very easily.
Rym: Hearts has the... Hearts teaches you de-suiting and ducking and all those kinds of strategies.
Scott: Very important things to know for Wizard.
Rym: But Hearts has no Trump, and Hearts has the card passing mechanics.
Scott: Well, Hearts are Trump in Hearts.
Rym: Well, they're not Trump.
Scott: Uh, sorta.
Rym: No, they're not Trump.
Scott: They're like reverse Trump.
Scott: No, they're not.
Scott: They are.
Rym: No, they're not.
Rym: They don't count extra for taking a suit.
Rym: No, but they're the... Trump only means it lets you take a trick that you wouldn't otherwise take.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Doesn't mean anything else.
Scott: But they're the special suit in that you don't... Yes, Trump does mean the special suit.
Rym: They're the point suit.
Rym: Don't fuck with me on trick-taking games.
Rym: I grew up in Michigan.
Scott: You're being a pedantic nonsense.
Rym: If you called that Trump among anyone who plays these games, they would laugh you out of the room.
Scott: You'll still be able to easily understand the concepts of Wizard after playing Hearts.
Rym: Scott, other... In America, other than one teaching game, I'm fucking undefeated at Wizards.
Rym: Don't you even.
Rym: So... But yeah, Hearts and Euchre are the two, like, arctic, typical games.
Rym: I'd say Wist, but no one fucking actually plays Wist.
Scott: Well, people did.
Rym: No, yeah, no one modern plays Wist.
Rym: And also, Euchre is basically just, like, Wist with a tiny deck.
Rym: So it's kind of like... It's almost like... Euchre is almost to Wist what pandanta is to poker as well, in a sense.
Scott: There's also Bridge.
Rym: Yeah, I hate Bridge.
Rym: But to articulate why requires...
Scott: Bridge is a big deal, though.
Rym: I know it is.
Rym: I respect Bridge, but I don't like playing Bridge.
Rym: But... So, let's talk about Wizard.
Rym: Because just play it.
Rym: But strategy-wise...
Scott: Oh, strategy-wise.
Rym: This is a good game with a very high skill cap.
Scott: So I think the thing is...
Rym: Playing this with people with noobs is like beating babies to death.
Rym: It's just... Right.
Scott: So you look at your hand and you say, "How many tricks can I possibly take with this
Scott: hand?".
Scott: And the thing is, well, you could... You might have a hand.
Scott: It's got, like, Wizard.
Scott: Okay, I gotta bet at least one.
Scott: I got a Wizard.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Then I got, like, two high trump cards.
Rym: Well, I should probably bet... Scott, I saw a game.
Rym: In the first round, two Wizards were in people's hands.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So shit happens.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So, let's say it's the hand of five.
Scott: You've got a Wizard, two high trumps, and two mech cards.
Rym: Are those mech cards the same suit?
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: If they're the same suit, I'm definitely bidding fucking four.
Scott: How are you gonna get four?
Rym: Because I'm gonna control with the Wizard, lead my other stuff.
Rym: The odds of other trump being out in the five hand, probably pretty low.
Scott: You're basically counting that one of those mech cards will be able to take a trick.
Rym: Because I'll be leading it toward the end.
Rym: And because they're mech, if someone else fucks me somehow and takes control, I'll probably be able to use those trump to get control back pretty easily because the odds of the highest trump being in the game are pretty low.
Rym: And two, because I'm de-suited, there's a decent chance I can use one of those trump to get back in right away.
Scott: Yeah, I would just bet three because even if I am able to take one of the tricks with one of those mech cards, right, I know that other people all have five cards in the hand.
Scott: Someone's gonna fuck me when I play one of my high trumps with a Wizard or some shit.
Scott: So I basically can't, those two, those, you know, the advantage I can do if I try to take the tricks versus the someone's gonna fuck me cancel out.
Scott: So I go three.
Rym: Here's the real thing.
Rym: My heuristic there, which was similar to yours, is just based on your hand.
Rym: Which is how like in the hearts, your hand is the only real core direction.
Scott: You don't get to see anyone else's hand.
Scott: That's all you got to go.
Rym: There's no bidding.
Rym: But in Wizard, players openly bid on how many tricks they're going to take in turn order.
Scott: So depending on who bids first and what they've bid, it's the hand of five.
Scott: The first player, let's say Rym goes, he has the hand we just discussed.
Rym: If I'm bidding first, I would bid three.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So he going first, he bids three.
Scott: If he's correct, that means among the three other players, only two people should take the tricks.
Scott: Meanwhile, I'm sitting to the left of Rym.
Scott: I look at my hand.
Scott: It's ridiculous luck day.
Scott: I have two wizards.
Scott: So, but all the other cards in my hand are like twos.
Rym: But you know that I'm really confident because I bid three not knowing anyone else's bid.
Scott: But I'm bidding two.
Scott: I got two wizards.
Rym: So the other two people either know they're not taking shit, are dumb and bid anyway.
Scott: So now it's a round of five and five people have already bid.
Scott: Two people have bid on all five tricks.
Scott: The other guy's holding like a really high trump card.
Scott: He bids one.
Scott: And the other person's got some high trump cards too.
Scott: They bid one or two.
Rym: Now this is where the game gets interesting.
Scott: So now the people have bid a total of like seven or eight tricks out of only five available tricks.
Scott: Someone's wrong.
Rym: And funny, sometimes it'll go way under.
Rym: Like I saw a game, a couple of games were like in one hand, the bids will be like one, one, zero.
Rym: And then the fourth person's like, uh, seven.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They got a really bad hand, but everyone else bid way low.
Scott: And the other thing is sometimes you'll underbid.
Scott: By accident.
Rym: Well, that was really it.
Rym: So when your example, the guy with that high trump, maybe he gets scared away from bidding because he knows like, all right, these guys got fucking wizards or whatever.
Rym: Right.
Rym: So he bids zero.
Rym: So now my shit hand is more likely to win because he's doing everything he can to not take any tricks.
Scott: So let's say I'm in a situation where I got like, I got a high card of every suit and a wizard.
Scott: So I've got, I think I'm going to take five tricks, but I'm pretty sure one of these is going to get fucked over.
Scott: It's a 10 and not a 13 and green or something.
Scott: So I'm like, yeah, someone's going to probably take an 11 or 12 green and I won't get that one.
Scott: So I'll go under by one.
Scott: I'll bid for.
Scott: then as we play all the I'm forced to play those high suit cards by following suit.
Scott: And I end up taking my four tricks and I still have my wizard in my hand.
Rym: So the other thing is when the bidding ends, usually you'll see like a lot like amongst people who are like really smart and good at trick taking games.
Rym: The bids are almost always within one or two of the actual number of tricks.
Scott: I've never been off by more than one.
Rym: Yeah, I've been.
Rym: I was off by two or three or four or five in toward the end.
Rym: If you're behind fucking just bid extra.
Scott: If you're going to lose.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Then your only hope to catch up is to try to take more tricks.
Scott: and nothing is like I'll play a hand and I'll bid three and I will take exactly three and say what a good job that was.
Scott: I got it exactly right.
Scott: But I didn't get it exactly right.
Scott: I could have taken four or five tricks.
Scott: I just didn't bet four or five.
Scott: So I chose during the round to not take tricks I could have taken because I bid too low.
Scott: So even though I got the right number and got the points and didn't lose points, I could have had more points because I made bidding was not aggressive enough.
Rym: So basically the game has the bidding aspects of bridge.
Rym: It has the trump protection aspects of Euchre and it has the ducking and de suiting tactics of hearts.
Rym: So it combines a lot of my favorite cards.
Scott: It's pretty much everything.
Scott: there is about trick taking games all in one game.
Rym: So it comes with a bunch of variants.
Rym: Plus wizards.
Rym: But whatever.
Rym: There is one problem with the game as written.
Rym: The game does not give you a way to deal with Renee.
Rym: So in like in Euchre if you fuck up and forget like you don't follow suit and then later it's like oops I had a heart and I should have played it.
Rym: That doesn't ruin the game.
Rym: The rules basically like the rules deal with that.
Rym: There's a rule for if someone Renee.
Scott: So let's say Renee.
Rym: Or if you live in the Midwest Renee because they just can't pronounce words.
Scott: So let's say Rym has a green card in his hand and I play green and he chooses to play some red card.
Scott: He forgets that he had green in his hand.
Scott: Then we find out later when he plays a green card I say Rym why didn't you follow that green card on the previous two turns ago and I played green.
Rym: Fuck we've ruined the game.
Rym: No way to fix it.
Scott: There's no fix written into the rules.
Scott: Now I know
Rym: I want I'm trying to come up with a rule that we as like our friend group is just going to agree upon as the rule for Renee just so that we don't have to deal with it because the fact
Scott: that I think the rules should be something along the lines of whoever takes that trick should take it according to the cards that were played.
Scott: But if you are caught basically you just lose chips.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You just lose points because you screwed up.
Rym: I'm trying to figure out like a number of them right.
Scott: I think the number has to scale up as you get deeper in the game.
Scott: It has to be.
Scott: the penalty should become worse.
Rym: How about this?
Rym: you lose a number of chips equal to the number of cards.
Scott: that might be too much though.
Scott: But at the same time it also depends on like how significant was the mistake you made.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It might not have mattered like oh you would have played it earlier and not taken the trick and the other card that you did play earlier would have not taken this trick.
Rym: And also you fucked up everyone else's card counting.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: the counting cards are very important.
Rym: So I'm not sure and if anyone has any suggestions discussed in the forum because that's the only flaw with this game.
Rym: The other thing is that there's a variant I really want to try because one thing that hearts has that makes hearts shooting the shooting the moon.
Scott: No.
Rym: So in hearts in the first hand.
Scott: Oh the passing.
Rym: You pick three cards and pass them to the dude to your left and the dude to your right passes three to you.
Rym: So I know that I gave this motherfucker three spades.
Rym: So I know he's got a bunch of high spades and I don't have any spades.
Rym: It's going to be awesome.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: So you can easily add that to wizard as a variant rule.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: Here's the question though.
Scott: Do you bid before or after passing?
Rym: I think after by default.
Rym: But hardcore mode is before.
Scott: I mean you could choose the cards you're going to pass, then bid, then see the cards you're picking up.
Scott: Because remember that you're still getting information from the other people's bids.
Rym: You could also have something cool where like you're allowed.
Rym: After you get your cards you're allowed to raise your bid but you can't lower it.
Rym: Like something like that.
Rym: This game is ripe for custom house rules.
Scott: The thing is with passing cards people are going to dump suit like pretty much immediately.
Rym: Yeah, that's what happens in hearts.
Scott: Trump cards become way more powerful.
Scott: And you'll be able to take way more tricks if you have any Trumps whatsoever.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Much like with Dune.
Scott: So do you reveal Trump before or after the bidding and passing?
Scott: The order matters so much.
Rym: Even then Scott, much like with Dune everybody has that power.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: And two.
Scott: But then luck becomes a big factor too.
Rym: In high level hearts play for example, I would pass my dad two high clubs and a middling to low club.
Rym: But maybe I didn't desuit myself of clubs.
Scott: Yeah, you got a low club.
Scott: I mean you're going to get rid of that.
Scott: no problem.
Scott: You kept the low one.
Rym: No, but I gave away a low one to imply that I had gotten rid of all my clubs.
Rym: and I'm probably some motherfucker who's going to heart and/or queen of spades someone.
Scott: You held one middling club.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's still not going to take a trick.
Rym: Hopefully not.
Rym: So you get into like the card.
Rym: in high level hearts play, the cards you pass themselves are a whole game of their own.
Scott: So it's like there's a whole process of seeing your cards, choosing which cards to pass, seeing the cards that were passed to you and seeing what Trump is and seeing the other players bids.
Scott: And you're also like when in that process the order that you do the things and when the people bid really changes the game a zillion.
Rym: So if you're an aspiring game designer and you think none of those things sound like a big deal, they're such different games.
Scott: If you don't understand why the order of those things changes the game like ten thousand percent, don't make any games.
Rym: And if you want to be good at this game when you first teach it to your friends, one, play a bunch of hearts online.
Rym: But two, a basic heuristic that a lot of noobs use is guess how many tricks you think you're going to take and go for one less than that because you're probably wrong.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You'll probably get wizarded or something.
Scott: It's like count the number of awesome trick taking cards in your hand that are powerful, the high Trumps and the wizards and whatever.
Scott: Take that number, subtract one and then try to take that many tricks and you'll probably beat most people who don't know what they're doing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And we're going to play, I mean, we're going to play a lot of games at PAX South, but I think wizard is going to be the like, it's going to be the default warm up game or the default.
Rym: four of us are waiting for you guys to finish eclipse before we do another thing game.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: Also, uh, at least our thing as came up at PAX offices, anytime someone plays a wizard, they basically sing that thing from Daffy Duck.
Rym: Behold, the wizard is incredible power that that you're pretty much obligated to say that out loud, possibly loudly every time you play a wizard.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, linked to that much like the posing in pen Dante.
Scott: This game is also, you know, it's a good, right?
Scott: Any good board game, any good tabletop game is going to have a thing that people say.
Rym: Y'all got a brick.
Rym: Y'all got wood from my sheep.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So the fact that this people are playing this game going wizard shows a good game.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.