Rym: It's Monday, January 27th, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight, USB.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: The
Rym: "usb.".
Rym: How come you jackasses will say "sequel" instead of "SQL" and you'll say "uet" instead of "uat" but you don't say
Rym: It's one of the few things that actually bothers me.
Rym: I mean, when someone says "jif" instead of
Rym: "dif."
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: "Usb."
Scott: It doesn't bother me on that level.
Rym: Are you going to be able to say that without bothering yourself in the long term?
Scott: If it bothers you, I can forget the bothering of me.
Rym: From back in the IBM days, it's just when people would be like "blah, blah, blah,
Rym: sequel.".
Rym: I'd be like, "What?
Rym: Sequel?".
Rym: But I've found that "sequel" and "uat" are getting said more and more in my circles.
Rym: I don't know how to fight against this tide.
Scott: Uh, you just keep saying "SQL"?
Rym: Yeah, I do.
Rym: I say
Rym: "uat.".
Rym: I guess I could just correct them.
Rym: Or I could act like I have no idea what they're talking about.
Rym: Like "uat," what?
Scott: I know people who worked for MySQL saying MySQL, so...
Rym: I know, I know.
Scott: They're wrong.
Rym: I mean, it's technically
Rym: "jif.".
Rym: It is.
Rym: I pretty much assume that anyone who says "jif" is either trolling or actually dumb.
Scott: Or the guy who invented
Scott: "jif."
Scott: Or they're talking about peanut butter.
Rym: That's
Rym: "jiffy.".
Scott: No, there's peanut butter.
Scott: that's just
Scott: "jif."
Scott: There is?
Rym: Or it's like a knockoff?
Scott: It's a brand of peanut butter.
Scott: It's
Scott: "jif."
Scott: That's the brand.
Rym: I don't really eat peanut butter.
Scott: It's really good.
Scott: You should eat it.
Rym: Also, the times I have eaten peanut butter...
Scott: You get ants on a log, you get a celery, you put peanut butter on it, and you put raisins in the peanut butter.
Scott: There's only one acceptable... Oh, you don't like raisins either.
Rym: I like raisins.
Rym: I don't like raisins as a snack.
Rym: A bowl of raisins is not appetizing to me.
Scott: You don't want any ants on a log?
Scott: Because you suck.
Rym: Ants on a log is kind of a lame snack.
Scott: You suck.
Rym: I much prefer the...
Scott: I'm gonna make some ants on a log when you get home.
Rym: See, peanut butter-filled celery is good.
Rym: No ass.
Rym: But...
Scott: Oh, see, because you're a raisin hater.
Rym: But it's gotta be, racist... It's gotta be crunchy, chunky peanut butter.
Rym: Or go home.
Scott: All peanut butter is good peanut butter.
Scott: Except for Peter Pan.
Scott: That shit sucks.
Rym: As a little kid, I used to like peanut butter toast.
Rym: I don't know if that's a thing.
Rym: Basically, what you do is you make some toast, and then you put some butter on it, and then you put some peanut butter on it.
Rym: And that's it.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's really good.
Scott: Butter is good.
Scott: Peanut butter is good.
Scott: Bread is good.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Fire is good.
Rym: It's way filling.
Rym: I feel like if I ate that in my modern adult life, my body would be like, "Oh, hell
Rym: no!".
Scott: That shit needs some bananas.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: Sugar.
Rym: I don't know about sugar.
Rym: That's too much.
Scott: There's sugar in the banana.
Rym: But you don't want extra sugar.
Rym: You don't want just banana sugar.
Scott: All sugar is good sugar.
Scott: All sugar?
Scott: Sugar plus butter is the best.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Butter dip butter with a glaze.
Rym: A sous-son of sugar.
Rym: I think bacon is kind of hipster overplayed at this point.
Scott: I'll eat it.
Scott: Bacon plus butter plus sugar.
Rym: Bacon butter sugar.
Scott: Brown sugar.
Rym: So yeah.
Rym: I was skiing the other weekend.
Rym: I've been skiing every weekend for a while now, and I gotta say...
Scott: Not dead yet?
Rym: Kinda leveled up to the point that I gotta fly somewhere now.
Rym: I got bored.
Scott: Go fly to wherever Michael Schumacher was.
Scott: Might as well hurry it up.
Rym: What I think I might do is... I'm gonna try to get another business trip to Omaha and then...
Scott: Skiing in Omaha?
Rym: Well, no.
Rym: Just after my trip in Omaha, I'll stop in Colorado for like three days and then come home.
Scott: Isn't Colorado beyond Omaha?
Rym: Yes, but flying from Omaha... That's not the way back.
Rym: So flying from Omaha to Colorado is much shorter than flying from here to Colorado, and I'm already over there anyway.
Scott: But you'll have to fly from Colorado to here, which is long.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the point is that the flights, other than my flight to Colorado, everything would be covered by my company.
Rym: And I would save the time because I'm already fucking over there.
Scott: They're gonna pay for your ski lodge, hotel, and lift ticket in Colorado?
Rym: No, I'll pay for that.
Scott: So I thought everything was covered by them.
Rym: Well, for the business trip part.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: The travel part is covered.
Scott: Why don't you just do business in Colorado?
Rym: There's really no business to be done in Colorado that I can find.
Rym: I've tried to do that.
Rym: I've tried to connive the business trip.
Rym: that is somewhere cool, but usually that's really hard.
Rym: I mean, Turkey's easy, but like...
Scott: How about the West Indies?
Rym: Uh, you've never been to the West Indies.
Scott: I haven't.
Scott: That's long ago.
Rym: But yeah, I have one thing to say about skiing.
Rym: Not saying snowboarding is a bad sport.
Rym: I think it's really cool.
Rym: I have nothing against it.
Rym: I think it is a skill-based and awesome activity equal to skiing, but different.
Rym: However, I'm just not allowed to say that nine times out of ten, if someone's doing something shitty at a mountain, it's a snowboarder and not a skier.
Rym: Just putting that observation out there.
Scott: Well, I think the problem is simply, it's nothing to do with snowboarding, right?
Scott: It's simply that mountains of ski that are used for skiing and snowboarding are populated mostly by people who want to snowboard, but don't actually snowboard, and instead get wasted and high and sit on the mountain.
Rym: Even if they're not good at skiing, I see skiers show up, do one run, and then take their skis off and just sit in the lodge for the rest of the day.
Rym: But the snowboarders will not get off the lift.
Rym: They'll get off the lift and just sit right down, and then the next lift comes up and people trip over them.
Rym: They just hang out at the bottom of the lift.
Rym: Nothing.
Scott: I would just step on them.
Rym: Yeah, they'll stop in the middle of a run.
Rym: I was skiing down a pretty fucking steep run, and there's this big sort of snow dune.
Rym: So I come up over the top of it, and I'm about to come down the other side at very high speed, and there's these two fucking snowboarders sitting there drinking beer.
Scott: Just sitting in the middle of the slope?
Rym: Yes, I literally almost hit them.
Rym: It took all of my skill to ski around.
Scott: Why wouldn't you just hit them?
Rym: Because that would have hurt me as much as it would have hurt them.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: If one guy's impaled by a ski, and you're just sort of laying in the snow, who's hurt?
Rym: Yeah, the thing is, so here's an example.
Rym: This slope, I actually fell another time on a similar snow dune, like in that same area.
Rym: I came over the top of one.
Rym: It was solid ice on the other side, but I hit on my side, like parallel, because I wanted to go across it.
Rym: But then it turned out that there wasn't snow there like everywhere else in the mountain.
Rym: There was a thin layer of fake snow, and it was basically solid ice, and I just slid on my edge so fast I could not stop myself even with full edging.
Scott: Skiing's totally safe.
Rym: It was totally fun.
Rym: I'm not saying it's totally safe.
Scott: You said it many times.
Rym: It's more safe than driving, I would say.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Rym: I survived, didn't hurt myself.
Scott: It's more safe than setting yourself on fire.
Scott: I've driven and not survived.
Rym: I'll bet the odds of you dying in a bike accident are higher than the odds of me dying in a ski accident.
Scott: All right, we'll see who gets hurt first.
Rym: All right, you're on.
Rym: You know, this is going to end with me getting a Zipcar and ramming you on your way to work on your bike.
Scott: So, news is, this news isn't that exciting, but I just thought it was interesting.
Scott: So, Stratasys, which is a company that makes 3D printers, announced that they have made the first multi-color, multi-material 3D printer.
Rym: Oh, I saw that thing.
Scott: It's sort of obvious idea, right?
Scott: The way a printer works is that there's some sort of head that squirts material, be it ink or melted plastic, right?
Scott: And it moves around, and it squirts, and it builds either images on paper or physical objects with this method, right?
Scott: It would be sort of obvious.
Scott: We already have color printers, and the way they work is they have multiple heads that squirt different colors.
Scott: So, you would make a 3D printer that had multiple heads and squirted different materials and colors with the different heads, thus to build a multi-material, multi-colored object in one print go instead of building separate objects and then sticking them together with glue at the end.
Scott: Or obvious idea, but no one had done it until now, apparently, because it's really not that simple to do with actual physical materials in a 3D printer the way it's simple to do with, you know, ink.
Rym: Yeah, because you're not building layers of stuff.
Scott: I mean, look how long it took to even get ink from, you know, dot matrix up to color desk jet and then laser color, right?
Rym: Yeah, I mean, when I was a kid, you couldn't just print to a piece of paper.
Rym: You had to print to this ugly-ass ribbon paper.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So, you know, we have finally reached this point, which is sort of the obvious development, but no one could quite pull it off into a product that could be sold, and here it is.
Scott: It's only $330,000.
Scott: I say give it, eh, three to five years before you can buy one of these for your house, and it's reasonable, like $1,000 to $2,000.
Scott: And then it'll be pretty awesome.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I mean...
Scott: Also, it's also a thing that makes me really like this is all the examples they have.
Scott: They're printing out multicolored bike helmets.
Rym: Ha!
Rym: Well, we've said this many, many times, so I'll just say it again briefly.
Rym: This technology, you know, milestones like this have been coming along pretty rapidly for a few years now.
Rym: 3D printing technology is moving way faster than the vast majority of humans think it is.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the things like we're hoping for, like brain into cyberspace, it's like we're not seeing much movement there.
Scott: All the movement...
Rym: We are.
Scott: All the real movement's happening in 3D printing right now.
Scott: We're gonna get to "Diamond Age" before we get to neuromancing.
Rym: Yeah, I just want to get to culture.
Scott: At the current rate, it's gonna be "Diamond Age" first, so...
Rym: My goal is just culture.
Scott: If you have to read some cyberpunk novels, "Diamond Age" is the first one to go to if you're worried about what's gonna happen soon.
Rym: Either that or just watch "Ghost in the
Rym: Shell.".
Scott: Yeah, but "Ghost in the Shell" is, you know, we're gonna have -- I'm saying, "Diamond Age" will come before "Ghost in the
Scott: Shell.".
Rym: I don't know, 'cause I point out that everything in "Ghost in the Shell" socially is happening except for the cyberbrains.
Rym: Like, we're doing all those things without cyberbrains.
Scott: But "Ghost in the Shell" doesn't have the 3D printing, which we are gonna have.
Rym: I know.
Scott: And we do have.
Rym: So we'll have the social "Ghost in the Shell" with the material "Diamond Age," but we won't have the far extremes of the other parts of the technology in the two.
Scott: We do need to make -- and maybe that's something that needs to be made -- the cyberpunk story that has both.
Rym: Uh, culture.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: You realize the problem with culture is that -- Yeah, because they don't need it.
Rym: They have it, and no one gives a shit.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: They're at the point where people will be like, "Yeah, I don't do simulation,".
Rym: 'cause there's literally no difference between simulation and reality.
Rym: Like, there's no such thing as "hacking" in the traditional sense.
Scott: You don't have to wait for the orbital to be built in the simulation.
Scott: It just is.
Rym: Yeah, if you don't want to wait for the orbital to be built, just stop your mind, save it in a substrate, and then get woken up when it's built.
Rym: Literally no time went by.
Rym: Yeah, culture books are really great, and I'm almost out of them.
Scott: Well, that's sad.
Rym: So I got another actually really cool news that you guys might not have been paying attention to.
Rym: So if you weren't aware, polio's not really an issue in the Western world, but still an issue in other parts of the world, even to this day.
Rym: But there's a big milestone.
Rym: India finally, after a long, long and hard battle, is on the verge of officially having eradicated polio.
Scott: Even in the places where, like, it's totally rural and there isn't really...
Rym: The numbers of cases in recent years were numbering in the hundreds, and now they're at the point to where some of the last work to do is to secure and/or destroy the samples of polio they have in labs because they've done such a good job of fighting polio.
Scott: Not to rain on a parade, but is this because maybe in the rural places they just infanticide babies with polio?
Rym: Uh, no, actually.
Rym: It's mostly due to the fact that they forced children to get immunizations.
Scott: That is a good news.
Rym: In fact...
Scott: And I have not found any badness in this news with my cynical powers.
Rym: They did it really obviously.
Rym: They got people together, they paid whatever needed to be paid to make this happen, and they had people at the border, even undocumented illegal refugees, whoever you were, if you had any kids, they'd be like, "Your kid's getting this vaccine," and then, "We're not gonna ask you any other questions or bother you in any other
Rym: way.".
Scott: Otherwise you can't come in.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Or they're gonna stab you with this needle, and then you can come in.
Rym: No, not even stab.
Rym: So they took the broad approach.
Rym: They used the other methods, like the nose spray and the other things.
Scott: Do they work?
Scott: I guess they must work.
Rym: They work almost as well.
Rym: So now that they've basically eradicated polio, by using that as this broad brush, they're using the more effective and safer injections to have another generation of kids with one higher level of immunity, and basically, India has solved this problem that has ravaged the entire world for a long time.
Rym: I mean, FDR had polio, guys.
Rym: That's why he was in a wheelchair.
Scott: He was in a wheelchair?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Actually, the U.S.
Rym: hid the fact that he was in a wheelchair to the point that, when he came to New York, he had a special train car that would be detached under Grand Central and had a special way for him to drive a car out of that train car into an elevator and go up into the hotel without anyone seeing him.
Rym: In that era, most people did not know that FDR needed a wheelchair because it was thought that it would damage the war effort to see him from a position of weakness.
Rym: That was a long time ago.
Rym: So if you think vaccines are bullshit, or you're one of those McCarthy-type people, you're a terrible person.
Rym: You should read this article.
Rym: Also, for everyone else, this is kind of an example of how we talk a lot about the far, far edges of technology -- the 3-D printing, the cyberspace -- and that stuff's all coming, but the very simple and basic application of existing technology can do more good for the world than anything on the cutting edge right now.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, the things that we're talking about have, you know, like, basic technologies that we enjoy every day have still not been deployed everywhere in the world, and that can do -- that can achieve more progress more easily than developing new whatevers -- It's like, yeah, if we would just fucking get fast Internet like they have in, say, Korea to everywhere in the world, it's an invention we've already invented.
Scott: We just had to deploy it.
Scott: The U.S.
Scott: doesn't even have that shit.
Scott: Canada doesn't even have what we have, right?
Rym: Yeah, or imagine if everyone in the world had access to clean water.
Rym: That would solve a lot of other problems.
Scott: Clean water?
Scott: We've had that technology for a long time.
Scott: Why don't we deploy that shit every single place people live, where there is water?
Rym: The problem is we keep deploying the shit.
Rym: We have to not deploy the shit and deploy the shit removal systems.
Rym: So, yeah, this is a long and detailed article about how India got rid of polio.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And you should really think about this because the United States went through this battle not that long ago.
Rym: There are people alive today who remember when people got polio in the U.S.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: You're all familiar with the fact that YouTube comments are -- They're not the literal bottom of the Internet because that's space dicks, but they're -- They're bad.
Rym: They're the bottom of the Internet that you can even see, like, below YouTube comments.
Scott: They're the worst Internet in the place that you actually go to.
Scott: See, it's like the worst Internet that you actually encounter normally that you can't really get away from.
Scott: Because you're gonna go to YouTube.
Rym: If you go to a city like Detroit and go to a really, really bad neighborhood and go to, like, the worst alley in that bad neighborhood, that's YouTube comments.
Rym: The only way to get worse is to go inside of a private crack house.
Scott: Right, but here's the thing, is that usually you don't go to those neighborhoods, right?
Scott: You don't go to space dicks.
Scott: But YouTube comments is like, "You're just walking down the street going to your regular old grocery store, and --".
Rym: You're like, "What's in that
Rym: alley?".
Scott: "And a guy from the really bad neighborhood walks into the grocery
Scott: store.".
Scott: That is YouTube comments.
Scott: And that's why there is such a problem, right, as opposed to if that guy stayed in his neighborhood in his space.
Scott: dicks, people wouldn't hate on it so much.
Rym: So this is a video, and these guys did an entire series of these.
Rym: So if you enjoy this, just click on that channel, Dead Parrot, and watch everything they got.
Scott: They're all brilliant.
Scott: Dead Parrot, you say?
Rym: Hell, yes.
Rym: So this is what they do.
Scott: It's not dead, I don't think.
Rym: They have actors.
Scott: They still had new videos uploaded.
Scott: They're not dead yet.
Rym: It's getting better.
Rym: He's pining for the fjords.
Rym: He's not pining, he's passed on.
Rym: All right, let's not quote the entire --.
Rym: I feel like nerds who were born in a certain era can start quoting Monty Python verbatim and not stop until an entire movie or scene is acted out.
Scott: So -- Neat.
Rym: Peng.
Rym: Neewum.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I concur.
Rym: So this is a reconstruction of a YouTube discussion between two people on the video of Nelson Mandela's funeral.
Rym: You can go look at the actual conversation that they are reenacting.
Rym: This is beautiful to behold.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Is that it?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Okay, so we've been reading, if you haven't been paying attention, there's been a lot of stories recently in the past few months or so about how most of the olive oil you get is not olive oil, right?
Scott: Apparently, what happens -- We might have talked about this in the show before, but a lot of the olive oils in the grocery store are, like, not 100% olive oil, and it's like they'll import other oils to Italy, combine them with olive oil, and then send them out, right?
Scott: So, you know, it's like now that that's been exposed to people who care, the only question we really want answered is, "Well, what the fuck olive oil do I buy?
Scott: that's actually goddamn olive
Scott: oil?"
Scott: Right?
Scott: So here's the answer.
Scott: Thing of the day.
Scott: Tom's -- I guess it's truth in olive oil.
Scott: Tom's Supermarket Picks.
Scott: Quality oils at good prices.
Scott: This guy went to a bunch of supermarkets.
Scott: He got olive oils, and he said, "Which ones are legit and which ones are not
Scott: legit?".
Rym: How did he determine that?
Rym: Did he test?
Scott: He is an olive oil expert person.
Rym: How do you know he's not a scam?
Rym: How do you know he's not in the pocket of Big Olive?
Scott: Because he's mentioned a whole bunch of different olive oils everywhere, and none -- Yeah, maybe the olive lobby has got him in their pocket.
Scott: I trust anyone who says they went to Trader Joe's and only three out of the six were the real deal.
Rym: Maybe Trader Joe's didn't pay up.
Rym: Too big oil.
Scott: It paid -- I don't know.
Scott: All right, fine.
Rym: Maybe he did not worship at the altar of olive oil.
Scott: If this page is an olive oil conspiracy, well, you're just fucked.
Scott: You're not gonna get real olive oil anyway.
Scott: But at least the next time I go to go buy some oil, I'm either A, gonna buy the cheapest goddamn oil they have, and if it's fake, who gives a shit?
Scott: I'm buying the cheapest oil.
Scott: Or B, buy the olive oil on this list.
Scott: Plus, I think I also learned you sort of need two olive oils.
Rym: Yeah, exactly what I was about to say.
Rym: You need extra virgin olive oil -- You got to get the olive oil -- -- for dipping things into.
Scott: Right, for dipping your breads.
Scott: And then you got to get the oil, the cheapo one for cooking.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's still olive oil, but you don't want that strong-ass olive flavor.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You got to get two different oils.
Scott: So, in the meta moment -- Oh, and you use the one for dipping also for salad dressing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The meta moment, the book club book was -- "I Do Do" by William Gibson.
Rym: It was pretty good.
Rym: We both read it.
Rym: We're gonna do a show on it as soon as we can.
Scott: Thursday?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Next Thursday.
Scott: Next Thursday?
Rym: The next book will be, I finally decided, "Wool" by Hugh Howery, because I was given a copy of this book by a listener.
Rym: I was given another copy of this book that was signed by the author by someone.
Rym: I got a copy of this book in the goodie bag at that PAX charity dinner that we went to.
Scott: I have one of those, too.
Rym: The CTO of my company was like, "Hey, you read a bunch of sci-fi.
Rym: I just read the most amazing
Rym: book.".
Rym: And it ended up being
Rym: "Wool.".
Rym: The universe is telling me to read this.
Rym: People are losing their shit over it.
Scott: And I gotta say -- It might be -- I mean, it wasn't quite that intense, but I had a similar thing with "Name of the Wind," and look how that turned out.
Rym: I was about to say, a similar thing happened with "The Kingkiller Chronicle," and it turned out that "The Kingkiller Chronicle" is Captain Nice Guy's penis adventures through the sex lands of fedora world.
Rym: And, yeah, I'm hoping either this book will live up, which will be -- That's a win, if it lives up.
Scott: Or so bad our episode is so good.
Rym: If I get to piss all over your parade, that is equally valuable to me.
Scott: Oh, what else do we got?
Scott: I hope they're not pulling the wool over our eyes on this one.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX East.
Rym: We're gonna be at Zenkai Con.
Scott: What?
Scott: Why?
Scott: We're gonna be at Anime Boston.
Scott: Okay, we can go there.
Rym: We're gonna be at ConnectiCon.
Rym: We're scheduling panels for ConnectiCon currently.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX Prime.
Rym: We're gonna be at MAGFest.
Scott: I'm gonna be at PAX Australia.
Rym: Scott is probably not going to be at PAX Australia.
Scott: Someone want to pay for it?
Rym: Yeah, we might get someone to pay for it.
Scott: Send me some monies.
Rym: Maybe we'll do a Kickstarter of "Bring Scott Along to
Rym: Australia.".
Scott: I don't need enough monies just for the plane ticket.
Scott: I also need monies to make up for my unpaid vacation days.
Scott: Nah.
Rym: What if you covered half of it?
Rym: 'Cause it's gonna be summer.
Rym: You can go to the reefs.
Scott: I know.
Rym: That's part of the reason why I really want to go.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much the only place I want to go.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I just don't want to -- You know, it's like, I want to go to every PAX, and I want to go to see the coral reef, but I feel bad going to the same country twice.
Scott: I haven't even been to Europe once.
Scott: I got to go to Europe.
Rym: My plan is to go to Australia for PAX.
Scott: The thing is, I want a convention to go to in Europe, but there's no PAX there, and all the conventions they have there, as far as I can tell, are just like land parties, besides Essen.
Rym: So, Scott, I'm planning to spend like three weeks.
Rym: My plan is to do PAX and then do work stuff, like basically go to Sydney and all these cities doing work stuff.
Rym: I kind of want to book enough days off to bike from Melbourne to Sydney.
Scott: I guess in the summer you can do that.
Scott: Well, we learned you can just bike on the freeway.
Scott: Yeah, just pass all those farms.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean, we saw there's bike lanes on the goddamn freeways there.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I'm really excited about that.
Rym: I looked online.
Rym: People have biked from Melbourne to Sydney.
Rym: It's not out of the realm for someone of my ability, and then I want to go up to the reefs and then go home, or maybe I'll stop somewhere in that region on my way home.
Scott: I think this year I'm going to spend my monies on just getting a new bike and maybe that camera if it comes out.
Rym: Ah, you should probably get that camera.
Scott: That rumored 4K.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: So people can really see our pores when we do GeekNights Presents.
Scott: And our Netrunner cards.
Rym: So yeah, tons of videos of our shit around the internet.
Rym: Spread them around.
Rym: The more you spread them, the more views they get, the quicker we make more.
Rym: We have created more episodes of GeekNights Presents, and as soon as I can get my ass down to editing them.
Scott: You mean one episode?
Rym: One is a number.
Scott: You said episodes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: We even created one episode.
Rym: Well, I'm trying to think of how I could stretch that into episode.
Rym: I could release it as two episodes like we did with that one Nanami thing.
Scott: That you should not do.
Rym: I could release episode 10 and then episode 10A.
Scott: Do not do that.
Rym: But I did that once.
Rym: We had the choo-choo aside.
Scott: Well, there's no asides in this one.
Rym: I could do an aside of just the shadow girls.
Rym: I could add audio explaining that it might have been a metaphor for that time when Chiyo Saito, or when Ikahara went to Chiyo Saito supposedly and said, "Hey, what color should the dress be?
Rym: This one or this
Rym: one?".
Rym: And Chiyo Saito was like, "That
Rym: one.".
Rym: He was like, "Okay," and then did the opposite of what she said.
Scott: According to an America.
Rym: Yes, according to an America.
Rym: I digress.
Rym: Join our forum.
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: So, you might be thinking to yourself, you kids out there, "Why are Rym and Scott doing a show on
Rym: USB?".
Scott: Because Rym wanted to.
Rym: There's so little to say.
Rym: I plug it in and it just works.
Rym: And that's kind of true.
Rym: But at the same time, the reason I want to do this show, you'll see I sort of have a point here at the end, a moral to all this, is that randomly over the last few months, I had multiple people who are technological in some fashion incorrectly correct me on a matter of USB.
Rym: Multiple occasions came up where someone had some question like, "I want to plug my thing into my cell
Rym: phone.".
Rym: I'd say, "Oh, you need a micro B or a mini
Rym: B.".
Rym: And then they'd be like, "Oh, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: What's this
Rym: thing?".
Rym: And I was like, "Oh, that's
Rym: A.".
Rym: And then they'd say, "No, I think that's B. I think you're
Rym: wrong.".
Rym: And they just didn't know what they were talking about.
Rym: And enough people were wrong about USB in the same way.
Rym: I don't know if someone just wrote some documentation incorrectly somewhere.
Rym: I don't know if someone fucked up somewhere and a lot of people don't know how USB works and in fact know it the opposite way from how it should be.
Rym: So what I want to explain is how USB works from the functional level, like the parts that matter to you as a technologist.
Scott: Well, I mean, first you got to understand the history of USB, right?
Scott: Back in the day, as late as the late '90s, when you wanted to plug something into your computer, there were a hundred different kinds of things you could plug in.
Scott: And we're just talking about the outside.
Rym: No inside shit.
Scott: We're talking external cables.
Scott: You had PS/2 cables.
Rym: You had parallel cables, serial ports.
Rym: Most computers did not have parallel ports.
Scott: We had parallel ports.
Rym: Yeah, usually you had to buy a card that was often a combination parallel port card, sound card.
Scott: Well, no, the sound card would have a game port on it, which I didn't meant, right?
Scott: And then there was SCSI on some computers, like RAM with the SCSI-ness.
Rym: I paid a lot of money for that fucking SCSI-ness.
Scott: Right, and that was just PCs.
Scott: Apple computers had a whole bunch of others, right?
Scott: And in those days also, when you connected hardware to a computer, you had to manually configure like the IRQ and whatnot.
Scott: So you had all these problems.
Scott: And what happened was is around the time that Windows 95, 98 came out, they solved the problem of detecting, automatically detecting what was plugged in.
Scott: So you didn't have to manually configure your shit.
Scott: It would just be like, "Oh, I see some hardware.
Scott: All
Scott: good.".
Rym: That was a big deal.
Scott: Right, it was called Plug and Play, right?
Scott: And it actually started to work.
Scott: And they could load the drivers for your hardware dynamically instead of you having to manually put them in.
Scott: So that allowed for the introduction of USB, the Universal Serial Bus.
Scott: They could replace pretty much almost all of those ports with one kind of port, the USB.
Scott: And the most important thing about USB is that you could plug and unplug something while the computer was on.
Scott: You didn't have to detect it when it turned on.
Scott: You used to have to like, if you want to plug something new into your computer, you'd have to turn your computer off, plug something in, turn the computer on.
Scott: Not USB, you don't do that shit.
Rym: Huge difference.
Rym: Huge.
Rym: So imagine this.
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: In the old days, I was at a LAN party, right?
Rym: In Southfield.
Rym: And I went with a bunch of my friends.
Rym: We'd respect our giant fucking CRTs.
Rym: Everyone rode with a CRT in their lap.
Rym: We go to this LAN party, we hook everything up, we play.
Rym: In the middle of a tournament, I kicked my keyboard cable out.
Scott: You had to restart your computer.
Rym: I had to reboot my computer.
Rym: You can't just plug that shit back in.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So all these methods were very, very simple.
Rym: The way these ports worked was so simple that you would almost laugh at them today.
Rym: Serial ports had all these pins that had all these different functions.
Rym: You could make a circuit that would respond to a serial port out of resistors and a breadboard.
Rym: Like you, right now, could just do that.
Rym: It was so simple.
Rym: Maybe a big chip with a bunch of NAND gates on it to make it easier.
Rym: Parallel ports, in theory, were faster than serial ports.
Scott: In theory.
Rym: Because serial ports were serial.
Rym: They said one bit at a time.
Scott: Just like a serial TV show.
Scott: Things in order.
Scott: So USB is serial.
Scott: It sends one bit at a time, basically, but the bits come in so fast, one after the other.
Scott: A parallel port can send multiple bits simultaneously.
Scott: Like, here are eight bits, and they all arrive at the same exact moment.
Scott: So it's like having eight USB ports.
Scott: That should be eight times faster, right?
Scott: Right?
Rym: Well, it was until you started clocking up the speed.
Rym: Because it turns out that in all signaling, one, it actually takes time for the voltage.
Rym: Because remember, signals, as we talked about, god, like five years ago on GeekNights.
Rym: If you want to send a one, you have to agree mutually on both sides.
Rym: What is a one?
Scott: Five volts is a one.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So your voltage changes to determine ones and zeros.
Rym: There's different encoding mechanisms for that.
Rym: But it takes time for the voltage to get to the threshold and then get to the other threshold.
Scott: It's like the voltage is at zero.
Scott: It goes up to five, which means it was at one at some point, and at two at some point, and at three at some point.
Scott: It's pretty fast when it switches up to five and down to zero again.
Scott: But it takes longer than zero seconds to get the voltage up and then bring it back down again.
Rym: So essentially, what happened was with parallel communication, the same thing happened with IDE and hard drives.
Rym: Parallel data transfers are very difficult to synchronize at high speed.
Rym: All eight of those wires have to be sending at the exact same timing or the whole thing breaks down.
Scott: And by adding technology to keep that stuff synchronized, you're actually just -- that's time taking away from -- It increases complexity.
Rym: It increases cost.
Rym: It increases a lot of issues.
Scott: You could just send one bit at a time really, really fast and just forget about trying to synchronize anything.
Scott: Instead of using some hardware to synchronize stuff, that hardware can just send more bits faster and read more bits faster.
Rym: Remember the background in PETA, parallel ATA.
Rym: Hard drives used to connect with those ribbon cables.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And then SATA stands for serial ATA, serial one bit at a time.
Scott: And notice how the cable is so much smaller because, yeah, it's only sending one bit at a time.
Scott: You don't need a million cables if you're only sending one at a time.
Scott: All those cables are all to send simultaneous bits on separate wires.
Scott: If you're only sending one wire has the bits on it, well, two technically.
Scott: Then the cables are much smaller for everything and easier to plug in.
Scott: and just everything is just better.
Rym: Now, you might be saying, but Black Dynamite, couldn't I send more than one bit at the same time over one cable?
Rym: Well, you sort of can, but then you have another level of complication.
Rym: For example, in radio signals, there's what?
Rym: QAM, quadratic amplitude modulation.
Rym: This is getting back into like my freshman year of RIT stuff.
Rym: Basically, you could have an encoding mechanism that says something like, if I get up to five volts, it's one, it's zero zero.
Rym: But if I get up to ten volts plus ten, then it's zero one.
Rym: And you could come up with an encoding scheme.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But now it takes longer to get to all those different voltage states.
Scott: Yeah, to go from zero to ten takes a long ass time.
Rym: And also you have to get to them reliably so that the other side understands, was that a one zero or a one one?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And you have all the same problem, well, not the same problems, but the same order of problems that you get with a parallel cable.
Scott: Now you could.
Scott: Well, if we could just make serial cables so fast, why don't we just have ten serial cables hooked up to one hard drive?
Scott: And it's like, sure, you can do that.
Rym: Yeah, if you have an asynchronous way of getting at the data you want.
Scott: None of those will be synchronized.
Scott: One of them might be going slightly faster or slower than the other ones.
Scott: You need beyond on the other side of the cables, you need some kind of software or something working at a higher level to sort of resynchronize all the data and put it together.
Scott: It's like, you know, if one of the cables sends you like a hundred bits and the other one is only sent one bit, you need to keep that shit in line somewhere.
Scott: And if you can do it, you can do it.
Rym: Now think about it, something like...
Scott: But then suddenly your CPU is doing this work, putting data back together instead of actually processing that data.
Rym: To use a far flung example, BitTorrent, against a bunch of stuff from a bunch of different sources and puts it together in one contiguous file, because you don't care about latency.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: You can wait, you don't need it in real time.
Rym: It turns out with a mouse or a keyboard, latency matters a lot.
Rym: If you click and something doesn't immediately react, you're frustrated immediately, at least you should be.
Rym: And there's a separate discussion we can have about how I think UIs needs to be prioritized above literally everything else in a modern computer.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: So, Windows 95 didn't even fucking support USB, because that's about when it came out.
Rym: Windows 95...
Scott: You had to get drivers to do it.
Rym: Windows 95, I think B supported it, but I never upgraded to B.
Scott: I only had B.
Rym: Yeah, I had A. I bought it, yeah.
Rym: Not getting into all that stuff.
Scott: I remember, I think I have the CD still, and it says with USB support on the disk.
Rym: So, USB got adopted, and it was actually a big deal when USB got adopted.
Scott: It was surprising, it came out, and some motherboards had it, other people had to buy cards to add USB ports.
Scott: But it was like when they started actually making hardware that used it, people were, you know, it's actually caught on.
Scott: And I think really what made it catch on is that almost all the people who had mice and keyboards started making USB mice and keyboards, and they always included in the package a USB to PS2 adapter.
Scott: So, it's like because that was able to exist, the USB to PS2 adapter was such a simple and cheap device, that that's what allowed everyone to switch to making USB mice and keyboards just in throwing these adapters in the package, so that, you know, USB adoption actually happened, right?
Scott: Otherwise, all the people who made mice and keyboards would have kept making PS2 mice and keyboards and USB mice and keyboards separately, and you wouldn't have had people all switching over as much as they did.
Rym: So, the way USB works, you don't care about the signaling.
Rym: Now, this is where I want to talk about the details, because I think a lot of people who think they're using USB 3 aren't.
Rym: No kidding.
Rym: Because I went around showing a lot of people what USB 3 cables look like, and everyone I showed these to, without exception, said, "Whoa, what's that?
Rym: Some kind of proprietary USB
Rym: bullshit?".
Rym: I was like, "No, that's USB 3.
Rym: You clearly are not using it on any device you
Rym: own.".
Scott: I'm using it.
Scott: I have a USB 3 USB stick, and I have a USB 3 holes on my computer.
Rym: Now, the difference is that actually there's different numbers of pins, and there's different kinds of connectors, partly to allow for backward compatibility.
Rym: We'll get to that in a minute.
Rym: So, USB 2 is what most people use and know about.
Rym: That's the USB that was useful.
Scott: It's just faster than USB 1, pretty much.
Rym: The big revolution in USB was that, one, it was serial, which was better because it could extend.
Rym: It could get faster over time.
Scott: You could unplug and plug things in while the computer was on.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Hot swapping.
Rym: And it could provide power to devices.
Scott: That is the super important thing.
Scott: It used to be when you had a serial cable or a parallel cable or any other kind of cable, you would have to -- PS/2 cables provided enough power to light those little lights.
Scott: Yeah, PS/2 provided enough power for your mouse and keyboard, but that's not enough power to actually do anything, right?
Scott: If you couldn't charge an iPhone from a PS/2 port, if you bought a hard drive that used a serial cable, you had to plug that hard drive into the wall.
Scott: Even when I had a USB 56K modem, that modem had a separate thing to plug into the wall to get power and then a separate thing for the phone cable, right?
Scott: It didn't get all its power just from USB.
Rym: So, kids, if you ever plugged your iPad into a USB port and it wouldn't charge, you didn't understand why, turns out the different versions of USB, as time went on, supported different amounts of power.
Rym: And there's actually a negotiation for, "Hey, device, how much power can you
Rym: handle?".
Rym: "Hey, computer, I can handle five amps.
Rym: Let's
Rym: go.".
Scott: You can't have five amps.
Scott: Pretty much most USB today, almost every USB you're going to encounter is going to be one amp, right?
Scott: Which is enough to charge a lot of things.
Scott: But an iPad is probably the most popular device that will only charge if it sees two amps.
Scott: And almost every USB port you encounter will only be able to provide one.
Scott: So you need to use the Apple given charger to charge your iPad or get a charger that has specifically USB two-amp ports on it and it'll probably have a cable to, you know, a power cable to plug into the wall to get extra juice to power those ports.
Scott: I bought pretty much the best one of these that you can buy.
Scott: And it only has two two-amp ports and two one-amp ports for charging USB devices.
Scott: Because think about it, that's already four, five, six amps.
Scott: That's a lot.
Scott: So, you know, if you made one that was like, you know, like ten two-amp ports, that's 20 amps, you could kill yourself with that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So speaking of killing yourself, here's the part that people don't seem to get.
Rym: There's four pins on standard two USB two.
Rym: Don't worry about USB.
Rym: one is effectively, like it's all backward compatible.
Rym: It all just kind of works.
Rym: You don't need to worry about it.
Rym: There's four pins.
Rym: Two of those pins are for data.
Rym: Because it sends the same data over both pins.
Rym: Opposite.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: The same way ethernet cables do.
Scott: So you have two cables and on cable, if you want to send a one from one end to the other.
Scott: If I want to send Rym a one, we have two basically cups on strings, right?
Scott: I want to send them a one.
Scott: So on the left cup, I say one and the right cup, I say zero.
Scott: And on his end, he gets a one on the left cup and a zero on the right cup.
Scott: And he's like, aha.
Rym: Now that works because of math.
Rym: If you send the same signal with the opposite, so one's plus ten and one's minus ten.
Rym: Just to give you some egregious example.
Rym: That's the point where you're sending your data.
Rym: Then if there's interference, it'll push both of those waves in the same direction because the cables are right next to each other.
Rym: So as a result, you can mathematically eliminate the noise at the other end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So something happens that ruins the signal there.
Scott: It's like, OK, I sent a one on cup one, so it'll become a two.
Scott: And the zero on the other cup will become like a negative one.
Scott: And if I go, he'll get it on the other end and be like, oh, all right, that should have been a one.
Scott: These both got boosted up.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Right.
Scott: They got pushed away from each other or toward, you know.
Rym: So USB can deliver a lot of power.
Rym: I mean, powered USB, which I'll talk about in a second.
Rym: I just looked up because I forgot how much.
Rym: It operates on a 48 volt DC and can send up to 25 fucking watts.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: That's enough for speakers, yo.
Rym: There's crazy stuff.
Scott: I mean, they have USB monitors now, so you can get some serious power out of it.
Rym: Well, powered USB is special, so we'll get to that.
Rym: That's not something that uses extra pins.
Scott: It's like power over ethernet power.
Rym: Actually, yes, it's very related to that.
Rym: So those four pins, the other two pins are one's ground and one's power.
Rym: It's actually really simple.
Scott: It's so simple.
Rym: So when you plug a lamp in, how do you not accidentally create a voltage loop?
Scott: Because it just is.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: it just is?
Rym: So I got a lamp.
Rym: I got those two little prongs that live in the United States.
Rym: Maybe let's say two prongs.
Rym: Forget the three prongs.
Rym: I can plug my fucking cable in either way.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: 180 degrees, it's fine.
Rym: How come I can't fuck up?
Rym: I can't plug an extension cord into power and then plug the other end of that extension cord into power.
Rym: Why doesn't that ever happen?
Scott: Because it's AC?
Scott: It's smart?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: No, because the ends are different.
Scott: I thought, yeah, but it doesn't matter which end is which.
Scott: They're just different shapes.
Rym: Yes, but they're different shapes.
Rym: The end with the prongs always goes into the place where the power is coming from.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So there's no way to plug the thing where power is coming out into the thing where power is coming from.
Rym: You can't plug a socket into a socket or a plug into a plug.
Rym: Unless you're a moron and you really, really work at it.
Scott: Oh, I thought you meant a loop between the two prongs.
Scott: You're talking about taking the end where the light bulb is and plugging that into the wall also.
Rym: Well, you can't make a loop between the two prongs either using standard cables because no matter what you plug things into, you'll never get a loop.
Rym: You can't get a loop with normal cables.
Rym: in a way that would be meaningful.
Scott: You could go and make a cable that has prongs on one end and prongs on the other end and plug them both into the wall.
Scott: And you know what?
Rym: People die every year doing that.
Rym: You know what the use case is?
Scott: Suicide?
Scott: No, no.
Rym: It's something you're going to go,
Rym: "Uh-oh.".
Rym: Every year, in fact, if you go to Home Depot around Christmas, you'll see signs saying, "Never do
Rym: this.".
Scott: Oh, Christmas lights?
Rym: Yes, because people will string up Christmas lights the wrong way, be done, realize they can't plug their shit in, and rather than unwind all the cables, they'll stick a plug-to-plug adapter.
Rym: in the end, and thus at the top of their tree is a death spike.
Rym: Lots of people get killed by that every year.
Rym: So USB has the same thing.
Rym: USB-A does not mean anything special.
Rym: USB-A is the connector that you plug into your computer.
Rym: It's the USB thing that you know, the rectangle.
Rym: The USB-A socket is what you plug into, and the USB-A socket is where power comes from.
Rym: It's where the controlling device is.
Rym: It's the computer.
Rym: Whatever counts as the computer is USB-A.
Rym: USB-B is whatever you plug that computer into.
Rym: That's the device.
Rym: That's the hard drive.
Rym: So that little square guy that you plug into printers, that's the reason you have two different cables.
Rym: Yeah, the big square one.
Rym: The thing you plug into a printer or a scanner, or like a shitty old phone.
Rym: Actually, I don't think any phone used B. I can't imagine a phone that used B. Mostly printers and scanners and hard drives back in the day.
Rym: That's B. That way, you'll never plug a computer into itself and cause the voltage to hit itself and short out.
Rym: You'll never cause an electrical loop.
Scott: But what if I just want to connect two computers to each other with a USB cable?
Rym: You fucking can't.
Rym: It's not designed for that.
Rym: The architecture is not designed to do that.
Scott: That's sad.
Rym: Now, you could have designed it that way.
Rym: You could have had computers have A's and B's.
Rym: There are cables that are active cables that have logic inside of them.
Rym: that will have an A cable coming out of both ends, an A plug.
Rym: Plug it into two computers and the cable acts like a device that will allow data transfer.
Rym: It'll make both devices look like, I guess, external hard drives.
Scott: Something like that.
Rym: Yeah, like those things exist.
Scott: A lot of people, there's buttons you can push to turn a MacBook into a hard drive and then connect it in that kind of way.
Rym: Ooh, we'll get to that.
Rym: I think that's like a USB on the go.
Rym: I think that's what it's called.
Rym: It's something with phones that I didn't know about until about a couple months ago.
Scott: Yeah, I think if you hold a certain button down while you boot up a MacBook, it becomes a hard drive and then you can plug that into another computer and mount it.
Rym: You might have noticed that people say there's micro and mini USB.
Rym: Micro and mini, what you see are both B connectors.
Rym: They're just smaller versions of the B connector.
Scott: Yep, they work in exactly the same way.
Scott: They're just a smaller, different, better shape because we have smaller, different, better devices.
Rym: Mini is deprecated because it's way too big.
Scott: Right, mini is the one that you usually see on Blackberries.
Scott: That one is dead.
Scott: Micro is the one you see on Kindles and Android phones.
Scott: That is the new one that is still being used.
Scott: No new device should be using the mini one, but I'm sure some still do.
Scott: I have a lot of devices that use it.
Rym: A lot of cameras and things that use it.
Scott: I have some external hard drives that use it.
Scott: It's still around, but you're not supposed to use it anymore, but people do.
Scott: There's not anything wrong with it.
Scott: It's just unnecessarily large.
Rym: So your typical USB cable you use to charge your phone is USB-A to USB micro-B.
Rym: But Black Dynamite, isn't there a micro-A?
Rym: And the answer is yes, but no one uses it.
Rym: There's also a mini-A.
Rym: There's two variants of both ends.
Rym: It just turns out that there was no--.
Scott: There's no one actually using that ever.
Rym: I've seen them in person.
Rym: I've touched them.
Rym: I had them for a few weird devices I worked with over the years.
Rym: You can find pictures of them online.
Scott: But if you have a printer, why do you need a micro-connector on a printer?
Scott: That's why you don't see these things too often.
Rym: You could have a micro-connector on a printer because that would be a B.
Scott: Well, you could.
Rym: Why would you need a micro on a computer is the question.
Scott: Well, you could have a situation where you had, say, like a keyboard, right?
Scott: And the keyboard had a removable cable, right?
Scott: So then you would see the weird-- Most keyboards, just the cables, just coming right out of the keyboard, right?
Rym: But if the keyboard actually had a completely detachable cable-- But then it would still be A on the computer end and then micro or mini-B on the keyboard end.
Rym: It wouldn't be micro or mini-A.
Rym: Micro or mini-A would only be useful if you were going to plug that tiny cable into a computer.
Rym: It turns out that any device that is the A device, the alpha, the computer, doesn't really matter if the cable is slightly smaller because it's a giant-ass computer or laptop anyway.
Rym: The variation on that that sort of complicates things is--.
Rym: I've got to look this up again because I've never used it.
Rym: Is the on-the-go USB on the go?
Rym: Go to whatever it is.
Rym: The connectors on some phones are both micro-A and micro-B compatible.
Scott: And they can only be one at a time?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So if I plug a keyboard into my phone, then it acts like an A and accepts the connection from the keyboard, and now I have a keyboard.
Rym: It's like I plugged a keyboard into my computer.
Rym: My phone is now a computer.
Rym: But if I plug a B cable into it, the phone says, "Oh, I guess I'm the external hard drive for some other
Rym: computer.".
Rym: And you need a lot of logic to make sure you don't fuck that up because only As can send power.
Scott: This is really similar to the Bluetooth situation, right?
Scott: Where it's like sometimes you're in your car and you want to connect your car to your phone with Bluetooth.
Scott: So sometimes you go into the car's UI to find the phone and connect to it, and sometimes you go on the phone to try to pair with the car, as one of them is in charge and one of them is sort of not in charge.
Rym: Now, luckily, you can't plug B into A and A into B. The sockets that allow this sort of on-the-go thing are designed to accept both A and B. So it's still pretty much impossible to plug anything into a USB port the wrong way unless you buy an illegal or non-spec cable.
Rym: that does something stupid.
Scott: So yeah, USB 3, the cables look-- Just way the hell faster.
Rym: USB 3, for one, uses nine pins, not four.
Scott: Yep, but they've arranged them in the cable in such a way that there's still the original four are in there and will be used as the original four, but it'll just be using USB 2, and those other pins won't be doing shit.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So usually the only way to tell is that a USB 3 port-- Are blue.
Rym: --tend to be blue, but that's not required.
Scott: It's not required, but it's sort of a helpful thing, right?
Scott: I think USB 2-- Everything I have that's USB 3 is blue.
Scott: Even the USB stick I bought is blue.
Rym: USB 2 was, I think, supposed to be white and one was black, but it doesn't really matter anymore.
Scott: Yeah, I don't see that ever.
Rym: Now a lot of USB 2s on laptops are yellow because that's the one that's also the give power while I'm asleep.
Scott: Yeah, the yellow one, I mean, everything is USB 2 now.
Scott: I haven't seen a USB 1 port in forever.
Scott: But yeah, yellow usually means even if you turn this computer off and put it to sleep, not off completely, and you plug this laptop into the wall, this USB port will still have power just coming out of it if you want to charge your phone or some shit.
Rym: So there's even further specifications.
Rym: There's nine pins in USB 3.
Rym: Powered USB 3 that can give a shit ton of power has two additional pins.
Rym: Now here's the difference.
Rym: USB 3 isn't just faster.
Rym: It also is bi-directional.
Scott: Full duplex.
Rym: USB 2 is not full duplex, shit guys.
Rym: You can't send and receive data at the same time.
Scott: Yeah, only one talker at a time.
Scott: This is a big deal.
Scott: We used to have an ethernet hub in college that was not full duplex, and that's why it was so cheap.
Scott: And basically it means that if I'm talking to you, you can't talk until I stop talking, and then you can talk again.
Rym: That's why CDMA in ethernet stands for collision detection multiple access.
Rym: So you would listen for collisions because sometimes two people would collide with each other.
Rym: But with modern switches with full duplex, there's no such thing as collisions because there's only one computer on any given segment.
Scott: So with USB 3, let's say you had a hard drive and you were reading data from the hard drive, like a USB stick, you couldn't write data to the hard drive at the same time.
Scott: You had to wait for the reading to be done and then do the writing.
Rym: Or interleave it back and forth.
Scott: You think, wait a minute, I dragged a file off my USB stick and then dragged a file onto it, and both of the progress meters in Windows moved.
Scott: They moved slow, but they moved.
Scott: It's like, that's right, because what Windows is doing is basically going read, write, read, write, read, write, read, write, read, write, and alternating between the two.
Scott: If you had a USB 3 stick and were using USB 3, both of those would move at full speed because it could read and write simultaneously.
Rym: Now, the reason why sound cards in the old days, even with USB 2, sucked ass, was that because it's not full duplex, it was really hard to have synchronous streams of data.
Rym: There was an isochronous mode that would let you do that, but it wasn't super high bandwidth.
Rym: ASIO.
Rym: Yeah, ISO.
Rym: I-O synchronous.
Scott: ASIO, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, not ASIO.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: That's something different altogether.
Rym: Let's talk about FireWire if you want to get into that business.
Rym: Now, I don't want to talk about the differences between USB and FireWire, but low bandwidth coupled with the fact that there's very high latency.
Rym: USB has latencies, depending on how it's configured, up to a millisecond.
Scott: This is why gaming mice are important to get because latency matters in a gaming application, but it doesn't really matter for printing or a lot of other things, but you need a gaming mouse keyboard mostly because it's going to mitigate USB latency as much as possible.
Rym: Now, depending on what mode the USB is operating in, that is or is not a concern, which is another reason why sometimes you might have issues.
Rym: USB cannot send data at its full rate and send its maximum power at the same time because the power interferes with the data.
Scott: Yeah, even using the two wires for the data is not enough to mitigate a crap ton of interference.
Scott: You can only have so much.
Rym: So that is why some devices, when they're charging, cannot also be used for data transfers or seem really slow suddenly.
Rym: So yeah, the last cool thing I really want to point out is that if you look at USB 3.0 connectors, they're complicated.
Rym: They look almost ghetto and hacked together.
Rym: They look like two connectors kind of stuck onto each other because that's literally what they are.
Rym: A USB 3.0 slot, a B-slot, is a big square with another rectangle hanging off on top of it.
Rym: That way you could plug a USB 2.0 cable into it for backward compatibility.
Rym: Micro 3.0 is a USB micro cable with another ghetto-ass micro 3.0 cable kind of stuck next to it for the same reason.
Scott: This is a pattern you see in a lot of computer cables.
Scott: If you build computers, you'll notice they had ATX power connectors, and then they did ATX+4, which is they had the ATX power connector and then a little four extra thingies hanging off the edge of it to make it bigger when they needed more power.
Rym: Whenever you get a power supply, and then depending on your motherboard and processor, you would break off some of the pins on the end of the power to plug it in.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah, so it's like that.
Rym: So USB 3.0 and 2.0 are, well, 3.0 is backward compatible to 2.0, so you can plug a 3.0 device into a 2.0 computer just fine.
Scott: And it'll just work slowly and shiddily.
Rym: But you have to know that you can just plug it into the bottom half or the left half of that jank-ass looking plug.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: The moral of all this, because I could go on, is that the only parts we talked about were the parts that are relevant in any amount of expert use of computers.
Rym: So you don't need to know the depth.
Rym: You don't need to know the actual signaling unless you're working with USB devices on the hardware level.
Rym: You don't need to know the exact voltages and amperages and powers available and latency.
Scott: Because you can look that shit up on Google if you need to know.
Rym: Unless you're the kind of person who does audio, for example.
Rym: You really need to know about how USB works if you want to use a USB-driven audio device and make sure it isn't a cheap-ass USB 2.0 audio device.
Rym: But the complexity behind USB is something that seems so simple, so straightforward, so ubiquitous that you don't even think about it.
Scott: The only reason we think about it is because I was there in those days without USB, so I appreciate the things it does.
Scott: These people who just always had USB don't appreciate, like, you used to not be able to just plug shit into the computer while it's on.
Rym: Yeah, read this Wikipedia page.
Rym: It is huge.
Rym: They'll show you the full depth of all this.
Scott: Every frickin' device used to have a different kind of plug.
Rym: Every aspect of computing is that deep, even the things that seem very simple.
Rym: But simultaneously, just because it's deep doesn't mean you should ignore it.
Rym: You need to know at least the shallow waiting depth of every part of a computer, if you want to call yourself a computer person.
Rym: Because then, when something doesn't work with USB, or you run into an issue, you'll at least understand the basic nature of the issue.
Rym: If you plug in a weird Blackberry and it won't charge, you'll at least understand the kinds of things that might be causing that.
Rym: So you'll know maybe how to fix it.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Yeah, or you'll at least know if you actually have USB 3.0 or not.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Scott: She came into the shop and said, "I want to know what the problem
Scott: is.".
Scott: I said, "You don't want to know what the problem
Scott: And she said, "I want to know what the problem is so I can get the problem
Scott: fixed.".
Scott: I said, "You don't want to know what the solution to the problem is and you don't want to know what your problem
Scott: is.".
Scott: She says, "How do you know that I'm not going to like
Scott: it?".
Scott: I said, "I know you're not going to like
Scott: it.".
Scott: So she said, "Just tell me what it is and I'll tell you if I like
Scott: And I said, "Maybe.
Scott: Maybe I'll tell
Scott: you.".
Scott: She said, "Why won't you tell
Scott: me?".
Scott: I said, "The problem's your
Scott: ass.".
Scott: She said,
Scott: "What?".
Scott: I said, "The problem's your
Scott: ass.".
Scott: She said,
Scott: "What?".
Scott: I said, "The problem's your fucking ass.
Scott: Your ass is all fucked up and you got problems with your
Scott: ass.".
Scott: She said, "Why are you saying this to
Scott: me?".
Scott: And I said, "It's your fucking problem.
Scott: You're the one with the fucked up...".