Rym: It's Tuesday September 30th 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: flouche It's and Dante.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I Don't think you guys understand how excited we are about the term flouche.
Scott: Yes, only a panda would know There are listeners are not pandas yet.
Rym: Yep So, yeah, we played pan Dante and it was pretty much the best it was.
Scott: so flouche Let's wait until the main bit to actually talk about the main bit one of the main bit to talk about the flouche.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Rym: So, uh in the news, you know, you're jumping straight to news there.
Rym: What do you got?
Rym: some other bid you want to talk about?
Rym: No, no nothing at all.
Rym: No.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Oh, though our live stream has already gone to bad status.
Scott: That's not my fault.
Scott: You suck at technology.
Rym: Actually, it looks like the Elgato software is fucking something up.
Scott: I've been using x-split which it costs money, but whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I like the Elgato hardware But the software is just bought and it just doesn't work that way.
Scott: only thing the Elgato software does that is good.
Scott: That other software does not do is auto ducking.
Scott: Nothing else does the auto ducking.
Rym: Yeah, I can do the auto ducking here with the onyx and everything.
Scott: Well, yeah and your heart but most people do not have some sort of auto ducking hardware.
Scott: Yeah, the Elgato doing it is you know, the Elgato software doing it is great.
Scott: Normally for other stuff you need like OBS there was like a weird shady plug-in that caused money.
Rym: though the Elgato You know, I guess it's relevant talking about game streaming.
Rym: the trouble with the Elgato hardware too Is that it'll usually between it and its software have a semi non-deterministic or broken delay?
Rym: Between your voice in the game.
Scott: You have to push the buttons in the right order.
Scott: They might have fixed that bug.
Rym: I don't think they did because I was testing and I still saw a lot of weird issues.
Scott: Anyway, let's now talk about news.
Scott: The biggest news in gaming yup on October 3rd, and right now we're recording this.
Scott: my calendar says September 30th.
Scott: for you It's probably October 1st.
Scott: They're going to release for the 3ds Super Smash Bros The most important game in all of video gaming a new release.
Scott: Hopefully not garbage For the first time ever on a portable system.
Scott: Not bad.
Scott: Oh my god This shit is going Mario.
Scott: It's weird because this basically destroys the competition Completely, but what is the competition Mario Kart?
Scott: It's like they're killing them.
Scott: every other multiplayer game that they make is now worthless Because the only game anyone is gonna play when there is more than one person with a 3ds is Smash Bros.
Rym: What about what about the new Tetris?
Scott: I mean, I'll play that but I mean it's gonna be if there's a free demo of Smash Bros In the in the e-shop so you can go play that now It's pretty much Smash Bros.
Scott: The only problem I have with it is that the controls.
Scott: they're trying to mimic the GameCube controls and in the demo You can't go to the settings and change them because just a demo.
Scott: so jump is why and right because they're Mike.
Scott: They're mimicking the GameCube which but on a 3ds that's backwards.
Scott: I don't want to jump with the button That's at the top.
Scott: I want to attack at that button and jump with B and then right.
Scott: so That's annoying at least our and I'll do the right thing.
Scott: Yeah, so we'll have to see what we do there because the game It's gonna take over the world pretty much in terms of handheld gaming.
Scott: and then when the Wii U one comes out I think only like serious people who are like either people have we use are gonna get it obviously But people are serious about competing if it proves competitively viable.
Scott: unlike the previous Smash Brothers they will get the Wii U one for their tournaments and such but The 3ds one I think is really gonna be the one that takes the cake.
Rym: well because the Wii U is up and also ran At this point.
Scott: in other news on the iPad you can now get the free-to-play Pokemon trading card game.
Scott: it was available on a way.
Scott: It still is available on a web version But now on the iPad a Nintendo game.
Rym: Oh Shit, so we'll see.
Rym: I mean we're not gonna review it from the demo.
Rym: We're gonna wait for the real game to come out.
Scott: I purred on Amazon.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just waiting for it to arrive and then we'll play.
Rym: I Think at least all my original concerns.
Rym: I was worried because of what they did to Mario Tennis that they were gonna do the same thing to smash.
Rym: But I think they at least Mario Tennis like they're making.
Scott: it does seem like they're putting in some effort to appeal to the competitive Gaming scene, but the problem is is I'm not good enough at smash to be able to tell on my own Whether this smash is competitively viable because my fingers are not fast, and I don't know how to wave - or anything like that.
Scott: so We need to consult an expert on these matters.
Rym: Yeah, well the other trouble is just that you know they ruined Mario - Mario Tennis is no longer a skill game It's just Simon says which Mario Tennis the newest Mario Tennis on the 3ds.
Rym: That's true and Mario Kart was pretty good.
Rym: So I feel like there's a lot of inconsistency.
Rym: like they they've decided They see certain games as being competitive, and I feel like if you're not one of those games fuck you Mmm.
Rym: They're going cuz you know that old thing about how Team Fortress 2 was way more popular among the players When they made it more random without telling them what they did.
Rym: so I wonder if Nintendo is going down the road of making games fun quote-unquote fun for players on average Irrespective of other concerns like tests of skill.
Scott: That's sort of the perfect storm of that because in terms of fun It's like default mode is items on but they let you turn items off.
Rym: That's it the fact that they let you turn the items off?
Rym: all their games have not let you do that as much so by Default?
Scott: it's crazy fun for everyone, but the hardcore people It's crazy fun for everyone, but the hardcore people can then make it hardcore, so it's fun for them as well.
Scott: So it's like imagine if an FPS didn't have invert y-axis.
Scott: Well everyone could play except Rym and Scott Johnson Mmm.
Scott: My muscle memories to the point to where there's no backing away from that, but then I imagine if a Spaceship free space shooting game like x-wing released today did not have invert y-axis.
Rym: What if a game like that just didn't support joysticks?
Scott: And wouldn't exist?
Rym: yeah, well joysticks.
Rym: Don't exist, but that says a whole separate show.
Rym: We should.
Scott: I would buy a copy to set on fire, but that would mean I have to buy a cop.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: So uh in other news five nights at Freddy's I'm amazed so my I'm surprised.
Scott: so my co-workers started talking about wait wait independently of me this I didn't even know it existed.
Scott: They started talking about it in relation to something and then a couple days later Rym talked about it.
Scott: And I'm like whoa.
Rym: this is why I'm amazed because at the same time like when I was talking to you about it you did not know much about it and I only knew from that conversation with my co-workers and the steam store page.
Rym: my co-workers never heard of it But I ran afoul of it in internet circles from day one Mm-hmm like I knew about this game when it was.
Scott: pretty much you knew about it early on when it was way early.
Rym: Okay, so and I'm not gonna get into the story of how it was made or anything We'll do a full show on it at some point if she's got a kickstarter or something.
Rym: so the game itself is Is Legitimately terrifying.
Scott: Not in not a baby.
Rym: No no not in the sense of like Yamashibai like.
Rym: oh my god It's scary.
Scott: I'm scared by anything since I was like two.
Rym: so can a jump scare get you?
Scott: It's not scary.
Scott: That's a surprise.
Scott: Yeah, Scott.
Rym: Yeah, there's the thing there's.
Rym: there's a gradient between surprise and scared.
Rym: I did not say the game scared me.
Rym: I said it terrified me.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Here's what happened.
Scott: I think terrified is just extreme for is the same thing is scared only to a greater degree?
Rym: No, I would say that terrified is extreme fearful surprise Yeah, you.
Rym: so here's the thing.
Rym: the game does not pretend that it's not getting you with jump scares.
Rym: In fact in the very beginning when you started it says warning.
Rym: This game is basically just jump scares.
Rym: great so, you know who you know and It uses jump scares Effectively to punish you for failing.
Rym: so as a result you're playing the game and Then my experience.
Rym: I start playing the game and I kind of know what the deal is and I play.
Rym: through night one It was pretty good.
Rym: But in night two when shit got real and the game was even like yo dog shits real now It tells you shit's about to go.
Rym: basically my heart rate was going up because the game is just extremely playing.
Scott: at a biometric sensor I could feel it.
Rym: My heart was pounding because the game is very stressful to play.
Rym: You have to be paying attention to all these things constantly.
Scott: You haven't even told people what the game is.
Rym: yeah, so because I'm saying this is why the game got me.
Rym: and then the moment happened where the game you're like I lost and The jump scare thing was about to happen and I knew a jump scare was coming.
Rym: So what I did is I leaned back from my monitor Folded my arms and I kind of looked away just like waiting for it to happen.
Rym: Like you do if you run you look at one of those like jump scare kind of memes.
Rym: So I'm just waiting for it to happen and then I'm gonna restart the game and it just doesn't happen.
Rym: it doesn't happen and it doesn't happen and I Literally Lee like I lean in a little bit and then it happens and I take the mouse and I move it to see if like The game crashed.
Scott: and then it happened.
Scott: Have you moved the mouse?
Scott: He wasn't gonna do it if you weren't there, but then I thought back.
Rym: the game warned me that moving the mouse would do it.
Scott: Oh did it?
Rym: so so here's the deal.
Rym: The game is very simple.
Rym: You are working minimum wage the night shift at Freddy Fazbear's Pizza restaurant.
Scott: in other words, Chuck E. Cheese Chuck E.
Rym: Cheese's Freddy Fazbear and there's some other.
Scott: there's four animatronic suits in other words the rock of fire explosion.
Rym: So your job is to sit there for midnight until 6 a.m.
Rym: And be the night watchman.
Scott: you can't okay.
Scott: So Chuck E. Cheese's don't have night watchman first of all.
Rym: Yeah, so this automated security systems if anything Yeah, so this one has.
Scott: they also I don't think have rock of fire explosions at Chuck E. Cheese.
Scott: They just have arcade games and cranes and shit.
Rym: So you're really gonna try to make this a realistic game here.
Rym: You're gonna really pick it apart on that level.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So here's what.
Rym: here's the deal.
Rym: You're sitting there in the room.
Rym: You cannot leave the room.
Rym: The only controls you have is you can move the mouse to look left or right.
Rym: There's open doors to the left and to the right.
Scott: Why are there two doors?
Scott: That's just like the security.
Scott: main security room is a weird-ass building.
Scott: who made this thing?
Rym: the labs actually really straightforward.
Rym: You're sitting in a room.
Rym: There's two hallways that go out from either side of you into like different areas of the complex.
Scott: Chuck E. Cheese has hallways.
Scott: It's a big open building with like a kitchen for the pizza.
Rym: Yeah Like the back hallways like where they store the animatronic suits that they're working on and like the arcade games.
Rym: They need issues.
Scott: They don't have those things.
Scott: They send them away in a truck and the kitchen and all that stuff.
Rym: Plus you're talking about Chuck E. Cheese's.
Rym: This is Freddy Fazbear's.
Scott: Okay, totally different place.
Scott: This is a fancy place.
Rym: Well, it's coming down on rough times Because if you're playing the game you'll do like you see a newspaper like pinned up to the wall and if you read it Like a kid got bit by one of the animatronics or something like that.
Scott: They're on a stage.
Scott: No one goes near them.
Rym: Yeah, apparently kid went and fucked with one of them.
Scott: Well, then he gets what he deserves.
Scott: They get electrocuted by that shit.
Rym: Yeah, apparently he made it a surprising amount of time without his frontal lobe after the bite of 87 Great.
Rym: So the game the conceit of the game for getting your bullshit is that you sit in this room?
Rym: You can't leave.
Rym: The only controls you have are look right look left.
Scott: Why can't you leave you tied down?
Rym: Oh, yeah, like there's no way out.
Rym: You're stuck in the room.
Rym: Who knows?
Rym: Why?
Scott: Okay, so you did so.
Rym: it's one of those disempowering things.
Rym: you can move the mouse down and that
Scott: look at your junk pulls
Rym: up a view a display in front of your face like physically like it pulls up in front of you and then you can see all the Security cameras and you click on the map on all the cameras and you see what that camera sees.
Rym: You can't control the camera.
Rym: camera like moves back and forth does its own thing in that room But you can look at that camera.
Rym: You can look at anything cameras.
Rym: if you move the mouse back up the console goes back down.
Rym: You're looking at the room again.
Rym: You can shut the door to the left or right and you can turn on the light in the hallway right there to the left or to the right.
Rym: as Long as you are using the camera have a light on or have a door closed your power consumption increases.
Rym: Okay, this place has limited power.
Rym: They're trying to save budget and the doors are open by default.
Rym: It takes power to hold them closed.
Scott: What is what kind of shitty door?
Scott: Just the wooden doors, right?
Rym: No, they're steel security doors.
Scott: What the fuck are the Steel's electronic?
Rym: Yeah So Scott if you play this game the the vibe is that what kind of fucked up join is this?
Scott: Yeah What kind of?
Rym: So you're in this room with steel security doors and they default open.
Rym: So if the power runs out all the lights go out and the doors open.
Scott: Doors default to closed.
Rym: No, so imagine imagine a safety like a fire code thing where.
Scott: imagine a grocery store with power doors.
Scott: They closed if the power stop.
Rym: So imagine a grocery store where the doors if they're closed and the power goes out They default to closed and you can't get out because there's still security doors.
Rym: Everyone strapped inside.
Scott: you just move them with their hands because they have manual controls because their doors.
Scott: you can open them with their hands.
Rym: Yeah, this place has a steel security doors that nothing can break.
Rym: through these things.
Scott: You can pull them open with their hands.
Scott: No, they're way.
Scott: they weigh like a ton.
Scott: They're they have a knob.
Rym: No, there's.
Rym: no.
Rym: now these are the kinds of doors like on the outside of a blast furnace.
Rym: They're like the doors you would put on the outside of a light saber to cut through.
Scott: Yeah, nuclear bunker door and a chuggy cheese.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So you're sitting there and you get a phone call like a voicemail from the guy who did your job like the previous week Like hey, dude, here's how to do the job.
Rym: Keep an eye on him.
Scott: So he still lived.
Rym: and what he warns you is that these animatronic suits they're AI controlled.
Rym: so during the day like they do their thing on their own they're programmed and At night, they like to roam around.
Rym: because if you don't let him move around at night their servers lock up or whatever.
Rym: he doesn't know or care.
Rym: that's just how it is.
Rym: and Part of the AI is that if they see an exoskeleton that's not inside of the animatronic suit That's against the rules.
Rym: So they will put it in a suit.
Rym: They'll go they'll take it and they'll shove it into a suit.
Rym: Okay They see a human being after hours.
Rym: They think it's an exoskeleton they shove it into a suit and because that suits full of a bunch of metal and electronics That's pretty much guaranteed to horribly kill you.
Scott: Okay, so if they see how strong are they I could I mean if I lay are huge and powerful But if I'm standing there if I meet the real rock of fire explosion, I can just kick one of those fuckers over and smash.
Scott: It's not that durable.
Rym: Uh, yeah, these things can overpower a human being so they're basically the Terminator.
Scott: Yes So if why is the Terminator?
Scott: we're getting a Chuck E. Cheese.
Rym: Yeah, so, you know on the fourth night You should be going to save John kind on the third or fourth night.
Rym: The guy's voicemail is basically like yes So and the guy's like I think this place kind of fucked up Vietnam.
Rym: I feel like you should go check on like what's in those other suits in the supply room.
Scott: And the third night after the first night, why don't you quit?
Rym: cuz you need this money.
Rym: I can get money elsewhere Maybe not because your name is Mike Schmidt and you probably need money the best.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I'll do.
Scott: I'll just rob this fucking place and leave if you win the game.
Scott: Possible, you know what it gives you.
Rym: It just shows you you made a hundred and twenty dollars by surviving this bullshit.
Scott: Oh, you beat it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I didn't beat it.
Rym: I I went looked up a spoiler.
Rym: so the way.
Rym: so you're sitting there in the game and You get these warnings and then you look at the stage.
Rym: there's three animatronic suits and you look at pirate Cove.
Rym: There's a fourth suit.
Rym: You can't see this behind a curtain and that's the whole game.
Rym: They roam around.
Rym: They you got to keep an eye on them.
Rym: They all follow different rules and Shit's kind of terrifying.
Rym: I don't want to spoil stuff.
Rym: I feel like you guys should play it.
Rym: cuz it's such a short game.
Rym: I'll give you two example of some shit that went down.
Rym: So I look at the stage.
Rym: all three suits are there.
Scott: Tell you about my character.
Rym: and then I look at pirate Cove.
Rym: the the curtains closed and then I see some sort of hallucination.
Rym: That happens occasionally.
Rym: and then I look at the pirate Cove and I look at the stage again and Bonnie the bunnies gone.
Scott: I just go chill out in the pirate Cove.
Rym: You can't move.
Rym: I'll see if you go there it'll see you and it'll kill you.
Rym: So I look at the stage and Bonnie's gone body the bunnies gone.
Rym: So I started looking around.
Rym: I find her on the camera and she's like in the hallway kind of near me.
Rym: So it turns out that the cameras actually have a blind spot as the guy warns you on the phone Right next to your doors.
Rym: So Eventually, I can't find Bonnie the bunny like.
Rym: look at all the cameras.
Rym: I just can't fucking find her.
Rym: then I just pull out of that pull out of the camera and I click on the light and she is right fucking outside the door looking inside and I slammed the door shut.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: She doesn't kill me.
Rym: Then I pull the camera up to look for Chica the chicken cuz he like is wandering around somewhere.
Rym: I couldn't find him I don't see him.
Rym: and then suddenly the fun that the chicken pulls the camera down and kills me out of Nowhere and it scared the ever-living fuck out of me.
Scott: Okay, so why do you use the cameras at all?
Scott: Why don't you just only use the lights and close the doors when necessary?
Rym: Ah, so here here's the spoiler.
Rym: So the the suit that's hanging out in Pirate Cove who Foxy the pirate is pretty cool guy he if you don't look at him enough or if you look at him too much because you're paranoid.
Rym: he slowly activates and Eventually, like if you look in the room and he's not there anymore like he'll open the curtain He's kind of looking at you.
Rym: then he's like hanging out in front of the curtain like in front of the auto-order side.
Rym: One time I looked in there.
Rym: he's gone just gone.
Rym: I'm like, oh fuck.
Rym: and then I look at the hallway and he's literally sprinting down the hallway toward my door Mm-hmm, and he'll just come and kill you.
Rym: Okay, the game punishes players If they fail with jump scares and the jump scares are artfully designed Such that even if you were an intelligent human being who thinks I won't be gotten by the jump scare It'll jump scare you anyway.
Scott: the game anyone can beat jumps.
Rym: the game is Clever in ways that I don't want to reveal because I feel like you should explore and experience these things yourself.
Rym: it Legitimately raised my heart rate.
Rym: it gave me an adrenaline rush like a for-real one the same feeling you get when a car almost hit you while you're biking and it's just generally extremely stressful and frustrating to play in a really fun way.
Rym: I Highly recommend you try five nights at Freddy's.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, Scott hates games like this interrupted me trying to explain it.
Rym: But obviously guys this game is great and you should play it.
Rym: I Don't know why you're so a on it.
Rym: I mean, why would you be at the game use it?
Rym: It's it does horror and How is it not horror?
Rym: What?
Rym: how could you make a horror game then?
Scott: An intelligent person can't be scared Uh-huh.
Rym: So there's no such thing as horror ever.
Rym: There's no horror fiction.
Rym: There's no horror movies.
Scott: Not for me.
Rym: So there's no such thing as a genre of horror.
Scott: back when I was a kid I can watch alien and I was scared.
Scott: Scott horror doesn't mean it scares you But now I can watch anything and be not scared.
Rym: That doesn't make it not horror.
Scott: It makes it not hard.
Rym: Why horror doesn't necessarily mean scare?
Scott: I do know one thing though Joe out and go boo is not scary.
Rym: horrors can be existential crisis.
Rym: also I think you misunderstand the definitions of horror and macabre and scare and all those different words.
Rym: I think you use a very reductionist definition system I think because you have no joy from games and no joy from jump-scare.
Scott: I think that you are a baby.
Rym: Yeah I'll put this so clever thing.
Rym: Freddy Fazbear fucking.
Rym: he got into the room and I had both doors shut.
Rym: So I gotta figure out how that works.
Scott: But uh, he was already in the room.
Rym: as he comes to kill you You'll notice that on his face are two pretty clear handprints Obviously from someone else he killed trying to resist him.
Rym: There's a lot of subtle things like that.
Rym: So anyway things of the day because Scott has no joy from games.
Scott: We should watch my thing today.
Rym: No, I did not.
Rym: I was busy setting up the stream.
Rym: that appears to be failing.
Scott: So my thing of the day this dude His only flaw in his entire life was being a Phoenix Coyotes fan.
Scott: If you did not know hockey is soon preseason.
Scott: hockey is now it is hockey time.
Scott: Yeah, we did pretty good at hockey last year.
Scott: So hockey this year of course is even more exciting than usual which is the most exciting sport can possibly be.
Scott: Yeah, so This guy this Phoenix Coyotes fan.
Scott: He set up a thing in his house.
Scott: That is the glory of glories.
Scott: He took two Lights the kind of light that caught a detective will put on top of his car.
Scott: Alright, he put him side by side.
Scott: Oh, oh, so if there's a goal of his television, he also connected to this system his stereo.
Scott: if There is a goal.
Scott: He pushes a button on the remote and there are four different song selections to play in the event of goal.
Scott: It is glorious.
Scott: It is majestic.
Scott: I need to set this up in everyone's house that in case I watch hockey at their house I can press the button.
Scott: the only thing I can play the same music They play at Madison Square Garden.
Scott: when there's a goal you need a crowd.
Rym: at the authentic home Arena experience you need a crowd that or a crowd simulator in your house.
Scott: Is there a market for this simulate being at the arena in your house?
Scott: Once we have like oculus rift It's it's like you're at the arena even though you're at your house.
Scott: Everyone everyone is sitting at center ice everybody for me.
Rym: There is definitely definitely a market for this.
Scott: I would buy if I could watch live sports as if I'm in the arena and it feels like I'm in the arena and looks Like I'm in the arena.
Scott: I would buy an oculus drift for that.
Scott: get on it.
Scott: I know listeners work there.
Scott: I don't think you listen though But there are people I know who work there and I'm gonna tell them.
Rym: The thing is you need you need.
Rym: the crowd simulator would have to simulate the physical feeling of a human being Jumping up next to you and elbow you in the face as he yells and screams at the top of his lungs getting beer spilled On you.
Scott: Yeah, you need a delivery company to bring the proper food The smells the cold.
Scott: you got to get the temperature of the ice, you know, you could be cold put on a coat.
Scott: Where your Jersey?
Scott: Yeah You know the whole thing.
Rym: so my thinking today this was this is one of those things It was funnier than it had any right to be.
Rym: it's called super bad Mario.
Rym: just a video.
Rym: someone made of bunch of people having a fail video moment and They have added Mario such that Mario is the cause of their fail.
Rym: That sounds like a really simple and dumb idea.
Rym: Shits hilarious.
Rym: It's way funnier than it should be.
Scott: It's alright.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Scott: This feels like old-school internet like five ten years ago.
Rym: Yeah, like blumpy org kind of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I'm into this.
Rym: It's doing them at a moment.
Rym: The book club book is a canticle for Liebowitz.
Rym: I guess Scott finished it.
Scott: I'm very close to finishing it now that what very close.
Scott: I'll finish it Tonight or tomorrow night.
Rym: Did you get to the Green Star part?
Scott: No, I'm at the part where they're about to get in a spaceship to leave because it's not good.
Rym: who's getting on a spaceship?
Rym: Catholics, yeah That pretty much sums up a canticle for Liebowitz.
Rym: I feel like I could review each of the three sections complete like I have a completely different.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Yes That's how it's gonna go down.
Scott: So let's get to the main bit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, is there any other meta moments?
Rym: Yes, so we're live streaming this but it appears to have failed on multiple fronts.
Scott: bad technology.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll see.
Rym: I'm giving YouTube some or Google some feedback.
Scott: We're actually working with YouTube on some streaming stuff.
Scott: Basically, we're giving them feedback on the streaming stuff.
Scott: Yeah, so YouTube streaming.
Scott: look out on our both of our channels for streaming YouTube type stuff.
Scott: Yeah Really, you know actually started another channel separate from my main channel for that because like we've used which reviews YouTube and YouTube is just From a streamers point of view technology wise.
Scott: YouTube is just better.
Scott: the major flaws the audience that twitch brings.
Scott: like I can start a gaming a game on twitch and people will Find me and start watching who don't even know me.
Scott: Yeah, not so much on YouTube.
Rym: So, yeah, the only other things are packs.
Rym: Australia is coming up.
Rym: I'm doing not one but two lectures all by yourself.
Rym: on Saturday I am performing Losing and on Sunday winning winning.
Rym: It's a rehash of how to win at games, but a little more Rym style and then not too far away as PAX South Where we will be there in attendance.
Scott: I should buy flights to PAX South.
Rym: I am now attending five fucking packs as a year.
Scott: So watch out pegs dev sort account.
Rym: Oh pegs dev is definitely Getting better every time I go and is definitely one of my must-go-to conventions at this point.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So PAX Prime.
Rym: we Got together a posse Some new people as usual classic packs in packs.
Rym: Uh prime's tabletop was a little sub optimal due to the fact that the library was in the Convention Center And all the actual gaming space was in a faraway.
Scott: we're still gaming tables in the Convention Center as usual, but not many mad crowded full hard to get into and Also, basically it ended up it was a pain in the ass to use the game library.
Rym: So we never checked anything out of the game library.
Rym: So we were dependent solely on games that we collectively brought.
Rym: Our friends brought a game called Pandante.
Scott: Pandante is made by Serlin games who you may know from such other games as Yomi and puzzle strike.
Scott: Serlin is the dude who sort of thinks the same things that we do is all about winning and playing a win and stuff like that and he's a dude who is like big in the fighting game community, but Wasn't as good at moving his hands really fast.
Scott: He's much better at it than we are but not you know Not good enough to be pro.
Scott: That's why he made games like Yomi and puzzle strike which are like these skill-winning type games that lets you Experience that high-level interplay without needing to master basic low-level skills along the way.
Scott: So the new game from Serlin games relatively new at least is Pandante.
Rym: This is the kind of game that and when we describe it to you, you'll feel this It's the kind of game that people like us usually will ignore or shut up.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So it's Texas holding poker With two key differences, right?
Scott: There are other differences, but there are two key differences difference number one pandas.
Scott: Difference number two.
Rym: It's a different deck of cards not usual deck of cards Yep, and and it's interesting because what this game does at its core is it takes say Texas?
Rym: Hold them which you need to be good at poker to enjoy, Texas Hold them pretty much or have so much money.
Scott: You don't care that you lose.
Rym: Well, you don't have to play for money.
Rym: I mean we didn't play this for money.
Scott: Wow, Texas hold them without money is good.
Rym: Well, then you're just playing for points.
Scott: but that's the thing.
Rym: the if you play Texas hold them.
Rym: the Differentiator of skill between like the person who's got like nine points of skill the person who has eight point eight points Only comes out over a long period of play.
Rym: pandante Distills that so that it's a relatively short game.
Rym: It plays more like a German board game or like the kind of table of games we like and you get the brain Feel and the excitement of the important rounds of Texas.
Rym: hold them without having to play 100 rounds of Texas hold them and without having for most of them Everyone just folds right away exactly and they're for almost no money.
Scott: And then the big one happens exactly Dante Every round is the big round.
Rym: So this game much like I said for that my thing of the day video.
Rym: It's a game that has is way more fun than has a right to be and we've resisted.
Rym: when our friends are like Hey, let's play this game We were like we'll play it once So we can review it and then we finish and then we all relate it the most.
Rym: so we should we play it again?
Rym: Should we play it again?
Rym: Should we play it again one night?
Rym: We played it all night until they kicked us out.
Scott: It was just really.
Scott: the other thing is just so easy to play compared to other games that had much more setup.
Scott: You know all this is just take a deck of cards shuffle them give everyone some chips and plates.
Scott: You know, it's more set up than say sushi go.
Scott: Yeah, but it's a lot less set up even than seven wonders.
Scott: We got to sort all the cards out and everything.
Rym: So the subtle key difference is to explain the game in detail.
Rym: It's pretty simple.
Rym: you play basically, Texas hold him.
Rym: But when you buy into a hand and you bid on a hand, you're not just bidding like I have the best hand.
Rym: You're not putting money in saying I got the best hand or fold.
Rym: You're betting on what hand you will have by the end right.
Scott: you're betting on a specific hand.
Scott: There are ten hands You can possibly have.
Scott: you put a chip onto one of them and you can't bet some crazy different amounts either.
Scott: You can't be like all-in on pair.
Scott: It's you bet a fixed amount or you quit, right?
Scott: So it's either bet five on one of the ten hands or fold.
Scott: Those are your two options.
Scott: So I'll bet five on three of a kind.
Scott: I have a three of a kind.
Scott: is what you're saying?
Rym: Yep, or I will.
Rym: I will have three of a kind.
Scott: I will eventually have three of a kind.
Scott: not I will have at least three of a kind.
Scott: not I will have.
Scott: You know something, you know better than three.
Scott: I will have exactly three of a kind.
Scott: if you have four of a kind and you bet on three of a kind Well, I guess that includes three of a kind.
Scott: but you don't get your credit for your four of a kind.
Scott: You only get the credit for what you bet on.
Rym: So the game works pretty much like Texas Hold'em in that regard though because you go down the river Pulling up cards along the way, but every time a new card comes out you have to bet you have to fold or Bet at or better than what you already bet on.
Scott: so you might have like you might be going for I don't know an inside straight right and you think that's.
Rym: that's a great idea.
Scott: You might be getting it.
Scott: You never know.
Scott: You're not getting you're only gonna spend.
Scott: you think I can spend ten bucks to see.
Scott: maybe a miracle will happen.
Scott: So you bet on straight and then you bet on straight again and Then you bet and meanwhile you just got like a three of a kind.
Scott: but Sorry, bro.
Rym: You can't go down.
Scott: You know, you can't go down to three of a kind.
Scott: So even though you have it, it's basically meaningless.
Rym: So there's another mechanic here much like how Texas Hold'em has all of its terminology.
Rym: It's poker terminology.
Rym: Pandante has panda equivalents of that.
Rym: So you buy breakfast you buy you take breakfast if you want then you have snacks and then you do like the paws and the Tail and all these little things.
Rym: so it has this fun little like interplay of using the words in the nomenclature of the game To the point that it started messing up my poker Brain.
Scott: now the snacks are actually a big component in the game right.
Scott: the way the snacks work is If you are the highest bidder in terms like I'm betting on straight blood Flush I got a flush.
Scott: That's not as good as a straight flush.
Scott: I got a flush good.
Scott: If you are the highest better at any given snack time you get free snacks Which means from your you know hidden cards.
Scott: you can throw some out and you draw a card and then?
Rym: You may or may not keep that card throwing away another card.
Rym: So you still have two cards, but you can swallow in and out by going big and betting big.
Scott: You actually have a chance to make that big a reality.
Scott: with all the snacks.
Scott: You can still get snacks if you are not the highest better.
Scott: But you have to pay for those snacks and the further away you are from the top the more you have to pay if you're Betting on pair and someone else is betting on straight flush.
Scott: You have to pay like 20 bucks To have a chance at snacks, so there's already a good.
Rym: You know because what's the fun part of Texas holding?
Rym: What's the fun part of poker?
Scott: the big bluffing and being and everyone falls for it?
Scott: And you make mad money when you had nothing.
Rym: this game distills poker into the bluffing and the odds and nothing else and it does it quickly.
Rym: so I might I Might bet a flouche even though I could not possibly have a flouche And I intend to fold just to make everybody's snacks more expensive.
Scott: and because I can see even though I can't possibly have a flouche.
Scott: Maybe the snacks will make a flouche happen.
Scott: Yeah, so And I'll get free snacks.
Rym: the game obviously because the deck is not a normal poker deck.
Rym: the Hands you can get our difference right.
Scott: so there are six suits with ten cards pursued.
Scott: number one Joker one through ten.
Scott: When do you guys examine it?
Scott: Oh?
Scott: No is there a ten?
Scott: Oh is it two through ten?
Rym: I think it's one through ten.
Scott: that would make eleven.
Scott: Yeah, right What are you nine?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I think it's two through ten.
Scott: I don't remember anyway.
Scott: Also the six colors, and then there's one wild card.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: It's a wild card.
Scott: Yeah watch out It's prismatic.
Rym: It's got all the colors, and there's some fun rules around that, but there's only one wild card.
Rym: Yep, and there's some special rules around the wild card.
Rym: So you play the game you bet everybody bets you buy snacks if you want and then another card comes out in the in the community cards and then you bet snacks and you do this three times and Then the show everybody gets to use a power.
Scott: So this is actually another bluffing aspect right based on the colors of the cards.
Scott: in your hand There are six powers.
Scott: six colors six powers You can it goes around and each person gets to claim zero one or two powers.
Scott: Right and try to use those powers.
Scott: so I can be like I'm gonna do the red power twice.
Scott: The red power is put five bucks in or if everyone puts five bucks in or folds.
Scott: So doing that twice means everyone in the whole game has to put in ten bucks or fold except me because I'm using the power Right.
Scott: oh No, I think I have to do it too right.
Rym: What?
Rym: no no you don't remember this game at all.
Scott: I only played it effects.
Scott: It was already a month ago.
Rym: So bravery every other player must put in five gold right fold.
Rym: so you evilness draw a card then discard a card.
Rym: But you have to reveal a card that you kept.
Rym: Orange deal a sixth community car.
Scott: oh shit everybody gets that.
Scott: it happens a lot of blue Privately.
Rym: see a random card from a highest hand.
Rym: so someone who's beating you as a highest hand you can see a card in their hand.
Rym: Black the fun one greed steal five dollars from the lowest hand.
Rym: unless they reveal a blue card from their hand.
Scott: Hopelessness purple you get to fold because normally you can't fold at that point you're already in too deep.
Scott: But that's like last-minute folding so you can pull some shenanigans and then fold if they don't work.
Rym: And there's a clever mechanic where if you use a power you can declare up to two powers because you can have two cards.
Rym: You know your car.
Rym: you have two cards in your hole.
Rym: Anyone can challenge you and there's a challenge mechanic like you.
Scott: you're not showing your two hidden cards, and you use these powers.
Scott: I'm like I'm using two red powers red power twice.
Scott: Yeah, people can either say okay.
Scott: We'll do the red power twice or They can say challenge you you don't have two red cards.
Scott: the cards are designed in such a way That you can reveal their color without revealing their number.
Rym: So I have to then either say yeah, you got me, and then I owe them some money.
Scott: Yeah, because they challenged me I was lying.
Rym: I give them money or I show them the colors and then they owe me money.
Scott: Yep, they challenged me, and they were wrong.
Scott: I did have two red cards so they got to give me one which can be great.
Rym: if say I'm Bluffing that I have a flouche and I show a card that corroborates my story that I have a flouche You
Scott: might really need say to use the orange power to have a chance at this hand winning but
Rym: using that don't have
Scott: any orange cards or
Rym: Using it implies that I don't have the hand and I'm hail marrying right
Scott: or you might have a really shitty hand and want to Say purple.
Scott: I'm gonna fold to just get escape, but you don't have a purple and someone calls you out on it.
Scott: That's the worst.
Scott: Or your hand is totally awesome And you want to kick some ass.
Scott: so you use red or black to take money from people But you don't have red or black and you get called if you have the crazy awesome, and sometimes you'll use orange or green Just to make everyone think that you're actually bluffing.
Scott: yeah, if you're using orange or green It seems like you're desperately trying to get a good hand.
Scott: people think you don't have the real hand But all you did was just draw a card and throw one away, and then you go down the challenges.
Rym: So after the powers after all that the cards are out there whoever has the highest hand Everyone has a chance to either challenge them right or say yeah, you win.
Scott: I bet on five of a kind and no one else bet on anything close to five of a kind.
Scott: I just win without revealing anything whatsoever unless you challenge me.
Rym: so Challenges in this stage are interesting because in on normal challenges with the powers if you are wrong you owe the other person some money.
Rym: It's not a big deal.
Rym: if you challenge someone's hand And they're winning and you're right you get a little bit of money And of course they don't win mm-hmm in the neck meeting.
Scott: that goes down to the next person.
Rym: if you challenge someone And you're wrong they actually have the hand.
Scott: I have five of a kind.
Scott: read him and weep you are fucked.
Rym: You owe them so much money.
Rym: It is Devastated.
Scott: you just lose the game.
Scott: basically yeah.
Rym: So if you are not challenged and you win and you were bluffing You can tell everyone yo dogs I was bluffing you're stupid.
Rym: And then you get to draw a panda Lord.
Scott: this panda Lords are so ridiculously Waggles.
Rym: all about waggles fuck everybody else.
Scott: Pretty much only took waggles because he was so much better than the other pen.
Rym: well I think we took waggles mostly because of the waggle action on the card.
Scott: It's also an excellent reason to take waggles.
Rym: But the panda Lord if you have him have one and you can just take one.
Rym: There's one of every color.
Rym: they just have weird powers like waggles.
Rym: power is the triple play quote.
Rym: during the ability phase You can play up to three different abilities that cannot be challenged.
Scott: So you could just be like red red red everyone put 15 in the middle or fold everyone right now And you lose waggles, but you know hey, that's ridiculously strong.
Scott: Yeah So if you basically bluff your way to victory on one hand you get a panda Lord which comes close to Ensuring victory on a future hand.
Scott: so when it does a huge incentive to win via bluffing So what look again the design of the game is?
Rym: Pushing you toward the fun parts of poker And it's kind of glossing over the really really tedious parts of poker.
Scott: But at the same so while it's basically pushes you huge incentives.
Scott: Just bluff your way to victory.
Scott: at the same time it ridiculously punishes anyone for Challenging if you're right, so it's like you have this built-in defense Making it sort of easier to actually bluff your way to victory because people are scared to challenge you if you actually have the hand Because they will just be fucked if you do have the hand.
Rym: now in my experience playing the game Nobody ever fucking has the hand except that one time The early games pretty much that we played.
Scott: of this everyone One person actually had the hand and someone challenged them.
Scott: that person was out.
Scott: the person who had the hand won the game the end.
Scott: Because they just got so much money from that it was over.
Scott: Yeah, not only did they get the money from winning the pot they got the money from the person who just got hosed.
Scott: I think what happened is they had so much money.
Scott: They couldn't be unseated.
Scott: They won a second hand.
Scott: then they had.
Scott: that was enough money to win the game.
Rym: But then I think pretty quickly what happened is our friends started getting competent at the game.
Rym: part of the problem was that it's not easy to calculate the odds or Viscerally feel the odds of the six color ten card deck.
Scott: yeah It was very hard to calculate the likelihood of like.
Scott: what are the odds?
Scott: he has a flouche pretty good actually.
Scott: There's like ten cards of that color right.
Scott: so the odds of those is he's got two of them.
Rym: So like a nice had like five snacks.
Scott: He's seen like seven cards this game and plus the ones in the table It's like they could easily be well houses right.
Rym: not that hard to get flushes slightly harder to get.
Rym: I don't know if it's because it's on the far right side or because we just really like the word flouche.
Scott: Only a panda would know what a flouche is.
Rym: yep, it says in the instruction manual The game's flavor text and just that.
Rym: the art and everything on the cards was well done to the point that We started using its terminology despite making fun of how dumb its terminology was.
Rym: when we learned the game Flouche became the breakaway word of PAX For the rest of the weekend.
Scott: Yeah fuck your official swear word flouche is the official word of PAX Prime.
Rym: I think the problem was we looked up flouche on Urban Dictionary and came up with something involving a female ejaculation whatever.
Rym: so a Few of us looked that up and laughed about it And then everyone else came back and then someone bet on a flouche who was not there when we had looked it up And that sealed the deal.
Scott: the other thing about this game is all the pandas on the cards have really great Expressions especially the number one.
Scott: where the pen is put in the red the pen is putting his hands in the air like what?
Scott: Raise the roof.
Rym: our convention was if you win you have to make the red one pose Unless you win with a panel or then you have to make the pose of that panel.
Scott: Oh, but basically we kept making the poses of all the pandas and saying flouche a lot.
Rym: Yeah This is a must-have in your game library.
Scott: If you're the kind of takes up somewhat little space and you probably already have poker chips of some kind.
Rym: if you're a gamer yeah, it's a deck of cards special deck of cards a couple of challenge cards and Little betting cards that remind you like what the order of this.
Scott: you don't even really need the betting cards You really just need the deck.
Rym: I think you need the betting cards.
Scott: So it'll tell you very helpful if people don't know how to play but once you're all good at the game You don't need that anymore.
Rym: I think you'll always need them.
Rym: So you will never forget the order of victory.
Scott: if you play the game enough, you will know the order of victory.
Rym: Yeah, just you're gonna remember that the straight is less than a full house less than a flouche.
Scott: Yes, because it's much easier to get a straight when there's six suits.
Rym: yep, but a rainbow straight versus four or five of a kind.
Scott: a rainbow straight is less than four of a kind and less than five and I see you can see that over my shoulder because I have the betting.
Scott: no because I remember that rainbow straight Is in the top left.
Rym: now flouche is in the bottom right and then just to the left of flouche should be Regular straight but seriously if you run board game nights if you were the guy who shows up at a con and has like hey I got a game we should play.
Rym: this is The.
Rym: this is like the perfect example of a social game.
Rym: That is good to get everybody warmed up and to get the kinds of people who don't want to learn a difficult game and balk At playing a game to start playing a game and get really invested in it.
Scott: I think this is also really good.
Scott: you find those people.
Scott: I know a lot of them who are?
Scott: They like to play poker right there in the Texas hold them whatever, but it's hard to get them to play real board games.
Scott: This could be the bridge game.
Scott: you can get them into sort of that like flouche culture While they're still playing a poker ish game that the like and you can go straight from flouche culture to brick for wood Culture.
Scott: yeah, you can and that's the bridge.
Scott: you can get them over the heap if they're unwilling to display.
Rym: So here's how Sirlin sells it himself.
Rym: He just gives you a set of bullet points.
Rym: No player elimination.
Scott: Well, I guess you're not permanently eliminated.
Rym: We'll get to that.
Rym: Yeah, no you don't have to fold all the time like you do in human poker.
Scott: It is panda poker though seriously as an aside, but you do fold a lot.
Rym: folding is if you Play poker with people and you are not a poker person.
Rym: My only advice to you is you need to fold about five times more often than you think you do.
Scott: last time I played poker for real monies in college I basically just folded whenever I didn't have a hand and didn't fold when I did have a hand and started raising the roof and I just had.
Scott: when I lost because I had no hand I lost almost nothing and then when I did have the hand someone usually stayed in and I had the hand so I made mad money and then I won.
Rym: quote.
Rym: It's actually fun to play for its own sake when no real money is on the line.
Rym: The pandas are laughing and joking the whole way through that is true but The game has to set it as its core rules and you can just play it and it's totally fun.
Rym: Just pick up game go nuts poker.
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: Then there's a section where Serlin's like so if you want to play it for real money if you're panda enough to play it for Real money.
Scott: Are you panda?
Rym: No, here are the four serious rules and all.
Scott: What's the difference with real money?
Rym: Well, I mean you're playing with real money.
Scott: What's the fixed bet?
Scott: You said it like at a dime.
Rym: I forget It's basically the same.
Scott: It's grandly the same.
Rym: the only difference is the bank doesn't cover the money that you owe when bullshit happens In the forest and get free money from the bank to come back in after you've lost.
Rym: you can buy back in with money money.
Rym: Yeah, so I kind of wanted to try playing this with real money effects.
Rym: No one else was super into it.
Scott: I'm not super into jail.
Rym: I Would not be worried about Jen.
Scott: I'm sure if you played games for real money in four and enforcers noticed you would not be welcome.
Rym: Oh Scott, even if you're playing for real money, you use poker chips.
Rym: You settle up afterwards.
Rym: Jeez It's like it's like me playing hearts for money in school.
Scott: Also play That's fine.
Rym: good There's we're not giving the house a cut.
Scott: and oops The book is slightly skewed here.
Scott: Yeah, you owe everyone owes me ten bucks.
Rym: There's poker chips.
Rym: What are you gonna have counterfeit poker chips?
Scott: No, I'm writing down in the book What happened and then you'll forget what happened.
Scott: then we'll look at the book and so we don't buy that.
Rym: You know what you do.
Rym: you take your fucking poker chips.
Rym: We all go somewhere like at a restaurant and then we exchange poker chips for money.
Rym: That's how it goes down.
Scott: Everyone walks out with chips in a little baggie.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not trusting you and your bookie.
Scott: I'm not gonna write down how many ships everyone has.
Rym: He blagged the bookies.
Rym: But Tyrone, seriously, it is rare that I will just Uncategorically and without reservation recommend a game for these purposes.
Rym: granted.
Scott: This isn't greatest game of all time territory No, but this is close to Tigger's New Freighties.
Scott: This fills a slot in the game library that no other game currently fills Right it is it?
Scott: so in that respect there is no other game that you can buy to do what pandante does Which is panda poker.
Scott: so you should get it if possible.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.