Rym: It's Wednesday January 29th 2014.
Rym: I am Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight we're sir let's do this.
Rym: so we were gonna do this.
Rym: show about I guess cartoons.
Scott: well he had this idea cartoons the hair dogs in them.
Scott: no there were so many animated movies that are like I'm not have dogs in them but are about dogs like all dogs go to heaven or all dogs go to heaven to Oliver and company yeah or Lady and the Tramp yeah 101 Dalmatians.
Rym: but you know we can do the same thing with cats I mean the Aristocats.
Scott: there aren't as many cat all-purpose cultural cat girl Nuku Nuku.
Scott: okay if you go bad tank police if you go that far what about?
Rym: what about the Jungle Book?
Rym: Jungle Book is about monkeys and cats mostly monkeys cats in there and actually there's a lot of bear.
Scott: the point is that while we know of something realize that there were so many dog movies in the animated category that we knew your luck hound and had seen in our lives.
Rym: I want to point out.
Rym: the reason we thought of this is because apparently I'm the only person in the world who remembers a dog Tanyan and the three musket hounds and that's how it should be so while we realized there were so many of these musket hounds forever.
Rym: it's been so long since we've seen any of them like.
Scott: I only remember the Vegas like one sentence description of each one like Lady and the Tramp.
Scott: yeah there's a really nice dog who's a lady who lives in a nice house.
Scott: I remember we found that you found a quiz that was like spaghetti behind the diner the Italian restaurant.
Scott: then they finally get together.
Scott: the end.
Rym: we should watch those all.
Rym: let's watch one of those movies like.
Rym: I've seen it in 20 plus years.
Scott: I remember when I was a super little kid.
Rym: Lady and the Tramp was one of my favorite movies ever.
Scott: it was not one of my favorite movies.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: I just really liked it.
Rym: a lot of reminded me of the sort of screwball comedy black-and-white romance movies that I was used to anyway.
Scott: so we had to abandon that episode and do some other shit because we could barely remember any of these things.
Rym: well Scott found this quiz that was like name this dog from an animated movie and I'm looking at one of them and I'm like alright.
Rym: so the options are Oliver II or company correct.
Rym: Emily knew more than both of us combined.
Rym: that's obvious like I knew Todd and copper from the Fox was which the hooned?
Rym: yeah yeah I thought Todd was the Fox but then maybe copper was the Fox.
Rym: pretty sure Todd is the Fox.
Scott: send your comments to him.
Scott: yeah show off how that.
Scott: you know this trivial piece of information.
Rym: if you are a dog-headed girl tell us all about your OC.
Scott: create a set of questions for a time of trivia war 9000 about dog related.
Rym: oh my god actually you know we should bring back.
Rym: we're smart enough to do it better now.
Rym: challenge you're on fire.
Rym: I still have the whole game show like ready to run.
Scott: it's all you okay?
Rym: so anyway let's go to a video of us running that it like Katsucon 2007.
Scott: I think we only tried to run a ConnectiCon once and failed.
Rym: no we ran it at Katsucon - remember we had all Stevie B and all the guests and basically none of the guests got past.
Rym: the second question we're like well that's really disappointing anyway news.
Scott: so boing.
Scott: boing made this post today snow piercer science fiction graphic novel about a train that carries all of Earth's remaining population and based on the title alone I'm like that is getting bought by me.
Rym: that is up our alley.
Scott: so let me read the longer description for you.
Scott: so first of all it's it's I think there's two volumes.
Scott: the first volume came out today.
Scott: the next volume is coming out February 25th so really soon.
Scott: it's a French novel and there's a new movie coming out based on it that will be released sometime in the first quarter of this year.
Scott: so it's basically all coming out for us right now.
Scott: but let me read the entirety of this incredible description that upon hearing which if your wallet doesn't empty itself stop listening and maybe I don't know don't listen to anything else ever again.
Scott: okay.
Scott: so let me read it coursing through an eternal winter coursing on an icy track wrapped around the frozen planet earth their travels snow piercer a train 1001 carriages long from fearsome engine to final car all surviving human life is here a complete hierarchy of the society.
Scott: we lost.
Scott: the elite as ever travel in luxury at the front of the train but for those in the rear coaches life is squalid miserable and short.
Scott: oh my gosh prologue is a refugee from the tail determined never to go back in his journey forward through the train he hopes to reach the mythical engine mythical engine and perhaps find some hope for the future.
Rym: the no just a big loop.
Scott: the original graphic novels have been adapted then why didn't he just go backwards one car?
Scott: the original graphic novels one way darted into an astounding new film directed by June ho bong and distributed in the u.s.
Scott: by the Weinstein company do release his course.
Scott: so it's a French comic with this incredible concept.
Scott: that is something between Galaxy Express 39 Titanic and why the last man and Final Fantasy legend one.
Rym: oh my god Final Fantasy legend one.
Rym: oh my gosh it's a tower.
Scott: they're trying to go.
Scott: I know I know we should just like in the train.
Scott: they're trying to go forward.
Rym: maybe we should do a show on that.
Scott: we could do a Final Fantasy legend Tuesday.
Scott: show my dad's a stealth bomber.
Scott: how awesome is that shit?
Scott: oh and by the way it shot down the moon whale and then spoilers dude Zagor.
Rym: so there's some news here.
Rym: I'm not gonna go through the whole history of what happened at anime Boston but suffice it to say there was.
Rym: there was a news update for anime Boston 2014. it was posted January 24th so not that long ago.
Rym: I give these dates in case you know dateline January 29th in case anything changes.
Rym: so if something changes and you listen to this and you don't have other sources of news you get what you deserve.
Rym: anime Boston is despite their quote best efforts of their staff and partners on quote not having a rave again.
Rym: basically what happened is years ago there was an incident at the rave.
Rym: they call it a dance.
Rym: every anime con calls it a dance.
Rym: every attendee of anime cons calls it a rave.
Rym: an incident happened.
Rym: police were involved and the thing got shut down.
Rym: I think that was the year that we were at PAX East two or three years ago.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I think it was two thousand and there have been incidents of many natures.
Scott: it pretty much every anime con rave dance.
Rym: okay here I think it was 2012. okay the informal dance as they called it but there's huge quotes around.
Rym: that is the rave got shut down.
Rym: there's a forum thread in their forum that's like why the dance gets shut down.
Rym: so there's a police and ambulance blah blah blah.
Rym: so they tried in 2013 to have the dance again and they had to move it to another venue because the incident was big enough to where the hotel convention center the Heinz that they use would not let them host it there for various reasons.
Scott: you had a problem with this event last time.
Scott: you're lucky.
Scott: we're still letting you be here at all because we want money but we can still make you cancel that one event and you can't nowhere else to go.
Rym: so I'm gonna quote the thing from last year.
Rym: unfortunately after the space was contracting everything was in place to hold the dance.
Rym: our entertainment license for the informal dance was rejected so by the city.
Rym: over the past several weeks I have personally reached out to police city and state representatives to find out the reason why our license were rejected.
Rym: the reasons were one there are a bunch of other events happening at the same time like Red Sox games which I think is kind of bogus because the same thing happens with Ravens games and Otakon on a regular basis.
Rym: and but as a result quote the Boston Police Department could not assign any detail officers to anime Boston's informal dance.
Rym: Two, after reviewing what happened last year the city of Boston needs a robust security and medical plan their primary concerns revolving around overcrowding issues and I'm quoting a hundred percent here the behavior of a very small segment of our attendee population.
Rym: so the city basically said no dance for you guys in 2013. so as it was announced now also no dance in 2014 for what appears to be the same reasons.
Rym: all right I think and this is why I'm putting this in the news this is not super exciting news except that I think this is the best thing that's ever happened.
Rym: anime Boston.
Rym: I think they should just drop the rave excuse to not have it.
Rym: yes because anime cons have this cultural problem where they will all copy each other.
Rym: because well it's an anime con.
Rym: that's just what you do.
Rym: you have the Thursday badge pickup even though you should really mail the badges.
Rym: you have to have the AMV contest gotta have the cosplay skits.
Rym: you gotta do all these things that every anime con does.
Rym: no you don't.
Rym: you could do something different.
Rym: guys try something different.
Scott: it might go really well it might go badly but no what'll happen is all these kids will show up expecting all those things and there won't be any of those things.
Scott: I remember it'll become lobby con and they'll just hang out in the hallways doing whatever they do all the time and get bored and maybe go home.
Rym: but I remember in 2013
Scott: a lot of people
Rym: who were grumbling like they were walking around like asking people where's the dance like they had literally at no point before anime Boston gone to its website at no point before or during it looked at its schedule probably had never looked in the con book.
Rym: no they just assume that it has all the things that every anime con has.
Scott: I mean how many times did we go to anime conventions and or any kind of convention and people would basically see there was some kind of dance party going on and coming off the street or come just for the dance as you know because it's like oh you know I mean they're like clubs and bars that will have dances and people go to those specifically.
Scott: so if a convention they don't care about the convention surrounding that dance they're just like oh there's a dance there I'll go to that and it happens
Rym: yeah though it's they have to get a badge to get into it unless the staff of the building and or convention are really bad
Scott: at checking
Rym: and keeping people who shouldn't be there
Scott: out.
Scott: I've seen that happen a lot in my bad conventions don't check so on.
Rym: I think anime Boston should embrace this and just give up on the dance and do something else like they have their in their formal ball which I think is really cool.
Rym: ConnectiCon does something similar.
Scott: therefore like magfest.
Scott: no wait that's still copying someone.
Rym: that copy someone just don't all copy each other.
Rym: it'd be like if I copied Scott and everything in my life and he copied me.
Rym: that doesn't work in the long run.
Rym: that's just a circle.
Scott: jerk you know what I would do if I had an awesome convention.
Scott: yeah I would have the non free feast a feast a catered feast.
Rym: you gotta have big pieces of meat with that bone stick long ass tables reserved seating whatever.
Rym: they gotta be tables big enough to have a tankard of ale and smash it down.
Scott: that's right.
Rym: there's gotta be dogs walking around.
Scott: you got a guy have a big fat King just slopping and yelling catered feast with entertainment and there would only be like a few hundred seats or however many at the long-ass Scott's.
Rym: I've been to conventions that have exactly what you want.
Scott: yeah but those are Ren fairs.
Scott: yes that's not.
Scott: I'm talking like at packs.
Scott: imagine if like the 200 people at packs who paid the most charity or whatever you know to the fundraising dinner you mean like that fundraising dinner we went to.
Scott: or it could be like you know a tabletop RPG feast at a gaming con.
Scott: you get seated at a table where you roll them bones and then eat meat off them bones.
Scott: but seriously I think she chose the vegetarian out.
Rym: I think this is great and anime Boston needs to embrace it mostly because if anime cons are have such a stick up their butts about usually because they're a nonprofit and they have a charter and whatever that their programming can only be anime programming.
Rym: then how do they justify the raves that mostly play generic house and dubstep and dance music even though they used to a long time ago?
Scott: there's gonna be at least one or two DJs playing the anime.
Scott: yeah but they won't.
Rym: I mean most of them won't accept panels that aren't just a hundred percent about anime.
Rym: hmm and they make a big deal about that.
Rym: but then they have the completely generic dance.
Scott: they have a tabletop room.
Rym: yeah exactly.
Rym: so also the culture in anime convention rave slash dances is toxic but it's toxic in this like 14 year old wannabe way.
Rym: I'm amazed at the behavior I see in these things that every con I go to especially because back in like I don't know 2006 2007 I'd go to like Katsucon and Friday night of the con it was 80s music and it was all people like my age dancing and the anime kids would come in and be like what is this and then walk out or they'd play.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: anime dance mixes at least at least give some sort of lip service to the music being at least almost Japanese.
Rym: but separate aside the excuses that the city of Boston everything gave our lame excuses don't make sense because one Boston is actually kind of known for having literally one of the best medical and trauma center responses available in the entire United States.
Rym: Boston is known for its ability to deal with mash cat mass casualties for a long time not because they've had so many incidents but just because that's what Boston is known for.
Rym: there's a lot of hospitals there's a lot of experts.
Rym: actually I read two a separate article saying that that was a big contributor to why so many people were able to get such good treatment so quickly after the Boston bombings.
Rym: so the the fact that the city made it so hard for anime Boston to have these dances really implies to me and this is just me speculating.
Rym: I think Boston does not want to have a PR problem with a convention mostly attended by young people having a police incident or a fatality or something.
Scott: there must be at least one person in the Boston government or bureaucracy who remembers what happened in anime Boston right and is just now you know has written that down and it's in the black book or it's on somewhere and they remember it and they're gonna hold to that.
Scott: now right it's someone somewhere or some record.
Scott: has you know?
Scott: maybe someone in the police department or something like has them you know given the black mark after the incident and that's it.
Rym: the saddest thing is the statement from this year says quote but unfortunately we could not find a location that would meet safety requirements was within a realistic budget and then there's a big final and here after the comma and be approved by the venues management.
Rym: there's a lot implied by that.
Rym: so yeah good luck.
Rym: anime Boston.
Rym: I have zero sympathy for the kids who show up expecting there to be a rave.
Scott: I hope anime Boston like basically said that and didn't even try just paying lip service to those kids that that is the kind of thing that we would do.
Scott: let's not even try to have a dance.
Scott: let's just write that we tried and failed so that people can't be hating on us and then that the you know we'll say we tried and failed and we did.
Rym: yeah dog I really wanted to schedule your fifth the homestuck panel but there just wasn't room but Rym.
Rym: there's like five empty rooms.
Rym: yeah fire code those rooms have to be empty at those times.
Scott: staff to man those rooms right there.
Rym: you've got eight staff just sitting behind you right now.
Scott: they're all busy doing something.
Scott: they're playing teach you.
Scott: yeah it's for the teacher tournament.
Scott: later they're practicing.
Scott: get the rules down.
Scott: they got it.
Scott: they got to manage it.
Scott: their panel staff not gaming staff.
Rym: well there's only so many staff here at that point that's when one of our staff is quietly come under behind them to just tase them.
Rym: all right let's move on two things of the day.
Rym: if you're one of those nerds there's a lot of you out there who makes fun of football and sports people.
Rym: and doesn't you know you get mad about the Super Bowl.
Rym: you make a point of being like I'm not gonna watch the Super Bowl or I only watch the Super Bowl because of the ads one shut up - they're just as nerdy as you.
Rym: and three the Super Bowl is pretty awesome.
Rym: so if you don't know anything about sports ball this is a very short pretty funny video that will explain the only things you actually need to know to be able to enjoy watching sports ball.
Scott: that's all.
Scott: that's it.
Rym: it's a thing.
Rym: no it's the best thing I saw today that I can share.
Scott: so you know there's a lot of animes lately that are like these short animes just for YouTube the most recent good ones of which are turning girls and inferno cup inferno cup.
Scott: have you watched inferno cup?
Rym: I've watched some inferno cup.
Scott: okay so there's a new one that is not bad.
Scott: it's definitely the best one.
Scott: since those it remains yet to be seen the overall quality but it's good enough that I want to watch more of it.
Scott: based on the first episode it's called senpai club.
Scott: it is the first episode is pretty much the most stereotypical anime you've ever seen.
Scott: right and it knows it.
Scott: it's doing all the cliches a hundred percent on purpose to the point is which the girl is like.
Scott: oh no I am late for school.
Scott: oh no I can't hold this toast in my mouth.
Scott: oh you know it's anime.
Scott: the anime yes it is animated anime which has been done before but the something about the way this is doing it is even more literal.
Scott: I think.
Rym: what really does?
Rym: it is the opening theme.
Scott: yeah and just the way it's drawn is sort of.
Scott: you know it's like a higher quality than turning girls.
Scott: it's more animated but it isn't drawn that much better.
Rym: then they like that point where she's just like back about go back go back go back and I'm the subtitles are saying something completely different.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: and then they have like.
Scott: they even have like the the fake sponsorship to where they're like you know.
Scott: oh sponsored week you know.
Scott: and then this concept of the senpai club.
Scott: I just want to know more.
Scott: like there's a club of senpais I don't get.
Scott: tell me more is it is it really?
Scott: this is like the harem I don't know.
Scott: we'll see it's.
Scott: it's pretty if you have watched.
Scott: I mean this isn't something that everyone will like.
Scott: but if you have watched an anime yeah or then you will under you'll like.
Rym: well if you've watched more than one anime right like watching this at a moment.
Rym: the book club book was I do by William Gibson.
Rym: it was a pretty good book.
Rym: I've read it twice Scott classic doing a show on it.
Rym: as soon as we can the next book will be a wool.
Scott: I'll make a page about it like to a shit that lambs got on them that you go and take it off and make a sweater.
Rym: that shit yes it's another sci-fi novel though my non book club recommendation to anyone who wants good sci-fi to read look at our book club for player of games and read that book because I'm almost done reading every single book that E&M banks ever wrote.
Scott: my recommendation is you should go back and read prince of nothing.
Rym: I was about to check.
Rym: I was waiting for you to finish saying that cuz I was gonna look at the next prince of nothing the official GeekNights' book if there's ever been a book that was.
Rym: I think almost everyone in the front row crew has read this book.
Rym: almost everyone we talked to on a regular basis has read this book.
Rym: good god can't see when the next book is coming out.
Rym: aspect Emperor.
Rym: but why like warrior?
Scott: whatever the official book series not book club of the month but just official book.
Rym: oh I got excited for a second.
Rym: I was like oh did the new book come out?
Rym: no it's just Canadian book cover.
Rym: yeah exactly right that got me.
Rym: that gets all of us.
Scott: they'll get you every time any other meta things.
Scott: you should go on the internet and find us.
Scott: we have YouTube videos and we have most important accounts and Facebook's and Google+ and forums and lots of our lectures from conventions are online.
Rym: also we have another show we're doing called GeekNights presents.
Rym: we're going through every goddamn episode of Jojo Kakumei utenna analyzing it in excruciating detail.
Rym: mm-hmm it's a pretty good show.
Rym: I'm actually really excited.
Rym: and not do 10 about our thing is it gets fun to do.
Rym: we're gonna try to do this more and faster but that really depends on you getting other people to watch it so that I have more incentive to spend all the time it takes to make it.
Rym: and yeah so we didn't do the dog episode.
Scott: no we didn't.
Scott: we do.
Scott: cuz I just you know what it would be.
Scott: I realized we you know we could do it but just be so boring.
Scott: I'd be like so hundred one Dalmatians.
Scott: she really wanted to make a code out of them and failed the end.
Scott: that's all I remember.
Rym: I would probably have a lot to say about all dogs go to heaven because that movie is pretty clear in my memory from it whatsoever other than there is a movie about dogs and it's called all dogs go to heaven.
Rym: all right.
Rym: well you know what guys tell us which animated movie that features a protagonist dog we should watch and we'll watch it and do a show.
Scott: instead of the all dogs episode just the one movie.
Rym: let's pick one movie that has a dog as the as it has to be the protagonist sure so he went to crunchy roll to look for some animes to watch.
Scott: I tried to pick one that no one had ever heard of or was just out of nowhere and the one that we noticed that we picked because it had short ass episodes four minutes long we love.
Scott: that was Wooser's hand to mouth life.
Scott: so obviously it's an anime.
Scott: it has short four minute episodes and apparently it's in its second season and the first episode we watched was actually the first episode of the second season and we went back and watched like three to five random episodes from the first and second seasons once we realized our mistake.
Scott: and yeah what the hell is this shit.
Scott: so I don't get it.
Scott: this
Rym: is the kind of thing where remember back at RIT anime when we showed everyone Excel saga and people flipped their shit yeah about how zany and crazy it was like what like it was so different from what they were used to but
Scott: it was a hyperactive energy that this did not have.
Scott: this is like Excel saga like just chillin like what's up.
Rym: this is a lot more like actually both in animation style and in humor and an amount of dialogue.
Rym: it's a lot like the cutscenes in WarioWare on the GameCube mmm like.
Rym: it reminds me of that more than anything and the opener is really video gamey.
Rym: the interstitials are very video gamey
Scott: yep
Rym: but if we showed some episodes of this to the same anime club that was super excited about Excel saga back in the day they
Scott: met when they liked it like
Rym: in the days before YouTube they would have liked it just because it was weird.
Rym: they'd be like what.
Rym: oh my god what was that?
Rym: I know.
Rym: but stuff like this really does not hold up in the modern era when I could see weird things anytime I want on YouTube.
Scott: so the concept here is you have this creature named Wooser.
Scott: he's a monster or an animal that doesn't have a name and he basically is a really perverted.
Scott: he likes to look up skirts and whatever and it's kind of horrible typical anime garbage there.
Scott: well right he like.
Scott: he wants money.
Scott: I guess he has never has a job but you never really see him getting money.
Scott: he just says literally that he wants money.
Rym: he also wants meat.
Scott: he likes to eat meat and he's just sort of around.
Scott: and there's these twin girls Rin and Len and they'll just be.
Scott: even though it's a four-minute episode the episode will be split into like multiple segments right that have almost nothing to do with each other.
Scott: most of the time early some of the time they do have something to do with each other but rarely and random shit happens in each one and I think each one is supposed to be a joke.
Scott: but only one of them that we saw out of like five episodes is funny but it was pretty funny.
Scott: it was pretty funny if one of them was funny but the rest were just sort of like either.
Scott: like the first episode of the second season was like whoa.
Scott: that's really perverted anime garbage I don't want to watch.
Scott: you know we're like girls playing tennis oh my god.
Scott: where he's like creeping on him from the behind the tree yeah or when it's raining and he's like oh yeah girls and their blouses are all wet.
Rym: yeah I can see their bras kind of through the translucent shirts like yeah not interested in that.
Rym: yeah there's literally one funny episode right?
Scott: yeah?
Scott: so the one funny bit in one of the episodes was basically you see a girl.
Scott: she seems to be at a club at school and she's playing a bass and then there's a second girl also playing the bass and there's a third girl playing a stand-up bass and then the fourth girl is playing air bass but she's making the noises with her mouth right and then you see Wooster like looking through the it that is.
Scott: you know that was the only funny bit we've seen.
Rym: the jokes are basically jack handy that he'll make observations and that's it.
Rym: he'll be like if an adult says that they're not gonna do anything they're probably about to do something like I will.
Scott: you know these girls will walk up the stairs not saying anything or just chatting away and on the wall you see posters that are like don't pull down skirts.
Scott: so the picture of Wooster pulling down skirts.
Scott: and then after they walk up the stairs you'll see him on the stairs that he got trampled.
Scott: he was all happy he looked up the skirts and he's like I can die now and then he dies.
Rym: so this thing is based on a journal column by a member of supercell which is actually a band okay which would explain why it was even made in the first place.
Rym: why people know?
Scott: I don't understand what that.
Scott: what can that journal column be like?
Rym: I imagine based on no research and just this show that it's a Japanese jack handy?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: it's just really weird.
Rym: also kids do any of you know what jack handy is without looking it up the ones who aren't kids do yeah.
Rym: so I guess that was a review of worse.
Rym: there's hand-to-mouth life.
Scott: yeah it's at least the title has some relation to what happens right hand-to-mouth implying that he's poor and he does want money a lot.
Scott: so but in I don't see how it's a depiction of his life and the art style changes a lot.
Scott: right there was an episode where they turn into magical girls.
Scott: it's one of those things where it's not ultra super deformed it is mostly super deformed.
Scott: I think there was like recently we discussed like the desu meter on the forums.
Scott: so I guess it's like desu meter seven and it'll.
Scott: actually it'll never go farther than that at least not that I've seen.
Scott: but it'll pull back and go to a lower desu amount you know for you know yeah which is sort of what Dama kadobitsu does.
Scott: oh yeah right same same kind of thing.
Rym: but Dama kadobitsu is one of the funniest anime ever made right.
Scott: but animation wise the default is kind of like really cutesy and whatnot.
Scott: and then it'll pull back to be less cutesy to do magical girl joke or a perverted joke.
Rym: but yeah honestly it's really not worth watching
Scott: even though the episodes are only four minutes and the opener and closer take up half
Rym: kind of reviewed it only because I can't find anyone else who's reviewed it other than we
Scott: tried to find something that we and crunchyroll just looking through the list that we had never heard of and don't think anyone else had heard of or cared about at all.
Rym: Wow so the only reviews I found are people posting reviews in forums.
Scott: and what are they saying?
Scott: up first I thought let's discuss these reviews for hilarity.
Rym: all right all right.
Rym: so here's a crunchyroll review.
Rym: this guy gave it five stars whoa maybe first I thought this was a mediocre kids show with nothing special.
Rym: cutesy little girls anime boy.
Rym: was I wrong?
Rym: this is a cock tease to anime with simple design.
Rym: the humor is great the animation is surprisingly amazing for something so simple and woo sir I love him.
Rym: this guy such a sweetheart I can't take it.
Rym: he makes this show work with how naughty he actually is.
Rym: do check it out.
Rym: it's just amazing.
Rym: this guy so dear wrote that review.
Scott: you are the fucking problem.
Rym: I don't want to do not be that guy.
Rym: okay I found every review this guy's master placed.
Rym: I let's see.
Rym: I'm looking at what other things this guy's reviewed.
Rym: he reviewed miss monochrome.
Rym: the animation only gave it two stars.
Rym: he bolds a lot of random words spoiler.
Rym: okay he keeps posting on woo sir.
Rym: I guess he really likes woo sir.
Scott: he's into woo sir.
Scott: yeah he's the woo sir number one fan.
Rym: ah it's hard to tell what he's done.
Rym: this forms actually not that good.
Rym: all right wow there's a bunch of people who really like woo sir.
Rym: in a short amount of time they pack a punch with this anime.
Rym: hilarious to the core fun to the point and the fan images at the end means it has a big following.
Rym: also go to the website following.
Scott: I don't deny that it has a second season.
Rym: wait a minute.
Rym: also go to the website and see some of the stuff you can buy.
Rym: I laughed at most of its.
Rym: I wonder if some of these are astroturf.
Rym: yeah they got that review.
Rym: that's the only thing that guy's ever reviewed and he doesn't have any other posts.
Scott: you think he's trying to sell woo sir merchandise?
Rym: I think that might be some astroturfing.
Scott: all right these review reviews are surprisingly trying to find a review with a low number of stuff.
Rym: all right here's the lowest review.
Rym: two stars.
Rym: woo sir's hands-to-mouth life.
Rym: basically another show focused more on the design and cuteness of the characters and on the content itself with a childish humor which isn't bad.
Rym: this is all spelled wrong by the way then sometimes makes you turn your head in embarrassment which is already.
Rym: keep spelling which wrong.
Scott: this guy's got the right idea.
Rym: I just can't write might be enjoyable by some but if you expect something deep and memorable you better jump to the bottom of a well for that you know what that's funny cuz of well is deep.
Scott: I'm using that.
Scott: thanks guy who can't spell you.
Scott: actually you're a guy with good ideas who should take some English classes.
Rym: all right frog socks.
Rym: what else I like?
Scott: the way you think you just got to work on your spelling.
Scott: oh no it's not frogs ox's Darien kin huh or maybe it's a smart person who just doesn't have English as a first language.
Scott: true that's you know.
Rym: it's also the only review he's ever written.
Scott: but I like his style.
Rym: I don't like his style.
Rym: I want to know more about.
Scott: he's got three crunchyroll points and next time someone says yeah that shit is shallow I'm gonna say if you want something deep go to the bottom of well or watch cowboy bebop.
Scott: and if someone says you know if I'm gonna if something is deep I'll be like man that shit's deep like a.
Rym: well so yeah whoo sir I think the reviews were more entertaining than the show characters ever.
Scott: the clip with the bass playing yeah that was fine.
Scott: to find that on YouTube I will.
Rym: I'll try to link to it if I can fire.
Scott: we can remember which of the episodes in crunchyroll it is that we can watch just that one episode and once you get past the part with the bass playing you can end.
Rym: I'll poke around.
Rym: I'll link to something.
Scott: maybe someone else will watch all the episodes and tell us if there's any other jokes of that caliber.
Rym: I'm waiting for someone to come out of the board work and be like you.
Rym: guys are the worst people.
Rym: your review was a ridiculous joke like the stuff that Mike always gets when he writes articles.
Scott: listen if you have a show and the first episode of the second season is upskirt tennis playing and wet blouse in the rain because girls forgot their umbrella you're the problem.
Scott: why would I like your show?
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Scott: they cross their hearts and pray.
Rym: they cross their souls.
Rym: night and day.
Rym: they drink a beer and swear.
Rym: they're faithful to the king.
Rym: no matter what you say.
Rym: they're never far away.
Scott: they're always ready to fight or to sing one for all and one for one.
Scott: Musker hounds are always ready one for all and one for one helping everybody one for all and all for one.
Scott: it's a pretty story.
Scott: sharing everything we're fun.
Scott: that's the way to be episode number one dog Tanyan's journey.