Rym: It's Wednesday, December 2nd, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight, the manga Prophecy by Tetsuo Ttsutsui.
Scott: Prophecy is literally the title of the manga in English.
Rym: Let's do this!
Rym: A manga for which there is not a Wikipedia article yet, except on the French Wikipedia, and where there isn't even an Anime News Network encyclopedia entry on it, there's just a misspelled press release saying that Vertical picked it up.
Scott: Alrighty.
Rym: So yeah, in the news, you know, getting right into this, I did something as an anime fan, as someone who has been an anime fan for, my God.
Rym: So let's see, I was in fourth grade.
Rym: My God.
Rym: My God, is that an anime music video?
Rym: So I've been an anime fan since I was, so I was in fourth grade at five years old, so I was like nine.
Rym: I was born in '82, 1991.
Rym: So since 1991, I've been a pretty hardcore anime fan.
Scott: Does Voltron and Transformers count?
Rym: No, well, no, if you count that, I've been an anime fan since like 1985?
Scott: Six?
Scott: So I guess Akira showed in the US in '89, right?
Scott: But I obviously didn't see it then.
Rym: I don't remember the year of that, I just know that when I was in fourth grade, I saw Vampire Hunter D, because my mom made me, and then I watched as much anime as I could get, and got hardcore into the VHS fan-subbing community long before RIT.
Rym: So in all that time, not only being a hardcore fan of anime, you know, the kind of person who goes to anime conventions, like doing a fucking podcast about anime, and a YouTube show about it.
Rym: Yeah, I never made an anime music video, until now.
Scott: Why did you suddenly make an anime music video?
Rym: Because my whole anime fandom, how many times have you or I said- You're gonna write a fanfiction next?
Rym: Actually, I promised someone I would now.
Rym: Okay, great.
Scott: Rym is devolving fandom back in time.
Rym: Yeah, someone hit me with the fan stone, so I'm evolving.
Scott: Yeah, I think he's gonna make some garage kits next.
Rym: So, in making an anime music video for the first time, because my whole life, I'd say like, "Oh, I should make an anime music video to that song.
Rym: That's an obvious
Rym: thing.".
Rym: And I just shit-talked and never did it, because it was hard to do shit with VHS whatevers.
Rym: And then in RIT, like, I could have made anime music videos, but didn't care enough to actually do it.
Rym: Like, what was the one you and I, we kept talking about?
Rym: doing the Chainsaw Juggler?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Do it now.
Rym: No.
Rym: Well, maybe, actually.
Scott: Whatever happened to that?
Scott: Chainsaw Juggler.
Rym: He was a good friend of mine.
Scott: He was?
Scott: How did you make friends with a chainsaw juggler?
Rym: How did he die?
Rym: That's the real question.
Rym: With his arms bloody by his side.
Rym: What?
Rym: I just kicked him to death.
Rym: So, anyway, I already talked about this, but that new My Little Pony Equestria Girls thing, don't watch it.
Scott: It's not-- Rym watched it because he wanted to.
Rym: I didn't actually watch it.
Rym: So, like I did with the first one, I watched some YouTube clips to see what the deal was without actually watching the whole thing.
Rym: And it had better music.
Rym: And one of the songs triggered the anime music video since, as has been triggered many times in my life of, "Hey, that clock never rings.
Rym: That song is
Rym: perfect.".
Scott: Talk to me.
Scott: Just tap your fingers right in the steering wheel.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: Spark in the eye.
Rym: Yeah, there's some motions that Ken Chiro makes sometimes, too, that fit that feeling.
Scott: So-- Turning around 180 degrees and standing still looking at someone right in the face.
Rym: So, there's that moment where you think, "Wow, that would make a really good anime music
Rym: video.".
Rym: And then I thought, "You know what?
Rym: Fuck it.
Rym: I'm just gonna make it because how hard can it
Rym: be?".
Rym: And you know what the answer is?
Rym: Not fucking hard at all.
Rym: It is really easy to make a pretty good anime music video.
Rym: So, I sat down and not counting the time it took to download the 40-gigabyte Blu-ray-Rip of Utena, it took me about two days to make this thing.
Rym: I just threw it together, two days, in from here, bam, done, uploaded.
Rym: And I'm convinced that it's in, like, the top fifth of anime music videos ever made because most anime music videos really, really suck.
Rym: And, in fact, I went around watching a lot of anime music videos after I made it, like, recent ones, like, ones made in the last year, like, ones that didn't win tournaments.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You have tournaments of music videos?
Rym: Contests.
Rym: Tournaments.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Little bracket.
Rym: So, I learned some other things making this.
Rym: One, a lot of people really liked it.
Rym: I'm kind of surprised by that.
Rym: Two, animemusicvideos.org still exists.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: That is still a place that is an active website, and it literally appears to be unchanged since 2003.
Scott: All right.
Rym: It seems to update every day with news.
Rym: It has its whole database.
Rym: that also appears to be running the same back end.
Rym: And they have a FAQ.
Rym: The FAQ appears to be vintage 2003.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It has, literally, the word "YouTube" does not appear anywhere on this website.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: And you still upload your anime music video to their website.
Scott: Where are they storing all these?
Rym: They're hosted locally.
Scott: They have enough storage and streaming power?
Rym: Well, their upload limit is 150 megabytes.
Scott: Oh, I see.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, so you guys know, I rendered out the video to upload, like, this rough cut to YouTube, right?
Rym: The anime music video I made.
Scott: 10 ADPs?
Rym: Yeah, well, not actually 10 ADP, 'cause it's 4x3, but the equivalent of that for a 4x3.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah, following YouTube's recommended output settings for maximum quality for their transcoder, 4 gigs.
Rym: 4 gigs for a 2-minute-and-something video.
Rym: So the fact that animemusicvideos.org still exists is updated daily and seems to have a community.
Scott: It existed in the days before YouTube, it was the only way to get anime music videos, and in those days, your computer couldn't even play a 1080p video if such a thing existed.
Scott: It was pretty much 480i for everything.
Rym: I remember the days, Scott... -And that was good quality.
Rym: ...of you, me, and James trolling that site, looking for anything worth showing to the RIT Anime Club, because we had shown every good anime music video in the world.
Scott: That we had access to that wasn't on just one VHS tape in some dude's closet.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the fag gets even better.
Rym: I found these how-to guides on how to make an anime music video.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: A lot of talk about how to deal with, like, VHS artifacts or embedded subtitles.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Cropping.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I learned another thing, 'cause I figured, "Oh, I'll enter this anime music video in a bunch of anime music video contests or
Rym: tournaments.".
Rym: Mm.
Rym: I'm gonna call everything a tournament now.
Scott: Call tournaments contests.
Rym: Apparently, and it seems to be like a new thing for this year, KatsuKan, of all cons, has three separate anime music video death matches.
Scott: Death matches?
Rym: I'm gonna keep escalating this term.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Contests.
Rym: They have the normal anime music video contest that every con has.
Rym: The Royal Rumble?
Rym: They have the, like, one-minute-or-less-submissions-only contest that is separate.
Scott: The Survivor Series?
Rym: That seems like an interesting thing.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And then they have the NC-17 one.
Scott: The Animania?
Rym: The HMVs, I assume.
Scott: I almost --.
Scott: Or the PMVs.
Rym: Oh, well, it still has to be anime.
Rym: It's just NC-17.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, PMVs.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, I almost wonder, is that just, like, violent stuff?
Rym: Is it straight-up, like, just porn music videos?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And if it is hentai music videos, does anyone do one that's in the drama category and is super serious?
Scott: And the HMVs clearly aren't on YouTube.
Scott: 'cause you're not allowed to.
Scott: Where are they?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, that opens --.
Scott: 'Cause, I mean, you know, you can find hentais on the Internet just by typing it in.
Scott: I've never searched or even thought to search for hentai music video.
Rym: I'm doing that on YouTube right now.
Scott: You're not gonna find anything on YouTube.
Scott: It's a hentai.
Rym: I've seen hentai on YouTube.
Scott: But it's gonna not be -- Is it 100% censored?
Rym: Hentai music video.
Rym: Here's a bunch of them.
Scott: Are they just censored?
Rym: That's a --.
Rym: That is a butt right there.
Scott: It's a butt with pants on.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Those -- Yes.
Rym: Those are, in fact, technically pants.
Rym: That's a --.
Rym: That's not a dildo.
Rym: That's a reverse dildo.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: That's --.
Scott: So, they somehow created a video in such a way that you never see anything and such that it's okay to put on YouTube?
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: This looks like it's skirting the very edge of the line.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: Anime music videos is still a thing.
Rym: And for anyone who thinks that they're hard to make, no, they're trivial to make.
Rym: It's really, really, really easy to make a good anime music video.
Rym: If you think otherwise, I don't know, talent yourself up a little.
Scott: You also have Adobe Creative Cloud.
Scott: makes it way easier.
Rym: Yeah, own Premiere.
Rym: If you don't own Premiere, don't bother.
Scott: You don't own it.
Scott: You're just renting.
Rym: Yeah, no, I own it.
Rym: I pay for it.
Rym: It's mine.
Rym: I can use it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, yeah, you got some news?
Scott: I do have some news.
Scott: So, one of the pleasures of living in New York City is, of course, seeing -- being able to go to screenings for things, right, that you cannot necessarily see anywhere else, especially including foreign or obscure things like animes.
Scott: But one thing in particular is gonna be screening in New York City on December 4th.
Scott: So, we got two days left.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Which is a documentary called "The Kingdom of Dreams and Madness," which is a documentary about Studio Ghibli.
Scott: But I don't need to go to that screening, and neither do you.
Scott: Don't come rushing to the city for this because on December 9th, you can just download it digitally.
Rym: Oh, nice.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And it'll be on, like, video on demand on January 27th.
Scott: So if you wait, like, a month, you'll be able to see this thing really easily pretty much everywhere.
Scott: It's probably gonna -- Who knows?
Scott: It'll be on Netflix, everywhere.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The only reason I will ever -- -And it's not -- You don't really need to see a documentary in the movie theater.
Rym: That's what I was saying.
Rym: The only reason I'll ever go to a theater is, one, if it's something you literally can't see elsewhere, like, when I saw that "Nothing Lasts Forever" movie -- -Well, you can't today.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But, like, that "Nothing Lasts Forever" movie -- -It was on YouTube for, like, a day a few months ago.
Rym: But there is a chance that -- Like, there are things that have been screened in theaters.
Rym: There's a chance.
Rym: there's literally no other way to see it.
Rym: Or, like, the director might be there.
Rym: Or it's a movie where you really need to see it in HD, crazy, IMAX, 3D, high frame rate, whatever.
Rym: But other things, yeah, don't need to see them in theaters.
Rym: No.
Rym: Especially not a documentary.
Scott: Especially not for the amount of money that they charge, you know, having to go to the theater, having to deal with people, possibly sitting in front of me, possibly screaming kids.
Rym: So, I just want to point out -- -Possibly who knows what.
Rym: Unless I go to, like, the Children's Film Festival or, like, a special hipster screening of something, every time I go to the theater, the theater is basically completely empty, and it's just a private.
Scott: - -'Cause we're going to the good theaters.
Rym: Yeah, we are, meeting the theaters that are going out of business.
Scott: If there's a risk, you know, at a wrong theater, you could get into trouble.
Rym: If they open that Alamo-whatever Drafthouse-style theater in Manhattan -- -I think there is one.
Rym: The one that was going to open in Manhattan failed to open for reasons.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Otherwise, I would see every movie there.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So... There is one more other piece of news.
Rym: There is a deadline, a timeline for this, so if you care about this, follow the link that we link to now.
Rym: The deadline is December 5th.
Rym: Otakon.
Scott: That's really soon.
Rym: Otakon, the anime convention that we went to for a decade and presented panels at every year until they banned us from presenting panels at it, the one that, you know, all the drama and whatever, the one that refused to mail their badges and, as a result, has had the ridiculous, most awful line clusterfucks in anime convention history, has an official poll to determine whether or not they should mail the badges next year.
Scott: Why do they even need to ask?
Scott: Just fucking do it.
Scott: Jesus Christ.
Scott: So...
Rym: I'm linking to the forum post and the poll, the actual poll, but you have to give your legal name, your e-mail address, your member ID.
Rym: You have to have attended Otakon in the last three years, meaning they don't want feedback from all the people who quit going because they don't mail the badges because about three years ago is when the Thursday Night Line pickup went from manageable to fucked.
Rym: So, they also don't want anyone who doesn't ever go to Otakon because they don't mail the badges, like the people who can't go or it sucks to go because of that.
Scott: It's just an example of, right, this is the problem -- one of the core problems of nerd geek culture in general is when someone who provides geek services or geek things to the geek audience, right, will prioritize further servicing the existing audience as opposed to prioritizing growing the audience.
Rym: You, Captain, proposed this exact thing for selling PAX badges at the previous PAX.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, are you a hypocrite?
Scott: There's a difference.
Rym: How is it different?
Rym: I'm not excusing Otakon here.
Scott: The audience for PAX is already larger than all PAXs combined.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Growing it serves no purpose.
Rym: Otakon's attendance actually dropped this year.
Scott: That's why they should concentrate on growing their audience and not on servicing the existing audience.
Rym: I feel like they would be better -- one of the easiest ways they could grow their audience, aside from mailing the badges, which is obvious, would be to have fostered a culture of having good panel content.
Scott: This is an example of their bad culture, though.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Specifically, you must have attended Otakon within the last three years to participate.
Rym: Submissions that do not match our records will be discarded.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: I submit it anyway, dealing with it.
Rym: Yeah, however, if you go to Otakon's or care about Otakon, even if you haven't gone in the last three years, if you have a member ID, go fill this out now, because I suspect they have made this poll so that they'll have ammo to then not mail the badges, because that seems to be how they work.
Scott: Uh, yep, probably.
Scott: If they mailed the badges -- let's say they mailed them -- would you go?
Scott: Me?
Rym: No, I'd only go if I present -- I don't go to anime cons unless I'm a guest.
Rym: That's just how it works.
Rym: I haven't attended an anime con where I wasn't a guest since Katsu-Con
Rym: 2004? 2004,
Rym: I think.
Rym: Maybe 2005.
Rym: Pretty sure it was 2004.
Scott: So, who cares?
Scott: Yeah, so if they invite us back as guests -- -But, I mean, that same phenomena of servicing your existing fans as opposed to growing your fandom can be seen in comic books.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It can be -- You know, this is the sort of thing, right, that the Gomer Gates comes out of.
Rym: Imagine if DC and Marvel had a joint poll where you could vote on whether or not the boobs were excessive in their recent comics, but in order to vote, you have to give them the back pages of three issues from the last year to prove that you're actually a reader.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's like, "Great.
Scott: Let's ask the people who read the titty comics if they want more titty comics,".
Scott: you know?
Scott: But, I mean, you know, the Gomer Gates is the same deal.
Scott: It's like, "Hey, you know, you video game companies, you keep making the games that we insular group of bros want," you know?
Scott: And it's like, "Don't make games for anyone else but us, bros.
Scott: Stop growing your audience.
Scott: Just service us.
Scott: Service our niche only," you know?
Scott: "Oh, my God, animes.
Scott: Why do you keep making moe shows that only otakas want to watch instead of making animes that everyone wants to watch, like Ghost in the Shell?
Scott: Why?".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is the same problem.
Scott: You can find it everywhere in all geekeries.
Scott: You can even find it in, like, fucking car companies.
Scott: "Hey, car company, make a car that, you know, with a manual transmission that us car people really want to drive.
Scott: No, don't make a Toyota Camry.
Scott: No.".
Rym: [ Laughs ].
Rym: So, things of the day.
Rym: I'm gonna cop out.
Rym: I'm making my anime music video my thing of the day because my anime is --.
Scott: You can't make your own thing a thing of the day.
Rym: Totally fucking can.
Scott: That's metamoment.
Scott: It's not thing of the day.
Rym: That's the thing of the day.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: You failed.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That was the worst.
Scott: Without -- I don't even need to look at the history.
Scott: Worse thing -- Even worse than the time you had no thing of the day, and I had two just last week or whatever is your worst thing of the day ever.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: Regardless of the quality of your music video --.
Rym: What is the rule of the things of the day?
Scott: You move something from metamoment to thing of the day.
Rym: But, Scott, did --.
Scott: That is the ultimate fail.
Rym: Did I make this for GeekNights?
Rym: Is it a geek?
Rym: - No.
Rym: It's mine.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: It's not GeekNights.
Rym: It's just me.
Rym: It's Rym.
Scott: Doesn't matter.
Scott: All right, fine.
Rym: So, here's an alternate thing of the day.
Scott: A real thing of the day.
Rym: Your little baby.
Rym: Here is how to cook shrimps in three seconds with a shrimp gun, a butter gun, a tempera, like, flake gun, and a fire gun.
Scott: Would you eat that shrimp?
Rym: Yes, because I've eaten raw shrimp.
Rym: So I would totally eat this shrimp.
Scott: No, but, I mean, it's not -- I mean, you're willing to eat it, but, like, do you want to eat it?
Rym: Kind of.
Scott: I would prefer to eat a properly prepared shrimp.
Rym: I think that there is a market for restaurants that prepare food in this manner.
Scott: Yes, it is a spectacle.
Scott: You will pay to see it.
Scott: Just like I was at Stu Leonard's over the weekend.
Scott: They had a thing that was, like, popping out tortillas, like, pop, pop, this weird, cool machine to make you go, "Ooh," and be interested.
Scott: But those tortillas didn't taste any different from any other one.
Rym: So, I would eat these shrimps.
Rym: It's a really cool video.
Scott: It's a good video.
Scott: Much better video than food.
Scott: So, I got a very good thing of the day that is very simple and Zen-like.
Scott: It is just a tweet with a photo in it.
Scott: Really, the photo is the thing of the day.
Scott: It's some baby stingrays, one of the best animals that exist on Earth.
Rym: Pretty good.
Scott: Definitely better than human.
Scott: Yeah, baby stingray.
Scott: You ever wonder what they look like when they're tiny?
Scott: They're even tinier than Mantic, the Pokémon.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: That's a stingray Pokémon.
Rym: It's actually way more adorable than you're imagining.
Scott: Is there a difference between a stingray and a manta?
Scott: Or are they just different kinds of the same thing?
Rym: Like, there's Calrays.
Rym: There's a bunch of different kinds of rays.
Scott: Are they all rays?
Rym: I don't know the full nomenclature.
Rym: Manta.
Scott: I think they're all rays.
Rym: Ray.
Rym: Yeah, but what level of binomial nomenclature is the ray?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And where did the word "ray" come from?
Rym: Ayanami.
Scott: This is a different kind of ray.
Rym: So, in the meta moment, some guy named Rin made an anime music video, but that's the thing of the day.
Scott: That's a perfectly fine meta moment.
Rym: It's not a meta thing about GeekNights, so we can't talk about it here.
Rym: Hopefully, we're gonna be at PAX South coming up in a couple months.
Rym: Kinetica and panel submissions are secretly open, but we're not publicizing it super much yet, but you can go ahead and submit.
Rym: Probably be making more official announcements about it in the near future.
Rym: We're probably gonna be at PAX East.
Rym: Probably gonna be in Anime Boston.
Rym: We have a bunch of shit on the internet, and I've started uploading a bunch of stuff, and I will have many more videos soon, from my appearance at PAX Australia.
Rym: I uploaded a very short bit.
Rym: That's just me talking about Shadowgate.
Rym: Death.
Rym: And I have a little bit I'm gonna upload later about Gone Home and how it's not a game and how actually it is a game and the people who say it's not a game are assholes.
Scott: Well, it's definitely not an orthogame.
Rym: You know what it is?
Rym: It's an interactive amusement.
Rym: It's entertainment software.
Rym: It is entertainment software.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That is what it is.
Rym: I have this whole bit where I'm like...
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It doesn't really... People just get hung up on the no true Scotsman.
Scott: Like, you say something's not a game, and they act like you're anti-Scotsmanning.
Scott: it when it's like the category of a thing has no bearing on the quality of the thing.
Rym: Yep, but simultaneously... -You can say tic-tac-toe.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: Tic-tac-toe is a game.
Scott: That doesn't make it fucking good.
Scott: It's still garbage.
Scott: Gone Home, not a game.
Scott: Still really good.
Rym: Simultaneously, a lot of people get really mad when...
Scott: Marching band, not a sport.
Rym: People say things are not a game because actually they just don't like that thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The same way that you... Most people are making the fallacy of no true Scotsman.
Scott: I'm not making that fallacy, but I am assumed to be making it because I'm saying the same exact words that some moron says.
Rym: Except it is a game, because "petty cake" is a game.
Scott: By one definition?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: By basically all non-Grognard definitions, "petty cake" is a game.
Rym: But anyway, you can watch these videos to see what the fuck we're on about right now.
Rym: The book is Watership Down.
Rym: It was delightful.
Rym: I read it.
Rym: I can't believe I'd read this book sooner.
Rym: You should all read it.
Rym: Scott probably hasn't started it yet.
Rym: I've moved on to reading a couple other books while I wait for him to finish it.
Scott: Like what?
Rym: Bunch of novels.
Rym: Which one?
Rym: So right now, I'm actually reading a long essay on basically the Bhopal industrial disaster.
Scott: So not a bunch of novels.
Rym: Yeah, I got novels queued up.
Rym: So you just lied.
Rym: No, I got novels queued up, too, -but this essay is really fascinating.
Scott: Yeah, you know how many novels I got queued up?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: Actually, I just bought a bunch of really bad... Well, I assume really bad novels.
Rym: Oh, great.
Scott: There was a mega sale going on.
Scott: So for like almost no money, I bought all the novels that are related to the Android/Netrunner/Infiltration universe.
Scott: So you're reading Android slash?
Scott: No, I didn't read any of them.
Scott: And they're not fan fiction.
Scott: They're official fiction.
Scott: But I haven't read even one page of those either.
Scott: I'm not going to anytime soon, but I got them.
Scott: So I can wield them as deadly weapons.
Rym: And of course, look at all our shit on forums and YouTubes and everything.
Rym: Our forum has been really rocking lately, and you should go poke around in there.
Scott: The forum cost me a lot of money.
Rym: There's also a funny thing.
Rym: A Gomer Gator came in and was like, "I'm trying to actually argue on behalf of Gomer Gate, because I'm not...".
Rym: But then... And a bunch of people, like I got some PMs from people and like, "Oh, we really want to argue and be earnest,
Rym: whatever.".
Rym: And then our good friend Andrew posted in the forum a link to a Gomer Gate web page where they basically like infiltrate forums and do this thing.
Rym: And it was like, "Wow,
Rym: really?".
Rym: And then suddenly all those people stop posting.
Rym: Yeah, Gomer Gate's dumb.
Rym: I only say this now in the meta moment, because three people got really mad when I made fun of Gomer Gate via an Utena video.
Rym: And I couldn't believe that there were people who were fans of us, like legit fans.
Rym: I know that.
Rym: I mean, they subscribe to me on YouTube.
Rym: They watch like all our stuff that comes out on YouTube.
Rym: I guess they've never actually listened to our show.
Rym: And they definitely didn't follow me on Twitter or else they would have known that I didn't respect them.
Rym: And they rage quit GeekNights, as far as I can tell.
Rym: And I feel like that was a good thing.
Scott: So if there's any Gomer Gate people out there now, please rage quit GeekNights.
Scott: We don't want you.
Scott: I just wanted to make it clear.
Scott: Even better, prove to us that you are worthy, you are a respectful, quality human being and change your ways.
Rym: And if not, well, good day, sir.
Scott: Get the fuck out of here.
Scott: I got time for your bullshit.
Rym: So Scott handed me this manga.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: The vertical, which is a seems to only publish amazing mangas in the United States.
Scott: Yeah, they've pretty much never published anything bad ever.
Scott: As far as I can tell, they had a manga coming out called Prophecy.
Scott: And I ordered volume one, probably based on the fact that they are publishing it, the low price and the cover and the description that I don't remember because that's all I had to go on in my preorder.
Scott: And then, of course, it sat in the pile of unread comics, as did every other comic that I bought recently.
Scott: And then I had to fill out the comic order form because, you know, even though I'm not reading comics still buying them by a lot less than I bought before.
Scott: I'm buying like less than $50 worth.
Scott: I used to buy like a hundred and fifty dollars.
Rym: I'm not playing games, but I'm still buying them.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I'm going to read them soon.
Scott: I'm getting into comics reading mood, especially with the cold darkness.
Scott: So I'm going through the comic order form and I see Prophecy two and it seems interesting.
Scott: And I'm like, what's that about?
Scott: And then I'm like, wait, did I order Prophecy one?
Scott: And yes, I did.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: I feel very vindicated now for the fact that more than once I've gone to steam said, oh, that game's on sale, tried to buy it and find out that I already seen that as a better job of telling you what you've already bought.
Rym: Yes, probably because people keep trying to buy things.
Scott: because so I'm like, I need to know whether or not I should buy Prophecy to let me go read Prophecy one.
Scott: So I went through the pile and found Prophecy one and my long lost lanyard.
Rym: Did you buy Prophecy two?
Scott: And I read Prophecy one to figure out if I should buy Prophecy two.
Rym: So did you buy Prophecy to that?
Rym: That'll tell us the most about the review that we're about to give.
Scott: Yeah, pre-order Prophecy two.
Rym: OK, I was hoping you did because otherwise I you'd be going to some cancellations.
Rym: So I don't know anything about the Magica.
Scott: I knew nothing about this whatsoever other than the description in the cover and the name and the publisher.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So pretty much what it's about is what if a 4chan type decided to become a terrorist and simultaneously listen to all those episodes on GeekNights about how to effectively be an evil person.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like this weird combination.
Scott: You've sort of got the police action of ghosts in the shell, like procedural police drama, but the police aren't strictly the good guys.
Rym: But the protagonist is definitely not a good guy either.
Scott: No, there aren't a lot of good guys here at all.
Rym: You know, there's one good guy that the one photographer with the funny face who's just like, she's a pretty lady.
Scott: That's not a good guy.
Rym: Keep saying it, though.
Rym: That's the best guy.
Scott: So the obvious pit boy is yes.
Rym: Well, I saw the mascot of the Internet Cafe.
Rym: Is that Pip-Boy?
Rym: And then two pages later, yep.
Scott: Well, no, there's another obvious good guy, the foreign guy who worked at the Pip-Boy and died.
Rym: Well, good guy or just tragic guy.
Scott: But I mean, he's not a bad guy.
Scott: There is nothing bad about that guy.
Scott: Every other character, there's something bad about them.
Rym: Yeah, that is true.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even the punk.
Scott: It's like it opens up introducing like the police characters by having them solve, you know, sort of like this other unrelated crime to the main story.
Scott: They set it up as many, many, many police things do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Batman catches some like just random thugs before the rest of the Joker plot is introduced.
Scott: It's sort of that kind of deal.
Scott: But the guy that these police catch right away, some punk kid who is pirating video games.
Scott: And on the one hand, you start off, of course, you know, being someone sympathizing with the kid, pirating the video games, thinking the police are bad.
Rym: But then the kid is like Super 4chan.
Scott: Yeah, the kid is a super piece of shit.
Scott: So you're sort of like, wow, bad cops arresting bad kid.
Scott: I don't really care.
Rym: But then the cops, like especially the lady cop, they go above and beyond being dicks.
Rym: Yes, like she is a super ultra dick, but the kids sort of deserves it.
Rym: But well, the kids a little shit.
Rym: So it's like a little shit, right?
Scott: The crime.
Scott: It's like, I don't think, you know, obviously stands on piracy are the problem of the reason that you feel conflicted about this.
Scott: If the kid had committed some other crime, like shoplifting, you'd be like, fuck that kid up.
Rym: But that was.
Rym: what's interesting is almost right away.
Rym: Like you see a picture of an R4 cartridge and I'm like, wait a minute.
Rym: That's a real thing.
Rym: And then they start talking about it.
Rym: And then I realized that this is taking a reasonably, in fact, a surprisingly reasonably realistic approach to the things it's doing.
Scott: Yeah, everything that happens in this manga is like 100% modern day technology realism.
Scott: There's nothing supernatural.
Scott: or how do you pull off his crime?
Rym: Like not a super spoiler, like a guy basically is uploading videos via a tunnel from one net and one net cafe to another net cafe.
Rym: And there's a big thing like, how do you break our encryption?
Rym: We've got a one time pad system.
Rym: We've got like that RSA dongle.
Scott: And by some convoluted way that's revealed, he got one of those dongles.
Rym: He's just got one of the dongles.
Rym: That's that's how that works.
Scott: Yeah, like he didn't crack some ridiculous encryption with God hacking powers.
Rym: Yup, that's how you break those things.
Rym: And what's interesting is that there's no other than the person who, the person in the past, that poor immigrant guy, who is sort of the genesis of the rest of this.
Rym: No one is really a sympathetic character.
Rym: The guy doing the terror is kind of a vengeful piece of shit.
Scott: Yeah, no, he's definitely, it's just vigilante justice.
Scott: And some of the justices he's fighting for are clearly injustices.
Rym: But some of them are like, so you're like you're feeling good.
Scott: on the one hand that like, yeah, justice is being served on to people that otherwise would not have justice served on to them that deserve it.
Rym: Like he goes after a guy.
Scott: He's dispensing justice that is far more harsh than it should be.
Rym: Like on one hand, he goes over the, you know, the sexual predator guy.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And like, you know what?
Rym: Not super broken up about what happened to that guy.
Scott: No, I mean, not anymore broken up than you'd be about, you know, Batman beating the shit out of people who are just stealing some jewelry.
Rym: But then he had, but then he basically beats the guy mostly to death with a baseball bat.
Rym: And as far as I can tell, was that the guy who was just mean to a nerd at his job?
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And there's definitely this undercurrent of like, it seems to be that the story is going in the direction of this guy committing these crimes, basically causes this sort of second order simulator goes to the shell kind of thing.
Rym: But it's among 4chan or gamer gator pieces of shit.
Rym: Like they're the people, the downtrodden, awkward, that guys are the ones who are rising up and they're using 4chan technology to commit acts of terror.
Scott: And the cops are going after him.
Scott: So you're sort of like, go cops, but the cops are pieces of shit.
Scott: Like the kind of like Ferguson kind of cops.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you're not.
Scott: And it's sort of fascinating to watch the shit go down.
Rym: I kind of like the aspect that I'm not rooting for anyone at all in this.
Rym: So I'm just reading it like, well, let's just see where this goes.
Scott: It's like you're rooting.
Scott: It's like the character that is the good guy.
Scott: is society, right?
Scott: And you're seeing like the dregs, the dregs of society, like all the bad parts just like set each other on fire.
Scott: And you're like, God, I hope all these people dies at the rest of society can be clean of them.
Rym: But in one way, I'm glad that this it's taking a surprisingly nuanced approach because if you could easily make the story be the smart internet kid is able to right social wrongs and change the world because old people can't keep up technology technology all that stuff.
Rym: But at the same time the kinds of people like say you and me who could easily do those sorts of things aren't amoral and evil like light Oh types now.
Rym: And on the other hand the cops they could be the good guys, but in the real world cops often aren't the good guys.
Scott: Yeah, good thing your product Death Note, right?
Scott: So, you know, there is a Death Note aspect to this of the cops procedurally trying to find, you know, the bad guys and you know, they're really actually quite clever these cops.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, as opposed to like L is a hundred percent good guy.
Scott: You just a little weird, right?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's the key difference here, right?
Scott: You also the be you know, the bad the terrorist guys are not doing, you know, they're not sort of like having this battle of minds with each other.
Scott: He's just sort of using his method that he's always used and continuing to use it and not changing anything about his method.
Rym: and he's also not by any stretch of genius.
Rym: He's like there's a great scene where the these other kind of uneducated people he's talking to or like, oh my God, that's crazy math.
Rym: You're doing what are you a genius?
Rym: And he's like guys.
Rym: that's like 11th grade math.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like some uber hacker.
Rym: It's just a person who knows how to use computers, but at the same time a person who knows how to use computers is by the standards of modern society and uber hacker.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: I mean the things that the hacking is really realistic.
Rym: That's like this kid.
Rym: However, it's not neo.
Rym: Yes, but at the same time like he's not he's making the kinds of mistakes that like if Scott or I were doing a similar thing, we would not have made like the camera thing.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's it's cool to just see something that's, you know, so tied to the real world in the present that I'm also
Rym: very topical
Scott: topic that you can relate to a lot, but at the same time has so many, you know, standard plots of high quality animes that we like otherwise, like Ghost in the Shell Death Note Etc.
Scott: All tied together.
Rym: Now the art is super generic.
Rym: I've literally nothing to say about the art.
Scott: I mean, it just looks like, you know, sort of a, you know, the more realistic kind of manga style, like closer to Urasawa, although not even like I was going to say five quality levels lower.
Scott: It's definitely a shadow of Urasawa like in terms of framing, It's the same, you know, it's that same realistic human beings real world style.
Scott: It's just the quality level.
Scott: I mean, it's not bad.
Scott: It's not like we're not saying Attack on Titan.
Scott: It's just unremarkable, right?
Scott: It's it gets the job done, you know, it's not like you're going to get prints from this or want sketches from the artist or anything.
Scott: Yeah, it's just a manga.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's really about the story.
Rym: It's like the writing in The Hunger Games.
Rym: It's not great writing, but it's a hundred percent serviceable writing that gets the story across without pissing me off.
Rym: Yeah, perfectly adequate.
Rym: Pretty much.
Rym: And the only real bad thing I can say about it is that a lot of the dialogue is really sort of that cliche.
Rym: This is a procedural drama about a thing.
Rym: So we're going to explain the thing to people who are like, it's almost like it's written for people who don't know what an r4 cartridge is.
Rym: Yeah, and don't know about like tunneling and RSA keys.
Rym: So there's a lot of like, hey, I'm cop number one.
Rym: What's that thing?
Scott: Oh, that's in technology.
Scott: in case the reader of this manga doesn't know it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Oh, that is something that they use to copy game data that blah, blah, blah, whole history of the r4 cartridge in Japan.
Rym: That that text is a little annoying and tedious to read.
Scott: But only because, you know, if you didn't know, right, think about this.
Scott: You're in a cooking manga and they're like, what is that saffron?
Scott: Well, saffron is actually this piece of this flower.
Scott: And it's very expensive.
Rym: And you and I are like, oh, man, saffron.
Rym: And a chef is like, oh, God, I know all about saffron.
Scott: Jesus Christ, don't give me a saffron lesson.
Scott: Just get to the golden rice and the tears up.
Rym: So thus, I'm not going to say that that is a deep flaw by any stretch, because I would rather that happen than the actual underlying thing they're talking about be portrayed just wrong.
Scott: Yes, it's all correct.
Scott: Like the story of the R4 cartridge is the correct story.
Scott: They don't say anything wrong about it.
Scott: And so if you're someone who doesn't know a lot about these things, this can actually be mildly educational and that it won't necessarily like make you a computer expert any more than Hajime No Ippo will let you beat Mike Tyson in the real world or anything like that.
Scott: But you will learn things about computers in real life that are true.
Scott: If you read this manga.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: So I clicked.
Rym: There's 12 posts about the fact that this was coming out on anime news network.
Rym: So I clicked on it just to see if anyone had said anything.
Rym: You may look at this talk back page, but please consider that this article is one year, two months old before posting.
Rym: OK, I feel like that there is a problem.
Rym: So what are the?
Scott: what are the comments about this manga on it?
Rym: Wait, I thought they didn't license Shueisha titles.
Rym: Sounds great.
Rym: Glad verticals doing this.
Rym: Looking forward to this.
Scott: Yeah, that is interesting vertical.
Scott: One of the things they don't like.
Rym: We can, but this isn't a Shueisha title.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: But is it in Jump X?
Rym: It is.
Scott: But isn't Jump X Shueisha?
Rym: So I'm actually poking around.
Rym: I'm getting conflicting information about this manga.
Scott: This is very interesting.
Rym: Japanese movie.
Rym: There's a movie coming the next year.
Scott: Oh, that movie will probably be interesting.
Rym: I learned that.
Rym: So the only actual source of information on this seems to be the French Wikipedia.
Scott: Is it French movie?
Rym: Prophecy, manga et retortant.
Scott: The prophecy of the manga.
Rym: But we're not sure.
Rym: An internet anime.
Rym: Anonym.
Rym: Enfublue du mascot du coup d'un, du papier journale.
Rym: Qui annoucez des prophecy.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Prophecy.
Rym: No, prophetez.
Rym: Prophetez.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm not sure what, like, usually a title like prophecy.
Scott: Pretty generic title.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I can't see anything in here about any prophecy whatsoever.
Rym: Well, notice he prophesized it.
Rym: Basically, he says, this crime will occur.
Rym: Oh, he's prophesying his own crimes.
Rym: He wears the newspaper as a mask, right?
Rym: On the current day.
Scott: So you know that he, right?
Scott: What day?
Rym: Basically, what the guy's doing to give you guys, he, he uploads a video to YouTube that he just recorded a little while ago of him saying, this crime is going to occur.
Rym: Like, right, like real soon.
Scott: And he says, why?
Scott: He's like, justice is going to come down in this person because they fucked up.
Scott: And they'll fuck up the way they fucked up or you'll get the same done to you.
Rym: And then like within an hour, like before the police could even react, the crime he prophesized occurs, right?
Scott: Like he records the warning video, sets it to upload and sets it to publish, like right before the crime is about to happen.
Scott: And then he does the crime, like as the video is like made public on YouTube.
Rym: So I suspect that what's going to start happening is that this is just a guess.
Rym: I haven't, I've only read the first volume.
Rym: I would not be surprised if eventually he makes videos, prophesizing a crime, doesn't have to do anything.
Rym: Some anonymous rando then goes and commits the crime.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: I think that's where this is going.
Rym: And this doesn't, like the manga doesn't shock me because this is like kind of baby's first, this idea.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's nothing in here that's like surprising or new.
Scott: It's just a decent execution of things that I like.
Rym: Well, and if you're not fit, like if you read this and this seems all kind of scary or like dangerous.
Rym: Seriously guys in our professional opinions, this stuff is a hundred percent plausible.
Rym: I'm actually really, really surprised that something like this has not already happened.
Scott: Kind of has sort of not, not on any wide scale.
Rym: Not, I mean, it's kind of petered out.
Rym: No one's done something crazy.
Scott: Imagine if gamer gators were told to Rob game stops instead of being told to, you know, send rape threats.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: But black dynamite, you already robbed the game.
Scott: Stop.
Rym: Why?
Rym: I think we're done here.
Rym: It's I don't want, we're not going to just read it.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: It's not great, but it's perfectly good.
Rym: Manga.
Rym: It's new cheap.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: There's nothing else like it in English that I know of.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: For the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.