Rym: It's Monday, December 1st, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Buying computers for other people.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So in New York, we know it's a lot better idea to have a company manage your rent and building than have a person.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Like some landlord.
Rym: I really like the fact that my landlord is a faceless and uncaring entity.
Scott: So my company was pretty good.
Scott: But sometime earlier this year, what happened was they would send me an envelope every month to send my rent in.
Scott: And one month I didn't get the envelope, so I couldn't send my rent.
Scott: I had to figure out how to send it some other way.
Rym: I love how despite being the greatest city in the world, you basically can't pay your rent except with checks.
Scott: Yeah, so I called them and I was like, "Hey, can we work on some kind of auto
Scott: pay?".
Scott: But it resulted in I paid a rent late because I couldn't send it on time because they fucked up.
Scott: But they refused to waive the late fee, so I basically lost 70 bucks because they fucked up.
Scott: And I'm like, "Well, fuck, it's not worth
Scott: it.".
Rym: Wow, 70?
Rym: My late fee is $15.
Scott: Right, so yeah, fuck those guys.
Scott: But anyway, after that, I was paying on time.
Scott: Everything went back to normal.
Scott: But fuck them, I want my 70 bucks back.
Rym: Still in small claims court.
Scott: Well, I switched and I went to my bank and I said, "Hey, bank, can you just mail them a check every
Scott: month?".
Rym: I tried that once.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: That's why our landlord in Beacon was so pissed off at us all the time.
Rym: Because it never fucking worked.
Scott: This actually worked when I did it.
Scott: But there was a problem.
Scott: You see, in August, the payment went out in late August for the September rent.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And it went out as normal.
Scott: And up until then, it had been working fine.
Scott: And it did work fine.
Scott: I can see in my thing that the check made it and cleared.
Rym: So they cashed it?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now they say they didn't cash it, right?
Scott: Two days after that, that check was sent by my bank.
Scott: I got a letter under the door that was like, "Management company's changing.
Scott: Send rents to this new
Scott: place.".
Scott: The new place apparently did not hear word of that rent, even though it was cashed.
Scott: But the new place is actually, even though they fucked up the laundry room, you can just go to their website and pay online and go to their website and complain and go to their website and whatever you need to do.
Scott: Even though it's sort of an old, cruddy, bad restaurant website, it works.
Rym: Wow, that's actually more than I have in my laundry building here.
Scott: I actually used that website to be like, "Hey, my fire alarm needs some
Scott: help.".
Scott: They came and fixed it right a fucking way.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: It was amazing.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: Wait, how'd they fuck up your laundry room?
Scott: They switched the machines out to a different company to manage the machines.
Scott: that charges more money and makes you use a really annoying smart card system instead of quarters.
Rym: I would kill for a smart card system no matter how annoying.
Scott: But now it's 75 cents more per washing machine.
Rym: What do you pay?
Rym: For me, it's $3.25 for the gigantic fucking... I can literally put every towel I own in there.
Scott: I was paying $1.25, now I'm paying $2.
Rym: Oh, it's $1.25 for our tank?
Scott: It's now cheaper for me to just go to the laundry lady and have her do everything for me.
Scott: Except for laundry.
Scott: I don't want to give them.
Scott: Anyway, so the machine is... The payment, the smart card is just annoying the way it works.
Scott: It's even worse than RIT flex money or whatever.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I remember RIT flex money.
Scott: Yeah, so the company is mostly good, as usual, as expected from a company.
Scott: But they seem to have fucked up.
Scott: Even though every single month I have made one rent payment every single month, this month they're like, "You owe twice as
Scott: much.".
Scott: And I'm like, "What the fuck are you talking
Scott: about?".
Scott: If I pay twice as much, I expect to not pay again until late January for February's rent.
Scott: And they're like, "Here's a record of all the payments you have sent
Scott: us.".
Scott: And I have sent them, the new company so far, three payments.
Scott: I sent them a payment in September for October.
Scott: A payment in October for November.
Scott: And... No, I said... September, October, November.
Rym: November for December?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I sent a payment in November for December.
Scott: Fascinating.
Scott: I'm trying to send the payment in November for December, you see, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But they have accounted it such to where that payment that I sent in August to the old company, right, they do not have record of that.
Scott: And they thought that that was an August payment.
Scott: So the payment that I sent them in September for October, they considered to be...
Rym: So my only question to you is, has this resulted in a phone conversation with a human yet?
Scott: No, I'm just emailing them instead.
Scott: You can choose on their website how you want to talk.
Rym: Alright, emailing's better.
Scott: So I chose email, so I have documentation.
Scott: But it's just like, I just sent the email that was like, "Uh, here...".
Scott: I think yesterday I sent the email that was like, "Uh, why is my rent
Scott: double?".
Scott: And then just now I sent the letter that was like, "I think you fucked up.
Scott: Why is everything...".
Rym: It's funny that you have this problem, because just now our rent for December came, the little slip.
Rym: So I'm like, alright, I guess it's my turn, so I'll pay it, because I'm the one I kind of semi-alternate on who pays it, just whatever.
Rym: And I open it up, and I owed like over $6,000, because they didn't... They said that I owed this next month, December, and I'm late on October.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: November, November.
Rym: God, we're bad with months.
Rym: I think we're getting old.
Rym: So Emily's like, "I paid it, and sure enough, we have a photo of the check.
Rym: Like, we mailed it.
Rym: They didn't cash
Rym: it.".
Rym: So the trouble is, the last time that happened to me, like years ago, I remember like calling these people multiple times and being like, "You didn't get the check.
Rym: You didn't get the check.
Rym: Do not cash the check.
Rym: If you get it, I'm going to send you another
Rym: one.".
Rym: And of course, I mailed them another check.
Rym: They then immediately, like within hours, cashed the check.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's a person whose job it is, basically just open checks and stamp them and put them in.
Scott: They don't think about them or care or have any like little list of like, "If you see this check, don't use
Scott: it.".
Rym: Yeah, the problem is, one, it cost me a lot of money to cancel a check, and two, I learned something.
Rym: Cancelled checks are only cancelled for up to at most a year.
Rym: So they're not actually cancelled forever.
Scott: So if someone gives me a check, and they cancel it on me.
Rym: Eventually, the cancel expires unless they paid or renew it with most banks.
Scott: So you write me a check.
Scott: I go to the bank.
Scott: The bank's like, "We ain't doing this.
Scott: It got
Scott: cancelled.".
Scott: They give me the check back.
Rym: Wait a few years.
Rym: Yeah, they give the check back usually.
Scott: And then I wait a few years, then go use it again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then it'll work.
Rym: That is what my bank told me when I asked them about this.
Scott: All right.
Rym: And I was like, "Yeah, I'm not going to cancel the check.
Rym: I'll just sue my landlord and small claims court if it comes to it.
Rym: That will be
Rym: easier.".
Scott: So I wonder what's going to happen here.
Scott: I want to try to resolve it with this company as much as possible and not have to resort to other measures.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The thing is, I've been itching.
Rym: I kind of want to go to small claims court.
Rym: But every time I've threatened someone with that, the situation has resolved amicably among adults.
Rym: So I guess I need to get into a conflict with someone where I not only have documentation that I'm correct and that they owe me verifiable damages, but where that person is not an adult.
Rym: But also not a minor by age.
Rym: They need to be above 18, yet not actually act like an adult.
Rym: And somehow have gotten into a situation where they owe me money.
Rym: I don't think that is likely to ever happen to me in my life.
Rym: So I got a bunch of news here.
Rym: It's Monday.
Rym: We're finally back from Thanksgiving.
Rym: I had way too much food and still reeling from the consequences.
Scott: I still have extra food.
Rym: I have extra farts.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I have lots of farts too.
Rym: Yeah, I have a surplus of farts if anyone would like to borrow some.
Rym: We also had multiple Thanksgivings.
Scott: You should play the South Park game.
Scott: A lot of farting going on.
Rym: So there's a story here about, you know, it's politics, but Scott and I, and you at least should be, are mad about gerrymandering.
Rym: Or gerrymandering if you know how that guy's name was pronounced.
Scott: Yeah, how's your animated gif going over there?
Rym: Yeah, but it is Eldridge Gary.
Rym: So anyway, we're mad about it and a bunch of scientists, a bunch of mathematicians, decided to try to apply technological solutions to this.
Rym: They started studying gerrymandering and studying.
Scott: We should study to see if the gerrymandering they do is even optimal.
Scott: Like if you wanted to be evil, could you be even more evil than they are now?
Rym: So they basically proved that gerrymandering as it is done now does not just wash out and evenly corrupt.
Rym: It's actually really biased toward Republicans.
Rym: And two, it kind of shows.
Scott: So why don't Democrats undo it?
Rym: They can't because Republicans control the state legislatures that make these decisions.
Rym: So basically the Republicans got control right before the Census in 2010 and as a result they'll basically have control until the demographics are so skewed Democrat that even maximum gerrymandering can't get them in office anymore.
Rym: I'm going to quote something from this, but basically they tried different simulations and models.
Rym: Like they do a thing where run every possible combination of district lines and figure out the most crazy things you could do based on the actual votes.
Rym: Like that kind of stuff.
Rym: "The results were startling.
Rym: After rerunning the election a hundred times with a randomly drawn nonpartisan map each time, the average simulated election result was seven or eight House seats for the Democrats and five or six for the Republicans.
Rym: The maximum number of Republican seats that emerged from any of the simulations was eight.
Rym: The actual outcome of that election was four Democrats and nine Republicans, which is statistically impossible.
Rym: It's not likely to
Rym: occur.".
Scott: So they're really, really good at gerrymandering.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: That's surprising.
Scott: I thought they would find that they weren't good at gerrymandering and could have done an even more corrupt job.
Rym: No, they're amazing at gerrymandering.
Scott: Who is doing this gerrymandering?
Scott: It's like the representative is sitting there drawing maps.
Scott: Well,
Rym: actually it turns out they do just drag and draw it manually because it's really easy to figure it out because basically people who tend to vote Democrat or third parties that aren't Libertarians, like Green Party, they live in tightly packed urban districts and everybody else is spread out among thinly packed conservative districts.
Rym: So it's actually really easy to gerrymander.
Rym: But it has to be active because if it's random, it doesn't occur, even in extensive simulation.
Rym: The reason I bring this up is one, it's easy to be mad about political things, but if you want to be really mad about politics, we need verifiable, scientific, objective, quantifiable politics.
Scott: Well, at least if it's a democracy.
Scott: Only a democracy has math.
Rym: It's kind of like what Lawrence Lessig's trying to do with that secretary.
Scott: Other types of government do not have math.
Scott: A king doesn't use the numbers.
Scott: The only number a king needs is one.
Scott: I'm the king.
Scott: Deal with it.
Rym: Well, the Soviets had to count how many boots they said they made.
Scott: That's economics, not politics.
Rym: The politics, they would say how many boots they made, thus pushing the politics forward.
Scott: Sure, but democracy is not capitalism.
Rym: But look at Lawrence Lessig's thing.
Rym: The Super PAC failed to achieve a lot of the results it wanted in the election, but they gathered empirical data and are going to attempt to use that data to come up with models of how to effectively intervene.
Scott: Move.
Scott: Everyone move, and they can't move the district faster than we can move our butts.
Rym: Should we move to a red state district in the middle of nowhere and vote Democrat?
Scott: Are a thousand other nerds moving with us?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Is there internet out there?
Scott: Will we be able to bring enough nerds to set up internet out there?
Rym: I think the chicken egg problem is pretty decidedly on.
Rym: Nerds won't go where there's not internet.
Scott: Google, build an office there or some shit.
Rym: So, the moral of this, everyone should read this, because regardless of your political affiliation, though if you're conservative, you're wrong, but regardless of your political affiliation, this is empirical evidence of straight-up objective corruption that is trivially fixed by the minimal application of technology.
Scott: Soccer?
Scott: Same thing?
Rym: Yeah, same thing.
Scott: I actually saw a soccer game this weekend, or at least a part of one, and the ref actually had a little wristwatch thing that told him when the ball went in the goal, and he used it, and he got a call right that he probably would have gotten wrong otherwise.
Rym: Scandal.
Rym: It's ruined football.
Scott: I know.
Rym: So, in other news, you know we talk a lot, you and me, about how as much as the U.S.
Rym: is bad about things, it's the least bad country in the world at regulating the internet.
Scott: It's not the least bad, but in terms of regulating internet, you can do a lot worse.
Rym: ICANN, ARPA level.
Rym: Regulating, like, interchanges.
Scott: Most of the countries on Earth, not all, but most, are worse than us in terms of internet censoring and such.
Rym: So the EU has once again proven why we can't let Europe have any control specifically.
Rym: With their anti-free speech.
Scott: Well, we already knew about their right to be forgotten, which is not a right.
Scott: Which they're making worse.
Rym: They're still fighting that.
Rym: When I have another news I'm not talking about.
Scott: Google should just give them the finger and be like, "Fuck you.
Scott: If you ask for the right to be forgotten, we'll increase your search rank.
Scott: Fuck you.
Scott: We don't have to do what you say.
Scott: Oh, you want to enforce it and make us enforce it in Europe only?
Scott: No Google for Europe.
Scott: Google's blocked in Europe.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: Go fuck
Rym: yourselves.".
Rym: The European Parliament, the EU, That's what they should do.
Rym: has voted in favor of forcing Google to be broken up.
Rym: As a solution to complaints that it favors-- To what?
Scott: A search company and a bunch of crappy worthless companies?
Rym: Yeah, I read the resolution.
Rym: They don't fucking know what they're talking about.
Scott: But it's not like Microsoft where you can be like, "Okay, we'll break apart the Xbox division, and we'll break apart the Office division and the Windows
Scott: division.".
Scott: It's Google.
Scott: All that makes fucking money for Google is search.
Scott: All the other things at Google are minuscule tiny garbage companies.
Rym: If you were going to break it up, I guess you could do-- Oh, no.
Scott: You could break Android off of Google, but Android doesn't really make any fucking money.
Rym: You could break YouTube out.
Rym: You could break Google search apps, all that stuff out separately.
Scott: YouTube can be a standalone company.
Rym: Those are three things.
Rym: And then advertising as a fourth thing.
Scott: But advertising and search are the same thing.
Rym: No, because if you say that, then YouTube and advertising are also the same thing.
Scott: They are.
Scott: The advertising is actually the only thing that makes money.
Rym: Yeah, but look at how they broke up the Ma Bell back in the day.
Scott: By geography.
Rym: Not just by geography, but also by business units.
Rym: So you'd basically have all these broken up pieces of companies doing business with each other just as separate companies instead of as divisions of the same company.
Scott: Oh, so the Google search company will just have an AdSense account like you and me.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Rym: It's stupid.
Rym: Luckily, even they realize that they have no power to enforce a breakup yet, but they're very happy with the vote.
Scott: And basically, the EU, the European Parliament-- Google, just stop serving anything to Europe.
Rym: Individual European countries in general have been repeatedly going after Google as a monopoly.
Scott: Because it's a U.S.
Scott: company.
Scott: If it was a European company, they'd be like,
Scott: "Weeee!".
Scott: They just don't like that.
Scott: some U.S.
Scott: company has such power over Europe.
Scott: They're all European and proud.
Rym: Back in the old days of Slashdot-- In the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: the same shit happened too.
Scott: Like, "Don't buy them Japanese
Scott: cars.".
Rym: In the old days, remember when Microsoft-- Nerds would be like, "Oh, Microsoft is a horrible monopoly.
Rym: They should be broken
Rym: up.".
Rym: Europe tried to break it up.
Scott: They were for like two minutes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, the only results of that were that web browsers, which were an integral part of operating systems in the modern era, had to be temporarily separated.
Rym: And it was kind of just a stupid disaster that didn't actually achieve anything.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, tech companies are often monopolies, right?
Scott: Google does have a search monopoly now.
Scott: There's no question.
Rym: What Bing exists.
Scott: Yeah, OK.
Scott: Apple sort of has some kind of monopoly-ish, or at least a duopoly.
Rym: It has a much larger market share and is growing faster at the expense of Apple.
Scott: That sucks.
Scott: It's some kind of duopoly.
Scott: Anyway, there's plenty of-- What-opoly?
Rym: They're the minority in every market.
Scott: Right, but those kinds of things-- Except, I guess, pads.
Scott: A company that has superior technology, right, can dominate an entire industry quite easily, as Windows has in the past, as Intel basically is, sort of, right?
Scott: And then they can wield power because of this.
Scott: Amazon can do this, right?
Scott: However, a technology company is easily thwarted by superior technology, which comes along from smaller companies.
Scott: That's the thing about technology.
Scott: A tiny company like Google, coming out of nowhere, was able to beat all these other search engines.
Scott: You could come out of nowhere and beat Facebook, right?
Scott: Facebook came out of nowhere and beat Myspace, which was unthinkable.
Rym: AOL is dead.
Rym: In Europe, at least.
Rym: Like, in the US, a scary number of people use Bing and use other search engines and stuff.
Scott: Sure, you don't need to use antitrust to bust up technology companies, at least software companies specifically, because that's cheap to make, unless they're in power for an incredibly long period of time and no one has any chance of unseating them and they're wielding their power in unfair ways.
Rym: Well, that's the thing.
Scott: You need to use your antitrust to bust up, say, Verizon.
Rym: So, Google has over 90% of the search market in Europe, which is their main concern, and a lot of local people in Europe specifically complain about Google's search results as being unfair or unfairly favoring...
Scott: Someone's always going to complain.
Scott: Whoever's not first will always complain.
Rym: I think search engine results should have basically the equivalent of common carrier protections, in that if you have an algorithm and the algorithm shows whatever search results, that's totally fine.
Scott: The real core of the problem is that the algorithm is secret, right?
Scott: And if it wasn't secret, people could game it, but while it is secret, you can't prove that it isn't rigged.
Rym: But who says you can't rig it?
Rym: Who says it should be illegal to rig it?
Rym: There's a first principle there.
Rym: What does rigging entail?
Scott: Because then it becomes... The phone book is an alphabetical order, right?
Scott: So is the yellow pages.
Scott: The yellow pages, you increase how much space you get by paying more money.
Rym: It would not be illegal to put a phone book in order by who paid the most.
Scott: No, it wouldn't be.
Scott: The yellow pages is exactly that.
Scott: But it is a transparent system.
Scott: You can't say you gave that guy preferential treatment and made his shit bigger for less money.
Rym: It's not illegal to give someone preferential treatment for less money.
Scott: It is if you're a common carrier.
Scott: You're supposed to treat everyone equally.
Scott: So if the search engine results are supposed to be treating everyone equally using the same algorithm, but you're just secretly arbitrarily making your own links way higher rank, that's not really fair.
Scott: Especially if it's your other businesses.
Scott: The thing about a monopoly that's illegal is using your monopoly power to help other shit out.
Scott: That's why Microsoft got in trouble.
Scott: They used their Windows monopoly to boost IE.
Rym: It's not just helping.
Rym: It's a little more narrow than that.
Rym: They have to provide a specifically unfair competitive advantage.
Scott: Right, so if Google ranks all YouTube results way high and down ranks other video sites results like Vimeo, that's an unfair advantage to YouTube.
Scott: if the Vimeo video is actually better for the same search query.
Scott: You can't prove that they're not because the algorithm is a secret.
Rym: Well except Scott, search for videos on Google video search and search for videos on YouTube.
Rym: There's a reason why no one uses Google's video search because the results are not nearly as good as the YouTube results.
Scott: No, yeah, but I'm saying if you do a search period just in regular Google, sometimes videos are results.
Rym: Right?
Scott: So what if there's a Vimeo video?
Scott: that's a better result and it's getting down ranked?
Scott: You wouldn't even know.
Scott: So even if Google is not doing that, they're not proving they're not doing that.
Rym: I don't think there's a moral problem there because I just don't care.
Scott: But people didn't care about Microsoft busting up IE.
Scott: I don't think there's a moral problem.
Rym: Actually a lot of people cared a lot about that very weirdly.
Scott: There's a legal problem there.
Rym: And actually I thought that busting the IE thing up was actually the worst possible way to go about that.
Rym: I think that was a mistake.
Scott: I think it was a mistake because the web browser was a free product.
Scott: It wasn't even a business.
Scott: But the video is a business.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time, I feel like with technology like search results, really the only way anyone should ever evaluate search results is by whether or not it achieves their personal goal.
Rym: And frankly, if someone doesn't care that the search results are skewed, I don't care either.
Scott: But even if you don't care that they are, it could even be on the level of racket.
Scott: To where Google's basically like, "You want to go to search results all day?
Scott: Better pay protection
Scott: fees.".
Rym: Except they don't have any business that lets you do that.
Scott: They don't, but for all you know, they could be doing that.
Scott: They could have partners, not like a web business that's on their site, but they could give preferential treatment to their partners and you wouldn't even know.
Rym: That activity, one, even if it were illegal, which arguably it probably actually isn't, could probably even still be caught through normal means without actually going after the search engine itself.
Scott: Sure, but we don't know.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: Because the algorithm is completely secret to anyone in the public, you basically, if you have a low rank, you assume because you're a conspiracy theory-minded nut that it's a racket.
Scott: And if you have a good result, you're like, "Oh,
Scott: okay.".
Rym: But again, because it's technology, because it's relatively easy to compete with technology if you have superior technology, and it's primarily just software, there are plenty of other search engines.
Scott: That all suck?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And, I mean, Bing pretty much gives you equivalent results.
Rym: It's not really better or worse for what most people search for.
Scott: I mean, for normal searches, like, "Oh, I forgot the name of that
Scott: website.".
Scott: Or, "What's the URL?
Scott: I remember everything about this page, but I forget the
Scott: URL.".
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: But if you actually need to research something, good luck.
Rym: But I feel like, technology-wise, I'm 100% okay with 100% black box searches, even if there's only one dominant provider, simply because, one, SEO people don't deserve jobs.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: And, two, they're mostly dead anyway.
Rym: If the results are actually unusable or are causing an actual problem, it would be trivial to then start competing with Google.
Rym: The only reason you wouldn't be able to compete with Google right now is because your "on paper better" search engine isn't actually better.
Scott: That's the other major problem, right?
Scott: I was just saying how someone with a tiny company, in software at least, can easily just make a better technology and compete with big boys, just like Facebook competed with Myspace.
Scott: I mean, a lot of super nerds use that.
Rym: There's that DuckDuckGo search that all the super nerds and varchanners use.
Scott: But the software of Google search is so ridiculously advanced that it would be -- it's the same reason.
Scott: no one compete with Photoshop, right?
Scott: It's just so hard to make any kind of competitor for that.
Scott: The effort required, you could never catch up to that.
Rym: Ah, but what I'm arguing is that if they were providing results based on some shady cabal that had the effect of making the search results less useful, then someone, by simply making search results that were actually useful, would beat them.
Rym: And if they're not making them less useful, then there's no way -- But it's still a shady cabal?
Rym: Well, it doesn't matter.
Scott: Well, maybe they're still the most useful of all the search engines, but could be more useful.
Scott: But they're not as useful as they could be, even though they're still the most useful because of a shady cabal.
Rym: But if they could be more useful, then there would be space for a competitor.
Scott: Ah, but that would be so difficult for the competitor to get into that space because Google is already so good.
Scott: Like, if Photoshop just sat still and left room for improvement, and we started to catch up, and then they just moved a little bit ahead and always stayed one step ahead of us, and we couldn't catch them just because they're so big and so awesome.
Scott: As opposed to what they're actually doing, which is update Photoshop constantly and stay way ahead of everybody.
Rym: Europe's answer to this perceived problem, which mostly rests around a lot of very specific and, in my opinion, really stupid complaints about the search results, are they want to break Google up because that's their solution to it.
Scott: Yes, I would like to break up a lot of European companies, too.
Scott: The U.S.
Scott: would love to break up Honda, Toyota, BMW, Volkswagen.
Scott: Oh, wouldn't that be so great?
Scott: Probably these American car companies.
Scott: Just bust up all these European and Japanese car companies.
Scott: One company per car, the Camry company, the Corolla company.
Scott: You can't share engineers with each other.
Scott: Yeah, that'd be great.
Scott: Every country wants to bust up all this country's shit.
Rym: Blackberry released a new smartphone.
Scott: Wait, Blackberry's still around?
Rym: Yeah, they have Passport smartphones now.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: They call them the Passport.
Scott: What does it look like?
Rym: I'm pulling up a picture of it right now.
Rym: I'm trying to pull up a picture of it right now.
Rym: Still trying to pull up, wow, the Blackberry side.
Rym: Here we go.
Scott: It's a square Blackberry.
Rym: They're really fat and they have a square screen.
Scott: Well, they're not fat thick, they're fat wide.
Rym: Fat wide.
Scott: But they're not tall.
Scott: No.
Scott: Even though they just said they sacrifice.
Scott: Oh, no, look at that picture.
Rym: That's still taller than my phone.
Rym: That's really tall.
Scott: It's not that tall.
Rym: It's basically a tablet with a low resolution screen and an awful looking physical keyboard.
Scott: So it looks like you can hold it in your hand.
Rym: That's not the news.
Scott: It's a one handed feeling.
Rym: Blackberry is, this is literally, as far as I can say, their last gasp.
Rym: They will give you cash if you trade your iPhone in for a Passport instead.
Scott: What kind of iPhone?
Rym: A 4S, they'll give you $90.
Scott: No, I could just get that on your Mac.
Rym: An iPhone 6, they will give you $400.
Scott: I spent more than $400 for my iPhone 6.
Rym: Yeah, so basically, they'll give you less than market value in credit toward their Passport smartphone.
Scott: What are they going to do with my iPhone?
Scott: Sell it on the internet, on Craigslist?
Rym: That's what I'm wondering.
Rym: If they give you money.
Scott: Are they going to pay my cancellation fee at Verizon?
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't look like it.
Scott: You're not helping.
Scott: Also, why would you pay me to, you should, to downgrade, you need to make up for the difference.
Scott: You need to give me money equal to the value between the quality of the iPhone and the quality of the body.
Scott: You need to give me like the thousand dollars to make up for the quality difference between the two phones.
Rym: So basically, they're going to buy iPhones for under market value from people to get them to use their Blackberry Passport.
Rym: And then I guess resell those iPhones in the secondary market.
Scott: Instead, you should just give people Blackberries for free, make them run Android or some shit.
Scott: But you have the ability to make hardware, good hardware.
Scott: You know, you have that ability.
Rym: I don't think they do anymore.
Scott: Make the best Android phone that exists because it's not hard to make.
Scott: Try making a small one.
Scott: Put it out there and your brand still means something.
Scott: If you made a high quality, small stock.
Rym: I don't think their brand means anything, Scott, among people under the age of 48.
Scott: If they made a high quality, small stock Android phone, which any of these phone companies could do, but none of them do, they could make a comeback.
Scott: Instead of trying to be Blackberry, just don't be who you are anymore because who you are is bad.
Rym: They're definitely not capable of that.
Scott: They're capable of it.
Scott: If I was the CEO of Blackberry, I could make it happen.
Rym: Yeah, the features include extra loud speakerphone, 350% louder than the Samsung Galaxy S5.
Scott: That's a feature they've always had.
Rym: The features of Blackberry basically scream, literally, I am old.
Scott: I am designed by an old man.
Rym: And I am for old.
Scott: But that tells me the person who made that phone is so old, their hardware skills must be incredible.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: They can make a really tiny, awesome phone.
Scott: if only I was telling them what to make.
Rym: So let's get this straight.
Rym: Blackberry is basically saying, if you translate this advertising thing, our phones are so shitty, we have to pay people to use them.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Or give us your iPhone so we can then resell it for a profit on the secondary market.
Scott: Or, man, we're stuck with a warehouse full of shitty Blackberries.
Scott: Maybe we can trick people to trade them for much better iPhones.
Rym: Oh, my God, it gets even better.
Rym: You don't actually get a credit.
Rym: You pay the full price of the phone and you get a Visa prepaid card with the credit on it.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I'm amazed that -- if this company should really just take all the --.
Scott: Has anyone done this?
Scott: You know who's done this?
Scott: Someone who stole an iPhone.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: That's who's doing this.
Scott: Basically GameStop.
Rym: Wow, the passport costs 600 bucks.
Scott: Listen, tiny phones are expensive.
Scott: It doesn't matter who makes them.
Rym: It's not that tiny.
Scott: There's hardware in there that costs a lot.
Rym: The Sony Z3C is only 640.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, maybe 540.
Scott: Listen, regardless of how well-designed your phone is or what software is on it, the pieces inside are expensive regardless of how you arrange them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What's the iPhone 6 if you buy it completely contractless and unsubsidized as well, like 750?
Scott: Just add up the price of all those parts separately, then add on the cost of the factory that puts them together and the labor and the testing and, you know, any phone that's modern is going to be 600, 700 bucks.
Rym: So, things of the day.
Rym: I got two tiny little things.
Rym: So, Russian darts.
Rym: This is just Russian darts.
Rym: Just watch this video.
Rym: It escalates to the appropriate humorous point and then stops.
Rym: So, my other thing, Scott and I talked about this a long time ago, but the video's from 2005 before we started doing GeekNights publicly.
Rym: So, it doesn't appear that we've ever actually used this as a thing of the day.
Scott: It's way older than 2005.
Rym: From Tom's Hardware, February of 2005.
Scott: It feels older, but that's fine.
Rym: Uploaded in 2006.
Rym: This was uploaded to YouTube.
Scott: I remember downloading this video, downloading, in video file format before YouTube, like, it was a thing.
Rym: This was uploaded by some guy.
Scott: This exact video, I have the files for it.
Rym: So, the video, nowadays computers are a lot more sophisticated, but this was a time where if you took the heat sink off of a CPU, the magic smoke would come out in many cases, especially with AMD chips, before you finished taking the heat sink off.
Scott: Well, this was like the era where we did the most computer building in late college, right?
Scott: With Pentium 3s, Pentium 4s, AMD Athlons.
Rym: Yeah, right up pretty much from the K7 800 up through the Thunderbird era.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, basically, the deal was is that if you took the heat sink off an Intel chip, the Intel chip would go, "Oh my God, I'm hot," and it would just stop at doing anything because it was too hot.
Scott: The AMD chip was dumb as a brick and would go, "Keep doing stuff," and then set on fire without the heat sink.
Rym: Now, keep doing stuff, it had a couple of milliseconds of keep doing stuff.
Scott: Listen, it doesn't take that long.
Rym: Yeah, like Intel Pentium 3 1000.
Scott: The Pentium 4 was even more advanced.
Scott: It would stop processing, and if you put the heat sink back on, as soon as the temperature went down, it would start doing stuff again.
Rym: It's just amazing to watch that all the Intel chips, the game just crashes, and then the chips are pretty much okay, and all the AMD chips, you take it off, and smoke just starts billowing out of the chips immediately.
Scott: Now, this is something that most people would never even encounter because they don't take their heat sink off their CPU ever, so it doesn't seem like a worthwhile feature to pay for, but it's little things like this that are the reason why I stick with Intel over AMD through this day.
Scott: The reasons like this are the reasons why I stick with Nvidia over ATI to this day.
Scott: Even if those other companies make up for it, and this is only one example, I'll give you another example, right?
Scott: So, this is a very tiny thing that most people will never notice.
Scott: We had built an HTPC, the first one we built, and I had an ATI GPU in there.
Rym: Oh yeah, because it had that S-video port on the back.
Scott: I had an ATI GPU in there, ATI video card, and we plugged in an S-video cable, and when you turned the computer on, you couldn't see anything on the screen.
Scott: It wasn't until the OS loaded and the driver loaded that it showed anything on the TV.
Scott: It would only output to the VGA port when you turned the computer on.
Scott: But, with the Nvidia video card, it doesn't matter if it was the VGA, S-video, or whatever other video port on there, you could see the BIOS posting on all those video outs.
Scott: A very small feature, almost no one would notice that, but it makes a big difference if you're trying to set up an HTPC, and I'm sure maybe these things have been fixed in more modern hardware.
Rym: Yeah, and a lot of these things are anecdotal.
Rym: It just so happened that...
Scott: Right, that one particular card we had, right, that we happen to have, that cheapo one, right?
Scott: I'm sure.
Scott: It might not even be the GPU's fault.
Scott: It might be the card maker's fault in that case.
Rym: Well, you know, it shows something else too.
Rym: People seem to... Nowadays, it's really easy to build a computer.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: But, back in the day, if you put the wrong RAM chip in a computer, you might literally ruin the CPU and the RAM chip.
Rym: Like, you could mess up installing a computer in non-obvious ways, and when I used to build computers, like the first time you post it, you turn it on, there was the crippling fear that it wouldn't post, because if that happened, nowadays, usually that just means, yeah, you've got to plug something in.
Rym: Or, power supply is not powerful enough.
Rym: In the old days, it was even odds that that meant you broke something.
Scott: You're fucked.
Rym: You ruined something, and there's no way to tell what.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But yeah, it's little things like that.
Scott: that just, you know, I've seen throughout history, the reasons for certain brand loyalties, and they have never steered me wrong so far.
Scott: When I had AMD's for a long period of time, I have a bunch of AMD CPUs.
Scott: Why do I have so many AMD CPUs?
Scott: Oh, that's why.
Scott: That's why I don't have as many Intel CPUs, because they didn't fuck up and never had to be replaced.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Why do I have a bunch of AMD power supplies?
Scott: Oh, that's why.
Rym: Well, part of that, too, is that the curve of power, like the Pentium 4 was way expensive for how fast it was.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the K7s came in, they're like, yeah, we're way faster and way cheaper.
Scott: You're faster like the way a hot rod is faster.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Leaving fire all over the ground.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: It wasn't until, like, past the Core 2 Duo that I was like, yep, Intel.
Scott: The Core 2 Duo is when Intel retook the throne.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And remained in it.
Rym: And now, like the Core, like the i5, i7, I can't imagine buying a non-Intel CPU.
Scott: So I would like to see someone make one that I could believe in, but no one has.
Rym: Should we break them up with their monopoly?
Scott: They are, but they're not using their monopoly power to any evil effect.
Scott: How do you know?
Scott: What are they doing with their CPU monopoly?
Rym: Maybe they're using it as monopolized engineering resources that no one can ever-.
Scott: An example of something Intel could do is be like, you know what?
Scott: We're gonna make our Intel CPUs such that the only OS that will run on our computers is Intel OS.
Scott: Fuck everyone else.
Scott: Fuck you, Microsoft.
Scott: Fuck you, Linux.
Scott: Fuck you, OS X. Everyone has to use Intel OS now or use some other CPU.
Scott: And you think everyone's gonna use some other CPU?
Scott: 'Cause there isn't one.
Rym: Remember the alpha chips?
Scott: DEC alpha?
Scott: Those are not for normal people.
Scott: Yeah, there was a time- That's way earlier than- You used to be able to run Windows on that shit.
Scott: That was a ridiculously long time ago.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: It's not even relevant.
Rym: So in- Oh, you gotta think of the day.
Scott: I do.
Scott: So there's a thing I learned about called mispronounced incoming Schleren optics.
Scott: So I'd still, even after reading Wikipedia and a whole bunch of different documents and watching YouTube videos, I only marginally understand how this works.
Scott: Basically, with the combination of a point light source that's really bright, a razor blade, the kind you shave with, a big awesome mirror, and some other reflecting type things, you can look into the mirror and actually see basically the density of air.
Scott: So if you look at a lot of the example videos, someone will be lighting a candle or blowing a fan.
Scott: Something that heats up the air or maybe an ice cube or something that makes air have different refractive indexes.
Scott: And then you look into the mirror and it's like, "Whoa, you can
Scott: see.".
Scott: And as soon as you see what this looks like, you're like, "Oh, I've seen that before
Scott: somewhere.".
Scott: That sort of effect.
Scott: Well, it's called Schleren optics.
Scott: And if you read, maybe you can figure out how it works better than I can.
Scott: The razor blade is the really confusing part.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's like when I was in high school physics and we were learning about polarization and quantum stuff.
Rym: And the teacher did the experiment with the strange attractors.
Rym: He puts a polarizer, then he puts another one, and now there's no light going through it.
Rym: Then he puts a third polarizer between the two and light came through again.
Rym: And I was like, "What the
Rym: fuck?".
Rym: And then it took him the entire class to actually explain it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So here's some videos of this Schleren optics that you can watch for awesomeness.
Rym: In the meta moment, the Book Club book is Watership Down, the classic tale of rabbit adventure, rabbit cultists, and rabbit fascists.
Scott: How about the next Book Club book, which is Fire Car Up?
Rym: Yeah, Scott, I'm done with Watership Down.
Scott: I read it.
Scott: Isn't it like a kid's book?
Scott: I'm sure it won't take me long.
Rym: It's 413 pages.
Scott: That is much longer than I expected.
Scott: What's the font size?
Rym: The first edition, so normal book from the '70s, was 413 '70s book pages.
Scott: Oh, well, I have it on Kindle, so I'm gonna get readin', I guess.
Rym: I really liked it.
Rym: Also, I need you to give me a link so I can actually post it.
Scott: Uh, why do you need me to give you a link?
Rym: So we get money if you click on it and buy it.
Rym: I need the referral link.
Scott: Our secrets!
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So guys, if you want to support GeekNights, buy the book.
Scott: If you buy a Book Club book and you click the link that is on our site when you bought that book, it is an Amazon affiliate link, and we get a ridiculously small amount of money if you do that.
Rym: If you buy other things in that same session, we also get some money.
Scott: It's also a ridiculously small amount of money.
Rym: But if you're gonna buy a couple of HDTVs and a new computer, might as well buy Watership Down along the way.
Scott: But also make sure to go to smile.amazon.com so that money will go to the charity of your choice, which cannot be us.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I wonder if it's possible to get an affiliate fee and the Smile charity at the same time.
Scott: Or is it just the affiliate fees that go to the Smile charity?
Rym: I'm not 100% sure.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I was never quite clear on how that works.
Scott: My Smile charity keeps changing between Creative Commons and Child's Play, and I can't keep it under control.
Scott: It keeps wanting to switch around, and I'm like, "What are you
Scott: doing?".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Actually, I was looking into.
Rym: Child's Play has launched a thing where we can set up an account.
Rym: that is an event runner account, not just a donator account.
Rym: And basically, you don't even really need a lot of permission.
Rym: We can do any arbitrary event, and there's just a widget we put, and the widget, it just credits us like, "Yeah, these guys caused that donation to
Rym: happen.".
Rym: But otherwise, we don't even touch the money.
Rym: It just goes straight to Child's Play.
Rym: So if you can think of a cool thing that you would donate money for me and Scott to do, we will consider doing some sort of live stream where if you keep putting money in, we'll keep doing that thing.
Rym: Maybe a DDR-a-thon?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I do not think we would survive a very long DDR-a-thon.
Rym: Well, you know how Desert Bus works, right?
Scott: Keeps switching off?
Scott: No.
Rym: People switch off.
Scott: Oh, we increase the price of doing another song?
Scott: We should also multiply by the number of feet in the song.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: Oh, you want us to do Dropout?
Scott: All right, well, it's going to be like a bajillion dollars.
Rym: You're going to give $1,000 to Child's Play?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Rym will do Dropout, and then, "Oh, look, Rym passed out because he's an old man.
Rym: He can't DDR
Rym: anymore.".
Scott: Max 300?
Scott: Yeah, that'll be the rest of the money we're trying to raise.
Rym: Yeah, you know what, old man Rym, I think I am physically incapable of passing max 300 on Maniac at this point.
Scott: I am definitely.
Rym: I did it once.
Rym: There was a time when I could barely do it.
Rym: I don't think I can move my feet fast enough to do it.
Rym: I think I literally cannot dance DDR like that anymore.
Rym: It's a sad day to be this old at 32.
Scott: Don't get old.
Rym: Don't get old.
Scott: Too old.
Rym: So, I needed a new computer for work, and the CTO was like, "You can't waste the time building a computer.
Rym: Just buy a Dell or
Rym: something.".
Scott: Right, so what I did for work usually when I needed a new computer is I either got a Lenovo ThinkPad, which now is no longer the greatest option, or I got the Dell Optiplex.
Scott: The Dell Optiplex, which I had in my previous job, is just a normal old desktop-y, tower-ish computer that comes in four different sizes, but the one thing about it is that when you open up the side, which is actually surprisingly easy to open for a Dell computer, the things arranged inside are very, very nicely arranged, and it was actually quite easy to put in a video card and other modifications I needed to make when I had one.
Scott: So, that was six, seven years ago.
Scott: I don't know what's changed since then.
Rym: Plus, also, as we talked about on a previous Monday episode of GeekNights, none of those pre-built computers give you the kinds of options that you actually need, like multiple hard drives.
Scott: Well, sure, but because it was so easy to open, I just bought the stock one that had the right CPU and the right amount of RAM, and then the video card I just bought on Newegg, that kind of stuff.
Rym: So, I bought the Newegg iBuyPower desktop Intel configurator PC.
Scott: Oh, so one of those configurators, but what the hell is iBuyPower?
Rym: So, I actually tried to figure that out, and I can't.
Rym: So, I think it's a separate company.
Rym: Maybe it's the company that bought Newegg or bought part of Newegg.
Scott: No one bought Newegg.
Rym: You don't know a lot about Newegg's internal stuff, do you?
Rym: I know,
Scott: but I went to the iBuyPower website, and that seems to be a website where you configure a computer, and it's actually a really powerful configurator that lets you configure a lot of details of the computer, except they put it together for you instead of you having to build it, and they give you a lot of good options that Dell and other people don't give you for desktop computers, even laptops also.
Scott: But then if you go to Newegg, there's an item that you can buy on Newegg, which is the iBuyPower configurator built into Newegg, and you order through Newegg, and it's very strange.
Rym: So, there's a lot of weird relationships between Newegg and a lot of other companies, and I really can't figure out what Newegg's full deal is.
Scott: iBuyPower is definitely smaller than Newegg.
Rym: Quote, "On September 28, 2009, Newegg filed for an
Rym: IPO.".
Scott: Yep.
Rym: "The filing stated Newegg had been profitable, blah, blah, blah, blah,
Rym: blah.".
Scott: Where's the IPO?
Scott: I want in.
Rym: "In 2011, the company withdrew its registration for filing an
Rym: IPO.".
Scott: No, bring it back.
Scott: I want it.
Rym: I don't know if I would invest in them.
Scott: I would buy Newegg.
Rym: So, anyway, Newegg is the place that, you know, we always talk about, like, any show like this, GeekNights, anything, will always say, "Oh, gonna get a computer?
Rym: Go to Newegg, buy all the
Rym: parts.".
Rym: However, a lot of times, a friend of ours, a listener, a mother, a grandmother, a coworker who is not in your inner circle of friends will say, "Hey, Rym, you know a lot about computers.
Rym: What computers should I
Rym: buy?".
Rym: That's the voice of someone who isn't me.
Scott: Well, nowadays, my advice is, if you are not doing media production, gaming, or coding, why do you need a computer?
Scott: Yeah, okay, philosophically, you should still get a real computer such that you will have the ability to do those three things if you so desire, or, you know, your horizons will not be limited by having, you know, a less powerful device, you know, and maybe having that more powerful device will open new worlds to you.
Scott: Like, when I bought a fancier camera, I thought I might have been throwing my money away, but actually, because I got the fancy one, I started caring about cameras more.
Scott: Maybe if I make this person get a fancy desktop, they will care about computers more, and it'll be good for them, but honestly, just get a fucking iPad.
Scott: You don't need a real computer anymore.
Scott: The end.
Rym: Yeah, and the main reason for me is that if someone asks you, "What computer should I
Rym: get?"
Rym: and they follow your advice, they're going to call you when anything goes wrong with that computer for the rest of your collective lives.
Rym: So, as a result, I'm very hesitant to recommend basically any technology to anyone that I know who isn't, like, a listener of GeekNights and I'm just talking at you and you can't respond to me and don't know my phone number.
Scott: These days, I tell people to get an iPad, and if they need a real computer for some reason, but they don't need, like, a real, real computer, get the Surface Pro.
Scott: I mean, it's a real-for-reals laptop that's totally modern and supported, and it's actually probably one of the best Windows laptops you can get.
Rym: Though, depending on the person, I might suggest that they get an old ThinkPad Lenovo X230.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't need, like, the newest CPU and, like, it's not going to matter, why not get an older but still brand new ThinkPad?
Scott: You know, I have a 220 for myself and a 230 at work, and they're both just fine.
Rym: Yep, I got a 230 for myself and a coworker has a 240, and I looked at it, and it's not better.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: And, in fact, it's worse in a few material ways.
Rym: So, I think the first thing you got to do is, like, you know, you said just tell them about an iPad.
Rym: You have to get them to answer a simple question.
Rym: What are you going to use this computer for?
Rym: And, like, you know, your parents want to ask for a new computer.
Scott: I'm like, what do you do with it?
Scott: You just, you know, visit websites.
Scott: The iPad does that.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And then, depending on their answers, unless they trigger a thing that requires a computer, just tell them to buy the iPad.
Scott: All right, so the one thing they said that was valid somewhat is there's some websites they go to.
Scott: You might need to fill out a form or do something on some website, and the iPad browser doesn't cut it.
Scott: You're going to need a desktop browser just to do a thing that requires a desktop browser.
Rym: Yep, that is true.
Scott: So, you know what you can get for that?
Scott: A Chromebook.
Rym: Nah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It runs real Chrome, and it can do things on real, legit websites you need to do.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Like that.
Rym: But, like, if someone says, oh, I type a lot of stuff, like, I type a lot of emails.
Scott: You can get a keyboard and connect it to your iPad.
Rym: In fact, when we were at the beach, Emily was typing a big chunk of her novel on a Bluetooth keyboard synced to her iPhone.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: That totally worked in Google Docs.
Rym: Just go.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: I think part of the problem is that a lot of these people, meaning most people, they don't really understand the idea of modular interchangeable, like, if they hear Bluetooth, everything that supports Bluetooth supports Bluetooth.
Scott: Well, I mean, I told my parents, like, a whole bunch of times.
Scott: My mom was like, I want a bigger screen.
Scott: I'm like, just connect your iPad to the TV.
Scott: How can I do that with an Apple TV or this $50 cable?
Scott: $50 is a lot less money than an entire computer.
Scott: And she didn't really understand what I was talking about until I connected my iPad to the TV and she saw it, and she was like, oh.
Scott: It's like they don't understand the words that are coming out of your mouth.
Scott: They have to see it to understand it.
Rym: So the questions are, do you need it to be portable?
Rym: Do you want to play games?
Scott: Modern games.
Scott: The newest, newest games.
Rym: Do you create anything?
Scott: Video, audio, code.
Rym: Significant amounts of text.
Scott: Photos, editing, as opposed to just immediately uploading direct from your phone to Facebook.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So if I decide that someone needs an actual desktop computer, for whatever arbitrary criteria, I'm pretty much just going to point them at this iBuyPower desktop configurator, because the thing I got in my office is fine for what it is.
Rym: It was put together inside.
Rym: It was really sparse, because it's a big case, mid-tower.
Rym: Tiny little ITX motherboard in there.
Rym: And everything was wired correctly.
Rym: And it was wired reasonably well, because actually today I was typing.
Scott: Some guy who does nothing but wire computers all day was doing that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like when I wire a computer, I've been doing it for years, but I've only done it 10, 20 times total.
Scott: I do a pretty good job.
Scott: But if I had to do that and nothing but that all day, my wiring would be a work of fucking art.
Scott: You'd be like, "Where are the
Scott: wires?".
Scott: I'd be like, "Where are they
Scott: indeed?".
Rym: My one job I had back when I was the guy... You had one job.
Rym: When I went and fixed fucked up situations back when I worked at the hospital, one time they sent me to a data center, and they're like, "There's a rack, and we don't know what the deal with it
Rym: is.".
Rym: And I was like, "That's really
Rym: vague.".
Rym: And they're like, "Just go deal with
Rym: it.".
Rym: So I go, and I was surprised I didn't find a dead body inside of that rat's nest of cables.
Scott: Why is it always a rat's nest?
Scott: Why can't it be something else's nest?
Scott: There's got to be something worse than rat's nest.
Rym: Hobo nest.
Rym: New York City hobo nest.
Scott: Why can't it be like jellyfish legs?
Rym: I thought you were going to say jellyfish nest.
Scott: Oh, a whole bunch of jellyfishes?
Rym: Yeah, that might be worse.
Rym: Snakes.
Rym: It was just a sea of snakes.
Rym: It was a mating ball.
Scott: Why did it have to be snakes?
Rym: It was a snake mating ball.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: So, yeah, it was 18 1U servers in the same rack with some network equipment and everything, and let me tell you, I spent an entire work day rewiring that thing.
Scott: Were the lights blinking?
Rym: I just turned everything off, because fuck 'em.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
Rym: I remember, that job, it wasn't like, "Go figure this out and deal with it, and you got to be
Rym: careful.".
Rym: The job was, "Fix it, we don't care
Rym: how.".
Rym: I was like the bad cop.
Rym: They'd send me in to take care of business.
Rym: It was a hospital.
Scott: You might have killed somebody.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty sure those servers were being used by nobody for nothing.
Scott: Why just turn them off and rip all the wires out?
Scott: Well, throw the wires in the trash and leave.
Rym: So I actually didn't turn them back on, because I was waiting to see if a ticket arose anywhere in the hospital asking about them.
Rym: But then I quit, so I never found out.
Scott: Yeah, for anyone who needs to know, the way to rewire a big mess like that, when you have things that are just connected to each other, and not to other random places, is you basically find one port on one machine, right next to it with a Sharpie, like one.
Scott: Find the other end of that wire on the other port, right next to that one, one, and then take the wire out.
Scott: And then do that until you've written numbers next to every single port, and then get all new cables and make them nice, going from one to one, two to two, three to three, et cetera.
Rym: I actually preferred the functional result, where instead I would simply look at each port and figure out, what does this port need to do?
Rym: And I wouldn't redo it on a one-to-one basis.
Rym: I'd redo it on a logically equivalent basis.
Scott: How do you know what the port needs to do?
Scott: I mean, if it's just like a switch and it doesn't matter, you know any of these can go to any of those.
Scott: Most of them are Ethernet.
Rym: All I do is just figure out if they had to be on special VLANs or anything stupid like that.
Scott: Yeah, but sometimes it's like, oh, you know, this one has to go there.
Rym: Yeah, one of them were these like 40-foot null-modem cables plugged into these like jank-ass serial ports, and they went under into the raised floor and disappeared.
Rym: And if I tugged on them, they were completely taut.
Rym: And I couldn't unplug that.
Scott: Someone at some point in time set that up.
Rym: I suspect the rat got moved.
Scott: Well, I wish I was there on that day to see what was going on.
Rym: The best part is that project, the one with the serial cables, failed, and like that whole project was a disaster and collapsed.
Rym: So I never figured out where the other end of that serial cable went.
Rym: Just cut it.
Rym: We did.
Rym: We cut the heads off as deep as we could get to them and left it with a little flag on the end.
Rym: that said, basically, it was a code that meant this cable is not used for anything.
Rym: If you ever find the other end of it, you can throw the whole thing away.
Scott: No, you can just go to every machine in the whole data center, cut all of them, and then when you pull all the ends, none of them should be taut.
Scott: You should all come out with half cables on every end, and then you can put them all in one bin.
Rym: So anyway, seriously, I knocked this thing over today at work.
Rym: The whole computer, facing forward, so the motherboard was on the top.
Rym: So it just fell.
Scott: You kicked it?
Scott: It was on the floor?
Rym: I just leaned back and kicked it the wrong way, and it just fell over.
Rym: And it was totally fine.
Rym: Nothing came loose.
Rym: So it was correctly put together.
Rym: And my advice to anyone who needs to buy a computer is just go here, choose options that match your maximum budget, and click add to cart.
Rym: It'll be fine.
Rym: There's not that many options.
Scott: And the thing is, there's a lot of people who are still into the nerdery of overclocking.
Rym: If you're into that nerdery, build a computer from scratch.
Scott: Obviously, but there are some nerderies that I think just need to die, and that is one of them.
Rym: I'm thinking about overclocking my laptop.
Rym: Why?
Rym: Because the Elgato encoding, if the CPU is less than 3.02 gigahertz, it cannot encode in real time 1080p 30.
Scott: You have the extremely rare, somewhat legit use case, but your laptop might explode.
Scott: Why not just buy another laptop?
Scott: You have money.
Rym: Because at this point it's cheaper.
Rym: I could just buy another computer and make that the streaming box.
Scott: Because you can afford to just buy another computer, why not overclock this one?
Scott: If it explodes, you'll just buy a new one.
Rym: The thing is, I need to overclock it.
Scott: And if it doesn't, you just saved yourself a bunch of money.
Rym: I need to overclock it so little.
Rym: Because it runs at 2.96 gigahertz.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: And the thing is, I tested.
Rym: I ran profilers, and I watched, and I'd encode different video.
Rym: It was amazing, because 1080p 30 was going fine on a static, simple to encode image.
Rym: But then I took the camera and went, "Woo, woo,
Rym: woo!".
Rym: And the CPU went,
Rym: "Max!".
Rym: It was amazing.
Scott: But yeah, most people who aren't encoding live streaming video with a laptop, even if you're playing games, the newest, newest possible games, the most ridiculous hardware they sell doesn't do anything.
Scott: I have a 680.
Scott: I'm still maxing out literally every game that Steam has to offer.
Rym: Well, no, it goes to show that the fact that it's almost 2015 proves something that we said back in 2005.
Rym: That if you're a nerd about computers, you can overclock to extend this further.
Rym: But if you invest in a high-quality, well-researched computer, and you buy top-of-the-line or second top-of-the-line, plateau-line components, and you overspend, I spent like
Rym: $3,400. 680
Rym: was $500.
Rym: I spent well over $3,000 on the computer.
Scott: I do have 32 gigs of RAM.
Rym: But seriously, in 2009, the computer I'm using now, I bought for a bit over $3,000.
Rym: It is 100% sufficient to do Geek Guides, edit HD video and 4K video live, and do everything that I do with a computer, including playing super-modern games today.
Rym: And I've spent a total of $500 upgrading it in the entire life of it so far.
Rym: $600, I bought a new SSD yesterday.
Scott: Since I made this computer, which is pretty much around the time the 680 came out, so years ago, it has not needed any modification or upgrading whatsoever, and it is still effectively perfect as fast as any computer anyone could possibly need.
Rym: I found a use case.
Rym: I kind of need more RAM.
Scott: I have 32 gigs, so how many do you have?
Rym: So I have 12.
Scott: Now you need more.
Scott: At work, I had four, and basically, I needed more, so I went up to eight, and now I'm only using like five at a time.
Rym: This computer has six DIMM slots.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: That's because I bought an awesome motherboard.
Scott: Do you have six times two?
Rym: No, I don't, actually.
Rym: I do have room to put more in.
Rym: But the use case I ran into where I needed more than 12 was I was using an effect in Premiere, and I couldn't play it back live.
Rym: It was one of those effects that even with the CUDA rendering, you just can't.
Rym: Because it was an effect that basically, I figured out what it was doing.
Rym: It analyzes all the frames, so it takes every frame into memory to do a calculation on the full set of the frames, and that's how it figures out what to do to all the frames.
Rym: So you need enough RAM to hold the entire set of frames that you've selected for the effect in memory.
Rym: To render it at all.
Rym: Now, with Adobe Media Encoder, you can render it, and it'll deal with it, but if you want to do a preview render, or you want Premiere to render it itself, my RAM just went up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up.
Scott: Well, for the preview, you can tell it, "Well, when I preview, only preview every other frame.
Scott: Don't preview all the
Scott: frames.".
Rym: Not with this effect.
Rym: This effect, you didn't have that option.
Rym: It wasn't the display.
Scott: You can also preview at half size.
Rym: That wouldn't have helped.
Scott: So that each frame takes up half as much space.
Rym: Yeah, that doesn't affect the rendering of a preview.
Rym: As opposed to the live playback preview.
Rym: Anyway, I ran into a case where maybe 24 gigs of RAM would be useful.
Scott: Yeah, for anything for a normal person, even today, where RAM is so cheap, you think, "Why
Scott: not?".
Scott: The reason I have 32, it was so cheap.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: I feel like 8 is a good default.
Scott: Yeah, if you have 8, you're not going to run into any problems whatsoever with any normal thing.
Scott: At work, I have a virtual machine always open.
Scott: I got two browsers, which use the most memory of anything, always open, and a whole bunch of other shit, like Outlook and stuff, and I'm using 5, at most, when I've got everything open.
Rym: So here, this iBuyPower thing, here are your options for RAM.
Rym: Every option.
Rym: 4 gigs of RAM.
Scott: Not enough.
Rym: That's just included by default.
Rym: Add $40 to get 8 gigs of RAM.
Scott: Done.
Scott: Add $116 to have- So it's insignificantly more money.
Rym: Add $116 to have 16 gigabytes of RAM.
Scott: That's more than you're going to need ever.
Rym: Add $136 to have 16 gigabytes of G.Skill Ripjaws X-Series RAM.
Scott: So no difference between the previous one whatsoever.
Rym: Let me look at the details.
Rym: Maybe there's a slight difference in- There is.
Scott: RAM is RAM.
Scott: Don't fall for that nonsense.
Scott: Guess what?
Rym: They're both PC 1280.
Scott: Yes, do not fall for the fancy RAM.
Scott: All RAM is RAM.
Rym: You know, I realize for all these years, me and most PC people say PC 1280.
Rym: It's actually 12,800.
Scott: Uh, whatever.
Rym: That's the rating.
Rym: God, remember when CAS latency mattered?
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Remember knowing what CAS latency was?
Rym: Going for that CAS 2 RAM?
Scott: No, I forgot what CAS latency was.
Rym: Instead of the CAS 3, it was the refresh ratio.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But, yeah, I'll recommend this to anyone who wants a computer.
Rym: Anyone who doesn't need a computer, I'll recommend an iPad.
Rym: And if they want a laptop, either buy the cheapest possible laptop or a Surface Pro.
Scott: I recommend not buying the cheapest possible, right?
Scott: The cheapest possible gets the job done.
Scott: It's sort of miraculous.
Scott: Like, whoa, $200.
Scott: I got this computer.
Scott: It works.
Scott: It does all these things.
Scott: Hooray.
Scott: The only problem with those, and I know a lot of people who buy them because they just can't afford to buy the good one, and they need a computer now, is that they break.
Scott: So as soon as you buy -- and it's not like the sunglasses strategy, right?
Scott: I'll buy $20 sunglasses, and if they break, I'll just buy more $20 sunglasses, and it'll be fine.
Scott: And it'll be the same as if I just bought $200 sunglasses once with less risk.
Scott: If you lose or break your sunglasses, you can go without sunglasses until buying new ones.
Scott: It's not really a big fucking deal.
Scott: If your computer breaks, you need a fucking new computer immediately, like that moment.
Scott: So if you buy a $200 computer, okay, that was all you could afford, great, but it's going to break, right?
Scott: You get quality by spending -- not more money won't necessarily get you more quality, but the good stuff is more expensive.
Rym: In my experience, the Asus craptops and the Asus just preconfigured laptops, like desktops and things, they're way better than they used to be.
Scott: They're better than they used to be, but they're still not good.
Rym: I don't get the impression they break anymore, they're just way underpowered.
Scott: Not just underpowered, but it's like they will not get the job done.
Scott: They will not last you the five plus years that my computers that I own have lasted.
Rym: Those things don't buy you anything over an iPad.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: That's the real answer.
Scott: You're not really saving anything by getting those, right?
Scott: Basically, when those break, you need to go out and buy another thing immediately, and again, you'll only be able to afford another $200 dude.
Scott: You're better off saving the monies, suffering with whatever you happen to have now, whatever it is, just suffer with it until you can afford at least the $500 or $800 dealie.
Scott: And once you get that, you're actually going to save money no matter how poor you are, because that thing will last you a fucking long ass time.
Scott: If a computer doesn't last you five plus years, you did it wrong.
Scott: I've never had a quality computer last less than five years.
Scott: Usually more than five years they last.
Rym: Yeah, so here's a good example.
Rym: My computer now, even if I include upgrades, I spent a little over
Rym: $4,000. $4,000,
Rym: right?
Rym: That seems like a lot of money for a computer.
Rym: If I use it for the rest of next year, if I keep using it and it lasts until Christmas next year, Christmas 2015, and then I replace it, I'll have paid under $600 a year to have had a supercomputer for that entire time.
Scott: I mean, my computer was less than $2,000.
Scott: I expect it to last at least six years, if not eight.
Scott: If we go with the conservative estimate of six, $2,000 divided by six years, right?
Scott: That's saving a lot of monies there.
Rym: In fact, the Windows Experience Index on my computer is still... Oh, my RAM and processor hold it down now.
Rym: 7.3.
Scott: I don't even know what mine is.
Rym: Yeah, 7.3.
Rym: That's not too bad, actually, for a computer that built in 2009.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.