Rym: It's Tuesday, November 11th, 2014.
Rym: Tonight, on Remembrance Day, we talk about Smash Brothers on the 3DS.
Scott: We didn't say that we are Rym and Scott.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: It's been a while.
Rym: We just did one last week.
Rym: We did, but that was a special, and so I was kinda sick.
Rym: Like, I was like, "Oh, I'm not feeling so
Rym: great.".
Rym: You know, after Australia, like, I felt like I was getting a cold.
Rym: And based on Emily's reaction to the cold, which was basically slight cold, and my reaction, which was, an hour after you left, I had a crazy fever and I passed out.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, my immune system was not too happy, so I don't remember.
Scott: I took a sick day yesterday, but I wasn't sick at all, but my apartment was sick.
Scott: And now it is kinda clean.
Scott: I'm cleaning it up.
Scott: Get my life back in order.
Rym: You know, a lot of my coworkers and bosses actually listen to this show, so I couldn't get away with saying something like that.
Rym: Maybe I could.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: I'm so afraid.
Rym: I haven't taken a fake sick day, though, in the new company.
Rym: Now, the old company.
Scott: Anyway, so yeah, we're back.
Rym: We're regular schedule until, I guess, Pac South.
Scott: Thanksgiving.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm not going anywhere Thanksgiving.
Scott: I mean, there's still probably gonna be some missed podcasts around Thanksgiving, around holiday season.
Rym: I think New Year's is when we're actually gonna miss a show or two.
Scott: On days when weather keeps us home.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but I'm gonna start stepping up.
Rym: So, what we'll talk about in a moment.
Rym: So, a lot of gaming news.
Rym: I mean, there was cheating in that ticket to ride tournament.
Scott: Oh, you wanna talk about that?
Rym: I don't really wanna talk about it.
Rym: That's an example of, there's like a hundred things we could talk about.
Rym: Try not to blow the load.
Scott: Well, I mean, gaming news is not something we have a shortage of.
Scott: True.
Rym: I feel like we should do a show on the cheating thing.
Scott: We've done cheating shows before, though.
Rym: I wanna do a tabletop specific cheating show.
Scott: Learn to be, learn sleight of hand skills by going to take classes in Magic and then use them.
Rym: So, here's an example.
Rym: I've noticed something.
Rym: When people cheat at Counter-Strike, like it happens.
Rym: The reaction is usually, "Oh my
Rym: God!"
Rym: And it's kind of funny for a while and then either the guy stops cheating or everyone just quits.
Rym: It's like, it's no big deal.
Rym: Like, only a few people will like really flip out.
Scott: Well, people will flip out if it was like Counter-Strike Championship.
Rym: Well, if it's Counter-Strike Championship, no one flips out.
Scott: This was the final game.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what the answer is?
Rym: Wow.
Scott: Tickets to ride World Championships.
Rym: Yeah, but the reaction to that would be, "Wow, you just forfeited.
Rym: Awesome.".
Scott: But, the game- Not even if it gets caught way after the game's over.
Rym: But the difference is that the game enforces the rules.
Rym: So, to cheat at Counter-Strike in a tournament, you either need to like have someone physically ghosting the other team and talking to you with like a secret spy shit.
Scott: Or- And usually you're playing in like soundproof things with the headphones and the- You need to like hack the computer.
Scott: Like, that is- Usually the competitive things that you're using computers provided by them- And not provided by you.
Rym: So, that's my point.
Rym: That's like, if you cheat in like a competitive Counter-Strike like national thing, that is some James Bond like- That's first degree murder, effectively.
Scott: It's like, they'll let you bring your mouse and keyboard usually, which would be really hard to cheat.
Rym: I hacked firmware on the mouse that as soon as I plugged it in- Yeah, they don't really care about that.
Rym: No, so the hacked firmware on the mouse actually hacks the computer and installs my aimbot.
Scott: They would notice.
Rym: But I'm saying, that's like first degree- You don't have root privileges on the computer, so- But cheating at a tabletop game is so different because there's nothing to enforce the rules.
Rym: Like literally, German board games, if you want to cheat, no one would ever catch you except maybe in a tournament when people are like, who aren't in the game are really watching you.
Rym: But, and also like I've noticed a lot of people like playing tabletop games, if they're not good at games, they fuck up rules and don't notice and effectively cheat it, but like don't realize it.
Rym: And people, if they mess up a rule with good players, like immediately, everyone at the table is like, hey, hey, hey, what did you just do there?
Rym: What just happened there?
Scott: If they're paying attention, right?
Rym: Things can happen- Yeah, competitive- I can't imagine someone like you or me, or anyone we know who's good at tabletop games, if they were playing for serious, not paying attention.
Scott: Well, funny you should speak of that.
Scott: So the Netrunner World Championships was this weekend.
Scott: Congratulations to Dan, who is also the Philadelphia regional champion.
Rym: What?
Rym: Wait, Philly?
Scott: Yeah, so he was the Philadelphia regional champion, which I went to.
Rym: Philly's a, you know, I'm going to say something that I might regret.
Scott: He's now the world champion.
Rym: Philly actually does count as a city.
Scott: What?
Scott: Who said anything about that?
Rym: Philly's a city, get some respect.
Scott: I was just using the geography to identify the person.
Scott: Philly sucks ass.
Scott: Fuck you, Philly.
Scott: I mean, Dan's an okay person, I guess, for someone from Philly.
Rym: I guess in the list of places that you could live in as a city, Philly is actually higher up on the list than Boston in recent analysis.
Scott: But anyway, there was an incident during the tournament, which is relevant.
Scott: So there's an agenda.
Scott: I don't know, I guess you had to understand Netrunner rules a bit for me to explain this, but basically, a player- Sure, okay, fine.
Scott: So he had an N.A.P.D.
Scott: contract on the table, which is a four advance for two point card.
Scott: And he's at five points, so if he scores it, he wins.
Scott: He could score it in one turn by advancing it three times, with his three actions and three credits, and then using his astro script token, which costs no actions, to advance it a fourth time and score it.
Rym: So he's got that hanging out, just ready to go.
Scott: However, there is text on N.A.P.D.
Scott: contract that says, "If you have bad publicity, the advancement requirement goes up by
Scott: one.".
Rym: Oh, and he had bad publicity.
Scott: He had bad publicity, so the advancement requirement was actually five.
Scott: This piece of text on the card is mostly forgotten by pretty much everybody.
Scott: A lot of people don't even know it, and when you tell it to them, they're like,
Scott: "What?".
Scott: Because it basically never comes up.
Scott: See, the thing is, this text on the card, and there's two sentences, and the first sentence says, "If the runner wants to steal the N.A.P.D.
Scott: contract, they have to pay four
Scott: credits.".
Scott: That happens all the goddamn time, and that's like the primary feature of the card.
Scott: So the fact that there's a secondary feature that almost never comes up, people don't even bother to read the card, and people don't know about that second penalty on the thing.
Scott: So there was an incident where we're watching on the stream.
Scott: No one can hear what the players are saying.
Scott: The people sitting next to the players are paying attention to their own games.
Scott: It wasn't a judged game in the super finals that was being watched very closely.
Scott: So the guy, we're not sure exactly what happened.
Scott: Some people say, "Oh, yeah, he was showing that he couldn't advance it four times and win, and he could have won anyway with the three scorches in hand, and the other guy was tagged, so he had two win conditions and the same turn.
Scott: He was just showing
Scott: them.".
Scott: So the guy basically won the game legitimately.
Scott: It didn't really matter.
Scott: So it's not a big deal like the Ticket to Ride where, yeah, he was cheating, or at least accidentally cheating.
Scott: But the situation there where pro players at the top of the game, top 16 players in the world, something can slip by you that if you would have done it, they might not have fucking noticed.
Scott: It's really hard to pay attention to everything that's going on when you've been playing a game all for two days straight.
Rym: Ticket to Ride has very little going on.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: It's much harder in Ticket to Ride than in a more complicated game to get fucked up.
Scott: And to not notice, to let your opponent take two turns in a row.
Rym: The etiquette I've always seen in all my life playing real tabletop games, like the For Serious tabletop games, has been that among good people who are in that community, a lot of times you'll think you messed up a rule and you're not 100% sure, but the game's still kind of hidden information kind of game, and it seems like the unspoken policy is if you think you forgot to do something or you messed something up, you just correct it in the way that harms you the most.
Scott: I mean, in a tournament like that, you just call a judge over, right?
Scott: You're expected to police the game yourself, but if something happens that's fucked up, you just call the judge and you say, "Judge, this is the fucked up thing that happened,".
Scott: and they tell you the remedy.
Rym: Did you see that video someone posted in the forum of how to cheat at Magic with the deck shuffling?
Rym: And apparently it's super common.
Rym: You shuffle your opponent's deck, and once it's shuffled, you're not allowed to touch it until gameplay.
Rym: You can't alter it in any way.
Rym: So you can't cut it after they shuffle it.
Rym: Anyone who's played card games could basically deal out all lands or all spells to you and force you to mulligan.
Rym: And apparently this is the thing that's been happening.
Scott: I mean, if there's money at stake, people are going to practice those skills, right?
Scott: In other games, like Netrunner, Ticket to Ride, there's no money on the line.
Scott: So there's no reason.
Scott: It's not worth it to practice Slate of Hand to try to win a playmat and a statue.
Rym: But I guess the real bar, I don't even think about the idea of anyone cheating at any game I ever play, even tournaments, really.
Rym: What I do is, one, I only play with people who, if they cheated, that's like friend level betrayal.
Rym: And two, I'm more worried about them fucking up the rules because I just taught them the game.
Scott: Anyway, so, I guess there's a whole bunch of news crammed in that cheating article.
Scott: There was also a Hearthstone World Championship, which didn't have cheating at all.
Scott: But you should, even if you don't care about Hearthstone, just go on, because Blizzcon happened, there's a ton of stuff there.
Scott: But just go and look at the set and stage they had for the Hearthstone.
Scott: It was like this huge booth with a fire in it and shit.
Scott: So it was like a tavern off to the side.
Rym: Yeah, you know what, this is something, so remember way back in 2002, Ostentatious Otakons felt like expo halls and things.
Rym: I'm really glad that we've kind of doubled down on the gaming cons, because production values be off the charts, yo.
Scott: Yeah, for reals.
Rym: So, my news is a short- That wasn't your news?
Scott: That took like how long?
Rym: You're just talking about games.
Scott: That took forever.
Rym: So my news is a succinct review of PAX Australia 2014.
Rym: Don't want to do a whole show on it, because if we review every convention we go to, you guys, this would be GeekNights, the convention.
Scott: This is the first PAX I haven't been to since '07.
Rym: Yeah, and meanwhile, some PA/REED people, like some high up enforcers and people who have been to more PAXes than us, I've gained on a couple of them by one.
Scott: Not everyone can go to Australia every year.
Rym: I'm pretty much convinced I'm going next year now, too.
Scott: How is that going to happen?
Rym: So here's my succinct review of PAX Australia.
Rym: One, no longer in a big top, in a real convention center- That takes away some of the charm, doesn't it?
Rym: So, it makes it different.
Rym: That first PAX Australia- Minus charm, plus every other area?
Rym: You know what it's like?
Rym: It's like when PAX Prime moved to the real convention center in Seattle.
Scott: We never were at it before the real convention center.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm saying like the difference in feeling that people talk about.
Rym: Or when MagFest moved from hotels to convention center.
Rym: The feel changed a lot.
Rym: So, I'm very glad I went to that first PAX Australia because that was most memorable.
Rym: But I'm glad it'll never be there again.
Rym: So, the new convention center is approaching as big as the Boston Convention Center.
Scott: The PAX East is at it.
Scott: I mean, we were outside of it when we were there last year.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: We fucked up.
Rym: We looked at it and assumed it was X size.
Rym: We were not looking at the Melbourne Convention Center.
Rym: That is the Melbourne Exposition Center.
Rym: Way, way, way, way, way the fuck.
Rym: behind it, like connected far off.
Rym: where we never walked, is the Melbourne Convention Center.
Rym: PAX used both.
Rym: Yeah, so when we talked about how big that place was and looked it up, we were looking at half the space that it had available.
Scott: There we go.
Rym: We were looking at basically just the expo hall and queue room.
Scott: So, they put the expo hall in that building.
Rym: we saw.
Rym: The queue room, panel room.
Scott: And everything else was in another building, I don't know.
Rym: The far end of the building, we didn't see that.
Rym: The building's also way bigger than we thought.
Scott: I'm sure it has underground parts as well.
Rym: There was a lot.
Rym: So, there's the backend stuff.
Rym: There were offices for enforcers who had important jobs to do.
Rym: Enforcing at that con was a step above and beyond any other enforcing in terms of the facilities to which you had access to make your job easier.
Rym: There were observation decks.
Rym: you would look down on the floor through windows and check on stuff.
Rym: It was crazy.
Scott: Who architected this and when can we hire them to build a New York Convention Center?
Rym: So, it had the feels of the Hartford Convention Center, the Kineticons that.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: That kind of feeling and vibe.
Rym: All the PAX stuff was there.
Rym: This PAX was a proper PAX, for real.
Rym: now.
Rym: And if I had to rank...
Scott: The other one wasn't proper?
Rym: It was weird.
Rym: It was off kilter a little bit.
Rym: If I had to rank PAX...
Scott: You said it was a real PAX last time when we did a show on it.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: Now it's a real PAX.
Rym: Now... So, if I had to rank the PAXs in terms of PAXness, PAX Prime, number one.
Scott: Duh.
Rym: PAX Australia, number two.
Rym: PAX East, number three.
Rym: Like, for real.
Rym: PAX East feels way different than both Prime and Aus.
Rym: There's a big jump in the field.
Scott: Let's see what PAX South is up to.
Rym: I'm really curious about PAX South.
Rym: Tabletop was rocking and pretty much full the entire time.
Rym: Once again, a three-day PAX closes at midnight, so they kind of lied to us back when they said that that was only because PAX Prime went to four days.
Rym: I think all PAXs end at midnight forever.
Rym: Tabletop library, wicked stocked.
Rym: Splendor tournament.
Rym: Did you win?
Rym: I didn't get to enter it because it conflicted with the panel I was on.
Rym: I was on three panels, not two.
Rym: You know what else conflicted?
Rym: And I'm really, really sad about this.
Rym: A Doom tournament.
Scott: You weren't in the Doom tournament?
Rym: No, and I got over there to watch the Doom tournament after my panel.
Scott: And you feel like you could have won?
Rym: I feel like I could have won.
Scott: No one else was doing wall running?
Rym: I could have won with my left fucking hand.
Scott: No one else was wall running and shit?
Rym: It was ZDoom, which is fine.
Scott: Fine, nothing wrong with ZDoom.
Rym: But yeah, no one knew how to wall run.
Rym: I don't think wall running is a known skill among the youth.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm really a little salty about not being able to be in that tournament.
Scott: How many people were in the Doom tournament?
Rym: Oh, it was full.
Rym: People were really excited about it.
Scott: I remember at the first PAX Australia you tried to go to the Counter-Strike tournament.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: So I'm going to tell you about the one bad thing that happened at PAX Australia.
Scott: It was a bad thing?
Rym: I entered the gun game, well I guess they call it...
Scott: Oh, the Counter-Strike gun game.
Rym: Yes, I entered that tournament.
Scott: Oh, you actually got in?
Rym: Yeah, so 96 players.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And they line us all up and they sit us down.
Rym: And so I sit down next to Bain and we're hanging out and we give each other GLHF.
Rym: And then we're ready to play and then no Enforcer ever comes over.
Rym: So eventually a guy comes over and says, "Alright, all of you here join server
Rym: 2.".
Rym: So we all join.
Rym: And then the guy at my left of me is like, "Ah, the server's
Rym: full.".
Rym: So we're like, "Sorry dude, I don't
Rym: know.".
Rym: So he's trying to flag down an Enforcer.
Rym: So we all just start playing gun game.
Rym: Next thing we know, an hour's gone by.
Rym: We've played like 11 matches.
Scott: Who won them?
Rym: We kept track because we didn't know.
Rym: So eventually an Enforcer comes over and we're like, "So what's the format of the tournament?
Rym: What's going
Rym: on?".
Rym: And he's like,
Rym: "Oh.".
Rym: And basically the tournament just kind of failed and petered out.
Scott: Who was in charge of the tournament?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: But I reported that the tournament failed.
Rym: So basically...
Scott: That was an innocent Enforcer's job.
Scott: Enforcer fucked up.
Rym: The line to play in PC free play was crazy long.
Scott: Because all these people were sitting there playing gun game for an hour, not getting up.
Rym: No, PC tourney is a separate area.
Rym: So because that line was so long, they didn't give you too super much time to play in there.
Rym: So I just stayed in the tournament area playing Counter-Strike for a long time.
Scott: That's a good move.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Most of us did that.
Rym: It was still super fun.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: So I'm not mad about it, but sorry dudes.
Rym: You guys kind of fucked up that tournament, like for reals.
Scott: Learned to run tournaments.
Rym: There was a Galaga tournament.
Scott: Who won that?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Me and Alan were hanging out watching it for a while, but we didn't... The second guy goes up and gets like over 300,000.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: That's way better than... I love fucking Galaga.
Scott: I am not anywhere good.
Rym: So I hope they couldn't overhear me, because everyone came up, I'd watch them play for two seconds, and guess their final score.
Rym: In terms of order of magnitude, I was like, "That guy's not breaking
Rym: 10K.".
Rym: And sure enough, one guy, he was doing pretty well.
Rym: He got to like 90K, 100K, and then he got a death.
Scott: Did anyone do the secret?
Rym: Which secret?
Scott: Where you dodge all the guys in the first level, and then you kill that one guy at the right moment.
Rym: No, no one did anything like that.
Rym: But everyone was doing the double ship.
Rym: Anyone who didn't do the double ship at the first opportunity, it was like, "Okay,
Rym: guys.".
Rym: Or anyone who didn't have an extra life at the first opportunity, like, "Yeah, you're
Rym: done.".
Rym: One guy was doing pretty well, and then at one point he got an extra life, and then he did a derp die.
Rym: He just died derpily.
Rym: But he was still doing okay, but he had no lives left.
Rym: And then an opportunity came, and he did it.
Rym: So, you know, game over, because he didn't have any extra lives.
Scott: Oh, he double shipped.
Scott: He tried to double ship, but it was his last ship.
Rym: As soon as it starts happening, he suddenly goes, "Oh!
Rym: Oh no!
Rym: Oh
Rym: no!".
Rym: And he just drops the controller and walks away.
Rym: It was beautiful.
Scott: Is this an arcade Gallagher?
Rym: No, this was Atari something.
Rym: Like, a weird Atari controller was awesome.
Scott: All right.
Rym: What else is interesting about this pack?
Rym: The panels went off without a hitch.
Rym: People were bothering me the entire convention about him.
Scott: That's typical.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: People really like the losing panel that you never wanted to do.
Scott: Again, I feel like- I mean, it started out as a culture of losing, right?
Scott: At least to the police.
Scott: So, they need the help in that area.
Rym: But, yeah, this PAX was crazy awesome.
Rym: If I had to rank gaming cons, period.
Rym: All gaming cons that I would ever go to.
Rym: The order is now, PAX Prime, Magfest, PAX OSS, PAX East.
Rym: Gaming for hope if it still exists.
Rym: Because that's actually a super fun con if it still exists.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, let's talk about- I guess we talked about the world championships of things.
Scott: So, now let's just talk about the- What's it called?
Scott: The Blizzard TF2 thingy.
Scott: What's the name of this thing that they're coming out with?
Scott: Overwatch?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, Blizzard is making- We already knew that they're making a competing game to compete against the MOBAs.
Scott: that's going to be all streamlined and whatnot.
Scott: It seems like they're going to compete with TF2 with this Overwatch in the sort of low barrier to entry team FPS department.
Rym: I sold all the old items that I just had from long ago on TF2 and I got like 10 bucks each for everything.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: I've never sold anything for that much.
Rym: I made a ton of fucking money on Steam.
Scott: I think it's because you might have actually played Team Fortress 2 in the hat era.
Rym: I played it in the beginning and I got a bunch of items right then and then I never played again.
Scott: See, I played it in the beginning before there were items so I only had- The items I had didn't go for that much when I sold them a long time ago.
Rym: Okay, so I just Googled for Overwatch just because I wanted to have the thing up, like have some info.
Rym: That's how we sound smart on GeekNights.
Rym: We're looking at our computers the whole time.
Rym: The first actual search result is summarized by Google because it's a long title.
Rym: So all it says is, "With Overwatch, Blizzard is trying to do women.
Rym: Kotaku.".
Scott: So anyway.
Scott: Yeah, people are, you know, even not knowing anything about the game, people are praising Blizzard because they've posted basically pictures of all the different classes that you could be and there are many women and peoples of color in all shapes and sizes as I guess you should.
Scott: But, you know, on the one hand, it's like, "Okay, yeah, you should do that.
Scott: That's a great
Scott: thing.".
Scott: But it also hints tiny bit of, "We did it so that we would get praised for
Scott: it.".
Scott: If someone does a good thing for a greedy reason, it's okay.
Rym: If Hitler saves a puppy, Hitler did a good thing and deserves praise for that one good thing.
Scott: Not for the other things to me.
Rym: Notice how I said that?
Scott: This is the same Blizzard that has like, you know, sexy dancing elves in World of Warcraft, right?
Scott: This is not really, you know, which part of their culture changed?
Scott: Do they fire and hire people, you know?
Rym: Wait, wait, what are you, some kind of social justice warrior?
Scott: Have you seen the mage in Hearthstone, right?
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: That's not the worst thing in the world, but still.
Rym: But yeah, I'm not super confident that it's a game I will like, which is interesting.
Scott: If you like TF2 and TF2 is getting old, this is probably a better choice.
Scott: that's going to be more modern.
Rym: But at the same time, what's our complaint about MOBA?
Rym: Our complaints about MOBA is the reason we don't play.
Rym: MOBA is the reason normal humans don't play those old games like Team Fortress Classic and Weapons Factory.
Rym: So, this is basically... But I'm old now.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: What Team Fortress was to those people, this might be to us.
Rym: For MOBAs.
Scott: Maybe we'll play them.
Scott: But Team Fortress 2 already exists.
Rym: But that's an FPS.
Scott: This is also an FPS.
Rym: Yeah, but we'll see how the gameplay actually works out.
Scott: I think the big difference here is the Overwatch game is supposedly not going to be like capture the flag as much as it is more like an FPS MOBA a lot like... There are some other FPS MOBAs out there.
Rym: We keep saying FPS.
Rym: I think we should just say FP.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Or first person.
Scott: But it's going to be like Team Fortress 2 level of barrier to entry and whatnot.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Interesting.
Rym: Of course, at the same time I just click on this article here and all I see is this naked elf butt with a lot of Rym light on it.
Scott: Well, there you go.
Rym: So, I guess it's not an elf.
Rym: It's a human with blue skin because there's no point of year there.
Rym: That butt's kind of disturbing because you can see way into it.
Scott: Compared to the major's butt on a scale of one to major.
Rym: Dude, this is like 0.6 major butts.
Rym: This is a for real butt.
Scott: Is it a cyborg butt?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Or is it a flesh butt?
Rym: I don't know what kind of butt it is.
Scott: It's like you're a butt expert.
Rym: I'm not much of an expert.
Scott: You're just a poop expert.
Scott: Poops and clocks.
Rym: Yeah, you know what we were talking about the other day?
Rym: Poop report.
Scott: That's your thing.
Rym: I feel like I should start reading that again.
Rym: So, also super brief news.
Rym: Five Nights at Freddy's was popular and successful.
Rym: There's already a sequel.
Scott: That was fast.
Rym: Five Nights at Freddy's 2.
Rym: Little salty about that.
Scott: Didn't you die in the first one?
Scott: How is there a second one already?
Rym: Different person.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I guess it follows the continuity.
Rym: If you'd listen to my lecture on losing, you'd understand the narrative of failure versus the narrative of success.
Rym: This is the narrative of success.
Rym: The guy survived Five Nights at Freddy's, got fired, and I guess they reopened Five Nights at Freddy's with new safety measures.
Rym: Basically, they give you a Freddy mask you can wear.
Rym: So, the things won't kill you anymore.
Rym: I'm assuming that just doesn't fucking work.
Rym: So, we'll see.
Scott: Just put it on and leave it on.
Rym: There are already like a hundred live streams of this game.
Rym: So, you can see where gaming culture is going.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: So, Scott, have you ever heard of Rat Boy Genius Dreams?
Scott: No.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Rat Boy Genius Dreams is one of those things that shows that we're old and it's one of those things that's very popular among the Minecraft kid sets.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Then it'll be popular among the Rym set as well.
Rym: No.
Rym: Not by default, no.
Rym: Because I don't like those things.
Scott: But you like all sorts of weird shit.
Rym: I do like weird shit.
Rym: So, this is where these things intersect.
Rym: While that is where this thing is from, what it is is so internet that you just have to watch it.
Rym: This is official, the official version of Potato Knishes.
Scott: Potato Knishes are pretty delicious.
Rym: That kind of rhymed.
Rym: That's the point.
Rym: I defy you to not get this song stuck in your head.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: That's my thing of the day.
Scott: If it gets stuck in my head, I can just like deploy 10 K-pop songs at you.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I was watching some old PMVs the other day and that fixed me from this song.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, usually when you see a dash cam video, right?
Scott: The person with the cam is in the right and they catch something on their cam that is not in the right.
Scott: For example, the typical Russian scenario of slamming on the brakes so that someone will hit you from behind, you get the insurance, whatever.
Scott: So, this guy with the cam is actually tailgating.
Scott: He is not driving well.
Scott: I mean, I guess he's not driving super dangerously, but he's definitely tailgating the guy in front of him, which is not cool.
Scott: He tailgated the wrong motherfucker and his cam captured all and I'm surprised he uploaded it.
Rym: I don't think we should even spoil it.
Scott: Just watch this and if you're in China, just don't tailgate anybody.
Scott: No matter where you live, if you're driving, don't tailgate anyone.
Scott: All I want to say is- But, if you are tailgating someone, just pretend that it's this dude and you will stop.
Rym: This looks like a scene from a movie trailer.
Scott: The guy who the guy could be, I would hire him to be in a movie and also I want the driving gloves that he has.
Rym: Because that is the kind of thing that happens in the kinds of Asian cinema that we like and actually haven't been watching a lot of movies in that genre lately.
Scott: You know, there's also a small possibility this could have been staged just for awesomeness.
Rym: Yeah, could have been.
Scott: I don't care if it was.
Rym: I don't care either.
Scott: I'm betting it wasn't though.
Rym: In the meta moment, the Book Club book is finally going to be announced and it is the classic, the famous Watership Down.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's super enthusiastic about rabbits.
Rym: So, this book is one of the first books to ever do the thing that it did the way that it did it.
Rym: It's arguably one of the earlier inspirations for things that later became like Mouse Guard, for example.
Rym: Like that genre- Don't you mean Redwall?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Redwall's actually quite different.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: In what way?
Rym: We'll do our Book Club show about it.
Rym: Eh, right.
Rym: It's closer to Rats of NIMH.
Scott: Animal Farm?
Rym: There are plenty of animal store novel fictions.
Rym: You'll see when I read the book.
Scott: There are plenty of fictions involving talking animals.
Scott: Charlotte's Web?
Rym: Talking animals is not the sole thing that makes this that possible for Janitor.
Scott: But it's the primary.
Rym: Eh, actually I don't think so.
Scott: You don't think so?
Rym: No, I don't think so.
Rym: Also, a lot of the art people I know really like this book.
Rym: And a lot of the people I know who like things like Mouse Guard like this book.
Rym: And a lot of people reference this book often and you probably don't realize it.
Scott: That's probably true, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So I'm going to just have to work really hard to get through this book and also find a book that I will enjoy very much that Rym will feel similarly about.
Rym: Scott, don't go down that fucking road.
Rym: So Scott, I'm turning around.
Rym: I'm not actually doing it because this is not video.
Rym: You're turning around with- This is the guy in Scott's Thing of the Day made.
Rym: Don't start this.
Rym: Because this road, the road you're on- Leads to a certain dumbass.
Scott: It leads to Alexandre Dumas.
Scott: A certain dumbass.
Rym: It leads to Dumas.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Which Dumas depends it- Should I just at this point, if he sends one of yours to the hospital, you send ten of him to the three musketeers.
Scott: I'd rather read that than your- Count of Monte Cristo?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Which is possibly his best work.
Scott: Listen, we don't got time for that.
Rym: I do.
Scott: No, we don't.
Scott: Yeah, because you already spent that time.
Scott: That time is spent.
Rym: In another meta bit, we made a new kind of video.
Rym: It's a kind of GeekNights programming we've never done before.
Rym: So we did it.
Rym: We uploaded a raw version of it on YouTube, partly to get comments.
Rym: What this is, Scott and I put on microphones, grabbed a camera, and literally just did what we do and have done at every expo hall and dealer's room of every convention for the last decade plus, but we recorded it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, people go to pecs and they go to the expo hall or whatever and they spend way too much fucking time in there waiting in lines and doing other stupid shit.
Scott: How long is this video?
Rym: This video is only 37 minutes long.
Rym: It's edited down, right?
Rym: Here's what is not included in this video.
Rym: Every time we were just fighting through a crowd, every time we had a conversation with a friend that we bumped into, every time I went to the bathroom or something, and the indie mega booth, because that is not expo hall.
Rym: That is the indie mega booth.
Scott: That's about an hour's worth of stuff.
Scott: It still means that if any of you give us a whole hour, even if you give us two hours for that, that is the entire pecs expo hall done in two and a half hours.
Scott: You walk around, you look around, and then you're done, and then you play tabletop games.
Rym: So, if you have any comments about this, let us know, because we're going to do this with much higher production values at pretty much every pecs forever now.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, we had to do it sort of crappily to learn lessons, to do it less crappily next time, but monopod will definitely be awesome.
Rym: Honestly, considering how crappily and quickly we threw this together, like doing it, a surprising number of gem choice moments occurred.
Scott: There are, I mean, I watched it, which I usually don't watch or listen to our own shit, but I wanted to see, and for all the parts that are not so good, there are a bunch of parts that are pretty good.
Rym: That guy.
Scott: I mean, I think you overdid it a little bit, you know, with that guy.
Rym: That guy, are you kidding?
Rym: Do you know how many people have already like commented on YouTube or been like, "That guy was the best part of the video.
Rym: That guy, that guy, that
Rym: guy.".
Scott: Yeah, those are the same people who like shit like your thing of the day.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Do you know what the song I used was from?
Scott: I don't remember the song.
Rym: Does anyone out there know what the song is just from?
Scott: I had to listen to it again.
Rym: All right, I'll bet you don't.
Rym: The brain thing was pretty good.
Scott: I know.
Rym: The moment where we're walking around, we walk by basically the saddest fake laptop in the world, and it's an Xbox.
Scott: Oh, the Xbox in the briefcase.
Rym: And I start laughing at it because like they're all updating.
Scott: Listen, there is someone in the world who needs that.
Rym: Yeah, but the conversation we had there was pretty good.
Rym: The fact that all the Xboxes were updating at PAX and no one could play them was just too ironically delicious, and Scott thought it was a PS3.
Scott: I mean, I didn't look at it very closely.
Rym: But no, this video was surprisingly watchable.
Rym: I was really surprised.
Rym: Also, that guy with the dice fetish, I think he wins the prize.
Scott: That guy's an awesome guy.
Rym: Yeah, he was.
Rym: Just don't go into his dice dungeon.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: We'll make better videos like this at other times.
Rym: Yeah, we will.
Scott: Can we actually do the show now?
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So Smash Brothers.
Scott: Came out on the 3DS.
Scott: The first time ever that there has been a portable Smash Brothers, and it is here, and we have had it for some weeks now.
Rym: I was highly dubious when this was first announced, this whole.
Rym: there's a Wii U and a 3DS one, because Nintendo has ignored the linkages between their devices since Four Swords.
Rym: Like they just, they fucking just dropped that train, even though it was-.
Scott: Well, the only linkage here is that you can use the 3DS one as a controller for playing the Wii one.
Scott: Which is okay.
Scott: If you get used to the 3DS controls, it's basically the same game, right?
Scott: If you get used to that as your controller, why switch it up?
Rym: Who can play any Smash Brothers that's not on the DS without a GameCube controller at this point?
Scott: You just can't.
Rym: So I was highly dubious that it would not be dumbed down in some fashion.
Rym: It's a real Smash.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like it's a real Smash Brothers.
Rym: It's legit.
Rym: It's all the fun and everything that Smash Brothers has always been.
Rym: And for a Smash Brothers, if you like Smash Brothers, you're obligated to get it, because it's the one.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, as far as competitiveness goes, going on the words of other people, they say it's legit, but I'm not, I can't even, I know there's a thing called the Wave Dash.
Scott: I can't do it and wouldn't even know if I did it by accident.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Never play this game with Scott.
Rym: If items are on, you will get nothing but him bitching about how the items ruin the game.
Rym: Even though somehow the items only ever kill him, so something's up there.
Scott: We could play again with, if you play enough times with items, some games, one person will get the good items and some games, the other person will get the good items.
Rym: You just don't, it's not about, I didn't get good items.
Rym: I just use the items effectively.
Rym: They're a part of the game.
Scott: But the problem is which item appears and who it appears near.
Rym: If a good item appears near your opponent, don't let him fucking get it.
Scott: It's kind of hard to do if you're far away and it appears at that moment.
Rym: Why are you far away, Scott?
Rym: Didn't you tell me that you should never be far away?
Rym: Wasn't that your other bitch?
Rym: So if I play fast and close to Scott, he bitches about how like, how come that hit me?
Rym: Uh, Scott, because of frame timing.
Rym: Frame timing is bullshit.
Scott: They should explain it.
Rym: And if I hang far away from him, he's like, how come you're hiding from me?
Rym: How come you're hiding from me?
Rym: Why don't you get up close?
Rym: And I get up close and I start like frame timing him again.
Rym: He's like, frame time's bullshit.
Scott: You don't know any frame timing balls.
Scott: You can just say that.
Scott: Scott.
Scott: Well, you don't know shit.
Rym: You had like, no.
Scott: If you had to play against a pro smash to play, you probably wouldn't even hit them even once.
Rym: I hit him one more time than you.
Scott: So zero times.
Scott: So, and then you start bitching.
Scott: I'm not saying I would hit him.
Rym: But then you start bitching like, oh, we got to play final.
Rym: We can't play these maps.
Scott: But I won on that final destination.
Rym: Yeah, barely.
Rym: It was a pretty solid.
Rym: Also, so you barely won and.
Scott: I won about half the games he played.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You barely won the final destination.
Rym: And I killed myself because I just jumped off the stage.
Scott: He was talking like he was like completely dominating.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We played many variations of different maps, different characters.
Scott: Items, no items.
Scott: Winning, losing.
Scott: And we won about the same rate.
Rym: My only point is that Scott playing this game with Scott, whether or not you were winning or losing is nothing but a litany of him bitching.
Rym: That is my only point.
Scott: But I'm not bitching like, you know, like John's where it's like excuses for losing.
Scott: I'm bitching like, why is the game this way?
Scott: Explain it to me.
Scott: And no one, even pro people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Can't explain it.
Scott: And it's the same.
Scott: It's basically the same shit you have with.
Rym: It's got wise counter strike that way.
Rym: Explain.
Scott: There is nothing to it.
Scott: There is nothing in counter strike.
Scott: that is mysterious.
Rym: So, Scott, do you know what, how much damage reduction is applied by every different surface you can shoot through?
Scott: It doesn't really matter.
Rym: Do you know the points to preshoot, to get guaranteed headshots and all the sniper spots?
Scott: That also doesn't really matter.
Rym: That matters more.
Scott: But it's not like in counter strike, you're playing and it's like, why did I die?
Scott: It's like, well, because it's exactly like that.
Scott: No, it's because somebody saw you had their mouse pointed at you and press the button.
Rym: Why did you die that one time in smash?
Rym: Because I use the toad counter, which is way powerful.
Scott: But there's never a situation in counter strike where, for example, I click on someone and bullets don't come out or the bullets, you know, just didn't do any damage, even though they hit.
Rym: Yeah, that happens all the time.
Rym: There's bullets scattered.
Rym: So you've got the crosshair point.
Scott: I'm saying even though they hit and you miss, there's never a situation where I aim at someone and the bullets just go in the opposite direction for no reason or, you know, nothing.
Scott: that doesn't make sense.
Scott: Just, you know, common sense wise, the details of how much damage was done.
Scott: So it's a thing.
Rym: I use the toad counter and it fucked you up.
Rym: Then you ate me.
Rym: And you use the toad counter and I hit you.
Rym: And the reason I hit you in that moment where you went crazy was because I was attacking you from a downward angle above the toad.
Rym: That makes sense even in the animation of the game.
Scott: But here's the thing that you're not seeing is that you're just looking at what's on the screen as someone who's playing the game.
Scott: It's like at that moment I was pressing buttons and they're both buttons cause no reaction whatsoever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And in Counter-Strike, at least if I press a button, even if I die instantly, bullets come out.
Rym: No.
Rym: So if you jump, try to jump again right away.
Rym: Doesn't work.
Scott: Yeah, it does.
Scott: You can jump twice.
Rym: Not the, you don't play much Counter-Strike, do you?
Rym: You slow down when you jump.
Rym: Your guy gets all fucked up when you jump.
Scott: Oh, you're talking about Counter-Strike.
Scott: I thought you had Smash Brothers.
Rym: No.
Rym: But Smash Brothers.
Rym: So, right.
Scott: But it's, but it's like if I'm playing, I'm playing a game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I press a button and then the expected reaction of pressing that button does not occur.
Scott: That is where this, the root of frustration, and it happens so fast.
Scott: That's a really slow move.
Scott: There's no explanation for it.
Rym: So you hit the button to start a slow move.
Scott: I'm a slow and old person.
Rym: While my foot was, my peach foot was already about to hit you in the face.
Rym: That was the problem.
Rym: You hit the button way too late.
Scott: But that's the problem is if it's already past the point of no return, I should have been hit already as opposed to, it looks like I'm about to get hit.
Scott: There are still frames of animation happening.
Scott: If I'm not actually hit yet, then it feels like I should be able to press a button to do something.
Rym: Because you could have hit a different button to do a faster attack.
Rym: Use a jab, use a jab instead of a heavy attack in Street Fighter.
Scott: But Smash Brothers, are you telling me that if someone's hitting you, you can press, there's only one button to press in Smash Brothers, which is A.
Rym: So Scott, if you just hit A.
Scott: If you push A and I push A, who wins?
Scott: We push A at the exact same time and we're both next to each other.
Rym: Exact same time?
Scott: We're both exactly next to each other.
Scott: We're in range of A and we both just press A. We use a robot that presses both A buttons simultaneously.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, it depends on the characters.
Scott: So give me a whole list of all the possible combinations.
Rym: Go look that up.
Rym: I'm sure someone's written a guide.
Scott: This is the kind of bullshit.
Scott: But the thing is, if you haven't memorized that.
Rym: Scott, what happens if two hockey players hit the puck as robots in the exact same time, the exact same way?
Rym: Tell me.
Rym: Tell me right now.
Scott: Every combination of things that can happen, the two sticks will hit the puck and the puck will be stuck between the sticks with my timing.
Rym: If I hit the ball, if I hit the puck at a slightly at all these different angles, tell me now exactly how that's all going to play out.
Scott: This is the thing is that there's so many possible combinations and timings of every possible move that's just in every possible position that Scott is too old to play fighting games, obviously.
Scott: But as you are playing it, if you are not an expert, if you are not a pro player, it can be frustrating because the expected result of just natural common sense, how you feel it should be, does not match the reality in any
Rym: way more than you, because what happens matches what I expect.
Scott: Like if you're Kirby and you do your like rock coming down, like if I turn into a rock and I'm staying in rock form, I expect to be pretty much invincible unless you use a grab to pick me up.
Rym: Scott, I'm piloting a robot with a propeller probably made out of like titanium and diamond or some shit.
Rym: Rocks can be easily broken.
Rym: What kind of rock is this?
Rym: Scott?
Rym: What kind of rock?
Rym: How do you know?
Rym: it's not talc?
Scott: It's made of Kirby.
Scott: It's very much the hardest rock ever.
Rym: Kirby's not made out of rock.
Scott: Kirby's a Kirby.
Scott: He turns into rock.
Rym: What kind of rock?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's what I thought.
Rym: That's what I thought.
Scott: Bismuth?
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Rym: There was a study.
Rym: I don't know if I'll build it.
Rym: I'll try to find the link to link to it in the show notes.
Rym: If I don't, I'll try to find it and link it in the forum, but the study showed that people who I believe are over the age of 24, I think 24 was the line.
Scott: Reaction times are garbage.
Rym: It's not that reaction times are garbage.
Rym: It's that the reaction times will slow in terms of how quick your finger actually moves, but you will perceive and feel as though you clicked or moved quicker than you physically did.
Scott: That's probably true.
Rym: Your body straight up lies to you.
Scott: That's 100% true.
Rym: You think you hit B before my foot got to your character's face, but in reality you hit it like after you were taking damage and your brain just lied to you.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So just play enough to be able to compensate for that a little bit.
Rym: Like expect that.
Rym: You're old.
Rym: You're going to die soon.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, it's over.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: We're dead.
Scott: The thing I always wondered, right, is like all fighting games, you know, competitive or not.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you push a button and an animation, you know, begins when you press the button and you know, some moves can cancel the animation to switch to something else.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like if I'm doing a release, but others, others can't.
Rym: So like if my character's hauling back to do a really hard punch and someone else hits me with a jab, imagine if you're hauling back to do a really strong punch slowly and someone just jabs you in the kidney.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Obviously that makes sense.
Rym: It's going to disrupt your animation.
Scott: But if I, you know, push the haul back to punch button and I see your animation of jab begin, if I put, I should be able to, while that haul back animation is not yet completed, I expect to be able to push a different button to switch things up.
Rym: Now you say that, but if I somehow push it in time, you say that, have you ever studied a martial art?
Scott: Not really.
Scott: Not anything that would count.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Go.
Rym: I was going to say not counting like taekwondo in elementary school.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So let's say you're doing some sort of like uppercut pumps, like for real, like you're doing like an uppercut and then suddenly you see that your opponent has a jab coming in with one of their hands at your unguarded, a soft and tender kidney.
Rym: How quickly can you as a human redirect your body's momentum to react to that?
Scott: Me as a human, I couldn't even do the uppercut to begin with, but I admit not me as a human.
Scott: This is Kirby.
Scott: It was a pink ball of puff.
Rym: You don't know what Kirby's musculature is like.
Rym: What is circulatory systems like?
Scott: He's a hundred percent muscle.
Scott: In fact, that he doesn't even have a skin.
Scott: It's just exposed muscle.
Scott: A hundred percent muscles.
Scott: Kirby is nothing but power.
Rym: Wait, so he's muscle up.
Rym: Scott, I'm riding a metal machine.
Scott: Samus is a metal machine.
Rym: Which Samus was?
Rym: Zero suit Samus.
Rym: That's just a girl.
Scott: That's even stronger.
Rym: I know.
Scott: Right?
Scott: I mean, Link has a sword.
Scott: If I sword you and you're punching, your hand should be chopped up.
Scott: I mean, we're not going to take it that far, right?
Rym: But you know, it's just- A sword's heavier and way slower to swing.
Scott: I'm just really curious.
Scott: What if someone made a fighting game where literally like every single, any press whatsoever would cancel anything, no matter what.
Rym: So you could react- So they would be all jabs?
Scott: No, you could just react to everything, right?
Scott: And it would basically be like this really fast rock, paper, scissors until someone was too slow.
Scott: Because you'd be like, you see a rock coming, the rock takes three frames.
Rym: I'm reading a thing here about King of Fighters 13 and it's saying something about how everything's fully cancelable.
Rym: I've never played King of Fighters.
Scott: I was never- I don't know either.
Rym: King of Fighters is so outside of fighting games I care about.
Rym: I know nothing.
Scott: We're like talking about fighting games you know nothing about.
Rym: Here's my order of fighting games that I actually know enough about to be able to play.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: The top of that list is still Soul Calibur.
Rym: Soul Calibur 2.
Scott: Not any other Soul Calibur.
Scott: Well I guess I'm really good at Soul Edge and Soul Calibur 1.
Rym: I can play?
Scott: Soul Calibur 2 is the jam.
Rym: I can play newer Soul Calivers?
Rym: I'm just not as good.
Scott: I mean I couldn't do any pro stuff at Soul Calibur.
Scott: but Soul Calibur is actually a great example of it's a game where things aren't cancelable, right?
Scott: But A, it's kind of slower.
Scott: so as an old person it works better but everything sort of makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, tell me how anything Voldo does makes sense.
Scott: But I mean in terms of the animations you see on the screen, the buttons you press, the things that happen, it's like you can understand that you don't really get into situations even when you lose horribly.
Scott: Like oh that was both, you know I pressed the button, it didn't, it's like no because you saw you had this big heavy sword in the air slowly moving down and someone kicked you in the gut.
Rym: Close normals are the fastest normal attack, faster than a crouching light attack and they're fully cancelable.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: There's no list of, no one is rated fighting games based on percentage of moves that are cancelable.
Rym: That's the thing.
Rym: Someone get on that.
Scott: I mean the fundamental game would be like rock, paper, scissors, but it's not reveal simultaneously.
Scott: It's you have three buttons, rock, paper, and scissors.
Scott: You push one.
Scott: It takes three seconds for that one to execute.
Scott: So if you push rock like or not three seconds, but like, you know, three milliseconds or three hundredths of a second, whatever it is, three tenths of a second, I guess is reasonable for a human.
Scott: It takes three tens of a second for the rock to execute.
Scott: If somewhere in those three tenths of a second, the other guy presses the paper button, you're going to be in trouble.
Rym: But why would you be though?
Rym: Because your rock would finish before his paper finished.
Scott: But he's already pressed paper in the time window.
Scott: So you're basically, your rock is going to get covered.
Rym: All you're saying is that if I, someone doesn't attack at me and then I react to them, my reaction attack is faster now because I'm reacting.
Rym: That's what you're saying.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So how you're supposed to, that's how almost every counter system works in fighting games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So then if I see his paper, I have until the time that my rock finishes to push scissor instead.
Rym: So you know what?
Rym: You can do two or three changes of that and then humans can't react that fast and that's it.
Rym: The game becomes random.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it would be awesome.
Rym: Why don't we make it and watch what happens.
Scott: Basically, I think it would be really interesting if you started it really slowly.
Scott: It's like the first thing you press takes five seconds to land.
Scott: And then the next, so the guy's five seconds and then the next one takes like, you know, wait a minute.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So, so you hit paper.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: If I do nothing, can you still change it?
Rym: If paper, if you change anything at all hits, if you change it and I've still done nothing is the timer reset?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I will never do anything until the last possible, you hit a button no matter what you hit.
Rym: I'll just wait.
Rym: And if it gets with, if you get to like that last millisecond, then I'll counter you because you probably can't physically react that quick.
Scott: Maybe what you, I think maybe the way it might've to design it is where every move you do basically starts slow and accelerates.
Scott: It's like, so it's like you have this, it's like every time someone presses a button.
Rym: Starts slow and accelerates is just an animation.
Rym: I would ignore it and count beats instead.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: But I mean, so there's no actual acceleration.
Scott: It's going to be about, it's, it's sort of like Simon Says, but really fast.
Rym: Here's how I would do it instead.
Rym: It's like it's paper, rock, scissors, right?
Rym: So the, or Simon Says, same thing.
Rym: Every time you hit an attack, you can hold any button down.
Rym: You can only hold one down at a time.
Rym: If you're holding one down, it's like you've got rock out.
Rym: and every time you hit rock, it does say 0.5 damage to the person.
Rym: If they're not doing anything, if they are holding rock or hit rock at the same time, then you cancel each other out.
Rym: No one's doing any damage.
Rym: And then if you do the attack that breaks someone else's out or simultaneous attack, you do double damage.
Scott: So basically you have a set of buttons for switching between rock, paper and scissor, and then one button that actually puts it out there.
Scott: Or it could be out or not out.
Rym: Or I'd say if you hit the button, it goes out and does damage.
Rym: If it like it hits and then it stays out doing no more damage, but doing its block.
Scott: That's not bad.
Scott: Like rock, paper or scissor, you can switch between them at will with three buttons and there's an attack button.
Scott: And if you put the rock paper or scissor out and there's no response to it, it does one point of damage.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So if the response to it is the is wrong, like if you put out a scissor and they put out a paper, you do like 10 damage.
Scott: If you put out a, you know, and then you have to take like you both put scissor, but it does zero damage.
Rym: The only way to make this work is you have to take like triple crazy damage if you attack the thing you're weak against.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because otherwise I win by basically mashing my keyboard simultaneously.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Anyway, there's your fighting game.
Scott: So more about Smash Brothers.
Scott: So let's talk about all the other stuff that's in the Smash Brothers besides Smash Brothers.
Rym: It's a well, it's so it's a great list of characters.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The character list is incredibly cool.
Rym: The I can't.
Scott: I'm having a hard time thinking of characters they didn't put in that I want besides boo.
Rym: I was about to say boo or generic Koopa.
Scott: You know, I can't go that deep.
Rym: Here's the show.
Rym: All right.
Rym: You want to know characters.
Scott: It could have been more of zero guys besides Captain Falcon.
Scott: That would have been nice because they have non too many fantasy type people with swords.
Rym: I really want to take one of those out.
Rym: I want Kaboom guy.
Scott: OK, sure.
Rym: That's the guy.
Scott: That's more of an item than a.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There should be an assist trophy.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But I still want him.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, Duck Hunt.
Scott: Dog is probably the most creative, amazing character.
Rym: Also, fuck Duck Hunt.
Scott: Dog.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Pretty much.
Rym: I pretty much play Pete.
Rym: My order is I play Peach Koopa kid and I usually either play Iggy or actual Koopa kid.
Scott: I like Game and Watch guy.
Rym: Game and Watch is right under that.
Scott: Pac-Man and Kirby.
Scott: But Kirby is like the most straightforward to use.
Rym: And Sam is still, of course, he's my spirit animal in every Smash Brothers.
Rym: Peach has been the character I played most of the time.
Rym: If I if I'm playing for serious, I'm playing Peach.
Scott: Peach got really juiced up.
Scott: They juiced up Peach big time.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: Peach has always been pretty juiced.
Scott: Now even more juiced.
Rym: They actually kind of gimped Falco.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Falco is not as good.
Rym: Falco used to have this like sideways.
Scott: Falco used to be like pro level, but now not, you know.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, of course, pro players are probably like, what the fuck is wrong with you guys?
Scott: As far as we're talking about, like how good they are for unskilled people using them.
Rym: Or like people of our skill, which is one step above or below.
Scott: The main reason I use Kirby is because Kirby is really easy to use for unskilled people because all his stuff, like he controls normally in like a way you would expect as a normal human being.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Not strangely like some of the characters like Duck Hunt Dog or whatever.
Rym: But I like some clever stuff like how Koopa Kid's like special up is like his third jump to escape.
Rym: He just literally throws the machine he's riding down and then it explodes.
Rym: You don't expect that shit unless you played this game a lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He hit me with it and I didn't even know that that was the thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You got to play that game more.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You already done?
Scott: I mean, I've already played so much of it that it's sort of like, okay, there's no real reason to play it except if it's multiplayer.
Rym: So surprisingly light variety in the number of stages and I actually don't like several of the stages.
Scott: Some of the stages.
Scott: I'm not into the stages.
Rym: Several of the stages have, they're so dangerous that even among like pretty skilled players, you can win at least if you're playing stock by letting the whole game is don't let the stage kill you.
Scott: I mean, there have always been stages that like move and stuff like that and have dangerous environments in them.
Scott: But in this one, it's like.
Scott: some of the environments are just so ludicrously dangerous or they scroll so crazy fast or whatever.
Scott: It's not like, like the most dangerous one used to be the F zero one, which they still have.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Now the rainbow road one's pretty similar.
Rym: It's actually not dangerous.
Rym: That one.
Scott: I'm fine with rainbow road.
Scott: I like rainbow road actually, but I don't like Gerudo village is pretty fucking dangerous.
Rym: The mega man one is fucking mega man one.
Scott: The yellow devil fills up the entire screen.
Rym: What's funny is because when I was playing with good people at packs, whenever the devil appeared, everyone sorta had this semi truce and they'd all attack the devil to like kill him.
Rym: So we get back to fighting and a few, and I can't like people like if you, if you left an opening, people would obviously attack you.
Rym: But like there was this unspoken thing that you went after that thing.
Rym: I don't go after that.
Scott: No, I just try to stay alive.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's, it's like if Phil, it's a dangerous thing that fills up the entire stage.
Scott: It's very, very hard to do anything about it if you're not pro.
Scott: It's like just play.
Scott: You could play single player in that level and it would be hard.
Rym: Well granted, I was hanging out behind him on that tiny ledge and you did your Kirby rock down and tried to hit me there.
Scott: But there's a tiny ledge.
Scott: I thought the rock was going to land on that ledge.
Rym: I shielded, so I pushed you a little bit and then you just missed the ledge.
Scott: I thought the rock goes through the shield.
Rym: No, it doesn't go through the shield.
Scott: That doesn't make sense.
Rym: What goes through the shield?
Scott: A giant rock that lands directly on top of it.
Scott: At the very least, it should land on top of the shield and sit there going hit, hit, hit, hit, hit until the shield breaks.
Scott: At least, you know, I just sit on your head as a rock.
Scott: Why should I fall off the side?
Rym: At that point, why should we even fight?
Rym: Why don't we just walk around and hang out?
Scott: We should.
Rym: Happy.
Rym: So yeah, the levels are... I mean, I like a lot of...
Scott: Wasn't the first Smash Brothers commercial for N64 like the Happy Together song?
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: That era, I was 100% PC.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Like I did not even own an N64.
Scott: I'm talking about the TV commercial.
Rym: I'm just saying, I didn't watch TV then either.
Rym: I had never played Smash Brothers until RIT because consoles were stupid baby games when I was in high school.
Rym: Where I lived, who I hung out with, my high school, the cable modems that we got early, it was console baby games and PC.
Scott: Smash Brothers N64 is not a baby game.
Rym: Yeah, but consoles were for babies in my high school.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: You know what the only games people played?
Rym: They played Smash.
Rym: I thought it was stupid looking and they played Blitz.
Rym: That was the only two games they ever played.
Scott: But you did not play any Blitz.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There was no Blitz happening.
Rym: They'd alternate between Smash and Blitz, Smash and Blitz.
Scott: There was no Blitz happening where I lived.
Rym: If we were at a camp, we'd play Goldeneye.
Rym: That was it.
Rym: Even then, Goldeneye, they showed me Goldeneye.
Rym: Like, "Oh, let's play Goldeneye.
Rym: Goldeneye.".
Rym: I'd never played a multiplayer.
Rym: They were flipping their shit about how awesome it was.
Scott: They played Goldeneye because they didn't have cable modems in their neighborhood.
Rym: All I could think was like, "Really?
Rym: This is like baby's first
Rym: LAN.".
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's wrong with you kids.
Scott: People don't have cable modems.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They weren't privileged to live in such a neighborhood.
Rym: Also, I had local LANs and LAN parties and no modems.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know how many of my friends had a computer that wasn't just like their parents' computer that they could pick it up and bring it somewhere?
Rym: When I convinced my parents- I was the only one who had a separate- I was like, "I need to buy a thing called a null modem.
Rym: I'm not even going to try to explain to you what it is, but I need one of
Rym: them.".
Scott: I was the only person who had their own computer that they built themselves.
Scott: That wasn't until senior year when I had money.
Scott: Anyway, the rest of the Smash Brothers stuff.
Scott: They got the All-Star mode and the Classic mode.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: In GameCube, I never played any of that bullshit ever.
Rym: Never once played that game single player ever.
Rym: In the next one that came out, also never.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Never.
Scott: Never, never, never ever played- You didn't play it in your 3DS?
Rym: 3DS, I only played it until I unlocked all the characters and I never played it again.
Rym: That Brawl, Smash Run mode, eh.
Scott: Smash Run mode is interesting because it starts out, basically, walk around this big map hitting stuff and getting stuff to power up, and then we're going to put you into an unknown mystery competition.
Scott: It might be a jumping competition, a race, or a fight.
Scott: You don't know which one.
Scott: If you did know which one in advance, then you might concentrate on getting the power-ups that would help you with it.
Scott: Instead, it's a mystery.
Scott: You can't, and the thing is, if you take out the powering up part at the beginning, which is sort of annoying and time consuming, and sort of really determines who's going to win the next one-
Rym: I've found that it usually does not determine-
Scott: Here's the thing- If you get a bunch of speed boosts and no one else does, and it's a race, you just
Rym: win.
Rym: The problem is- Here's the real problem.
Rym: The race is a bullshit mode.
Rym: I like it, but it's stupid.
Scott: I think that if you had the race, but all you chose was a character- The characters all run at the same speed is really stupid.
Scott: I played one of those once just where- It's about dodging obstacles and such.
Rym: Yeah, you think that.
Rym: I played it once where by chance- And maneuvering and hitting the other people.
Rym: Three of the players had basically the same speed.
Rym: Everyone's running at the same speed, dodging all the obstacles basically perfectly.
Rym: If you tried to attack anyone, you just fell behind, then you could never catch up ever.
Rym: That was it.
Scott: It has the potential to be more like that game we played at PAX.
Rym: Which was a good idea, poorly executed.
Rym: I got all the fun I needed out of that game by playing it at PAX, because it just wasn't.
Scott: But it's like there's something there.
Rym: There is.
Rym: No one's made that game though.
Scott: But anyway, so yeah, there's no reason to play Smash Run mode really.
Rym: I'd like to play it with more humans.
Scott: Because also- I wish that you were in the Smash, the first part with the other characters and not by yourself.
Rym: Yeah, that would be a lot more fun.
Scott: Because then I wouldn't- Because then you can go around trying to prevent people from getting power-ups.
Rym: Yeah, kill some people and knock them down a peg before the real thing.
Rym: Right.
Rym: That would be way more fun.
Scott: The classic mode, it's very strange.
Scott: If I turn the difficulty up to the maximum, the highest possible level- All the way to the hands, and then they kill you.
Scott: I get all the way to the boss without dying, even on the hardest level, which makes me think for someone like me who sucks, what's up with the AI?
Rym: Because that's always been Smash Brothers.
Scott: But then the boss is just ridiculously hard.
Scott: It has all these phases, like tons and tons of phases, all the way up from giant person, two hands, everything.
Scott: So if you play on the hardest difficulty, it starts at the hardest phase, and then you have to beat it every single phase without dying.
Scott: You only have two lives to beat all those phases.
Scott: So when I get to that, I can only beat the boss starting at like phase five and a half, maybe, and working my way down from there.
Scott: It's really hard.
Scott: It's like you basically have to beat it by dodging tons and tons of attacks that are ridiculously hard to dodge, and then getting in like one pot shot when it's open and repeating that for a very, very long period of time.
Rym: Oh, like almost every boss fight in every game ever.
Scott: No, I mean, a lot of boss fights that are good boss fights, there'll be like, "Time is when you can get your hits in without getting hit too
Scott: badly.".
Scott: Super Metroid would be the difficulty that I'd be looking for in a high quality boss fight.
Scott: It's like, "If you know what you're doing, it's reasonable to beat this boss.
Scott: You're going to take some damage if you mess up a little bit.
Scott: You could die pretty
Scott: easily.".
Scott: The boss fight, and this might be one of the hardest, but if you count the level 10 boss, this might be one of the hardest boss fights ever.
Scott: I mean, not hardest video games ever.
Scott: It'd probably be easier to beat that than to beat all of Silver Surfer, but maybe one of the hardest boss fights ever in any video game.
Rym: All those modes, I remember watching people hanging out in our apartment at RIT, playing the single player Smash Brothers while we were hanging out, like you're on the GameCube.
Rym: That shit was boring, not fun, never was.
Rym: The single player in this game exists, and that's all that needs to be said about it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think there is some fun to be had in the single player.
Scott: Some of the stuff is sort of puzzly, like the baseball home run game has always been kind of puzzly.
Scott: It's like, "How do I, with this character, do as much damage as possible in a short period of time, and then still have time to use the bat, and also be in the right
Scott: position?".
Rym: I do enjoy that one only because it's so quick.
Scott: Yeah, and it resets really quickly, too.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of the other modes are not quick.
Scott: There's a lot of the different games like that, the minigames, there's something to them that is interesting.
Rym: Well, those are how to get good at the game in one sense, in that you need to be able to master how to do the combos and max out the damage on that sandbag.
Scott: Not that a game doesn't teach you this combo, you just sort of have to push buttons until you figure the shit out.
Rym: I ran into a problem with PAX with the game, because the real reason why I think this game is so important, because I'd say buy it if you care at all about Smash.
Rym: Unless you're in college, or in a place where you will have people physically over with a console, you're not going to get that old Smash Brothers feeling that often.
Scott: Unless you go to a convention or something.
Rym: You can just start a game of this anywhere with anyone who has a 3DS.
Rym: Play it a lot of just four player Smash, and two player Smash, just walking around PAX, it was totally awesome.
Rym: However, you can make it on Finale, couldn't play it, because everyone was trying to play it, and the wifi just failed and no one could play it.
Scott: That's always been true, even since the first DS.
Rym: Well, GBA solved that with the physical cable option.
Scott: Yeah, but no one hardly ever used that except us.
Rym: Only we did, for Advance 4 was once or twice, and then some jack off, because they had their worm light plugged into that thing, would bump the worm light and then everything would crash.
Scott: A whole four player game would be ruined by moving one cable, you think they could hot swap the fucking cable, seriously?
Rym: Yeah, I'm not saying we go back to those days.
Scott: No, but I mean, why can't they solve this fucking wifi problem?
Rym: Well, Scott, do you want to know why?
Rym: It's like signaling technology, just like there's not a lot you can do.
Scott: But like, you're Nintendo, you have enough money to manufacture all these 3DSs, right?
Scott: So set up a lab, and put in like a hundred radios all in the same room, and then force the radios to form, you know, a hundred, you know, twenty four player games, and keep working on it until all of them work.
Scott: And then, you're amazing.
Rym: So one, probably not possible with wifi.
Scott: Well, I mean, you don't work on some kind of wireless technology that makes it work.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of those frequencies aren't available worldwide.
Scott: Listen, there's got to be a solution.
Rym: I've done a lot of research on this stuff recently, because I was thinking about buying that wireless kit.
Scott: There's reasons.
Scott: I'm not saying it's easy, but you can do it.
Rym: Also, there was crazy powerful working wifi at all of Paxos.
Scott: That's amazing.
Rym: Oh my god, like, my T-Mobile like free global data roaming is working great, but I didn't get great cell signal.
Scott: Couldn't everyone use their DS's to connect to that wifi, and then sort of play on that?
Rym: No, because you couldn't click on the "I accept the terms of this bullshit" in the browser on the 3DS, so you couldn't actually get internet on it.
Scott: That sucks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, and also, if everyone tried to do that, I don't know how much bandwidth it actually had, but.
Scott: I mean, you could be, I hope it has LAN mode, right?
Scott: I never tried that.
Scott: Is that even a thing?
Scott: No.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Why don't they do that?
Rym: Why would they?
Rym: Who would use that?
Rym: but you and me?
Scott: Because you could have your DS connect to the internet at the same time, but if anyone else was on the same wifi network as you, you could play over that really quickly.
Rym: No one wants that except us.
Scott: A lot of people, I think, want that.
Rym: No one will buy the game.
Rym: who did not already buy the game because of that.
Scott: Obviously.
Rym: So, that wifi was also a factor, I think.
Rym: So, the only time it failed was the Omegathon finale while we were waiting, and the main events hall is gigantic, so.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But yeah, before the panel, I connected my laptop to the wifi, edited some slides, put a bunch of big images in, re-downloaded the 30 megabytes of slides, and then did the panel.
Rym: Like, I could not have done that at another convention.
Scott: Why didn't you have the slides?
Rym: No, because I thought of something and I really wanted to make a change to add a topic after I learned that no one in Australia, apparently, had ever heard overplayed Five Nights at Freddy's, and it was highly relevant to what I was talking about.
Scott: How did they not hear of this game that was all over the internet?
Rym: Yeah, no one in the room had heard of the game or played it except, like, one dude who I'd talked to earlier about it.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: So, yeah, I've gotten a lot of emails from people who were like, "Oh my god, that
Rym: game.".
Scott: Why are people, like, in Australia not on the internet?
Rym: Actually, you'll be happy.
Rym: A lot of people came up to me and thanked us, thanked you and me for learning about Burning Wheel.
Scott: Oh, you're shocking.
Rym: A listener sent me a long and very good question about Burning Wheel that I'm going to answer on the next Tuesday.
Rym: Geek Notes.
Scott: What question could they possibly ask?
Rym: The gist of it is basically, in our panels and talks and every time we try to sell people on Burning Wheel, the examples we use are pretty much always examples either from the book, from canned adventures, or, like, it's always the same examples.
Rym: So his question was basically, he's worried that we never use, like, our own personal anecdotes and examples.
Rym: Does the game actually play the way we talk about it?
Scott: If you play in a one-shot scenario.
Rym: No, but I'm saying, like, the question's a little more nuanced than that, but that's the gist of it.
Rym: And it's a really good question that I'll answer next time because I actually want to give a really long answer.
Scott: All right, whatever.
Scott: You made this episode really long.
Scott: You couldn't fit that in somewhere.
Rym: No, I could smash.
Rym: And we're back.
Rym: I'm full of energy.
Rym: I'm hungry, too.
Rym: It's Smash Brothers.
Scott: How much can you really say about it?
Rym: If you like Smash Brothers, buy this one and you'll play it a lot.
Scott: If you've never played Smash Brothers, you should go back and play the old Smash Brothers first.
Rym: Yeah, I would start with the GameCube one.
Rym: Yeah, well, OK, because I thought you were going to N64.
Scott: No, playing the N64 one is like telling someone who's never played a platform game before to play Mario Brothers and not play Super Mario Brothers.
Scott: You should play Super Mario Brothers if you've never played a platformer before.
Scott: You should play GameCube Smash Brothers if you've never played a Smash Brothers before.
Rym: But yeah, this game's actually super fun and pretty pro and good set of items.
Rym: You can turn the items off.
Scott: The Wii U one is going to have eight players simultaneous, which is going to be the ultimate party game.
Rym: I'm going to play that at other people's houses.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know where I'm going to play that?
Rym: You know where we're going to play that the most, I think?
Rym: Killy.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Do they Wii U there?
Rym: I'm sure they will.
Scott: Someone will bring one over?
Rym: I think they will.
Rym: And also, you know where else we're probably going to play it?
Rym: Wildman.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Thank you.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Media: Little black squash balls.
Media: This machine creates little black squash balls.
Media: It brings potato pancakes to the black squash balls.
Media: This is where I make centipedes.
Media: I sure love to make centipedes.
Media: I turn little black worms into centipedes.
Rym: It's Thursday!
Rym: Nope.
Scott: No it's not.