Rym: It's Monday August 25th 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight Electricity it's all Rym.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, I sort of realized that Despite the fact that we thought oh, you know We got a bunch of free time tons of episodes tons of GeekNights and then packs I kind of forgot that after packs I got a fly like all over the goddamn world and gonna miss a bunch of shows.
Rym: because of packs OS and a bunch of weddings and An FPL show in Singapore and swinging through Istanbul and London I guess I'll be able to play a lot of netrunner in.
Rym: yeah I should leave everything set up so you and Emily can do the show while I'm gone.
Rym: Yeah, you guys could totally pull it off or I could just play netrunner.
Rym: Yeah So, uh the other day is biking to work right and I felt as is tradition That's what I talk about
Scott: and
Rym: I'm just going really fucking slow and I feel really tired and old man Which occasionally happens like you're
Scott: using like this top gear for no for accident
Rym: No, so I was using my normal gears and I'm just really tired And I'm like I made an okay time like Strava was like, yeah You were like three minutes longer than I just felt like shit the whole way going in and I felt like I really struggled Over the bridges.
Rym: so I kind of write it off.
Rym: I get extra coffee.
Rym: I'm at work.
Rym: I do my thing on the way home.
Rym: I also ride like shit and I feel like crap.
Rym: It's just like this terrible ride.
Rym: So I go to bed early and the next morning I get up and I start to bike and again I feel like crap.
Rym: So I decide that something's wrong.
Scott: which part of your body felt like crap?
Scott: my legs Okay.
Rym: Before I had maybe I had thought that maybe I'd worn myself out from like rock climbing and like my muscles just needed a day To recuperate or maybe I was getting sick.
Rym: but I start to bike again and It's just really hard to go up this hill and I look down and it says I'm in the gear I expect myself to be in.
Rym: and then I sort of Decide that maybe something's wrong with my bike because I hadn't inspected the bike previously because on the bike to work I was in a hurry.
Rym: I had to get to work I had a meeting and on the bike home.
Rym: I was in a hurry to get home.
Rym: so we could like do GeekNights.
Rym: So now I'm not in a hurry.
Rym: So I immediately stopped and I get off and I start inspecting the bike.
Rym: I expected that maybe like the gear shifter was off or something.
Rym: sure enough The gear indicator in the front was four gears off from what was going on in the back.
Scott: Well, I would notice that pretty much immediately.
Scott: I know what a gear feels like I do.
Scott: but if it says that it's in like, you know A certain gear and it's pedaling is much more difficult than what it says.
Scott: I Would notice that within seconds.
Scott: How could you not notice that?
Rym: Well, I have a very different gearing.
Scott: if you look at what I do Are your four gears off from where you're supposed to be?
Scott: I wouldn't notice.
Scott: I wouldn't think something is wrong with my body.
Scott: I would look at.
Rym: the Thing is I would have noticed if I'd gotten to a higher gear But my highest gears are basically unusable unless I'm going like 30 miles an hour plus.
Rym: so Really never get up that high.
Rym: and it was only on the bike to work.
Rym: So it was the bike to work in a hurry bike home hurry next day.
Rym: It's like oh shit.
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: So I look and And Because it's off by four and because of the direction it's off It's higher rather than lower.
Rym: I think it must be that like the cable got frayed or something near the cassette, but that's all fine.
Rym: So I go to the front and I investigate a little bit and what I discover is that the cable had not snapped.
Rym: Usually when the gears are off like that is because the cable just like snaps and you can't ship.
Scott: I thought it's off usually because the cables too tight or too loose or the changes gets moved and doesn't move back.
Rym: So what had happened was the cable like half the strands had snapped.
Rym: So the rest of the cable just elongated by a couple centimeters.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So it just kind of jiggered everything off.
Rym: So I wasn't about to fix that.
Rym: I do no longer have any of the equipment to fix that on my bike to replace the whole cable.
Rym: So I just replaced the cable at the bike shop.
Rym: They charged me $11.
Scott: That's about right.
Rym: Yeah, and then the next day when I had it all fixed my bike to work I beat my Strava time over both bridges Mm-hmm.
Rym: It happens.
Rym: Yeah, that's all I got.
Scott: I beat the time for you.
Scott: I beat my time.
Rym: today I am the a hundred and eighth fastest person to ever bike over the Williamsburg Bridge according to Strava.
Scott: I don't know where my rank is on the Queensborough Bridge.
Rym: Well, look at one of those like bridge.
Rym: There's all these different routes.
Scott: So it's like a whole bunch of different bridge routes.
Scott: I don't know which one's the real one.
Scott: one of them says actual Queensborough Bridge.
Scott: one says full Queensborough Bridge.
Scott: Yeah, you realize on the ones like Queensborough Bridge West Climb.
Scott: But it's like two of those.
Rym: Yeah Cuz people like to have their stats like just on the climb just on the descent.
Scott: Just it was.
Scott: cares who's fastest on the descent.
Scott: I could probably toward a front speed on the descent.
Scott: if no one's in the way, he's gonna kill me Slow.
Rym: I would argue that you couldn't beat me because I have a higher gear ratio at the upper end.
Scott: It doesn't matter terminal velocity going down that hill.
Scott: What will matter is if your bike starts to shake and you just you know or break going that fast.
Rym: I have a race down the Williamsburg Bridge.
Scott: I Mean as it has to be at a time when there's no one in the way We should go over there some morning at like 7 in the morning on a weekend.
Scott: It'd be better to race down like a perfectly smooth hill somewhere in the middle of nowhere where there's no cars or people that to crash into and nothing and nothing at the end that you have to stop for.
Scott: because then Brakes also matter right.
Scott: a lot of the thing that limits my downhill speed is Actually brakes because I had to start braking way the fuck soon.
Scott: I don't get killed at the bottom.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I do.
Scott: if I had powerful brakes that were stable Then I could go ridiculously fast and brake pretty close to the end and still have a smooth stop.
Rym: You have mostly the same brakes I do.
Scott: I mean they're V brakes But they're not friggin, you know Like ridiculously strong.
Scott: if I'm going downhill at like 30 miles an hour.
Scott: It takes a while to stop.
Scott: You can't just slam on them you go right over the handlebars and die.
Rym: You gotta feather them.
Scott: Yeah, it takes a while.
Scott: That's a whole bunch of distance that I basically can't have to stop accelerating.
Rym: I feel like we should bike down a hill together.
Rym: I want to see what you're doing breaking.
Scott: Well, I'm not.
Scott: I mean by Just be danger sense because you know No based on how we drive right when we drive when you drive a car you hit the brakes like Ridiculously close to the red light and then the car goes Shikanka Shikanka.
Scott: All right, and it jerks.
Rym: But are you sure you're not gonna see me for most of our friends?
Scott: Well, your our friends are worse than you, but you are still bad at it, right?
Scott: So basically everyone in the car is uncomfortably lurched forward.
Scott: when I break in any vehicle I break so smoothly that the car that the vehicle does not move forward.
Scott: You wouldn't even know that you had stopped and started because my acceleration is so smooth.
Scott: All right All right, so because of that right I'm breaking.
Scott: probably or you know, I could break later safely if I was in a race But I do not do so because comfort is higher priority.
Rym: Yeah, my only priority biking home is not one not dying to speed.
Scott: Yeah, also, you know I could break even harder and like get the brakes going squealing like I'm not doing that either.
Rym: If I break harder, my brakes don't squeal.
Rym: I just flip over the handlebars.
Scott: Well, I mean There's limits here for everything, right?
Scott: You also wear your brakes out more.
Scott: if you're you know breaking hard Who cares?
Rym: you replace your brake pads every year.
Scott: I don't place them every year.
Rym: I've replaced my brake pads every year No need to replace them.
Scott: Well, maybe when you overuse the brakes you need to replace.
Rym: So anyway, the other thing is out.
Rym: So I was gonna bike to work today because like the most beautiful goddamn day.
Rym: and I didn't because as I'm rolling my bike out I see a mark on my tire like a long line a white line.
Rym: No, it's like it's like a lighter colored lines like a centimeter wide like eight centimeters long.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: and I remember seeing that yesterday when I look behind myself while I was biking for something and I saw like a line come around in The tire couple times like oh, I must have rolled through something.
Rym: So I saw it again.
Rym: I'm like, maybe I should inspect that I inspected.
Rym: It's the metal inside of my tire.
Rym: I've actually worn the entire tire down to the fact that it is.
Rym: it is like one bump away from exploding.
Scott: So I'm gonna be metal inside the tire.
Scott: Wouldn't it be your tube?
Rym: We use very different kinds of tires, I do not have tubes.
Scott: you don't have tubes.
Scott: You just have a solid piece of rubber.
Rym: Not a solid piece of rubber.
Rym: So my rear tire is a tubeless tire that just takes a high-pressure air inside of it and it seals against the Rym.
Rym: There's no additional tube in there.
Rym: All right, and independently I have worn the tire completely out almost all the way around.
Rym: I'm Really lucky that didn't blow out like last week because I must have worn it down like in the last eight or nine days.
Scott: Maybe you wouldn't brake so heavily you would have less friction of your tires in the ground.
Scott: It wouldn't wear out like that.
Rym: They only wear out like that from braking.
Rym: if you skid the tires Which I pretty much don't use.
Scott: my rear tires still wear out from They from braking and accelerating.
Rym: yeah, the wear pattern is pretty much uniformly around.
Rym: there's another warm spot on the other side and Inspecting the entire tire.
Rym: It's basically worn out.
Rym: So I got to go.
Rym: this is now my fourth rear tire, and I'm still on the original front tire.
Rym: That is my biking story.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: Gigantic news saving the day.
Scott: so I have something to talk about.
Scott: The rumors were that YouTube was gonna buy twitch which is good news and bad news.
Rym: that would have been great news For me and bad news for a lot of other people.
Scott: so the good news of that was gonna be that you know YouTube streaming technology is vastly superior from these streamers.
Scott: end of things and we would have much enjoyed using YouTube streaming technology on twitch.
Scott: and No Twitch is crappy streaming.
Rym: there is a caveat that people who use twitch regularly seem to not like the YouTube one And I think it's because they don't use sophisticated software and don't know how it works.
Rym: But I digress.
Scott: having the preview alone.
Scott: And why would you say that having a preview is bad?
Scott: that feature alone regardless of other features that you know may?
Scott: Just make things harder, but if you don't know what you do, but it's not Natural like you got to get that whole setup like people like to see like the natural you want to see the unprofessional shit Yeah, go fuck yourself.
Scott: Yeah, all right, but it turns out that that didn't actually happen.
Scott: 100% confirmed real Let.
Scott: Amazon is buying twitch for about a billion dollars ish.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Don't know how I feel about that.
Rym: that's gonna be interesting because I like Amazon from a Selfish human being who buys stuff perspective.
Rym: Oh, yeah, don't like Amazon from a corporate behavior Perspective.
Rym: they're not the worst.
Rym: don't get me wrong.
Rym: There are no months.
Scott: I mean the things I don't like about Amazon is I've heard rumors of bad stuff in their warehouses.
Rym: Yeah Lot not rumors of them bullying small book publishers, okay?
Scott: Well, okay, let's talk about bullying small and large book publishers, right?
Scott: So Amazon is just a retailer.
Scott: They buy a book and they sell a book and they need to sell the book for a higher price.
Scott: and they buy it for Even though they don't sell anything for higher price.
Scott: But theoretically they have to do that right.
Scott: the book publisher is Refusing to lower the price of an e-book.
Scott: an e-book cost like 15 goddamn dollars for a right on Amazon Which means Amazon is paying what like 10 bucks or something.
Scott: you can get every song ever Spotify or whatever for 10 bucks a month.
Scott: Ebooks are worth about fucking five cents, right?
Scott: So Amazon is actually.
Scott: you think they're bullying small book publishers.
Scott: No, they're just fighting for fucking reality Which is I'm not gonna pay fifteen dollars for a goddamn book one.
Rym: you powered all your books anyway, so why do you even care?
Rym: The thing is those the marginal cost to Amazon or zero.
Rym: Why not just let them sell the ebooks at whatever price they want?
Rym: and if they don't sell because they're too expensive that's on them.
Scott: Because Amazon does make money selling kindles because technology, you know Electronic devices are worth money and Amazon can't sell kindles if they don't have all these books on there.
Scott: So the Amazon wants to sell the books, but they can't if the books are too expensive.
Scott: No one's gonna buy a Kindle if all the books on there are 15 bucks.
Scott: They want the book prices to go down.
Rym: Is that buying a Kindle is worth it because then you can get the books for the same time I get the impression that Kindle is actually kind of petering out and being replaced by tablet Kindle fires.
Scott: Well Amazon was also smart in that regard.
Scott: right you can get just an Amazon Kindle app on an iPad or iPhone.
Rym: I see more and more people who are buying Tablets and then reading ebooks on tablets, but honestly having used both to read books the ink Whatever is way more comfortable than a backlit tablet screen to read pretty much anything.
Rym: That's just text.
Scott: Okay, so I agree and also disagree at the same time, right?
Rym: So on the one hand Yes, also holding the Kindle in one hand is way lighter physically.
Rym: Let's agree.
Rym: Yeah, so I had the battery last like a month.
Scott: Yeah, so I have a Kindle and an iPad mini, right?
Scott: So the Kindle is indeed much more comfortable to read on if there is light adequate light Obviously and it's a lot and the weight definitely less.
Scott: battery way less, you know.
Scott: It's all those regards.
Scott: The Kindle is vastly superior, right and it can hold a ton of books because storage for books, whatever Right, but the iPad mini is superior in book reading in one regard.
Scott: Well two regards.
Rym: All right I'm curious to hear these.
Scott: one regard is that you know I'm comparing this to the ink Kindle not the Kindle fire.
Scott: Right because the Kindle fire is basically the same thing as the iPad right?
Scott: It's not really there in terms of book reading only, right?
Scott: The just being able to have the touchscreen with all that stuff that you can do instead of you know.
Scott: So if I want to do things like highlight and copy or all that kind of stuff that you just can't do, you know I can let you know what you know.
Rym: when I do that either from a PC or from a tablet I'm saying but you know not what I'm reading.
Scott: Sure, but I can you know, look a word up.
Scott: I can quickly go to a browser Look a word up.
Rym: You're saying you don't know the definitions of every word.
Scott: You don't know the Every word.
Scott: I have it.
Scott: Why are you working on Wall Street?
Scott: You can make a lot of money into playing Scrabble.
Rym: I would argue that knowing the definitions of every word would in no way help you in Scrabble.
Scott: The definitions know but by knowing by knowing the definitions that would imply you also know every word which would help you.
Rym: Scrabble players know every Scrabble word and that's all that matters.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Well Scrabble words are words.
Scott: So if you knew the definitions of every word you would know every Scrabble word.
Scott: well Then I would just be at the same level as and there are ways you can make more money by knowing every word than Scrabble Regardless.
Rym: but my point being is that the problem with Amazon is that because they're pretty like they're not a monopoly but they're They're a monopoly on like online retail.
Scott: Yeah, and yes, that is a problem But the right is that where else can I go to buy?
Scott: You know I wish there was another place I could go to just buy everything I wanted online and then there would be a Competition and the prices would go down even further.
Rym: not even just prices but service and things is the fact that I'm uncomfortable Any time there is one That has a primary control like, you know The dispute with the publishers over ebook prices would be a zero debate if there was any alternative.
Scott: the alternative They should have.
Scott: just so they should just sell ebooks at a low price directly from their own website, but they're technologically incompetent.
Rym: Well selling from your own website is tough because even if you have your own e-commerce thing and it's perfect and it integrates perfectly With all the hardware out there.
Rym: It's really hard to convince people to go to those places Even if you have better deals.
Rym: I've seen games Cheaper on places other than steam and no one buys them on those places except little kids who spend all their time looking for those Deal, right?
Scott: Well, I mean this is a common thing that we see.
Scott: right is like Marvel and DC.
Scott: You don't buy comics from the Marvel and DC apps.
Scott: you buy it from the comics ology app.
Scott: some other company That's technologically competent had to do it because the companies that actually produce the content were too dumb to do it.
Rym: Because Amazon, you know if it's the specialized market like, you know Grubhub is the specialized market for you want food right now, and they pretty much have a monopoly on that.
Rym: But with Amazon their original specialty was basically we're the specialty thing for books.
Scott: Then they become the specialty thing for everything because they had the technology and they're basically a technology service, right?
Scott: They're basic, you know It's like.
Scott: are you too dumb to sell things online and in a way on your own and no one's coming to you?
Scott: Well, we did you know, it's like they were just being like.
Scott: well We can sell things online because you have warehouses and we have shipping and we have a little what I would do.
Scott: So we'll do it.
Scott: Oh wait, we're suddenly selling everything online.
Scott: So now this side effect happened, which is really benefiting.
Rym: if I were going to compete with Amazon I wouldn't try to compete with them on the everything store because that's impossible Obviously compete with just one of their stores.
Rym: What I would do is partner with like Kickstarter and things like that to have their ebook store integrated because obviously it is difficult to sell any Copyrighted IP media in any form because of the whole supply and demand thing.
Scott: I think the way to compete with something like Amazon is the same way.
Scott: you compete with something like reddit Right?
Scott: is you pick just one area and do that area better than they do it.
Scott: So like you can't make a reddit that has you know Just every community but you could make like a gaming.
Scott: only reddit like stack stack overflow is an example of it's sort of Thingy going on but that will stack exchange right everything sure but it competes in just like this one area.
Scott: the question answer area Right, and if you look Amazon isn't really selling everything online.
Scott: steam is competing with it in the one area of games.
Scott: right, even GOG competes with steam in the one area of old games and New egg competes with Amazon in the area of computer shit.
Rym: that is true though increasingly I find better deals on Amazon.
Scott: just sometimes but not always but sometimes I'll buy from new egg Even if the deal is similar because new egg is so much easier to search for computer parts specifically.
Rym: That is true, right?
Scott: It's if you pick just one area someone who's doing it generically Right isn't serving that.
Scott: you know niche market so you can like, you know Etsy can compete right because they're honing in on just one area of e-commerce and doing that better than Amazon can do it because Amazon has to worry about every kind of e-commerce and can't just worry about one.
Scott: Yeah But Amazon also in addition to selling every goddamn thing in the universe also specializes in books.
Scott: So it's very very hard to compete with books as your as your target thing Because they specialize in it and simultaneous have the resources of selling everything.
Rym: But the point of all that is that you need to have some competition to force people to make features better.
Rym: Very few companies will make features better or user experiences better unless they're forced to out of fear That is.
Scott: one interesting thing is while that is true and you can see it in the cable industry if you don't believe it's yeah Amazon strangely keeps acting like they have competition.
Scott: when they don't I keep lowering Prices and they keep serving the people who are their customers really?
Scott: Well, it's like oh you have Amazon Prime here.
Scott: Just watch all these videos for free.
Rym: Up until about a year and a half ago whenever I ordered anything from Amazon I always picked super saver and you know what everything always arrived like the next day.
Rym: Mm-hmm now everything arrives at the far Maximum end of the period is eight days minimum if I do super saver, but oh I can just pay for prime.
Rym: They're really trying to push everyone toward prime.
Scott: Yeah, but I pay for prime.
Scott: It's not that much money.
Rym: It's really pays for prime So I don't have to.
Scott: yeah, I mean, it's really great.
Scott: It's totally awesome.
Scott: Why you know, I mean, it's not like they're ripping you off with it Like some other people are ripping you off of stuff.
Rym: So YouTube has far superior technology compared to twitch.
Scott: and for the people who are doing the streaming.
Rym: Yes, but Well that yeah, but even even for the consumer of it that what they did things differently the community stuff and Google all sucks, obviously Yeah, so and they don't really give good ways for streamers to monetize.
Rym: But personally I don't really care about that aspect of it.
Scott: No the two things that Bob the only two things I think are wrong with the YouTube streaming right now is Number one.
Scott: you have to set a start time and it counts down.
Scott: the set time doesn't have to be accurate.
Scott: You can start whenever you want.
Scott: You can start after or before the clock hits zero.
Scott: You can't even change the clock whenever you want Yeah, but it while before your stream starts that clock is there counting down.
Scott: I like that and you can only choose it.
Scott: set it on a half-hour.
Scott: I wish I could.
Scott: just it's like that's confuses people.
Scott: people might come to my stream and I think okay Like I did netrunner stream on YouTube yesterday, right?
Scott: I thought my friend might show up around 1230.
Scott: He showed up like 1130 so originally had the clock set for 1230 so people would come see it leave But then it's like oh actually we started an hour earlier.
Scott: Then I told you we were gonna start.
Scott: people showed up at 1230 and like oh it's been going for an hour already.
Rym: What well, that's your fault for picking a time.
Scott: and then what time?
Scott: I suppose they make me pick a time.
Scott: Yeah because time my supposed to fucking pick if I don't know what I'm starting because Scott as On a half-hour increment.
Rym: remember like I said YouTube's.
Rym: the whole thing was designed around events exactly Streaming an event but that's still a problem.
Scott: That is a problem with it.
Scott: I should be able to set unknown time and just have it say starting soon or please wait and not actually had to pick A time.
Scott: also I have to start on a half-hour.
Scott: Professional things sometimes start at 15 minute mark 5 minute mark 10 minute mark.
Scott: I should be able to type in any goddamn time I want.
Rym: yeah, so that's a plus my point.
Rym: They will not implement changes unless they're forced to because someone else does it better.
Rym: right because they're pretty much the go-to for that Other than in-house or white-labeled solutions, yep The other.
Scott: the other problem I have with the YouTube streaming is just the chat is not as good as like Yeah, the community stuff is just awful.
Scott: the chat isn't it's just a YouTube chat.
Scott: It's just this live chat that's kind of crummy and then when the thing is done It turns the chat into the YouTube into YouTube comments immediately.
Scott: But at least it saves your video as a YouTube video immediately Which is very nice.
Scott: and had YouTube bought the Google bought twitch I would have been great because we would have gotten the technologies merging.
Scott: Well, it would have been bad in terms of the competition aspect we just discussed right.
Scott: there would be only one player.
Rym: now There's still two players, but it would have been good as we saw when twitch suddenly said hey We're getting rid of all our archives.
Scott: Yeah, now are they now?
Scott: so Amazon now owns it and it sort of competes with YouTube.
Rym: Export these videos to now is YouTube.
Rym: So right either have to export them to YouTube That competes with Amazon or what lose them.
Scott: Yeah, I guess what you have to do as a streamer is Usually the software that you're using to stream.
Scott: every single software that you use to stream that I know of also records locally.
Scott: so you're gonna have to basically record your streams locally and then upload them later as opposed to Let it you know, just uploading the whole thing as the stream and then dealing with it online.
Rym: Well, we don't know if that'll be the case or not.
Rym: I'm curious what Amazon will do but right now the only integration is with YouTube.
Rym: My worry is that if Amazon wants to compete hard, they'll make it difficult to get things from Twitch to YouTube.
Rym: Yeah, I don't expect to like or use Amazon stuff.
Scott: See now if I was Amazon what I would do is I would buy Vimeo and what I would do is I would leave Vimeo as is as is because you don't want to mess with that.
Scott: But I would take Vimeo's technology and set up basically a copy Vimeo on.
Scott: you know Cuz Amazon has Amazon web services.
Scott: They have hardware to install another Vimeo like overnight basically just and Vimeo runs on Amazon web services to begin with.
Scott: so Copying Vimeo and making a second Vimeo at another domain is not a problem.
Scott: getting some front-end people to retheme It is not a problem, but make it stored gaming videos only Right and basically use that to as you know to basically make it be almost like twitch has two sections.
Scott: I like the live section and the saved video on demand section, right?
Scott: It's like twitch just got rid of that feature.
Scott: But Amazon should just bring that feature back and double down on it.
Scott: and it's like.
Scott: you don't have to upload your video saved Game video to YouTube and you don't have to save it on your computer because we have this Vimeo clone We just installed.
Scott: that's gonna do it in super HD awesomeness.
Rym: Well, we'll see.
Rym: my only hope is that I want there to always be competition in this space.
Scott: I want there to be competition in every space all spaces.
Scott: Yep, but especially this one because it's the thing I use.
Rym: Yep, though I use it in a lot of different cases and ways.
Rym: and honestly from a like watcher of things I never watch anything on Twitch.
Rym: I I just hate watching stuff on Twitch rarely watch things on.
Scott: I watch Dave Riley on Twitch.
Rym: Twitch plays Pokemon.
Scott: Yeah things like that.
Scott: I'll check out for like an hour at most total But that's about it.
Rym: So some brief news because it went on for a while about that I was does.
Rym: a huge news is a billion dollar news But it's also the kind of news that you say.
Rym: isn't tech news?
Scott: that is business news Yeah, but there's nothing else to talk about.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: What about the Linux divide?
Rym: That doesn't.
Scott: I mean that's questionable.
Rym: whether all of you who are IT people computer science people system administrators I've noticed something.
Rym: There's a good article that kind of explains this.
Rym: but basically the people who know Unix as opposed to Linux you mean the neckbeards?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Okay, or the people the Unix Santa clauses, you know I think neckbeard.
Scott: now guys you write for the kernel like.
Rym: I guess that's like a Frodo like the old-school neckbeard because now the other district is more like the fedora trilby E-cigarette Rainbow Dash shirt.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: No, not that guy.
Scott: He doesn't know anything about Linux.
Rym: Yeah, we're talking about cell Unix Santa's, right?
Rym: Yeah, the people who know I'll make it very simple the people who know how slash dev works or know what?
Rym: Why Etsy and var log and all those things exist?
Rym: I know a dying breed.
Scott: I'm dying.
Rym: And meanwhile, why am I dying?
Rym: the people who are I guess I am done making contributions to Linux distros.
Rym: and I said what happens with Linux distros not doing that?
Rym: don't care Don't give a shit about any of that history.
Rym: and they keep questioning.
Rym: Like why do we do things this way?
Rym: Let's just change it.
Rym: and there's this huge growing schism between the old guard and the new guard That's causing a pretty rapid fracturing of the Linux base Like beyond the kernel.
Scott: that's been true for as long as I've Linux.
Rym: that has also been true as long as I've Linux.
Rym: But I feel like it's accelerating and I think it's actually more subtle than this article makes it out.
Scott: Well, I think it's a wider cultural problem just in the.
Scott: our industry to begin with is even just to say web technology, right?
Scott: I'm running if I set up a website today.
Scott: I'm using trustworthy shit.
Scott: That's old and crusty.
Scott: I'll use Apache today, you know, maybe maybe I'll use nginx maybe right I'll use fucking MySQL even though people hate it.
Scott: I'll use postgres QL only if I have to because it's a serious application right like a bank or something.
Scott: Yeah, right my SQL use instead.
Scott: why?
Scott: because it's old and trustworthy.
Scott: Postgres as you all is actually new hotness compared to MySQL.
Scott: I'm gonna run like an old Ubuntu not even the new I'll.
Scott: even Ubuntu is newish.
Scott: I'd rather run like a Debian or you know something that is gonna be a reliable distro.
Scott: That's not gonna change It's just gonna get security updates.
Scott: But meanwhile you look at other people especially like in the web.
Scott: They're running node JS Mongo DB Fancy angular all this like the hottest newest thing that's been out for five minutes and they're trusting that with their website.
Scott: And it's like you were just asking for your shit to go down like ten times a day, dude.
Scott: And it's I see the same thing happening, you know across the board these Linux people, you know The people who like work on the kernel.
Scott: It's like they're old Unix people.
Scott: They do it the way that they've learned that is the best way over decades and that shit doesn't break.
Rym: Yeah, I mean here's a quote.
Rym: This is the Unix philosophy write programs that do one thing and do it Well programs that work together programs that handle text streams because that is the universal interface.
Scott: Yes and that's what those people do and you.
Scott: the best place to see this in action is If you look at git.
Scott: Linus Torvalds wrote git.
Scott: it's fucking hard as balls Relatively speaking for people to use.
Scott: I mean, I know how to use.
Scott: it's not that hard if you try, right?
Scott: But it's a crusty command-line interface.
Scott: That's obviously super Unix II in every conceivable fashion and it's ridiculously powerful.
Scott: It's the whole hog metaphor.
Scott: We've talked about 10,000 times for Neal Stephenson, but look at how many people Right.
Scott: just try to cover up git with some kind of GUI or come up with some git wrapper to do things in a Fancy friendly way and like there's tons and tons and tons of people trying to do this all over the place Just trying to cover up that Unix crust rather than learn it Right.
Scott: the last thing that it's it's easier for them to spend weeks writing a GUI than to spend a day learning a command-line program.
Rym: never mind the fact that because The interest in the like the what the way things are the way they are and why decisions were made in the old days Distros are increasingly diverging like there was a time not five or six years ago.
Rym: What if I sat down in front of Ubuntu or Gen 2 or like all these different.
Scott: only really thing you need to new different.
Rym: Back then was the name of the package manager Yep, and maybe like they all had their different in its stuff But you know what?
Rym: Well like in red hat you could have like service space whatever and like there's distros that use that method that way to like Yeah, the other ones you just do in a D start/stop.
Rym: Yep, but then Nowadays like I've taken some new buntus and some new distros down like right at our red hat six and all these things and It's not always straightforward the right way to do things.
Rym: But while I don't know the right way that that distro expects me to do things the Etsy in it D bar log crap all still works.
Rym: just fine, of course.
Rym: But most people younger than me that I interact with in the industry.
Rym: They know the service level only so they can either only use one distro or If the distros stuff doesn't work a hundred percent.
Rym: They have literally no way to troubleshoot that.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: I Don't.
Rym: I mean this has been a problem.
Scott: when people are not learning Unix skills that is not a skill that's being taught or prized.
Scott: You know.
Scott: look you can get a line node for like five line.
Scott: Oh, it is so cheap.
Scott: now they keep lowering the prices and making them better, but people keep setting up their websites on Heroku.
Scott: Why why do you pay so much money for Heroku?
Scott: Because that way you only have to learn Ruby on Rails and HTML CSS and JS.
Scott: You don't to learn anything else.
Scott: and then they take care of the rest because they have Unix skills And they just charge you to borrow their Unix skills.
Scott: You don't have to learn them.
Rym: Yep, and that's what I'm seeing people It's there's no incentive as a technologist except for in a very vanishingly small number of cases to actually Understand all that Unix II crap because that's not the problem you're trying to solve.
Rym: That's not the thing you care about.
Rym: you want a server to run probably monolithic software on top of and On top of that.
Scott: right how many you can tell by developers who are using max?
Scott: now you meant max or Unix.
Scott: Why?
Scott: of course Mac people be Unix II and they do use the command line and stuff on their max when they're developing But they're mostly using GUI programs, and you know what Mac Unix No matter what anyone wants to say.
Scott: you BSD people talking about how you know the OS X kernel is a real Unix or something?
Scott: the user space on OS X is fucking bullshit.
Scott: It's not real Unix.
Scott: No source code you get right for some BSD program is gonna run Just perfectly and nicely on OS X. even brew the best package manager OS X has ever had.
Scott: Every time you brew something it spits out a ton of fucking instructions about.
Scott: oh, yeah this package.
Scott: You're gonna do all this fucking bullshit to make this work.
Scott: You know on any Linux distro fedora devian Ubuntu arch Linux Even I use the package manner.
Scott: install a package.
Scott: it fucking works immediately no questions asked.
Scott: if I get the source code I run configure make make install it fucking works.
Scott: end of story right.
Scott: OS X is not Unix and the people who are developing on it aren't using the Unix II part for the developing using GUI.
Scott: bullshit Right and I think the spread of OS X as the platform of choice for many developers.
Scott: I'm using Windows, but I'm using a Linux virtual machine in Windows.
Rym: Yeah Which seems to be the model everyone uses except I have one developer who actually actually uses Cygwin.
Scott: I mean I would know that's fine that works.
Scott: I would use Linux straight up If I had you know didn't wasn't using a laptop which Linux still runs poorly on.
Scott: right but That spread of OS X has caused this lack of Unix has been Even a lack of you know just there.
Rym: so like you just said you run Linux in a virtual machine on Windows And I'd said that most developers I know do it that way.
Rym: only the servers run Linux on the bare metal exactly.
Rym: The problem is starting to also become that Unix as a philosophy Solved problems from the 80s and isn't suit like it.
Rym: It's too Generically Big iron and it doesn't really help modern people solve the problems that modern people care about it could solve those problems.
Scott: But those crusty old guys right who your complaint?
Scott: who are doing things the old trusty way What they need to do is they they're only interested in stuff.
Scott: They're only solving the problems They're interested in solving which are things like we got to make the kernel faster more reliable.
Scott: They need to solve the problems that normal people want solved with the correct old Crusty solution and that is the thing that can save Linux.
Scott: but it will never happen because that guy is not interested in making surround sound work perfectly on every Linux distro ever or Making 3d games run really easily and nicely from Steam or they have like no interest in doing that.
Scott: They have interested in like writing a file system to be more efficient and stuff like that Doesn't affect the end-user in any way or it does in ways that the end-user can't Understand or do it doesn't make it.
Scott: Yeah If you look at a kernel changelog as a user of a normal computer user and you look at like the things that have changed Like the last hundred Linux kernel versions Maybe you'll find like a USB driver for something that you have in your computer and now on the
Rym: server
Scott: side.
Rym: Thank you in any way whether you use an old Linux kernel or a new one like free from recent years I mean DRBD was included as part of the Linux card.
Scott: That's your favorite and That's your favorite.
Rym: That was a great thing that solved a real problem that the users of the operating system needed solved even though arguably High level like file system replication is not something that really Deserves or is expected to be in nobody OS space.
Scott: Nobody who has Ubuntu on a desktop will give a shit about DRDB ever Yep.
Rym: But increase it like Linux makes it very difficult and so does Windows like there's.
Rym: no it's not like we're saying.
Rym: Oh Windows is better.
Scott: You can't develop on Windows.
Scott: The only reason you can develop on Windows is virtual machines.
Rym: You also can't run the software you make on Windows.
Scott: You theoretically can but it's even worse than OS X which is why OS X became the platform of choice.
Rym: Windows servers are awful and usually whenever I see a Windows server in my industry It's because someone bought some software made by a company that develops solely in C sharp net.
Scott: like if you're programming on Linux It just works.
Scott: on OS X it works But it's janky.
Scott: on Windows you put in a virtual machine because you can't make it and then it just works.
Rym: Yeah Well, it's impossible if you don't use it and then most developers have no idea to look in varlog messages to see what happened to Their system.
Rym: they don't even know Things of the day.
Rym: I have to because one of my things the day is a little bit mean-spirited.
Rym: So if you do not want to watch it, I have an alternative.
Rym: Mm-hmm my alternative.
Rym: I'll give that one first.
Rym: I was in a wildwood playing some ingress and It's near the end of the summer season and I had just become lovely.
Scott: ingress broke and I stopped.
Scott: but I got it.
Scott: I got to try to mess with it.
Rym: So I had like a boatload of level 8 shit tons of it.
Rym: I used it all by capturing pretty much every goddamn portal I could find.
Rym: Just I destroyed like so I made like 40 or 50 thousand experience points from destroying all these gigantic Fields and the portal.
Rym: I'm trying to hold on to that.
Scott: I dumped a bunch of my shit on Like logging and recharging it with the portal key all the time.
Rym: I get an alert if anyone attacks this shit.
Rym: Okay, is the boardwalk Loo Memorial?
Scott: There's a guy named Loo.
Rym: There's a guy named boardwalk Loo.
Rym: he looked I think he was a cop in Wildwood or North Wildwood and He seems interesting.
Rym: I can't find any information about him.
Rym: There seems to be a character Named that in boardwalk Empire.
Rym: I don't think is the same person.
Rym: Okay, so this is my thing of the day because if any of you have any information on boardwalk Loo I would like to find out My mean-spirited thing of the day.
Rym: This is a compilation of people fucking up the ALS ice bucket challenge.
Rym: Okay, how could you fuck it up like that dropping the bucket on your friends?
Scott: That doesn't seem like a fuck-up.
Scott: that seems like he purposefully fucked his friend over.
Rym: now A lot of these people just like a lot of them will be someone picks it seems like he did that to his friend on.
Scott: That is not a fuck-up.
Rym: I've seen some where someone picks up the bucket it's heavier than they expected and they end up either dropping it on their friend or They fall over.
Rym: that lady just threw the bucket at the guy's face.
Scott: Okay, well that looked like accident, but you know, yeah people trip and fall on themselves.
Scott: This girl just dumped the ice on the floor cuz he was weak.
Rym: Yep This guy's lifting it.
Rym: He's working on it.
Scott: He's He is just weak.
Scott: Okay, that was definitely a fuck-up.
Rym: a few people lose the tops And the best one of all these is not a fail but a win.
Rym: Patrick Stewart took the challenge.
Rym: Mm-hmm You know Patrick Stewart did.
Scott: I saw the thumbnail and he had a classy hotel ice bucket and I was like That's the kind of ice bucket you should use.
Scott: and I figured he just classily Dumped it on himself or put his head in it or something or you know.
Rym: like that so much class I didn't even bother watching so you should have watched it.
Rym: Do you know what the challenge actually is?
Scott: you're supposed to either a donate or Or You know dump the ice on your head.
Rym: so he has the ice bucket he pulls money he turns down He writes and signs a check.
Rym: Yep, then he takes ice out of the ice bucket and drink some whiskey with it.
Rym: Basically the moral is if you respond to the ice bucket challenge with the ice bucket challenge, you're an asshole.
Rym: You're supposed to give money to charity.
Rym: That's the point.
Scott: Well, and a lot of people gave money and also dumped ice but then it's not a challenge.
Rym: but no.
Scott: But part of the thing is that when you dump the ice, especially if you're a celebrity, right?
Scott: You're you know, there's.
Scott: there's a still some people who are living under rocks who haven't heard of it true, right?
Scott: And you know, this is spread around the world.
Scott: Even the kpop people have been doing this thing, right?
Scott: So if there's a fan of you who's not a fan of anything else They they just might come into their Facebook feed and they'll discover it for the first time.
Scott: So doing the challenge or at least making a video right spreads you word farther Which is why ALS is raking in a good jillion dollars.
Scott: So someone's donating what's amazing?
Rym: We're in Wildwood Emily and I and we go to this little like store to buy some stuff
Scott: and people were buying ice for the People are
Rym: talking about like, oh my god
Scott: I biked around on Saturday and I went past a park or a bunch of people were playing volleyball And off in the corner of the park someone who's had a video camera and someone else is dumping the whole Frickin You know friggin cooler full of ice onto this their friend's head after they drank all the beers.
Scott: Yeah And there you go.
Rym: So you got a thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, it's an annoying kpop video cuz I couldn't resist using it.
Rym: How you're using it.
Scott: I'm using it.
Rym: Oh now Prepare to have this stuck in your head for like a month.
Scott: Yeah, so orange caramel who is like a plus plus Amazingness made a new video even though they just made one like a few months ago, which is pretty awesome.
Scott: You don't see people like making videos constantly like that.
Scott: But the new video is also a game and also a catchy song and also a dance all at once.
Scott: Pretty epic right there.
Scott: So I just want to infect everyone with this.
Scott: Also, one of them did the ice bucket challenge.
Scott: the other two didn't know.
Rym: No one's challenged us or if they have I haven't noticed.
Scott: I decide I'm just not gonna do anything about it unless I'm actually Challenged.
Rym: Oh, you're not gonna challenge.
Scott: It has to be from someone who was challenged down the chain.
Scott: It can't be like some spot one listener who's just like I challenged Scott, but it's like well who challenged you?
Rym: Yeah, you have to give us a certificate of authenticity show.
Scott: I want to see the chain going to back to like, you know some famous per.
Scott: you know I didn't start with like hockey dudes.
Scott: I think it started with like hockey dudes.
Scott: Nah, so I want to see you to show me all the way going back to the hockey people who started it.
Scott: Alright, whoever started it, you know the chain of people who requested and then if it gets to me then that was legitimate, right?
Scott: But if it doesn't it doesn't All right.
Rym: in the meta moment the book of the book is still a canticle for Liebowitz.
Rym: I'm convinced that Scott will never read it before the events in canticle for Liebowitz actually take place.
Rym: You like that one.
Scott: that was a great one.
Rym: I decided to say that like over the weekend while I was driving home.
Rym: We were driving well, we were quiet cuz I was exhausted and then suddenly I just laughed at myself.
Rym: Emily's like you just laugh and I'm like, nope.
Scott: Well done.
Scott: Well done Golf clap.
Rym: Well, you're going to be at the motherfucking penny arcade Expo.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Be the go.
Rym: You can't get tickets.
Scott: Nothing else matters on Tuesday.
Scott: I can die on the plane back to New York.
Rym: We're doing a lecture.
Scott: Well, I could if there weren't another pecs in 2015.
Scott: We have the reason I'm going to stay alive the next year.
Rym: We have put more Work into the lecture We're going to do on Monday at noon in the sandworm theater than we have ever put into one.
Rym: It is the reason I hit the brakes early on my bike And we will have an official GeekNights meetup at PAC.
Rym: So if you want to actually hang out with us, we are notoriously difficult to track down at conventions Go to any tabletop room and then if we're not there go to the other one.
Rym: Yes But if you come at those times we might blow you off because we're probably already in.
Scott: we're going to blow You off if I'm playing a game and I can really have time to talk to you because I'm trying to win or because we're Going to go to a restaurant.
Scott: that's way too expensive for you or even if it wasn't too expensive for you I barely know you and I just want to say hi to you and if you try to follow me to the restaurant when I've Known you for like five minutes.
Rym: That's kind of weird However, but take note anyone who's come to a restaurant with us before had you been one of those people?
Rym: We would not have let you come.
Rym: so don't worry But we were doing an official meetup at one o'clock right after the panel.
Rym: Mmm, because basically that is the time we can guarantee no matter what we decide to do We have to show up to that panel or packs won't let us come back.
Rym: Yeah So we are going to be there no matter what.
Rym: if one of us dies the other one will be there.
Rym: if both of us die Emily will be there.
Scott: I don't know if I died.
Scott: I might not be there if you die.
Rym: I'll be there.
Rym: I'll bring your body.
Rym: I'll roll you and be like Scott's not doing so.
Scott: Please preserve me so I don't make a stinky for the audience.
Rym: You wouldn't stink right away.
Scott: You'd be surprised Depends on what I ate How quickly it evacuates but at one o'clock outside the sandworm theater?
Rym: Well, you're one.
Rym: if you want to ask us questions about the panel Well, that's probably the only time we're gonna do it because we don't take questions during the fucking panels And maybe we'll time our panel poorly and finish early and have to take questions.
Rym: that is possible.
Rym: But - that is where we will coordinate the real meetup Which is we're going to reconvene at the line to the omega-thon finale on Monday afternoon And the idea is that we will all get in that line together.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and that's gonna be awesome.
Rym: Yeah, also if you're a pegs dev totally gonna be there come say hi.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: You can't say anything else about pegs, dude I can say that I'm going to be there.
Rym: Yep It's all I can say.
Scott: if you're gonna play in the netrunner tournament on Saturday come lose to me, please Please please come and play.
Scott: play against me in my group and then lose against me on purpose so I can win.
Scott: That is what I'm asking you All right, so when I was a kid one of the toys that I had Oh this this episode is all rims idea by the way, I got nothing.
Rym: Oh, yeah, my main idea was we should.
Scott: we got no Monday ideas.
Scott: Please send your Monday ideas to GeekNights at front.
Scott: recruit calm.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We're aware.
Rym: There's a forum threader.
Rym: You've suggested a ton of them Although they were any good.
Scott: We would have done them already.
Rym: Those are actually a lot of them great ideas, but they'd require like 20 minutes of research.
Scott: Good doesn't just mean good idea.
Scott: It means doable idea.
Rym: I'll do a little meeting.
Rym: It requires less than 10 minutes of research.
Rym: Yes So when I was a kid one of the toys I had was a cardboard box and that made me tell I had that toy.
Rym: that box was filled with consumer and residential electronics but not electronics like Integrated circuits or devices light switches.
Rym: Yeah, I'm talking like light switch panels power outlets Screw devices screw fuses fuse boxes.
Rym: Yep circuit breakers all the shit that I don't know how to hook up But but know how to use and basically I would spend a lot of time making elaborate Setups with that and occasionally when my parents weren't looking plug it in plugging them in.
Rym: My goal when I was super little was to make a loop because I somehow thought that if I did that I can make an Infinite magnet and I make a magnet.
Rym: All right, I was really upset With plugging one power outlet into another power outlet and I wanted to put a light bulb on it.
Rym: I thought that something awesome would happen.
Scott: Yes, an awesome will happen.
Rym: YouTube all the views And I realized that I think I know a lot more about residential electronics than Scott does.
Rym: or rather like electrics like electricity Hey or electric system.
Scott: I know how to go on YouTube and do whatever it says.
Rym: No Do you know how a two-way switch works?
Scott: You mean the kind where there's two different switches and at the top of the stairs in the bottom of the stairs We'll turn the light on or off.
Rym: because I lived in a house once a rental house where one of those was wired up Incorrectly.
Scott: there was a time when I knew how it worked.
Scott: It's one of those things you look up and then you forget and you look up and you forget and I'm sure if I had A pencil and it could draw some lines I could figure it out again.
Scott: Yeah, but at the moment I could not instantly tell you how.
Rym: yeah, so one thing listeners if you don't know how one of those works I have an assignment for you try to draw how it should work and then look online and then you're gonna feel really dumb.
Rym: But I was thinking about this because the other day one of the halogen lights in the ceiling of our Kitchen just fucking exploded.
Rym: really just like made it.
Rym: Oh, it made an explosion sound and There was like a flash and then a little bit of smoke and then all the lights in the kitchen went out.
Rym: Yep, I was like, all right circuit breaker went.
Rym: so I hadn't actually looked in our circuit breaker panel until you know Since we moved in I kind of forgot about it.
Rym: Mm-hmm So I go over there and I open it and I was struck by a revelation.
Rym: I have 20 amp circuits in a tiny two-bedroom apartment my panel 18.
Scott: My panel doesn't have that many circuits.
Scott: I don't know exactly how many it has.
Scott: some of them are doubled up to be 40 amps to deal with like Mine are doubled up too, but basically I have like almost a whole panel's worth for my little one bedroom.
Scott: So it's busy two rooms and a bathroom and a balcony Which is like half as many as my parents have in their house, which has two stories in a basement Yeah, and an outside in the front and the back and everything.
Rym: I mean most houses I visit attic even houses built like in the 70s and 80s.
Scott: There's just not enough holes No, and my parents house only has holes with two and not three.
Scott: When I was there last I was like, you know Cuz we had this weird adapter and I was trying to plug in my stuff.
Scott: My stuff all needs three holes.
Rym: really actually it's funny cuz all my stuff nowadays takes two holes Really?
Rym: Anyway, I'll like go look laptops.
Rym: They all take two holes.
Scott: No, my actual power strip took three holes though.
Rym: Oh Right.
Rym: I don't carry a power strip anymore because all the things I would plug into the power strip only need two holes.
Rym: But anyway, so I need that I carry a two-hole USB power strip.
Scott: The point is and it's like you should have three holes, right?
Scott: So I went on.
Rym: you know, why you need three holes For the third one's ground?
Rym: why?
Scott: because it keeps you from getting shocked and go It just does Because that plug actually goes to pretty much the same place.
Rym: that neutral goes.
Scott: Well, usually it goes to like the actual physical ground.
Rym: Oh, it doesn't.
Scott: in fact depends on your how.
Rym: When I looked on YouTube because I was looking how to change it Shows it going to like, you know, I'll stick that you stick out.
Rym: That's not how houses work anymore because you can't ground for shit with earth in most places.
Scott: Well, apparently supposedly at the box in the basement.
Scott: There would be a place to connect the ground, right?
Scott: Yeah, but This house the boxes in the basement were actually upgraded and so was the electricity in the house recently.
Scott: But the wires were not upgraded.
Scott: It's just two mad old wires going through the new box in the basement to your crappy outlet upstairs.
Rym: Yeah I mean I've been in houses like as a kid or like rental houses or just like people I know that had like like.
Rym: these are houses from the turn of the century and there'd still be some like Tin or whatever wiring or like you'd see wires with the cloth insulators on them like wow That is more dangerous than just having a toaster back there.
Scott: So what I did learn is that for building code if you put in a three-hole outlet But the third hole isn't attached properly can't do that.
Rym: shit you're.
Scott: you're allowed to do that as long as you put a sticker next to it.
Scott: that says no ground is bull, right.
Scott: and The other thing I learned is you know in a bathroom or a kitchen They'll be the one with the buttons around fault interrupts.
Scott: Yes, the ground fault interrupt.
Scott: I learned how that works.
Scott: Oh, it keeps your magnet.
Scott: Yeah it keeps you from getting killed.
Scott: but if you have a house and you want to put in a three hole and you only have Two wires and you don't have the third wire for the third hole You can.
Scott: just you're allowed to put a ground fault interrupt there with the no ground sticker.
Scott: Yeah, and that will actually Kind of protect you a little bit.
Rym: It'll protect you from certain say all that does is protect you from the situation where suddenly water whole shit Ton of electricity is coming out.
Scott: It protects you.
Scott: if you take a hairdryer and drop it in the bathtub and you have one of those Theoretically it will turn off the hairdryer pretty quickly and you probably won't die.
Rym: However, that's a lot like those saw blades that have the skin detector.
Rym: That'll stop the blade if you shove your finger into it while it's spinning.
Scott: those work.
Rym: Yes, those work.
Rym: Don't go test it.
Scott: Only test it if you're the guy demoing it in the infomercial.
Scott: Yeah Or test it with a hot dog.
Scott: That's perfectly good.
Rym: That is pretty good.
Rym: Yeah I've seen the hot dog test on them but when I was a kid because you know We had a lot of power tools and things the reason you need that ground plug primarily is that if the electricity?
Rym: If you short the device out without one of those what can happen is Especially in like it like an old drill or something or microphones killed people back in the days to like old shitty microphones.
Rym: The case of the thing would become basically electrified and if you grab it the electricity would ground out through you rather than going back down to neutral.
Rym: because The only way around that is you have the polarized plug and then separately you have the ground that takes a separate path to your unified Ground in the basement somewhere.
Rym: Yep Okay, yeah, but as a kid we had did a lot of that I was on.
Scott: the cases of things were made of plastic.
Scott: Yeah, because they just invented bakelite.
Rym: But even then like you saw that story about the woman who was killed by her USB charger, right?
Scott: Was someone really killed by the?
Rym: that's not that uncommon.
Rym: Don't buy it.
Scott: She eat it.
Scott: Was it a cheap knockoff?
Rym: one up?
Rym: Don't buy cheap USB chargers because you plug it into the wall.
Rym: they don't have a clear like good separation or gap between the wall voltages and USB side.
Rym: so if it's inside the circuit Yeah she was.
Rym: she basically was.
Rym: where is he?
Rym: at her cell phone and She was like it's listening to music and that headphones plugged into the cell phone and the USB charger shorted out and electrocuted her.
Scott: Yep when I was making my My crystal LED clock thing.
Scott: That was the number one thing it emphasized in the kit instructions.
Scott: It was like this part of the circuit board is where the voltage comes in.
Scott: Keep all the high-voltage shit on that side.
Scott: Leave a big-ass gap between that shit and this shit on the other side after the voltage is converted so that this dangerous Explosions don't happen.
Rym: Yep, but it's interesting how nerds who are really into electronics and Circuits and soldering and all that other cool electricity stuff.
Rym: Usually don't know a lot about how their house is wired up.
Scott: Well, cuz that's an electrician's job As opposed.
Scott: and even at RIT there were so many different majors.
Scott: there's computer engineering electronic engineering Micro-electronic engineering and they were all really different.
Scott: even you know, you sure they learn a lot of the same things.
Scott: But and there are a lot of the same classes But they were very different from each other.
Rym: but at the same time the gap between those Disciplines I think is where a lot of dangers and fatal nerd accidents happen where you know a good amount about electricity But you don't know the practical realities of.
Rym: I Guess like the way I would describe it is, you know how thin cables work, but you don't know how thick Yeah,
Scott: someone who's a master of micro-electronic engineering it can design, you know The next Intel core quad chip and knows how to handle individual electrons and one at a time with tiny transistors Would not do well with a large Anything at the power plant.
Scott: don't let them near it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like here's a crazy example.
Rym: if you have high voltages Most people think of a switch as just a switch.
Rym: switches are discrete no matter what on or off.
Rym: Mmm, but Ever see the switch in like a high voltage power station or like a substation.
Rym: Those switches are like four feet wide because you need a gap wide enough to where the electricity won't just keep going across the gap.
Rym: Yep Yep, I Just feel like more people should know about this stuff because it's really really practical to understand things Like what a ground fault does.
Rym: or if you own a house or you look like you're a kid and you live in someone's house.
Scott: I'm not gonna be able to own a house.
Scott: Enough old people died that house price stresses.
Rym: like if you're living in a shitty house that you're renting.
Scott: I hopefully won't live in a shitty house Knowing the difference between.
Scott: I can YouTube everything I need to know.
Rym: an annoying electrical problem and a dangerous electrical problem is probably pretty good practical advice, especially considering that people like us We I have like a hundred things plugged in in this apartment right now.
Scott: I sure do.
Rym: It's good to at least have some idea as to how that all works and why it may not be a good idea to string Eleven power strips together to make an extension cord.
Rym: Oh, that's a bad.
Scott: Hey, the number one thing is if I'm gonna mess with some electro electricity in the house I turn.
Scott: I know how to turn it off and make sure I'm not Really know how to turn it off.
Scott: You go to the circuit breaker and you hit the switch and then you see if the light bulb is still on and you keep Doing that until the light bulb is on.
Scott: the holes that you're gonna mess with is off and then you know that it's off.
Rym: Do you know the circuitized like what if there's another circuit that goes somewhere nearby and it's not connected to a light bulb?
Rym: like the microwave Is down its own circuit and the wires are right.
Scott: I'm not gonna mess with the microwave.
Scott: I'm gonna assume that I'm only if I'm gonna do.
Scott: if I'm gonna mess with the microwave I'm gonna turn the microwave on and flick switches till the microwave turns on.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta be very specific.
Rym: It's.
Rym: luckily the only time I ever got shocked was when Unrelatedly, I got shocked by that cage with servers in it that itself was electrified by one phase of a 220 line Mmm, I think I told that story before.
Rym: I won't tell that story many moons.
Rym: I've told you how many moons ago many times.
Rym: I've told it no more than twice on the show enough time.
Scott: It's not that bad And we're not usually tell stories a hundred times.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I also I don't think we've ever done a show on soldering.
Scott: What is there to say about soldering?
Scott: It's be welding for babies technique.
Rym: Like are you good at soldering?
Rym: I'm okay I was actually always pretty bad at it and my soldering joy.
Rym: I was okay on like board.
Scott: I can't make really tiny ones, but I can make really neat normal-sized one.
Rym: Yeah, I I made a pretty Fucking inefficient power distribution bus once in middle school for a science Olympiad event.
Rym: Like it was way inefficient and poorly designed and the solder joints were to quote the guy who was mentoring me on it Dreadful.
Scott: the main problem I have with it is that I really like the smell but it's really poisonous even if you use lead-free.
Scott: Yeah But I keep smelling it cuz it smells so good.
Rym: yep This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.