Rym: It's Monday, June 2nd, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Old computers, the oldest.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So for those of you who don't pay attention to what I do kind of outside of GeekNights, a lot of my job when I'm not flying around the world hosting fancy cocktail parties is doing concept design for features for products and services.
Rym: So I'll draw a picture of, like, this is the feature we should have in this thing, and it'll graph data like this, or it'll let someone do this, and I'll mock up, like, here's the functional design, and here's the widgets people could click on, and vague things like scale these graphs according to whatever.
Rym: You know, not a mock-up like the final development specification that someone who knows nothing about the thing itself could write, but like the.
Rym: here's enough for a smart person to write this code, and it'll do pretty much what I want it to.
Rym: And what I've discovered over the years is that fucking nobody ever reads those documents.
Rym: Ever.
Rym: I recently sent one of those documents to someone who had asked me for this feature thing.
Rym: I was like, how about this?
Rym: Does this do what the customer is asking for?
Rym: And the response I got back immediately was a question.
Rym: that said, can you see them by message type?
Rym: And I was like, that's in the picture that I showed you.
Rym: It's also in the footnote of that picture, and it's in the actual paragraph that explains what the thing does.
Rym: Do you have any more questions?
Rym: And without skipping a beat, he proceeded to ask me another question to which the answer was the same.
Rym: I don't know how software gets made.
Scott: You should have said, please read my document before asking any more questions.
Scott: I will not answer any questions until you have finished reading all the documents that I have sent you.
Rym: Yeah, I have attempted that.
Rym: You know what happens?
Rym: Radio silence.
Rym: And then I just develop the thing in a vacuum followed by, hey, it doesn't do this thing we wanted.
Scott: Well, then why didn't you read my document?
Rym: Yeah, that's the world.
Scott: Are you incompetent?
Rym: Clearly.
Scott: You're fired.
Scott: I'm hiring someone competent.
Rym: What I wonder is if it's different in larger companies or if it's just more Dilberti in larger companies.
Scott: My company is less Dilberti.
Rym: I wonder if I was doing that same thing at Google.
Rym: Would the people who care actually read my spec or would it be the same?
Rym: I wonder.
Scott: They tend to have a bunch of people work on something together.
Scott: Not one person just tells someone else what to do.
Rym: From what I gather, I've been talking to a lot of them lately because they keep bothering me, there's an implication that at least in some of the divisions or in some of the products, there'll be one person who has the vision of what X should do and they kind of do the guiding principle document and then other people flesh it all in and work as a group.
Scott: I think Google's plan is to get eventually to get all the tech people there ever were.
Rym: That are under the age of 35.
Scott: All the tech people, period, to work for it and then basically just hold the world hostage.
Scott: As long as there are other tech people, they can't enact that plan.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I'm not working for them.
Rym: I would work for them if they gave me the right stuff, but they'd have to give me the right stuff.
Scott: I work for anyone who gives me the right stuff unless they want me to murder people or something.
Rym: Depends what kind of people.
Scott: Or be murdered.
Rym: I don't think there's that many jobs that pay enough for you in the be murdered category.
Scott: All military jobs?
Rym: That's not be murdered.
Rym: That's be in danger.
Scott: That's very dangerous.
Rym: That's a very different job.
Rym: The casualty rate for anything you would ever do for the military is probably lower than you being in a car.
Scott: I don't do anything that be dangerous, such as underwater welding or going to any country where people have guns.
Rym: What's your threshold of danger?
Rym: Are you going to ride a bike?
Rym: Are you going to drive in a car?
Scott: Not really liking the car part.
Rym: Yeah, you were just in a car not that long ago.
Scott: No, not much choice.
Rym: And one of our friends went, "Oh, not much
Rym: choice.".
Rym: So yeah, you got any news?
Rym: Monday?
Rym: Tech day?
Scott: Well, just giant Apple news today.
Scott: It's Apple day.
Rym: I'll be honest, I didn't notice it was Apple day because I don't actually use any Apple products anymore.
Scott: Yeah, so it's the worldwide developer conference.
Scott: So they mostly announce all the things for developers, usually the software updates, the OS X and the iOS.
Scott: The things that developers that don't actually work at Apple need to know.
Scott: So there was a bunch of stuff, but none of it is really anything to talk about.
Scott: a lot.
Scott: Like OS X and iOS are converging in look and feel and features.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait.
Rym: What?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I thought that already happened.
Scott: It's happening more than... It's gradual, so it's just more.
Rym: Well, good luck with that because while they can probably pull it off better, there's... Well, I don't know.
Rym: I don't know if the people who use Apple computers to do work will have the same adjustment issues that the people who use Windows have when suddenly the single screen touch interface converges with the multiple monitor keyboard and mouse interface.
Scott: It's not like that.
Scott: It's like they change the icons for the apps to be the same.
Scott: And they change the style of the pull down menus to be the same.
Rym: That's not even fucking news.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Like even to a developer, it's like you don't even have to care about that.
Scott: You can also wait till I finish saying all the things before you make comments.
Rym: I know, but I'm just saying...
Scott: Because you sound like a moron because you don't know the whole story.
Rym: Yeah, I'm looking through this whole list right now.
Rym: I'm reading in parallel.
Scott: Anyway, the big important ones that actually mean something is number one, they made a new programming language called Swift, which is... Because Objective-C and C are basically really shitty to write iOS and OS X apps in.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: So instead of just letting everyone use some language they already knew, they made some new language that they're claiming is so awesome that no one knows anything about.
Scott: So if you want to make money and you're a programmer, if you learn this language like today, you will be way ahead of everybody.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: And it's pretty much guaranteed to be a job getting thing to know, and there won't be a lot of other people who know it.
Scott: You know what this will be like?
Scott: If you start today writing apps in this language as like this second, go buy a Mac if you don't have one or install it, right?
Scott: Install the developer Xcode, pay a hundred bucks to get the Apple developer account.
Scott: Start learning Swift and become a Swift expert before anyone else.
Scott: If you have good general programming skills, like I could do this, just start learning Swift, become a Swift expert, and that will probably be your career for the next decade at least.
Scott: You know what it's very much like?
Scott: You won't even have to actually program much in Swift.
Scott: You'll have to write like two apps maybe, and then the rest of your job can be just teaching other people Swift and doing talks on it.
Rym: Remember when Ruby came onto the horizon, and suddenly now there's a whole, like if you just know Ruby and aren't dumb, there's a million jobs at startups and web companies everywhere.
Rym: Crappy jobs.
Rym: They're not that bad.
Rym: They're better than the average non-tech job.
Scott: The big thing for me in terms of not really a developer feature, while developers have to know it so that they can work with it, right, is this really fancy shit they're doing when you combine an iOS device and a Mac together, right?
Scott: Specifically an iPhone.
Scott: So for example, they got a thing now where you can, first of all, the Apple Drive, the Google Drive competitor, iCloud, is now like super synced.
Scott: So it's like you take a picture and boom, it's on the Mac and it's on the thing like instantly.
Scott: I guess even more so than it was before.
Scott: Like you can be like editing a photo on your iPhone, and then the photo will be being edited like in your photo viewer on your Mac, like while you're doing it, right?
Rym: Yup, that's pretty chill.
Scott: You can, if you get a phone call, right?
Scott: It's like your Mac will see that there's an iPhone nearby.
Scott: You can connect it.
Scott: Like you get a phone call, the thing will show up on your Mac.
Scott: You can click no or yes, I'll pick up, and then it'll be on speakerphone on the Mac.
Rym: See, that is the one level.
Rym: That's the kind of stuff that because of their conversions, Google cannot do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if you get SMS messages from people who don't have iMessage, right, because they don't have iPhones, and it hits your phone, but your phone is currently connected to your Mac, those messages will show up on the Mac in the iChat or iMessage program, right?
Scott: Like basically, you know, it's like all your devices are going to be like one, you know, device basically, right?
Scott: Even more so than pretty much any other combination of devices you can buy.
Rym: I think I speak for everyone when I look forward to the divergent software implemented version of that that Google does a year down the road that half works and then they give up on.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: You know, that's really interesting.
Scott: And they're also.
Scott: the other sort of somewhat big news is they're allowing.
Scott: basically they opened up iOS a lot more than they did before.
Scott: So like you can make custom keyboards now.
Scott: So there's going to be swipe and all those things.
Scott: And, you know, basically everything Android and other OSes, it's Apple's typical play, right?
Scott: They don't invent anything.
Scott: They just steal everything and act like they invented it.
Scott: It's like spaces.
Scott: Virtual desktop is like 20 years old, guys.
Scott: Spaces.
Scott: You've never seen them before because you've never used Unix before.
Scott: Normal people.
Scott: We invented these, right?
Rym: Even though, funnily, the more like the more advanced my personal computer workflows get, I need multiple desktops, less and less, unless I'm writing code like they're less and less useful in a world of.
Rym: I've got three monitors on my desktop.
Scott: Yeah, three monitors.
Scott: Most people have one.
Scott: But no.
Scott: But so it's like all.
Scott: they're adding all this stuff to iOS that Android and other OSes have had for a long time that they didn't have.
Scott: For example, like in the notifications, there's notifications that you can interact with.
Scott: It's like if I get a message and I look at my notification pull down and it says like message, I can push reply.
Scott: right the fuck there.
Scott: Android has been doing that for a long time.
Rym: Yeah, it has.
Scott: You can put widgets and shit.
Scott: They haven't had widgets.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I still stand by the fact that the new look is one of the most milquetoast announcements in the history of Apple.
Rym: Flat design, translucent panels, absence of gradients.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: Like that's those are the three headlines there.
Scott: OK.
Rym: Oh, new icons.
Scott: Oh, and also, if you try to email someone an attachment, it'll upload your attachment to the cloud and send them an email with a link.
Scott: So that way you don't have to worry about giant email attachments fucking you over.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Actually, Google Drive has been doing that pretty well for a while now.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, you're the person you're mailing might not have Gmail.
Rym: Yeah, but in that case, I just give them one of those semi secure.
Rym: Anyone can click on this obscured link to get it thing.
Scott: The thing the other thing is interesting is so you can use Siri hands free, which I don't care about, but more importantly, when you do the searching where you just type things in, it actually does like a Siri search, just not with without the stupid talking part.
Rym: That was a long time coming.
Scott: You can get a really powerful search as opposed to just searching like the apps on your phone.
Scott: You can actually search everything you know what Siri would do.
Scott: so I can just type into my phone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like on the search screen score the football game and it'll tell me as opposed to that.
Scott: Used to be something I would have to either ask Siri or go to a website and Google.
Rym: True.
Rym: But at the same time, what do I do?
Rym: Google now just kind of pops up and tells me the score to every sport I care about for every team I care about.
Scott: I have Google now also.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's not a big deal.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's about it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, just they didn't announce anything particularly exciting to anyone but developers.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: All this stuff is just nice.
Scott: Apple fanboys.
Scott: Do they go crazy?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Even if I was a fanboy, I'd be hard to go crazy.
Rym: This would be like if they were like we're releasing Evangelion like 11.11.11 and it's the same as episode one.
Scott: You should read.
Rym: But we used a new cell shader algorithm on the old print to make it look better.
Scott: So I'm linking to the Verge article because it's the best summary.
Scott: But I was watching the Verge live blog, whatever, and the guy doing the live blog, he commented a fuck ton about the music they were playing.
Scott: And then he commented a whole lot about how it bothered him that the icon for the weather app didn't actually have the live weather in it.
Scott: He commented on that like a whole bunch of times.
Scott: And then during the part where the guy was demoing the Swift programming language, he was pretty much just like, I have no idea what's going on.
Scott: There's a wizard on stage, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Scott: And it's like, wow, this is journalism right here.
Rym: For the year 2014, me and play journalist.
Scott: Yeah, Verge, you should maybe have someone at the developers conference.
Scott: who knows something about development.
Rym: May I make a modest proposal?
Rym: They should do what sports does, have a color commentator and a developer commentator.
Rym: That way they can pass the puck back and forth.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So in other kind of more disturbing news for those of you aren't aware, true crypt, which is a pretty useful disk volume encryption system.
Scott: You basically use it to encrypt your whole goddamn hard drive.
Rym: Or to take a file that could basically just looks like random gibberish and have it somewhere and then you can mount it as a drive and see the data on any computer.
Scott: It's like your whole C drive is encrypted.
Scott: If someone just takes your computer from you, they can't read any files on it whatsoever.
Rym: Or on your computer, there's a file that's called, I don't know, static audio dot wave.
Rym: And if you open it in true crypt, it magically decrypts into all your pornography.
Scott: It becomes the D drive and the D drive is full of dick.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So, well, that's what the D drives for.
Rym: That's where those drive letters came from, you realize.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If someone comes and rips your hard drive out of your computer and puts it in another computer, it'll easily be worthless to them.
Scott: They won't be able to do shit with it.
Rym: It did other things too.
Scott: It might as well be blank.
Rym: True crypt, at least the use case wise, not talking about the backend technology, was really aimed around very practical hiding of data.
Rym: So, for example, true crypt had the deniable encryption, where you could have an encrypted volume.
Rym: There's a file block.
Rym: It's 10 gigabytes, let's say.
Rym: Statistical analysis of that block, in most cases, will show it as completely random data.
Rym: But if you type in the correct passkey, then you see the data.
Rym: You could set it up with layers of deniable encryption, where if I type one password, you see a bunch of porn.
Rym: If you type another password, you see my bomb making instructions.
Rym: And there's no way to prove that either.
Rym: one is the "true
Rym: volume."
Rym: Right.
Scott: You basically take a whole bunch of porn videos and a whole bunch of bomb making instructions and you put the dick on the D drive and you put the bombs on the B drive, but you put them both in the same package together.
Scott: And then you'd be like, okay, the password for the porn is "dick" and the password for the bomb is
Scott: "bomb.".
Scott: Someone types in
Scott: "dick.".
Scott: All the dicks come out, but the bombs don't.
Rym: So when the NSA or the FBI or the CIA or Mossad or MI6...
Scott: They're like, what's your password, dick?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So they type it in.
Scott: Oh, it works.
Scott: There's no way to know.
Scott: And there's a bunch of dick.
Scott: No, there are edge cases.
Scott: It's legal, dick.
Scott: It's all 18 plus.
Rym: There are edge cases where you could statistically analyze it to figure stuff out.
Rym: Like, for example, if you run a live boot disk or a volume inside of there in one of them, so you boot your computer into multiple different windowses, the fact that your bomb making instruction windows has changing metadata within the volume compared to other volumes, they could statistically be pretty sure that, yeah, you've got other sets of encrypted data you're not showing us, but they couldn't prove it.
Rym: Anyway, we've talked about encryption and stuff before.
Rym: The news would be, and the news that some people are trying to tell you is that TrueCrypt is being abandoned by its creators and they've recommended that you move on to BitLocker, which is the built-in Windows/Microsoft encryption volume system.
Rym: I do not know enough about BitLocker's technology to comment on its usability, its ability to replace this, its security, whether or not it has any weird back doors mandated by it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Don't know.
Rym: No comment on that.
Rym: Something fishy is up with the way TrueCrypt went down.
Rym: It's a really weird situation.
Rym: The web page for it, like, suddenly lost all its sort of style information and just put up this ghetto web page that just tells you how to migrate your existing TrueCrypt into BitLocker.
Rym: They took down the old versions of TrueCrypt and the current version, 7.2, removed all the encryption capabilities and just gives you the ability to decrypt an existing volume.
Rym: At the top of the page, they put up in red text, "Warning, using TrueCrypt is not secure as it may contain unfixed security
Rym: issues.".
Rym: Someone pointed out, but I think this is just funny and a coincidence, that it says, "Warning, TrueCrypt is," and then, "Not secure
Rym: as.".
Rym: The first letters of those three words is NSA.
Scott: This would be a great practical joke.
Rym: It would.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: This would be the best practical joke.
Rym: But the signing certificates changed.
Rym: A bunch of other stuff happened, and the developers have just disappeared from the earth.
Rym: They're not responding.
Rym: No comments.
Rym: No further discussion.
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: As you know, Scott and I take a very dim view of conspiracy theories and lizard people in the John Birch Society.
Scott: But this is lizard people?
Rym: Not saying this is lizard people.
Scott: It's just crab people?
Rym: What I'm saying is that this has all the trappings of something, a concept you might not be familiar with, called the, there's a lot of terms for it, but basically it's the canary, or the cop canary.
Scott: The bumble.
Rym: Yeah, or the warrant canary.
Rym: The idea that, say, I run a shady business where people buy and sell illegal goods at my home.
Rym: And let's say that one day, the police come to me and say, "You're fucked, and we're going to stake you out to get some of your customers.
Rym: If you say anything, we'll put you in jail forever.
Rym: If you play along, we'll give you minor charges at the end of all this,".
Rym: or immunity or whatever.
Rym: So, I can't just go to my friends and be like, "Yo, dog, the FBI's here.
Rym: Don't come and buy drugs from
Rym: me.".
Rym: That doesn't work.
Rym: But what if I say, just, you know, I put out a classified ad somewhere saying, "The FBI has never visited this house.
Rym: Here's the address.
Rym: Have I committed a crime?
Rym: Have I violated the terms of whatever deal I
Rym: signed?".
Scott: A judge would be the judge of that.
Rym: So, it appears, in my sort of outside opinion, and in the opinions of a lot of very smart people, that whoever did this to the website is trying to burn the brand of TrueCrypt as hard as possible to prevent people from continuing to use it or trusting it.
Rym: Especially in light of the fact that all analysis seems to point at the last stable version of TrueCrypt before this went down, which I believe is 7.1(a), as being still, as far as anyone can tell, perfectly secure.
Scott: And it's open source, so people have looked through the code on this thing.
Scott: It's not like there's a hidden back door, like there could be in some closed source thing.
Rym: So, right now, everyone who gives a shit about encryption is pouring over that last code with a fine-tooth comb.
Scott: Yeah, someone should just fork it and make a new project.
Rym: They probably will.
Scott: Like a little x386 to xorg situation.
Rym: There are four options for what happened here, and I'm going to list them for you in order of likelihood in my opinion.
Rym: Option one, the NSA sent these people one of their sealed security letters.
Scott: And they were cowards.
Rym: Yeah, like LavaBit.
Rym: Honestly, if the NSA came to me and Scott right now and gave us the security letter, I might consider not divulging it to try to not get fucked by the system, at least until I could get out of the country.
Scott: I would consider many options with the advice of lawyers.
Rym: Yes, but some of these letters don't let you talk to lawyers.
Scott: I talk to them anyway.
Scott: The lawyers not going to, how do they know I talk to a lawyer?
Scott: The lawyers has to be confidential too.
Rym: NSA security letters are bullshit, but I digress.
Scott: I talk to, I definitely wouldn't, there's no document anyone could hand me that I would not talk to a lawyer about.
Scott: It is possible.
Rym: I would comply enough to not get fucked by people way more powerful than me.
Rym: I'm not going to pretend that that would not be an option.
Rym: I would consider.
Rym: I am not that invested in protecting the forum from the NSA.
Rym: if they come for me, guys.
Rym: I got backups.
Rym: And as a result, the people involved complied, burned the brand and backed away.
Rym: Option two, there was an existing back door, someone tried to fix it or something happened and the NSA was like, no, no, no, you can't fix that.
Rym: and then they burned the brand.
Rym: Option three, the developers are just weirdos and this is what they thought was a perfectly rational way to shut down the project.
Rym: Option four, prank/someone compromised the site and the original owners have no way to uncompromise it due to their commitment to being semi-anonymous.
Rym: Option five, lizard people.
Rym: Option five is lizard people.
Rym: So be wary and stay tuned.
Rym: A lot of very smart people are doing a lot of analysis to figure out just what the fuck happened.
Scott: So if I want to encrypt my drives and I've never even thought about it before in my life and I don't have TrueCrypt installed or anything, I've got a bunch of unencrypted drives and no software to encrypt them, what should I do today?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: If I was ultra paranoid, I would do things we're going to talk about in the second part of this episode.
Rym: If I wasn't ultra paranoid, just use BitLocker for the time being.
Scott: I'm sure the Microsoft approved thing is completely safe from the government.
Rym: Yeah, it's probably safe for most use cases, but if it matters, you've got to do some due diligence research at this point.
Rym: Just saying.
Rym: I'll cover this in depth once there's follow-ups, believe me.
Rym: This is like NTP.
Rym: This kind of thing is deeply in my wheelhouse and I will let you know as soon as I learn more.
Scott: Are you using TrueCrypt?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: For what?
Rym: Not much.
Rym: I have multiple TrueCrypt volumes.
Rym: Most of them have inside of them the clear text passwords to a lot of things that I've accessed over the years that I might want to access again one day.
Rym: Burner email accounts that I established years ago, servers in places with stuff, the passwords to every bank account ever, just all that kind of shit, just in case.
Rym: You never know.
Rym: Also, scans of my passport and my driver's licenses and my birth certificates and all the things I would need to prove who I am in case something ever really fucked me.
Scott: Or you could just lose those hard drives.
Rym: Yeah, those encrypted volumes are in a lot of places.
Rym: Because what?
Rym: Someone finds them?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: What are you going to do with it?
Rym: It's fucking encrypted.
Scott: Use the back door.
Rym: Yeah, if there is a back door.
Rym: I hope you don't find my files if there's a back door.
Rym: If there isn't a back door, going to keep using the version of TrueCrypt that I used up until we figure out what the fuck happened to TrueCrypt.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: Scott's got a pretty typical thing of the day here.
Rym: People like to make logic gates.
Scott: Using mechanical things, which is the first way logic gates were ever made.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it's not a surprise.
Scott: But he did it using strings and pulleys and little rings and it's really cool.
Scott: I'd never even thought of this before.
Rym: It kind of really illustrates the increasing complexity of certain kinds of logic gates in terms of just like what they're doing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And notice how NAND is like the simplest one that's complex in any way.
Rym: That's why you can buy chips that are tiny that have like 400 NAND gates just in them.
Scott: Yeah, and that's why, you know, your CPU is mostly NAND gates.
Rym: Well, the other reason is you can derive all other gates from combinations of NAND gates.
Scott: It's like, oh, you don't need to make an AND gate.
Scott: You can just stick a few NAND gates together and make an AND gate.
Scott: And it's like, oh.
Rym: That was the only interesting class I took in IT my freshman year was we had to, it was like circuits and design and logic and hardware and engineering and all that.
Rym: So it was all about like signal processing.
Scott: So if you care about the stuff we talked in like the earliest of early GeekNights Monday episodes about how computers actually work, here's a very good video to help you understand that even better.
Rym: Though if you're trying to learn logic gates, to be perfectly blunt, the the water flowing through pipes with physical gates method is probably a better analogy.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: This is just cool.
Rym: So this is just a video.
Rym: So it looks like some guys put together and it's actually pretty entertaining.
Rym: They try to figure out what the tallest physical vertical straw as in a straw you drink through could actually be used by a human.
Rym: Like, could a human drink from this straw?
Rym: How tall could it be?
Rym: And it's fun because while you could calculate the you know, I mean, it's a well-known number, the maximum height that any siphon pump could work at.
Rym: If it's working based on vacuum.
Rym: And other things like that.
Rym: But this one.
Scott: You can go less than vacuum.
Rym: This one has.
Rym: Well, I guess if I use gravitational forces.
Scott: Now, you had to increase the pressure at the other end, right?
Scott: So if you do this experiment, say at sea level, you're probably going to get a lot higher than if you did it, say, at Mile House Stadium in Colorado.
Rym: Well, the interesting factor here is that they actually have people trying to drink from these straws and it's very well produced.
Rym: So I highly recommend you watch this.
Rym: It's really funny.
Scott: They didn't use it.
Scott: See, the thing is the guy just tried to drink from the straw and then he stops and he can't go any further.
Scott: What I would do is I would pinch the straw shut with my hand.
Scott: To basically hold the vacuum in there to keep the liquid up.
Scott: Take a breather and then go back to it.
Rym: I think he could not generate more force.
Scott: And I could.
Scott: I could suck even more air out of there and get the liquid.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Yeah, maybe.
Scott: I mean, once you have a vacuum, you have a vacuum.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm sure there was at least some air left in that straw that could have been sucked.
Rym: Well, let's have a straw sucking competition.
Scott: Let's do it.
Scott: Who sucks the most and the hardest and the longest?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I concede.
Rym: You win.
Rym: You suck the most.
Scott: I'm the best at sucking.
Rym: So in a moment, the Book Club book is I Canticle for Liebowitz.
Rym: It's basically the precursor book to all the types of apocalypse, post apocalypse books we've been reading recently.
Scott: And I don't think I have to read anymore because it's just sort of seal the deal.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Watch our YouTube join our forum.
Rym: Seriously, join our forum and post in it.
Rym: I see a lot of you in the forum, but since we've debated out a lot of the serious issues, most of you are lurking.
Rym: Post.
Scott: Say hi.
Scott: Just talk about whatever is nerdy right now.
Rym: Start up an old argument again.
Rym: And more importantly, a lot of women are in the forum lurking, but very few of you are posting.
Rym: Just pointing that out.
Rym: I've noticed that in the last couple of months.
Scott: Also go to all the other places that we have for communicating.
Scott: Twitter, Facebook, Google Plus.
Scott: We have a newsletter that I've actually been sending again because I set up a reminder.
Scott: It's a really good newsletter.
Rym: Connecticut is July 10th, 11th, 12th, 13th.
Rym: It's going to be fucking awesome and most of the schedule is up.
Scott: Beat that every other con ever.
Rym: God.
Rym: After some changes that happened internally, I'm pretty confident that next year the panels and workshop schedule is going to be up by March.
Scott: If you want to be part of Connecticut, you had to be really dedicated and get on that shit early.
Rym: Well, a lot of you submitted early, but due to other issues, we couldn't schedule early.
Scott: I think the cosplay deadline for Connecticut is in a week or something like that.
Scott: It's really fucking soon.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Take that every other con.
Rym: Oh, it's in Hartford, Connecticut.
Scott: That's the only problem with it.
Rym: Don't fly across the Atlantic Ocean to come to Connecticut.
Scott: If you can drive to Connecticut in one day and get there in time after you wake up in the morning and you're a nerd, you should be there.
Rym: If you live within one day's drive period, like six, seven hours.
Scott: And you don't have another more important plan.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Most things are now more important.
Rym: I mean, a wedding.
Scott: There are very few things that are more important, but there are some.
Rym: State level.
Scott: I would, I would miss a Connecticut.
Rym: Probably not.
Scott: I would miss a Connecticut if there were a pressing issue.
Rym: I would miss it for PAX.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I'd miss pretty much any convention for a PAX.
Rym: What about another PAX?
Scott: What, there's two PAXs at the same time?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I have a president's order.
Rym: PAX Prime trumps all other PAXs.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: So between PAX South and PAX East, might pick PAX South.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know anything about PAX South yet.
Rym: But Boston is increasingly disagreeable to me when it comes to PAX East.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: PAX is awesome.
Rym: Boston, not so much.
Scott: PAX South is much warmer with the weather.
Rym: So the old days, we're talking pre x86.
Rym: There were other kinds of computers that people had.
Scott: Even x86 is pretty old.
Rym: Yeah, we'll talk about those.
Scott: Even 486 is old.
Rym: Well, we have to talk about those because while you had an Apple IIgs, the first computer I owned was actually a 486s.
Scott: I didn't get that Apple IIgs until I was in high school.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In high school, I got a 486 and then later we got a Pentium Pro.
Rym: And before that, we didn't own a computer.
Rym: So I used some Apples and some Amigas and some IBM PCs in school, but I never owned one until that 486.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much the same deal.
Scott: We didn't own, you know, we didn't buy, I mean, my cousins had Commodore 64s, but we didn't have a, you know, general purpose computer.
Scott: that wasn't an Atari or an NES or anything until we had a 486.
Rym: So I'm going to get this out right before we talk about nostalgia and all that, because I referenced this at the beginning of the show.
Rym: There are two primary uses for that old technology today.
Rym: Three uses.
Rym: Primary use.
Rym: Use number one, showing people what old computing was like being in a museum, historical research.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: That is the most important use of that technology.
Scott: Every object created by man can have that purpose.
Scott: So that is pointless to say about any object ever created by man.
Rym: I think it's worth noting because people seem to forget about those things and then pieces of technology disappear due to no one bothering until it's too late.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Number two, and also, you know what?
Rym: That's useful to like, if you have a kid and they're complaining about their current computer, whip out your Apple II and be like, listen, fucker.
Rym: This is what I grew up with, so you shut up.
Scott: How does it work?
Scott: They try to touch the screen.
Rym: Tell you what, if you figure it out, I'm giving you your real computer back.
Rym: Show me Frogger running on this and then we'll talk.
Rym: Option two, use number two.
Rym: Hack them to do crazy fucking shit.
Rym: Use them with modern technology.
Rym: Get a CD-ROM to work on an Apple II.
Rym: Connect an old Amiga to the internet and then play a flash game.
Scott: There are a lot of ways to connect, you know, relatively old computers to modern technology.
Scott: My favorite one is a lot of old computers for like drives would use cassette tapes and the way that would work is you take cassette tape and you'd rewind it and press play and the audio on the cassette tape would basically be zeros and ones and it would work just like a modem.
Scott: A modem went...
Rym: You could save Atari games and stuff to cassettes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, well, you can, the thing is, okay, so you take that, right?
Scott: You basically have a recording of what a modem sounded like.
Scott: That audio is turned into zeros and ones.
Scott: It goes over this cable into the computer and the computer loads all that noise.
Scott: It takes as long as it takes the cassette to play.
Scott: Usually it would play the cassette at a faster speed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it just basically take all the audio data from the cassette, put it into RAM, then point the program counter at the beginning of the data and run it.
Scott: And that's a program that got loaded into memory.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: What you can do nowadays is you don't need a cassette.
Scott: You can just have an MP3.
Scott: And an MP3 can be loaded from the internet.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: On your phone.
Scott: So I can actually take my Apple 2GS, take a little cable out the top of my iPhone, plug it into the back of the Apple 2GS, go to a website, go to my Apple 2GS and type loader, whatever the command is.
Scott: On that website, there'll be a, you know, a built in audio file player press like SoundCloud or something.
Scott: I go to SoundCloud on my phone, press play.
Scott: And that wave file that's playing is right.
Scott: And then I'm basically downloading a program from the internet into the Apple 2GS and then running it.
Rym: Not so much.
Rym: Cool.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I think that's where most people are interested in.
Rym: this old technology is like taking an Apple 2 and just doing something crazy with like.
Rym: the demo scene is really into that still.
Scott: Are there still people in the demo scene?
Rym: The demo scene has not died.
Rym: The demo scene is kicking in strong.
Rym: That's something we need to bring to a PAX.
Scott: Well there's a thrice.
Scott: Or a ConnectiCon.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Any of you out there, if you're into the modern demo scene.
Scott: Or know any demo scene peeps.
Rym: Yeah, seriously, email me because I will get you into ConnectiCon either this year.
Scott: I don't know if they want to go to ConnectiCon.
Rym: Do you want like a dedicated place to demo this stuff to people?
Rym: I will make that happen.
Rym: Jesus.
Rym: Computing technology is the thing we lack the most at ConnectiCon right now in terms of our wide range of contents.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And that would be fucking awesome.
Rym: And I'm sure the overlap with the OC Remix people would be high.
Scott: I think the thing with the old computers, right, is if you want to do something cool with an old computer, you can probably do a similar thing with a modern but basic computer.
Scott: Like if you have an Arduino or Raspberry Pi, why would you do it with an Apple IIGS other than for the style factor?
Rym: About the style factor.
Scott: That's the only factor, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, your modern computers, you know, don't really have a lot of connectors on them that can be used to do things, right?
Scott: Like a USB, it's kind of hard to interface with the USB.
Scott: That's why you need like an Arduino where you can, you know, and all you do is use the USB to flash the Arduino.
Scott: and the Arduino interacts with the real world with more basic circuitry.
Scott: An Apple IIGS, you can just hook shit right up to it.
Scott: You don't need an Arduino in between.
Rym: And that stuff went all the way through to the, like the, until the serial and parallel ports died.
Rym: I mean, even my 486, it came with this huge manual that was just voltages and pin outs and information for all the weird fucking ports in the back.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I just plugged things in with wires and plug those wires into things and you could do stuff.
Rym: You could send arbitrary data over those pins.
Scott: Well, the other major thing about most, you know, the original PCs, right, up until, I guess, DOS, everything pre-DOS, even DOS came with basic, but like Commodores, Apple IIGS, Amigas, all those sorts of computers, when you turn them on, it was just, you didn't, I mean, there wasn't even a command line, like a shell, like DOS.
Scott: It's just the basic interpreter was just right fucking there.
Scott: And you were programming right from the get go.
Scott: Whereas on a modern computer, you need to install like a development environment to do any sort of programming stuff.
Scott: It's like the whole setup thing.
Scott: And I think that is like the key reason that, you know, programming is less accessible to people is because it's not in their face as it was in the olden days.
Scott: You know, even people today with like Macs will learn like some Bash shell stuff because there might open terminal once in a while, but they don't learn to program shit unless they want to learn to program shit and go out of their way to learn to program shit.
Rym: Now, maybe that's a secondary use from showing people stuff in that make it, getting someone, if someone really wants to learn technology, taking one of these old computers and giving them a task to accomplish with that computer, I think might be a great teaching tool.
Rym: because I learn more about computers, trying to figure out how to make games work on my computer that I learned from decade of schooling and a decade of working in the industry.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much just I wanted to make SimCity work.
Rym: Wouldn't fucking work.
Rym: I learned about memory management.
Rym: I learned about bootloaders.
Scott: I learned about boot disk partitioning.
Rym: I learned about the differences between extended and expanded memory.
Rym: I wanted to make my modems connect to play Doom.
Rym: I learned about null modems.
Rym: I learned how modems worked.
Scott: I learned about modem commands, serial cables versus parallel cable.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Everything I know about computers dates back to the fact that computers were complicated,
Scott: but
Rym: they were deterministic in a way that I don't want to say modern computers aren't deterministic, but they are to do an uninformed user, especially because software is so complex that a lot of software will effectively not act in a consistent manner when you try to use it.
Rym: So as a result, you can't learn as well about the underlying technology trying to interact with modern software on top of it.
Rym: Did word crash because of a bug?
Rym: Because of hardware?
Rym: Why did it crash?
Scott: It's like if you're trying to learn board games and the first board game anyone tries to teach you is like Twilight Struggle.
Scott: It's like that shit ain't gonna happen.
Rym: But if it does, you'll learn Twilight Struggle, but you won't learn board games.
Scott: It's like you gotta learn something simpler first, like maybe a backgammon or something where you can learn basic mechanics like this is how die rolling works, this is how moving pieces works.
Scott: Okay, you've learned two things, rolling dice and moving pieces.
Scott: Let's now move on to a game that has those things.
Scott: and a third thing.
Scott: The oldest computers only have a very few things, so you can learn a lot about computers in general with a very crappy computer that doesn't do anything really nowadays.
Scott: Whereas if you use a modern computer, all you can do with those is learn how to use a modern computer.
Scott: You can't learn anything about computers because it's way too complex and all that stuff is hidden beneath many, many layers of extraction.
Scott: So, what was the, uh, what kind of old computer?
Rym: Pause for a second.
Scott: Oh, you paused?
Scott: Why'd you pause?
Rym: And in a stroke of ridiculous irony, Audition, which we used to record GeekNights.
Scott: Our extremely modern and expensive software.
Rym: Just did something really weird and we had to stop recording to show because like it, all the waveforms disappeared.
Rym: It just flipped out and I had to restart it.
Scott: If we're using a trusty old Commodore, this wouldn't have happened.
Rym: Yeah, probably not.
Rym: It would have crashed because it ran out of memory or something.
Rym: Or because I unplugged it.
Rym: Or because there was a bug in the software, but then the bug in the software would be trivial to diagnose.
Rym: But, uh, I think there is a use.
Rym: If I was in charge of like a high school computer program, day one, everyone would get like an Apple 2GS and they would basically have to, over the first half of the course, learn how to use that thing to do everything they wanted to do and they'd have to use it to do their assignments in other classes.
Rym: And then in the second half of the year, they get a real computer.
Scott: You gotta upgrade him.
Scott: DOS next.
Rym: Oh yeah, take him through all the stages.
Scott: All the stages.
Scott: Up and up.
Scott: So what kind of old computers did you actually use in your life?
Rym: I actually used various IBM PCs, but my memories are so vague because this was like first, second grade that I cannot for the life of me tell you what like XT, whatever they were.
Rym: But we never used the computers raw.
Rym: All we would ever do is you go to like a computer lab and they'd have some software already running that would like ask you questions or make you learn how to type or something really stupid.
Rym: And I didn't learn anything about computers from that.
Scott: So pretty much only in school?
Rym: Yeah, not until I joined in middle school because in elementary school we got the, I typed essays in like fourth and fifth grade.
Rym: And then in sixth grade we got the four 86.
Rym: That was when I started using computers hardcore.
Rym: And the first things I did was install games that four 86 SX.
Rym: The second thing I did was realize that we fucked up buying the SX.
Rym: We should have gotten the DX.
Rym: It wasn't that much more money.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I actually, the first time I used a computer was an Apple two E in kindergarten.
Scott: And so of course we started out just like put in the word munchers floppy and turn it on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But within a few minutes I found the debug menu for word munchers and that was that.
Scott: Um, you know, pretty much every classroom in elementary school had an Apple two at least of some kind, EGS something.
Scott: And I would use it whenever I was permitted to do so.
Scott: And I just messed all around with it as much as possible.
Scott: And like I even went to summer camp and well, there was like a crappy summer camp I went to, which is basically go to one of the elementary schools in town for half a day every day in the summer.
Scott: And you could choose two activities.
Scott: So I always chose generic sporting activity for half of that time and sit in the computer room for the other half of that.
Scott: And you'd play Oregon trail and you'd program stuff.
Scott: And we mostly, it started, it was just like logo moving the turtle around.
Rym: Yeah, we did logo even, even in a middle school, we did logo and this is elementary school, right?
Scott: And then the Mac started to coming out and then shit went crazy and we're doing Mac paint and all that nonsense.
Rym: I really wanted a computer pretty much from kindergarten on.
Rym: Like I knew what they were and we use them in school occasionally.
Scott: You saw them on TV a lot.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But couldn't really get one.
Rym: I had my NES, which was enough.
Scott: Well, you could have one of those Atari computers, like an Atari 800 XL or something.
Rym: Yeah, no, I just had Atari gaming consoles.
Scott: My cousins had Commodore 64s, which I used a few times.
Scott: Some friends had them too, but they mostly use them like make music using the SID chip and whatnot.
Rym: My uncle worked at IBM, so he had a, he had a computer at home.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I was always excited to look at it, but he wouldn't let me mess with it too much.
Scott: Other people's houses that I went over mostly had early IBM's and we, you know, or like I go to my dad's office, he had like a 386 and he'd play some Wolfenstein, stuff like that.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: When I got the 486 and then I joined the computer club in quotes in middle school, the club was pretty much, if you had a computer or not, you could just stay in the school after hours for like four hours every Monday and just do whatever you wanted on the computers.
Rym: And pretty much all we did was play scorched earth.
Rym: We just played scorched earth every day forever.
Rym: But we had the shareware version and we were desperately trying to figure out how to unlock it to get that multi-shot tank.
Scott: I mean, I guess I went to a real summer camp where they taught programming also.
Scott: It was nerd camp and I was doing like HTML, learn C there, learn Pascal.
Scott: We were writing games, stuff like that.
Rym: I learned Q basic.
Rym: Like someone told me, like someone in the Science Olympiad, an adult was like, you should learn basic.
Rym: And then I found Q basic and then I wrote a bunch of applications that mostly did nothing useful and at best were really annoying to other people.
Scott: In high school we started a computer club and we basically collected all the old computer because that was about the time when Pentium ones were out, like maybe junior year, you know, Pentium twos even.
Scott: And basically we went around collecting all the computers that no one else is using anymore in the school, like all the Apple twos and shit.
Scott: And then we basically put them all together in this one sort of space and up top of the library that no one was using.
Scott: And we made like an old school computer lab.
Scott: And we were even like buying extra bits on eBay that they didn't have.
Scott: And that's that's where my Apple two GS and stuff that I have now.
Scott: My Mac Pro, not Mac Pro, Mac Plus, one megabyte comes from those days.
Rym: I remember carrying a single floppy disk around with me that had pretty much every file I cared about in the world.
Scott: I carried up until I got to RIT even, right, this plastic case that had a whole stack of floppies.
Rym: Well, I had a floppy that was just scorched earth and a couple other games because that one, like I'd leave in computers doing stuff.
Rym: I had another one that was Stuntz 4D Racing.
Scott: I had one that was my MUD client.
Scott: And that's another great example of even in the Pentium days, right, we had Windows 95, 98, and you really didn't have that low level sort of old computing experience to learn anything from.
Scott: I was doing more advanced stuff like doing MUDs.
Scott: So I was learning all about networking and how the Internet works, trying to tell that into servers, knowing what ports were and firewalls and all that kind of stuff.
Rym: I did my most fucking around with my modem.
Rym: I had a 2600 baud modem.
Rym: And what I do is I war dialed my neighborhood and I was looking for other modems and I was trying to get.
Rym: basically any time I found another modem, I tried to connect to it and see what was there.
Rym: And I found a couple of local BBSs.
Rym: I hit a lot of fax machines and people who seemed mad that a modem was calling them repeatedly.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't learn about modems like that kind of stuff.
Scott: The only thing I did was I dialed into the local library in my town to check what books were there because they actually like had a card at the library that said how to do it.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: I'd never thought about trying to, and I dialed friends to play command and conquer and stuff, but I never actually like realized you could dial into BBSs or anything like that.
Rym: I remember that moment of revelation where me and this kid Brock were like, like he was the super nerd.
Scott: He had rock Pokemon.
Rym: He had way more, this was before Pokemon.
Rym: He had way more, he was like the stereotype of the nerdy computer kid in every way.
Rym: But he was a cool guy, cool guy.
Rym: And he had a modem, I had a modem and I was, and we both kind of knew how modems work.
Rym: So we were like, we should be able to call each other and connect.
Rym: We spent an entire weekend calling each other, trying to get our modems to connect.
Rym: And that is when I learned fucking everything there was to know about modems.
Rym: And then there was this moment on Sunday afternoon where it's not like you get to Google anything.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We were reading the manuals to our computers, the back of my computer manual, this HP book that was like an inch thick, had a list of like modem commands, but some of them didn't work.
Rym: I didn't know why.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Computers don't come with that shit anymore.
Rym: It came out with like voltage diagrams of everything.
Scott: I bought a copy of Borland turbo seat plus plus.
Scott: I can had that for windows 3.1 and it came in this giant box.
Scott: It was 90 bucks with so many.
Scott: I still have those manuals somewhere.
Scott: Giant, giant programming manuals for like the owl libraries, which will let you actually make windows 3.1 windows show up and stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That was, that was a big deal.
Scott: Object windows library.
Rym: The cool kids had Borland C plus plus.
Rym: My parents wouldn't buy it for me cause it was expensive.
Scott: I bought it myself.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I spent all my money on NES games.
Rym: What'd you pay for that?
Rym: This is way later.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What'd you pay for that?
Scott: This is like middle school.
Scott: 90 bucks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Middle school.
Rym: So SNES games.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: For 70 bucks I brought chrono trigger.
Rym: That was way more important to me in my development.
Scott: I had enough games.
Rym: I did not.
Scott: I bought, I also bought mech warrior 2 and descent.
Rym: I, but when we, I typed like, Hey, are you there?
Rym: And he saw what I typed and typed back at me and we saw it in each other's consoles.
Rym: Like I saw the entire future blowing through my eyes and I knew what I was going to be when I grew up.
Rym: I was going to be a computer.
Scott: You have success.
Rym: So there is a fourth use for this technology for the old crap.
Scott: It's funny how like we have to talk about the uses that these gold computers still have.
Scott: because seriously, if you sit down at a computer, even a computer like a four 86, if it doesn't have internet, you really can't like modern internet with modern browsers and stuff like that.
Scott: It's really hard to find any reason to use spend any time using that computer short of playing an old game on it.
Rym: But there was a time in my life when I would sit at a non network computer for four hours in a row and be enjoying, I was having the time of my life, but now it's unthinkable.
Scott: It's like what?
Scott: This is a useless piece of junk.
Rym: So the fourth use is if you care a lot about encryption and privacy and security, don't use one of those computers.
Rym: That's not what I'm saying.
Rym: Use it offline to generate your GPG keys because that is the only hardware you will ever get your hands on.
Rym: That is pretty much guaranteed to not in any way be compromised.
Scott: I should generate keys with my apple two GS.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Then the only thing you have to trust is Scott and sell them.
Rym: You have to trust Scott.
Scott: No, you come over and we put a floppy disk and it generates the key and you walk out.
Rym: They have to trust the software you're using to generate the key.
Scott: I'll let them read it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And then they can press run themselves.
Scott: I'm dead serious because that hardware, I'll put the code on the internet, open source, then come to my house, download that software, put it into the apple two GS.
Rym: The hardware in those old computers is effectively open source hardware for all intents and purposes.
Scott: I mean, we talk about the apple two GS a lot.
Scott: And the reason is because the apple two GS is, it's an apple two.
Scott: It's not a Mac, right?
Scott: The Mac was already out when the apple two GS came out.
Scott: Uh, the apple two had existed for a long time.
Scott: The apple one even longer, right?
Scott: But, and I think the apple three was even out, but the apple two GS, the GS stands for graphics and sound.
Scott: It's an apple two, but the screen is much higher resolution.
Scott: It's not, it's all colors, not just green.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the sound is really great.
Scott: And if you, most of them have as Steve Wozniak's like signature inside of them.
Scott: And you think about apple computers now, and they're known for like this beautiful design and whatnot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's mostly in their software.
Scott: And the outside of their hardware, the inside of a Mac is, you know, in some ways a modern Mac.
Scott: on the inside is beautifully designed, but really it's complicated as fuck because it's a modern computer, right?
Scott: If you open an apple two GS, the inside of it compared to any other computer you're ever going to see is just miraculously beautiful.
Scott: Like the, the power supply goes straight down.
Scott: one side is all these identical slots lined up in a row.
Scott: Everything is perfectly labeled and laid out right in a logical way.
Scott: And not, it looks like you think like, ah, if you were, you're, they sacrificed all this performance to, to line things up in a way that's really friendly.
Scott: It's like the most user-friendly hardware desktop computer in the universe.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just, it's like this miracle.
Scott: So like if you want to get an old computer, I recommend that computer pretty much above any computer else that's old anywhere.
Rym: And think of this because the hardware is so well documented with those old documented, there's so much software for it.
Scott: You can get a hardware for it really easily.
Rym: You could plug this thing that you're going to use to generate your GPG keys into a hardware, like reliable random number generator.
Scott: There are so many things you can get for an apple two GS.
Scott: Like people plug, put heart modern hard drives in them.
Scott: People connect them to the internet and browse the web.
Scott: People play Wolfenstein 3d on them, which came out in the nineties way after.
Scott: like this note, this computer has no right to run that software, but it does.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It just, it's, you could, the favorite, the thing that I have is you basically have a novel, a serial cable.
Scott: So it goes USB on my real computer.
Scott: Then there's like a connector.
Scott: And then it goes into the modem port on the apple two GS.
Scott: I typed some commands in the apple two GS and I run some software on my computer.
Scott: And the apple two GS now thinks that the files on my hard drive in my modern computer are basically like floppy disks that are loading on it.
Scott: And it can, right.
Scott: And it's, it's, I think it's called ADB or ADP or something like that.
Scott: You can just search for it, like apple disc something.
Scott: And it's pretty miraculous.
Scott: The kind of stuff that you can do with that, right?
Scott: Like I can write apple two software on my modern computer and loaded onto the real hardware and not use an emulator.
Scott: So it just very, very supported.
Scott: Commodore 64 is also very supported, but you know, they're a little more annoying to use a little less reliable, whatnot.
Scott: But Hey, uh, the Commodore 64 put a man on the moon, so it's not, it's not shabby.
Rym: We didn't even get into calculators.
Rym: I think we did a show on calculators though.
Scott: Graphing calculators?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: My TI 85 fuck your 86 and it's bullshit.
Scott: My 86 is vastly superior.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The 85 had issues.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But your expanded memory was way slow.
Rym: You had to load stuff in that tiny memory area if you wanted performance.
Scott: I didn't need performance.
Rym: I needed performance to play mostly games.
Scott: Assembly program games.
Scott: They were fast anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I was writing basically basic games.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: For the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Scott: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: It's Monday, June 2nd, 2000.
Rym: Scott's microphone is not plugged in.