Rym: It's Thursday April 3rd 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and tonight's on GeekNights.
Rym: Whoa Let's do this.
Rym: I Guess more properly the GeekNights book club.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah it is so uh warm today.
Rym: Ah So Luxurious.
Scott: I was so close to bike only had to wear like a hoodie and not really much coat.
Rym: I little as not.
Rym: I was like I should bike to work tomorrow.
Rym: Then I went to bed then I woke up and I was like I should bike to work today.
Scott: It's right on the borderline where I think you'll be totally cool biking to work.
Scott: But since you'd be wearing shorts, and then you go over the bridge You'd be a little cold like not.
Scott: you'll make it and then it'll be.
Scott: it's like it's.
Scott: it's almost.
Scott: It's like on that border.
Scott: I have to grant warmer like fuck.
Rym: Yeah, I was significant advantage.
Rym: the Pulaski doesn't really count.
Rym: It's barely a bridge hair.
Scott: So no no I had hair.
Rym: I could bike now by the time I get to the Williamsburg Bridge, which is the bridge I have to worry about.
Rym: I'm already hot and sweaty from biking Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't have a bridge early in my ride only late in the ride.
Rym: The only reason I didn't bike was that I have not actually looked at my bike Since last time I biked.
Scott: yeah, I need to.
Scott: I mean I guess all I really need to do The tires.
Scott: I can probably just pump it up and go But I still got to check the brakes and make sure it.
Scott: I gotta clean it.
Rym: I got a lube it I actually want to degrease the chain and regrease it.
Scott: Do that now.
Rym: mine is pretty fucking grody.
Rym: Mmm.
Scott: It's only a year old.
Rym: Yeah, it's never been cleaned.
Scott: That's Apparently, you know you still have the original grease.
Scott: That's from the when you've got the chain when the bike was new Supposed to not remove that for as long as humanly possible because you can basically never get lubrication better than what came from the factory.
Rym: Well, my old mountain bike actually I never lubed it ever in the like 15 years.
Rym: I used that bike.
Scott: Well, that's too long.
Rym: Yeah, it worked fine.
Scott: But yeah that lube that come when you buy a brand new bike the chain like comes pre lubed from the factory.
Scott: Supposedly even on shitty bikes that is like the master lube like the amazing.
Scott: you cannot do better than that.
Scott: So you should basically not clean that off Until like years when you absolutely have to and it's like okay it the master lube has finally stopped working.
Scott: now I have to resort to my you know bottle of whatever.
Rym: So, yeah, we're not gonna do much news because it's the book club.
Rym: but I just want to point out because it's kind of breaking news that Pax East which after the Boston bombings did not have to go through the security theater that anime Boston was forced to go through as of 2014 is now inexplicably and suddenly being forced to go through the ridiculous Intrusive bag checks at every entrance.
Scott: Oh, well, that's gonna be real bad.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll see how it goes.
Rym: Not too excited about it.
Rym: The only thing I can really say about this is that if you're mad you should complain to the city of Boston Like you should actually email the mayor of Boston.
Scott: I mean actually this, you know, we all know it's security theater, right?
Scott: We don't need to talk about that again for the 10 billionth time.
Scott: This is so obviously a scam to basically quote create jobs, right?
Rym: Yep So I mean it's because the city provides these people.
Rym: there's tons of them.
Rym: None of them want to be there.
Rym: I remember one lady when she was checking my bag at anime Boston Was going through the motions cuz her manager was there and she kept saying to me.
Rym: I'm so sorry I'm sorry.
Rym: I have to do this.
Rym: Really.
Rym: I'm just I'm sorry.
Rym: She kept saying that everyone she was checking the bags for they know.
Rym: So yeah, this sucks.
Rym: The only thing I can say is that Pax Prime is literally in every way objectively superior to Pax East at this point.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Pax East I'm gonna see it's gonna be hilarious.
Scott: So a few thousand people are gonna try to get in on Friday at 10 a.m To go to the keynote, right?
Scott: As far as I can see Waiting in the security line and then they're going to go up to the real line and While the keynote is.
Scott: if the keynote starts on time The room might not even be full.
Scott: people might still be in the security line and then as soon as they get through running to The keynote and getting there while it's in progress.
Rym: I also predict that unlike Pax Prime Pax East basically no attendees are in a hotel that's connected to the convention center.
Rym: That shit was sold out before the hotels went live.
Rym: So the vast majority of the people attending Pax East are walking to the convention from far away or taking a shuttle From far away.
Rym: They're all gonna have bags and there's more people there than anime Boston.
Rym: I'm not saying it's gonna be disaster.
Scott: They're all people who want to get in immediately as soon as the thing opens either for the keynote or the dealers for hall Exhibition room.
Rym: Yep, a Couple.
Rym: all that with the fact that there's really only two entrances.
Scott: But actually because people don't meander in and out of the Pax East a whole lot during the day Like once they get that line through it should actually be okay, but then once people leave at night They ain't coming back which I already weren't coming back because of the hour decrease.
Scott: They're really not coming back.
Rym: Pax ends at midnight and I get dinner at 8 p.m I'm not going back.
Rym: Well, I am cuz I'm.
Rym: I have to.
Scott: I'm enforcing.
Rym: my enforcer shift is the entire con.
Rym: I'm not.
Scott: well I'm enforcing.
Scott: I hopefully I picked the night shift.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah.
Rym: so Not super excited about this.
Rym: I hate to say it, but Probably wouldn't attend Pax East if I weren't a guest speaker and or an enforcer that goes for pretty much every convention.
Rym: I would go to Pax Prime if I was just an attendee.
Rym: Yeah, sure I would go to mag fest if I was just an attendee.
Rym: Well, obviously those are probably the only two major cons I'd go to if I was just an attendee.
Scott: to be perfectly blunt I might go to ConnectiCon if I was cuz you know what.
Scott: I would go to Just an attendee of ConnectiCon.
Scott: you know what I could do.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'd play fucking game.
Scott: Oh, man, right?
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I would go to ConnectiCon if I was just an attendee even though I've never done that cuz.
Scott: I've always been a guest Or staff or something, but we have gone to kinetic cons where he didn't have much to do.
Rym: Yeah Well, we were in panels, but that was it.
Rym: Well, there was that one year but way back where we showed up not knowing if we had panels tricked the staff into giving us badges as guests and then we looked through the schedule found that they had scheduled all the same panels that we did the previous year that year without Telling us and then proceeded to show up in front all those panels.
Rym: kinetic ons come a long way guys But yeah, that's neither here nor there GeekNights book club, but first things of the day.
Scott: So there's this guy.
Scott: I'm not sure what the context of this video is.
Rym: it doesn't really matter It is bikes.
Scott: I think this guy is like an important person or maybe famous or something and I just don't know him.
Rym: I'm gonna try to figure it out.
Scott: Let's see being interviewed by someone or something.
Scott: I don't know Tyler the Creator.
Scott: Yeah, he's someone he's Somebody.
Rym: this video only has 4,000 views.
Scott: He's just not as somebody that I know.
Scott: the point is whoever's interviewing him, right?
Scott: I guess ask him something.
Scott: But the video does not contain the question only contains the answer.
Scott: and this is the greatest advice Regarding bicycles that I've ever heard in my entire life.
Scott: and a seven-second YouTube video You can have.
Scott: you have seven seconds.
Scott: You can watch this video.
Rym: so I think I I still don't know what he is.
Rym: I think he makes music.
Scott: Okay, I Knows about bikes.
Scott: It's all that matters.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: He knows everything about bikes.
Scott: bicycle advice.
Scott: That is Google new.
Rym: He's a rapper.
Rym: Tyler Gregory on Konma better known as Tyler the creator is an American rapper rapper and record producer from California.
Rym: He's 23 years old and his albums are called wolf bastard and goblin.
Scott: I'm liking this guy more every second.
Rym: also the three pictures of him that Google decided to show me.
Rym: I think he's a cool dude liking this guy.
Scott: Okay, you see that I don't know if that's his official Twitter or not.
Scott: I'm just looking at your screen in the Google search results.
Scott: Yeah, it seems if that is the real account and not a parody account that his actual Twitter handle is fuck Tyler.
Rym: If that is true, he is the best.
Scott: This guy's awesome.
Rym: We'll find out.
Rym: I'm gonna listen to his music later.
Rym: Yeah, maybe I'll put it in the anyway.
Rym: So yeah My thing of the day.
Rym: This is a short.
Rym: It's actually a long short.
Rym: It's pretty long.
Rym: It's called the expert Mmm, and I will say this this is a hundred percent too real.
Rym: I Real I have been the most real in meetings that if you literally take this exact conversation and just I didn't so many of these meetings just replace the proper nouns with TCP IP and Servers and shared objects.
Rym: It is literally the same meeting right down to Exactly what the executives say the body language of the executives the.
Rym: well Let's not lose track of the big picture here.
Rym: We have a task that's set before us.
Rym: Those exact words have been said to me dozens of times.
Scott: I've been in this exact meeting many times.
Rym: So if you want to know what the jobs of people like me and Scott are like when we have when we have a meeting When we have a meeting with someone who is not a technical person.
Rym: It is it is literally this and I know what you're gonna think when you're watching this video.
Rym: You're no one that you yourself if I were in that room.
Rym: I would quit and walk the fuck out.
Rym: Yeah Yeah That's happened.
Rym: Yeah, I've done that.
Rym: I've seen people in meetings like this quit their jobs in said meetings.
Scott: that actually What I do in this in meeting situation is you know, it's like the guy sort of caves in.
Scott: he's like, I'm you know I can do anything.
Scott: I'm an expert where I'm like, no he didn't.
Rym: that was obviously.
Scott: he's Sarcastic and he's checked obviously, but what I do is I'm like, no really really I like.
Scott: I basically try to make that the other.
Scott: I turn it on them to make them seem He went and then people don't like me.
Scott: But that's not.
Rym: he went through all the stages that the engineer goes through including trying to use stupid back at stupid.
Rym: He's like, well, I'm gonna draw the other six with transparent ink.
Rym: How's that?
Rym: I'm doing it right now.
Rym: Yeah, so if you cringe while watching this welcome to the corporate world reality This is what's real.
Scott: It's a stone-cold dose of fucking real if you're like in college and you're getting ready to go enter the job world.
Scott: Just be ready Once you have a job and you're a smart person.
Scott: That is what the job will be like when you have to communicate with people who are dumbasses.
Scott: now guys know anything about technology.
Rym: I want to say something else because this isn't Monday GeekNights.
Rym: It's Thursday GeekNights.
Rym: I don't know who the fuck you are but if you watch this video and you've been in meetings that are of this nature like a technologist and the salespeople and the stakeholders and all that business and You're one of the people other than the engineer
Scott: right like an you're in a meeting and an engineer told you that's not and that's impossible.
Scott: that can't be done.
Rym: like if you could envision a meeting like this where you're not the engineer and You don't think that meetings went this way.
Rym: You're wrong.
Rym: that meeting went this way and you're the problem.
Scott: You are the problem.
Scott: You don't deserve your job or whatever monies you have.
Scott: you should go back to school.
Scott: I go back to school right now.
Rym: This is way too real.
Scott: This is the most real.
Rym: In the better moment the book club book was wool.
Scott: we're talking about it right the fuck now This weekend when they chose the wool or were you the one that shows?
Rym: I chose the wool because too many people gave me free Copies, I do have a sign free copy.
Scott: I haven't chosen anything else yet because I didn't realize I had to do something.
Scott: No, I'll choose something for the next episode.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: That's fine This weekend if you're in New York City, which Someone wind up.
Rym: Well, a lot of people we know are in New York City for this.
Scott: Oh, you don't say we know a lot of people in the place where we live.
Rym: Yeah, but no a lot of people who don't live here are here because it's the mocha fact because it's New York City Mocha fest is this goddamn weekend.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: We're gonna be there Saturday pretty much at the open Until we leave it until we see everything there.
Rym: We're gonna go buy a pie.
Scott: Yeah, and then eat an awesome lunch somewhere.
Rym: Yep, if you're going to be next weekend in Boston and you can get through the security theater one I recommend try to snag some tabletop gaming space in the hotel Early like if I were you and I was going to PAX East.
Rym: Do all the stuff in the con you want to do before noon.
Rym: get a huge lunch at legal seafood test kitchen.
Scott: That's the only place to eat and then go to the hotel.
Rym: Get a space to game and don't fucking give up that space for anything for the rest of the night.
Rym: That is my suggestion to you but Friday 1 p.m.
Rym: In the badger theater.
Rym: We will be doing our most controversial panel.
Rym: yet Why no one will game with you.
Scott: It's so controversial.
Scott: We're gonna get in trouble.
Scott: It'll be the last packs panel we do up.
Rym: if we didn't get in trouble after our Vietnam When we fucked up that late show, I don't think we could get into we would.
Rym: I would have to like get on stage Say something racist and drop my pants.
Scott: Yeah, what was that?
Scott: There was a dancy guy who got kicked out, right?
Rym: Yeah, and all he did was take his pants off.
Rym: Yeah, as far as like.
Scott: well That's a lot.
Rym: I'm not gonna say all he did was take his pants off.
Scott: That's a lot.
Rym: the straw that broke the camel's back was taking his pants off.
Rym: He was otherwise just a fucking.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of fucking.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, so Why no one will game with you.
Rym: That's that's actually what we're talking about.
Rym: Why no one's gonna game with you.
Scott: let you right now because no one likes you.
Rym: Yeah Or at least they don't like your game.
Scott: dumb person in the meeting.
Rym: Ah Badger theater.
Scott: other matter items.
Scott: Come and find us on the internet and all the places on the internet that people are and existing.
Scott: We are also there.
Rym: We're gonna be a zenk icon on Saturday and Sunday doing panels in Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Rym: April the fuck is this con a 25th?
Rym: So I guess the 26th and 27th of April we're gonna be there.
Rym: Kinetic count is coming up a couple months down the road.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and we're gonna be at PAX Prime.
Rym: I'm probably gonna be at PAX OS.
Rym: I'm gonna be at PAX dev.
Rym: I don't know if Scott will be there or not.
Rym: Maybe probably gonna be at the next PAX East probably be the next anime Boston Getting way ahead of ourselves.
Rym: So well, I picked will as a book literally because So many people gave me free copies of it and a bunch of people were talking about it on the internet.
Rym: Either it was gonna be good Which is awesome or it was gonna be another King killer chronicle.
Rym: captain penis fucks his way through being a nice guy in a fantasy world.
Scott: Well, I mean anything in the world is either good or bad.
Scott: Yeah But but not just bad but bad enough to where I'm actually what there was no chance of it being slightly bad or just mediocre.
Scott: It was either gonna be amazing or crap.
Rym: There was no.
Rym: someone tweeted at me recently and they said something like man The King killer chronicle really shat in your Cheerios didn't it?
Rym: and I was like, you know what?
Scott: Kind of did but yeah, no, I mean whenever something is ridiculously popular, right?
Scott: Some nerds have a reaction where they don't even know anything about it.
Scott: yet All they know is that thing over there is ridiculously popular and that either makes them Want to check it out super hardcore or if they're a different kind of nerd it makes them want, you know Immediately judge it to be shitty and mainstream or too popular and they completely, you know Say it sucks even though they're nothing about it yet, right?
Scott: There tends to be a lot of nerds that do that Whereas for me when I see something that's ridiculously popular I go Mmm, and I don't.
Scott: I don't necessarily say that sucks cuz it's not you know, most of the time it's it's not complete garbage Right, very few things are ridiculously bad, right?
Scott: Oh Dean comes across once a century, right?
Scott: But I don't immediately like jump on board either right?
Scott: I'm always just skeptical like why is that thing?
Scott: So popular?
Rym: we'll do a little bit of research.
Scott: Why am I seeing this so frequently?
Scott: right before I even read wool I saw someone on the train on the subway Reading shift which is the sequel and I was like, huh?
Rym: Which apparently we were told is shit.
Scott: What's up with that?
Rym: So, yeah And like I said, the anecdote was I was given a free copy by two different people And we got a free copy when he went to some charity dinner in like the goodie bag Yep, so I had all these free copies.
Rym: So and So all that last I'm gonna say this one last time guys, it's a book club.
Rym: we're talking about it assuming you already read it.
Rym: So I'm not gonna summarize the plot.
Rym: We're gonna spoil Everything and there's a lot to spoil.
Scott: and this is one of those books where it's like.
Scott: it looks physically large like large paper.
Rym: No, it takes like a few days.
Scott: it takes like no time to read this book.
Scott: the text is big.
Scott: it reads really fast.
Rym: So if you haven't read it yet Stop listening and go read the book.
Rym: the whole point of the book club is that you've read the book.
Scott: We're trying to make you read a book.
Rym: We're trying to enjoy that experience That is so rare where you and all your friends all saw the same movie or read the same book and then you talk about It like the last several months of Kill La Kill So wool, uh, I liked it actually.
Scott: Yeah, it's okay.
Scott: I mean, you know, I said this on a previous episode, right but might as well compact it.
Scott: You know reiterate myself for anyone who's just listening to this when I first read like page one, two, three I'm immediately thinking of you know, Logan's run Fallout paranoia RPG all those I'm like, this is another one of those and I'm like, well, that's kind of good I like those.
Rym: those are things I'm down with and there aren't that many of those that have Multiple of those in the same story.
Rym: that paranoia is usually just paranoia Brazil is usually just Brazil.
Scott: Brazil doesn't have the see.
Scott: this is more specific than that.
Scott: right.
Scott: Logan's run paranoia and fallout all have Not just the sort of post-apocalypse weird society issue Which also Brazil has yeah, but it they also have the specific thing of people Locked in to a place right where the entire society is enclosed sealed in Phoenix Phoenix volume 2.
Rym: future also has them within that space like the paranoia side The people are color-coded in some fashion and don't Right, but any.
Scott: well, there was some intermingling at least in wool, but it was superficial.
Rym: That's kind of the point.
Scott: So on the one hand I'm like that is that is a trope a story mechanic that I like a kind of story that oh Wow, Wikipedia fucking spoils it immediately, right?
Scott: But on the other hand, right?
Scott: Immediately, I'm also giving it minus points in the first few pages.
Scott: cuz I'm like, oh it's just ripping off Paranoia fallout etc.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So on the one hand it's like, okay It's another one of those things that I like that I've seen so often.
Scott: But it's another one of those right plus and minus from the get-go, but then I realized something After like chapter 2 I'm like, you know, let's let's think about this for a second.
Scott: Logan's run right fallout paranoia the RPG Phoenix volume 2 Those are fucking obscure things only nerds know about.
Scott: I mean, maybe Logan's run.
Rym: Well, maybe if you've never read a like a lot of fantasy fiction You might read Game of Thrones and think oh my god.
Rym: It's so serious.
Scott: Maybe Logan's run.
Scott: a normal non nerd would know about.
Rym: it has to be a normal non Nerd who's also kind of old at this point, right?
Scott: It's like the things that tell this story.
Scott: this story has been told at least five six times before But every place the story has been told is in an obscure nerdy You know media that only people like us even know about.
Scott: they're super popular among people like us But among the general populace of the world.
Scott: this story has not really been told in pop culture outside of Logan's run Which isn't that popular?
Scott: Yep, so This is like hey, you know, I saw people reading this shit on the subway.
Scott: This is introducing that story that it to them.
Scott: This seems unique and amazing and original Right.
Scott: I don't know if the author of this, you know borrowed or came up with the idea I do.
Rym: if this guy has never heard of any of those things I'm kind of amazed at his.
Scott: well supposedly Harry Potter lady never read any, you know book of magic or whatever.
Rym: I could see that though.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Anyway, yeah what?
Scott: so and and supposedly What's it called Hunger Games?
Scott: never read battle royale or knew it existed Right, but you wouldn't believe it unless you know.
Rym: There's one thing that you might not realize out there that you probably should.
Rym: this was written as sort of a series of short stories.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it wasn't originally a single book, right?
Scott: So the wall guy so the book that we got that was just wool is actually like five books.
Rym: It's five books, but really it's three books.
Rym: One though, you know the first guy and again last warning fucking spoilers.
Scott: That's up until the the mayor dies is book one, right?
Rym: No book one is up until the first cleaner We see dies.
Scott: That's like not long at all.
Rym: Yeah, that's book one.
Scott: That's like four pages You know what?
Rym: I really like book one because book one Reminded me in every way of what is not even a book as a pamphlet.
Rym: You know what it is It's a Ray Bradbury short story.
Scott: Yeah book one is a pamphlet.
Rym: It's even in the style of a Ray Bradbury short story.
Rym: I mean look it sets up.
Rym: Oh, but you know, it sets up this world really quickly.
Rym: It sends him out there like oh He wants like a tent like he wants to go for a clean Twilight Zone episode.
Rym: Yeah, but explains the deal.
Rym: He's convinced that you know.
Rym: His wife went out there because she learned that they had the technology to make the screen show whatever it wanted.
Rym: She's like, oh they pulled the wool over her eyes.
Rym: The screens a fake.
Rym: She went out there didn't come back.
Rym: So he's like, I know that she knew something.
Rym: I know the screen can fake it.
Rym: I'm gonna go out there.
Rym: Holy fuck the world's awesome.
Rym: Oh wait, they can fake it but wrong screen Mm-hmm, and that ending where he pot, you know You think he pops the mask off and then he just fucking dies out in the wilderness in the toxic air.
Rym: Yeah, that was great.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not gonna say I didn't see it coming But I didn't see the fullness of it coming.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't see the.
Scott: you know the.
Scott: you know it's like you're reading the description of the screen over the face and it's like I only had to read two words of that description before Completely grok the whole situation right and then like it felt like when I'm reading the rest of those paragraphs like yep Yep, I already got it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yep, you know, but I didn't get it before like the first two words of that paragraph.
Scott: Yep, it's weird like that.
Scott: It's like, you know, you sort of you feel like you figured it.
Scott: you didn't figure it out actually in advance, right?
Scott: But you figured it out basically Right before Actually reading it like at that moment.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: It's almost like your brain has already read the rest of the words in the page But you still haven't read the rest of the words in the page.
Rym: But all I could think was that whole system seems clever because just knowing that from the beginning part of the book All right Anyone who expresses a desire to leave is probably gonna be a problem in a society like this.
Rym: So set up a system that guarantees they'll go die.
Rym: But then why have this ridiculous that's over?
Scott: After I read that first book one, I guess technically right as soon as I finished it I was like, aha Aha, so many questions have been answered right away.
Scott: very interesting.
Scott: and then I'm like, but why?
Rym: yeah It's like that you could just fucking shoot those people and say don't fucking go outside.
Scott: Why you know, why do you have to lie to someone who's going to be dead any second?
Rym: Well, obviously you could think it's to trick them into doing the cleaning anyway, but would that get?
Rym: why not cleaning?
Rym: Why not just fake the screen not needing cleaning and just kill people who break the rules?
Scott: Yeah, I didn't.
Scott: it didn't make a lot of.
Rym: so why don't I just fake them doing the cleaning and just have them all go out There and die they can't get back in.
Scott: You don't need to show the real outside world.
Scott: You can just show some fake outside world that you've curated with your computers and then anyone who goes into that room You just incinerate them into dust.
Rym: Yeah, and you just animated a person going out of them going out and cleaning.
Rym: Yeah, I I don't know.
Rym: so it was interesting that book two started and then just killed all those characters, too.
Rym: Yeah, I like that a lot actually.
Scott: Well, I liked it in that we got to.
Scott: you know You read like an Ursula manga right and he constantly introduces a new character and then makes you care about them.
Scott: Yeah, right But they're never there.
Scott: all these side characters that he makes you care about for like a minute and then he moves around a whole Bunch here.
Scott: It's sort of similar introduce a new character make you care about it.
Scott: I like that because there's more characters to care about and you end up caring about them But they're all main characters and then they kill them and then they introduce you another one and that you care about that.
Scott: Why - after book - and you're not like.
Scott: I'll bring back the old one.
Rym: No Like after book one just because the the plot seems so sort of over complicated.
Rym: Now I thought of that as being minus points, but then after didn't see it's another complicated.
Rym: Well, no, no, no, not the plot of the book the plot of the screen.
Scott: Oh, yeah Contrived like.
Rym: really you're gonna have a super complicated like.
Rym: right, right.
Rym: Okay, but then after book two, I Like the sort of when you say you start to figure out that actually it is a lot more complicated.
Rym: I actually really got invested in what the fuck was going on with this world.
Rym: Well, I mean because it has this theme that was kind of subtle of the it's.
Rym: again It's always the zebra storyteller that the first characters the initial people who die Got the seed and then went out and died.
Rym: They had to be killed before that seed could sprout but a tiny tiny piece of that seed survived Inside of the silo.
Rym: someone else found it and otherwise had they not learned about the screens They would have died too, but they learned about the screens.
Rym: But because they started a slightly ahead of everyone else and had a tiny bit more Before they learned that.
Rym: yeah, they learned the resolution.
Rym: So when she goes outside there's that moment of oh my god, the visor is XP, you know exit to eight by two inches.
Rym: So she knew exactly what the fuck was going on because she'd been primed a tiny bit.
Rym: and the look at the overall theme of this book.
Rym: Information is the most powerful thing in the world.
Rym: having the tiniest tiniest sliver of information a hundred percent changed the outcome of that.
Rym: cleaning Juliet instead of dying could a hundred percent save the day and because she shared that with one other person He was able to make the supply thing happen.
Rym: Yeah, and then that everything just cascades from there and information is literally a small not literally.
Rym: information is a snowball in these books.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's something I didn't like about that aspect of the story.
Scott: right is that you know information is so powerful Which is why IT sort of ran the show.
Scott: The bad guys.
Scott: I guess, you know, at least the organization IT was the bad guys.
Scott: Yeah, but even though any all the individuals in IT even the baddest guy were Bernard.
Rym: I hated Bernard so much.
Rym: But then as he's at least sympathetic at time because he makes that really good point of yes The people who set this up are horrible and evil.
Scott: but what the fuck are we supposed to do instead?
Rym: They already did it.
Rym: They already ruined the world.
Rym: And what do you want me to do?
Rym: Let everyone die.
Rym: My chance my options are follow through with their plot so that at least someone will survive to rebuild or Fuck it.
Rym: Let's just all die.
Rym: Right like it's very hard to see another way out for him.
Scott: No, no But yeah, I hope that we're gonna see some sideways digging I guess in the future books.
Rym: if you read I'm not gonna read the rest of the books because you learn.
Rym: Luke Burrage basically said they're literally not worth reading and I trust him a lot.
Scott: I trust him also.
Rym: Yeah, also I read what they're about.
Scott: Well, the second one's about silo 1 right which is interesting cuz like you kind of want feel like that.
Scott: Would that's like where all the mysteries are at.
Scott: you want to know about that, right?
Rym: Yeah, except it seems to be a prequel and it's about a congressman.
Scott: Oh It's not actually about what's happening in silo 1 right now.
Rym: Oh, no, did you actually did you read the afterword in the book the Q&A with the author?
Rym: Yes, where he was like you won't believe what's going on in silo 40.
Rym: It's like really now I really want to know what's going on in silo 40.
Scott: I don't care about silo 40 I care about what's happening in silo 1 where the big bad guys are right now.
Scott: That's like knowing what's going on in the Death Star where the Emperor is.
Rym: Yep I don't know what's going on and you know, most of the silos made it only what like three Yeah died.
Scott: so probably all just carrying on the same way that the wool silo was carrying on Yeah before any bad things happened.
Rym: But that was that was the moment when I did not see coming like.
Rym: I expected a lot of things from this book But when she didn't do the cleaning and she walked over the horizon When Bernard was like, oh fuck.
Rym: and then he calls the other silos.
Rym: He's like, this is silo 18.
Rym: We got a problem.
Rym: I didn't expect there to be all these other silos Silos really but why I expected there to be other silos and it to be a really sort of Disconnected plot of like they're not to get.
Rym: I did not expect the IT departments of all the silos to be in constant communication.
Scott: Right, it's because they present right like Bernard and IT of their silo as like the biggest bad.
Scott: You couldn't imagine a square boss really like at the square boss you imagined was hiding in the silo right not somewhere else It was sort of like a clever ruse, but it's like I didn't under even at that moment.
Scott: I'm like, why is it such a big deal that she didn't clean and walked over the hill and she'll die over there?
Scott: Who gives a fuck?
Scott: Yeah, why is it important that they see her die on the thing?
Scott: Why is it a real, you know, you saw?
Rym: yeah Why are they engineering the suits the way they did all this stuff?
Rym: like I thought the plot was going to be up before that point.
Rym: they engineer the suits to fail because They are evil and they're trying to keep the people in the silo from trying to expand For what you know just so they can maintain their power kind of like in North Korea Mm-hmm, but then you find out that actually no they're trying to maintain all the other North Korea's so that they can all keep going.
Scott: Yeah, because I guess if the North Korea's all knew about each other they wouldn't be able to keep going.
Rym: Well, no the idea is that because look at how dangerous information is and look at how apparently silo 17 like silo 18 Almost had the same thing a little bit of information just cascades into disaster and the silos done Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the idea is to segregate the silo.
Rym: So if one goes crazy all the rest are fine.
Rym: Hmm.
Scott: What do you do if your head of IT is all fucked the fuck up?
Scott: You're putting all your eggs in one basket in one silo depends entirely on one person.
Rym: Yep That's actually that kind of body.
Scott: That's what happened in this particular silo.
Scott: Is it fucked up?
Scott: because Bernard fucked up trying to poison.
Scott: he could have just not done that and it would have been just fine.
Rym: Yeah, if he hadn't poisoned the mayor actually none of this bullshit would have happened, right?
Rym: He was just stupid.
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: I guess there must have been something in the order that told him to do that.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: It's hard to say.
Scott: Yeah, it's like why.
Scott: why did he do that?
Scott: Yeah, he wasn't trying to poison the mayor.
Scott: He was trying to poison the sheriff guy.
Scott: Yeah, you know The second income, but even then why poison him?
Rym: all that's gonna do is raise questions and cause fucking issues.
Rym: Why Russell Jimmy's that can be left on rustled, right?
Scott: I'd like why did he like?
Scott: what in the order told him to do that?
Scott: Why was that?
Rym: also he trusted?
Rym: Let's say he's way too quick.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, let's say he had succeeded in Poisoning.
Scott: just the second, you know, the the sheriff is great.
Rym: So now you have a mayor who's gonna be sad and pissed off and a new sheriff who she trusts Who's gonna be really pissed off and they're gonna investigate the fuck out of that, right?
Scott: It's not that you know, his plan was not a plan that was going to help the silo.
Scott: So I don't understand, you know why he did that or what order suggested.
Scott: that was a good one.
Scott: I also don't understand is why the silo all the other silo or maybe just letting what's your name the main character?
Rym: Juliette.
Rym: Yeah, if you let Juliette really you forgot I can't the whole subplot about Romeo and Juliet and I remember that now.
Scott: Yeah, if you if you just let Juliette be sheriff would that really have brought about the doom of the silo on its own?
Rym: Or he could have gotten rid of her later if she figured stuff out.
Scott: I mean the sheriff was already bad seed or whatever, right?
Rym: So yeah, if he hadn't called her back up to do the cleaning she probably wouldn't have figured any of that shit out, right?
Rym: Anyway, but yeah, honestly the only part of this book I did not like is the whole Super long section about her going down to get the pumps going again and then the drama of that failing Oh in the other silo.
Rym: Yes, that store that Chapter that like plot was way too long.
Scott: Yeah The pacing of it was was way off and it was cause.
Rym: it was happening at the same time as the much more Interesting plot in silo 18.
Rym: Yeah with the revolution I wish that holds like it.
Rym: I think a better editor would have told them to Literally skip over that part.
Rym: have her go down be successful with the pump come back up and find a solo knocked out.
Rym: Right that should have been like a few.
Scott: it's like, you know, they build that up so much They spend all this time building it up and it's like yeah doesn't matter need to build that up.
Scott: diving with like Shoddy diving equipment under all that water is fucking scary You don't need to explain it to me for like two chaff.
Rym: and also she's a goddamn engineer the whole book.
Rym: She is like the the the uber engineer and yet she doesn't test this at all doesn't do a test.
Rym: If you're gonna give me that level of detail on the production dive Then show her doing the test dives then it makes sense that it failed because she didn't account for something.
Rym: Don't just have her be stupid.
Rym: and then have her be stupid for like an entire fucking set of.
Scott: And then don't days X the recovery with the air trapped under the stairs and shit.
Rym: Yeah, that also wouldn't have worked.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I was just that whole chapter That seriously who edited this book.
Rym: that should have been cut anyway.
Rym: Yeah, that was just.
Rym: that was just baby's first novel.
Scott: The other thing that bothered me slightly about this book was how you know I tease the bad guy and mechanics is the good guy, right?
Scott: It's like you it's Where the tones.
Scott: were they really the good guy?
Rym: because what was their immediate reaction?
Rym: a rabble rabble rabble?
Rym: Let's kill it.
Scott: I'm just saying is that you know, there there is a luddist tone.
Scott: That is I'm not a fan of.
Rym: ah But at the same time they weren't anti technology.
Rym: In fact, they were pro technology and those among them who tried to advance technology got killed.
Rym: Mmm, I mean they were like, why don't we just make more silo guys?
Scott: Well, I mean that heard that's something else that bothered me right?
Scott: is, you know You had the one guy who like never left his room.
Scott: He seemed to be the only one capable of inventing anything.
Scott: You're telling me this silos been around for I guess century at least they.
Rym: they said that up pretty clearly.
Rym: Anyone who tried to invent anything was murdered.
Scott: It's like no one had any inventive abilities.
Rym: remember the Juliet's former lover was murdered because he was inventive.
Scott: What what did he invent?
Rym: He tried he tried.
Rym: he figured out a plan to drill sideways.
Rym: They were like nope death.
Rym: and then he figured out a plan to drill down and then there's no death.
Scott: Hmm any.
Rym: it's implied that anyone who innovates at all is murdered because anyone who fucked around with radio equipment Would have heard those other silos immediately.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: I mean the radios themselves.
Rym: if you spend any time analyzing the radio.
Rym: Look how quickly he figured it out.
Rym: You didn't even need to see the dial with 18 written on it, but to even know a radio is possible, right?
Rym: Well, he knew radio was possible I guess because radio is.
Rym: everyone knew the sheriff's had radios and it was part of the pack.
Rym: death penalty If you have a radio you're not supposed to have.
Rym: But how come Bernard was stupid and he just has this long argument with Juliet over the radio as soon as she talked.
Rym: He should just shut the fuck up or held down transmit so no one could hear what she was saying like seriously, dude Or how come the other silos didn't be like what the fuck?
Scott: and then to jump down on this How are they supposed to jump down on it from far away in a silo?
Rym: IT any one of them could have just held down.
Rym: transmit Sure, that's how that works.
Rym: Remember at the Kinetic Con where we lost a radio channel Sure, and remember how hard it was to get around that.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Yeah So, I mean it was a super fun book Well written mostly except for that one long overdone scene.
Rym: the plot was pretty good Reasonably complex.
Rym: I liked it.
Rym: I'm really sad that I'm told the rest of the books are really bad.
Rym: Mmm
Scott: I mean, you know I realize you know Like I said at the beginning this story of the people trapped under in a sealed society in the post-apocalypse Right where they can't leave is a story that feels like it's been told often but hasn't actually been told that often.
Scott: it's a story I like and After reading this I'm like, you know what this story hasn't really been exposed to the mainstream people.
Scott: So I kind of like it to be like a wool movie.
Scott: You'd probably go over Well, and I would like to see the story told again.
Scott: Why the fuck not Fallout 4?
Scott: bring it on Anything else?
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, I I'll say this had I not been told by a bunch of people that the rest of the books are shit I would have immediately started reading the next book.
Scott: Yeah, I feel like you know, it wasn't like the book was ridiculously deep or anything.
Scott: It's just it's just a page turner.
Scott: Just like really straightforward Like you just really got to read that next page, which is part of why it didn't take that long to read it.
Rym: Yeah So it's a good book.
Rym: I guess Scott is pick another book.
Scott: I'll pick one real soon.
Rym: Yeah, you gonna fix something good.
Scott: I'll pick something real good.
Rym: Real good?
Rym: All right No shows next week cuz I'm flying to Paris and then immediately from there to PAX.
Rym: so See you guys at PAX East!
Rym: Yes, it's also really fucking hard to fly to Boston.
Rym: Yeah, not super respectful for Boston anymore.
Scott: Fuck you Boston.
Rym: I would not.
Rym: I would not move to Boston after what they've done to these conventions because I don't trust the city.
Rym: But that's neither here nor there.
Rym: It's almost Boston's IT departments.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.