Rym: It's Tuesday, May 27th, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, Hanza to Tonica, a board game by Andreas Stedding.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Oh yeah, back from a weekend of pretty solid board gaming.
Scott: And biking.
Rym: Yep, and biking, but also board gaming.
Scott: And eating.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But we were at an awesome party, and suffice it to say, the pleasure of playing board games with intelligent people who take their turn quickly and try to win, cannot be understated.
Rym: And more importantly, Scott, you didn't win any of those, did you?
Rym: Did I win any?
Rym: I don't think you won.
Rym: Ro won by one point, and then I won by one point.
Scott: On Hanza to Tonica?
Rym: Yeah, Hanza to Tonica mostly.
Scott: No, I didn't win that, no.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't play a lot of other games.
Rym: We really focused on the Hanza to Tonica.
Scott: I won the game that was basically Dominion Scrabble.
Rym: Oh yeah, I remember that, I remember that, because in the next game, everyone who was in that game said that they will never play that game with you again, Mr.
Rym: Won't Take His Turn.
Scott: The same reason you won't play Street Fighter again with someone who kicks your ass.
Rym: The same reason you won't play Acquire with Scott Johnson.
Scott: I'd like to point out that in that game, right, which is Scrabble with Dominion, I was sitting there taking a long time on my turn in order to make big plays.
Rym: That is in fact the exact argument that Scott Johnson makes in a game of Acquire.
Scott: You know what the other players were doing to play their turns so quickly?
Rym: Not thinking.
Scott: They were using their phones to basically look up fucking words and directly cheating.
Scott: That's like just, you're playing Scrabble and just pulling out the dictionary right in full view of everyone.
Scott: Not to check or challenge a word someone tried to play, but to actually help you play a word.
Rym: Oh, that gave me the greatest trash talk.
Scott: I was not doing that.
Scott: I was thinking, and I beat them by tens of points.
Rym: So, in that Viking show that I'm watching, there's the scene where two Vikings have a duel.
Rym: So they come out with sword and shield, and the first guy looks at the guy, takes his shield, and just like fucking just throws it down.
Rym: So what's the other guy gonna do?
Rym: He either has to throw the shield down like the first guy or look like a coward.
Rym: So, when you're playing Scrabble with someone.
Scott: I would just put my sword down and take out like a fucking Morningstar or one of those, a flail with a big spiky ball on it and be like, "I bet you want to pick up your shield now,
Scott: dumbass.".
Rym: So, next time you're playing Scrabble with someone, if you're pretty sure you can beat them, sit down and hand them a dictionary and say, "By all
Rym: means.".
Scott: I use it as a general rule in any game whenever there's a fuck up or an asterisk, but we're not gonna reset or quit.
Scott: I just tell the, I either just let it go in the opponent's favor or I'll say, "You decide whatever you want to have and
Scott: happens.".
Rym: I usually, I do that too.
Rym: Sometimes there's a really minor fuck up, like on my turns, like did I take my extra point or not?
Rym: When in doubt, do the thing that hurts me the most.
Scott: Like I was at the last Netrunner tournament I was at, the video, this is online.
Scott: I basically won, but on the turn I won, I didn't do things slow enough and there was technically a chance for the opponent to not lose if he anticipated what I was doing or something, right?
Scott: So, I was just like, "You know what?
Scott: All right, fuck it.
Scott: You just write win or lose on that score sheet.
Scott: It's up to you.
Scott: I don't
Scott: care.".
Rym: What do you write?
Scott: Win.
Rym: For you?
Rym: For him.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: If I say that, I can't say, "Write whatever you want on the sheet," and then if they write that they win, then complain.
Rym: Well, that just means that when you were telling him to write that, you did not prep him enough to coerce him into effectively writing what you wanted.
Scott: I wasn't trying to coerce him.
Scott: I was just like, "I just want to play the second game and go home quickly.
Scott: Let's end this game now.
Scott: This game is
Scott: slow.".
Rym: So, I noticed something weird about Tom's and Teutonica in the board game geek thing that I'm going to figure out, but we'll get to that in the main bit.
Rym: So, we're back trying to do GeekNights regularly until I fly off to Istanbul.
Rym: So, in the news, you might know that we stopped playing Dungeons and Dragons quite some time ago at this point.
Rym: Yeah, a long time ago.
Rym: Back when we discovered the burning wheel and then unearthed the veritable treasure trove of indie RPGs, bespoke RPGs, RPGs that actually do what we wanted.
Scott: Tabletop RPGs of non-mainstreamness.
Scott: And I'm still the RPG hipster would play.
Rym: What's interesting is still, at this point in my life, I played D&D for more years than I played any of those indie RPGs.
Scott: Well, those didn't exist or we didn't know about them.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: So, D&D still has a really good place in my heart.
Rym: To this day, I remember a lot of bullshit about Dungeons and Dragons.
Scott: Listen, if you want to walk around a dungeon and kill shit, D&D is not a bad game and sometimes I want to play that game.
Rym: Yeah, but not even that.
Rym: I played a lot of second ed D&D, Advanced Dungeons and Dragons, which has its own interesting things going on.
Rym: But, as you know, Wizards of the Coast has, over time, continued to make D&D, in my opinion at least, worse.
Scott: Well, they just completely stopped for the dish.
Scott: It's like if they're not selling it currently or putting out products currently, they don't give a shit.
Rym: Well, remember, it was TSR who made poor financial decisions that eventually faced full life consequences.
Rym: WotC bought them and I remember then, when Wizards of the Coast bought TSR, that all the D&D people were saying, "This is the end.
Rym: WotC's going to turn it into
Rym: Magic.".
Rym: And they didn't.
Rym: They turned it into World of Warcraft.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway.
Scott: But, yeah, it's like if they're not currently selling product for D&D, then they don't promote it and there's like nothing happening with it, right?
Scott: Unlike Magic, which is always happening.
Scott: So, it's like, because Magic doesn't really have, you know, versions where it's like they're not compatible.
Scott: It's just they keep putting out new cards all the time.
Rym: Well, there are versions that aren't compatible.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Of Magic?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: You can't use your old cards in most tournaments.
Scott: No, but I mean, it's not like a different rule book.
Rym: It kinda is.
Rym: A lot of the old rules have been superseded.
Rym: The point is, there's just always new Magic cards.
Scott: There isn't always new D&D, right?
Rym: Well, because TSR experimented with that when they released those brown books.
Scott: In Magic, you're not selling the rule book.
Scott: That part is, right?
Rym: That's the difference.
Rym: But the thing is, what else are you going to sell?
Rym: A lot of people who grew up playing D&D would make...
Scott: They tried to sell miniatures and dice and adventures and character expansion books and all sorts of things.
Scott: But anyway, so, in Third Ed, they had this open D20 system thing.
Rym: Which, in my opinion, actually set role-playing games back.
Rym: But that's only in retrospect.
Rym: do I have that opinion, because at the time, I thought it was revolutionary.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Basically, what it was, is they released a core set of rules, like the D20 system, and said, "Go nuts with this, guys.
Rym: You can't use a lot of our specific IP, like if we release a Forgotten Realms
Rym: thing.".
Scott: You can't do any Beholder shit.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Or Mind Flayer shit.
Rym: So, and then there was a Star Wars D20, there was an L5R D20, there were all these games.
Rym: The problem was, all those games had the same rules.
Rym: Which seems great, but is actually terrible, because those games all felt the same.
Rym: You just swap the proper nouns.
Rym: Once you realize that the Star Wars D20 looked, played, and felt identical to L5R D20, you basically didn't want to play any of them anymore.
Scott: It had extra rules for lightsabers and the Force, and also, uh, spaceships.
Rym: So, psionics and, uh, magic swords.
Scott: Spaceships.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, spelljammers.
Rym: But it's interesting, because back then I remember thinking, "Wow, look how forward thinking and progressive they
Rym: are.".
Rym: But now, just in retrospect, knowing more about games and game design in the industry, I see this as the opposite.
Rym: But now, 4th edition, really, like Scott said, kind of just disappeared.
Rym: I mean, in Australia, at PAX OS, they didn't even bring it.
Scott: Yeah, and at PAX East, the only D&D that there was, that was, you know, there, was unofficial, 20-sided store, running 5th edition, like a few times a day, at their own booth, using like the preview rules that came out a long time ago.
Rym: Now, well, let's see, well, TSR did experiment, Scott, with constantly selling D&D.
Rym: Remember those Brown books?
Rym: The Complete Guide to X?
Rym: The Psionics Handbook?
Scott: That's 2nd edition.
Rym: The Elephant Head, yeah.
Rym: Dungeons and Dragons.
Scott: But how can you make new classes and new races all the time?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Well, they, they also, you could have the model of...
Scott: You could treat it like World of Warcraft even more, whereas you keep adding new content at higher levels, but people don't actually have campaigns that keep going like that.
Rym: Uh, I did.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm saying how many people do.
Scott: It's like, okay, here's all this content for levels 1-5, and then suddenly everyone in the world gets to level 5, and then you're like, okay, we're printing a whole bunch of new books now for levels 5-10, everyone.
Scott: It's like, it doesn't work like that.
Scott: It's not like...
Rym: I think that's what's gonna happen to Torchbearer.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: The news here now is that...
Scott: Torchbearer, you can't make it to level 5, dude.
Rym: Torchbearer, you can't make it back to town.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So Dungeons and Dragons, which we've talked about at length on the show over the years, and it'd be interesting to see if someone took all the times we've talked about D&D and roleplaying games and strung them together into one episode just to see how our opinions have changed, but they're trying this again, and they're releasing the Dungeons and Dragons like starter set, this basic PDF that supposedly covers levels 1-20, Cleric Fighter, Rogue, Wizard classes, and the essential subclasses for each.
Rym: It also provides the Dwarf, Elf, and Halfling as racial options alongside humans.
Scott: So it's first at D&D.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I think that it's interesting.
Rym: D&D has almost been regressing back to an earlier state in some ways.
Rym: They've, over time, what little roleplaying that was added to D&D seems to have been removed over time.
Scott: You mean the one sentence that says, "Please roleplay while playing this game"?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But simultaneously...
Scott: And make up your own rules, please.
Rym: They've been tightening up the rules around combat to the point that you can't just sort of fudge it and kind of make the combat roleplaying interesting like you could.
Rym: an old D&D.
Rym: Not old as D&D, but second and third ed.
Rym: So I don't really know who D&D is aimed at anymore.
Scott: It's aimed at people who just want to go into a dungeon and kill monsters and get loot and level up and play World of Warcraft at a table with friends to get those extra social aspects into it.
Rym: Ah, so I think there's something more subtle here.
Scott: Those people, in their mind, think they want roleplaying, but they don't actually, and they're getting what they want, but they're being lied to and told they're being given something else.
Rym: But at the same time, how many times do we talk about the gamer mystique of the people who say they're enjoying those D&D games, but quietly are just looking at their phone most of the time?
Scott: There are people like that, too.
Scott: But I read a story about a study recently.
Scott: I actually read the study, and it talked about how there's different parts of the brain for wanting things and actually liking them.
Scott: And we can see this all the time with people we know.
Scott: Emily talks about how whenever she plays a board game, it's super fun, but whenever she thinks about playing a board game, she doesn't want to.
Rym: Yep, which is a common complaint of many people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But as soon as she actually is playing it, she's like, "We need board
Scott: games!"
Scott: Right?
Scott: So I think that with D&D, I think there's a lot.
Scott: The people who play D&D a lot are people who, in their minds, want roleplaying and think they want roleplaying, but they don't actually like roleplaying.
Scott: What they like is go run a dungeon, kill things, and look up.
Scott: But they don't know that they want that, and D&D basically sells them, telling them that D&D is what they want, so they buy it.
Scott: And then once they play it, it's not what it was sold as, but it is what the person actually wants to do, truly.
Rym: I think it's more subtle than that.
Rym: Because on one hand, how is D&D really sold to people?
Rym: How do people decide they want to play D&D?
Scott: Based on their name?
Rym: From nerdy, well, from history.
Rym: From hearing about, like, "Oh, that's the roleplaying
Rym: game."
Rym: They're lucky if they even know there are other roleplaying games.
Rym: From their uncles and whatever.
Rym: And from the nerd media around it.
Rym: What's one of the biggest examples of that?
Rym: Wil Wheaton's stuff and Penny Arcade's Acquisitions Incorporated.
Rym: What do those focus on?
Rym: People who are funny, playing the game in a funny and engaging manner, and most of what makes those games enjoyable is everything but the actual rules of D&D.
Rym: It's the fact that Gabe and Tycho are just fucking hilarious people.
Rym: And also, they get that idea that that's what D&D is like, and then when they play and it doesn't work out that way, what's the advice they get from other people in the community?
Rym: "Oh, you need a better game master.
Rym: You need to roleplay
Rym: better."
Rym: They put the onus of failure on the person, so they try to improve themselves, not realizing that the game will basically never do that for them.
Rym: It's a very complex thing.
Rym: But I think you're right, a lot of people like the idea of D&D, but don't really know what they actually want from D&D.
Rym: But this is subtly different from the D20 system, in that the D20 system was sold as a system that you could use to make your own commercial products.
Rym: This is not that.
Rym: It's just a free PDF, so you don't have to buy the rulebook.
Scott: Before they had free speech, now they've gotten rid of free speech and replaced it with free beer.
Scott: See how that works.
Rym: Now, they're not gonna include any content, which is fine, because I hate all their content now.
Rym: And two, if they're not gonna include content, whatever.
Scott: You don't like that giant spider lady?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I already own all the books that tell me all the proper nouns.
Scott: You don't like Two-Sword Guy?
Rym: Oh, Artemis and Terrari?
Rym: Fuck that guy.
Scott: You don't like, um...
Rym: Well, Drizzt?
Rym: Are you thinking of Drizzt or Artemis?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The one you hate?
Scott: I don't like either one of them.
Scott: Incredibly powerful old wizard guy?
Rym: Well, there's two.
Rym: There's Kelvin Blackstaff and Al Minster.
Scott: Yeah, both of them.
Scott: Those guys.
Rym: But I already have the books that tell me all that stuff.
Rym: The only thing those books are missing is the stats that when I was young, we made up anyway.
Rym: So, with this system, what's interesting is that they say, and I quote, "It is equivalent to the old Dungeons and Dragons rules
Rym: cyclopedia.".
Scott: That's a very large book to be given away for free.
Rym: Yeah, that book is huge.
Rym: And also, you literally will never need any other materials to play D&D.
Rym: So I'm not sure what they think they're going to be selling.
Scott: Yeah, that's not giving a little free sample of starter book.
Scott: That's like the book.
Rym: This almost feels like a graceful exit from Dungeons and Dragons as a company.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: This is a way to keep the brand around so they can have the brand exist in case Hasbro wants to make some monies on it.
Rym: Kind of like how, this is very obvious if you're not paying attention, the rights to Gem, the old cartoon, were in flux until relatively recently.
Rym: But Hasbro effectively has them as far as I can tell.
Rym: They have not re-released Gem.
Rym: They've taken My Little Pony and they've taken a lot of the aspects of what Gem is and made a spin off My Little Pony show.
Rym: that's basically Gem.
Rym: Because they call it brand confluence, where you can have one brand name and brand iconography and have many properties under it to simplify your marketing budget and to simplify your, just basically everything in your company outward facing in social media.
Rym: It makes the brand more powerful as a whole.
Rym: You can target different demographics.
Rym: I think this is the same thing.
Rym: This is Hasbro saying, "You guys fucked up.
Rym: We can't get rid of the brand because the brand's too powerful.
Rym: This is the cheapest way to keep the brand as big as possible in a holding pattern until we come up with a new way to monetize
Rym: it.".
Rym: That's just my guess.
Rym: I have no insider knowledge.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that very well could be.
Scott: They might just be like, "All right, this D&D never made
Scott: money.".
Scott: I was thinking that they were basically, I was under the assumption that Fifth Edition is basically their last try.
Scott: Like, "All right, if this doesn't work, we're not doing D&D anymore because this shit ain't profitable and Hasbro's going to cut it
Scott: off.".
Rym: The brand is too well known to let die or let someone else have it.
Rym: Imagine if Luke Crane got a hold of the D&D license.
Scott: Right, but now what you say makes me think that maybe what they're doing is just to keep the brand alive, making a product that's just like, "Okay, this is D&D.
Scott: It's this set of books," and not doing this whole universe of products and making a whole bunch of garbage.
Scott: Just be like, "Okay, this is D&D.
Scott: It's on the shelf.
Scott: We'll leave it there forever just to hold its
Scott: spot.".
Scott: Players Handbook, Masters Guide, Monster Manual.
Rym: But they're giving away for free, so I think it's also kind of trying to inoculate the market against competitors.
Rym: because D&D is still, literally, unless you listen to this show, you probably have no idea that other role-playing systems even exist.
Scott: Pathfinder's pretty big.
Rym: It is, but even then, it is popular among the nerds among nerds.
Rym: Go to someone on the street and say, "Hey, do you know about role-playing
Rym: games?".
Rym: If they say anything other than,
Rym: "What?"
Rym: or, "Get away from me," they'll say, "Oh,
Rym: D&D.".
Scott: Or Final Fantasy.
Rym: Yep, Final Fantasy.
Rym: JRPGs.
Rym: Transistor.
Scott: All right, so another news.
Scott: That news took way too long, so...
Rym: I warned you it would.
Scott: Anyway, Nintendo, right?
Scott: They're bombing lately, so they need to get some monies.
Scott: For a long time...
Rym: Wouldn't you say bob-bombing?
Scott: Sure.
Scott: For a long time, they've been being really annoying on YouTube.
Scott: If you upload a YouTube Nintendo video, Nintendo yoinks that and gets your ad revenues, right?
Scott: I guess they share the ad revenue with YouTube, but they're trying to scrape up any money they can, and this is why people love Twitch and why they're kind of slightly worried.
Scott: One of the reasons they're worried that YouTube bought Twitch is because on Twitch, you can just put up a video of a Nintendo game, no problem, but on YouTube, Nintendo's going to claim ownership of that video if you plan Mario 1, put ads on it, and take money from it, which is annoying.
Rym: Annoying and, I think, unethical.
Scott: Sure, but Nintendo needs every penny it can get, because they're fucked.
Rym: I firmly believe that me playing a game is a unique performance of that game.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But anyway, Nintendo, today, there were like two tweets on the official Japanese Twitter account, so all the details aren't out yet, basically, because it's only so many characters' worth, but they're going to have a new affiliate.
Rym: I clicked on the tweets like, "Oh, I'll read them.
Rym: Yeah, it's in
Rym: Japanese.".
Scott: It's in moon language, right, yeah.
Scott: But you can say a lot more in fucking moon language than you can say.
Rym: I can't.
Rym: There's so much kanji.
Rym: I can't read this at all.
Scott: Yeah, but you can say a lot in a few tweets, right?
Scott: Anyway, in Japanese, they're going to have a new affiliate.
Scott: They're going to keep that affiliate program alive, where they just take your money.
Rym: All right, so they're keeping the bad thing going.
Scott: But they're also going to start an alternative thing where you basically partner with them in an affiliate program, and then I don't know if you had to put ads actually in your video directly or what.
Rym: They'll do the YouTube ones, I guarantee.
Scott: Or something, but basically, if you join the program and Nintendo approves your videos, then you put them up, and not only does Nintendo get money and YouTube gets money, but you also get money.
Scott: So if you go through them first, and of course, if they don't like your video, it's not going to get put up on YouTube.
Rym: This is anathema to freedom of expression.
Rym: It's one of those dying grasps of a company that's failing.
Scott: It's like, if you want to put a video up on YouTube about our stuff, then you have to make sure that we get some of the money, and maybe if you're really nice to us, we'll give you a little bit of the money also.
Rym: All right, so what's the difference, Nintendo, between a parody, a review, a let's play?
Scott: Right, and then on top of that, Mario Kart 8 is going to have YouTube integration, so I don't know if that's going to connect you to this thing by default.
Rym: Knowing Nintendo, what that's going to do is if you share a friend code with someone, you can make a video of yourself playing, and then they'll see it, but it removes any audio and replaces it with music.
Scott: Who knows what's going to happen.
Rym: Oh, and if you don't have someone's friend code, you can't see their videos.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: This is cute, and I had a much more depressing thing.
Rym: I decided not to jump down all you guys' throats yet with.
Rym: This is just a cool animation about an encounter with a dancing witch in Minecraft.
Rym: It's pretty funny.
Rym: It's got good dubstep.
Rym: I enjoyed it.
Scott: It's cute, but whatevs.
Scott: Typical internet whatevs.
Rym: What do you think things of the day are for?
Rym: It's the best thing I saw in the last day.
Scott: That's not much.
Scott: So check out this dude.
Scott: He's going biking on a trail in a national park.
Scott: I don't even know what fucking country it is.
Scott: It doesn't matter, right?
Scott: They speak English there, whatever country, or he speaks English.
Scott: He's biking through the park along a trail.
Scott: looks like a nice trail, not very hilly, you know, nice.
Scott: It's dirt, but it's pretty hard packed, easy to ride on, right?
Scott: And as he's going through the park, he comes across some cars and then some people.
Scott: And then, oh my God, it's just the surprise random rave in the woods that probably doesn't belong there.
Scott: And he says some funny stuff and he sees some funny stuff with, I assume, what is a GoPro camera.
Scott: So, uh, I, you know, I really identified with this cause a lot of times.
Scott: we're biking through New York and you know, it's not sudden unofficial rave, but it's just like, oh, look at this thing that I did not expect to be here on this day.
Scott: Here it is.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I mean that Kickstarter block party, I kind of forgot it was happening and we biked past it.
Rym: We're like, what the fuck is going on over there?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: That happens all the goddamn time.
Scott: So it was, it's funny to see it happen in the middle of the woods as opposed to the most important city on earth.
Rym: So in the meta moment, the book club book is a canticle for Lebowitz.
Scott: I started reading it.
Rym: I will start reading it probably on my flight to Istanbul.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Uh, we had a bunch of YouTube videos.
Rym: Kinetic Con is coming up in July.
Rym: You should totally go.
Rym: A good chunk of the schedule for panels and workshops and guests and things is already up on the website.
Rym: And I am told we'll have guide book.
Rym: I don't know if I'm supposed to announce that, but whatever.
Rym: If we don't have it, I want you to complain to Con asking why we don't have it.
Rym: Pretty sure we got it now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I don't want like to use GeekNights as like a mouthpiece for this guide book to actually rate panels and our panels.
Rym: We are going to be doing ourselves one complaint we've gotten over the years that we don't do enough of our own stuff at the con.
Rym: Who's complaining about that.
Rym: People have asked me listeners, they're like, Hey, what's a kinetic con?
Scott: And you guys, so we'll do five more panels that have three people attending them.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the problem is I usually, because, you know, we do more stuff, attend more because we schedule the whole con.
Rym: We're also busy doing con stuff.
Rym: So for example, it's, it's kind of unethical for me to schedule it myself in the large room at prime time, especially when I have like 10 other big things I could put there.
Rym: Secondly, I know that I'll show up wherever I schedule it and I have time slots that are bad.
Rym: So I tend to put our stuff early in the day and I know it's hard to get other similarly good people to go and I know we'll actually show up and do it.
Rym: So there's at least something good in those slots, but we are going to do, we're going to do our bad games and we're going to do our wine.
Rym: No one will game with you.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Maybe a third one.
Rym: We'll see how to win every game.
Scott: Maybe because we need more.
Scott: What does the con need?
Scott: Does it need more gaming content?
Rym: It needs more anime content.
Scott: Let's do an anime.
Rym: What do you want to do?
Rym: Which, which of our stale ass anime panels do you want to recycle?
Scott: Well, for anime Boston, we did the spring chart.
Rym: Maybe we can do the summer chart because that's, that's so much work to put together.
Rym: You want to put it together?
Rym: You want to do what I did for the last two?
Rym: Go nuts.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: But yeah, anyway, kinetic con is super awesome and you should attend it because it's pretty awesome.
Rym: But if you submitted a panel and I've gotten no emails from the website yet, I suggest you log into your account.
Rym: You might see your panel either accepted or rejected.
Rym: There was an issue preventing emails from being automatically sent out a while ago.
Rym: that has since been resolved.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Any other metas?
Rym: Not really.
Scott: Go on the internet and find us and follow us.
Scott: I mean, how could you, if you're listening to this podcast, you've already found us and followed us, right?
Scott: So tell your friends to listen to GeekNights.
Rym: And also join the forum.
Rym: I see a lot of you lurking, but fewer people are posting recently.
Rym: Maybe because it's one now.
Scott: Are you not an important person?
Scott: You don't have anything to say.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, you're not going to join one of these arguments.
Scott: Illiterate?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: So Hans and Teutonica, we pointedly waited to do this review because for a while, well, Rym waited.
Scott: I was fine doing it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But we've lately just due to constraints of time and due to feeling very self-assured in our ability to assess games quickly have been reviewing games, especially tabletop games based on one playthrough.
Scott: Sometimes that's enough.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And you know what?
Scott: Koo, C-O-U-P, one play was enough.
Rym: In the case of Hans and Teutonica, one play through was also enough, but I had to be sure.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I wanted to give a real deep review of this game.
Scott: I haven't played it enough to go really deep.
Rym: We can go deep enough.
Scott: Like four or five times.
Rym: We have not solved it.
Rym: However, I can say this.
Rym: Hans and Teutonica came out in 2009.
Rym: Andrea Stedding is a stand-up tabletop game that is quick to play, quick to teach, and has survived repeated plays with experienced and skilled gamers.
Rym: That is more than I can say for most tabletop games that have ever existed.
Rym: That's more than I can say for most tabletop games that I own.
Scott: I think the fundamental thing with Hans and Teutonica, right, is you look at a lot of board games out there that have multiple victory conditions or multiple ways, paths to generating victory points.
Rym: Like Kalis, you can go in the castle, you can try to do the gold thing, you can try to do the buildings thing.
Scott: And in most of those games, in most of those games, one way is just better than the other way.
Rym: In Kalis, you should just go for the castle.
Rym: Fuck everything else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Unless you get some magic jeweler thing happen.
Rym: And even then, he lost by a point.
Rym: Like, it still didn't work.
Rym: It was just close.
Scott: But in the five, six times I played Hans and Teutonica, right, all ways are not necessarily viable in a single instance of the game.
Scott: But, across playing the game multiple times, based on what people do, different ones will become the way you should have gone.
Scott: Like, if the game is going long, then the key becomes the way to go.
Rym: The key and the network and building houses.
Rym: But, that means you need your Pribilica Pop.
Scott: If the game is really short, right, then like one colon might be enough to win.
Rym: You and Cold Guy learned that when me and Ro just fucking blitzed the end of the game and left everybody behind.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like, you get like these piddly points, like during the course of the game, just from building offices.
Scott: And it's like, those points usually don't matter if people get a whole bunch of end of game points.
Scott: But, if you can get enough of those points quickly enough, the game will just fucking end.
Scott: And then, those end of game points will be so insignificant compared to the during game points.
Scott: So, it's like, not only do you have to choose a path of victory, but you have to see how the game is going.
Scott: And, if there's a lot of players, you don't have a lot of control over how the game is going.
Scott: And, you have to play for the path that is going to be the winning path in that game.
Scott: And, not end Hans Deutonica overall.
Rym: That is what makes this game so fascinating to me and why I have such a high opinion of it.
Rym: Because, let's look at two similar, like two different directions of game.
Rym: Agricola has the same, there are multiple paths to victory.
Scott: But, you just get the baby.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, get the baby, yeah.
Rym: But, there's other, like, do you go for house upgrade points?
Rym: Or, do you go for animal points?
Scott: Well, your cards usually tell you what to do.
Scott: And, the resources available usually tell you what to do.
Scott: And, you sort of have to do a little bit of everything to get a good score in that game anyway.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So, you have two things affecting the game in a sense.
Rym: On one hand, your strategy is driven, what?
Rym: By your preference and your cards.
Rym: Not so much by what anyone else is doing.
Rym: So, if I see Scott's going for a house upgrade, that almost doesn't affect my strategy at all.
Scott: Unless you were going for house upgrade and now I'm taking it from you.
Rym: Even then, usually you're not taking it from me.
Rym: Because, the game's set up for two people doing the same thing isn't too big.
Scott: There's enough for two people to do the same thing.
Scott: There's not enough for three people.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: The only game interaction though, it comes down to blocking Scott's move at a critical point.
Rym: Oh, you wanted to build the baby.
Rym: Well, guess what?
Rym: I'm on the baby.
Rym: You can't build the baby this turn.
Rym: That kind of blocking other players is all that matters.
Rym: And two, the game has extremely diminishing returns in every victory point direction, forcing you to do all of them at least a little.
Rym: Now, going the other direction, a game like El Grande has the direct player fucking, the direct player interaction.
Rym: Everything I do directly relates to what you do and before and after what I do.
Rym: I move some pieces there, you have to react to that.
Rym: The game is so reactive.
Rym: Your strategy has to be so high level in meta.
Rym: But as a result, the game is almost purely political.
Rym: Hansa Teutonica has the direct interaction.
Rym: The game is extremely reactionary.
Rym: Your strategy mostly has to revolve around reacting to other players on a tactical level and maybe changing strategies mid-game.
Rym: But at the same time, you still have this solitaire sort of build-up optimization.
Rym: It takes the best aspects of a game like Agricola and the best aspects of a game like El Grande, mashes them together into something that's actually really quick to play.
Scott: Right, so the way the game works generally is that you have cubes and discs.
Scott: Fuck with their actual name.
Rym: Oh, yeah, actually we got it.
Rym: So, problem with this game.
Scott: The rulebook is garbage.
Rym: We complain about rulebooks and tabletop games being poorly written for the last decade.
Scott: It's not as bad as Attica.
Rym: No.
Scott: Not Attica.
Scott: Hellas.
Scott: It's not as bad as Hellas.
Rym: Attica's fine.
Rym: Attica's got fine rules.
Scott: Hellas is the best.
Rym: Read the rules in old games like Puerto Rico or Tigger's New Freighties or Bonanza and then read the rules of Hansa Teutonica and I defy you not to try to shoot yourself in the face.
Scott: Right, so there's one piece.
Scott: The disc is called a merchant and the cube is called a trader.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: How the fuck are you going to keep that straight?
Rym: Well, do you draw them from your stockpile of merchant traders or your supply?
Scott: My supply or my stockpile?
Scott: No.
Scott: Fuck that.
Scott: We called it the disc and the cube.
Scott: And we called it the graveyard and the whatever.
Rym: The graveyard and the supply.
Rym: No, the graveyard and the bag.
Scott: The bag.
Rym: And the general term.
Scott: The bag is an action.
Rym: Discs and cubes collectively are dudes.
Rym: So, for example, you must play a disc on this place, but you may return a dude from your supply.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Meaning either a disc or a cube.
Rym: Seriously, don't like the rulebook.
Rym: Just cross out.
Scott: There are problems with the rulebook besides the fact that it names things weirdly.
Scott: That we had this game taught to us by multiple people multiple times and they all got shit wrong until Rym read the rules extremely carefully and referred to BoardGameGeek multiple times.
Rym: And while I was reading them was repeatedly swearing out loud.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: We might even still be playing it wrong, but I doubt it.
Rym: Yeah, I think we're pretty good now.
Scott: So, anyway, the way the game works is that you have dudes, cubes and discs, right?
Scott: And you put them on the board on these roads.
Scott: And each road has a number of spaces.
Scott: Once you've filled it, it takes, you know, actions to get guys out there and fill up a road.
Scott: But eventually you fill up a road.
Scott: Then you can use an action to score the road.
Scott: When you score the road, you can usually just put one of your dudes at the end of the road.
Rym: Either end if there's two ends.
Scott: Every road has two ends.
Scott: Except for the ending roads.
Rym: Those have two ends.
Scott: Yeah, every road has two ends.
Rym: They have two.
Scott: Yeah, I guess so.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: And then you put your guy, one of your guys who was on the road, into the space on the end of the road.
Scott: Now, if any road that is touching that guy, right?
Scott: You're gonna get points, pretty much, when people score it in that general area.
Scott: But, there are a few roads that are magic roads.
Scott: And if you score on those, you can score normally.
Scott: Or, you can upgrade your shit to be more efficient.
Rym: So you have a little eclipse-style thing in front of you, meaning you've got a board where you put a bunch of cubes and discs on it, and to upgrade, when you do that action, you take a cube or disc off of the appropriate spot, put it into your bag, AKA your supply, and then your power is upgraded.
Rym: So you lift a cube off the Acciones, and now Daddy 3 Acciones.
Scott: So, the things you can upgrade is you can upgrade your Acciones.
Rym: We're gonna use our terms, not the game's terms.
Scott: Right, well, Acciones, I think, is also the game's term.
Rym: It's just actions.
Scott: Yeah, it's just more actions.
Scott: So, obviously, that's a basic thing to go for.
Scott: It's not a bad thing to go for at all.
Rym: Yup, for example, take two actions.
Scott: It's generally just good to get more actions.
Rym: It's just on your turn.
Rym: How many actions?
Rym: I get five actions.
Scott: It's like having a baby in a gricola.
Scott: It's pretty strong.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: The bag.
Scott: So the bag is, one of the actions you can take is to get guys from the graveyard into the supply.
Scott: Or the bag.
Scott: Yeah, you can only use guys who are not in the graveyard.
Scott: So being able to get more guys out of the graveyard with a single action basically saves you actions.
Scott: So upgrading that is very similar to upgrading your Acciones in that it increases your efficiency of getting shit done.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: There's the Lieber Sophia, or as we call them, Liebers.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Or just disks.
Scott: So the Liebers is really powerful.
Scott: The Lieber is.
Scott: one of the actions you can use is to helicopter guys around the board.
Scott: So it's sometimes you might be able to get guys onto the board for free, but they'll be in a bad place.
Scott: So you can use the Lieber helicopter to move guys.
Scott: The more you upgrade the Lieber, the more guys you can move with a single action.
Scott: That's really frickin' strong.
Rym: And also upgrading it, remember the mechanic I said is Eclipse style.
Rym: You take the cube, or in this case the disk, off of that area and bring it into your bag.
Rym: So now you have more disks.
Scott: Right, so you start the game with one disk and there's four disks sitting on the board.
Scott: To get those four extra disks, well three extra disks, you need to upgrade the Lieber, which is upgrading the helicopter power.
Rym: There's the Pribiligum, as we like to call it.
Scott: Right, so there are certain places on the board where you can't put a guy because they're upgraded colors.
Scott: And you need to upgrade your privilege to go into those spaces.
Rym: Yeah, mini, maxi, and maximum.
Scott: So there's a lot of spaces where no one can go and there won't be any competition for those spaces because people don't have Pribiligum.
Scott: So if you get Pribiligum, you can just go there uncontested and it's pretty frickin' strong.
Scott: And the final upgrade is the key.
Scott: The key doesn't do anything to make you more efficient.
Rym: It's a score multiplier at the end of the game.
Scott: It multiplies one of the scoring aspects of the game.
Scott: So it's the network aspect.
Scott: So if you have a large network of dudes in houses on the board at the end of the game, you get a lot of points for that.
Scott: The key will multiply the number of points you get for that if you upgrade the key.
Scott: So that can be really strong scoring-wise.
Scott: But if you don't have a big network or if the game is very short, not allowing anyone to build a big network, upgrading the key is pretty futile.
Rym: Yep, it doesn't do anything for you until the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So usually the key gets rushed at the end, but it's really easy to get early.
Scott: So maybe you just go for it early.
Scott: No, never.
Scott: Never.
Scott: But then if the game doesn't go long, you just wasted that shit.
Scott: And if someone else goes for the key early, maybe try to rush the game so it ends quickly.
Scott: so their key is useless.
Scott: Because if they went key early and the game goes long, they're just gonna win.
Rym: So to give you a sense of all these multiple paths to victory, you can farm a network.
Rym: So as you put guys in these towns, they're your largest contiguous branching network.
Rym: So not a line like most games.
Rym: They can get to everything else.
Rym: The biggest branch you can possibly make.
Scott: Blob, basically.
Rym: You just multiply the number of dudes you've got out there in that branch times the key value, which goes up to four.
Rym: Which can be tremendous.
Scott: That alone will just win the game.
Rym: I've seen people get 20, 30 plus points.
Scott: More points than any other scoring mechanism combined, right?
Rym: You also get points at the end of the game for every special disc you use.
Rym: We'll talk about those.
Rym: last.
Rym: The plates.
Scott: The plates.
Rym: You also get points for every city that you control in terms of having a lot of guys in those cities.
Rym: Like, you're controlling that one city.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, "Okay, I didn't make a network, but I just got control of a lot of
Scott: spots.".
Scott: You know, so that's times two.
Scott: That's pretty strong.
Rym: And there's the colon table where you can upgrade there and put a disc into it just to get a big fuck ton of victory points at the end.
Scott: It's pretty much just, "Get
Scott: points."
Scott: And usually that's the way to get a lot of points if you have...
Rym: Well, when Ro filled up three of those things.
Scott: Yeah, you need Privligum to get those colon points except for the lowest one.
Scott: And that adds up because it's like, what?
Scott: 8, 9, 10, 11 or something like that?
Scott: Or 9, 10, 11, 12?
Rym: The top one's 11.
Scott: Right, so it's 8, 9, 10, 11.
Scott: What's 8 plus 9 plus 9 plus 11?
Rym: It's not 8, 9, there's a bigger jump.
Rym: I forget the numbers.
Rym: It's like 7, 8, 9, 11.
Rym: Whatever.
Scott: It's a big frickin' score if you can get more than one in there.
Scott: So upgrading your Privligum and then getting colons is just a pile of points.
Scott: you can ignore the rest of the game.
Rym: But you are giving up your discs to make that happen.
Scott: Yeah, you need to get Liebers also.
Scott: So if you go all Lieber, all Privligum, then you can go colon and get those points.
Rym: Seriously, you might think we're being dumb for not using the terminology in the book.
Rym: The book fucking sucks.
Rym: So the way you actually play... Oh, there's more points.
Rym: If you control the city, anyone who scores that city from any road... Yeah, you get a point.
Rym: There's some bonus points for scoring certain places and putting your dudes on them.
Scott: So scoring in a hot area early.
Scott: So if I go to the city that's touching the Axiones road, and I put a dude in it early, anyone else who tries to upgrade their Axiones is gonna end up giving me a point when they do so.
Rym: Unless I immediately jump in there with my Privligum.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: And get above you.
Scott: But then you're not getting an Axione either.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But you also get points...
Scott: And I get a point when you do that.
Rym: At the two ends of the map, there's two red flag cities.
Rym: If you connect them with dudes...
Scott: Which happens more often than you think it would.
Rym: You get a pile of points.
Rym: And all the second set of points we talked about, you get during the game.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: The rest of the points are at the end, and that's key.
Rym: Because the way the games end are... One, if ten of the cities on the board get full of dudes...
Scott: Never happened in any game I've played ever.
Rym: Two, if the... There's a better order to do this in.
Rym: The plates run out?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: If the special plates that we haven't talked about yet are all taken, and there's some nuance around that, but it's pretty straightforward if you read the rules closely.
Rym: Or three, if anyone gets to 20 points.
Scott: Now the scoring track goes all the way around the board to 100, which makes you think, "Aha!
Scott: The end of game scoring is really most of the
Scott: points.".
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: In a lot of games, it is.
Scott: But because that end of game score is so low, just 20, it's possible to rush it, preventing anyone from having a large end of game scoring.
Scott: Scores overall will be low, and those 20 points that you got really quickly might just be enough to end the game.
Rym: So there's another reason this game is so interactive.
Rym: The actions you can take, the actual things you do with your Acciones.
Rym: Now again, on your cheat sheet at Clipsboard, there are five little reminders as to what the actions do.
Rym: They are worse than bullshit.
Rym: They will confuse you.
Rym: I would recommend cutting them off of your game.
Rym: I would actually recommend blacking them out, putting stickers over them.
Rym: Anyone new who tries to look at those things just gets confused as to what they mean.
Rym: They're literally worthless.
Rym: But you can pull guys out of your bag.
Rym: You can put guys on the board.
Rym: You can move guys around with your Libra helicopter.
Rym: You can score something.
Rym: Scoring takes an action.
Rym: Or, and here's where the game gets doubly interactive, you can displace someone from a spot they're already on on the road.
Scott: So let's say there's a road to upgrade Acciones, right?
Scott: And I put two guys on it.
Scott: One, two.
Scott: Then Rym goes and he puts a guy in the third spot and that's the whole road.
Scott: Well, in order to score the road, I have to have the road have three guys on it that are all mine.
Scott: So either, A, I leave those guys there forever, pointlessly.
Scott: B, I helicopter them away to a different road.
Scott: Or C, I bump Rym off that road, taking control of it and allowing myself to score it.
Scott: But if I bump Rym off, I have to spend not only one guy to put a guy there in place of Rym's guy, but another guy has to go into the graveyard who had to fight Rym.
Rym: And then I get to take the guy he bumped and put him on an adjacent road, and I can take a guy from my graveyard and put him on the board.
Scott: So he basically gets a free action of putting a guy onto the board, and a free action of getting the guy out of the graveyard.
Scott: So it super helps someone when you bump them off.
Rym: So getting bumped is a really reactionary thing.
Rym: People are trying to get bumped sometimes, but sometimes they don't want to get bumped.
Scott: Right, well it's like if you upgrade your bag, allowing you to get guys out of your graveyard really efficiently, then you want to be a bumper, right?
Scott: Because it's so easy for you to bump people off, you have tons of extra guys.
Rym: But if you keep bumping people, you obviate their need to ever bag.
Scott: Right, if you're getting bumped a lot, you can just upgrade your lever and helicopter, right?
Scott: And then when someone bumps you, it's like, okay, I have to move my- I get extra guys on the board, but they're in a shitty location.
Scott: But that's fine, because I'll just helicopter them into place really efficiently.
Rym: So the lever discs, the merchants, I guess?
Scott: To bump them, you gotta bump two daddies.
Rym: Two guys going to the graveyard, and then the guy you bumped gets two extra guys out of his graveyard.
Scott: That's why lever is so strong.
Scott: Just upgrade lever, put discs out, and then get people to bump your discs off.
Scott: And you'll get all these free guys on the board without having to upgrade your bag.
Scott: And then because you upgraded lever already, you can helicopter them into the good position really quickly.
Rym: So with all of this, there's also special plates.
Rym: And you're gonna fuck those rules up like three or four times before you get it right.
Scott: There's always supposed to be three on the board unless the game is over.
Scott: So many games we've played with all smart people, we ended up with two on the board, one on the board, five on the board.
Scott: How the fuck did that happen?
Scott: We all fucked it up.
Rym: So at the end of every turn, our meme we always say is, "Is plate integrity
Rym: maintained?".
Rym: And then everyone has to agree that it is before we continue to the next turn.
Rym: The plates, if you score a row that has a plate pointed at it, you get the plate.
Rym: And then you can take a new plate to put somewhere on the board.
Rym: The plates have powers like, "Remove three dudes from the
Rym: board."
Rym: Or, "Hey guys, four extra actions right
Rym: now.".
Scott: Some of the plates are just obviously more strong, like the four or five extra actions at once.
Rym: I find those to be weaker.
Rym: I like the swap-a-dude, and I like the remove three dudes.
Scott: The swap one can be very strong in the right situation, but in other situations it can be worthless.
Scott: The remove three dudes is ridiculously strong in just about any situation.
Scott: Especially if your bag is not upgraded very well.
Rym: The plates are also worth points.
Rym: The more you get, the more points each one is worth.
Scott: So you can just play for the plates, and then using the plates also helps you get more plates and more other things also.
Rym: I've seen people win this game ignoring everything and just trying to get every plate as fast as possible.
Scott: Yeah, and that ends the game as well.
Scott: So even if no one gets to 20 points, if you get enough plates, you can end the game pretty quickly.
Rym: This is a game, primarily, if you want to talk about the skills involved, of predicting what other players' strategies are, and coming up with the best counter to them, while simultaneously obfuscating what you're doing, or putting yourself into such a position of strength that people can't stop you.
Scott: It's not a game where I can tell you, like settlers, just do one of these two things every game.
Scott: It's like, alright, you have to really assess what's going on in the whole lay of the land every turn, see what everyone's doing, and there will be a different path to go every different game based on what people have done.
Rym: Yup, and your path might change mid-game.
Scott: You also just might be fucked based on where you're sitting or something.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: A pretty powerful strategy I've found is to focus on a few things.
Rym: Like, upgrade your actions a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, just focus on something basic early on until you see the lay of the land.
Rym: Yup, and wait and see, and hope that people move the game in a certain direction that you can then react to and capitalize on the fact that you were waiting for them to move.
Scott: The theme of the game has something to do with...
Rym: The Hanseatic League?
Scott: Yeah, and it doesn't exist.
Scott: We can't figure out what the fuck is going on.
Rym: Yeah, ignore all the theming of the game.
Scott: Trading, some shit, whatever, who cares.
Rym: That's why games like Puerto Rico or Tigger's New Freighties to this day hold this extra tier for us.
Rym: Because one, they're extremely complex, well thought out mechanically as games.
Rym: But two, the theme is integrally woven into the games in such a wonderful and nuanced way that a lot of more modern games just don't do.
Rym: This game has terrible iconography.
Rym: It's extremely confusing without a very specific and detailed explanation of how to upgrade everything and how everything works.
Scott: From someone who read the rules 20 times on the internet.
Rym: But otherwise, it's a really solid game.
Rym: I'm really surprised it held up.
Rym: I mean, Thurn in Texas, which we loved, didn't make it through four playthroughs before we figured it out and we were done with it.
Rym: This game, I think, will have a decent bit of staying power.
Scott: Thurn in Texas is a lot like Ticket to Ride, basically.
Rym: Yeah, this is more like those older German board games with cubes in a lot of ways.
Rym: I'll point out, we're talking about strategy.
Rym: If you upgrade your actions or your bag once, you get an immediate bonus.
Rym: If you upgrade your actions a second time, you don't get a bonus.
Rym: You have to upgrade it a third time.
Rym: So it's usually not worth it to try to blitz actions hard.
Rym: Your best bet is to blitz actions as fast as possible just to get to three actions.
Rym: And then you don't need that fourth action immediately.
Rym: You can do that opportunistically if you're clever.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if there's an opportunity to just be like, "Helicopter
Scott: score!"
Scott: with two actions to get that action when it's upgraded, I would go for it.
Rym: Yeah, but don't spend three turns orchestrating your four actions early game that you get much more bang for your buck getting that third action and then going somewhere else.
Scott: Or getting one bag upgrade, which is probably easier to get and is also going to save you actions.
Rym: Yup, if all the other players are just having this deathmatch with discs everywhere around the actions, go upgrade your key and your privilium a whole bunch.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or just start taking cities in the middle.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: People forget they can take cities in this game sometimes.
Scott: That's another thing.
Scott: is that usually in a game, there's like a hot spot where all the valuable shit is and people fight over that.
Scott: In this game, there's valuable shit all over the place.
Scott: There's not like areas of the board that are dead.
Scott: Why would you ever go there?
Scott: It's like, no, the whole board is hot.
Scott: There'll be a plate over there that's looking hot.
Scott: There'll be a nice city you can get over there.
Scott: Easy connection, right?
Scott: You can go for the colon.
Scott: If no one's going for the colon, it's like that's worth a ton of points.
Scott: It's pretty hot.
Rym: If you just sneak in there once.
Scott: Oh, everyone's going for all those other hot things.
Scott: I'll just take Sanacione, right?
Scott: It's just hot stuff everywhere.
Scott: And you'll see, once people, if you play with people who've played a lot, there'll be cubes all over the place, not just in like one area.
Scott: that's awesome.
Rym: Now, the game takes two to five players, but there are three variants to accomplish that.
Rym: Two player has this thing where there's these knights that move around.
Rym: I haven't played it.
Rym: We haven't either.
Rym: People say it's not that great.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Two and three player use one side of the board.
Rym: Four and five player use another side of the board.
Rym: that has just more connections between cities.
Rym: I think the game is best with three or five players.
Rym: Board Game Geek says the game is best with five players.
Rym: But three and five are very different, kind of like the difference between three and five and Puerto Rico.
Rym: Very different strategies, very different game.
Rym: I worry that with four players, the board's a little too open.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I think four players doesn't work on the smaller one, so I think you should try to avoid playing with four people.
Rym: Go for three or five.
Rym: So, I don't know what else I can say.
Rym: I mean, you guys should play this game.
Scott: If you're playing board games, play this one.
Rym: So, Andreas Steding, it's interesting, because I actually didn't know who he was, and he doesn't seem to have a lot of games, at least that are known in the US, to his name.
Rym: Like Scottish Highland Whiskey Race.
Scott: That's amazing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't care what that game is.
Rym: Hispania is the only one that I've heard of.
Rym: I mean, Italia, I've seen but I've never played.
Rym: Heart of Africa, I've seen but I've never played.
Rym: Oh, the Hansa Zutana expansion, I need that.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: God damn it.
Scott: Who knows what's in that thing.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of really want it now.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And it doesn't look like he's published anything since 2010.
Scott: Huh.
Scott: Maybe he's working on a masterpiece.
Rym: I hope so.
Scott: Maybe he's got a job.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.