Rym: It's Thursday August 7th 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight salad with lettuces and such.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: oh my god, I should have made my thing of the day.
Rym: salad day.
Scott: It's not a thing of the day.
Scott: That's the thing of the day of the decades before you're born a game of tennis.
Rym: Ah The thing is that skit is funny even if you don't get what it's actually making fun of.
Scott: I Actually only have get what it's making fun.
Rym: Dude does the name peckinpah ring a bell.
Scott: It's a familiar word.
Rym: Really, how is that a familiar word in what context?
Rym: give me any relation to that word?
Scott: It's a word I've heard before.
Rym: where?
Rym: how?
Scott: it's just the word.
Rym: is it?
Rym: it is not a new word to me It's a name.
Rym: Okay, you have never heard that word, but I've heard it.
Scott: I don't know what it means or I don't think I've heard it, but I have heard it.
Rym: I don't think you've heard of Sam peckinpah.
Scott: I have heard that name.
Scott: I don't know Sam peckinpah.
Scott: I've heard the fur the word.
Rym: no one would ever say peckinpah unless they were referencing Sam peckinpah.
Scott: I have heard it in my life.
Rym: Uh-huh so can you guess why?
Rym: it's related to salad days.
Scott: He was a dude like that?
Rym: Oh Like what he?
Scott: maybe he was a crazy killer who went to guys playing tennis and murdered them by cutting No one's off.
Rym: No one murdered anyone in salad days.
Rym: That was just a series of horrific accidents.
Scott: Maybe he was just really accident-prone, dude Quotes.
Rym: dad David Samuel Sam peckinpah February 21st 1925 to December 28th 1984 was an American film director and screenwriter who achieved prominence following the release of the Western epic the wild bunch.
Scott: No, I know them.
Rym: I heard of that movie blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: He was given the nickname bloody Sam owing to the violence in his films.
Rym: His characters are often loners or losers who desire to be honorable But are forced to compromise in order to survive in a world of nihilism and brutality.
Scott: I should go see that movie.
Rym: didn't you notice in the salad days sketch that they're like directed by Sam peckinpah?
Rym: No, that's the joke.
Rym: It's not just the horrific accident.
Rym: violence, okay Learn something new every day.
Scott: There you go every day.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: So, uh got some news here.
Rym: I'm kind of Shocked and amazed that regular media was really not covering this at all.
Rym: And I'm not talking about in that sense of Republicans and Fox News being like but Benghazi.
Rym: why doesn't anyone care about Benghazi?
Rym: Yeah Talking about actual news is you don't care about Benghazi?
Rym: So the American media has been going crazy about Ebola But they're not going crazy about it in terms of the humanitarian crisis in the countries where it is occurring.
Rym: They're going crazy about it in the sense of oh my god.
Rym: What if it comes here?
Rym: Of course, but what they're not talking about is what happened in Toledo the other day.
Rym: Okay, you know what happened in Toledo.
Scott: I really couldn't give any fewer shits.
Scott: Well, you wouldn't give any shit about anything that ever happens in Toledo, Ohio Unless for some reason.
Scott: Toledo, Ohio decided to clear war in New York or something in which case I would sign up and shoot them in the face.
Scott: But other than that, I don't care if a new kid Toledo, Ohio.
Scott: Well, I still wouldn't care.
Rym: you are familiar with the Toledo war right.
Rym: that was between Michigan and Ohio Over the rights to the Toledo disputed.
Scott: That's why the only thing I'm concerned with is maybe they might start that shit up again only pointed in the wrong direction.
Scott: They're pretty far away.
Rym: wait, so you're saying in the war between Ohio and Michigan you're on Michigan side.
Scott: No, I'm saying if they decided to you know, take the warlike ways to New York, I don't give a shit.
Rym: How would they even get here?
Scott: Listen, they have cars.
Scott: All right, it's modern times.
Scott: They're more cars than we have because we don't drive.
Rym: I look this war is great because belligerent state of Ohio territory of Michigan casualties and losses.
Rym: Ohio lost nobody and Michigan had zero dead and one wounded.
Rym: I think like 14 shots were fired.
Scott: I'll tell you they start that shit up with New York.
Scott: Those numbers gonna be a lot higher.
Rym: I'm gonna go volunteer gonna sign up to be one of the dough boys.
Scott: It will not be good for you people from the state with two O's in the name heading over on the Erie Canal to do Some some battling.
Rym: Yeah now so what happened in Toledo?
Rym: because a lot of people don't seem to realize that anything happened.
Rym: There was some news about a water crisis And that's most of what people heard.
Scott: what actually happened was something usually that shits out in California, Arizona.
Scott: Yes run out of water So they have water there.
Scott: It's not a no water place like Arizona so you can read the details about it.
Rym: but the irony of the fact that this occurred in a city that borders the Great Lakes it Really tells you how much of an actual crisis this was.
Scott: how couldn't they just start drinking a Great Lake water?
Rym: Yes, it's got.
Rym: they do drink Great Lakes water.
Rym: Here's what happened to Lido and the entire metropolitan region around it, which is about a half a million.
Scott: This did not affect Cleveland Columbus.
Scott: It's now.
Rym: it affected Toledo in a surrounding so about 500,000 people give or take were affected so almost Nova up on the grand scale of the country.
Rym: That's bigger than a lot of places.
Scott: It's less than it's always like my neighborhood's worth.
Rym: It's more than Seattle.
Rym: So Toledo Declared.
Rym: they announced that there was an emergency and that nobody should drink the water Touch the water brush their teeth with the water cook with the water bathe with the water.
Scott: How could the whole Great Lake be poisoned?
Scott: That's impossible.
Scott: Now the sheer amount of poison is impossible.
Rym: Actually, it's very easy for that to happen and it was just the area around the reservoir intake thingy.
Rym: So the reservoir intake thingy is massive and it's out in the middle of Lake Erie.
Rym: obviously Lake Erie Has been having for a long time now algal blooms.
Scott: So you did algae in the water?
Scott: Yes, doesn't the water treatment center clean that shit out?
Rym: Uh, it's supposed to but one because we don't have the water treatment center because we don't invest in civil infrastructure.
Rym: Toledo's water treatment system kind of old kind of shitty.
Rym: so it broke and the intakes are near to the surface.
Rym: No, what happened was the algae had a huge bloom More so than has happened in recent memory at least since they started testing clogged.
Scott: it clogged the shit up.
Rym: No, so this toxin was just created in such quantity that it could not be removed from the water.
Rym: It also is very difficult to test for this toxin.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: you drink the water if you die?
Rym: No, this toxin causes cumulative liver damage from what I can gather.
Scott: Oh, it's not like.
Rym: you're not from drinking it from being exposed to it.
Rym: People who have had liver problems.
Rym: It's really lakes hepatitis from being near lakes that were also near farms or pig farms.
Rym: Because what happens is fertilizer runoff and phosphates get into the water in like ponds algae go.
Rym: Oh fuck There's more food here than we've ever had.
Rym: So algae explodes everywhere.
Rym: Just algae everywhere Yeah, and then the algae makes poison.
Scott: can't they just go out into the lake and spray all the algaes to kill them off?
Scott: Yes by putting poison in the water sure, but there are people from Ohio so we don't care.
Rym: So there's already poison in the water.
Rym: the the result of this can't make it worse.
Rym: usually when there's a water Emergency like that in the civilized modern industrialized world I mean there aren't and daughters make can't do something at the water treatment facility.
Scott: insert some new equipment that takes care of.
Rym: that would Take probably years to put in place Money even then.
Scott: Oh, all right, Ohio doesn't have any.
Rym: also the problem is that Lake Erie being shallow being Warmer due to global warming and he's pretty happy right and being increasingly flooded with fertilizer runoff due to largely Unregulated farms and golf courses of living in farm places.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but places that could regulate and choose not to Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's basically a perfect storm of everything conservatives believe don't happen or matter.
Rym: Actually poison the water supply of a city.
Rym: for three days The water was toxic and unusable.
Rym: the National Guard had to be mobilized water had to be trucked in every store ran out of water.
Rym: It was a disaster and people likely would have died.
Rym: They suddenly declared after a few days that the poison levels had dropped below the line And thus it was okay to drink the water again.
Rym: This is far from over.
Rym: this could happen again at any point.
Scott: now I'm much more concerned of Ohio declaring war in New York to take our treasured water supply.
Rym: Why would they not declare war on Michigan?
Rym: because Ohio has one great lake the shittiest great lake.
Scott: granted It's not even that great.
Scott: It's just the good way.
Rym: The thing is it's the great lake.
Rym: Lake Erie is still better than any other fucking lake in the world.
Rym: What Lake Champlain.
Rym: Lake Champlain is like a hundredth the size of like.
Scott: I'm thinking of lakes like on the other side of the planet.
Scott: There aren't that many lakes that big and those are the ones I thought of ours actually sees.
Rym: so Ohio is on the smallest and Shittiest of the Great Lakes.
Rym: Michigan has access to Lake Superior, which is pretty fucking awesome in terms of water to drink Mmm, and you know the other great lakes up there like Lake Superior, but that's clearly yeah.
Rym: It's also deep and fucking cold the middle of summer.
Rym: go there like August 30th on a sunny hundred degree day.
Scott: That water is 32.1 degrees thing is you're so proud of these fucking lakes.
Scott: Any none of these lakes even hold a candle to a sea.
Rym: a sea is just unbeatable unless you want to drink the water Black Sea Red Sea Mediterranean Sea.
Rym: Yeah, don't drink any of those.
Rym: go drink some of the Dead Sea.
Rym: What's it called again?
Rym: Oh, right.
Scott: You don't drink it you floating in.
Rym: it's a The point of this news.
Rym: I'm not gonna go do the play-by-play.
Rym: Read about it.
Rym: go read what happened.
Rym: the news didn't cover it at all outside of that area.
Rym: But think about for a second what just happened in the United States of America one of the most Industrialized and advanced countries in the world one of the safest water supplies in the world.
Scott: Well depending on which state you're in.
Rym: but even the shittiest states have better water here than most of the rest of the world.
Scott: Yeah, where there's dysentery and shit.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I mean when I go to India I have to drink bottled water even in like major cities in luxury hotels.
Rym: That's fucked up.
Scott: actual luxury hotels not hotels that just use the word luxury.
Scott: exactly.
Rym: Yeah, but in America in a normal city, I mean Toledo is not the smallest city It's actually on the scale of cities in the country one of the bigger cities.
Rym: The entire water supply was poisoned and we could do nothing about it But for the fact that the algae just happened to recede enough to where the toxin levels drop just low enough where we'd say it's Okay to drink is the only reason the people are done.
Scott: It's just not as much poison.
Rym: had they had this not subsided It's not out of the realm but a staged evacuation of the city would have had to occur.
Scott: No, I mean, there's probably enough water for like a few people to say that Yeah, but I mean they were trucking it.
Rym: They emptied pretty much every source of bottled water within the region.
Scott: Couldn't they just seal the intake and then make a big pipe to somewhere else from where?
Rym: how long do you think that would take?
Rym: This shit is not fast to do.
Scott: Make a pipe we have.
Rym: how many decades did it take Scott to make a new pipe to New York?
Rym: Even when we spent a lot of money, it's not easy.
Scott: Well, I mean if you put the pipe above ground said underground you have to
Rym: just consider the fact that this happened in the year 2014 in a city in the United States of America and the news gave zero fucks about it Despite the fact that this is an unresolved issue.
Rym: This is fucked.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: Anyway, that's my news.
Scott: You got something less depressing Yeah, so tomorrow we are going to go see Angry video game nerd movie.
Scott: Oh, yeah in New York City.
Scott: I mean, it's already been screened a bunch of places.
Scott: I think it's being screened at PAX amongst other locations Yeah, but I don't want to spend packs hours my New York hours, but we're gonna go see it tomorrow.
Scott: He's finally finished it right?
Scott: He didn't shit talk good on him.
Scott: We'll let you know how.
Scott: it is Kind of somewhat exciting not because I think it's gonna be the greatest movie ever, but it could be good but because It's like there's this dude who've been watching all this time.
Rym: Someone on that level like made a thing that's big enough to be screened at Lincoln Center.
Scott: Yeah, well Lincoln Center ish area, right?
Scott: You know, how come we haven't done anything?
Scott: You know higher than our level because he is attacked only one.
Rym: we have it.
Rym: We have like half as it Lee attacked like a hundred things.
Rym: So true, we're slowly stepping up the game.
Scott: Why don't we quit everything then and just attack only one?
Rym: I've thought about that.
Rym: remember with the savings we've got now you me and Emily could move to like the equivalent of beacon and live For like two years with no income.
Scott: I was thinking the other day I read this article about what it takes to win this field this yarn.
Scott: I was like, you know what?
Scott: I just quit my job and just make games in forever until I win.
Rym: I'm bringing my prototype game to packs to play.
Scott: Yeah, but you're not gonna win this field.
Scott: this now It's like I should just concentrate on doing like.
Scott: I should pick one thing like that If not that and just do that and only that.
Scott: yeah I get it my my.
Rym: that like my longest term goal I have in my world is someday I want to be important enough in the games industry to give the a keynote at apex.
Scott: Imagine if I want to spiel this yard, like I go Germany and they give me the little red Scott Reuben on it has the red pond on it.
Rym: if I won one I would tattoo that trophy on my body.
Scott: someone I would do that, but it's like I could.
Scott: just I could die with no regret.
Scott: It's like oh, all right, I'm good.
Rym: Oh and there's a side news I know.
Scott: think about this right.
Scott: the Dominion dude Donald back arena, whatever motherfuckers got to Yeah, Dominion and then Kingdom builders one also, right?
Rym: Oh did it?
Rym: Yeah, I think it did Yeah, so I got a little funny news to that.
Rym: This is this is one of those stories that may be apocryphal and Gawker linked to it and a FARC and I found this whole tree and as far as I can tell the nearest source I can Get is a single post on reddit, but supposedly guy was in line at a Burger King and Behind him was the shitty little kid who's having a tantrum about how he wants some fucking pie And he's really mad.
Rym: his mom's like fine I'll buy you some pie.
Rym: So he being two people ahead of that family asked how many pies they had.
Rym: It was only 23.
Rym: So we bought them all.
Rym: Okay, and that's it Mm-hmm.
Rym: I found that was funny and mostly I'm curious Whether or not this happened and I'm curious why all these different news sites today decided to like Cannibalize off of each other into this like ouroboros circle jerk and linked to this thing.
Rym: Okay, it's like a circle where I think they all link to each other and there's no origin.
Rym: maybe things of the day But when we were young during our salad days One thing that we did we fancied a game of Mario Tennis.
Rym: Nah we were.
Rym: we were coming out of Wegmans after buying our groceries and Next to in like in the area of the lottery machine that one time I put five bucks into and I won like 40 bucks The only time I ever put money in that thing and next to it were the vending machines that had like vampire teeth blood Really shitty candy.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: and one day Scott notices something called homies.
Rym: Go over and look a little action.
Scott: Well, they're not action figures, but little figurines little little, you know Plastic dudes and they were like little thug dudes called homies and they had.
Scott: they had a lot of character.
Scott: They're actually pretty funny.
Scott: You're cool For 50 cents.
Rym: They were pretty quality.
Scott: So I used to actually get him at the burger place of the train and Bill Gray's had the best homie machine man.
Rym: I remember a lot of weird late nights Like we'd.
Rym: it'd be like 930 and we're hungry and we're like, yeah Let's just go to Bill Gray's and no one else ever went with us.
Rym: It was just like.
Scott: that place is never crowded, but I know huge.
Rym: It was huge.
Rym: The food was mediocre.
Scott: It was okay food.
Rym: They didn't have air hockey, but they had that other hockey.
Scott: You could get a fried chicken sandwich there.
Scott: That was slightly.
Scott: that was better than you could get at a fast-food place and that wasn't widely available.
Rym: in retrospect I can't figure out why we ever went there instead of J's The diner.
Rym: Yeah Like why?
Rym: why was it when it was the two of us steak on French bread?
Scott: Yeah, cuz I guess there's.
Scott: you know, I just sit with a weight, you know weight service and whatnot.
Rym: true It was faster.
Rym: give it that.
Scott: the place I always wanted to go was that there was like there's a place called moonshine barbecue.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that drive-thru barbecue is just a barbecue restaurant.
Scott: But then they opened up mine She moonshine barbecue Express across the street from millennium and that you can get the best barbecue sandwich there.
Scott: Yeah, but that didn't last very long.
Scott: I think I was the only one who went there and then it was gone.
Rym: I remember what's that weird sandwich place in that weird.
Rym: now whenever?
Scott: yeah, whenever I see a similar sandwich other elsewhere I get it.
Rym: thing is if I went over there as much as I like that place I go to a meals and get one of those like chicken cordon bleu meals.
Scott: Why'd you go to the palace which is a?
Scott: we could literally walk completely different kinds of food.
Rym: The Bellas is a saw but meals is a chicken sandwich.
Rym: Yeah, but I digress.
Rym: so we.
Rym: we kind of collected these homies.
Scott: Yeah, I have a bunch of them.
Scott: I found them the other day.
Rym: Yeah I remember I kept the one that was the cop in the car is like a toad.
Rym: Oh, we had.
Scott: we got some doubles right because you're buying these Randomly from a from a machine.
Rym: I basically I had like three of this one guy with a long face We're in like like a basketball shirt had bad luck and I had two of the cop.
Scott: I got quite a few.
Rym: I should bust him out got that girl with the weird hair a couple times, too.
Rym: So, uh, here's the documentary vice documentary.
Scott: when we these things were useful It wasn't just like we were collecting stupid figures in college.
Scott: for no reason.
Scott: We played a lot of cheap ass games that just kill dr.
Scott: Lucky which ended up being killed.
Rym: dr.
Rym: Homie
Scott: kill dr Homie cuz you need you got to supply your own pawns Yeah, so
Rym: so yeah If you ever wanted to know what the story was with homies because they were actually way bigger than we realized at the time This is a documentary about the guy who was responsible for the homie Empire.
Rym: Well, let me tell you this is fascinating.
Rym: This is depressing.
Rym: So fair warning.
Rym: if you watch this you're gonna see the most stereotypical Staten Island guy with his voice and I fuck this shit fucking mother fuck shit.
Scott: Fuck and It's my homies.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: It's so sad.
Rym: 30 fucking dollars.
Rym: These are 12 bucks.
Rym: My man.
Rym: I'll see you later.
Rym: That guy sounds like what a lifetime of misery and cigarettes does to the human soul.
Scott: Okay, so there's a question I've had for a long time and I knew that it's probably I definitely had an answer that I could Find on the internet, but I just never actually went through the effort of finding the answer on the internet Until just now I did.
Scott: the question was if you know see the giant ass crane building a skyscraper or something.
Scott: How do they build that crane?
Scott: How do they get it up there?
Rym: a lot of people's response to that question is duh And then they trail off.
Scott: is they can't really figure it out Of course, and you think oh another crane.
Scott: obviously use some small cranes to get started.
Scott: But here's a video on YouTube showing how a tower crane works.
Scott: I'm gonna spoil it.
Scott: It's really fascinating.
Scott: So they build a small piece of the tower just by building with other cranes.
Scott: then they put the little control, you know room and all that stuff on top right and It's a crane.
Scott: It's just really short on This the tower that the crane is on.
Scott: there's a hydraulic lift.
Scott: The hydraulic lift basically lifts the crane up one sections worth.
Scott: Then the crane goes and uses the actual crane that is working to lift up a new section and it slides in.
Scott: Then people screw it, you know, they attach it.
Scott: then the hydraulic lift lifts the crane itself up one more section And that's how it works.
Scott: So this led to a more fascinating question.
Scott: as soon as I saw this video I was like, aha I get it That's amazing incredible.
Scott: It's everything I expected.
Scott: How do they take that fucking shit apart?
Scott: You think they would just do the same thing in reverse But actually no, so here's a video also second thing of day Dismantling the world's largest tower crane.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: is that is that representative of how they take apart all cranes?
Rym: or is that one special?
Scott: It's specifically tower cranes Not any other kind of crane.
Scott: There are many cranes that are not tower cranes.
Scott: This is a tower crane.
Scott: This is how they take that one apart.
Rym: All right In the meta moment the book club book is the mechanical for Liebowitz, I'm hoping Scott will read it as I I actually Opened up yesterday to where I was bookmarked and then immediately closed.
Scott: they went to bed.
Scott: That's great.
Scott: without reading any words.
Rym: We got a bunch of videos on the internet.
Rym: not gonna dwell on all that stuff.
Rym: We were running a contest to win two four day badges to PAX Prime.
Scott: Those other people have had at least one person has received their tickets in the mail already.
Rym: So the deadline is fast approaching.
Scott: when Scott receives them I'll probably give like one grace day and then pick a winner randomly from amongst the people who have tweeted properly.
Rym: We'll link to the rules.
Rym: But basically you have to tweet promotional stuff about us and gig nights.
Scott: Yes, at least one person is tweeted incorrectly neglecting the PAX hashtag.
Rym: Oh You got it.
Rym: You better check and make sure it wasn't you.
Scott: you can still tweet again and get it, right?
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: We're going to do a search to find all the correct entries.
Scott: Yes, some people actually tweeted but did not link to any GeekNights content.
Scott: You're all.
Scott: your tweet will also not count.
Scott: Ah So make sure you tweeted correctly.
Scott: Otherwise, you know, I just even it.
Scott: I know some of you people too.
Scott: I feel bad missing your entry But I gotta do what I got to do.
Scott: if I'll be fair follow the rules or else your entry doesn't count.
Scott: more than one Entry isn't gonna count either.
Scott: You're just gonna get one
Rym: now granted if if packs Announced or at least told panel like panelists and presenters and speakers if they had a badge ready for them or not Then we wouldn't even bother buying badges and giving them away like this meaning two more people could have just bought batches.
Rym: Yep, but this is the world we live in.
Rym: I'm not risking not going to a PAX.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So if you're going to be a PAX either because you win these badges or because you're awesome noon Monday how to win every game Monday.
Scott: Are you say packs for day?
Scott: Oh my god I always forget.
Rym: packs is four days until like the week before and I go oh fuck.
Rym: and for me Packs is six days because I'm also gonna be a pack Sunday full day of packs.
Rym: I'm gonna be a packs for six whole motherfucking days and I'm gonna be there the Tuesday before and the Tuesday after To play games in the lobby.
Scott: This is I only hope permanent packs can come about within our lifetime If we all just move to one place.
Scott: Permanent packs packs.
Rym: Yeah packs New York It would you know what it should be like.
Scott: you should be like one of those Just kick everyone out of white planes and make it pack.
Rym: It'll be like the Greek gentlemen societies that they have everywhere like the societies for like particular ethnic groups that moved to New York.
Rym: We need a big one of those that's just packs.
Scott: Oh, so it's like a certain neighborhood just becomes the nerd neighborhood.
Rym: Yep, and then there's a bunch of those facilities like where we had the first burning con.
Scott: Mmm, which neighborhood should we take over?
Rym: Uh, Well, obviously the Upper West Side.
Rym: So Yes, if you're gonna be a PAX dev let me know.
Rym: maybe we can hang out go to some panels together.
Rym: If you're gonna be at the pack sky high charity prepacks, whatever event we're gonna be there you can play some games.
Rym: I hope you have a VIP because I don't know if we can bring non VIPs in the VIP room which we just paid money for.
Scott: and Otherwise, that's it spending too much money lately.
Scott: Anyone wants to send me money.
Scott: I have a second packs badge.
Rym: The good news, however, is that Part of the reason we're spending all this money is that we bought some equipment that's going to let us Continue to make content for the internet in great.
Scott: I don't think there is any Equipment we could possibly get that we do not already have that we would need for anything at this point.
Rym: having people to do The work is all we need.
Rym: Yep, if someone else would video this shit.
Rym: So yeah We're gonna try to use this shit at packs and at other places and expect a lot of video Content to be coming out of us in the near future.
Rym: Mmm, so salad?
Scott: Yeah, so we want to do food episode.
Scott: We always seem to like the food but we needed something more specific than just food which had Rym wanted to do.
Rym: Yeah, what once called fire.
Scott: so to be fair, that's a great episode.
Scott: So yeah salad is a kind of food I eat a lot and make a lot So I guess we can talk for 30 minutes about it pretty easily.
Scott: I'm a big fan of salads.
Rym: I my whole life as a kid.
Rym: we would have a salad as a pre dish Or a side dish pretty much every meal.
Scott: that is true.
Rym: What sickens me is that most people I know that is not the case.
Rym: How what the fuck family did you grow up in a family that I don't know?
Scott: ate McDonald's every dinner some fat family.
Rym: Maybe I don't give it a McDonald's when I went to McDonald's as a kid unless it was breakfast I usually got the salad.
Scott: when I was a kid McDonald's did not have salad and I stopped going to McDonald's when I was still in single digits of age and then I guess they had salad after that.
Scott: I think the last time I went to McDonald's or Burger King like for reals was when they had Thundercats toys.
Scott: Oh, that's how long 80s.
Rym: I went to a McDonald's.
Scott: That's not to say I didn't eat fast food.
Scott: I went to many in Arby's.
Rym: Yeah, we tried to go to that one army.
Scott: It's not that many years ago We went to Wendy's near at RIT.
Scott: Yeah But I did not go to McDonald's because Wendy's was right next to putt-putt.
Rym: that had the DDR machine and they had $1 Chicken nuggets, let me tell you when you're poor you have no money at all.
Scott: Nuggets.
Rym: five orders of $1 nuggets was a pretty good deal.
Rym: So, uh, let's get right to the point.
Rym: What's your favorite kind of salad Scott?
Rym: I like so many kinds of salad like if you had to name one like if you had to pick one salad To eat right now.
Rym: Oh, right into salad.
Scott: That's the thing.
Scott: My salad mood changes But one salad I go to then.
Scott: Mmm Well, I go to fresco a lot.
Scott: that's like my favorite salad place.
Scott: that's just a normal salad place not a fancy restaurant.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta just salads for salad a lot.
Scott: And when I go there, I usually order one of two salads one that they've taken off the menu, but you can still order.
Scott: You're one of those people which is the Fiesta and the other one which is they don't make the Fiesta anymore.
Scott: Well, they do.
Scott: you just say I want the Fiesta and they make it for you But it's not on the printed menu on the wall anymore.
Scott: Every single person who works there knows what it is someday.
Rym: That will not be true.
Rym: Maybe I too have lost a kingdom.
Scott: if there's someone there teach it to them and Pat You know play it forward like if you're all right.
Rym: RIT kids I know a lot of you listen go to while Java Wally's on campus and try to order a chaplain.
Rym: That is the ultimate test.
Scott: The other one that they have there.
Scott: I really like is the South Beach.
Scott: So the South Beach is like fruit and nuts and raisins and gorgonzola cheese and this, you know It's sort of that kind of salads.
Scott: They're a summary and the Fiesta is basically like Chipotle in salad form.
Scott: It's some like crispy fried chicken all chopped up with you know lettuce and Like sour cream.
Rym: What are those salad?
Scott: Little tortillas.
Scott: It's basically just an enchilada tomato onion all kinds of cheese Some Tex-Mex dressing on there.
Rym: I realized when I grew up as a kid There was a default salad because I lived in Michigan in the Midwest and in the Midwest it seems like the default salad is basically the chef salad.
Rym: So cubed ham, maybe some cubed turkey Maybe some cubed salami some cubed Monterey Jack some cubed cheddar, maybe some cubed and like Colby sometimes iceberg lettuce onions Tons of ranch dressing and maybe bacon bits.
Rym: Yeah, it was basically just a. it's almost like if you it's like Making cereal with croutons and instead of milk.
Rym: It's so croutons instead of cereal ranch dressing instead of milk.
Rym: That's basically what these salads were.
Scott: So the chef salad and the Cobb salad are actually my least favorite Salad.
Rym: I was saving that for the end.
Scott: that is my least favorite Salads because the chef salad contains those cubed ham.
Rym: Oh my god that cubed ham is so good.
Scott: not a fan of Really any to be fair.
Rym: I'll give you that because if you don't like cubed ham if you don't like like pink boiled ham I can understand why you wouldn't like a chef.
Rym: the Cobb salad has the hard-boiled egg, which also not a fan Oh, but the hard-boiled egg Which is not a salad usually.
Scott: No the time of the Cobb salad has the egg and the chef salad has the ham neither of which I'm a big fan of.
Scott: so I tend to avoid those in the elementary school cafeteria.
Rym: You could order.
Rym: usually they have two options for dinner or dinner for lunch and it was always like the bullshit food in cafeterias.
Rym: That's awful like their chicken nuggets or the awful hamburger and then the other option was pretty much always the chef salad.
Rym: So I ate chef salad like every goddamn day, and that's also what I made at home.
Rym: Scott's poking me for some reason.
Scott: Yeah, I just decided to do that cuz I can.
Rym: yeah, okay poking me with the microphone boom.
Rym: Yeah, the extra microphone boom, but we don't need anymore because we bought those countryman microphones.
Scott: boom We're not gonna use this for the podcast.
Rym: No, but I don't need this third boom anymore I guess not.
Rym: we're using those for video no longer.
Rym: We'll just gotta sit there for like an hour while I like.
Scott: position the stereo mics anyway More salad action.
Scott: so making a salad salad.
Scott: I usually make it home is very similar to the salad My parents would make it home.
Rym: Oh, so garden salad or Caesar salad?
Scott: Yeah, it's usually garden.
Scott: ish right cuz basically once I got to high school.
Scott: They told me to make this out.
Scott: Yeah, so what we my dad doesn't like cucumber, but we had cucumber anyway, and he just wouldn't get any.
Scott: yeah Amazingly some lettuce usually romaine iceberg something like that, okay, so lame-o lettuce standard lettuce.
Scott: Yeah, chop it up nicely tear it up.
Scott: you with your hands actually not supposed to cut it.
Rym: I learned that from From.
Rym: oh my god.
Rym: What sitcom did I learn that from?
Scott: Anyway, go on Seinfeld.
Rym: I don't know way before that.
Scott: okay.
Scott: You tear lettuce with your hands.
Scott: You don't cut it.
Rym: Carrot Charles in charge really that there's an episode about that.
Scott: apparently that guy's supposed to be a dick.
Scott: I've heard.
Rym: uh I don't I can't comment on that.
Scott: I've heard rumors that the Charles charge.
Scott: I heard rumors that I was named Scott.
Rym: right Scott Bayo.
Scott: is that the guy's name?
Rym: Anyway, I want Charles anyway charge of your salad.
Rym: so yeah in that episode basically carrot lettuce.
Rym: in that episode Every time he walks into the room onion cucumber they're making a salad and someone's always there either cutting lettuce with scissors or With a knife and every time he comes and he's like ah you got a tear it why?
Rym: otherwise it'll go brown why?
Rym: You're just supposed to know that yeah, but why does it go brown?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: and this happens like every time he comes in someone's fucking up the salad.
Scott: There is a time when you're not supposed to tear a lettuce with your hands.
Scott: You know and that is a wedge salad.
Rym: I like wedge salad.
Scott: I gotta use a big knife and make a big wedge and that lettuce and then you can make a wedge salad.
Rym: oh In the modern era people seem to agree that tearing the salad is pointless.
Scott: why?
Rym: uh That it's all a myth.
Rym: Okay I'm doing some research here.
Scott: So basically I depend on the kind of lettuce.
Rym: That's what I think it is.
Rym: I take this guy did an experiment.
Rym: So I tear green leaf lettuce and red leaf lettuce unless I'm making a chopped salad.
Rym: I don't actually as much as I really like.
Scott: If you're doing the thing that the salad places do where you just chop everything up like crazy before putting it in the bowl doesn't matter And it doesn't matter whether you tore it or chopped it.
Rym: when you make a chopped salad you put it in a bowl and actually Toss it With the dressing.
Scott: No, I usually just put the dressing on and use my fork to just turn it over.
Scott: No, I don't have a bowl.
Scott: It's like I got that dirty a whole extra bowl just to toss the salad in and then poor it's worth it Mmm.
Rym: It's kind of like when you fry rice like if you if you put that effort in to quote every single grain of rice with a It is so worth all five flavors to come out.
Scott: It'll be so golden.
Scott: Yeah, you'll shed a manly tear.
Rym: Oh In real life.
Rym: It doesn't matter how you divide the leaves as long as you don't apply dressing before storing for a prolonged period.
Rym: Obviously the lettuce is browning on the ribs before it doesn't the edges.
Rym: the difference between cut and torn is no longer important.
Rym: Wait, no longer.
Rym: When is this important?
Rym: All right, you talk.
Scott: I'm gonna read this See a typical salad I make lettuce tomato cucumber carrot peppers onions croutons.
Scott: What kind of peppers dressing?
Scott: Oh any kind I can get right?
Scott: So sometimes the red ones sometimes the green ones Sometimes the yellow and the orange.
Rym: We're not using like poblanos or jalapenos though.
Scott: No, I mean those are in the Fiesta.
Scott: That is more like I don't like one of those like taco salad using some kind of bell pepper whichever one looks good at the Store, maybe I'll buy a package of like the trace colores peppers.
Rym: All right, this guy argues the opposite.
Rym: tearing lettuce is always worth the effort.
Scott: Okay, why?
Rym: uh, it takes a reasonably similar amount of time and the different.
Rym: but what?
Rym: what if you were planning on eating a god?
Rym: Damn it you people.
Rym: This is too complicated.
Scott: I got to call the Culinary Institute.
Rym: Yeah, we do.
Rym: Well, yeah, I got to see what they learn in their class.
Rym: We should pull.
Scott: we should pull multiple chefs and get their opinion.
Scott: I was always told by Like nine out of ten dentists to prove of this toothpaste.
Scott: How many chefs out of how many say you should tell the right Ma's and Ma's?
Rym: Told me to tear it as did Charles in charge.
Rym: the internet seems to think that it doesn't matter.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Anyway, whatever.
Scott: So yeah What do you think of lettuce in a bag?
Scott: I?
Rym: Used to buy that when I didn't have a lot of time to cook but fuck that now.
Rym: See now I always get all fresh everything and prepare the salad entirely from scratch.
Scott: when I was growing up My mom had mad Tupperware including this green bowl a special green bowl that you could put a head of lettuce in.
Rym: Yeah, guess what?
Rym: We got one of those.
Scott: now if you bought lettuce that comes in head shape We got one and if you put lettuce in that bowl, it stayed good for so fucking long.
Scott: It was amazing.
Scott: that's like this incredible green Tupperware bowl that they don't make anymore.
Scott: and Because I didn't have that bowl and whenever I bought some kind of lettuce It went bad pretty quick even though iceberg lettuce for a dollar is the cheapest even romaine lettuce, right?
Scott: It's like buying it's the cheapest way even in like a escarole or something.
Scott: But and had the bowls lettuce went bad so fast.
Scott: Okay These people bought lettuce in a bag to avoid, you know.
Scott: So I'd spend less money and use more lettuce and be more efficient.
Scott: But when it once I got out of college, I went on eBay.
Scott: I bought that motherfucking bowl.
Scott: Sadly, I as my no more bag lettuce for me.
Rym: I really like iceberg lettuce, but which is you know the head?
Rym: Yeah, unlike like green leaf lettuce, like I can't put in a bowl like that cuz it's long big Yep, and lately I've been getting Batavian lettuce was just like this monster.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: It's good.
Scott: You can put other non head lettuce.
Scott: I mean there are lettuces that are sort of head like like the escarole is sort of like a. you know It's a different shape, but it's still a head.
Scott: true You can put a cabbage in there.
Rym: But the problem is I can feed the rabbits because we have to feed the rabbits fresh greens.
Rym: So we've alternate from the parsley and cilantro and lettuces and all these things.
Rym: Uh Rabbits can't eat iceberg lettuce because it's got too much cellulose and we'll give them gas and get basically a hundred percent cellulose.
Scott: It might as well be celery in leaf form and as a kid.
Rym: I always had this perception that Iceberg lettuce was like the bad lettuce like iceberg.
Scott: It's not a bad.
Rym: Let's just a general that no not bad like taste bad like not as good for you as other lettuces.
Scott: It's just as good for you as other lettuces.
Scott: That's actually debatable But it's a generic lettuce.
Scott: right?
Rym: iceberg lettuce is the lettuce that you use to make a salad.
Rym: that's primarily consisting of cheese and Meat and croutons and dressing.
Scott: Yeah, is it like bears the most weight and it has the most water going on Like.
Scott: I was never much better for sandwiches and other lettuces.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: It is the same as the kind of sandwich sandwich though, right?
Scott: Some what?
Scott: sometimes you make a sandwich and you want those those lettuces that are just like leaves.
Scott: You know like I do that you know, it feels like you're eating a tree Kind of sandwich chunk of romaine just across the entire sandwich.
Scott: in that case see I like doing that flavor wise But often it creates this surface for things just slide off of.
Rym: ah, you're stacking incorrectly You didn't?
Scott: you never worked at the Bellas But lettuce at the bottom things drip into it and then the romaine has this chute down the middle and all this lettuce goes on Top.
Scott: No, this goes.
Rym: lettuce goes at the very top It goes in the bottom.
Rym: lettuce goes on the top.
Scott: bottom.
Scott: You.
Scott: basically you make a salad on your on top of the bread and then you put the meat and cheese on top of that.
Rym: You don't know shit about making sandwich.
Scott: I do know shit.
Rym: We gotta do Sean sandwiches.
Scott: Okay next Thursday Thursday is no longer whatever night.
Scott: It's no longer the lounge now food night.
Rym: But here's the difference.
Rym: if I use iceberg lettuce may have done sandwiches already.
Rym: I'm gonna put some creamy ass Dressing on oh for sure if I use because it's watery dressing.
Rym: It's already so watery I would never put oil and vinegar on that.
Scott: oil Just slide right off like a friggin slip and slide.
Rym: oil and vinegar is if the individual lettuces had care.
Scott: Yeah oil and vinegar has got to go on a salad where the lettuce can actually like absorb some of that maybe An iceberg.
Scott: it just nothing sticks to that.
Scott: It just goes if you put oil and vinegar You're gonna get a pool of oil and vinegar at the bottom of the bowl.
Scott: You won't eat.
Rym: well oil and vinegar is got to be used.
Rym: if the salad is an appetizer or not the main meal and if the salad consists primarily of greens that are themselves high quality It's got to be a salad that would taste good with no dressing Yep, because then the oil and vinegar is just an enhancement to that.
Rym: Otherwise, perfect salad.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But if I'm making a you know big ol like Rym is hungry and this salad is dinner then the salad actually consists mostly of meat and the lettuce is basically just A vehicle to make me feel a little less bad about eating a bowl of me.
Scott: I actually almost never put meat on a salad.
Scott: The only time I get me in the salad is like if it's like, you know Make that myself.
Scott: I'll only get that at places.
Rym: I'll make that a lot usually for dinner like if the salad is dinner.
Scott: But I should do that like if I make a steak.
Scott: I should just make two steaks and then instead of just usually I'll use the leftover to make a sandwich.
Scott: I should cut the leftover up and make a salad.
Scott: I just don't think to do that, but that's a good idea.
Rym: So I also put I always get a little bit of like arugula or cilantro and arugula is real good.
Rym: And arugula is great, but don't make the mistake of thinking.
Rym: Hey, I like arugula.
Rym: I'll make a small side salad.
Rym: This is 100% arugula.
Rym: Wrong.
Scott: Bad news.
Scott: Notice, you know, it's okay to use 100% iceberg 100% romaine.
Scott: Those other kinds of lettuces usually got to be mixed in.
Rym: Yeah, like dandelion greens.
Rym: if you put more than one big ol green of dandelion in your salad that thing tastes like bitter shit.
Scott: Yeah, that's why I don't eat it at all because it's nasty.
Scott: It's not food either.
Rym: I don't know what your problem is with dandelion greens.
Rym: It's not food.
Scott: Dandelion greens are delicious But then you just said it was bitter shit.
Scott: Yeah, which one is it?
Rym: So are most of the kinds of green vegetables that you saute.
Scott: Yeah, don't eat that shit or saute it first, right?
Scott: Especially Kale spinach.
Rym: don't eat raw kale.
Rym: you motherfuckers.
Scott: people be kale's like this huge trending motherfucker.
Scott: That shit is poison.
Scott: Yo, so is spinach.
Scott: unless you cook it It's loaded with this acid called oxalic acid.
Rym: Spinach is not as bad.
Scott: spinach is actually worse.
Rym: Well, because people don't eat as much of it, you know, you don't make a whole salad with nothing but spinach.
Scott: obviously The point is it tastes great.
Scott: I'm not gonna deny that Kale and even worse spinach in their raw forms contain a ton of oxalic acid Which is just straight-up bad for you.
Scott: the same way that like trans fat is bad for you, right?
Scott: It's just bad.
Scott: There's nothing good about eating that acid.
Scott: So if you want to eat kale or spinach, you should either eat a very small quantity of it raw like, okay There's a couple spinach leaves in your salad.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: You won't die big deal, right?
Scott: I've eaten.
Scott: I eat red meat.
Scott: That's bad for you, too.
Scott: But don't eat a big huge pile of kale.
Scott: I see salad put at these salad places that are 100% kale raw not good.
Rym: Those people always get the same thing.
Rym: They order like a kale and quinoa blend as possible salad.
Rym: Yeah, I hate quinoa.
Rym: It's quinoa.
Scott: I think it depends.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm gonna call it for non quinoa Because I don't care.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: It's bad.
Scott: It doesn't taste good.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's the kind of thing that people eat out of obligate.
Scott: They like they like liking it.
Rym: I should eat something healthy and I've noticed that with salads to a lot of people.
Rym: I believe that this is healthy despite any evidence suggesting so I think a lot of people Would prefer to eat a salad comprised and mostly of ranch dressing and croutons.
Scott: It's called a Caesar salad, but except that Caesar dressing.
Rym: But they will eat oil and vinegar on a bland salad Because they they perceive that it's better for them or they don't want to be seen as the person eating the ridiculously fatty salad.
Scott: I think they just believe it's better for them.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time if you don't like marketing works don't get that on your salad.
Rym: if you like ranch dressing go for it.
Rym: unless you're fat then don't.
Scott: If you're fat, no get it.
Scott: It's these.
Scott: you're eating a salad and not McDonald's.
Rym: I could construct a salad That's way worse for you than any hamburger.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Meat in every salad.
Scott: You're putting a hamburger in your salad.
Scott: That's where I grew up in the Midwest.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, my salads rarely contain meat.
Rym: Actually, usually I'll do a lot of cheese and nuts and not meat because I've been cutting a lot of meat.
Scott: I know it's also rarely contain cheese.
Rym: Uh It's very rare.
Rym: I will not put cheese in my salad unless the salad is just an appetizer.
Rym: Not even not an appetizer.
Scott: I do enjoy cheese.
Scott: So if it's just a side dish like I have the partition plate like when you go to a diner and there's like like Cheddar and whatever in the salad.
Scott: That's real good.
Scott: I love that shit a cubed or shredded.
Scott: I like the shredded because then you can sort of mix it up a lot more especially with a carrot shredded.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Rym: I've noticed Emily doesn't like the same kind of salad I do like.
Rym: I make really over-the-top salads.
Rym: But the problem is I think I like croutons and sunflowers way more.
Scott: you like croutons, huh?
Scott: You don't say yeah.
Rym: Well, I mean, they're basically advanced crackers.
Scott: I also like root does but only in salad.
Rym: why?
Rym: Why arbitrarily limit yourself join me?
Rym: It's not an arbitrary limit It is the very definition of an arbitrary.
Scott: I just eat ketchup then it tastes great because that's the condiment.
Scott: So are croutons.
Scott: They're a salad condiment.
Rym: Uh, no, they're not because you can eat them on their own.
Scott: You you can eat ketchup on its own.
Rym: You shouldn't.
Scott: you shouldn't eat croutons on their own either.
Rym: What about if you crumble up crackers into your salad suddenly you're not allowed to eat crack?
Scott: That's only because you didn't have croutons.
Scott: cuz you suck.
Rym: That is true Don't?
Rym: every times in my life when I was a kid I would like make a salad like in high school.
Rym: I can come home didn't have any fucking crew time, but I'd make the salad first and I assume we have croutons.
Rym: I reach in there's no croutons and you assume then I'm like going through the whole house looking for like anything crunchy to put in that salad.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I Really actually like the crunchily onions, but I never keep them around.
Rym: so Don't think we should really talk about.
Scott: I was just thinking about those two seconds ago.
Rym: I love those things.
Scott: gonna buy some on the way home.
Rym: Oh my gosh.
Scott: So I don't need hot dogs for dinner.
Rym: And I feel like we should not talk about the other branch of salads of potato salads.
Rym: in the light.
Rym: That's a separate show mean potato salad chicken salad.
Scott: The other thing is I'm not really into a lot of those.
Rym: I am increasingly into them and I've always always like potato salad because that goes if you go to a garden party in the Midwest plus someone's bringing a ranch dressing heavy chef salad and the same person usually brings Potatoes.
Scott: the reason I don't like a lot of those is because most of them tend to just be a bunch of stuff all mixed up Basically drowned in mayonnaise.
Scott: and I'm yeah, not big on man.
Scott: I'm big on mayonnaise pasta salad.
Scott: I love pasta not big on pasta salad.
Rym: I just made a pesto pasta salad with pine nuts the other day.
Scott: Oh, I still could be good.
Scott: It's not like a boy.
Scott: It's not mayonnaise.
Rym: Yeah, make a pesto pasta salad sometime.
Scott: That could be good right fucking amazing.
Scott: It was great.
Rym: Here's the secret.
Rym: But however much butter you think you're gonna use when you're less more.
Rym: Yeah, just butter it up.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's great I don't like.
Scott: but sometimes you get that pasta salad.
Scott: It's like pasta and some vegetables and some potato bits all drowned in mayonnaise and the pot it's cold.
Scott: now because they cook the pasta It's supposed to be cold.
Scott: Yeah, I don't not a big into that.
Scott: Yeah, right I want the pasta at least be warm and drowned in something.
Scott: That's not mayonnaise.
Rym: Sometimes I'll live dangerously.
Rym: instead of using hard-boiled eggs I'll use deviled eggs Not big into any.
Rym: I don't know what's up with you and eggs.
Scott: I like eggs.
Scott: I just don't like weird.
Rym: So tomatoes.
Rym: what tomato do you use?
Scott: Oh for a salad?
Rym: Yeah Depends on the salad because I used to not know better when I was young.
Rym: and I just get the beefsteak tomatoes.
Rym: No, what's that?
Scott: That's for sandwiches lately.
Rym: I only I pretty much only use Zima's or like heirloom cherry tomatoes.
Scott: Okay, so sometimes I'll you.
Scott: obviously if you have a tomato you grew yourself like a cherry tomato.
Scott: That's a great ago.
Scott: Okay, any tomato you grew yourself just tastes better than any tomato.
Scott: you combine this for sure, right?
Scott: There is a brand of tomato they have at the store that's expensive that actually tastes almost as good as backyard tomato.
Scott: So you can buy that and just shell out the money.
Scott: That's also.
Rym: if you're doing that just buy any tomatoes.
Scott: I think it's like a cherry tomato or a grape tomato or something like that but by the ones that are not red.
Rym: because though basically from what I've read read the The things that make tomatoes taste good and the same and the jeans that make tomatoes red.
Rym: Nah, there's a there's like a negative alignment there.
Rym: So if you breed tomatoes to look good, they don't taste good.
Scott: Yep Also, you know a plum tomatoes not bad because you can sort of cut it up nicely and the tomatoes on the vine are usually More expensive, but there's usually reason for that.
Rym: Yeah, then the grocery store.
Scott: I found they're not as good and also those bends of the grocery store Like one grocery store near me has so many different kinds of tomatoes and they are all horrible.
Scott: and the other store You know has like.
Scott: the thing is you tend to lean towards the tomatoes that are just sort of out in the open.
Scott: They always had the prepackaged ones and they're always sort of suspicious.
Scott: but actually those are usually really good.
Scott: They just cost a lot more.
Rym: I found if I'm making like a garden salad What I'll usually do is take moderately sized like holding my hand tomatoes and I'll cut them into like fifths wedges.
Rym: I'll put the wedges just in the salad.
Scott: Yeah, that's what you gotta do wedges.
Scott: I also cut the wedges in half to make like mini pyramids.
Rym: No because I found if I do that Usually it's too mushy and watery.
Scott: Well, that's not you got to get a tomato that has more structure to it.
Scott: Not one that's all full of water, but usually the watery ones taste better.
Scott: No, the structurally ones taste better.
Rym: But if I'm making a child, I like tomato.
Scott: I like tomato flesh.
Scott: I don't really like tomato water and seeds.
Rym: if I'm doing the chop toss salad What I'll do is not let this might seem like overkill, but it's worth it I'll get cherry tomatoes or the Zima tomatoes like the little ones the orange ones and I'll cut them all in half.
Rym: That's a good idea because then you get the benefit of both worlds.
Rym: Mm-hmm Yeah Occasionally, I'll do celery but I find that celery doesn't add a lot to the salad.
Scott: No, I don't buy celery.
Scott: too often you all it's mostly cuz you have to buy so much celery.
Rym: Yeah, and I never.
Rym: I use like two stalks of it and then the rest gets.
Scott: I'll have to just eat celery straight up to Finish it all I know.
Rym: and I don't like eating celery straight up.
Scott: I like it in like soup carrot pro tip instead of buying like the you know carrots in a bag or Baby care.
Rym: why baby carrots are not baby carrots as regular carrots cut down to look like baby care.
Scott: We know that God you all didn't I were you go to the actual vegetable section.
Scott: You can buy the big motherfucking.
Scott: care careful.
Rym: Careful.
Rym: The ain't the larger a carrot is the inside is usually kind of bitter.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: I like the bigger.
Scott: to me at least the big carrot tastes way better than any of the carrots They have.
Rym: I like to get the baby carrot.
Rym: That's actually a baby.
Scott: can I usually buy two big carrots?
Scott: And I'll use one for salad.
Scott: just eat the other one.
Rym: Well, if I get a big carrot, I shred it into the salad.
Scott: No, I just instead of cutting it I cut the carrot and even though it goes from small to big so it's hard to cut evenly.
Scott: now Technique where you rotate the carrot so all your carrot bits are equally sized.
Scott: As long as do it right or what?
Rym: I'll do is I'll get the moderately to bigger sized carrots And if I don't even I don't want to shred it What I can do is I can chop it pretty fine or I'll slice it is usually pretty good.
Rym: or if I really want to Go nuts.
Rym: I'll take that carrot and put it on the mandolin and just make like nice thin long carrot strip
Scott: something else You can do just take your peeler peel the carrot
Rym: and then keep peeling it
Scott: And then once it's peeled go over to the salad bowl and peel peel peel.
Scott: Yeah Julianne.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I'm big fan of the carrots.
Rym: I'll put those in almost everything.
Rym: I'm a big fan of the nuts to like sunflower and walnuts.
Scott: walnut is good.
Rym: Sunflower seed maybe depends on the salad again.
Scott: Walnut is really like the ultimate salad nut.
Scott: It's also one of the best nuts period.
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Rym: I just got new walnuts for salad.
Scott: like you don't put a peanut in a salad.
Rym: my thing lately I haven't especially when it's like cooler out is I like to make a?
Rym: That's like a lot of different kinds of greens.
Rym: Maybe no tomatoes at all really finely chopped peppers goat cheese oil and vinegar.
Scott: The thing with that kind of salad is there's something psychological about having a lot of different colors in the salad.
Scott: I don't like.
Rym: that's why I put ready a red Decio in the salad even though it doesn't add a lot of flavor.
Scott: even if the salad as is amazing if it's like all green It's sort of like I can't.
Scott: it's hard to eat I like.
Rym: that's why I gotta eat the carrot the tomato, you know peppers that are different color I'm telling you get to get a radicchio and just cut a little bit of it into every salad.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: I just went to Wikipedia and the fourth heading here is toxicity.
Scott: Uh So don't eat right, that's that's if you use chicory in Coffee, we know the chicory is poison.
Rym: I like chicory though.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yeah Blah-blah chicory farms, whatever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Riccio is good in salads.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: It's a little bitter but not as bitter as like dandelions.
Rym: Alright, I kind of wanna make a salad now.
Scott: Yeah, I'm hungry.
Scott: I got a dinner feeling salad.
Rym: We did a food show.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, I think if I had to pick a salad though That's my favorite as much.
Rym: I like as much as I appreciate and really enjoy the simple artistic salad.
Rym: That's mostly the vegetables themselves with the right amount of oil and the right amount of the right kind of vinegar Maybe a little bit of lemon just sort of squeezed over it.
Rym: The salads that I enjoy the most are the ones that are just a big old fucking cob salad.
Rym: That's mostly meat like.
Rym: I'm not gonna pretend that it's not my favorite kind of salad.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: Yes, isn't it?
Scott: I Say anyone for tennis Cat.