Rym: It's Wednesday, May 21st, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, Sailor Moon.
Rym: Because Scott had actually never seen any of it until now.
Scott: I saw some.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Also known as Bishoujo Senshi Sailor Moon.
Scott: I meant you should have said that instead of any of the other stuff you said.
Rym: Instead of what other stuff?
Scott: You should have just said tonight, Bishoujo Senshi Sailor Moon.
Rym: Oh, you're still mad about me doing long openers?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: You're still mad about that?
Scott: Are you trying to make up for the openers you're not doing because you're in Europe?
Rym: They've got to be just long enough to make it through the pre-canned opening scroll that I got in the audio.
Scott: You know, you can use a smaller can, right?
Scott: If you only get so many beans, put them in a half-size tin.
Rym: No, double tin.
Rym: Double it up.
Rym: I should release a DVD of just GeekNights openers.
Scott: Do whatever you're going to do.
Rym: So yeah, there's a limited time for this, but if you're an anime fan, which I assume you are, why else would you listen to?
Rym: GeekNights Wednesdays, which was once the easiest GeekNights to do, is now increasingly the second most...
Scott: I've watched a ton of animes.
Scott: Which one would you like to talk about that you haven't watched?
Rym: Here's the trouble.
Rym: How many animes have we collectively watched?
Rym: if we reviewed all of them?
Rym: That'd get us a month.
Rym: Two months of shows.
Scott: We only do like two anime shows a month at most.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You gotta watch like one or two anime a month to make GeekNights happen.
Rym: Yep, but we gotta watch enough to properly review them.
Scott: It's enough.
Rym: But anyway, if you're an anime fan at all, you know that other than pretty much Kill La Kill and Madoka Magica, the last great anime was Ghost in the Shell Standalone Complex.
Rym: I have since second gig and...
Scott: Not counting movies.
Rym: Yeah, not counting movies.
Rym: Pretty much all I've wanted out of anime.
Rym: Though Kill La Kill kept me going.
Rym: And though Madoka kept me going, and there were other good shows along the way, I pretty much just want more Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: So, as you know, there is more Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: It's not done yet.
Rym: Arise is still ongoing.
Rym: It's kind of a prequel, a little bit of style change.
Scott: It's one of those OAV kind of things, like Gundam UC, where I was planning to wait for it to all be done and then watch it.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: Well, Gundam UC is done now, so I'm gonna watch it.
Rym: But there are also... We have conflicting policies of watch any anime that's in a theater in New York.
Scott: Right, so Arise is gonna be in a theater in New York.
Rym: Borders 1 and 2 are being screened in New York, Atlanta, Cambridge, Baltimore, Alexandria, and like 12 other cities on May 29th, which is next Thursday.
Scott: It's using this weird system where enough people have to want to go in order for it to happen.
Rym: It's like Kickstarter just for a movie screening.
Scott: So it's like in some of the cities, not enough people signed up for it, so it's not gonna get screened.
Rym: Yeah, so if you want to see this, the deadline is in days.
Scott: I wonder if we can use this and get things we want to watch in the movie theater.
Rym: Huh.
Rym: Attack the gas station.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Something like that.
Rym: I think I could get a couple hundred people to come and watch that.
Rym: I don't know if I ever want to watch Ebola Syndrome again.
Scott: I don't either, but if I put it on the website, maybe other people will subject themselves to it by accident.
Rym: I wonder if it's just on YouTube or something.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: I can believe that.
Rym: Ebola Syndrome might literally be the most abhorrent piece of fiction I've ever watched or consumed in any way beginning to end.
Scott: That is 100% correct.
Rym: The only reason that is true.
Scott: I can't even begin to think of anything, not even shit like Apocalypse Zero.
Rym: Apocalypse Zero is basically a children's anime compared to Ebola Syndrome.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: E.G.
Rym: the Killer is a romp through the park.
Rym: Oh, Ebola Syndrome.
Rym: But the only reason it's the most important thing I've ever seen all the way through is because I did walk out of Martin Short's Clifford.
Rym: So yes, go buy tickets to this.
Rym: If you go to the one in New York, well, we're going.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: You can say hi.
Scott: I imagine the same people I see at every- If you're tall, don't sit in front of me.
Rym: Every screen of anime we ever go to in New York City, we see the same people at every time.
Rym: I imagine those people will all be there.
Rym: If you want to join Anime New York, go to the screening.
Rym: Everyone in line is going to be awesome.
Scott: Alright, in other news, the show that we're going to talk about in our main bit, Sailor Moon, is back.
Scott: Now we all knew there was going to be a new Sailor Moon series, Sailor Moon Crystal, something, something, whatever, right?
Scott: And people have been waiting for it and it's been delayed and teased and all kinds of- Not just delayed, but delayed with no information, no art, no trailers, nothing.
Scott: Suddenly, probably the biggest news in U.S.
Scott: anime, you know, period, has happened, right?
Scott: Sailor Moon, the whole thing, I don't know anything about movies, but all the TV serieses, right?
Scott: Are being subbed, and new dubbed, and released, uncut in the original Japanese form, on the internet, and DVD, and buray.
Rym: Original, uncropped, 4x3.
Scott: In order, nothing missing, starting already.
Rym: I like how this website I'm looking at makes a special point to say, yes, that includes Sailor Stars.
Scott: Yep, everything, the whole deal.
Scott: It's like, it's happening.
Rym: No, it's interesting, because this is more the news bit.
Rym: There is a small, but not trivial, backlash against this.
Scott: Well, it's the same as like, right?
Scott: So, most people who are like Sailor Moon are like, I mean, I'm excited about this.
Rym: Sailor Moon is a pretty fucking important anime, both in Japan and the United States.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, people, you know, like in the United States, it's like because it was on TV, right?
Scott: That's the reason it's a big deal.
Scott: But you think, oh, is it one of those shows, like in Japan, no one gives a shit about Sailor Moon, and in the U.S.
Scott: it was a big deal, just because it was the only one that made it on TV.
Rym: Yeah, it introduced the concept of a magical girl to most of the non-Japan world.
Scott: Right, but in Japan, it's like, wait a minute, if this show wasn't a big deal in Japan, like, say, Cowboy Bebop isn't that big a deal in Japan, why are there like four different seasons with 200-something episodes?
Scott: Oh, because it was a big deal in Japan.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: In fact, it was a big deal around the world.
Rym: Sailor Moon is one of those iconic, recognizable characters where everyone knows what it is.
Scott: Yep, it's like Hokuto no Ken big worldwide, right?
Rym: -Yep.
Scott: -So, this is a big deal.
Scott: So, if you didn't watch Sailor Moon back in the day, now is the Sailor Moon time.
Scott: It is the revival of Sailor Moons.
Scott: So, we're doing a Sailor Moon show.
Rym: Yep, but what is interesting is that I was previously going to say probably not worth watching all of the old Sailor Moon, because I've watched all of it.
Scott: -Why not watch all of it?
Rym: -Multiple times.
Rym: Now I'm older and I have a lot more free time to watch these long--.
Rym: When I was younger, I couldn't really deal with a lot of--.
Rym: Ah, but I fly around a lot.
Rym: Do you know how many movies I've watched in the last two weeks?
Scott: The way I view it, right, is.
Scott: it looks like they're going to be putting out more-- releasing episodes in order every Monday, right?
Scott: So, basically, it's like if I just have nothing the fuck to do, and I can't go outside, and I can not at work, and it's just like I got 20 minutes with nothing, Sailor Moon.
Rym: -You know what?
Scott: -And eventually I'll see it all.
Rym: Having just watched the first two episodes again, it's kind of worth watching.
Scott: -Anyway.
Rym: -It's actually a pretty good show.
Scott: For what it is.
Scott: But yeah, all the Sailor Moon that was beneath the surface has now risen to the top, like a giant mountain above all other animes.
Rym: I guess that means I don't need to dig out my VCR to be able to watch my Vkill fansubs.
Scott: No, we can sell all that shit.
Rym: Actually, I was looking around to find some info to see if the guy who did those was still around, and I found a number of people who are desperate to buy them, not to watch, but just to have as collector's items.
Scott: All right, sell it off, make some money.
Rym: Because this guy was pretty fucking serious about it.
Rym: -Back in the day...
Scott: -Make some dough.
Rym: Because it's not really relevant to the show itself.
Rym: I guess I'll tell this story now.
Rym: As you guys know, I've been watching anime for pretty much literally my entire life.
Rym: Since I was a little kid, my mom made me watch Vampire Under D. Anime, anime, anime.
Rym: So by the time Sailor Moon was on American TV, and I was watching it, I was already old hat into anime.
Rym: High school was when Cartoon Network had their big rebirth, because they brought out Sailor Moon R.
Scott: I could see Sailor Moon in middle school because it was syndicated on the broadcast.
Rym: It was, but that was only the first season.
Rym: Of course, heavily edited.
Rym: And then Sailor Moon R, the next one, has two halves.
Rym: These Alan and Anne, aliens in a tree from space do their thing.
Rym: And then there's the second half.
Rym: that's all Prince Diamond and those assholes.
Rym: They only ever aired the first half on Cartoon Network when, at least originally, when they were like, "Hey, we got more Sailor Moon.
Rym: You can watch more than just what you saw as a kid.
Rym: Oh my
Rym: gosh.".
Rym: But even then, anime was old hat.
Rym: So I knew at that point about anime.
Rym: I knew information.
Rym: I knew there were clubs out there.
Rym: I knew there were fan subs.
Rym: And I had some friends who were also really into Sailor Moon.
Rym: I really wanted to see.
Rym: what I heard was the crazy crap that happens later.
Rym: And I knew a decent bit about it.
Rym: So I did the thing that you did back in the day.
Rym: Bought a bunch of really high-quality VHS tapes.
Rym: And I mailed them to a guy along with a check.
Rym: And he mailed me back really nice clam shells.
Rym: Like big, heavy, thick white clam shells with laser-printed, full-color, high-resolution images from the laser discs on them.
Rym: These things were way high production values.
Rym: Every - I keep saying "thinking disc".
Rym: - Every VHS tape had its own edge label and its own side label.
Rym: Again, printed high quality.
Rym: All of Sailor Moon.
Rym: Every bit of it.
Scott: - With subtitles.
Rym: - Yes, with subtitles.
Rym: - Good subtitles.
Rym: - Mastered with his fucking genlock machine from the laser disc masters that he had and the translation he did himself.
Rym: Vkill seems to have been kind of a legend among Sailor Moon fans.
Scott: That guy had so little to do that he sat there and made those tapes for you.
Scott: And how many other people?
Rym: Apparently a lot of people.
Scott: That guy was just sitting there making tapes all day.
Rym: That was what anime fandom was.
Scott: How many VCRs the fuck did that guy have?
Rym: That is what anime conventions were until, what, the year 2001?
Scott: But anyway, there's some people in the community, right, who were like, "Ah, this is
Scott: awful!".
Scott: Because they are like Robotech people, where they - it's like, you know, a lot of those shows that were originally brought to the US were fucked the fuck up.
Scott: Like, Robotech, they changed everyone's name and combined three shows into one.
Scott: And Sailor Moon, they changed people's names and cut shit out, right?
Scott: And some people, it's like their nostalgia is for that edited American crappy version.
Scott: And they don't like the original version.
Scott: They're like, "No, you're ruining it.
Scott: Her name is not Usagi.
Rym: Ah, ah,
Rym: ah.".
Rym: These people will refer to - her name's not, you know, we're not gonna - they shouldn't be using the other name, which we won't actually write out in English characters because that disrespects the ancient power of the Japanese language.
Rym: It's not - Usagi is just our rough interpretation of that word.
Rym: Weaboos amaze me to a degree that sometimes surprises me.
Scott: It's hilarious.
Scott: That's all there is to it.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: But little known fact, that guy, he subbed a couple other things.
Scott: Evangelion?
Rym: He subbed End of Evangelion, which I watched without having seen Evangelion, not even knowing it was related.
Rym: And he subbed, I think, the Tokimeki Memorial, like, OAV special?
Scott: It had anime?
Scott: I thought it was just an SNES game at first.
Rym: Was it Tokimeki or was it - no, it was Two Heart.
Rym: It was one of those dating shows, whatever.
Scott: Two Heart came way later, digital subs.
Scott: That was one of the early digital ones.
Rym: Yeah, but he did one of those dating game type things, had a show, and he did it as part of everything else he did.
Rym: And since I was getting all of Sailor Moon, I just got everything he'd ever fan-subed, which was Sailor Moon plus those handful of other things.
Rym: But first, things of the day.
Rym: So, you guys know we're really into Counter-Strike, and while we're old - I haven't played Counter-Strike in a long time.
Rym: I don't know why not.
Rym: Counter-Strike is great right now.
Scott: I'm busy.
Rym: Busy doing what?
Rym: You can play some Counter-Strike.
Rym: Doing other shit.
Rym: What games are you playing lately?
Scott: Uh, video games?
Rym: Yeah, what video games are you playing?
Scott: None.
Scott: None video games.
Rym: You should play some video games.
Rym: We've had some - so, GeekNights actually has an official Counter-Strike server, and you know what?
Scott: It's still up?
Scott: People still go there?
Scott: People have been playing there.
Rym: Really?
Scott: In fact, we just had - Listeners or just random internet people?
Rym: Uh, listeners.
Scott: Really?
Rym: We had - it's all talk.
Rym: It's set up for our use.
Rym: It's an awesome server.
Rym: So, we've been playing a bunch of Counter-Strike there, and it's super fun.
Rym: It's amazing how it's the air hockey problem.
Rym: I'm way better than pretty much most of the listeners.
Scott: I'm probably garbage now.
Rym: You were always garbage.
Scott: I was not always garbage.
Rym: You were never that good at Counter-Strike.
Rym: I'm not gonna lie.
Scott: I was that good, just how that - You were okay.
Scott: I was good at a point.
Rym: You were good when the P90 was OP.
Scott: There were also times, right?
Scott: I wouldn't be consistently good, but I would have one in five matches.
Scott: Moment of greatness.
Rym: There would be that moment where you just randomly flip around and click, and then you headshot a guy across the map, and you're like, "I'm gonna do
Rym: that.".
Scott: That happens a couple times, but also, there would be days where I'm really good today.
Scott: Or when we were at PAX Prime, and I think we played with Conrad, and I was mowing everyone down with a parrot.
Scott: I think there was something about that mouse.
Scott: The sensitivity was just right.
Rym: That's why you buy a really good mouse.
Scott: I have a really good mouse.
Scott: For some reason, I don't know what sensitivity they had that one set on.
Rym: So we talk a lot about head-clicking and about games of skill, and we're just talking about mouse, and how the mouse is so important to Counter-Strike.
Rym: So this gentleman killed you with a wheel.
Rym: He puts up a video where he ends the debate between what is better for Counter-Strike, a gamepad or a mouse and keyboard, by using a wheel.
Rym: And the opening of the video was so great, because he goes into the console while music is building up to it, and he types, "Joystick
Rym: 1.".
Rym: Uh-oh.
Rym: And then his only goal is to not be in last place.
Rym: This is amazing to behold.
Rym: They even have their own song.
Scott: ♪ Killed you with a wheel.
Rym: ♪ ♪ Killed you with a wheel.
Rym: ♪ ♪ Headshot with the wheel.
Scott: ♪.
Scott: You kind of need to get a headshot with the wheel.
Scott: The biggest problem with the wheel is you can't go up and down, so if a guy's far away or too close, you can't get him.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But if he's just right, oh, watch out.
Rym: But you're watching, like, trying to hit some people, and it's just almost painful to watch, but because there's a wheel there, it's great.
Scott: All right, so Florida Man, notorious for drugs, disorderly public conduct, and many other bad behaviors.
Rym: There's a reason FARC has a tag for only one state.
Scott: Yeah, you might wonder -- and there's a Twitter account, Florida Man -- you might be wondering, "What does Florida Man do when he's not either making meth and exploding it and killing
Scott: himself?"
Scott: Or consuming meth.
Scott: Or using meth.
Scott: Or bath salts or whatever.
Scott: have you.
Rym: Bath meth.
Scott: You'd probably go scuba diving because Florida's kind of warm and nice, and if you're in the water, you're far away from the other Florida people.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's why people swim in Florida.
Scott: Right, but of course, because so many Florida Men just die and float out to sea, it attracts certain dangerous animals that this Florida Man had to contend with in this pretty good video, which looks like it was shot with a GoPro, so watch it.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: Florida Man succeeds.
Scott: They should have this Florida Man take out all the other Florida Men.
Rym: Well, he's got that spear gun.
Scott: A few million enter, one man leaves.
Rym: In the meantime, the Book Club book is A Canticle for Leibowitz.
Scott: I started reading it.
Rym: I will read it soon.
Scott: It's got Jews in it.
Rym: Oh, oh, oh.
Rym: You think?
Scott: You don't see Jews in the sci-fi too often as a nerdy Jew.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: You know, that is kind of true.
Rym: There are a couple of characters that exhibit some of the stereotypes that you're thinking of right now, Scad, in the culture books.
Rym: You don't say?
Rym: Nah, a few.
Rym: But, yeah, not many sci-fi characters named Leibowitz.
Rym: All this one.
Scott: You don't say?
Rym: Our forum's awesome.
Rym: YouTube's awesome.
Rym: Lots of videos coming soon.
Rym: I'm not going to Hong Kong next week.
Rym: I wheedled my way out of it, so I'm going to try to edit up the GeekNights Presents Utena.
Rym: We've got two more episodes to upload.
Scott: If you ever do go to Hong Kong, I should give you a list of electronic things to acquire and bring back.
Rym: I'm going to come back with a suitcase full of all the things.
Rym: You know how many HDMI splitters, DRM removers?
Scott: I'm talking about bigger things than that.
Scott: You can get camera lenses and all that kind of shit.
Scott: Stuff that's more expensive, but it's still cheaper there and often available there, but not available here.
Rym: Things that I legally have to pay a duty on if I bring back into the United States.
Scott: Also, bootleg things, right?
Scott: I was watching some photo videos online.
Rym: They can confiscate your bootlegs at the border.
Scott: Whatever, but it's like these guys, they're in Hong Kong, right?
Scott: They're like, "Okay, here's a camera challenge.
Scott: Take pictures using this flash,".
Scott: and it's the Fuke 960.
Scott: No, it was the Fuke 690, that's what it was.
Scott: F-U-Q 690.
Scott: It was just some cheap flash that you can get on the street in Hong Kong, and it's like, "That's so cheap,
Scott: though.".
Scott: If I had three of those, instead of one really good one...
Rym: Instead of one good camera, I'd buy 12 terrible cameras.
Scott: But the guy did amazing shit with those flashes, because they work, right?
Scott: And it's cheaper than getting real ones, right?
Scott: No.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Sailor Moon.
Scott: Oh, we're already talking about Sailor Moon?
Scott: We're not talking about conventions you should go to?
Rym: You should go to ConnectiCon.
Rym: It's the next big convention we're going to.
Scott: Keep pressing F5 while you're listening to this podcast.
Rym: Penny Arcade Expo badges will go on sale, I'm pretty sure.
Rym: My guess is tomorrow.
Scott: We're on orange alert right now for PAX Prime tickets.
Rym: My guess is tomorrow, Thursday, May 22nd.
Scott: Probably today for most of us.
Rym: My second guess is Monday.
Scott: Yeah, they wouldn't fuck us on Friday.
Rym: Well, the website went down today for a minute, and for a second I thought, maybe I shouldn't tell anyone but my close friends.
Scott: Everyone in the world knows.
Scott: There's no secret keeping here.
Rym: There's a Reddit thread longer than any thread in the GeekNights forums within seconds of that going down.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: You're pretty much fucked if you want to go to PAX.
Scott: And to think, his award, a lot of people, their method of finding out is they've got a notification on the official PAX account, so whenever it tweets, they get a mobile notification.
Rym: Yeah, you're going to get a notification if the badges are sold out.
Scott: That shit is delayed one to three minutes, yo.
Scott: In that time, you're going to be locked out.
Rym: You might get a Monday and a Sunday badge.
Scott: If you're super lucky, you might get the four one days.
Rym: But you're definitely not going to be staying in the Sheraton or the Red Line.
Scott: Hell no.
Rym: What was that fucking hotel we stayed in?
Rym: PAX dev was like here.
Scott: The serviceable, but kind of annoyingly far away hotel.
Rym: Well, the thing is, say PAX is in the middle.
Rym: This hotel was way away to the right.
Scott: Listen, just stay in an airport hotel and use the light rail every day.
Rym: Yeah, you know, random aside, I stayed in an airport hotel for the first time in my life last week, like a hotel in the airport.
Scott: In the airport?
Scott: Not just next to it?
Scott: I stayed in hotels next to an airport, but never in an airport.
Rym: So directly connected.
Scott: As in you could walk from the hotel to your gate?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Without going outside?
Rym: I did not have to go outside.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I did have to go through security though.
Scott: Alright, that's obvious.
Rym: Yeah, there appeared to be a way to do security in the hotel if I was first class flying, but I was not.
Scott: And they just drive you to the plane?
Rym: Yeah, I think they had a personal concierge who will take care of you and do personal security, but I digress.
Rym: So, Sailor Moon.
Rym: Scott knows almost nothing about it.
Scott: Okay, so I watched more than zero Sailor Moon in my life, right?
Scott: I watched when it was on the TV.
Scott: I watched a few episodes, but mostly it would be on like right before the show I actually wanted to watch, which was Bot's Master, or it would be on like after something I wanted to watch like Voltron, when it was like Cartoon Network.
Scott: So it's like it was never on at a time when I was going to watch it.
Scott: So I watched it like a few times.
Scott: And I know that there's a girl, she turns into Sailor Moon.
Scott: It's really stereotypical magical girl.
Scott: There's a bad guy, monster of the week.
Scott: She fights it.
Scott: She does some makeup thing and transforms.
Scott: There's a tuxedo guy who's obviously that dude and that's her boyfriend.
Rym: No, why would you say that?
Scott: There's other sailors who are different colors for different planets, and the plot just gets bigger and bigger and bigger, and then there's lesbians and then it's over.
Rym: What I do enjoy is how you make a lot of guesses about the show, like from the first two episodes.
Scott: I'm mostly right because it's so stereotypical.
Rym: You're mostly like completely wrong, which is really funny.
Scott: How could you be so wrong about something so cliche?
Rym: Well, you're like Sailor V. That's Sailor Venus.
Rym: So there's already Sailor Scouts.
Rym: No, she's not a Sailor Scout.
Rym: She's just Sailor V. She's the underwear pervert.
Rym: She's not a Sailor Scout yet.
Scott: Oh, yet.
Rym: And yeah, she doesn't come in until way later anyway.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But she's going to be Sailor Venus later.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: You thought that Naru's mom was Queen Beryl?
Scott: Well, you know, they made it look like it.
Scott: Different hair!
Rym: You can only tell some of these characters apart, I realize, in retrospect, because their hair is slightly different.
Scott: Oh, they had that dude who works at the arcade who looks just like Jedi.
Rym: Jedi-t.
Scott: Jedi, sorry.
Rym: Jedi-t is...
Scott: Yoda.
Rym: Is miltoast.
Rym: He's like Green Beryl's first general.
Rym: His primary trait is being nondescript and boring and then getting admiraled.
Scott: Yeah, that whole Queen Beryl thing reminds me a lot of Voltron, right?
Scott: Because in Voltron, you've got what, Zardoz?
Scott: No, it's not Zardoz.
Scott: Zardoz.
Scott: What the fuck is that dude's name?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: It definitely has a Z.
Rym: I'm going to admit to you, Scott.
Rym: I watched Voltron, but I did not like Voltron.
Scott: Voltron's good.
Rym: As a kid.
Rym: But I had the Voltron board game.
Rym: Are you looking it up?
Scott: Oh, is it Zoltan?
Rym: Zoltan doesn't sound right either.
Scott: Zoltan?
Scott: It was something like that.
Rym: Regardless.
Scott: But yeah, it was like him, right?
Scott: And then there was Zarkon, right?
Scott: Okay, so here we go.
Scott: Thank you, Wikipedia.
Scott: So it's King Zarkon.
Scott: He's like the real bad guy, right?
Scott: Then there was his son, Prince Lotor.
Scott: He was like the second in command kind of bad guy, right?
Scott: And then there was the sort of person on the side who would summon all of the row beasts that Voltron would fight, right?
Scott: So, you know, the Sailor Moon setup is really similar, right?
Scott: Like Queen Beryl's at the top, and then there's the henchman Jedi, whatever.
Scott: And then he summons the monster of the week that Sailor Moon actually has to fight.
Scott: And she doesn't actually fight the top bad guys, just like Voltron doesn't, you know, ever fight, you know, Prince Lotor or whatever.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But yeah, Nephrite, or not Nephrite, that's still Jedi.
Rym: We didn't get to all the much better ones yet.
Scott: They all have 'ite?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Look, you see the theme going, right?
Rym: Jedi, zoisite, malachite.
Scott: Well, I guess it's- Oh, they're all gems.
Scott: They're all gems.
Scott: Not gems.
Scott: Stones.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I guess someone wasn't in Science Olympiad as a kid.
Rym: But you might remember zoisite is the one who in the American dub, they made him a girl to just kind of remove this whole homosexual relationship that was going on.
Scott: Oh, it's an androgynous person?
Scott: And he- Well, you could freaking go to, you know, Messenger Z with the- Oh my god, yeah.
Rym: But that wouldn't have been on American TV either.
Rym: But it's interesting, you know, I watched all of Sailor Moon twice.
Rym: All of it.
Rym: But most of the first like 10 or 15 episodes- Of Baron Asher, right?
Rym: I saw, dubbed in the English release, and I never bothered rewatching them in Japanese.
Scott: Even though you had all the tapes?
Rym: I didn't have tapes of season one.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: You only had those Vkills for all the other Sailor Moon?
Rym: I had R, S, Super, S, Stars, Amichan no Hatsukoi, and the three movies.
Scott: Oh, you know, when I was watching the trailer, right, they made a trailer for the rerelease, and the trailer only mentioned Sailor Moon, S, Super, S, and Stars, and R. It didn't mention anything about- The movies.
Scott: The movies or that other thing you just said.
Rym: Amy's first love.
Rym: It's a side story about Sailor Mercury, and she falls in love with this hacker boy who's dating someone else.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: And then she comes to team.
Scott: So I'm really curious if like the movies and everything's gonna be included in there or not.
Rym: I'm also curious, the movies are, in fact, they're so stereotypical of anime series movies that if we ever do our all-anime or the same panel, we have to add all three Sailor Moon movies to it to buff it out.
Scott: Maybe some of those Tenchi movies also.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, kind of.
Rym: Yeah, the Tenchi movies do, but these movies occur on islands.
Rym: They bring in side characters who then die.
Rym: Like, it's pretty much straightforward.
Rym: I think Sailor Moon dies in all of them too.
Scott: But anyway, so since I was in middle school or high school, whatever, we watched the first two re-released episodes of Sailor Moon in their uncut, subtitled version on the moon.
Rym: Now, episode two is notable because it was never even aired on American TV because it showcased too much juvenile delinquency and panty shots and Satanism.
Scott: Yeah, so you never saw it before.
Rym: Never saw that episode.
Scott: Okay, so let's just talk about Sailor Moon.
Scott: So first of all, this show has a lot, you know, it's weird in that right from the beginning, you have all these magical girl show tropes, cliches, hardcore, right?
Scott: Running out of the house late for school.
Scott: She didn't have toast in her mouth, but she might as well would have, right?
Scott: Helping pet friend transformations.
Rym: Say moon tiara, whatever, make up, magic go.
Scott: Magical attacks, everything, right?
Scott: The whole bag, right?
Scott: But unlike, say, modern shows, everything sort of moe, creepy pervy or cutesy kitty, it's a lot more wacky, comedy, gag manga style, like Ursa Yatsura or kotocha or any of the other, you know, gag mangas of that era, right?
Scott: Or even earlier.
Rym: So, and it's actually honestly, it's pretty funny at times.
Rym: Like I forgot how funny this show can be.
Scott: So in that way, it's sort of, you know, unique in that it's sort of combining the magical girl and the gag, you know, genres together.
Scott: But it also has some funniness to break up the tedium of the formula fighting the monster of the week.
Rym: Though I realize something that's interesting is that Scott's opinions of this, having only kind of seen the beginning of Sailor Moon and episodes from season one and none of the later stuff, the show is way more Green Lantern-y and superhero-y later on than is obvious from the beginning.
Rym: And the manga is just Green Lantern with girls.
Scott: Even from the beginning?
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: The manga?
Rym: I haven't even read all the manga, but from what I've read of the manga, it is, it is the Green Lantern.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It is all just space politics and battles and it's crazy.
Rym: Kind of want to read the manga actually.
Rym: Go for it.
Rym: I've been thinking for a while to get it all and just try to read it.
Rym: I used to read it in Borders books.
Rym: Or no, no, no, Walden books.
Scott: So the first thing you notice when you watch Sailor Moon is that Usagi is dumb as a brick.
Rym: Yeah, Usagi is pretty fucking dumb actually.
Rym: And, uh, spoilers, she never gets smarter.
Scott: Even at the end where it's all Green Lantern-y?
Rym: Uh, she pretty much, as far as I can tell, Scott made an observation that I never thought of much having, you know, just cause I've, I've seen the show a lot more, closer to it, so it's easy for me to kind of gloss over these things.
Rym: Scott, you describe Usagi or Sailor Moon as almost being a weapon wielded by others.
Scott: Yeah, she doesn't do anything.
Scott: It's just like the cat tells her what to do.
Scott: Tuxedo guy tells her what to do.
Scott: She just, she doesn't actually attack the bad guys or do anything of her own volition cause she's so dumb.
Scott: It's, other people just make her do it.
Scott: And it's, she has all this power, but she has no, you know, will whatsoever.
Scott: Her primary power seems to be- She just stands there while the bad guys are coming at her.
Rym: Then she cries.
Scott: One guy throws a rose once and that somehow stops all the lower henchmen.
Scott: Cause he's way powerful.
Scott: Yeah, and then it's just like, throw the tiara, hello.
Rym: Welcome to the trope.
Scott: She doesn't even transform on her own.
Scott: It's just, hey, transform now.
Rym: Do I have to?
Scott: Say these exact words.
Scott: What were the words again?
Rym: I forgot.
Rym: I got 30% on my English test.
Rym: Let me tell you what, her grades only go down as the show goes on.
Scott: How could you go down, how could she not get kicked out of school or held back?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: Maybe that's why, I mean, how long, she's in eighth grade now, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So she's almost in high school.
Rym: She will make it to high school in Sailor Stars.
Scott: She actually makes it.
Scott: So that means she has to pass the classes, right?
Scott: In middle school.
Rym: Uh, I guess.
Rym: She's, you know, she's pretty dumb.
Rym: But she, as far as I can remember, she doesn't do much of her own volition.
Rym: Like really?
Rym: Like there's a moment in Stars where she is finally like, you know what, I'm going to do this thing.
Rym: And then she does it and everyone else is like, no, don't do that.
Rym: It's kind of like when Monica's mom is like, you should do something that's the wrong thing.
Rym: And she's like, fuck yes.
Rym: And she throws something somewhere and then all shit breaks loose.
Rym: Sailor Moon has a scene like that, but it takes all the way until Stars to get to it.
Rym: But, uh, I don't know, the show, I kind of want to watch the entire thing again because it has been about 14 or 15 years since I watched Sailor Moon.
Scott: It'll be 14, 15 years before you see it all again.
Scott: It's 200 episodes.
Rym: Kind of amazed how much I actually do remember, but most of what I remember is from S and Stars and Super S is just...
Scott: What's the order?
Scott: so people know?
Scott: Obviously you watch Sailor Moon first.
Rym: Sailor Moon, the first...
Scott: When you watch Sailor Moon, how many seasons does that have?
Rym: Uh, so one season was what was available.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Sailor Moon, 26 episodes and that's just the whole Queen Beryl arc.
Rym: And you learn, and by the end of that, you learn the backstory that she's the reincarnation of the Queen from the previous era.
Rym: In a sense, Sailor Moon is a post-apocalyptic story.
Rym: This is a world that was rebuilt after an apocalypse.
Scott: But I mean, if you just watch Sailor Moon on its own, it's a complete story with an end and you can stop?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Okay, so each one of them is a complete story?
Rym: Pretty much, yes.
Rym: Each one is a stand-alone story.
Scott: But obviously you need to watch the previous one to understand the next one?
Scott: Not really.
Scott: Really?
Scott: You can just watch Sailor... Like, if I just started today and all the episodes were out and I watched Super S, I would know what's going on?
Rym: You wouldn't know who most of the characters were, but it wouldn't really matter that much.
Scott: But there wouldn't be any loose ends from the previous one or loose ends hanging at the end?
Rym: So, interestingly, after Sailor Moon, which the end of that is...
Scott: It's only 26 episodes, Sailor Moon?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The end of the first season of Sailor Moon is actually one of the high points of the show.
Rym: It's a really good ending.
Rym: Not gonna lie.
Scott: Well, I imagine they kill Queen Beryl's as dead, right?
Scott: It's complicated.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Sailor Moon R is the next Sailor Moon.
Rym: Sailor Moon R has two story arcs.
Rym: There's Alan and Anne.
Rym: I've watched that in English.
Rym: I didn't have fansubs of that shit.
Rym: If I did, I actually didn't watch them, I don't think.
Rym: But they're just some aliens coming down in a tree and they're trying to steal people's energy.
Scott: Oh, so the arcs are based on the big bad guy?
Rym: Yes, whoever the big bad guy is, is the arc.
Rym: And then the next half of that is... ...is Prince Diamond and all these sort of other royals come down and they have their business going on and they resolve that.
Scott: Why is everyone messing with Earth?
Scott: Aren't there a zillion other planets they can mess with?
Rym: You'll find out later why that's the case.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: They didn't rebuild after their apocalypses?
Rym: Sailor Moon S is when, in my opinion, shit got good because that is the crazy apocalypse.
Rym: The Holy Grail is out there.
Scott: There's these aliens trying to come in.
Scott: The same one Jesus had?
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: Maybe?
Scott: So Sailor Moon has to go and get the cup that Jesus drank from.
Scott: Was Jesus like Sailor Desert or something?
Rym: I'll put it this way.
Rym: There are multiple... You know some of the scenes in Kill La Kill where they're experimenting on babies and/or trying to make clothes in a lab?
Rym: Some of those scenes are cribbed shot for shot from scenes in Sailor Moon S. Sailor Moon.
Rym: S is some of my favorite Sailor Moon.
Rym: That's the dark stuff, the weird stuff.
Scott: So why was it called R and then S?
Rym: Fuck if I know.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: If I knew at any point, I have forgotten.
Scott: As opposed to Sailor Moon 2 or 3.
Rym: S is also a complete story.
Rym: S is a high body count and S is when you get introduced to the outer Senshi, the Sailor Scouts from the outer planets.
Scott: They're still introducing characters way late.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Dude, Sailor Moon is by herself for a good chunk of the first season.
Rym: Then she gets Sailor Mercury and Sailor Mars kind of early.
Scott: But it's like they're in the opener, right?
Scott: In the first opener of the first episode, you see these other Sailors, right?
Scott: And you see Sailor V before you even see Sailor Moon in the show.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: She basically awakens them as time goes on in the early parts of the show.
Rym: Then they find Sailor Jupiter and she's this badass punching girl.
Scott: Yeah, punching.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Sailor Venus is already awakened because there's another cat that found her.
Rym: And he is like, "Yo, you're powerful,
Rym: whatever.".
Rym: So she's an underwear pervert in her own regard.
Rym: And then she becomes, she realizes she's a Sailor Scout and all that stuff.
Rym: But that's the inner Senshi.
Rym: They're responsible for internal bullshit within the solar system.
Scott: So in this universe, is our solar system the center of the universe?
Rym: No.
Rym: There are other solar systems that have their own sets of Sailors.
Scott: So why is Sailor Moon so much more important than any of those other people in the other solar system?
Rym: Who says she is?
Scott: I think she obviously is because the show's named after her.
Rym: If we're watching a cop show that's set in Baltimore, that doesn't mean that there aren't cops in France.
Scott: Sure, but this show goes into the outer space parts.
Rym: Yeah, so here's the deal.
Rym: The inner Senshi are responsible, they're like the FBI of the galaxy.
Rym: The outer Senshi are like the CIA.
Scott: How come there's no Sailor Moon?
Scott: How come there's no Sailor Io or Sailor Titan or Sailor Europa?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Huh.
Rym: Some of that might be dealt with.
Rym: There are characters that have names from those other moons and things.
Scott: Also, clearly their astronomy was all fucked up because there is a Sailor Pluto, right?
Scott: But there shouldn't be.
Rym: Well, Sailor Pluto's weird that she can't really interact much because of her power.
Scott: And what's the other thing that's out there next to Pluto?
Rym: Oh, Charon?
Scott: Yeah, how come there's no Sailor Charon?
Rym: Well, Sailor Saturn is the most powerful one.
Rym: Her power has basically destroyed the entire universe.
Scott: Well, rings.
Scott: Duh.
Rym: Well, Saturn.
Rym: Chronos and all that.
Scott: Rings.
Rym: Yeah, not really rings is why.
Scott: Well, wouldn't Jupiter be stronger with that badass fucking storm?
Rym: Yeah, but she just punches people.
Scott: Well, if you're that big, you usually only need to punch people.
Rym: So, what's funny is in Sailor Moon S...
Scott: Don't play an ace when in due school.
Rym: Like, you get used to these Sailor Scouts, like this team of five.
Rym: They're like the thing.
Rym: And then you meet the outer Senshi and they're a little bit older.
Rym: They're like later middle school, early high school.
Scott: But they're still just people on Earth?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: They, however, drive cars, act like adults, and they're so much more powerful than the inner Senshi.
Rym: It's almost a joke.
Scott: I don't know what can be more powerful than, like, Tiara Action, you're dead.
Rym: Yeah, so they...
Scott: What if she accidentally shoots Tiara Action, like, at the ground?
Scott: Will the Earth disintegrate?
Rym: I think it only works on living things.
Scott: I don't really remember.
Scott: Like, would it disintegrate an elephant?
Rym: Doesn't work on everyone.
Rym: Like, she has to upgrade over time.
Rym: She gets constant upgrades.
Rym: Super S is all about her daughter from the future.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Comes back to learn things.
Scott: And you're a middle school girl, and here's your daughter from the future.
Rym: Yeah, so in Stars, a younger person comes from the future, and for a while they're like, "Well, is that her
Rym: daughter?".
Rym: Granddaughter from the future.
Rym: What the fuck's going on in the future?
Scott: Why would people coming from the future... I mean, clearly people are coming from the future.
Scott: The future's doing pretty good, right?
Scott: So why are they coming back to the past?
Scott: You should go with them back to the future.
Rym: Well, because then you aren't there to save the past.
Scott: Fuck the past.
Scott: The future's all good.
Scott: People are coming from there.
Scott: They have time machines.
Rym: Because you're still there as soon as you leave.
Rym: It's like the Bravest Warriors, where he tries to go back in time and fix things.
Rym: And he's like, "If this is a bad idea, I would obviously come back here and destroy this machine right
Rym: before.".
Rym: And then he comes back and destroys it right in front of himself.
Scott: That is that.
Scott: That's why Bravest Warriors is so good.
Rym: Oh, Bravest Warriors.
Rym: Bravest Warriors.
Rym: I like that show about as much as I like Pokemon Rusty.
Rym: Sailor Moon.
Rym: Did you watch the new episode of Pokemon Rusty?
Scott: How different is Sailor Moon, really, from Pokemon Rusty?
Scott: The only difference between Sailor Moon and Pokemon Rusty that I can see is that Rusty fails and Sailor Moon succeeds somehow.
Scott: That's the only difference, right?
Scott: If Pokemon Rusty actually managed to beat Team Rocket and catch Pokemon and whatnot, he would just be Sailor Moon.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Interesting commentary going on here.
Scott: Rusty is just as dumb.
Rym: Watching the show in this early episode and seeing all this school stuff, that's really not there in later episodes.
Scott: Well, that's most anime.
Scott: Start with the school and it goes away, right?
Scott: Well, Full Metal Panic has a school that goes away.
Scott: Naruto has a school that goes away.
Scott: I think Yuu Hakusho has a school that goes away.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: Koto-chan has a school that doesn't go away.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: I like, and the thing is, school stuff, it's like so many mangas start in school, right?
Scott: And then they break away from it to go to some sort of formula of battling or who knows what.
Scott: But they start with school because school stuff is so good.
Scott: It's just really hard as a writer to keep writing school stuff where you keep it fresh constantly.
Rym: Well, you should watch Shinsekai Yori from the New World because they're in school.
Scott: The whole time?
Rym: Well, then they're adults, but they're in college.
Rym: You should watch that show.
Rym: That gives you interesting ways to use school.
Scott: Right, but I'm talking about concentrating on the Japanese middle or high school and staying in it.
Scott: The only kind of shows that can really manage that are stuff like Azumanga Daioh.
Rym: Why don't they make a shounen fighting show?
Rym: that's about getting good grades in school?
Scott: They did.
Scott: It's called Cromartie.
Rym: So anyway, Sailor Moon Super S is all about her daughter.
Scott: Sailor Moon RS Super S.
Rym: And it's her daughter falls in love with a unicorn boy.
Scott: Wait, unicorn boy?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Does he transform?
Scott: Or is he always a unicorn?
Rym: He can be a boy too.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And that's kind of, it's important and standalone.
Rym: I think it gets more treatment in the manga, but it's kind of cute.
Rym: I really like the closing theme.
Scott: Wait, where are the unicorns from?
Rym: Space bullshit, I don't remember.
Scott: Is this planet with unicorns?
Rym: It's all Green Lantern space bullshit.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So,
Rym: S.T.A.R.S.,
Rym: the last season, up through episode 200.
Scott: Oh, that's the last one?
Scott: Because I saw that in the trailer and it looked like Macross 7.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: S.T.A.R.S.
Rym: is the one where there's dudes who, they transform into Sailor Scouts, so they just become women.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: When they transform.
Rym: And they are as more powerful than the outer-senshi, than the outer-senshi are, than the inner-senshi.
Rym: They're just like gods.
Scott: So the Macross 7 people are the most powerful?
Rym: They're the most powerful Sailor Scouts.
Rym: They're badasses.
Scott: Wait, but that thing that's all.
Scott: Macross 70 is the end of the whole thing?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: So, everything up through Super S is kind of constrained to this galaxy.
Rym: So, it's like our bullshit and our solar system within the greater galaxy doesn't really matter.
Rym: It's just that our solar system has all these problems and we're dealing with them.
Rym: There's an external threat from elsewhere in the galaxy.
Rym: We fight it off.
Rym: S.T.A.R.S.
Rym: is about the galactic crisis where...
Scott: That's why you need the gods to help you?
Rym: Yeah, there's a bigger Sailor than...
Scott: So how does Sailor Moon even contribute when there's these god guys taking care of it?
Rym: So, like I said, there's a point where she kind of, like her powers work, but she's really not contributing.
Rym: And there's a moment in S.T.A.R.S.
Rym: where she's like, "Fuck this.
Rym: I'm doing the
Rym: thing.".
Rym: And she does the thing and it's a thing.
Scott: But she has a thing to do?
Rym: She actually actively does a thing despite, you know... She demonstrates volition and forethought in a way that is rarely seen in her character up until that point.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, but it's interesting to watch the show and see, like, these middle school hijinks and, like, her stereotypical anime friends, Wakaba and Creepy Dude.
Scott: Or, well, we could actually just call Wakaba Naru.
Rym: Yeah, but she's a Wakaba.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Wakaba 100%.
Rym: In fact, Wakaba in ways that are surprisingly apt in terms of things that happen to her later.
Rym: In terms of her not being special in any way.
Rym: Kendall Hill Wakaba is not in the 10 Universe.
Scott: But still being a character in the show that matters in the show.
Rym: And she matters in the plot, but she's not special in whatever magical way that the special people are special.
Scott: She's not Sailor anything.
Rym: Yeah, she's not a duelist.
Rym: She's not a Sailor.
Rym: As I recall in S.T.A.R.S.
Rym: and even in S, you kind of learn that people who aren't Sailors, their souls just fucking disappear when they die.
Rym: Like, they got nothing.
Rym: They don't get reincarnated.
Rym: Only Sailors get reincarnated because they have real souls.
Scott: Oh, so then Sailor Moon could just, like, get killed in a fight and it wouldn't matter.
Scott: She'd come right back.
Rym: That's the greater plot.
Rym: Sailor Moon is the reincarnation of the princess from the previous world that was destroyed in an apocalypse.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So anyway, S.T.A.R.S.
Rym: is the galactic crisis where there's kind of, like, the head Sailor who is taking over the entire galaxy and she's evil.
Scott: And Sailor Moon in this... Oh, there's an evil Sailor?
Rym: Yeah, there's...
Scott: Why does the... I mean, if this is such a universal thing, what does the universe know about sailing, which is a really Earth-centric concept?
Rym: That word means something special.
Rym: That word's the equivalent of... It's like a kryptonite.
Rym: It's a proper noun.
Scott: Uh-huh, but they're wearing clothes that resemble sailing.
Rym: Yeah, I guess humans got their sailing tradition from... Well, I put out the Sailor, the galactic Sailors from far away, the Starlights.
Rym: They don't wear that shit.
Rym: They just wear, like, these black leather outfits.
Scott: Sexy sailing.
Rym: They're the sexiest.
Scott: In the Navy.
Rym: They also have the best opening theme ever.
Scott: Well, if it's all Macross 7 style, they better, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, every time they're about to appear, you hear this snapping.
Scott: Oh, that's so badass.
Rym: And then someone starts whistling and then they appear.
Rym: They're the best.
Scott: If we snap and whistle, will they show up?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think I remember.
Rym: It's like...
Scott: Oh, someone's coming!
Scott: Someone's coming!
Scott: Oh, it's just Proto Man.
Scott: Never mind.
Rym: So, again, people are going to correct me, I'm sure, because I've gone over 15-year-old memories.
Rym: Their names were Taiki, Yaten, and I forgot the third guy.
Scott: Not Taiko?
Rym: No, I think it's Taiki.
Rym: Yaten is the one I definitely remember, because I think there's... Oh, I remember... It might be a translation error.
Scott: Are they named after nebulas or some shit?
Scott: I remember seeing a weird... Oh, they're named after stars because they're stars?
Rym: Well, one of their powers is a cosmic uterus thing, so...
Scott: Is there one named Soul?
Rym: No.
Scott: Huh.
Rym: So, anyway, I recall a weird, possibly implied romance between Luna and Yaten.
Scott: The cat and the rocks?
Rym: That sailor, Starlight, the one with the gray hair.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I remember thinking I saw that happening.
Rym: Cat sex?
Rym: And then I mentioned it to another friend of mine who was like, "Yeah, I always kind of thought that
Rym: too.".
Rym: And then he showed me even other scenes where like, "Oh, there was something going on between those
Rym: two.".
Rym: Even though she's supposed to be dating Artemis, the white cat.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, I mean, it would be hard to date anything that's not a cat.
Rym: Yeah, they would.
Scott: You're a cat.
Scott: You're not transforming like the unicorn.
Rym: She dates the unicorn, and right now he's still a unicorn right there.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Okay, then.
Rym: That's fine.
Scott: Everyone's getting freaky, and Sailor Moon's just clueless.
Rym: But yeah, the stars is like, now the galaxy's having this crisis, and Sailor Moon is just like the one power from this one region that's still holding out, and they have to fight back, and it's
Scott: this whole- Oh, because they did such a good job of defending their solar system.
Rym: They're like the only place where- They're the only place- Yeah, they're like the only place left unconquered.
Scott: So they end up, by virtue of the fact that they didn't suck in their small local battles, they become like the home base for the galactic battle?
Rym: The galactic resistance basically lands there.
Scott: It's not because they're actually any more special than anyone else.
Scott: It's just they happen to be in a good location.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: The other things I really remember that specifically, Haruka and Michiru are the best characters in the entire show.
Scott: I don't even know who those people are.
Rym: They're Sailor Neptune and Sailor Uranus.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I know Sailor Uranus from Salty Bet.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Bet on her usually.
Rym: Yeah, you know what, Uranus, everyone has their token item.
Scott: Oh, I bet Uranus, almost.
Rym: Uranus carries a sword, an actual sword.
Scott: Cutting people?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And Neptune is, for my high school eyes watching this show- The hottest?
Rym: The hottest character I'd ever seen in anime other than Unipuma from Tank Police.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Not Unipuma?
Rym: I was always more a fan of Unipuma.
Scott: You could tell the difference if I had two pictures?
Rym: I'm pretty sure Unipuma had slightly lighter hair.
Rym: Pretty sure.
Scott: Could you tell the difference in the manga where there's no color?
Rym: Probably not.
Rym: But manga didn't make a lot of sense, I remember, when I tried to read it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Is there anything else to say about sailing around the moon?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I feel like I'm going to watch it all again because my memories of it, it's interesting.
Rym: I remember all the big plot points and they seem really epic and interesting, but at the same time, watching episodes, I'm reminded that 90% of it is her saying, "Sukimi, kawate, ojikio, kyo," and doing all the transition.
Rym: Battles in middle episodes of the season are every Sailor Scout doing their scripted attack one by one.
Scott: Yeah, I'm saying the whole thing is what, 200-something episodes?
Rym: Exactly 200.
Scott: But the first season's only 26?
Scott: It's like, "Oh, all
Scott: right.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And how many, there's five seasons, 20?
Scott: Hey, that doesn't make sense.
Scott: How do you get to 200 episodes with only five seasons?
Rym: Well, there's Sailor Moon, RS.
Rym: Let me pull up the full list of episodes.
Scott: Some of those other letters of Sailor Moon have to have a lot more than 26 episodes to make this work, right?
Rym: Sailor Moon episodes.
Rym: Here we go, list of Sailor Moon episodes.
Rym: Let me get the full breakdown because I'm going to be off on some of my numbers.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Oh my God, no, I was wrong.
Rym: The original Sailor Moon is actually 46.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: That makes more sense.
Scott: I'm like, "How are they going to kill Queen Beryl if they've only just doing Monster of the Week right
Scott: now?".
Scott: That makes no sense.
Rym: Six episodes were cut from the English release.
Scott: Was the second one of them?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: What were the other ones?
Rym: So, the other ones were, let's see, what was cut?
Rym: Punish Them, The House of Fortune is the monster mansion.
Scott: Sailor Moon fucking loves punishing.
Rym: A Monster's Scent, Shanella Steels Love, Protect the Melody of Love, Usagi's the Cupid's Scent, episodes five and six were both cut as well.
Scott: All right.
Scott: We'll probably see those next Monday.
Rym: Episode 20, The Summer, The Ocean, Our Youth, and a Ghost.
Rym: Ooh, spooky ghost.
Rym: Yeah, 1992.
Scott: I was 10.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I forgot.
Rym: So, they cut the entire backstory of Sailor Venus.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: They just skip that.
Scott: Wait, so Sailor V you don't know anything about?
Rym: Yeah, they basically just skip her past and her.
Rym: because, and I remember this because this is when I went to seek the fan subs when I learned about this episode, Sailor Venus basically has a friend who's, something weird happens and Sailor Moon.
Rym: all could have killed her and there's a debate where they almost kill a regular person and they decided that was too violent for American TV.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Even though no actual violence happens.
Rym: It's just an anime.
Scott: There really isn't any violence in this.
Scott: Sailor Moon doesn't punch or kick.
Scott: She got cut?
Scott: Yeah, but all she does is stand there and eventually throws the tiara.
Scott: and this isn't like an actual action scene, right?
Scott: Utena has more action and it's more poorly animated because there's actually a sword fight going on.
Scott: She just stands there, waits for the bad guy, and eventually she throws the tiara.
Rym: That trope does not change pretty much until the end of the show.
Scott: You could probably watch.
Scott: Why would you not?
Scott: Why would you need to change it?
Scott: The thing is, I wish she would just get there and just immediately be like, tiara action, dust done, instead of waiting there for like 10 minutes and then doing it.
Scott: It's like, all right, bad guy, I'm going to let you do a bunch of shit and then I'll do it.
Scott: It's like, why?
Scott: We just want to look at the bad guy because it's so ugly.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: What's funny is that the title of the episodes almost seem to get longer and crazier as the show goes on.
Rym: I mean, eventually you get the brightness of the ceiling of the calling stars, Haruka and company into the war.
Scott: If we make a show, that's the kind of episode titles we're going to have.
Rym: Yeah, that is pretty much the best way to title anything ever.
Scott: Every title should be like a full...
Rym: When the galaxy perishes, the sailor soldier's final battle is four episodes from the end.
Scott: Okay, so moons, sailing, important animes of historic note.
Rym: We will probably do some for real modern reviews of every season, or at least every season.
Scott: Yeah, we'll make a few videos.
Scott: We're not going to do a video of every episode like Utena because it doesn't warrant it, and there's 200 of them.
Rym: You can do an episode of every plot point, but that wouldn't take that long.
Rym: But it's kind of like how if you tell someone the story of an X-Men comic, but you skip all the kind of stupid bullshit that happens in between the actual plot points, it sounds like a really interesting and epic story.
Rym: But then you read the comic, and there's all this bullshit in between, and the actual dramatic moments, knowing the spoiler of what happened is not much more dramatic than seeing it happen, or not much less dramatic.
Rym: Sailor Moon is kind of the same way in that a lot of it is just stupid filler, but there's little character interactions and little bits that occur in every episode along the way that are actually really good and really plotty.
Scott: I really wish I could see the consequences, like in the second episode of the kid being evil the day before.
Rym: Yeah, like how come he wasn't kicked out of school and sent to jail?
Scott: Right, and how about the other kids?
Scott: And how come?
Scott: every time the bad guys come, all they seem to do is put evil on every middle school kid in town?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Yes, you eighth graders!
Rym: Go out and tear this town up.
Scott: This will give energy to my boss enough to finish their evil plan.
Rym: Well, Scott, you know what the answer is?
Rym: That's why Jedi is going to get Darth Vader in a little bit.
Rym: Jedi is kind of milquetoast.
Scott: Malachite and- He doesn't even do anything himself.
Scott: All he does is like send out a bad guy to do something.
Rym: Actually you can tell that I only watched the dub for the early episodes because I think his name is Kunzite in the Japanese.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah, I know it was Malachite.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: He's the baddest ass of all of them.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.