Rym: It's Thursday, March 20th, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, air travel, because I can't believe we never did a show on this.
Scott: Or we did.
Rym: And we're bad at this.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, we're kind of phoning it in.
Scott: We got Anime Boston tomorrow and unlike- We're lucky we're even doing a show at all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's the crab people.
Scott: In fact, I showed up late- We also have no show ideas lately and you guys aren't exactly helping either.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I showed up late tonight.
Rym: Like, Scott was here waiting at the studio when I was late.
Rym: Partly because I was trying to book a flight.
Rym: So, going to talk about that.
Rym: Oh well.
Rym: But, Anime Boston.
Rym: It's very rare.
Rym: You know, in the old days, we always would show up to a con Thursday.
Rym: That was like the thing.
Rym: You show up at noon on fucking Thursday.
Scott: Anime Boston Reg has already started.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: People have badges right now.
Scott: We still do that for- There are cosplayers in Boston eating as we speak.
Rym: I remember every year we had a tradition.
Rym: We'd get up at like 6am.
Rym: We'd drive to Otakon.
Rym: Our goal was to be in Baltimore by noon on Thursday.
Rym: Get badges.
Rym: Break into the- Usually sneak around somewhere we weren't supposed to be because no one stops us.
Rym: And then swim in the pool all night and hang out.
Rym: And we really only do that for gaming cons now.
Rym: Anime cons, we tend to show up like noon on Friday and leave at like noon on Sunday.
Scott: The few anime cons we go to.
Rym: We go to two anime cons a year now.
Rym: Well, and one third.
Rym: Two and a third because ConnectiCon is one third anime con.
Scott: Well, ConnectiCon is one third everything.
Rym: So yeah, that's it.
Rym: It's con season.
Scott: Yeah, it's getting slightly warmer.
Scott: Today is the first day of Le Spring.
Rym: Warm today.
Scott: Haha, you Australians take that winner.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Getting a little cold, aren't you?
Rym: That's a shame.
Rym: Because PAX got moved back, when I go back to Australia this year, it's gonna be fucking summer.
Rym: Fuck yeah.
Rym: I'm taking back my summer days because last year I went to PAX Australia.
Rym: I missed a week and a half of summer here to get a week and a half of winter there.
Rym: So now I'm taking it back.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So yeah, I got a news that is interesting.
Rym: So many of you know, a while ago, our book club book was The Player of Games.
Rym: Ian M. Banks, the GeekNights book.
Rym: that isn't The Prince of Nothing, The Player of Games.
Rym: That book is legit.
Scott: There are a lot of books that are The GeekNights book, but those are them.
Rym: Yeah, Player of Games, The Prince of Nothing.
Rym: Very few things come close, but I read all the other culture books because they're delightful and I love just about everything about them, but one of them.
Scott: It's all you can do considering you can't actually live in the culture.
Rym: I know.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: I want to live in the culture.
Rym: Thing is the culture's awesome in the sort of awesomely boring way.
Rym: I'd almost want to be in the special circumstances where suddenly I'm risking death.
Scott: Go for it.
Rym: Yeah, but I digress.
Rym: One of these books is called Surface Detail and not to spoil anything about it, but the conceit is that in these highly advanced future societies like galaxy spanning societies with incredible computing technology and VR technology, it becomes eminently feasible to literally recreate your religion or literally create a hell.
Rym: that when people die, you take their consciousness and put it in hell forever.
Scott: So even though there is no hell, you make a real hell.
Scott: And then when someone's about to die, imagine like ghost in the shell, right?
Scott: You can just turn someone's brain into like, you know, computerize it, digitize their brain.
Scott: Okay, you're about to die.
Scott: Okay, I'll take your digitized brain and put it in a digital virtual hell.
Scott: So yeah, there is hell.
Scott: I put you in it and now it is real.
Scott: It's in this computer.
Rym: The book Surface Detail talks about the ethics of that, the ramifications of that.
Scott: Yeah, it's not cool.
Rym: Well, heavens exist as well, so there's one funny sort of side story.
Scott: That's kind of awesome.
Scott: Do that.
Rym: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: So heavens end up having their own problems and then the debate comes down to whether or not it's any different from just still being alive.
Scott: It isn't.
Rym: Yeah, but there's one society where they create their afterlives and then billions of suicides as people are like, "Fuck this.
Rym: I'm just going to heaven
Rym: now.".
Rym: Hell yeah.
Rym: So then the people who run heaven are like, "Yeah, fuck this.
Rym: You're all going to hell.
Rym: No
Rym: suicide.".
Scott: You can't force me.
Scott: I can do what I want.
Rym: No, they have all the power.
Scott: You know what I would do?
Scott: I would just make my own heaven in my own computer and go into it myself.
Rym: Yeah, then someone turns it off.
Scott: I would give it to like a bank or something.
Rym: Yeah, it also talks about virtual war and all this stuff.
Rym: So the reason I give you that sort of backdrop is that there's a story on Slashdot.
Scott: A true story of the real world.
Rym: That's kind of terrifying.
Rym: Basically, the idea is there are scientists and doctors legitimately researching and kind of seriously proposing that one way we could deal with prisons is to basically dilate time in people's brains using technology like chemicals or transcranial stimulation or whatever to make them live out the equivalent of thousand year sentences that take a matter of weeks or months to sufficiently punish them for their crimes while at the same time pragmatically being able to release them sooner.
Scott: That is, I mean, so being able to do that is totally awesome and we should totally research how to do that.
Rym: Yeah, put me in prison for a thousand years if that time dilation is me experiencing a thousand years of consuming all human media.
Scott: No, I mean, that's a very important thing to research and I'm sure such scientific research will bear much fruit that is valuable to humanity, but using it in that way is just evil.
Rym: Scott and I, if you haven't, are very...
Scott: I mean, prison's evil to begin with.
Scott: You're basically just making it more evil.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So this article, you're just a vengeful piece of shit is the purpose of the purpose of criminal justice isn't vengeance.
Rym: Well, that is the purpose for most people, right?
Scott: Well, those are the evil people.
Scott: Fuck them.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Or they should be like, we should get vengeance upon them.
Rym: They might just be ignorant and fearful, which is the same thing as being evil has the same effect.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So fuck them too.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But it's interesting that so many people like this whole article and this whole debate is predicated on the idea that the primary purpose of prison is punishment.
Rym: You like that alliteration there?
Scott: Stan Lee would be proud.
Rym: Which is kind of the worst possible thing.
Rym: So we'll take someone who is going to be in jail for 90 years cause they like raped a bunch of babies, put them in jail for five minutes.
Rym: They experienced 90 years of jail and then they're back out on the street.
Scott: Great.
Rym: And they're going to live as long as they would have lived before.
Rym: Anyway, I suspect baby raping will continue.
Scott: No, you don't say he just went a thousand years without raping a baby.
Scott: He wants a baby more than ever.
Rym: You gave him infinite babies in that virtual hell.
Rym: Then maybe he'd baby himself out.
Scott: Great.
Scott: He'd move on to fetuses.
Scott: Fetus ravers.
Rym: So everything in this is predicated on that idea when in my opinion, and not to belabor the point cause this is not what the show is about, the primary purpose of a judicial system and a punishment structure should be one, if possible, to undo damage that was done, secondarily to prevent if possible and reasonable future harm.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: So, I mean, it's really, it's only the second one.
Scott: You can't change the past, right?
Rym: But the judicial system, like for example, say I rob you and you get arrested, maybe they take your assets and give them to me to replace what I lost.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's not undoing.
Scott: That's simply rectifying.
Scott: Yeah, it's rectified.
Rym: But it's undoing it in a sense that it mitigates not undo like Photoshop.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I guess goal one should be as much as possible repair the damage.
Rym: Like if you stab me, the judicial system should make sure that I get unstabbed as much as medical science allows.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But not the number two, it takes away your knife.
Scott: But stabbing the stabber doesn't help anyone.
Scott: They both just frickin.
Rym: if there was evidence that it did, I would be more okay with there isn't.
Scott: It's just Hammurabi barbarianism.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Now there are for you on enlightened.
Rym: There are instances where certain combinations of likelihood of being punished and severity of punishment is a deterrent to certain crimes, but not all crimes.
Rym: Probably not.
Scott: You think if these drugs were perfect and had no side effects and worked as exactly as they would provide any extra deterrent?
Rym: No, that's the thing.
Rym: This is both evil and misguided.
Scott: I'm just saying that, for example, if there is a punishment, if you're not in order to deterred by prison, you're not going to be deterred by drug prison.
Rym: Like if there's a punishment for littering and that was actually enforced, a lot of people would probably not litter who otherwise would litter.
Rym: But studies show time and time again that the punishments for murder don't really prevent the kinds of people who murder from murdering because the reasons they murder, if someone, most people who decide I'm going to murder someone, they're not really thinking about the likelihood of the death penalty.
Rym: They're not like, well, is this worth 20 years in prison?
Rym: If they got to that point of asking that question, they're probably not going to murder.
Rym: Or it's going to be one of those situations like in the old days in Texas where the judge will be like, not guilty.
Rym: He had it coming.
Rym: So, yeah, this is a fascinating article about a lot of people who are effectively evil, even if they don't realize they're evil.
Scott: Well, they could be doing valuable research, though, as long as they don't use it for what they want to use it for.
Rym: Yes, seriously, the research of put me to sleep, I wake up in Boston for PAX, and along the way I watched every movie humans have ever made.
Rym: I would pay it for a small fee for that service.
Scott: It's called The Matrix.
Scott: I know kung fu.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I want that very badly.
Scott: It's pretty high on the list.
Scott: Top five of things I want very badly.
Rym: Yeah, you know what that is?
Scott: Not number one.
Rym: That gets real close to the culture.
Scott: Oh, look, I know every language that humans have ever spoken, even lost and forgotten languages.
Scott: How useful is that?
Scott: All right, so this is a completely unrelated news, sort of a...
Rym: I would assume so.
Rym: How many news can there be related to real world hells?
Scott: Right, it's also sort of a self-centered news, but whatevs, it is somewhat important to anyone who's nerdy and cares about technology.
Scott: So the camera that I have right now that I've been using for Netrunner videos and taking photos at cons and pretty much everything I do is a Panasonic GF2, which some people call the GF series the girlfriend series.
Scott: And basically it's a micro four thirds system.
Scott: So people don't know, micro four thirds camera is a camera where you take the lens off, just like a real serious DSLR, right?
Scott: But there's no mirror in between the lens and the sensor.
Scott: So the camera is much, much smaller.
Scott: The other thing is the sensor is much, much smaller, not much smaller to where it's like as small as your point and shoot or your phone, but smaller than a full frame DSLR.
Rym: Small enough where I can carry it around running without much difficulty.
Scott: So yeah, it's basically this weird balance between I want a smaller, lighter camera, but the sensor is still big enough to where, wow, the quality is that much better than a phone.
Scott: It's actually worth having this camera.
Rym: Such quality.
Scott: Yeah, it's not as, it's not as quality as the full for real DSLRs, but it's such quality that it's way better than your phone to where it's actually worth carrying this extra thing.
Scott: If you care about photo quality or videoing, anything of consequence.
Rym: I basically have a moderately newer version of what essentially is the same line.
Scott: I have the GX one, the GX seven, I guess is the newest of that line is also a G. They still make the GFS, but basically after the GF two, the GF series started basically becoming, you know, the dumb cameras, you know, but they all take the same lenses, whatever.
Scott: So they announced recently.
Scott: the GH for the GH series is like the, wow, it looks like it's a DSLR.
Scott: It's got the grip on it and it has a bunch of buttons and it's like super pro and super fancy look and take the same lenses.
Scott: Uh, but it's like serious business, still way smaller than a DSLR though, way smaller, but serious business.
Scott: And a lot of people were using GH twos and GH threes for video because they're totally fucking awesome for video.
Scott: If you're doing 10 ADP videos, GH twos and GH threes are still super awesome cameras.
Rym: The only reason I don't use mine for video at conventions is that due to the quick setup, tear down nature and the variability of access to things like power, I use a camcorder like a handicam with a hard drive and giant batteries in it.
Rym: that's not as good from a video standpoint, but much better from an actually using it to record multiple hours in a row.
Scott: So the GH four, see like if you're just going to make some 10 ADP videos, you're probably going to be able to get a GH three mad cheap.
Scott: People will probably be selling them used on eBay and stuff.
Scott: So I might even just pick one up if it's cheap enough or even a GH two cause one extra camera can't hurt.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, but the GH four is super insane and it's, you can preorder it now and it'll be out like beginning of may.
Scott: So not in time for these conventions of course, but in time for every other convention after that.
Rym: And why is it in time for a really stepping up the game of our own video production?
Scott: So why is this camera such a big deal?
Scott: Just another upgrade in the series of existing cameras because this camera can do four K videos.
Scott: Oh my glob.
Scott: And it's only, it's still expensive.
Scott: It's not a cheap piece of equipment, but it's $1,800.
Scott: Now in terms of other cameras that can do four K video, you've got the GoPro three, which is only a few hundred dollars, but that doesn't really, that doesn't do it right.
Scott: That's not the same kind of video we're talking here.
Scott: Other cameras that do four K are like for real cameras that cost tens of thousands of dollars.
Scott: So suddenly you're getting the equivalent of like, you know, something that is definitely capable of doing for reals pro video four K for less than $2,000.
Rym: Of course now you start to run into the, the issue, not the issue, but the reality that a lot of the infrastructure around doing four K has nothing to do with the camera, right?
Scott: I mean, the red camera was a big deal in that, you know, it basically was the equivalent of a multi hundred thousand dollar camera for only tens of thousands.
Scott: And now they've got the GH four, which is the equivalent of a tens of thousands of dollar camera for under 2000s.
Scott: is going to be crazy.
Scott: And all my existing lenses work on it.
Scott: So I don't have to like.
Scott: if you look at like the features of this thing online, it's pretty ridiculous.
Scott: Oh, in body stabilization that doesn't have embodies.
Scott: That's the only thing it doesn't have.
Rym: This review says it does.
Scott: That review is wrong by Panasonic.
Rym: The G seven incorporates seven.
Scott: The G X seven does.
Scott: The GH four does not.
Scott: Ah, uh, it seems to be a big deal for a lot of people.
Rym: The in body stabilization, if you get, if you want a lens, if you want the camera to do it, you have lenses that don't do it, but then right.
Scott: The only way to do it would be, I guess, in post.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or you only really need the stabilization if you're, if you're like running around with the camera while videoing or something like that.
Rym: Well, I need it a lot because a lot of the pictures I take even are in pretty low light conditions and zoomed in.
Rym: And with those combined, the stabilization really helps me out.
Scott: That does help you out.
Scott: But yeah, most of the Panasonic lenses have it built into the lens.
Scott: The thing is the one built in the lens is good, but not as good as the in camera ones that like Olympus has.
Scott: They're really good.
Scott: But if you're serious, you're just getting like a steady camera, some shit if you really need it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, the thing is, you might be saying, well, even so, why do I need?
Scott: why is a 4K camera even no matter how cheap a big deal?
Scott: No one has a 4K TV right now.
Scott: It's like, OK, it's future proof, which is nice, but why not just buy a 4K camera later when everyone has 4K TVs?
Scott: And there's some truth to that.
Scott: But recording 4K video is a bigger deal for other reasons.
Scott: For example, I can record a 4K video of us up on a stage doing a panel.
Scott: And when I zoom in to just my face, that'll be 1080p.
Scott: Right now, we record 1080p if we zoom into one person's face, that's less than 1080p.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also, every time it's like you have multiple cameras for the price of one camera, we need more cameras to have more camera angles at these conventions.
Rym: So might as well, every time I buy a camera, buy the most future proof one out there.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: So that eventually our cheapest camera is only the backup.
Scott: Another thing you can do is instead of like taking photos, you can just take 4K video, right, of everything.
Scott: And then when you get home, look through the 4K video, find the single frame that is the photo you wanted.
Scott: And that's an eight megapixel photo, which is, you know, you couldn't print like a super fancy magazine with that, probably.
Scott: But that's still.
Scott: eight megapixels is definitely enough to print.
Rym: Storage and power considerations notwithstanding.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like, you know, that's definitely a process that a lot of people are switching to is don't take photos, just take video of everything and then pick out the frames, you know, because the video is good enough for whatever you're doing.
Scott: You don't need, you know, it has a 16 megapixel sensor.
Scott: Well, what if I don't need a 16 megapixel photo?
Scott: I just need eight.
Rym: So also you've got this.
Scott: What are the odds that I'm going to push this button at the exact right moment of this sporting event versus the camera button is always pressed and I'll just find the awesome frame later.
Rym: So software stabilization can be way better because if I'm if I'm producing 1080 video and I've got a 4K source wide, I can stabilize the ever living fuck out of that.
Scott: And after effects, that is absolutely another thing that I was about to mention.
Scott: So, you know, if you're someone out there who does photos or videos like this camera is, you know, there are other cameras that beat it in pretty much a lot of different categories like low light photography.
Scott: Yeah, a Nikon D4S is going to just crush you because it goes up to like ISO 256,000 or something like that.
Scott: And the smaller sensor, you know, like once you go above ISO, maybe 6400, it's not good anymore.
Scott: Even 6400 might not be good.
Rym: I still gotta go through all those pictures we tried to take of the stars that one night.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: But it's like, you know, in each area, this camera is deficient in some way compared to others.
Scott: But overall, like this thing is is game changing, not just for people like me who change, who are already like invested in the micro four thirds camera system, but just cameras, videos and photos in general.
Scott: This thing is pretty significant.
Scott: So also, you know, even if you don't care about this individual camera, it's basically pushing the whole market.
Scott: Now, almost every other camera maker now has to come out with some sort of 4K thing.
Scott: So 4K recording is going to be available in general to the average prosumer population within a year or two.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And YouTube already supports 4K.
Scott: And I do know at least one or two people that have 4K TVs.
Scott: So watch out.
Scott: It's happening.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: Got a thing of the day?
Scott: Well, you know, baseball, the spring training is going on.
Scott: A lot of people are paying attention to that.
Scott: baseball and the the college basketball tournament, I think, starts like now or tomorrow.
Scott: It's starting basically now ish.
Scott: So that's pretty much taken up all the U.S.
Scott: sports.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And even NBA is getting tons and tons of coverage.
Scott: People forget the most important sport of all ever.
Scott: Ice hockey is still happening right now.
Scott: It is still the ice hockey season.
Scott: Just no one's paying attention to it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Partly because Red Wing is not doing so well.
Scott: The only reason not doing so well anyway.
Scott: So to remind people that the most important sport ever, ice hockey, is still happening as we speak.
Scott: Here is a hockey video.
Scott: It's not actually an NHL video.
Scott: It's from the LNAH, which is, I think, something some Canadian league, whatever, minor league hockey.
Scott: But it is a hockey fight.
Scott: And from the start, it looks like a pretty good hockey fight as far as hockey fights go.
Scott: But watch till the end.
Scott: Trust me.
Scott: Watch till the end.
Rym: Not even going to spoil it.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Scott: Watch to the end of this video.
Scott: This shows you why hockey is the best sport.
Scott: Ignore that basketball bullshit that's happening.
Scott: It's worthless.
Rym: So we've talked about this before, but John Green's Crash Course is amazing.
Rym: The Green Brothers.
Scott: Your favorite thing.
Rym: Yeah, it's an amazing thing.
Rym: Have you watched any of it, Scott?
Scott: No, I still no.
Rym: You really should.
Scott: I got better shit to do.
Rym: They're short.
Rym: They're like 12 minutes long.
Scott: I ain't got time for that.
Rym: And they teach you stuff.
Rym: They're better than any documentary.
Rym: They're brilliantly done.
Scott: These are the template for how to do informative, engaging, interesting content on YouTube.
Rym: Also, I would kill to have their studio.
Scott: Would it be better if they recorded in 4K?
Rym: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: They do the whiteout background, which we cannot do for lack of space.
Rym: So they have started up a couple of new series because they've gone like American history, world history, all these things.
Rym: So I want to particularly highlight.
Rym: John Green has restarted the literature one, which very famously did The Great Gatsby.
Rym: A lot of GeekNights listeners enjoyed that multi-part commentary on that book and how great it is.
Rym: But he started with The Odyssey and Hamlet.
Scott: I have pop-up Odyssey.
Scott: I know everything there is to know about the Odyssey with my pop-up book.
Rym: Yeah, the moral.
Rym: Odysseus was kind of a dick.
Scott: No, you don't say.
Rym: This video is just delightful.
Scott: You could have called him Odysseus if you wanted to.
Rym: The only person more of a dick than him is Poseidon.
Scott: The king of all dicks.
Rym: You know what, Poseidon?
Scott: Is the awesomest.
Rym: Poseidon, I do not mean that as anything other than a compliment.
Scott: Well, no, because think about it, right?
Rym: Please don't drown me.
Scott: It's like they're both dicks, right?
Scott: But it's like, you know, it's like there's different kinds of dicks, right?
Scott: Odysseus is like, "Wow, what a dick.
Scott: Fuck that
Scott: guy.".
Scott: And Poseidon is like, "Wow, what a glorious
Scott: dick.".
Scott: Holy shit, that is amazing.
Rym: Oh, you're disrespecting me?
Rym: You wanted to go home?
Scott: Oh, you're in a ship.
Scott: Why are you disrespecting me when you're in my house?
Scott: How stupid could you be?
Scott: I mean, I've seen a lot of stupid people out here in my house before.
Scott: You are by far, by far the dumbest.
Rym: I mean, even Athena is like, "Yeah, I don't piss him off, guys.
Rym: I don't want to piss him
Rym: off.".
Rym: Even Zeus is probably like, "Yeah, just let him
Rym: be.".
Scott: Listen, the ocean, there aren't a lot of people out here in total.
Scott: I can pay a lot of attention to you, and I don't really have much else going on right now.
Scott: I mean, some fishes over here and some waves over there.
Rym: Charybdis just hanging out.
Scott: I'm kind of bored, so I got no problems fucking you up.
Scott: I mean, them other gods, they might be real busy.
Rym: This gave me an idea.
Rym: This is the kind of thing that I don't want to make because it'd be too much effort, but I want to see a skit at a convention, right?
Rym: Where there's a guy dressed up as Poseidon, and on Thursday morning, he picks one dude and ruins his entire con over the course of four days.
Rym: It just follows him everywhere, knocking food off the table, stealing his cosplay, interrupting his panels.
Scott: Go to the bathroom, fill a bucket with water, splash it on him.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In the meantime, the Book Club book is Wool by Hugh Howrey.
Rym: I've read the first few chapters.
Scott: I read the whole thing.
Rym: Yeah, I'm burning through it pretty quickly.
Rym: All I want to say, the first set of chapters, like the very first story that kind of ends effectively, it reminded me a lot of a Ray Bradbury short story.
Rym: That stood on its own as a great short story with the correct twist.
Scott: But am I not correct?
Scott: Did you get the Logan's run feel?
Rym: Got the Logan's run, got the paranoia.
Scott: Did you get the paranoid feel, the fallout feel?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Rym: That's what it is.
Rym: There's some other feel that I'm not quite sure about yet going on.
Scott: There's some other feels in there.
Rym: I haven't read too far in yet.
Scott: I know everything.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Problem is, the author has a lot of sentences that have the same word too many times.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Let's just do the whole Book Club episode now.
Scott: I've finished it.
Rym: She stood before the door before.
Rym: She was like, "No, don't say before
Rym: twice.".
Rym: That's the kind of person I am when I read books.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: It's a Book Club book.
Scott: Save it for the Book Club episode.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I got to finish reading it.
Rym: We are going to be at Animu Boston.
Scott: Tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're taking a bus.
Scott: We're going to be there at noon.
Scott: So you can come see us there.
Scott: We got some panels.
Scott: What panels are they?
Rym: Friday, 2 p.m Panel 309.
Rym: Fundamental anime.
Scott: It's anime you should see.
Scott: We retitled it.
Scott: Don't come.
Scott: if you've seen anime you should see before.
Rym: Tell your friends who watch shit anime to go see it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Saturday at noon.
Rym: The secret guide to running panels.
Scott: We've done that a hundred times.
Scott: You can even just watch it on YouTube.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: When we recorded it from our living room.
Scott: But maybe if you know, you need that extra kick in the ass to do some panels at a con.
Rym: So guys, when we do panels like that, how to run an anime club, like how to panel, we don't fuck around.
Rym: Like we'll take some questions and we're going to give you real answers.
Rym: You might not like the answers.
Scott: More real than like people say they're going to give you the real deal and they don't.
Scott: Ours is too real.
Rym: Here's an example.
Scott: So real people can't handle it.
Rym: We've never put up a video of when we do those, like how to run an anime club panels, but we give advice like have a democracy, but on the inside you need to be super corrupt.
Rym: And here's how to be corrupt.
Scott: Make an autocracy that looks like a democracy.
Scott: Rig the election if necessary.
Scott: Take everyone's votes and then just announce the winner is the person you wanted all along.
Rym: You are grooming people in advance, like strategies on how to get rid of that guy, like how to make that guy stop showing up to your anime club.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Saturday at 2 30, panel 3 0 9.
Rym: Not all anime are what they seem.
Scott: A panel we came up with to fill the schedule.
Rym: And it ended up being a pretty good panel.
Rym: There's a section in the middle, a little bit trolly.
Rym: You guys might enjoy it.
Rym: And then Saturday, 7 30 p.m.
Rym: in the constitution room.
Rym: Judge anime by its cover.
Scott: The good panel.
Scott: People loved it last year, so let's just keep it going and do it every year.
Rym: I think we'll do it every year because it self-populates.
Rym: And by definition, we cannot prepare for it.
Rym: Preparing for it ruins it.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: All the prep I do is I take all the shows on the chart, put them in a slideshow, and I do a Google image search on like five random ones just to see.
Rym: And that's it.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: It's super fun for us to do, too.
Rym: So I'm digging this.
Scott: And people liked it last time, so why not?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So come say hi.
Rym: Come to our panels.
Rym: Mike Tool, all the other cool kids are going to be there doing panels.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Go to Anime How, go to Dubs of Time Forgot, go to all the... There's a panel that we can't go to.
Scott: Oh, I got to bring this up in my guidebook.
Rym: Uh-oh.
Rym: There's a panel we can't like.
Scott: There's a panel that's conflicting with our panel.
Rym: Well, I'll go to it.
Rym: You do the panel.
Scott: That is... Hold on.
Rym: You had to run that Nightrunner panel by yourself at ConnectiCon because I had to go deal with a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Japan Ice Hockey and the Asia League.
Rym: What?
Scott: This panel, look inside the world of ice hockey as it pertains to Japan.
Rym: Who the shit is running that?
Rym: Because we're getting them on GeekNights.
Scott: We can't go to it.
Scott: No, we're going to... It's at 2.30.
Scott: It's right on top of fundamental anime.
Scott: So we can actually, if we run out of fundamental anime, no, it's only a half hour long, their panel.
Scott: No, their panel is a 15 minute panel.
Rym: What?
Scott: Guidebook is fucked up.
Scott: Okay, whatever.
Scott: Their panel and fundamental anime both end at three, but theirs starts at 2.30 and ours starts at two.
Scott: So we can't see it at all.
Scott: We can ask Lou who's running it and find that person.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: You might say that's in our wheelhouse.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Go to that panel.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're also going to be at PAX East.
Rym: We're also going to be at Zenkai Con.
Rym: We're also going to be at ConnectiCon.
Rym: We're also going to be at PAX Prime.
Rym: PAX Dev.
Rym: I'm going to be at PAX Australia.
Rym: Shit's happening in the future.
Rym: Forum, YouTube, watcher stuff, whatever.
Scott: Our IRC channel.
Scott: We have one.
Scott: People are in it.
Rym: So I hope we didn't do a show on this.
Scott: We almost definitely did a show on this.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: I kept searching and all I kept finding was flying ghost shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I found that also.
Scott: This is one of those things where it's like, we've discussed it.
Scott: This is the hard part, right?
Scott: It's like you've discussed a topic on tons of shows.
Scott: And if you went back through all our shows and cut out all the pieces, we've talked about this.
Scott: We've probably discussed.
Scott: We're probably just going to be repeating ourselves, but it's never actually been the main bit of an episode.
Scott: So it'll be consolidated.
Rym: You can link to it.
Rym: You can discuss it.
Scott: And it helps us get away with the show.
Rym: Partly because I fly a lot these days, both for work and for GeekNights.
Scott: I mean, I've always flown a moderate amount more than most people, but never the crazy amount that a business traveler does.
Rym: So as a kid, I didn't fly often, actually.
Rym: I never flew anywhere.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: I didn't fly, didn't fly, didn't fly, didn't fly for the longest time.
Scott: And then once I started to fly and I flew like crazy.
Rym: I think that's a consequence of living in the Northeast or the Midwest.
Scott: Well, I mean, the only place we ever went as in my childhood that was worthy of flying was Florida.
Scott: And my parents would like, first we drove there.
Scott: Then we drove there again.
Scott: Then we took the auto train there.
Scott: And then we started flying.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It took like three times of doing it the inexpensive way before giving up and doing it the fast, least superior way.
Rym: We were always a road trip family.
Rym: Like we would prep the fuck out of road trips.
Rym: We would like the days before we'd be like filling the car with stuff, making like getting the cooler like situated.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Road trips.
Scott: That's an episode.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: We'll do a show on that.
Scott: That's an episode we definitely haven't done.
Scott: You know, and then like once I went to college, I was using JetBlue to fly home to JFK.
Scott: It's like a 45 minute flight.
Rym: I was driving because there aren't cheap flights to Detroit from Rochester.
Scott: That's a shame.
Rym: Which was fine because we're not talking about road trips.
Rym: So I didn't fly a lot as a kid.
Rym: And the first time I flew other than in like a Cessna or something was when I flew to Florida with the marching band for like a marching competition in the orange bowl or citrus bowl or whatever.
Scott: Usually schools will use buses for that and won't use planes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're not taking buses to Florida.
Rym: Fuck that noise.
Scott: People do it.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't.
Rym: We flew there and then we took buses around.
Rym: I was gone for like two weeks.
Rym: It was like over New Year's and everything.
Rym: It was actually kind of awesome.
Rym: So I started flying a lot, mostly for conventions.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because, but.
Scott: You can't get to PAX without a plane, at least not easily.
Rym: I did.
Rym: I never had to fly to conventions regularly until I got sick.
Rym: Although there's one time we flew to Boston.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Because we just didn't want to deal with other transit.
Rym: And it's basically not faster than taking the train.
Rym: If you take into account security and cabs.
Scott: It's also really cheap to take a short flight like that.
Rym: But now I fly all the time for work.
Rym: And we also fly to most of the bigger conventions we go to, except for the ones that are right here on the East coast.
Rym: But most of the conventions we go to are an easy drive.
Rym: It's more convenient to drive than to fly.
Rym: The only times we don't drive is because driving ends up being more expensive.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Because we don't have a car.
Rym: And also gas is expensive and parking costs every dollar.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Like Boston.
Scott: The amount you pay for parking in Boston, if you're there for an extended period, will just be the cost of the plane ticket.
Scott: you should have just flew.
Rym: DC was easier because we'd park way outside and take the metro.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: We parked in this way far the fuck away.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Not in the city.
Rym: So I have an observation.
Rym: I think that most people in America have never flown before and are somehow always at the airport and not in front.
Scott: Well, I mean, you got to consider, right?
Scott: The people who know how to fly and fly often, right?
Scott: Go to the airport and breeze through.
Scott: So most of the people who are still in the airport going slow are people who don't fly often.
Scott: And any given flight, you got to imagine, right?
Scott: So take a random jet blue flight, like, I don't know, New York to, I don't know, West Palm, right?
Scott: What percentage of that flight are people who fly all the goddamn time and know what the fuck they're doing?
Rym: But when I was a kid, you know, because I remember the time when the TSA didn't exist.
Rym: Like I would just fucking walk on the plane, go through a metal detector, put my bag in the extra, that was it.
Rym: I could put whatever I wanted in my carry on.
Rym: And it was always super easy and no one was ever in my way.
Scott: The TSA has definitely made things worse, right?
Rym: But like boarding planes was just like, go, go, go.
Rym: Like no big deal.
Scott: Listen, when the TWA terminal opened in JFK, my parents just went and you could just walk in off the street with no plane ticket or anything.
Scott: And watch planes take off out the window.
Scott: But I guess it's the can't go to the gate now.
Rym: What amazes me is that every time I fly and I have to check in at the desk, because, you know, you can't always do some sort of auto check in.
Rym: There's always every single person in front of me stands there at that check in thing for like five plus minutes.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And there's always some problem like, and I can never figure out what these problems are.
Scott: The problem is they're incompetent, but like they're always getting angry.
Rym: The person there is just typing forever and typing forever.
Rym: And then they like call the manager over there and he stands there watching while they keep like, what the fuck are they doing?
Rym: How do you fuck this up?
Rym: Because every time without fail, when I get up, I hand them my passport.
Rym: They hand me my boarding pass and I immediately walk away.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: It's because people, you know, when you don't do something often, right?
Scott: You got to imagine this person flies once every few years, if that, right?
Scott: You don't know what the fuck to do.
Rym: The first time I flew, I figured it out.
Rym: It's not hard.
Rym: Pack everything in a bag.
Rym: Pack the stuff in a smaller bag you want with you on the plane.
Rym: Bring some books.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Like what?
Rym: How do you fuck this up?
Rym: You already bought your plane ticket.
Rym: I'm convinced that most of the people in front of me in line aren't actually trying to fly anywhere.
Rym: They just wandered into the airport by accident.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe they bought a plane ticket that was wrong.
Scott: They came at the wrong day or the wrong time, or they came too late, or they brought too much stuff and they're, you know, they didn't realize they couldn't bring that much stuff.
Rym: Everyone in line seems to have a cart covered in like a hundred suitcases.
Scott: Well, I mean, I can understand the families, right?
Scott: So you have five people.
Scott: They got like five suitcases and they, you know, pushed them around.
Scott: It's like, okay.
Scott: But then you see these people, it's like, they got suitcases are like enough to carry every clothing I own.
Scott: And it's like, where are you going and for how long?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: If I'm going somewhere that long, I actually pack less because I do laundry.
Rym: In fact, the only time I pack a lot of clothes is if it's a weird trip where I'm going somewhere just long enough to need a lot of clothes, but not long enough to do laundry.
Scott: It's just, people just don't know how to, how to do anything.
Rym: I've also noticed something that really annoys me lately where they call for boarding, right?
Rym: And they always call like Rose 50 through 80 can board now.
Rym: And what I've noticed is that without fail, when they announced the first boarding group, pretty much everyone just stands up and tries to get on the plane.
Rym: And the airlines don't actually stop anyone who wasn't supposed to board then.
Rym: So the boarding just is a clusterfuck.
Rym: There's the one fat slow lady blocking row two while everyone else is trying to get to the back.
Rym: So I was on a flight, not that long ago, right?
Rym: I was in London and they did that.
Rym: They called like the last X Rose.
Rym: So I get in line behind a million people and the lady at the front turned away almost every single person.
Rym: She actually turned away.
Rym: People weren't supposed to board yet.
Rym: They got so mad.
Rym: One lady's one girl woman started like screaming at this attendant.
Rym: Like, what do you mean?
Rym: I can't get on the plane.
Rym: My ticket says, and she was like, do I have to call security?
Scott: Yeah, I would have pulled a conductor.
Scott: Go for it.
Rym: I wish every airline did that.
Rym: The sheer joy I experienced watching these extremely want to fly that airline.
Rym: angry, but it's almost always middle-aged ladies who are in line trying to board her.
Rym: And they're not supposed to.
Rym: It's never like the business traveler by himself.
Rym: It's never.
Scott: the airlines are one of those things where I wish, I think somebody could, you know, make a lot of money or I hope they could make a lot of money.
Scott: They would definitely get my money if they would just make jerk airline, which is basically this airline is for people who know what the fuck they're doing only.
Scott: And basically the rule would be if no soup for you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If even no soup for you airline, it's like, oh, you fucked up.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: You're just going to suffer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Oh, you tried to get on the plane when you weren't supposed to.
Scott: Next flight.
Scott: You can't even get on this flight.
Scott: Tough shit.
Scott: Oh, no refund either.
Scott: Oh, you need to reschedule.
Scott: Well, you're not getting your refund for that ticket.
Scott: Got to buy another one.
Scott: Tough shit.
Scott: You should have planned your fucking schedule in advance.
Rym: You know, there is a jerk airlines.
Rym: It's called spirit air.
Scott: But that's just a jerk to everyone.
Scott: Even the people who know what they're doing.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's the discount.
Scott: Like Dr.
Scott: Nick airline.
Rym: Hi everybody.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, this should be like, if you are good and actually do what you're supposed to do and obey all the rules and are fast and get on the plane right away, it should do, it should actually reward you, right?
Scott: You need the stick and the carrot.
Rym: I'd make it like a Japanese game show.
Rym: If you get from walking out of the plane into your seat with your luggage, put in the overhead bin and your seatbelt buckled within 45 seconds, your flight's free.
Scott: The whole flight would be free because only us people would be on there.
Rym: I have a feeling it would.
Rym: No, the thing is you subsidize this by letting a third of the people on the plane.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Who think they can do this, but can't like what I?
Scott: Oh, if you can't lift up your carry on over your head, we take it away from you and we put it on the next flight.
Scott: So you'll actually, not only will you not have it with you on the plane, you won't have it with you until like the day after you get where you're going.
Rym: Unless you pre-certify with us that you are handicapped or elderly and you physically can't do it so that we can have someone help you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's, you know, that's obvious.
Rym: Yeah, it should be.
Scott: You'll still get on the plane as fast as you can, given your condition.
Scott: I see.
Scott: Listen, and the other thing is, right, it's not people, right, that with handicaps and whatever that are the problem, right?
Scott: Those people just pre-boarding and they get on pretty damn fast.
Scott: Even the old people, they go, they're pre-boarding.
Scott: By the time I get on a plane, the old people are already seated with the shit above their heads.
Scott: It's these other people, right?
Scott: Who just have carry-ons that are way, that are too big.
Scott: I don't know why they let them bring it on.
Rym: I saw a couple of airlines.
Scott: Or too heavy, they can't pick it up.
Rym: Three weeks ago, a couple airlines suddenly instituted a zero-tolerance policy on oversized bags.
Rym: And it caused disaster and complaints and they're basically like, yeah, well, fuck you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Whatever airline that is, I like it.
Rym: I saw news stories about it while I was in the airport.
Scott: A-plus.
Rym: But like, these people bring these giant bags carry-on.
Rym: Why?
Rym: It's not like you can even get into that thing.
Rym: It's so big.
Scott: What are you going to do with it?
Scott: There's a human body in there.
Rym: Yeah, probably.
Scott: That's the only explanation.
Rym: I blame the TSA for most of this, though.
Scott: And TSA, I mean, the TSA basically slows down even the fast people, right?
Scott: Which is the problem.
Scott: If the TSA was gone, everyone would be sped up, you know, across the board.
Scott: But even without the TSA, there's still a lot of slow garbage, mostly from people.
Rym: It's mostly just people.
Rym: It's like they move so slow in their lives.
Rym: Like, if you all moved a little faster.
Rym: I did an experiment a couple months ago and what I did is on my way to and from work for several days, I started to stop watching my phone and I tried two ways.
Rym: One, I tried walking at the pace that whoever's in front of me is walking.
Rym: Not like trying to fight my way past people.
Rym: And then I recorded it on weekends, like on similar routes, when there was no one in my way.
Rym: If I didn't have to deal with slow people just being slow in front of me, I would save multiple hours per month.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, people are like, why are you in such a hurry?
Scott: Stop and smell the roses, whatever.
Rym: But it's like, I don't want to smell the hobos in the subway.
Rym: Get the fuck out of my way.
Scott: It's like, do you realize like people don't realize that by going slow, just how much time you're losing to do other things.
Rym: Stop to smell the roses.
Rym: I'm in the subway.
Rym: I'm on my way to the roses.
Scott: Are you the same person who's complaining like, oh, I don't have time to do these extra activities and oh, there's just, you know, I can't, I can't add this extra thing to my schedule.
Scott: It's like, yeah, cause you're fucking slow as balls, right?
Scott: It's like, why do you think I can do all the shit that I do?
Scott: Podcasting, you know, it's just running, sleeping properly, cooking dinner, right?
Scott: A lot of that actually, not all of it, you know, most of it's just good time management and scheduling, but a lot of it comes from just like walking fast and doing things that don't and I don't need to stop and smell as quickly as I possibly can and actually trying to hurry.
Scott: Not like running out of breath fast.
Rym: Well, what's the phrase?
Rym: Let us hurry so that we do not have to rush.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: So I got places to be.
Scott: Get shit, get somewhere on time and then take my time at the time at the doing the thing I actually care about doing and then hurry up and get to the fucking next thing.
Scott: Don't waste my time on a plane.
Scott: I don't want to be on the plane.
Scott: I want to be on the beach.
Scott: Let's get the plane into the air as quickly as possible because then I'll be on the beach 20 minutes sooner, 20 minutes more beach.
Rym: I also run into kind of a technological disconnect problem that Scott has the same problem, I assume.
Rym: So we have fancy insertion airbuds that block outside sound and are really high quality.
Rym: If I plug that shit into the entertainment system on a plane, one, the lowest volume setting is loud enough to injure me.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And two, the announcements from the pilot are loud enough to deafen me.
Scott: It depends on the plane.
Scott: Some planes, I can't even plug it in without a weird adapter to the pitchfork.
Rym: Or even if you do, like the audio quality is so shitty.
Rym: Like there's this whine in the background.
Scott: You know, when I used to fly JetBlue back in the college days, it was like TV.
Scott: Fuck yeah.
Scott: And I'd be watching like ESPN on the plane and whatever.
Scott: Then, like ever since the iPod era, like when I actually had an iPod and had stuff, podcasts to listen to, and especially when I had laptops and things to watch video on.
Rym: Or just play Civ V.
Scott: Or DS's and such like that.
Scott: It's just like I go on JetBlue and I just turn the TV off.
Scott: I don't really use.
Scott: the only thing I use on the in-flight entertainment system is watching where the plane is.
Rym: Occasionally, if I'm on a long flight, I'll watch a movie or two.
Scott: Even going to Australia, the longest flight ever.
Scott: I did not watch even one movie or television show on the entertainment.
Rym: I watched the movies during mealtimes usually because I can't have my laptop out at that time easily.
Scott: Uh, I don't know what I did during the meal time.
Scott: I think I just concentrated on the meal.
Rym: Nah.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Con, you really wanted to enjoy that meal.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: It actually was much better.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It wasn't like people, you know, airline food is sort of a joke.
Scott: Like cafeteria food is a joke.
Rym: But really, it's just United States airline food.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's like, well, first of all, JetBlue is great.
Scott: They don't give you food.
Scott: They just give you fucking snacks, right?
Scott: It's like, we're not going to insult you with shitty food.
Scott: We'll just give you no food.
Rym: I can eat at like the cheeseburger cheeseburger at the terminal before I fly.
Scott: But you know, on the flight to Australia, which, you know, the food was not bad.
Scott: It was perfectly edible.
Rym: I fly all around the world and all in all my experience, the worst food on our airlines outside of the United States is better than the best food on most US domestic flights.
Scott: I'm sure if you're on the first Amazo class.
Rym: No, I'm the fucking coach.
Scott: I'm saying if you're in the first class in the US, the food might be edible.
Rym: So about that business class food in the US is categorically worse than economy class food, unlike Turkish Air or Eddie Hod.
Scott: Well, Eddie Hod is a fancy airline.
Rym: Turkish Air is the best airline I've ever flown.
Scott: Have you flown Emirates?
Rym: I haven't flown Emirates yet.
Scott: How about Lufthansa?
Rym: I've flown them.
Scott: OK.
Rym: I've flown a lot of airlines.
Scott: And how about you haven't flown in the Concorde because they don't fly it anymore.
Rym: That's not an airline.
Rym: That's an airplane.
Scott: It was an airline.
Rym: It's an airplane.
Scott: Well, who owned the Concorde?
Rym: Air France.
Rym: It was a joke.
Scott: I thought I thought it was just like its own airline.
Rym: Really?
Scott: That owned them all.
Scott: No, they didn't.
Scott: They were just white.
Scott: They didn't have a logo printed on the side of them.
Rym: That's also not true.
Scott: I've never seen one that wasn't 100 percent white.
Rym: Here's a picture of one on Wikipedia that British Airways logo.
Scott: Well, there you go.
Rym: It's a plane.
Scott: I've still never seen it because your head's in the way.
Scott: But it was made by Air France.
Rym: It was like a joint thing with them and British Airway.
Rym: I'm not going to get into it.
Scott: I'm sure the food on it was amazing is the point.
Rym: Why would it be?
Rym: It's such a short flight.
Scott: You're paying a thousand fucking dollars.
Rym: You're paying for the short flight.
Scott: I want to be able to eat during that one hour.
Rym: I would not mind if the Concorde came back.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: I mean, it's significantly shorter, but not it's still not like two seconds.
Rym: It's shorter enough to matter.
Scott: If I wish it still existed, I would pay for it.
Scott: I would say I would have gladly paid to take it to Australia for like six thousand dollars.
Rym: Dude, I was just in London.
Rym: I don't think you can make it to Australia.
Scott: You don't think so?
Rym: No, I would.
Rym: I would have taken it to London because that would have been great.
Rym: Oh, that would have been the best.
Rym: Here we go, Scott.
Rym: Fab JFK to London Heathrow under three hours from takeoff to touchdown.
Scott: How much money?
Rym: I have no idea, but whatever.
Scott: I'd pay a thousand dollars.
Rym: I would pay a thousand dollars for that.
Scott: Easily three hours.
Rym: Scott, that's shorter than our ride to Boston.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: How awesome is that?
Scott: Plus three hours.
Scott: I'd like some food.
Scott: Give me a snack.
Rym: Yeah, just like JetBlue.
Rym: Get some peanuts.
Scott: Peanuts.
Scott: They don't go to a lot of airlines.
Scott: Don't do peanuts because people with allergies might get killed.
Rym: Yeah, I'm really sad about that.
Rym: I really like peanuts.
Scott: I like peanuts too.
Rym: I get air.
Rym: I get peanuts.
Rym: A lot of non-United States.
Scott: Bring them on the plane?
Scott: So the TSA is not going to take my peanuts.
Rym: They might.
Rym: I wouldn't be surprised.
Scott: And I happen to sit next to a stranger who's allergic to peanuts and then they start dying.
Scott: I got to jab him with an EpiPen and apologize.
Rym: Yeah, most peanut allergies are not like that.
Rym: Maybe while they're asleep, you just like grind them up and jam them in their mouth.
Rym: But that's murder.
Scott: Only if I know.
Scott: What if I didn't know?
Scott: And I was like, hey, you want a peanut?
Rym: Oh my God, I didn't know.
Rym: I think that's the paper skull, whatever, doctor.
Rym: If I punch you and you're just super weak and it crushes your skull, I'm still guilty of manslaughter.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if I offer you a peanut, like, hey, you want a peanut?
Rym: There's an issue in offering it to you and grinding it up and shoving it into your mouth while you're asleep.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't think it's good to grind up anything and put it in someone's mouth while they're asleep.
Rym: But I just, I can't express to you how awful most airlines inside of the United States are the more I fly overseas.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Also how awful the TSA is the more I fly overseas.
Rym: Everything about the experience of flying within the United States is awful.
Scott: compared to the US is bad.
Scott: Flying is amazing.
Scott: The miracle of flight.
Scott: It's like other people, they get on planes and it's like, I see people who prefer the aisle seat.
Scott: I guess they want to get up and go to the bathroom without having to make one else get your flights under 10 hours.
Rym: Why the fuck are you getting up?
Rym: Sit there too.
Scott: It's like people don't want the middle seat.
Scott: Obviously never want a middle seat.
Scott: The worst.
Scott: But people have the window seat.
Scott: It's like they don't look out the window.
Scott: It's like I've flown a bunch of times.
Scott: Every single time I still look out the window and go, Holy fuck.
Scott: Miracle of flight.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I'll look out three times the entire takeoff because that's awesome.
Rym: The entire landing because hey, I look out the window.
Scott: If I'm in the window seat, which I usually am, I'm looking out the window like 80% of the time.
Rym: Well sometimes when it's sunny and you're above the clouds, you can't look out the right or it's pitch black and you can't even see anything because you're above farms and mountains.
Rym: When I was flying to Tokyo, I remember at one point we were flying over northern areas and you could see like the hints of Aurora off on the horizon.
Scott: Could you see like Mount Fuji?
Rym: No.
Rym: Not that that was over the Arctic at that point.
Scott: Oh, you were flying over the top?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's how you get direct from JFK to Tokyo.
Scott: Over the top, not around.
Rym: Yeah, over the top.
Scott: But yeah, no, it's like, uh, you know, people, they just, you know, they fly without, you know, it's like without appreciating.
Scott: You are fucking flying.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: And it's like, dude, seriously, if you don't look out the window and say, holy shit, you shouldn't be allowed to fly.
Scott: You're like, oh, if you're not going to appreciate flying, you don't get to fly.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The actual act of flying.
Rym: If the TSA went away, I would fly almost everywhere I go.
Scott: I would fly to work if I could.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: People like a hundred years ago basically couldn't fly.
Scott: Even today, only very few people, relatively speaking, are privileged to fly.
Scott: Caesar could not fly.
Scott: Queens and Kings of ancient times could not fly.
Scott: Even Abraham Lincoln could not fly.
Rym: I like how that's your even Abraham Lincoln.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Someone that recent could not fly.
Scott: I don't think Teddy Roosevelt flew.
Scott: Did he?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't, you know, people who are really important and really recent did not have the privilege to experience the miracle flying that I am privileged to have.
Scott: Better fucking appreciate that.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So I just type did Teddy Roosevelt?
Rym: and the suggestions are invent the teddy bear, marry his cousin, see Bigfoot, have polio, get shot.
Scott: Wrong Roosevelt on the polio.
Rym: But at least someone thought to look it up.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I guess that person was educated.
Scott: So good for them.
Scott: Much better than the person who keeps getting it wrong.
Rym: Oh, when did Theodore Roosevelt fly in an airplane?
Rym: On October 11th, 1910, everyone Roosevelt Scott was the first president to fly in a plane.
Scott: Hallelujah.
Scott: Deservedly.
Rym: So he was the first, I bet he fucking appreciated it.
Scott: He was probably like, holy shit, this is fucking amazing.
Rym: Bully, bully, bully the entire way.
Rym: Just bully.
Scott: I mean, in his day, you wanted to get to California to use a fucking boat through a canal that he dug with his own hands.
Rym: or road trip.
Scott: They didn't really have cars.
Rym: They had road trips.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: He's got an all-around trail.
Rym: Or there were road trips.
Scott: You could use a train.
Rym: There were road trips back in the day.
Scott: There were trains.
Scott: Trains were the way to go.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I've never flown first class.
Scott: I have also not flown in the first class.
Rym: But I've seen inside a first class.
Scott: I've seen inside all the first class.
Rym: Yeah, you've basically got a tiny walled apartment with a lay down bed.
Scott: Well, I mean, the thing is, even the first classes that are that fancy, the ones on Emirates are even fancier.
Scott: So it's like the first class on one airplane is like coach on some other.
Rym: I've flown business class several times.
Rym: It's plenty.
Scott: It is.
Rym: It is so great.
Rym: I thought like, oh, I should maybe I should upgrade to business class on this flight to Australia.
Rym: And I expected it to be more expensive.
Rym: It was so much more expensive.
Rym: It even was like a ludicrous price.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If it was if it was a little bit more money, I would have done it, too.
Scott: But it's not.
Rym: I would have paid an extra thousand dollars.
Scott: Prohibitively expensive.
Rym: But there is a secret.
Rym: If you fly overseas that I've found is that a lot of overseas airlines have something that they call premium economy or something like that.
Scott: It's a plane is big enough.
Rym: It's better than what business class is inside of the U.S.
Rym: And most airlines like in Turkish air premium.
Rym: a little more legroom, a lot more like better seat, a huge seat that reclines all the fuck way back and multi-course dining like they bring you.
Rym: Here's the menu.
Rym: Here's appetizer number one.
Rym: Which of our four dessert selections would you like?
Rym: Here's a bottle of wine.
Scott: Here's your crack pipe prewarmed.
Rym: I do also enjoy how outside of the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: pretty much every airline just gives you as much alcohol as you want.
Rym: Like they don't charge you.
Rym: It's just free.
Rym: Inside of the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: they're like, would you like an awful rum and Coke for nine dollars?
Scott: For me, this is not an issue.
Rym: Yeah, but also juices, free juice, as much juice as I want.
Rym: Just give me all the orange juice.
Scott: Give me all the orange juice until I can't drink it anymore.
Scott: Until I'm so sugared up, I can't.
Rym: Orange juice is so important on flights.
Scott: Until I turn orange.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So yeah, I've noticed also that we're really, really fucking spoiled by living in New York.
Scott: Yeah, we can just go to the airport immediately and we don't have to drive to it, park at it.
Rym: Yeah, or even I know a lot of people who...
Scott: Like in terms of flying, right, it's like if you're taking a trip somewhere and you have to factor in like getting to the airport as part of the time, I see why a lot of suburb people like flying won't actually save them anything.
Scott: Like let's say you live outside of the city of Boston, you know, fly to New York.
Scott: It's a three hour drive.
Scott: You drive 45 minutes to get to the airport and park and you got to pay for that.
Scott: Then you spend like half hour to 45 minutes getting through the airport and then you fly.
Scott: It's like if you would have just drove to New York, you would have made it in the same time.
Scott: I live in New York.
Scott: I get on the air, the subway.
Scott: It takes me to the airport.
Scott: I get on the plane.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: I'm there.
Rym: Even look like when we lived in Beacon.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Hour train into the city, hour and change like hour and a half hour from there to the airport.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Then fly.
Rym: Or maybe go to the local airport, fly to the real airport and then fly.
Scott: If you... There are a lot of like.
Scott: you got to look at these airports that aren't the major airports, which a lot of people don't look at.
Scott: There's a lot of secret flights there that people don't know.
Scott: that can save you a fuck ton of time.
Scott: For example, one I know of that my mom uses is White Plains has an airport.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You wouldn't know that White Plains has an airport, but it does.
Rym: Dude, I used that.
Rym: I used Stuart Airport by Beacon multiple times.
Scott: That's bigger than White Plains Airport.
Rym: Yeah, but Stuart Airport.
Rym: Well, that was.
Rym: I think it was a landing place for the shuttle.
Scott: Well, White Plains Airport is really tiny, but you know what?
Scott: You can fly direct from White Plains to West Palm Beach on JetBlue.
Scott: Just like, oh, so if you live in like Connecticut, don't drive into fricking, you know, or up, you know, slightly upstate New York.
Scott: You can get there really quick.
Scott: Like 30 minute drive is a huge radius of, you know, people living.
Rym: But even among the big airports, like you think Boston you mentioned or D.C.
Rym: or New York, New York is such a cut above.
Rym: If I want to fly almost like when I... Not LaGuardia.
Rym: Not Newark.
Rym: When I fly to Turkey, when I fly to Brazil, when I fly to India, when I fly to London, all these places, there's multiple direct flights from JFK every day.
Scott: I mean, a lot of people, if you live somewhere else besides like New York, Chicago,
Scott: L.A.,
Scott: like a major, major city, you know, you can't really get direct flights to all these places.
Scott: So flying is just not flying again.
Scott: The convenience goes down.
Rym: Like, so I was late to the studio tonight.
Scott: If you're in Seattle and you want to go to, you know, I guess, I don't know, Germany, you're taking like three flights minimum to get there.
Rym: But no, when I was here.
Scott: Seattle is somewhere else.
Rym: Direct flight to Frankfurt.
Rym: Whatevs.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No biggie.
Rym: So the reason I was late to the studio is that I was trying to book a flight because I actually have to be in Paris like the days before PAX East this year.
Scott: Well, if there was a Concord, you wouldn't have any problems.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: You get there, you could go day of.
Rym: So I was looking for flights.
Rym: So I'm going to fly out, do my thing, and I'm going to fly.
Rym: Basically, I wanted to fly from JFK to Paris.
Rym: Trivial, tons of flights.
Rym: Want to fly from Paris to Boston so I can just go straight to PAX like Thursday.
Rym: Like, there's no reason to go.
Rym: Yeah, it is cheaper and faster to fly to JFK and then take the fucking Acela to Boston.
Rym: Boston does not have a lot of direct flights.
Scott: There's like one flight from Paris to Boston.
Rym: And the few that exist.
Scott: Because how many Parisians are like, let's go to Boston.
Rym: Yeah, and I remember when I was thinking back.
Scott: They wouldn't say it that way.
Rym: They would say, "huh-huh, let's go to
Rym: Boston.".
Rym: And I'm in New York, so we were trying to both meet in Turkey.
Rym: He had to take like this bullshit flight because there just weren't a lot of flights to Turkey and most of them had transfers.
Rym: And I can just fly everywhere direct because I'm in New York.
Scott: So flying is really convenient and awesome for important people who live in important places and go to important places and really not convenient for you plebs in the sticks.
Scott: So shove it.
Scott: We will experience the miracle of flight and appreciate it for you.
Rym: But then again in the sticks, I have to say when we lived in Beacon and we wanted to drive somewhere, we lived at the intersection of two of the biggest freeways in America.
Scott: They're pretty big.
Rym: If we wanted to drive, there was no drive to the freeway and then go that most people have.
Rym: It was just like, let's go.
Rym: Driving was so fast and so convenient so that now when we live in New York City, I can fly anywhere in the world.
Rym: But if I go to like Hunter Mountain, which is not that far away and I want to drive closer than any place you're flying to and I want to drive home, I'll spend the last hour of that drive within like 20 miles of my apartment.
Scott: I mean, New York City is also much closer to all these major highways and whatnot, right?
Scott: It's just we don't know.
Rym: It's closer in terms of distance, not in terms of time.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If we had a car, though, if this was not New York City, it would take 10 minutes to drive to JFK.
Rym: It's only because it's New York that it takes a goddamn hour.
Scott: I can bike to JFK.
Scott: I have.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's faster to bike than to drive on certain days anyway.
Rym: Flying is pretty awesome.
Scott: Let's just talk a little bit about the actual terminals themselves.
Scott: So a lot of airplane terminals, they're all really kind of different, but all sort of the same as well.
Scott: It's it's kind of a strange two tiers.
Rym: There's the modern one with good food and the old school one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But even the food is you ever know.
Scott: I always get confused by the ones that have like the sit down restaurants.
Scott: And it's like, OK, you got like even the new fancy JetBlue terminal, awesome terminal, Super modern.
Rym: I can tell you exactly why those they have the fancy restaurant.
Scott: It's like, OK, maybe if I'm landing in JFK and I'm going to take a different flight to leave and there's a huge gap between the two flights, I might use the sit down restaurant.
Scott: Why else would I ever use that sit down restaurant?
Scott: What other circumstance?
Rym: I get to the airport early because it's always an international flight for me.
Rym: So I get there, you know, two and a half hours early.
Scott: That's way too early.
Rym: Uh, the reason for that is because I almost missed my flight home from Brazil once because sudden traffic jam.
Rym: What do you do?
Scott: I'm not driving to the airport.
Scott: I'm taking the subway.
Rym: Yeah, there are subways to most airports in the world, but I'm talking about right.
Scott: But OK, but there's this one here in New York, New York.
Rym: So in these other countries, I need to leave a lot of time because a lot of things can fuck me on my way to the airport.
Scott: And if something doesn't fuck you, you sit down at that restaurant and eat dinner.
Rym: Yeah, I'm a business traveler.
Rym: Company dime.
Scott: Company dime.
Rym: Also, it's pleasant to not be sitting in the normal lounge to be sitting somewhere.
Scott: So what if you're sitting there and you're eating dinner and it's like, oh, shit, the food still hasn't come out.
Rym: Oh, those restaurants are designed around people who are in a hurry.
Rym: They bring you the check fucking immediately.
Rym: Soon as they see that you're done, they bring you the check.
Rym: You telling your flight, they'll remind you how you should go.
Rym: If you order something that won't be ready quickly and your flight's coming soon, they warn you.
Scott: Well, what about in the airline terminals?
Scott: Right.
Scott: All the fancy stores that I mean, I understand.
Rym: I don't get that at all.
Scott: I understand that if you shop at those places, I understand the store that's selling the snacks and the magazines, you know, the stuff that's like.
Rym: the only reason those jewelry stores are there is so guilty.
Rym: Cheating businessmen can buy gifts for their wife on the way home.
Scott: I understand even the store that sells clothes because, hey, maybe you, you know, didn't pack like, oh, shit, I need I ruined my shirt or something happened to a clothing and I really need one or, you know, something like that.
Scott: There might there's a case where I need to buy a clothing in an airport.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The jewelry, I guess you came up with the only possible reason for that.
Scott: Yeah, but the the stores that sell overpriced everything else, especially like the duty free.
Scott: It's like, OK, theoretically, you don't pay tax on this.
Rym: Now, what's the scam?
Scott: It's overpriced to begin with.
Rym: I've I've all I've checked the prices many times.
Rym: Everything you ever see in duty free, I can get cheaper on Amazon or at a local liquor.
Scott: Now, some of those things, items they sell in duty free, regardless of the price, we're assuming you're going to pay overpay for this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Makes sense.
Scott: Like, oh, I saw on a duty free.
Scott: They were selling fancy cameras.
Scott: It's like you're a tourist.
Scott: You might not have a fancy camera and you might decide up.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know, a lot of people seem to get tricked and buy a lot of alcohol.
Scott: You know, luggage makes sense.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Alcohol, I guess, might make sense if you're an alcoholic, but it's like this on TVs in there and it's like, OK.
Rym: So part of that, Scott, is that we live in the US where it's not a big deal.
Rym: Most other countries, especially in Europe, have huge taxes on importing things and duties and things, and their prices are also messed up.
Rym: So I think it actually works out for a lot of those people.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Like they see a TV and they're like, I need that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's a really good price.
Rym: You can structure buying that TV to where you end up not paying taxes on it.
Rym: That might actually make up the difference.
Scott: You mean you'd save more money, though, just buying one at like Best Buy in the US and then find a way to get it.
Scott: Well, you just flew somewhere.
Scott: Where did you fly?
Rym: So, Scott, if you buy it in the duty, if you buy it in the US and try to export it through customs, it's harder than if you get it through the duty free.
Scott: But like the duty free also has that tax person at the end who doesn't actually do anything.
Rym: What's funny is I end up going to these places in the airports and international terminals to buy like a bottle of water.
Rym: And then they're like, can we scan your boarding pass?
Rym: And then I don't pay taxes on that water.
Rym: So I have.
Rym: I have shopped at those places.
Rym: I've bought bottles of water and occasionally I've bought bags of Kit Kats.
Scott: Yeah, I buy candy, too.
Rym: Mostly Kit Kats.
Scott: In Israel, I bought the bazooka gum.
Scott: that says bazooka in Hebrew.
Scott: The whole sack of it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, it's like they got stuff in there.
Scott: that makes no sense.
Scott: I mean, hotels have jewelry stores in them, too.
Scott: I never understood that shops at the hotel jewelry store.
Scott: And how sad is the person who is the person who has to work in the hotel jewelry store?
Scott: That's their job.
Rym: If you're if you're working boring retail, I think the best possible case is boring retail where there's never a customer.
Scott: So you spend all your time reading.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You just sit there with your fucking smartphone the whole time and don't do anything.
Rym: That would be that would be a fine job compared to actually serving real customers in the same situation.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: Of course, your commute now involves going to the airport every day.
Rym: That alone might be worth killing yourself.
Scott: Hotel jewelry store.
Rym: That would be.
Rym: But imagine working at the airport.
Rym: It's like the people who work at the rest stops on the freeway.
Rym: Like it's just.
Rym: it's so weird and fake.
Scott: There could be jobs you can get at the airport that are cool.
Scott: Orange stick guy.
Scott: Pilot.
Scott: Best job.
Rym: No, pilots, the worst job.
Rym: They get paid shit.
Scott: I thought they had an awesome union.
Scott: They get paid a ton.
Scott: They get paid fighting all the time.
Rym: Wages for pilots who aren't doing like.
Rym: basically the pilots who are making like six figures plus pilots are fucked.
Rym: In fact, the wages for most pilots in the U.S.
Rym: is approaching minimum wage.
Rym: What?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: I thought their union made them have tons of money.
Scott: No, that's a shame.
Rym: Being a pilot really sucks.
Scott: Well, they get to experience the miracle of flight all the time.
Rym: Well, flying is pretty awesome.
Scott: Maybe that's why they make their planes disappear.
Rym: I think we're done.
Scott: Didn't get paid enough.
Rym: I mean, what else?
Rym: I get really thirsty on planes.
Rym: I drink a lot of water.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Everyone else gets up to pee a million times.
Rym: I don't.
Scott: I'm not afraid of the plane.
Scott: Anything bad happening to the plane.
Scott: Everyone else is.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Granted, it's interesting.
Rym: We live in a world where a 777 disappeared.
Scott: It's fascinating, but I'm not afraid of it.
Rym: Not afraid of it either, but it's interesting that that happened.
Rym: Flying.
Scott: I'm hungry.
Rym: Let's go down to Boston.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.