Rym: It's Monday, Cinco de Mayo 2014, I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Prosumer versus professional.
Rym: You probably don't want the latter even if you think you do.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So for the first time this year, I think it's time to bike to work.
Rym: I bike to work today?
Scott: So I go out and I'm like, "Oh, I'm gonna dig and get on my bike, start biking to
Scott: work.".
Scott: Then I checked the weather before I went to work and it said high fifties, low sixties.
Scott: And I'm like, "That's warm
Scott: enough.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I'm biking, I get to the old bridge.
Rym: Which bridge?
Rym: The Queensborough?
Scott: 59th Street, yeah.
Scott: It's the only bridge I can take to work.
Scott: And the wind starts going whoosh.
Scott: and I'm like, "What the fuck is
Scott: this?".
Rym: The wind was strong enough when I hit the Williamsburg Bridge this morning to catch my new helmet and pull my head to the side.
Scott: The wind was so strong that when I was going downhill, I had to pedal to go.
Scott: That's how strong it was.
Rym: How strong was that wind?
Scott: Too strong.
Scott: Right?
Scott: But meanwhile, when I checked that weather and saw high fifties, low sixties, you know what it said?
Scott: Wind-wise?
Scott: Three mile an hour wind from the north.
Rym: Yeah, did it not say 30 mile an hour gusts?
Scott: It did not say that.
Scott: It was horse shit, that weather.
Rym: See, you know what?
Rym: I was fine.
Rym: That anemometer?
Rym: Dysfunctional.
Rym: While that wind was notable, it was not in any way impinging.
Scott: I guess I made it to work.
Scott: It was not pleasant.
Rym: I also have a much longer ride than you, so by the time I get to that point, I'm in that mode of just fuck it, just pedaling, pedaling, pedaling, pedaling.
Rym: I mean, it takes me about a half hour to get to work on a bike.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Scott: Mostly the thing is, you know, it takes me like 15 minutes to get to Manhattan.
Scott: And then it takes me 15 minutes to cross town on 49th street.
Scott: because for the past, I've been biking to work since 2009.
Scott: In all four of those years, well, 9, 10, well, I guess 10, so 10, 11, 12, wow, a lot of years.
Scott: Every single year, as long as I've been biking to work, the left lane of 49th street has had permanent construction on like two blocks.
Rym: Wow, you're right now that I think about it.
Scott: That's never been, it's never, it's always been there all the time.
Rym: Maybe they just forgot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's like some new buses are deciding to stop somewhere.
Scott: It's like I was behind a bus.
Scott: I couldn't get through the spots in between.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's a red light.
Scott: It's a green light.
Scott: The bus zooms across the intersection, immediately stops blocking the entire right lane as soon as it gets through the intersection.
Scott: And there was like three buses in front of it.
Scott: I'm like, well, left lane gone, right lane gone.
Scott: And now on top of all that, right, they decided to repave 49th street.
Scott: So it's all ground the fuck up.
Rym: Might I suggest a different street?
Scott: All right, so what should I use?
Scott: 51st street or 47th street?
Rym: 51st, it's fine.
Rym: I've used it.
Scott: I'm going to try tomorrow.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Go to 55th or 58th street.
Rym: 57th, I forget.
Scott: 57th is kind of crazy.
Scott: It's full of cars and shit, but yeah, 49th street.
Scott: And then the part that's not all ground up, the deadliest potholes imaginable.
Scott: Like there was one that was like a foot deep.
Rym: Oh, there's a pothole near Manhattan Avenue in Brooklyn that if you don't notice it and you hit it in a bike and you don't have large tires, you're just fucked.
Rym: There's like two on Crescent.
Scott: Crescent's got two.
Scott: One farther up north and one near you.
Rym: I noticed that when I biked your place.
Scott: If we call 311, they're supposed to fix it.
Rym: Have you called 311?
Rym: I haven't.
Rym: Well, that's why they haven't fixed it.
Rym: We're waiting for you to call.
Scott: I'm not going to stop my bike, call 311 every time there's a pothole.
Scott: I think you had to work.
Rym: So since we're talking, I guess the show's about bikes now.
Rym: On my way home, because I was wearing glass and I thought, you know what I'm going to do?
Rym: I'm going to take a picture of everyone who does something egregious and like from now on.
Scott: You're not going to be able to push the button in time.
Rym: I was like, maybe, you know, I'll, I'll get egregious photos.
Rym: I'll make a blog that's like shit heads in New York.
Rym: Yeah, so I got an archive of 40 something shit heads just for my commute home.
Scott: In like 10 minutes.
Rym: It was like 15 or 16 people who were just biking the wrong way on a one-way bike lane.
Rym: Two of these motherfuckers.
Rym: There was, the street had a bike lane going the right way on the same street.
Scott: Dude, I could have given you 10 red light runners, right?
Scott: Just on First Avenue.
Rym: I saw some teenage shit head actually just ram into an old lady.
Rym: I stopped and she seemed okay though.
Rym: She didn't speak English.
Rym: And he was yelling at me like he wanted to start a fight with me.
Rym: That was all today.
Rym: It was awesome.
Rym: Also, I had a cab honk at me and then swerve into the left lane to get around me, almost hitting another cab who then started honking at him.
Rym: And then they got stuck stopping traffic.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, that was, it was a fun day.
Scott: He was in a hurry.
Rym: Yeah, I guess he had to be somewhere.
Rym: So yeah, I guess there's news.
Rym: It's Monday.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So it's sort of a two Twitter news, right?
Scott: So Twitter news number one is the one that people probably care about more.
Scott: And that's that Twitter is considering adding a feature that I really want, which is the mute feature whereby...
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: The fact that you even say it's a feature you want already leads into what I have to say about this.
Scott: Where you can follow someone, but you can mute them so you don't see their tweets.
Rym: Honestly, that already belies an issue with friendship and social networks.
Rym: The very fact that you need to be able to be following someone yet do not actually want to see what they have to say means that you don't want to be following them, but are under some sort of obligation to follow them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like if you follow your grandma and you don't want to see all the racist stuff.
Scott: Now, hold on, hold on.
Scott: I knew that you would go there because that is also the first thing I thought of.
Rym: And I knew because of the way you phrased this that you were leading me there so that you could then redirect.
Rym: So now I'm waiting for your redirect.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: So you are correct and I 100% agree with you.
Scott: If you're following someone, you don't actually want to see their tweets, just fucking unfollow them.
Scott: And if they notice that or get upset by it, who gives a shit?
Rym: Well, hopefully they'll stop talking to you and then you win.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: The reason to mute someone is temporary muting.
Scott: For example, so and so went somewhere and is tweeting like a fucking nut job because they're at some crazy event and you don't give any fuck.
Scott: So mute them until tomorrow.
Scott: That is the feature that I want.
Rym: That's not a bad feature.
Rym: It has to have a deadline.
Scott: So you just go and click unmute the next day.
Rym: I don't know because then you'll forget.
Rym: You might as well just unfollow them.
Scott: I'm sure there's a page you can go that will list the people you've muted.
Scott: I guess you could unfollow someone and follow them again the next day already.
Rym: Which is a better thing.
Rym: I actually still wish I could, within Twitter, very easily see when people follow and unfollow me because I've noticed that the number of followers... It's not this steady, slow, slow rise, but it'll fluctuate pretty widely week to week.
Rym: And I'd really like to see what things I say cause a bunch of people to unfollow or follow me.
Scott: The thing I really want is Twitter lists, which exists, but doesn't really exist on mobile.
Scott: That way I could categorize everyone.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Cause you know what I want?
Rym: I'd follow a lot more people or at least have a bunch of people in lists that are basically my personal equivalent of total fark.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like the people that I actually care about every single tweet they tweet, I will have in the main feed that I'm constantly reading all the time.
Scott: But say there's someone who tweets about, I don't know, something I kinda care about, maybe programming stuff that I'm doing at work.
Scott: It's like I don't want to read their tweets in my main timeline, but I could take all those people, put them in a list...
Rym: And then when you're bored...
Scott: And then only read that list.
Scott: if I need to read that list, right?
Scott: And I could be like, oh, and a Twitter in this list.
Scott: I'd probably read that list constantly, but it would at least be separated from my main feed, right?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But they don't add Twitter lists to the mobile app as far as I know.
Scott: It's like, for example...
Rym: It's like only in the web app.
Rym: Some people probably follow me for my occasional social justice related tweet, and then they're put off by my tweet.
Rym: that's just me saying f*ck a whole bunch.
Rym: Right.
Scott: The other thing is that there are people I'm friends with that are totally cool, and I follow them... And I like to read their tweets... But... They'll tweet like one gaming thing and like 20 social justice things, and it's like, I do not disagree with you at all in your, you know, things about social justice.
Scott: I am 100% with you.
Scott: But I do not want to read 50 posts about it every day.
Scott: Why is that all you talk about?
Scott: I know that it's very important, but it's not so important that I need to read 50 tweets about it when I agree with it every single day.
Scott: We know.
Scott: You know, the only other piece I can see for this... But your tweets aren't solving the problem.
Rym: Is the situation...
Scott: Anyone who's following you is already solved.
Rym: I almost, all I really want is the ability to... I want your list, like you said.
Rym: I would like the ability to mute a specific conversation.
Rym: Because, you know, like maybe like me and Mike Toole will like start half arguing about something.
Scott: And I'll reply to just one tweet and suddenly my name is getting added in every tweet.
Scott: And it's like, no, stop it.
Rym: And then we keep arguing for like another four hours.
Scott: I just tossed in one comment.
Scott: Stop that shit.
Scott: Stop adding me to everything.
Rym: I kind of like the mechanism design of that.
Rym: Like, you want to get involved in someone's argument?
Rym: Well, you're fucking involved now.
Scott: See, I'm actually curious in that when I reply to a conversation that has a bunch of people in it, I will only at the people who I can tell from the conversation that my comment is relevant to and will not at the extraneous people that has the side benefit of giving me some extra characters to work with.
Rym: I at everyone, one, out of a misplaced sense of pride for getting my ideas out with increasingly less space available.
Rym: And two, because I just don't give a shit and I don't want to think about...
Scott: You are not courteous at all.
Rym: Nope, which I think is why...
Scott: That is not a mystery.
Rym: Which I think is why my Twitter followers...
Scott: That is not a new development.
Rym: I am courteous in person.
Scott: If you are, in fact, anti-courteous, someone will tell you, "Rym, that is annoying noise.
Scott: Stop making it.
Scott: You will make it
Scott: more.".
Scott: And that is the way of Rym.
Rym: If anyone wants to read the Tower of Rym, that's line number one.
Scott: If someone is bothered by a thing, do that thing as much as possible in their presence.
Rym: But you see, you guys have to learn that if you tell me to stop it, I'll do it more.
Rym: If you don't say anything, I assume it's okay.
Rym: There's really no way out.
Scott: Anyway...
Rym: It's Rym's Gambit.
Scott: So the second...
Rym: It's my Kobayashi Maru.
Rym: The second Twitter news... You don't even know what Kobayashi Maru is, do you?
Scott: I've heard of it.
Rym: Do you know what it is?
Scott: I can't think of it right now.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: When you look it up, you'll laugh a little bit.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: The second Twitter news is that Amazon is going to let you buy things on Twitter.
Scott: Now, how the hell does that make sense?
Scott: I can already link to Amazon...
Rym: I can already see that being me accidentally buying a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Right, we can already put links to things on Amazon on Twitter and they get shortened with the Amazon URL shortener.
Rym: Now we know, here's the thing.
Rym: I want to make it quick.
Rym: This is something that I hate about every technology discussion, forum, site, blog, podcast in the world.
Rym: And if something like this is announced and the armchair coder general journalist will be like, "But what if I make a link that auto buys something for $1,000 and someone accidentally clicks on
Rym: it?".
Rym: Obviously, it won't work like that.
Scott: Obviously, you're a moron who didn't read what I actually... And the problem is, it really is not that person.
Scott: It's the person who writes the headline that Amazon lets you buy things on Twitter, which is not true at all.
Scott: That's what all the headlines say, but that's not actually what they're doing.
Scott: What they're doing is, if someone tweets a tweet with a link to an item on Amazon, and you reply to that tweet with a hashtag, I forget what the hashtag is, but it's some Amazon checkout hashtag or something, it will then add that item to your cart on Amazon, but it won't check out.
Scott: And then when you go back to Amazon and look in your cart, that item will be there.
Scott: Now... And that's all they're doing.
Scott: That actually... I don't know how that counts as buying things on Twitter at all.
Rym: It's also actually, I think, pretty exploitable.
Scott: Maybe, yeah.
Rym: So, Juan, I compromise your account...
Scott: You tweet something with the hashtag, and then other people tweet or retweet it, and now that item is in their carts.
Rym: Or I compromise your Twitter account and do that to add things to your cart, and you might not notice.
Scott: And then you accidentally check out without looking at your cart and noticing the price is ridiculously high?
Rym: Which I usually don't look at my cart that much.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: 'Cause I add things to it over the course... Like, every few weeks, I go to my cart and I'm like, "All right, there's a bunch of stuff in here.
Rym: Check
Rym: out.".
Scott: Well, you are exploitable.
Scott: I actually look at what I'm buying.
Rym: Plus, I would add little things.
Rym: I'd go for, like, two or three dollar things.
Scott: I would put my own things into fulfillment by Amazon, right?
Scott: Then, with my own affiliate account, link to them, and then get people to buy them.
Rym: Not a bad idea.
Scott: Yeah, maybe I'll make a specific Twitter account, ScottSells, and I'll start selling all the... I'm gonna sell a bunch of shit, so maybe I'll do it that way.
Scott: That'll be interesting.
Rym: You wanna sell some of my shit?
Scott: Only after I sell all my shit.
Rym: All right, 'cause I got some floodlights that I really wanna get rid of.
Scott: I don't know how to sell those on Amazon.
Scott: I only know how to sell books.
Rym: Nah, I'm sure Amazon will take them, but it might cost too much.
Rym: Oh, that's all you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It'd be cheaper to throw them away.
Rym: So, in other news, this article really hits the nail on the head.
Rym: The nail being something I'm pissed off about, and I have been for a long time.
Rym: Your name is pissed off about something?
Rym: Yeah, this issue is personal.
Scott: Well, why don't you go find that thing that you hate so much, figure out what noises it doesn't like to listen to, and make them at it?
Rym: Apparently, what it doesn't like to listen to is, "Hello, police?
Rym: Someone stole my phone.
Rym: They're right over there.
Rym: I can prove it's my phone.
Rym: Can you go take it
Rym: back?".
Rym: Nope.
Rym: So, I guess that annoying noise.
Scott: That's always weirded me out, because it's like the police won't go and get your phone when it's right there.
Scott: But if you're on the street, and your phone was literally just stolen like a minute ago, and there's a cop who happens to be nearby, they'll start a chase with no problems.
Rym: Well, that happened when my bike got stolen the second to last time.
Rym: I called the police, and they were like, "When did it get
Rym: stolen?".
Rym: I was like, "In the last five minutes,
Rym: tops.".
Rym: And then cop cars rushed over and canvassed the area.
Rym: But when they didn't find the guy right away, they instead pressured me into not... They didn't actually want me to file a police report, because crime statistics.
Rym: So, here's the deal.
Rym: Police departments around the US are warning people that we have the technology now.
Rym: If your Xbox or your iPhone gets stolen, odds are you can use technology to find out what house it's in right now, because the people who steal them usually just fucking use them.
Rym: They just fucking use them because the cops don't do anything.
Scott: All the cops will actually do is take the serial numbers of those objects, if they're expensive, and give them to pawn shops, and then the legit pawn shops, which I guess if the criminal's really dumb, they'll take it to a legit pawn shop.
Rym: If the criminal's smart, he'll just use it as long as he can.
Scott: Or sell it to a non-legit pawn shop or something.
Rym: Just use it for your phone.
Scott: And if that serial number appears, those places are supposed to report it to the police or whatever, and they usually kind of do.
Rym: I guess.
Rym: I don't really interact a lot with pawn shops.
Scott: That's really your only hope.
Rym: So, the police are warning people that even though we have this trivial technology to, "Oh, my iPhone was stolen, and it's at this apartment building.
Rym: Oh, it's walking down the street.
Rym: Oh, it's that
Rym: guy.".
Rym: They're telling us to not confront the people who have them to get them back.
Scott: Well, it is dangerous to do so.
Scott: There's no question about that.
Rym: And they're saying, "You should come to the
Rym: police.".
Rym: But I know for a fact that the police give zero shits about this.
Scott: I think the real solution here is legislative.
Scott: There needs to be a law that says the-- The police must investigate.
Scott: I think--no, it's the--I don't know what you should--something along the lines of the Consumer Detective Act.
Rym: Like, if you have on your own collected sufficient evidence that, you know-- I can shoot holes in this idea right now, but I'll let you finish.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I like the idea, but-- If you have proved and collected significant evidence, there needs to be a place where someone whose job it is to look at the evidence you brought-- Officer Scott, I've collected significant evidence that aliens stole my cell phone.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Followed by literally thousands of pages of documentation.
Scott: And your evidence is bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, my evidence is bullshit, so yeah, everyone's evidence is bullshit.
Scott: You just take it to this person who looks at it, and the person goes-- And I know how that'll work.
Rym: That person will say it's all bullshit no matter what.
Rym: Because they don't want to deal with it.
Scott: Point is, there should be, you know, obviously you have to word the law in a way.
Scott: a lawyer would word it so that there aren't stupid loopholes.
Scott: The Rym is shooting in a thing that I just said two words of.
Scott: Actually, all I would-- And the police will be forced by law to where.
Scott: if you say, "Find my iPhone.
Scott: Here it is.
Scott: It's in this
Scott: house.".
Scott: They have to go and get it.
Scott: Or you can sue them.
Scott: That's how it needs to be.
Rym: Or maybe it says if the police won't do it, you get a vigilante license.
Scott: The police won't do it.
Scott: They have to compensate you and give you what your iPhone is worth.
Rym: That'd be cool.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like, "I have proof my iPhone is in this house.
Scott: Either you help me go retrieve it, or you buy me a new
Scott: iPhone.".
Scott: And by law, they must do it.
Scott: And if they don't, you can take them to court.
Scott: And if you win in court, they pay your court fees too.
Scott: And compensate you for your time of going to court.
Scott: And the officer who refused gets fired and is never allowed to be police or military ever again in their whole lives.
Rym: This is a specific example of that situation where technology has gotten to a point to where we can do ghost-in-the-shell shit.
Rym: If someone steals your stuff, we know where it is.
Rym: Just go get it.
Scott: Right, but I'm not the invincible major who can actually go and get the thing.
Rym: Ah, but the police could use this technology to improve the quality of life of everyone.
Rym: I mean, imagine if all the petty crimes that were solvable by technology in New York City were solved.
Rym: I have a feeling that a large percentage of the people who are mugging people for their cell phones would no longer be in polite society within a few months.
Scott: I mean, if this law existed, I would buy a $2,000 bike, I'd put a GPS in it, right?
Rym: And I'd use my bike all the time.
Scott: I wouldn't even lock it.
Scott: I would leave that shit on the street, and I'd be like, "Go for
Scott: it.".
Rym: You know, Scott, I'm of the mind that while I want the government to take care of a lot of things, I believe in a modicum of due diligence.
Rym: Like, a guy shouldn't steal your car if you leave the keys in it, but if you leave the keys in it, you're a dumb fuck.
Scott: If I can find it, if I know with 100% certainty that if you take it, I'll know where it is, and you will be arrested, that's like bait.
Scott: I'd just buy shit that's expensive and leave it the fuck around with GPS in it, and it would just help fix the problem faster.
Rym: I start stealing bikes, putting them in Faraday cages and removing their obvious GPS units.
Scott: That's obviously, I said, if there's 100% certainty.
Rym: There's no certainty in life.
Scott: There is a certainty.
Rym: There's no certainty in anything.
Rym: Solipsism.
Rym: Anyway, my point is this.
Rym: This is a specific example.
Rym: I mean, we have friends who have had shit stolen.
Rym: Scott knew where his Xbox was.
Rym: Another friend actually had the ad for her bike that was stolen on Craigslist in her neighborhood.
Rym: The cops basically told her to go fuck herself.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Either legislation needs to fix this or, guys, seriously, get a really big friend or find a Hell's Angel and just go get your phone back.
Scott: I think we should just start a company, right?
Scott: We hire some people who are like...
Rym: Hire a vigilante.
Scott: No, we just hire people who were bounty hunters or were bouncers or those security professionals.
Scott: Legitimate people who aren't crazy in the head because a lot of people...
Rym: I would hire only off-duty cops.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good one, too.
Rym: Or retired cops.
Scott: Also good, right?
Scott: Any of those types of people, right?
Scott: And some of those people in those professions are crazy in the head, so we would make sure we only hire the not-crazy-in-the-head ones.
Scott: And all we would do is if you come to us and prove that your phone or your whatever is at a specific place with the serial numbers or some evidence that we're comfortable with, you pay us a fee and we will go and recover your item.
Scott: But we'll go with you to recover your item.
Rym: I'm mostly mad about the fact that police departments seem to be advocating that the correct solution to this is that stolen phones should have mandated kill switches to make them not valuable, as opposed to trivially arresting people who are probably guilty of more than one crime.
Scott: Well, here's the reason for that, right?
Scott: They don't want you to go to someone's house because it's dangerous, right?
Scott: Killing the phone proposes no danger to anyone.
Scott: If a cop has to drive somewhere and knock on a door, that's one more dangerous situation they have to be in.
Scott: They would rather no one be in any dangerous situation.
Rym: But I would argue...
Scott: I'm like, sorry, your job is to go into the dangerous situation.
Scott: That's what you signed up for.
Scott: Someone has to do it.
Scott: That's a separate discussion.
Scott: When there's a cop has a funeral, isn't there all this talk about bravery and courage?
Scott: It's like our whole society now looks down on bravery as stupidity, but it's like they want to use the word all the time to congratulate themselves, but they don't want to actually practice it.
Scott: And the rare case that someone actually does, it's like, oh my God, it's like, no, all of you should be doing that, right?
Rym: I think there's a side discussion to be had here that in general, because the police by and large will not help people with the kinds of crimes that most people experience, people don't really trust the police.
Scott: That's one reason people don't trust the police.
Rym: I am way more nervous around police than I am around shady hooded figures in an alley at night.
Rym: Like, for real.
Scott: I would be much more afraid of weird things that could happen if I go to the police station and say the wrong thing.
Scott: And weird things that could happen if I go try to recover my phone.
Rym: The only thing I'm more afraid of than cops is judges.
Rym: When I'm in a courtroom, I'm just sitting perfectly silent, even if I'm not on trial, just like, please don't send me to jail for nothing.
Rym: I guess I'd be more afraid if I was in a jail that they'd accidentally keep me there, but I don't go into jails.
Rym: And I will never will.
Scott: Or prison.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Scott: I'm just going to leave my phone here and call the police and be like, this guy, my friend stole my phone.
Rym: I'm sure they'll come after me.
Rym: I'm sure that'll happen.
Scott: You'll go to that jail you never wanted to go to.
Rym: I'm sure the police will get right on recovering that cell phone.
Scott: Maybe they will.
Rym: Meanwhile, I'll be in your apartment, I'll claim squatters rights.
Rym: It'll take you at least three months to kick me out.
Rym: Plus, I've never actually been convicted of trespassing, breaking, or entering.
Rym: Though I've been chased before.
Rym: So yeah, things of the day.
Rym: I've got kind of serious things of the day.
Scott: The mayonnaise is a big deal.
Rym: Mayonnaise?
Scott: I don't like mayonnaise.
Scott: It doesn't taste good.
Rym: What the fuck, Scott?
Scott: Chipotle mayo tastes good.
Rym: That's just mayo plus something.
Scott: Yeah, but that covers up the nasty taste of regular mayonnaise.
Rym: How can you hate mayonnaise?
Rym: It's disgusting.
Rym: It's as American as apple pie and trans fat.
Scott: I'd never put mayonnaise on something on purpose.
Scott: If I get like a chicken sandwich or something, it happens to be on there.
Scott: It's like, okay, but yeah, I'd never put mayonnaise on something intentionally.
Rym: So, mayone.us.
Rym: We don't talk about politics often on GeekNights.
Rym: We will do a Thursday show about this in depth later.
Rym: Scott and I both gave money to a super PAC.
Rym: That shit doesn't happen.
Rym: So, I urge you to go to this thing, read about it, and consider the fact that me, I'm a little more politically motivated, and Scott gave money to a political cause.
Scott: Well, it's, you know, why'd lack political motivation?
Scott: Because government's just fucking corrupt and you're not gonna do anything anyway.
Rym: Yeah, Lawrence Lessig's argument, corruption is the first thing we have to solve.
Rym: We can't solve anything until we solve corruption.
Scott: I 100% agree with that.
Scott: I agreed with it before he even said it.
Rym: So, as I've noticed, I was going through some of the details, it seems like mostly Democrats are on board with this, and mostly Republicans are not.
Scott: Well, but they're both corrupt as fuck.
Rym: Yeah, they are, but Democrats are at least paying this some lip service.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Scott: He's been playing at lip service for how many years and done nothing.
Rym: He?
Rym: So, the Democrats are embodied as a male?
Scott: Obama, specifically, said in his campaign- Oh, Obama.
Scott: Yes, he specifically said that he would do things to fight, you know, the influence of money in Washington, and it's been like six years, and he's done nothing.
Rym: Well, because it's Congress's job, really.
Scott: He didn't even say anything.
Scott: Since being elected, he did nothing.
Scott: Didn't even say something, like, "Hey, Congress-".
Rym: Well, that's because he's too busy covering up the aliens at Benghazi.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: Actually, Bill Clinton said, there was an interview with him, unrelated.
Scott: Well, somewhat related.
Scott: He said that when he became president, he sent his aides to go check out Area 51 for aliens, and that there weren't any.
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure that, one, even if- I mean, I'm assuming there's no aliens in Area 51.
Rym: But, if there were, the aides who came back were either lizard people, clones- Of course.
Rym: And if he said he wanted to go there himself, they'd just drive him to some warehouse somewhere.
Scott: But anyway, the mayonnaise, right, the deal is, is they're gonna have a super PAC, and use the money to, basically, run ads to make sure that corrupt fucking congressmen don't get elected.
Scott: On an individual level, so they're gonna pick specific elections- And beat them, so they don't get elected back into Congress.
Rym: They're trying to get the most bang for their buck, and, basically, the deal is, if they get a million dollars worth of pledges, they have unnamed donors who will match that, doubling our power.
Scott: So there are at least some rich people who don't want to have to pay- They would rather not have to pay Washington and have the government be uncorrupt, than just pay Washington and get what they want.
Rym: Now, this is the same Lawrence Lessig that you're thinking of.
Rym: He's also proposed a constitutional amendment in his free ebook, One Way Forward, that is a specific proposal on a way to fix this problem.
Rym: Since no one paid attention to that, he's doing this instead.
Scott: Right, now how much confidence do I have that this will work in any way?
Rym: More than zero!
Scott: More than zero, which isn't much, but you know what?
Scott: What else has any chance at all?
Scott: Nothing realistic that anyone has proposed or is doing at all in any way, anywhere.
Rym: The money I gave this thing probably counts more than any vote I've ever cast.
Scott: Right, so, I mean, the arrow's probably gonna miss, but no one else shooting any, so might as well shoot if I don't pay and ain't gonna shoot.
Rym: Unless he's aiming at us, but at least it's Lawrence Lessig.
Rym: He definitely is not aiming at us.
Scott: Look, guys, if we can- Lawrence Lessig, certified, smart, good person.
Rym: If we can't trust Lawrence Lessig, we should just end human society right now, because we're fucked.
Scott: One thing I am worried about, right, and this is sort of con- also cons- you know, speaking of aliens, conspiracy nuttiness, right, but if this shit starts to move, right, it's sort of like, it's all him, right?
Scott: If someone tries to assassinate him, what are we gonna do?
Rym: No one cares about it now, but if there's significant progress, and we're getting close to the point where we can do something- He assembled a board of directors that- imagine if you did this, and you assembled the board of directors of people to work with you on it.
Rym: He did the same thing.
Rym: He's got a bunch of people working on it.
Rym: You'd probably have to take all of them out.
Scott: Listen, these powers that be that can control a government with money can kill a bunch of people in a- I'm gonna make a reference.
Rym: I'm curious if you get this reference.
Rym: You got to be a spirit.
Rym: You can't be no ghost.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's ultra relevant.
Rym: You have no idea?
Scott: I know, it's that movie where the guy's president but he doesn't give a shit.
Rym: Okay, you know.
Rym: Bullworth.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Good movie.
Rym: Really depressing movie.
Scott: I prefer Dave, which is just like, "I'm president?
Scott: Yeah, I'm just gonna do
Scott: it.".
Rym: Dave is the eagle of American politics.
Scott: That's exactly right.
Scott: Yeah, Dave and Eagle are my style.
Rym: Yeah, I think Bullworth is the-.
Rym: no, this is how it really would go down.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So you got a thing of the day?
Scott: I do.
Scott: So this guy had this idea, genius idea.
Scott: Every day he gets up and looks in the mirror in the bathroom, and he sees his ugly face, and he says, "You know what?
Scott: It'd be really cool if when I looked at this mirror, I saw other things while I was brushing my teeth.
Scott: For example, maybe news headlines, or the weather, and we have technology.
Scott: Why can't that happen?
Scott: How much time would I save?
Scott: I wouldn't sit at my computer.
Scott: I could do two things at once.
Scott: I could wash my face and my hands and also get the news reading done.
Scott: How much time would I save in the morning?
Scott: I could bike around a little bit and then go to
Scott: work.".
Scott: So you know what he does?
Scott: He goes and first he acquires a piece of observation glass, which is not the same as one-way glass.
Scott: One-way glass is one side is black and the other side you see through.
Scott: Or one side is a mirror and the other side you see through.
Scott: This is what they have in police observation rooms, where if the lights in one room are on and the other ones are off, then you can only see through one way and the other side's a mirror.
Scott: But if the lights in both rooms are on, it's just a piece of glass.
Scott: And it's crazy that that even works.
Scott: But I'm sure the internet will tell you how that works.
Scott: I didn't look it up on the internet yet.
Scott: Then he took that piece of glass that it was kind of hard to get, actually, and he put a monitor behind it, and he made a webpage on the monitor with a Raspberry Pi with a black screen, and he only put the stuff he wanted to see in white text.
Scott: So it's like a mirror that he can look at his own face in, but then information shows through.
Rym: That's the kind of thing you see in movies that you think, "Oh, that'd be really
Rym: cool.".
Scott: Well, it exists today and you can build your own and maybe you can turn it into a product.
Rym: And hopefully not burn your bathroom down.
Scott: And get a good price in observation glass and shitty Chinese LCD screens.
Rym: I'd be worried about burning my bathroom down, at least a little bit.
Scott: Oh, maybe you don't put it in the bathroom.
Scott: Maybe it's a bedroom mirror.
Rym: I don't have a bedroom mirror.
Rym: Maybe I should get one.
Scott: So you can look at your -- hang it on the ceiling?
Rym: The only mirror I have is in the bathroom, which sometimes is a problem, actually.
Scott: The only thing I really like -- my mirror is gigantic in the bathroom, but I lack the full-length mirror.
Rym: Because you really got to see if those slacks are -- I know.
Rym: Matching the purse and the shoes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: All right, metamoment.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Connecticut.
Rym: It's coming up.
Scott: Oh, is it the next convention?
Rym: It's the next convention we're going to be going to.
Rym: So Connecticut's awesome.
Rym: If you didn't submit a panel, well, it's way too fucking late for that.
Rym: I'm in the middle of scheduling everything, currently.
Rym: Yeah, Connecticut's awesome.
Rym: It's the best non-Pax, non-Magfest gaming convention I can think of in the United States.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Pretty much straight up.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Other news I can see on my calendar.
Scott: Today is Cinco de Mayo.
Scott: Party.
Rym: I saw the most racist ad that a frat put out for their Drinco -- It was all Corona?
Rym: They put on a Drinco del Mayo event, and the poster was racist to the point of,
Rym: "Ah.".
Scott: Ah.
Rym: Ah.
Rym: It was really bad.
Rym: I think their frat guy kicked off campus, though.
Scott: Good.
Scott: I guess the Netrunner Regionals, where I live, are coming up.
Scott: So there's one on the 28th -- oh, 21st of June, and one on the 19th of July.
Scott: All right.
Scott: One's in Boston, one's in Philly.
Scott: Fuck you, not putting one in New York.
Scott: What other news is there, really, for meta-ness?
Scott: Oh, the book club is -- You forgot the name again.
Rym: It's your book.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: I didn't start reading it yet.
Scott: I probably should acquire it.
Rym: I'll acquire it and read it because I'm flying.
Rym: There's going to be no GeekNights next week.
Rym: I've got to fly to London and Stockholm and Hamburg and Dublin.
Scott: I guess I'll be biking and Netrunning.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So no GeekNights.
Rym: We'll see if we get anything done this coming weekend to have a little bit of bonus content along the way.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: Tuesday episodes of GeekNights will be streaming live on Twitch once we short out the rest of the shit to make that happen.
Rym: A lot of shit that has to be sorted for that.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: For other things, check out all our stuff on the internet.
Scott: We have YouTube channels, even though mine's mostly Netrunner videos.
Rym: Mine's mostly GeekNights lectures.
Scott: We've got Twitters.
Scott: We've got Facebooks.
Scott: We've got Google+.
Scott: We have IRC.
Scott: We have a newsletter that I said I was going to write, but I didn't write, but I'm going to add it to my.
Scott: Remember the Milk right the fuck now.
Rym: Well, I forgot about it after last show.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I can't log in to Remember the Milk right now.
Scott: But anyway, I'm definitely going to write another newsletter.
Rym: I'm definitely going to forget it until Wednesday.
Rym: We have forums.
Scott: Sign up for them.
Scott: We have every possible thing on the internet.
Scott: However you communicate on the internet, you should go.
Rym: But Black Dynamite, I only use Gopher.
Scott: Gopher's dead, Black Dynamite.
Scott: It hasn't been used since, like, I'm sure someone's going to tell me it's not dead, but it might as well be dead, right?
Rym: It's pretty much dead.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Any place you go on the internet to communicate and be with people, we are in that place.
Scott: If you're listening to this, why would you not also be in that place with us?
Scott: At least a little bit.
Scott: Go find that place and be happy.
Rym: So, you bought some technology.
Scott: I guess I did.
Scott: So, I bought this camera that we sort of needed, I guess.
Scott: I mean, we didn't 100% need it, but if we want to do awesome video shit.
Rym: It could be argued that we needed it to justify the cost.
Scott: Sure, maybe.
Scott: So, the camera I got is the GH4.
Scott: Panasonic GH4, which is a Micro Four Thirds mirrorless camera.
Scott: But the main feature of it, compared to the GH3, is that it can record 4K video.
Scott: And it's only, like, $1,700, which is very expensive.
Scott: But compared to any other camera that shoots 4K, that's not like a tiny GoPro or something, this is pretty much it.
Scott: Like, the next cheapest camera is, like, $4,000.
Scott: And after that, tens of thousands or hundreds of thousands of dollars to shoot 4K video.
Scott: So, that's sort of ridiculous that it even exists.
Scott: And it's pretty incredible.
Scott: You can basically use this shit to make professional movies and TV shows, like Hollywood level.
Scott: You know, you might need extra equipment around the camera, such as lighting and such and such.
Rym: Yep, that's where I've been acquiring surprisingly expensive doodads.
Scott: Yep, lighting, lenses, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: But the camera on its own for $1,700 does all that.
Scott: Upgrade, and it helped, because I had a GF2 going to the GH4, right?
Scott: And they both used the same Micro Four Thirds lenses.
Scott: So, it's like, "Oh, all the lenses I already bought are still
Scott: good.".
Scott: And, you know, I sort of realized, since starting to get cameras that actually change lenses, the lenses are the more expensive part, and they're the part you actually care about, right?
Scott: Because you buy a lens, it's good for fucking ever, right?
Scott: The body of the camera, it's like, that shit, you just get new ones every few years, right?
Scott: That shit gets out of date.
Rym: So, we'll see what we can do with this.
Rym: I mean, there's a lot of, like, basically what we have to do now, me and Scott, is with this new camera and actually trying to do video content on a regular basis.
Rym: You might remember the old, old days of GeekNights, like eight years ago, where it took us a while to make a pipeline that we follow the pipeline and GeekNights comes out.
Rym: Like, it used to be, like, every night we'd, like, talk for an hour about what we were going to do the show on.
Rym: We'd fuck around the mixer and plug a bunch of stuff in.
Rym: We'd talk a bunch, re-talk some stuff.
Rym: I'd edit for, like, two hours, start the encoder, that would take, like, a half hour.
Rym: Then we, like, manually input all this data into a website on a pretty primitive backend.
Rym: It was a tough time, and over time, we refined, refined, refined, and now it takes about five more minutes than the time we spend talking to do an episode.
Rym: So, we got a good pipeline there.
Rym: Video's an order of magnitude more work.
Scott: I don't think it will be possible to get the video pipeline down, and let me tell you, I used the camera to record some Netrunner games, right?
Scott: I did it in 1080p, not 4K, and I did it at the lowest bitrate, which is 50 megabits per second.
Scott: You could take it all the way up to 200 megabits per second, 1080p, which will do something called All Eye.
Scott: So, what All Eye is, is normally, when you're, like, because it's recording, like, an MOV or MP4, right?
Scott: Normally, if there's, like, two frames of video next to each other, and one pixel is the same color in both frames, it doesn't store the pixel twice.
Scott: It's just, like, yeah, that pixel's the same, bro.
Scott: And it saves space that way, right?
Scott: When you do All Eye, it actually stores each frame individually.
Scott: So, if you edit it in After Effects or something, or Photoshop, right, you can edit all the frames individually, right?
Scott: So, I didn't even use that mode.
Scott: I used the 50 megabit per second, 30 FPS mode, well, 29.97 FPS mode.
Rym: Ooh, not even 60 for that good action?
Scott: Yeah, and I recorded all these, you know, four rounds of Netrunners.
Scott: It took up almost the whole 128 gig SD card.
Scott: Yeah, well, it took an hour just to transfer that to the computer.
Rym: Welcome to my world, where our existing pipeline to video like a GeekNights lecture, which is an hour long, on my old prosumer camcorder that has a 300 gig hard drive in it, compressed pretty heavily the video that comes out, 1080p60.
Rym: It's about 20 to 30 gigabytes per panel, and that's with old-as-shit technology, heavily compressed.
Rym: And it takes me a while to turn that into a resulting video that is now for people to watch on YouTube.
Rym: So, you gonna store all that B-roll forever?
Rym: Hold on to that B-roll?
Scott: It's not B-roll.
Rym: It's the A-roll.
Scott: It's only A-roll.
Rym: You gonna hold on to that A-roll?
Scott: I got space.
Rym: For now.
Rym: How many Netrunner things you gonna go to?
Scott: A lot.
Rym: So, I'm already working on a pipeline for massive video files.
Rym: I might have to upgrade my computer in the near future to handle this stuff.
Scott: My computer is pretty much as upgraded as it gets.
Scott: I mean, my NAS is full of drives.
Scott: So, you know, there's not really much I can upgrade other than getting some like monster servers or something else you can do, right?
Scott: And this is what Vimeo actually does, is when they need to encode, when you send your video upload to Vimeo to get encoded, right?
Scott: They send your video to all these Amazon instances that just spring up, encode your video, and then shut down, right?
Scott: So, you can just like get, you know, some ridiculous cloud server on Amazon.
Scott: If your internet is fast enough, upload your video, encode it, download it again, and you'll actually, if your bandwidth, if your download and upload are fast enough, you'll actually save time because the encoding will be so fast.
Scott: And you got some ridiculously powerful machine to do the encoding, which costs a lot of money, but you're only using it for what, five minutes?
Scott: So, you only paid like a dollar to use that machine for five minutes maybe, right?
Scott: And you can actually, you know, if it saves you a lot of time, that's fucking worth it, right?
Scott: I would pay a dollar to save a couple hours of time.
Rym: Yup, absolutely.
Rym: But all that aside, what I've been researching, and I actually haven't bought anything yet because it's a very complex field made more complex by the fact that we live in New York.
Rym: We want good microphones.
Scott: We have lots of good microphones.
Rym: We do, but they're very bad, they're good for recording like GeekNights.
Rym: They're not good for recording lectures at conventions because we can't bring all this shit with us.
Rym: And even then it's hard to integrate it into their systems.
Rym: and then on video, like we don't like to hold microphones.
Scott: Yeah, holding microphones on video is only good in certain situations.
Scott: Usually where, you know, if you're doing like a TV show, like where you're a sitcom, you don't want to see anything on the screen, right?
Scott: So you need to have a boom guy, right?
Scott: Holding the microphone up above.
Rym: Or a bunch of lavaliers, a lot of ways you can do it.
Scott: You don't use lavaliers when you don't want anyone to see the microphone at all.
Scott: It depends.
Scott: On a sitcom, but you could use lavaliers on, say, a talk show where it's okay for people to see that, right?
Scott: But then if you're like, you know, doing an interview with someone on the street, holding a microphone as a news reporter, that's okay with a little box around it, you know, and you kind of want to have that.
Scott: You want that there, right?
Scott: That's like the thing that people are used to seeing and you get your logo on there and everything.
Scott: And it also helps not just on the screen when people are watching at home, but also in person, like when you're on the street, right?
Scott: You can't just wire someone up with a lavalier to interview them, right?
Scott: But you still need to mic them.
Rym: It's interesting because I've seen a lot of reporters do just that when they're interviewing people.
Scott: They wire people up with a lavalier.
Rym: Yeah, they wire you up with a lavalier and then they do the interview and then they take it off.
Scott: It's so much faster to just walk up to somebody like, "Hey, how you
Scott: doing?".
Scott: Shove the microphone in their face.
Rym: Yeah, it depends on what you're doing there.
Rym: So hence, pipeline.
Rym: So the problem is, the one thing that really prevents this from being easy, we don't have studio space.
Scott: No.
Rym: And even if we did, we're kind of trying to get studio space in the city somewhere.
Scott: Just to the west of my apartment near the bake shop, there's all sorts of industrial-ish, empty-ish places.
Scott: And there's a lot of tiny businesses that have moved in there, like Random Hair Salon.
Scott: I saw yesterday, there's some Bosnian group hang out.
Scott: They bought a space.
Scott: They're renting it or whatever.
Scott: And they were just Bosnian dudes hanging out together.
Scott: And it's like, that's cool.
Rym: We should make a gaming society that's like that.
Scott: I'm sure we can find a space.
Scott: We just need to find a way to pay for it.
Rym: Yeah, but it's also a space that we'll then be leaving a lot of very expensive equipment in.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know.
Scott: But the other key is that for lighting, to save a lot of money, if you could get some west- or east-facing windows.
Rym: Yeah, because we totally do all our video when the sun's out.
Scott: What I'm saying is, if you can get some east- or west-facing windows, you can do video in the morning or the afternoon when the sun is shining right through those windows.
Rym: Actually, through the windows like that usually is not great lighting, just because of the angles involved and the glass.
Scott: The sun is the best light.
Rym: Yeah, naked sun.
Rym: Not sun, through glass at an angle that you can't control.
Scott: No, we're talking about huge fucking windows, not tiny little box windows.
Rym: Yeah, that doesn't exist here.
Scott: It does.
Scott: Some guy was telling me how he bought a space.
Rym: Yeah, you told me about this guy.
Rym: Yeah, that's not going to happen.
Rym: Not feasible.
Rym: Also then, what, we're only going to do video on Saturday and Sunday during the golden hour?
Scott: Well, only video that needs to be really bright.
Rym: So, here's an example of a very specific issue.
Rym: I'm not going to install booms in my house for microphones.
Rym: And I can't pad the entire living room in acoustic foam.
Rym: So, the only way to get good audio when we do a video is either to close mic us with our existing Geeknives microphones.
Scott: Which you'll see in the video.
Rym: Which wouldn't be that bad.
Scott: We could dub over ourselves.
Rym: Yeah, because we'll totally do that.
Rym: ADR.
Rym: That'll totally happen.
Scott: It'll be hilarious.
Scott: ADR.
Rym: But because of the restrictions on the room and the fact that I also don't want to just tear apart the living room every time we do video.
Rym: Because the idea is we're going to be doing video like once a week.
Scott: Well, hopefully.
Rym: Yeah, or at least once every other week.
Scott: Make more videos.
Rym: So, I need microphones that don't require shit to be set up in the living room to do it.
Rym: Because right now, either I put these microphones in front of our faces and then they cast shadows because despite all the lights I own, there's still not enough lights.
Rym: We can't be far enough away from the background to just green screen or whatever it out.
Rym: So, the other option is I can mount one boom higher up temporarily and do a stereo mic from the ceiling.
Rym: And it works okay, but the audio's not great.
Rym: And it's a giant pain in the ass to set that up every time.
Rym: So, what we want is if Scott's buying an expensive camera, I've been investigating to buy the E6 Countryman head-mounted microphone.
Rym: Which appears to be the best head-mounted microphone.
Scott: That's the one they use in the TED Talks.
Scott: It's like a little flesh-colored stick.
Scott: Most of the equipment is on your ear, right?
Scott: And then it's just sort of this little stick that comes out and then in front of your mouth.
Rym: It is so tiny.
Scott: You can see it, but you forget it's there.
Scott: It's great if you don't care if someone sees it, but you want really high quality and you don't want to hold anything.
Rym: Everyone I've ever talked to, all the research I've ever done, this is the fucking best.
Rym: So, duh, we'll get that.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But you gotta plug that shit into something.
Rym: Now, here's where it gets complicated and annoying.
Rym: This is where professional equipment is so much more expensive and harder to deal with than prosumer equipment.
Rym: Like Scott's camera.
Rym: If we want to do full-on, full-on video, camera's not enough.
Rym: We need this huge base station to plug into it, which is like two grand by itself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This camera, the reason I got it is because of that very reason, right?
Scott: It's this weird piece of equipment in that, in the hands of a pro with all this extra shit, it can get the job done.
Scott: It's great.
Scott: But also, you could just, as a photographer, just a normal person, it's totally usable, just on its own.
Scott: It's extreme rarity, right, in the world of audio/video production, that this one thing, like, expands such a wide range of amateur to professional use.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But even then, you need all this extra equipment and pipelines to do the, like, if you want to use it in a studio, you need a bunch of other shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, if you just take this to your house and, like, take a video of you, it'll probably be a good video, right?
Scott: But it's not going to look like a fucking Hollywood movie.
Rym: So here's the complication with the E6 microphone.
Rym: For one, it has a ridiculous number of options that if you don't already, if you aren't already an expert in this stuff, it won't make any sense.
Scott: What could the options possibly be?
Rym: It has to do with the kind of cartridge in it, how directional it is, how much padding it has.
Scott: Wouldn't there just be the one they use at TED Talks?
Rym: They use different ones for different people.
Rym: There's a lot of options.
Rym: So we know that stuff.
Rym: We sort that stuff out.
Scott: That's crazy though, right?
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Scott: It's like, there's no different SM58s for different people, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, do you use an SM58 or a beta 87A or a beta 58?
Scott: This is a beta 58A.
Rym: Yeah, I bought that specifically.
Scott: Do you need different ones or different people?
Rym: So my microphone is a beta 87A.
Scott: Oh.
Rym: It's got a more cardioid pattern.
Rym: It's a hypercardioid.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Which means if I move my head too much, suddenly I'm really quiet.
Scott: You also just talked really quietly.
Rym: No, I guess I did.
Rym: Talking at the same volume, now I'm next to the microphone, now I'm going back to the front of the microphone.
Rym: So anyway, tons of options, tons of complicated shit.
Rym: But we know this stuff, so that's fine, and this thing's the best.
Rym: So what do you plug it into?
Rym: Well, if we just wanted to do video in the house, I could get it hardwired to XLR, powered with phantom power, plug it directly into the mixer with a cable.
Scott: But that has a long-ass wire.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: That's doable.
Scott: And we couldn't really walk around a lot either.
Scott: Easily doable.
Scott: How do you hide that wire?
Scott: Down your shirt, down your pants, onto the floor, across the room?
Rym: Well, down your shirt, down your pants, behind us is sitting the Marantz.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: That kind of rhymed.
Rym: Like, that actually would work pretty well.
Rym: There are cases where I would want to use the wired option.
Rym: Like, for example, if I'm just doing a Twitch video and I got my face on screen and doing some stuff, I'd kind of just want to plug it into the mixer and go.
Scott: You could also just, like, walk around the convention and sort of have the Marantz hanging, like, behind you on your belt, flapping against your butt.
Rym: So here's how we do it.
Rym: I wear the Marantz.
Scott: You're wearing the thing.
Scott: The wires are behind you, but the video's only in front of you.
Scott: And the Marantz is battery-powered.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So we can sync that shit up later.
Rym: Lots of stuff we can do there.
Rym: that's nice and cool.
Rym: But the cartridge, the actual microphone, is fundamentally different.
Rym: if you want to wire it hard-wired to be able to take phantom power and plug it into a mixer versus if you want to plug it into a wireless system.
Rym: And guess what?
Rym: Half the other times we want to use this is, like, at a convention, we want to use our awesome microphone instead of the shitty microphones that, like, Pax gives us.
Scott: Yeah, we have to buy two.
Rym: So, no, we have to buy...
Scott: A wired one and an unwired one.
Rym: Four.
Scott: For two people.
Scott: Four.
Rym: Yeah, they're, like, four to six hundred bucks each.
Scott: Well, my camera was seventeen hundred, so five hundred times four is about the same amount of money.
Rym: Now, say we want to do wireless.
Scott: Plus, you're not even counting the lenses I bought.
Scott: I bought a thousand-dollar lens, also.
Rym: That is a really good lens, though.
Rym: That lens...
Scott: I mean, because the other lenses were not really the greatest for video, so...
Rym: Yeah, yeah, they're not.
Rym: Like, my pancake lens, not good at video at all.
Scott: Yeah, no.
Rym: Yeah, zoom lens, I can kind of wing it, but I got to manual focus that shit out of time.
Scott: No, that lens is so not sharp.
Scott: That's the cheapo.
Rym: Yeah, but it works pretty well.
Scott: It works, yeah.
Rym: Especially if I'm going down to, like, 720p, anyway.
Rym: So, wireless systems, if you've never dealt with wireless, I'll just say this.
Rym: If a band tours, either every single venue they go to, they contact and say, "Take care of all the microphones for us," or they hire an RF manager.
Rym: The RF manager tours with them and figures out what equipment and frequencies and everything to use in every venue.
Rym: So, if Scott and I buy some, like, cheapo wireless microphone shit, it might work here, but it might not work very well in Chicago.
Rym: Just fuck you.
Scott: Well, isn't that why you can change, you know, channels on it?
Scott: So, we go to Chicago, and we push the "Search for New Channel" button, and it's supposed to find a channel.
Rym: Yeah, so already, if you want the ones that let you search for a channel, that's, like, twice the price getting into prosumer territory.
Scott: All right, well, that's already mandatory, right?
Rym: Yeah, so that already eliminates most of these systems in the world.
Rym: So, if you look at Just Sure...
Scott: But even if we just buy those, that should be fine, right?
Scott: Eh.
Scott: We don't need an RF manager.
Rym: So, if those have a single antenna, as opposed to dual channel, then odds are, if you walk around at all, your audio will just periodically drop out for a second.
Scott: Yeah, you added that you're not hitting the one antenna.
Rym: Yeah, because fuck you.
Rym: Two antennas eliminates that.
Scott: All right, so you need two antennas.
Rym: That eliminates a bunch more of these types.
Scott: And searching for a channel.
Rym: So, basically, eventually...
Scott: But we have two people, so we actually need four antennas and two searching for channels.
Rym: So, eventually, you get into, like, if you go to Sure, the ULX S&P series.
Scott: Aren't they competitors?
Rym: Yeah, I'm just, I know Sure, and they seem to be the ones I'm going to buy.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I've used, like, other types before, but I've always used them in the sense of either someone else rented them and I just configured them.
Rym: I never had to think in terms of...
Scott: Do the Cavaliers, the Canyon people, also make the wireless things?
Rym: They actually, no.
Rym: So, when you buy their microphone, then you tell it what kind of wireless system you're going to use with it, and then they make it custom for that system.
Rym: The connectors are all different.
Rym: It's not just XLR.
Scott: Why wouldn't they make an interchangeable connector?
Rym: Because the voltages are also different, because if you're pushing regular old phantom power from something with a 9-volt battery in it on your back, that's not going to work so well.
Rym: So, they take different voltages.
Rym: So, I came down to the ULX S&P versions.
Rym: The differences between them are almost negligible.
Scott: Why do they even have two different versions?
Rym: So, the S is considered the prosumer version.
Rym: It's pretty much awesome, but it doesn't have group scan.
Rym: ULXP has group scan.
Scott: So, group scan is when you have more than one.
Rym: Group scan says the unit will find a group, because every different wireless system has a set of channel groups.
Rym: So, you pick a group, and then each microphone needs a channel within that group.
Rym: So, the group scan will find the group near you that has the least interference and thus most available channels.
Scott: And then it will give one channel to one guy and one channel to the other guy?
Rym: Basically, yes.
Rym: Without group scan, you have to just fucking guess at which group and then scan within the group.
Rym: Wouldn't have been a problem, but the difference between the two is only like $200 per unit, and everything I ever read on the internet from anyone said, "Really wish I bought the P. Wasn't that much more
Rym: money.".
Scott: Can you imagine sitting there going like, "How many channels are there?
Scott: 12?".
Rym: There's like 9 to 12 groups.
Scott: You sit there with number 1, and you scan it, and then 2, and then you scan it, and you're manually pushing the buttons.
Scott: Wouldn't you pay money to never have to push those buttons?
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So, this gets more complicated.
Rym: There's a lot of cheap systems on eBay.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: That shit's all illegal.
Scott: Wait.
Scott: How could it be illegal?
Scott: If it's on eBay, it's illegal.
Scott: Wouldn't eBay say, "Hey, you can't sell that illegal equipment.
Scott: We're taking down your
Scott: listing.".
Rym: Because people don't even know.
Scott: If I try to sell a gun on eBay, eBay's like, "Fuck
Scott: no.".
Rym: A lot of people still don't know.
Rym: So, in 2010, it finally became illegal to use wireless microphones on the 700 MHz band.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: Because that band, after the whole digital TV conversion and a whole bunch of stuff that happened, is used primarily by reserved special services, police, fire, EMT.
Scott: Wait.
Scott: I don't get that.
Scott: Emergency services had frequencies they've been using forever.
Rym: That were overcrowded and not that effective.
Rym: The whole idea is that they rejiggered a lot of the frequencies to make better frequencies available.
Scott: So, if they rejiggered over to 700 MHz, they must have left some... What were they used to be using?
Scott: We can use that now, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, that's also reserved for other things.
Rym: And every wireless system works in different ranges.
Rym: And if you want to use a particular wireless system, the advice everyone gives you comes down to, "Well, where are you installing this?
Rym: What TV stations are active near
Rym: you?".
Rym: So, shit got complicated way quick.
Rym: And one blog listed cities in terms of difficulty.
Rym: Like, how pro...
Scott: Well, New York is going to be most difficult.
Rym: Yeah, the list was like, how pro...
Scott: New York is god mode.
Rym: How pro does your RF manager need to be to handle a concert in this city?
Rym: And at the top, by itself, New York.
Scott: Right, but wouldn't you be in... Most of the good concert venues are in a shielded stage place, right?
Scott: Where you're not going to interfere with anything outside the building.
Rym: Yeah, you'll interfere with your own shit internally.
Scott: Right, but if you're doing an outdoor concert, fuck you.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So, doing all this research and all this research, I finally got to the end.
Rym: I figured out everything to buy, kind of like how Scott did all this research.
Rym: Like, this is the camera.
Rym: It's worth the money.
Rym: So, I decided to get a ULXP system.
Rym: I go to buy one.
Rym: And then, oh, ULXP's can be bought in one of three bands.
Scott: Which one is the New York one?
Rym: So, each band has its own set of frequencies.
Rym: They're all hardware, so if you buy one, you want to use a different band?
Scott: Fuck you.
Scott: You've got to buy three of each.
Rym: Also, say we buy the G3 band, I think is one of them.
Rym: And all the other systems use different bands and different band names, different band sets.
Rym: So, if you want to use that system at SayPax, depending on what band...
Scott: So, we're going to take our equipment to Seattle and then to Boston, but we might need a different one in a different place than New York.
Rym: And it doesn't just depend on the city.
Rym: SayPax already has a bunch of equipment.
Rym: What bands are they using?
Rym: What channels are three?
Scott: Can't we just hook up to their equipment?
Rym: Maybe, if they'll let us.
Scott: Oh, but wait.
Scott: But our lavaliers are for our equipment.
Rym: Now, we could plug our lavaliers because the one part of the reason why I want to go with Shure is because every con we've ever been to has used Shure wireless.
Rym: And I know the connector, I know how that shit works.
Rym: Even the anime club at RIT, that's what we used when we had microphones.
Rym: So, we could plug our countrymen into their battery packs and just use our awesome microphone there without having to bring the other equipment.
Rym: Which is fine.
Scott: Oh, Zenkai Con, they had Sennheiser.
Rym: Yeah, Zenkai Con.
Rym: PAX and everyone else had Shure.
Rym: In fact, I took pictures of all the equipment at all the PAXes to do the research later.
Rym: So, yeah, that got real complicated real quick.
Rym: And the moral of all this, I guess, is unless you need pro equipment, don't fucking buy pro equipment.
Scott: Man, it's so weird.
Scott: It's like, is it that thing with the Bloomberg terminal where it's hard just to make pros feel like they know something?
Scott: Or is it just, it's hard because it's pro?
Rym: Oh, and by the way, are you licensed or not?
Rym: Because if you buy some wireless microphone systems and you set them up in certain ways, oh, you're breaking the law.
Rym: You're fucked if the FCC comes knocking.
Scott: But couldn't you just get the license for the FCC?
Rym: FCC license for microphone broadcast locally at higher amplitudes or different reserve frequency ranges costs a lot of money.
Scott: But a ham radio license doesn't cost much.
Rym: Ham radio is a totally different thing.
Scott: Come on, all the licenses should be the same.
Scott: Why is this one so expensive?
Rym: It's not that it's so expensive, it's that it's expensive for us not making money.
Rym: Also, you have to have a legit reason and be something.
Rym: Podcast doesn't count.
Scott: Why don't we just go to a different country that doesn't have an FCC?
Rym: Yeah, other countries, it's way complicated.
Rym: Basically, all this equipment I'm looking at, US only.
Rym: Do not bring it to the EU, they'll confiscate it.
Scott: Why don't we just go to the northern, well, no, not the northern part, near the tropics on an island where there's no one interfering with anything.
Rym: and who gives a fuck?
Rym: And then in the middle of our Twitch broadcast, you hear the pirate radio.
Rym: just start chiming in.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: Actually, that was pretty awesome.
Scott: Dude, if I lived in a boat in the tropics, I would listen to the pirate radio.
Rym: I'd be looking forward to it.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: And then I'd see the guy in his boat with his big antennae sticking on and he'd say, "Hey, good morning, what's
Scott: up?".
Rym: But let's say you aren't, you know, doing pro, like.
Rym: you're not trying to do live, like for real video streams to Twitch.
Rym: You're not trying to like record for real lectures at conventions on a regular basis.
Scott: Don't buy wireless.
Rym: There's cheaper consumer level systems that'll work pretty fucking well.
Rym: if you're okay with occasionally there's some static or occasionally it fails.
Scott: Can't we just get that and then remove the static in post?
Rym: Well, the static removes what you were saying.
Scott: Well, obviously we just re-record that part with ADR.
Rym: Yeah, because we're totally going to do that.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: You'd save a fuck ton of money, right?
Rym: Eh, would we?
Rym: Because then we're spending time instead.
Scott: How much time?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Also, the more pro equipment we have, the more likely it is a major convention would let us use it with their stuff.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: But basically, unless you're doing something for serious and you're actually willing to do the requisite research and be an expert in that field, you should never buy professional equipment.
Rym: Because either you're going to waste money or you're going to get in trouble or break something or somehow cause a problem for someone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it sounds similar to like, so the camera, right?
Scott: The one problem I had with the previous camera is that when you record it, well, first of all, it wasn't even 1080p, it was 1080i.
Scott: But you'd record video, but if the battery ran out, video ends.
Scott: Well, that's no good, right?
Scott: I'm in a weird situation where, like, you don't really need, like, the battery lasts for hours, right?
Scott: It's not really a problem most of the time.
Scott: But I was recording Netrunner videos and each round is an hour, or at least unless you play fast, right?
Scott: And, you know, you're using a battery, maybe round one the batteries- Well, you don't have a bandolier of batteries.
Scott: Even if you have a bandolier of batteries, I can't stop in the middle of a game to change the battery.
Rym: No, you have the bandolier that self-powers through that special weird-ass cable.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: There's no way to apply power to that old camera, right?
Scott: Except through the battery holes.
Scott: It doesn't have, like, an AC or DC input hole on it, right?
Scott: Like a camcorder does or anything.
Scott: And, you know, you recharge the batteries by taking them out of the camera and putting them in a charger.
Scott: So, basically, even if you only use, like, three quarters of a battery, that extra quarter is basically now useless to you because you can't record a full game on it.
Scott: If you try to use that power to record a game, the camera will run out mid-game.
Scott: You'll have to stop, change the battery, and start again.
Scott: Even if your memory card is gigantic, no good.
Rym: My camcorder has a special battery that's basically just an interface to the battery ports.
Rym: And then that has a cable that goes down to a bandolier of batteries.
Scott: So, the newer camera, right, you can buy this thing, which is exactly that.
Scott: It's a fake battery.
Scott: It's in the shape of a battery with a wire coming out.
Scott: And the camera even has a little flappy bit so that the wire can escape the battery hole and stick out of the camera.
Scott: Separately, they sell an AC adapter that plugs into that.
Scott: They don't provide them in a package, even though one is useless without the other.
Scott: I don't know why, but they don't.
Scott: So, in the instruction manual, it says, "Don't use any AC adapter except this AC10
Scott: PP."
Scott: And don't use any battery, you know, plug thingy except the DC whatever number, right?
Scott: So, I tried to get those model numbers.
Rym: Yeah, once you go pro, very specific model numbers of things mean a lot to you.
Scott: So, I go and I finally B&H'd and miraculously they had the fake battery bit, but they didn't have an AC adapter.
Scott: How do they order a not equal number of both products?
Scott: I do not know.
Scott: So, I go searching on the internet for the AC adapter.
Scott: No one has it, except like some Japanese places.
Scott: And it's like, "Wow, are they just not selling this
Scott: here?".
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, here.
Scott: But then I noticed the GH3 had the exact same batteries as the GH4.
Scott: It had the exact same DC coupling bit, but it had a different AC adapter, the AC8, not the AC10.
Scott: And I'm like, "Huh, why wouldn't the AC8 work in the same as the AC10
Scott: does?".
Scott: I mean, clearly they've changed the product, but this takes the same batteries as that camera and the same DC coupler and the same everything.
Scott: Why wouldn't it use the same, right?
Scott: So, I decided to take a risk for the internets.
Scott: I went and I bought the Wasabi batteries meant for the GH3, the third-party batteries, and I stuck them in there.
Scott: Camera could have exploded.
Scott: Didn't explode.
Scott: They worked great.
Scott: And that made me think, "Aha, it is exactly the same as the GH3, isn't
Scott: it?".
Scott: And they're trying to bullshit me.
Scott: So, then I found another camera store in the city and they had the AC8.
Scott: They had one left.
Scott: And I got it.
Scott: And I was in the store and I'm like, "Let me plug this into my camera before I buy it from you.
Scott: If my camera explodes, that's on me.
Scott: I'll just get the warranty or whatever.
Scott: I'll find a way.
Scott: If it doesn't explode, I'm buying
Scott: this.".
Scott: And of course, it didn't explode.
Scott: It totally worked.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: So, I can now plug the camera into the wall.
Scott: Something you would think is so simple.
Scott: Plug your camera into the wall so you can take video until the memory card is full without stopping indoors.
Scott: You think that would be basic.
Scott: Like, the camera would just fucking come with that.
Scott: But no.
Scott: Pro shit just doesn't come with that.
Scott: The same as the stupid wireless mics.
Scott: It just doesn't.
Scott: You have to...
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Well, here.
Rym: Let's configure an E6 Countryman right now.
Scott: Something so simple.
Scott: Just plugging it into the wall.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So, what are we plugging our fucking microphone into?
Rym: There's a dropdown with like a hundred options.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: Let's say,
Rym: "Sure.".
Rym: And all the other options you get change depending on what you pick here.
Scott: It's like filling out your taxes.
Rym: I'm gonna say,
Rym: "Sure.".
Rym: Oh, now I gotta pick a model.
Rym: Let's go with the ULXP.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: Flexibility.
Scott: That's the one with the group scan, right?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Flexibility.
Rym: There are three codes here.
Rym: No code for a classy springy boom.
Rym: I for a very flexible boom.
Rym: Or X for a flexible boom and a springy ear section.
Rym: And then paragraphs of description of what each one of these is.
Scott: So why would you even need one or the other, right?
Scott: This is the boom that goes from the ear to your face, right?
Scott: You would want one that is where you can bend it and it stays in the shape that you bend it to.
Rym: Ah.
Rym: So here's the explanation.
Rym: Just to give you an example.
Rym: The classic E6 is a good choice when one person alone will wear the microphone.
Rym: It holds its shape.
Rym: Just put it on and go.
Rym: The eye is highly flexible with the larger silicone rubber piece to use when multiple people share the mic and you have to reconfigure it on the fly for different people.
Scott: Oh, so the first one you reshape it and it stays in that shape forever?
Rym: Basically.
Scott: The other one you can keep reshaping a bunch.
Rym: And then the flex is a compromise between those two.
Rym: For like theater, you might have to fuck with it occasionally.
Scott: Sure, the first one you can shape it once and leave it that shape forever.
Scott: You can reshape it.
Scott: But why not just get the reshaping one always?
Rym: Because the reshaping one will possibly lose its shape over the course of doing something.
Rym: And you have to refit it to your head every time you put it on.
Scott: Oh, it sort of loses its shape.
Rym: The classic, like you do a thing and then it's set.
Scott: The other one is really firm and stays that way forever.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: It stays that way for as long as you need it to.
Scott: But it can be reshaped.
Scott: But if you reshape it too much, it's going to break?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, why not get just that one always?
Scott: Or the compromise one?
Rym: So what if you own it for a venue where you have a different person speaking every night?
Scott: If that firm one can be reshaped a bunch without breaking and it holds its shape once I shape it, why not use that one?
Rym: It's not easy to shape.
Rym: I watch videos on how to shape it.
Scott: It's not just like you.
Scott: don't just bend it and that's it?
Rym: No.
Rym: You like flex and pull and the idea is that you make it perfect for one person.
Rym: Leave it that way forever.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: That's what it's aimed for.
Scott: Because that matters that much, right?
Scott: If it's a little bit out of place.
Rym: At these volumes, it kind of does.
Rym: So pattern.
Rym: Omnidirectional or directional?
Scott: Well, it's always being worn on someone's head pointing at their mouth.
Scott: So why wouldn't you always want it to point straight at the mouth and that's it?
Rym: Well, usually actually you want omnidirectional for these things.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Why is that?
Rym: Because it's usually not pointed at your mouth.
Rym: It's just near your mouth.
Rym: And omnidirectionals don't fuck with the sound.
Rym: Directional microphones actually do fuck with your sound a little bit.
Rym: And they also, if they get a little out of place, now you're fucked.
Scott: Why would you then ever want the directional one?
Rym: So you and me on a stage, we probably want omnis because it's just us talking.
Rym: What if we're on a stage singing with Britney Spears and there's tons of noise on stage?
Rym: Then we need a directional.
Scott: Oh, so that the guitars jamming and such don't go into the microphones?
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And then there's all these different types of directionality.
Rym: We'll skip all that.
Rym: We'll go with the omni.
Rym: So, sensitivity.
Rym: Three of the options are grayed out because of the options we chose earlier.
Rym: We can choose the W5, W6, or W7.
Rym: Standard gain for general speaking, moderate gain for speaking and vocals, or powerful vocals.
Scott: Oh, so it's basically how much...
Rym: How sensitive is this thing before it just blows out?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, it appears that we need the W6.
Scott: We would get the more sensitive one.
Rym: Not the most sensitive one, though.
Scott: What's the most sensitive one?
Scott: Standard.
Scott: That's the one where you whisper?
Rym: No, standard gain for general speaking.
Rym: The advice, and again, there's tons of advice here, it basically says standard spoken word, W5.
Rym: Musical theater or, and I'm stressing this, dynamic presenters, W6.
Rym: Considering I'm yelling into this microphone right now, I think we need W6s.
Rym: It warns you, W7.
Scott: But if we're too quiet, if we just sit and have a chat, maybe we won't get heard.
Rym: Well, it means we have to pump the gain up, it'll be a little noisier then.
Rym: But that's probably better than blowing it out by being too loud for the thing when we start yelling in the middle of a panel.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: W7, basically, it's like only fucking use this if this is opera.
Scott: If you're yelling, then you'll maybe get to move.
Rym: Not even yelling, it says opera singer or other extremely loud applications only.
Scott: In other words, if we put those on and we start doing a podcast, we won't even move the needle.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Alright, color.
Rym: Light beige, tan, cocoa, or black.
Scott: I guess that's because you care about hiding it, right?
Scott: But we don't really care about hiding it so much.
Scott: The fact that it's so small, it's already hidden enough for us.
Scott: We're not honest, in theater, trying to really hide it when we're doing something really classical.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: So we would just get, I guess, the white person color.
Rym: Yeah, well it's interesting because they give you a lot of notes.
Scott: And it's like, you're going to see, even if I get white person color, it's like facial hairs and stuff.
Rym: Well, they warn you, for example, for placement against skin, when in doubt, choose the darker option.
Rym: Lighter colors on camera look like scars from a distance.
Scott: Right, plus my beardedness and whatnot, right?
Rym: Or we just go black and then it's obvious it's there, but it's kind of techno future.
Scott: I like black too.
Rym: Alright, cable diameter, one millimeter.
Scott: And the solid black is not racially insensitive if anyone has to use it.
Rym: Albinos.
Scott: Sorry, albinos.
Rym: Racist.
Rym: There is a white option.
Rym: Stark pearl white.
Scott: Way to go, Canyon.
Scott: That's actually, no, that looks like a scar.
Scott: Anyway, keep going.
Rym: Unless you're an albino.
Scott: Go albinos, go.
Rym: Also, that one can be colored with felt tip pens.
Scott: Dude, somewhere there's the awesomest albino nerdy person ever.
Rym: There has to be.
Rym: Dude, if any albinos listen to GeekNights, totally talk to us.
Scott: And they're doing all the cosplays that no one else can do and everyone is mad jelly.
Rym: Name a character they can do other than Ray Iannami.
Scott: Someone who's like really, really white.
Scott: Dylan Dow from Escaflownia is really white.
Rym: That kind of works.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: Alright, one more option.
Scott: Various ghosts.
Rym: Do we want the one millimeter.
Scott: Vampires of various sorts.
Rym: The one millimeter Eremid reinforced cable or the two millimeter Duramax.
Scott: We're not the Duramax cable.
Scott: We're not trying to hide the cable.
Scott: We are buying an expensive.
Rym: The Duramax cable provides 50 additional pounds of tensile strength.
Scott: Right, we are buying an expensive thing we do not want to break.
Scott: We are not buying a thing we are trying to hide.
Rym: Our sku is an E60W62SL.
Scott: How much is it?
Scott: So $1,000 for two.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: And that won't work with the Marantz.
Rym: Fuck.
Rym: So guys, don't go pro.
Scott: Couldn't we get something that it can work with that goes in between it and the Marantz?
Rym: A wireless system.
Scott: Right, the wireless outputs into the Marantz.
Rym: Yes, that's what we would do.
Rym: We would always use the wireless system.
Rym: Assuming that we broadcast on a legal channel, the laws don't change.
Scott: But couldn't we connect it to those little wireless backpack thingies, the gauntlet belt clip?
Scott: And then couldn't we have a wire coming out of that?
Rym: Those things usually don't have a local output wire.
Scott: Couldn't we find one that does?
Rym: I don't know of one, to be honest.
Scott: Couldn't we make one?
Rym: Now there are devices I've found that I have not vetted that will give the proper voltage to this thing and convert to XLR.
Rym: But I've got to do a little bit of research on those.
Scott: You don't want to explode your $500 thing, even though I almost exploded my $700 camera.
Rym: No, because here's the other thing.
Rym: With professional equipment, if you go back to the store and you're like, "Yeah, it just stopped working," they can figure out exactly what you did to it.
Scott: That's exactly right.
Rym: That is not the case with consumer and prosumer stuff.
Rym: No.
Rym: Except cell phones.
Rym: They know if you dropped it in the toilet.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.