Rym: It's Monday, May 19th, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight it's a tech news roundup.
Rym: 'Cause tons of stuff is happening.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah, little unexpected GeekNights hiatus 'cause I was in Sweden and the UK and Germany.
Rym: Two cities in Germany hanging out doing stuff.
Rym: Playing games, drinking with people late into the night because the sun just doesn't fucking set in Stockholm.
Scott: Oh, pretty far north there.
Scott: Summertime, yeah.
Rym: I walk out of this thing pretty drunk and I look around and it's, you know, kinda light out.
Scott: Isn't it weird though?
Scott: All the light is coming from the north?
Rym: But yeah, good times.
Rym: I'm back.
Rym: Not gonna dwell on the trip now.
Rym: I'll share choice anecdotes from the trip later.
Rym: But one thing I can say is in Sweden, the news played nothing for the entire time I was there.
Rym: But replays of the Rangers winning that game.
Scott: Oh yeah, Sweden-New York bonding.
Scott: Our goalie happens to be the best person from your country.
Rym: I'm usually in places where people care a lot about soccer or football, which I really don't care about at all.
Rym: And I have to kinda be polite and be whatever and I got no one to talk to.
Rym: But when I was in Sweden, I was the one who liked hockey.
Rym: None of the other people there except the Swedish people knew or liked hockey.
Scott: But you could bond with the Swedish people.
Scott: Those are the people you actually care about.
Scott: Who cares about the other people who came with you from some other country?
Scott: So while the Red Wings didn't quite make it, they didn't even come close to making it.
Rym: Yeah, not a good few years coming up for the Red Wings with their team disposition and everything.
Rym: But Rangers got a shot.
Scott: We have a small shot.
Scott: It's rare.
Scott: But we got one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Good news.
Rym: Good times.
Scott: Well, we'll see about that.
Scott: I feel somewhat confident about getting to the finals, which is crazy.
Scott: I don't feel very confident about beating the Blackhawks or the Kings.
Rym: I'm just excited about Game 7s.
Rym: All these Game 7s.
Scott: Well, the Rangers are the best at Game 7.
Rym: Game 7 is my favorite game.
Scott: But the Kings are probably easier to beat than the Blackhawks.
Scott: The Blackhawks are most dangerous.
Rym: In fact, having been a Red Wings fan for so long, my favorite games are either Game 4 or Game 7.
Rym: Depending on what year it is.
Rym: 96, 97, 98, Game 4.
Scott: Listen, if the Rangers win seven more games before the end of the season, we have a parade.
Rym: Yeah, I will skip work to go to that parade because hockey.
Scott: That's like my third parade since moving here.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: Rangers are my second team.
Rym: So I guess it's a Tech News roundup because lots of Tech News happened while I was overseas and away.
Scott: So you think Tech News roundup, that's a lazy cop-out.
Scott: We haven't done a Tech News roundup since, coincidentally, one year ago.
Rym: One year.
Scott: Not too bad.
Scott: We're not lazy too often.
Rym: Let's get right into it though because lots of stuff.
Rym: It's funny, we always complain among ourselves that most Tech News is actually some other kind of news.
Rym: Most of these involve some big company buying some other company.
Rym: Or politics.
Scott: It's always tough because that's business news.
Scott: That's politics news, right?
Rym: I think there's a better moral here.
Rym: All news is technology news.
Scott: I guess you could make an argument that all news is political news.
Rym: Yes, because politics...
Scott: All news is business news.
Rym: Is politics or technology more fundamental?
Rym: Can technology force politics?
Rym: Or does politics hold back or force technology?
Scott: All news is science news.
Scott: These atoms interacted in this way today.
Rym: And thus, there is no free will for all is preordained because for every action there is an equal and opposite reaction.
Scott: Should we just do all the... Since it's Tech News roundup, should we do news now or should we just do thing of the day and then do all tech news?
Rym: Oh, jump right to the thing of the day.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's news and then news.
Scott: What's the point of splitting it in half for no reason?
Rym: Well, I think the music is telling us what we're going to do.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: This is just pretty great.
Rym: I didn't verify to see if the statistics are real, but I'm pretty sure they are just by eyeballing them.
Rym: This is the spurious correlation engine.
Rym: Pick two variables and generate a correlation that is probably not a causation.
Rym: For example, there's a strong correlation between US spending on science space and technology and suicides by hanging strangulation and suffocation since 1999.
Scott: The more we spend on science, the more people will kill themselves.
Rym: The divorce rate in Maine correlates extremely strongly.
Scott: Or the more people kill themselves, the more we spend on science.
Rym: The divorce rate in Maine actually correlates really closely with the per capita consumption of margarine in the entire United States.
Scott: Stop divorcing in Maine.
Scott: They're divorcing because of butter margarine arguments in the household.
Rym: While you present your thing of the day, I'm going to figure out where they got the stat from.
Rym: Because the age of the winner of Miss America until 2009 correlated very strongly with, and I quote, "Murder by steam, hot vapor, and/or hot
Rym: object.".
Rym: I did not know that was a category.
Scott: Because Miss America is hot.
Scott: That's how she gets hot.
Rym: How is that a category of anything?
Rym: How many people are murdered by steam, hot vapors that there is a category for this?
Rym: Apparently in 1999 the answer was seven.
Scott: Listen, okay, so here's how it works.
Scott: When the winner of Miss America is old, how did she win if she's less hot because she's old?
Scott: Because she murdered the judges who were going to vote for the young people.
Rym: But that's arguing that people are murdered by the hot object.
Scott: Right, with her hotness.
Scott: And then, when the winner of Miss America is young, no one had to be murdered for that to happen.
Scott: They just let the judges decide.
Rym: Alright, I found a lot of interesting information about murders by steam and hot vapors, but this is my thing of the day.
Rym: This is very enjoyable.
Scott: Okay, my thing is gaming related.
Scott: So what this is, it is the, you probably saw it on the internet a while ago, we haven't done a show though, is the algorithm that I guess at least the first Pokemon game uses for what exactly happens when you throw a Pokeball.
Scott: All the math.
Rym: Oh, oh god.
Scott: Right, down to exactly what happens.
Rym: Guys, hitting A at the right moment does not have an effect.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Rym: So it's actually- I still do it though.
Scott: It's actually pretty interesting, right?
Scott: Basically, there's this sort of auto catch factor, right?
Scott: And it's like, depending on whether, what kind of Pokemon it is, and what kind of ball you're using, right?
Scott: It's like, you might, it's not just like percentage to catch done, right?
Scott: It's like there's two different ways to catch.
Rym: Whoa, frozen works better than paralyzed, interesting.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, so sleep and frozen are the best, basically, right?
Scott: So with sleep and frozen, you're basically expanding the initial sort of catch possibility, and if you get that catch, then you're good, right?
Scott: If you fail at that catch, then it goes down to the other one.
Scott: that's based on the low HP and whatnot, right?
Scott: So if you're trying to catch like a legendary, it might actually be easier to like sleep it and just use great balls, right?
Scott: As opposed to some other kind of, you know, another Pokemon might be better off to bring it down to one HP and use an ultra ball.
Scott: And it's very interesting exactly how this happens, right?
Scott: But it basically, you know, to sum it up, there's two different chances to catch.
Scott: And if you can catch, if you can increase your probabilities on the first chance, you don't care about the second chance.
Scott: So the HP doesn't matter.
Scott: And if you fail at the first chance, and sometimes it's easier to just bump up the probability on the second chance, which is the HP based chance, right?
Scott: And then you can ignore the other, you know.
Rym: Oh my God, it even tells you how it determines how many times the Pokeball wobbles.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And even the message that shows up.
Scott: So actually, yeah, the messages that show up.
Rym: Darn, the Pokemon broke free.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Those messages are actually related to the virtual die roll, right, that happened in the game, you know, when you played.
Rym: Oh my God, the three wobble and then shoot, it was too, it was so close too.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's the worst.
Scott: So yeah, if you care about Pokemans, read this.
Scott: Also, this is the kind of work that like Nintendo does that makes games great.
Scott: that is unheralded and usually unknown.
Rym: Guys, if you design a game and you don't have math like this, your game might have issues.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, this is why, you know, at least fundamentally in the polish, right, Nintendo's still making games better than most people.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Though I did see a great article where someone was arguing that Mario Kart 8 is like the end of good Mario Karts.
Scott: Well, that happened a while ago.
Rym: Yeah, granted, that argument seemed specious because their primary debate was, or their primary point was, Battle Mode got gimped.
Rym: Seriously, Battle Mode is the worst mode.
Scott: No one gives a shit about Battle Mode.
Rym: Except apparently these guys, I guess it's their Windjammers.
Scott: It must be their Windjammers.
Scott: But yeah, no.
Scott: At least they were, you know, reporting on the actual game in sort of the right way.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Even though they're wrong.
Scott: I mean, they're right and wrong, right?
Scott: They're wrong that Battle Mode is important.
Scott: They're right Mario Kart is important.
Rym: That Battle Mode should not exist.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No one wants Battle Mode, guys.
Rym: Except these guys.
Scott: Except these guys.
Rym: So yeah, Metamode, very briefly, the Book Club book is a canticle for Leibowitz.
Rym: I started reading it.
Rym: There's no fucking legitimate ebook of it.
Scott: I think there's an expensive Kindle one.
Rym: On the Amazon store there was not one.
Rym: Oh, well, I... And when I searched for a Canticle for Leibowitz ebook, I found a bunch of books that have the text from the author of Canticle for Leibowitz that do not include that story.
Scott: Huh.
Scott: Well, I just went on Google.
Scott: I didn't even find it on Pirate Bay.
Scott: I went on Google.
Scott: I found a webpage that had links to ebooks in every format.
Scott: I downloaded one and I dragged it onto my iPad and my Kindle.
Rym: That is what I'll be doing.
Rym: because I don't want to buy... I can buy Canticle for Leibowitz on a paperback for $0.71.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Rym: So I'm going to pirate that $0.71.
Rym: Sorry, dude, selling the $0.71 copy.
Rym: The used copy.
Rym: I'm going to get the illegal, probably not official, ebook instead because I'm done with physical books.
Scott: The ebook that I got is pretty good looking.
Scott: It looks like an official, you know, real deal.
Rym: You know what I almost want to do?
Rym: This is a brilliant idea.
Rym: Make ebooks for books that don't have ebooks or that people like to pirate.
Rym: Make them totally legit for like the first three quarters and then just have a different ending.
Rym: That would be the greatest troll.
Rym: I want someone to do this.
Scott: Do it.
Rym: I'm too lazy to do this.
Scott: Alright, let's do other meta moments.
Rym: In fact, or better, better, don't change the ending.
Rym: Just add a weird sex scene.
Rym: And that's all you do.
Scott: Do something to each book differently.
Scott: that's a book appropriate.
Rym: I think different ending and weird sex scene are the best possible things you can do.
Scott: So, Kinetic Con is coming up.
Rym: Kinetic Con!
Rym: We'll get the schedule up as soon as we can, slowly filling it on the website.
Rym: We'll be there doing some panels, running the panels department.
Rym: Kinetic Con is awesome and you should all attend.
Rym: If you live in the Northeast, like within a reasonable drive of Hartford, Connecticut, in the summer, there are few better conventions to go to that cater to anything other than just animu.
Scott: Any nerdery that you have has representation at Kinetic Con.
Scott: Fighting games, got it.
Scott: Animes, got it.
Scott: Tabletop games, RPGs, got it.
Scott: Sign by, book writing, we got that.
Rym: Yep, you want panels on like literary criticism, they're in there.
Scott: Tea ceremonies, we got that.
Rym: The films of John Waters.
Rym: Homestucks, maybe.
Scott: There will be homestucks there for you to hang out with.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Any nerdy thing that you are into that is modern.
Rym: And yeah, look at us on YouTube, blah blah blah blah blah whatever.
Scott: We're on the internet, come look for us.
Rym: Yes, Google for GeekNights guys.
Rym: I'm amazed at how many people, they're like, they want to get in touch with us.
Rym: I'm like yeah, just Google GeekNights.
Rym: And like they don't get it and they want a URL.
Rym: Like they don't realize they can type things into Google and get information.
Scott: Then they're probably not going to understand anything that we talk about on this show.
Rym: Yep, like I've almost gotten to the point where I kind of want to take the URL off of our business cards.
Rym: And just have text on the back that says Google for GeekNights.
Rym: And if they don't find us, it was never meant to be.
Scott: There are some other Geek Nightses.
Rym: Yes, there's the Oxford Geek Nightses.
Rym: We completely dominate them on Google Juice.
Scott: There's also some other podcast that's in Spanish that's like GeekNights CUU or something like that.
Rym: We could send them to CND.
Rym: We have a common law trademark.
Scott: I think it's like some Spanish university organization or something.
Rym: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11. 11
Rym: of the 13 links if you Google GeekNights on Google, Google on Google, are us.
Rym: And then the other two are for two GeekNights meetups in Albion.
Rym: Oh, related searches.
Rym: GeekNights with hosts.
Rym: GeekNights Rym.
Rym: GeekNights Utena.
Scott: Oh, you should watch that GeekNights Utena.
Rym: Yes, two new episodes will come out as soon as I have time to edit them if I'm not flying around to Europe like every goddamn day.
Rym: Warning, might not be GeekNights next week.
Rym: My boss is trying to send me to Hong Kong Tuesday morning.
Rym: I never thought I'd say this, but I don't want to go to Hong Kong on Tuesday.
Rym: I would rather that not happen.
Scott: I don't want to go to Toronto.
Rym: In Hong Kong, children have cigarette ads for faces.
Scott: No, but there's a lot of people smoking cigarettes there.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: So the biggest news is that there is a rumor that was pretty solid.
Rym: that has since had some clarification.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: It went from solid to rumor to solid to rumor.
Scott: I don't know what to believe anymore.
Rym: YouTube is buying Twitch for a billion dollars.
Scott: That makes sense.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now, one, Reddit went apeshit about how they're going to ruin Twitch.
Rym: And all I have to say is that for anyone who has never used real streaming technology, which includes the guy who was working with me, who worked for Twitch at PAX, who had never used YouTube's live streaming before, the backend of YouTube, live events.
Scott: The part most people don't see, because in order to have the access to the live streaming on YouTube, you have to have a thousand subscribers at least, and you have to try to use it, and you have to set up real technology.
Scott: So almost no one has seen it.
Rym: I think they've since relaxed those requirements.
Scott: Yeah, but even so, almost no one's actually messed with that technology.
Rym: So Twitch, right?
Rym: Twitch, you just turn on your whatever software and point it at Twitch, and it kind of just works.
Rym: YouTube, first you set up your technology with end cameras.
Rym: Primary and backup for each camera angle.
Rym: Arbitrary numbers of camera angles, different encoding formats, different encoders, as many bandwidths, as many resolutions as you want.
Rym: You set up all that bullshit.
Rym: And then you get a dashboard where you can preview your stream, something you can't do on Twitch.
Rym: And then you can check your stream out, check the sync.
Scott: Make sure it's working.
Scott: Make sure the audio's working.
Rym: You can start your event at a designated time, as in it fades in and you're there doing your thing.
Rym: As opposed to Twitch, where the first ten minutes of every stream is someone like Dave Riley sitting there going, "Is this working?
Rym: I'm just going to hang out here.
Rym: Is anyone... Alright, I got the game going.
Rym: Oh, someone joined the channel.
Rym: Okay, we'll start in like ten
Rym: minutes.".
Scott: Hey, can you see what I'm doing?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Hey, does this work?
Rym: Can you see me?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Can you see me?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Hopefully, if this does happen, that will be the one major thing that happens that will affect actual users is the streaming technology for streamers will be vastly improved.
Rym: The average streamer doesn't understand how this shit works at all.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But I think one of the negatives that I can see would be that the YouTube copyright enforcement regime would be all over Twitch.
Rym: The only reason I use Twitch instead of YouTube live events is because I often get copyright takedowns that stop my stream on YouTube.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like, let's say I was playing Mario on YouTube, right?
Scott: And it's like you get these copyright things that are like, "Hey, you got the Mario song in there.
Scott: That's copyrighted,
Scott: yo.".
Scott: And it's like, yeah, because I'm playing Mario.
Rym: But you can't appeal it.
Rym: Your stream just shuts down.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But on Twitch, it's like, "Oh, play Mario.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: That's what this is
Scott: for.".
Scott: It's like, why is it a problem on YouTube?
Rym: However, Twitch somehow got away with it.
Rym: I'm confident that YouTube will be able to similarly get away with it.
Scott: Yeah, if they want to.
Rym: Well, they have to or Twitch is dead.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see what happens.
Scott: You know what I'm really curious about that no one's discussing, assuming this happens, what about Justin TV, right?
Rym: Justin TV is dead.
Scott: Right, Twitch is Justin TV.
Scott: And Justin TV made Twitch and then Twitch got bigger than Justin TV.
Scott: So that's probably going to be... There's still people on there.
Scott: It's still got a community of users and stuff, but it's probably going to die-die.
Scott: Like, really die.
Rym: Yup, because now...
Scott: Like, delicious.
Rym: Now, it's interesting.
Rym: So the most up-to-date article we have here says a few things.
Rym: So update number one, the acquisition talks are "at an early stage and the deal is not
Rym: imminent.".
Rym: Imminent, according to the Wall Street Journal.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Citing two anonymous sources familiar with the matter.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Usually those are legit.
Rym: Two, Twitch supposedly evaluated multiple bids.
Rym: Microsoft was probably the second bidder.
Rym: Like, the second highest bidder.
Scott: That would have been dangerous, because suddenly it can only Twitch from Windows and Xbox.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Though the thing is, the Twitch people...
Scott: And Windows phones, not iPhones.
Rym: The Twitch people who run official events seem to use Wirecast for everything.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Direct.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Twitch decided on Google's YouTube as it believes the company will be the best fit.
Rym: Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Probably.
Scott: I mean, if they sell for a billion dollars, how much was the initial funding on Twitch?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: They're going to probably make, like, at least 3X, if not more.
Rym: The thing is, I'm confident that none of the people who will cash out on this are going to cash out and go to the beach.
Scott: I think no one's going to go to the beach except for some VC people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: VC people seem to never go to the beach, though.
Scott: I don't understand them.
Rym: They suckle that.
Rym: They make trillion dollars and then they die all day.
Scott: All the money they're going to make on Twitch, they lost on all those other stupid startups.
Scott: So, really, they're just going to finally break even when Twitch sells.
Scott: It's one of those... It's like, think about it.
Scott: Everyone's like, "You're going to be the next
Scott: Facebook.".
Scott: Well, let's see.
Scott: How many Facebooks have there been?
Scott: Facebook?
Scott: Twitch?
Rym: What?
Rym: Not Orkut?
Rym: Twitter?
Scott: There's been like six?
Scott: Except maybe, right?
Scott: It's like there's been less than ten.
Rym: Well, I mean, what about like Instagram?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: You know WhatsApp, which I'm going to sound like an old man.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: I didn't know what WhatsApp was until like a month ago.
Rym: Because I just ignored it.
Scott: It's pay Twitter.
Rym: It's not even pay Twitter.
Rym: It's Alenston Messenger is back as a new app that costs money.
Rym: I can't imagine who would use it except suddenly everyone in the financial world is like asking me what my WhatsApp ID is.
Rym: And I'm like, "What the fuck,
Rym: dude?".
Rym: People, I was like...
Scott: You should have been like, "Oh, I don't have one.
Scott: What's your Orkut
Scott: ID?"?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I was like, "What's your live
Rym: journal?".
Scott: "What's your Friendster
Scott: ID?".
Rym: "What's your
Rym: myspace?".
Rym: "What's your ICQ
Rym: number?"?
Rym: Oh.
Scott: Your favorite.
Rym: Oh, I think I might have forgotten it.
Rym: finally.
Rym: I know mine.
Scott: Mine's longer though.
Rym: I had a six digit one.
Scott: Cognac stock photo.
Scott: Mine's 93572776.
Rym: I think mine was 15036112.
Scott: Why'd you type ICWQ?
Rym: And then the one before... Yes!
Scott: Oh, wait.
Scott: Oh, cities.
Scott: Rims never to be finished or even worked on page.
Rym: That was a page that I had to build for RIT.
Rym: Let's see if it comes up.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Rims lair.
Rym: So this assignment I had to make...
Scott: Find Rims lair, everybody.
Rym: I had to make a graphic that had a text overlay and I had to provide some text.
Rym: Oh my God, are the pictures there?
Scott: What are the pictures?
Scott: Oh, it's the Rims stand up comedy Seinfeld picture with the trumpet.
Rym: And it's the Rims actually playing his trumpet.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: The third one's broken.
Scott: What, what?
Scott: I wonder what...
Rym: Oh no, it's not!
Rym: It's me and a sword.
Scott: I've seen all these pictures before.
Rym: Yeah, there's nothing new.
Rym: You should edit that page and add TRM.
Rym: I should add... No, I don't even know how the fuck I could edit this.
Scott: Log into Oocities or whatever the fuck that is.
Rym: I should add this to my LinkedIn profile.
Rym: Do it!
Rym: And see if anyone notices.
Scott: Search for mine.
Scott: 935 72776.
Rym: What was that?
Rym: 935 72776.
Rym: Man, you came way late to the party.
Scott: Space ICQ.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I had a lower number because I got in way early.
Rym: So, your profile on the Ubuntu forums.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Your TeamSpeak community forum.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: And you have a user profile on CX7 Club.
Scott: I have no idea what the fuck CX7 Club is.
Rym: We'll find out.
Rym: CX7 Club, it says you're in Beacon, New York.
Rym: You have 13 posts here.
Scott: Is the CX7...
Rym: You were born on April 30th in 1982.
Rym: You joined this in 2006.
Scott: Oh, you know what that might be?
Rym: Ford Fusion.
Scott: Yeah, that's a forum for, remember I had the Mazda, right?
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: See, they're referring to Mazda CX7.
Rym: It says you're a moped rider.
Scott: Yeah, because that's the ranking of how many posts you've had.
Rym: I love how moped rider is the lowest.
Scott: I posted in this forum when it was still the Mazda 3 Club about how to attach the iPod thing back to the car.
Rym: It says you last visited this on April 30th, 2013.
Scott: Yeah, no.
Scott: That's not true.
Rym: At 1044 AM.
Scott: That is not true.
Rym: That's what it says here.
Scott: That's wrong.
Rym: You posted 13 times.
Rym: Oh, I can find your posts.
Scott: Yeah, go for it.
Rym: I got to be logged in.
Scott: You can make an account.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: TeamSpeak.
Rym: No recent activity.
Scott: It was probably like how to set up TeamSpeak server, how this works.
Rym: Whoa, someone named Stefan Mildred visited your profile page for TeamSpeak recently.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: What's up, Stefan?
Rym: You last posted in 2004.
Rym: And your Ubuntu forums.
Rym: You have five cups of Ubuntu.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: All right.
Rym: That was interesting.
Scott: Let's move on to a different tech news.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, the last thing about tech news is that this obviously has antitrust implications.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, we'll see what comes of that.
Scott: Wait.
Scott: For each news, let's do a scale.
Scott: How much was that actually tech news?
Rym: This one, I'm going to say 50% because there's the architecture infrastructure backend side, especially if I say a little bit more.
Rym: YouTube has way more capacity than Twitch.
Rym: And Twitch has had bandwidth issues for me often.
Rym: Also, Twitch limits uploads to a pitiful amount of MBPS.
Rym: I can upload at 50 megabits per second per camera, YouTube.
Scott: My camera can take in 200 ridiculous amount, right?
Rym: I maxed out my Fios pipe once to YouTube just to see if it would work, and it totally worked.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, I'd say it's a lot of tech news, mostly because even though it's really a business news, it creates a lot of concerns for technologists who are streaming video because pretty much these are your options for streaming video.
Scott: I really wish Vimeo would step into the streaming game.
Rym: It's interesting though because YouTube, despite having the live events, is really only used by big convention events.
Rym: that will have our special thing and not nerdy stuff.
Rym: It's interesting how nerdy people don't use the YouTube streaming even though it's pretty much better in every way technologically.
Scott: They just don't know how.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: YouTube doesn't market it well.
Scott: That's probably why they're buying Twitch.
Rym: But Twitch, I wonder if they're going to keep the Twitch brand.
Scott: You can't get rid of the Twitch brand.
Rym: There's debate as to whether or not they're going to keep it.
Scott: You can call YouTube Twitch.
Rym: I also wonder if they're going to keep the sort of walled off video game or gaming only area.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Because that's the one thing where you're thinking about streaming.
Scott: If they do anything, it'll be long term and slow gradual.
Rym: Yup, because they can't fuck up Twitch.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Even though I foresee... People will just bail and make something new.
Rym: I foresee an exodus of nerds who say they're going to stop using Twitch because they're afraid, who then realize there's nowhere else to go and come back.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Or someone will make their own thing and it'll be really shitty, like all those people who try to make not Facebooks.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: And then, yeah, those never work.
Rym: So, kind of a fun one.
Rym: Emory University apparently accidentally, I'm going to read a summary from this TNW website.
Rym: Quote, "A Windows 7 deployment image was accidentally sent to all Windows machines, including laptops, desktops, and servers.
Rym: This image started with a repartitioned reformat.
Rym: As soon as the accident was discovered, the SSCM server was powered off.
Rym: However, by that time, the SSCM server had itself been repartitioned and
Rym: reformatted.".
Rym: That last sentence is probably the funniest part.
Scott: What's the SSCM?
Rym: I guess that's the software they used.
Rym: I used to use, when I worked at IBM, that was one of my jobs.
Scott: But powering it off is not going to stop the machines from...
Rym: Yeah, I'm ignoring the fact that people don't know how to troubleshoot issues like this.
Scott: That might actually fuck them up because they're trying to re-image the image they can't download anymore or something.
Rym: Yeah, but there's a couple morals here.
Rym: One, back stuff up.
Rym: Two, you've got to assume that at any second of any day, a hobo could run into your apartment and stick a knife into every hard drive in your computer.
Scott: Pretty much.
Rym: Those are pretty much the... Emily is laughing really loud at that.
Scott: You've got to go farther than that, right?
Scott: Imaging software is used in places that have large deployments of computers, usually, right?
Scott: And it's really great for solving problems.
Scott: Like, "My computer's all fucked up.
Scott: It's full of malware.
Scott: Okay, I'll just push a button from my desk in
Scott: IT.".
Scott: And you're fixed.
Rym: Yep, because your home directory, all your files, they're on some sand somewhere.
Scott: Right, it doesn't even matter.
Scott: Basically, if your computer has any sort of imaging software installed on it, you have to assume that hobo is living in the computer, right?
Scott: And he's just waiting.
Rym: He's been living there for a long time.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You know how hard drives die?
Rym: You can hear him sharpening his knife when you're accessing data.
Scott: That software is the hobo.
Scott: So if you've got that software because you're at a school or a business that has it, do not store anything on any hard drive in that computer whatsoever, ever.
Scott: Keep everything on USB sticks or on network drives or something.
Scott: Because even though every Windows computer on their network got formatted, I highly doubt that their NAS or their storage solutions were completely reformatted.
Scott: Though, I have seen incidents where someone has a mounted device and- That ends up being where the OS goes because it's the first device when the thing reboots?
Rym: No, but just that the software that was doing some task like this- Formats all drives in the computer?
Rym: Yes, has permission to delete files and in some sort of replication.
Rym: Like say it's replicating a computer to a backup site and does a two-way replication.
Rym: So someone updates one, it'll replicate across and back.
Rym: Like wikis and things will do this.
Rym: I've seen situations where the things were mounted on NASes for protection and the replication was intended for other purposes.
Rym: Someone unmounts it by accident on one side.
Rym: The other side then replicates the blank one onto the mount, destroying everything.
Scott: Don't fuck up.
Rym: I've seen that happen more than once in my life.
Scott: Number one, I hope that from this situation a lot of people there can learn a lesson of using cloud storage.
Scott: Learn how their computer works and why it fucked up.
Scott: But they'll probably just blame IT and be, even though they're at a university, be anti-intellectual and say they don't have to learn anything about computers, fuck you.
Scott: And there's probably some professor who's so mad about losing his research that he's just in a blind rage and doesn't care.
Rym: Two, if you're in school or you're learning IT, a thing that you should really learn is not just the general concepts, but learn a couple of the specific software packages that are used to image computers.
Rym: Because knowing how that shit works can get you a job so fast.
Rym: That was one of my jobs at IBM.
Rym: A good example of how to use this stuff was the factory had these computers that people would use to go to a web page and enter data while they're doing their work, like scanning barcodes and the kind of stuff you do in a factory.
Rym: So I made these computers that were running Linux and they didn't have any local data.
Rym: It was basically just a web browser with predefined shortcuts.
Rym: So if anything went wrong with one at all, I would just send an image to it.
Rym: And if that didn't fix it, I would just physically replace it.
Rym: I just find this story hilarious.
Scott: On the scale of "Is that tech
Scott: news?"
Scott: I would say very much.
Scott: that's tech news.
Rym: Yeah, that's 100% tech news.
Scott: 90% tech news.
Rym: Well, because all things...
Scott: It's 10%.
Scott: "Look, someone was stupid" news.
Rym: 9% that and 1%.
Rym: "Ah, the solipsistic doubts of all
Rym: things.".
Scott: Sure.
Rym: So, the Lithuanian mob was caught smuggling cigarettes into Russia using remote-controlled drones.
Scott: That's not...
Rym: My hat is off to you, Lithuanian mob.
Scott: My hat is off to you, drone-using mob.
Rym: Technologically, this is a tech issue in the sense that this technology is moving way faster than people realize.
Scott: But, see, with other sort of... I guess you can view this as a hacking attempt, right?
Scott: It's like the bad guys have found a way around the law, right?
Scott: They've found a way to skirt the defenses.
Scott: But it's not a situation where there's some really smart nerd at DEF CON and the FBI can't figure out what he's doing.
Scott: This is, "Oh, they're using drones.
Scott: We already know the answer to that.
Scott: Shoot the drones down.
Rym: Boom.
Rym: Done.".
Rym: And actually, that's hard.
Rym: They're too small to be picked up by radar, usually.
Rym: They're tiny.
Scott: Use a gun.
Rym: Have you ever fired a gun, Scott?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You're gonna shoot a drone that just kind of... You don't even know where the drones are.
Scott: It's like skeet shooting.
Scott: A drone is bigger than a skeet.
Scott: Use a shotgun.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: How do you know where the drone is in a giant forest?
Scott: You know it's somewhere on the border with Lithuania.
Rym: No, you don't.
Scott: It's a Lithuanian mob.
Scott: They caught one by accident.
Rym: Lithuania's really small.
Rym: All right, Scott.
Rym: You, how many people would you need to prevent drones from getting over the East River?
Scott: Over the East River?
Rym: At any point.
Rym: 24/7.
Scott: Only next to Manhattan versus Long Island geographically?
Rym: Yeah, just Manhattan.
Scott: Not the northern...
Rym: Just Manhattan.
Scott: I'd probably do, like, five or six big boats that had, like, auto turrets on them.
Rym: Yes, because auto turrets within firing distance of the windows of Manhattan is an excellent idea.
Scott: Well, they'd be firing shotguns.
Scott: It's not like a little shop pallet's gonna hurt you.
Rym: But I guess what I think... This story kind of points out that right now, despite the laws and regulations that are coming around this, smart nerds can make drones do really cool stuff.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And I look forward to the crazy crap that's gonna start happening when, like, high school pranks involve a drone flying into the school and dropping stink bombs everywhere.
Scott: I've been surprised, right?
Scott: It's like I've seen a lot of drones used for cameras a lot.
Rym: Well, there's that guy who flew around New York City.
Scott: Yeah, you're allowed to.
Rym: No, you're all, "That's
Rym: debatable.".
Scott: No, there was a guy... That's another news.
Rym: Yes, it is debatable, though.
Scott: Anyway, but I'm surprised I haven't seen them used for more just, like, fun things.
Scott: Like, you've never gone to, like, a concert and a drone flies around, you know, dropping confetti on everybody.
Rym: Partly because they can't carry much of a payload yet.
Scott: You get a lot of them.
Rym: Yeah, but then they're likely to fall into the crowd.
Scott: Or, like, you have something really high up, like a confetti cannon, and a drone flies up there to trigger it instead of...
Rym: Yeah, because that's so much more effective than wireless.
Rym: That's so much more... It's more epic.
Scott: Or, like, you're at, I don't know, the sea lion show at the aquarium, and they put the beach ball on the drone, and then the sea lion jumps up and hits it.
Rym: So, there's a pedophile.
Rym: I'm slashed off.
Scott: How much tech news was your drone?
Scott: Not much tech news.
Scott: I mean, they used drones, but other than that, it was crime news.
Rym: But that drone technology as a discussion is primarily technological.
Scott: Sure, but the news... I'm talking about the quality of the news on its own.
Rym: The technology has gotten...
Scott: We're gonna make a technology discussion no matter what the news is.
Rym: The technology has gotten good enough...
Scott: We can have news about squirrels in the park and make it technological.
Rym: The technology has gotten good enough to have autonomous drones delivering contraband over borders.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's relatively recent in terms of carrying capacity, GPS capabilities, being able to operate without line of sight.
Scott: I wonder what kind of drones they're using.
Scott: Is it, like, the octocopters with the eight blades?
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: Russia detained it.
Rym: Let's see if there's a picture of it.
Scott: Eight rotors?
Scott: Or a six?
Rym: Alright, that's just a picture of cigarettes.
Rym: Thank you, news article.
Scott: That was really helpful.
Rym: That was great.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Let's continue.
Rym: Blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Doesn't say what kind... Oh, oh, oh, oh, here we go.
Rym: It was established that the aircraft with a wing spread of four meters...
Scott: Oh, so it's like a real drone.
Rym: Had been made in Lithuania and was radio-controlled from Earth.
Scott: Yeah, this isn't like, you know, a drone you buy at the store.
Rym: This is like a real one.
Scott: A GPS system was built into it.
Scott: That's the kind that they use in the military and shit.
Rym: A drone operator probably controlled the flight from a PC somewhere.
Rym: The drone could carry ten fucking kilograms of cargo.
Scott: Yeah, this is a real drone.
Scott: Like, the ones... Yeah, so... How do you even get one of those?
Scott: Those are not cheap.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: If you know enough, just build it.
Scott: You know, we could just go to, like, Afghanistan and, like, steal some.
Scott: As the U.S.
Scott: is flying them, we can, like, interfere with them and get them to crash and take them.
Rym: That's supposedly what Iran did to that one.
Rym: That's a very dubious story.
Scott: I'm sure that story sounds dubious, but, I mean, we could probably get away with it.
Scott: Well, how do we get away with it?
Scott: But we could accomplish it if we really tried.
Rym: Well, we're not going to get away with it now.
Scott: No, but we could accomplish it if we tried with all our might.
Rym: And we hadn't said that just now.
Scott: Yes, that is true.
Scott: We're never going to go to Afghanistan in our lives.
Rym: So, anyway, back to the pedophile.
Scott: Already, this pedophile news doesn't sound like tech news.
Rym: A pedophile has asked to be deleted from a Google search after a European court ruling.
Scott: Okay, so it's part law news, part crime news, part tech news.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, this is a long-standing debate.
Rym: There's this debate in Europe about the so-called right to be forgotten.
Scott: There is no right to be forgotten.
Rym: Yeah, so Europe wants to make it a law that you have a right to be forgotten on the internet.
Rym: Meaning that, say Scott...
Scott: Well, fuck you and your unenforceable law.
Rym: Let's say Scott posts a picture on my forum of himself naked, like, dancing on top of a donkey.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Then 10 years later, he emails me and says, "Yeah, that was a long time ago.
Rym: Please remove that
Rym: image.".
Rym: Uh, no.
Rym: Europe wants to make it a crime for me to not remove that image.
Rym: On the grounds that it was a long time ago, he has a right for information about him to be removed from the internet.
Scott: Alright, you know what I had to say to that?
Scott: Make me.
Rym: Oh, you can't.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: So, this is Europe.
Rym: Remember, Europe is a place where...
Scott: Where they don't have freedom of speech, yeah.
Rym: And also, if you go to any website, a giant banner appears by law that informs you with a lot of text that this website uses cookies!
Scott: Oh my god, cookies!
Rym: It's a crime to not tell you about the cookies!
Scott: Cookie!
Scott: Nom nom nom nom.
Rym: The European Union, in terms of the internet, makes me terrified that they will get any more control of the internet away from the United States.
Scott: And this is just another example of it.
Scott: And look how bad the United States is at internet.
Scott: The EU is even worse.
Rym: We're bad and we're the best.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: That's usually how the world is.
Scott: The US is bad and awful at things and still better than everyone else at the same time.
Rym: Now, there are still places where you can advocate for privacy rights and privacy.
Rym: There are privacy rights that could make sense both technologically and ideologically and pragmatically.
Rym: However, the right to be forgotten is not one of them.
Scott: It is not even a right.
Rym: Information exists.
Rym: The only way to fight information is with more information.
Rym: So, for example, maybe you could argue that in a high-profile website, like a journalistic organization, there could be a rule that forces an old article called "About a Crime" to have an update or a note added to it if someone was later exonerated.
Scott: Uh, sure.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: I'd be okay with that.
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Scott: Nothing.
Rym: Yep, exactly.
Rym: Unless you're trying to, well, whatever.
Rym: There's no good argument against it.
Rym: I can come up with a lot of specious arguments against it.
Scott: Well, I mean, you could argue, "It's my website.
Scott: You can't force...".
Scott: I mean, it's basically the same defense for both situations, right?
Scott: It's like, "It's my website.
Scott: If I don't want to edit it, I don't have to.
Scott: I can write anything I want on my website.
Scott: You can't force me to write something additional on my website just as much as you can't force me to delete something on my website.
Scott: It's my website.
Scott: I put there what I want.
Scott: Fuck
Scott: you.".
Rym: But basically, this whole debate is coming around this fundamental divide between what people want technology to do and what technology is.
Rym: The sheer technology that the picture is digital means that it will exist forever and will be public forever.
Scott: I think the problem is you have people who are very unskilled and unknowledgeable, but they are doing things that have full life consequences.
Scott: Well... So they fuck up because they suck, and then later when they learn that they fucked up, they want to undo, and it's like, "No.
Scott: It's a
Scott: consequence.".
Scott: I see there are two kinds of problems in this world, right?
Scott: The first kind of problem is...
Rym: Only two kinds.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This is a real problem.
Scott: Like, "I have a problem, and I need to solve it.
Scott: What do I do to get it out of this
Scott: time?".
Scott: You want to know what the problem is?
Scott: Right.
Scott: The other kind of problem is, "I have already fucked up, and I am suffering consequences.
Scott: How do I alleviate these
Scott: consequences?".
Scott: And the answer to that is you don't.
Scott: They're consequences of the thing you already did.
Scott: You suffer.
Scott: There's no solving.
Rym: So Scott, I cut my hand.
Rym: To alleviate the consequences of cutting my hand, I put some balm on it and abandoned it.
Scott: How is that wrong?
Scott: Your hand will never be restored to what it originally was.
Scott: You have a full life consequence of this scar on your hand that cannot be undone.
Rym: That's a small cut.
Rym: There might not be a scar.
Scott: You might get lucky.
Scott: It wasn't a major fuck up, right?
Rym: What if in the future we have technology to completely undo my cut?
Rym: That'll happen.
Scott: Sure, but there might still be a consequence of having to pay for the use of that technology.
Rym: No, universal healthcare, post-care, it's a new society.
Scott: You still have to use... Well, I mean, there's still... Then you didn't fuck up, did you?
Scott: You didn't cut yourself on purpose.
Rym: I think there's a more nuanced point here.
Rym: We are in a liminality right now between... People talk about a new world order or technological singularity.
Rym: The biggest and most important one in the world right now is that we're at this dividing line between a world where most of what you did in your life up to this point is lost, save for the memories of people around you, and this world where every picture you ever took is on the internet forever, and every picture anyone ever took of you is on the internet forever, along with everything you ever posted to your live journal.
Scott: Right, and the solution is not to go back to the old world, because that is impossible.
Scott: The snake jumped out of the can and hit you in the face, and you can't put it back in, because damn, that can is small and that snake is long.
Rym: Yes, so in the past...
Scott: You have to deal with the world we have.
Rym: So as I'm saying, in the past, a politician who did something stupid as a child could still be elected if that information was obscure enough.
Rym: In the future, everyone did stupid shit as a child, and as a result, every politician has a picture of them with their dick out.
Scott: But we're in the world where half the politicians have pictures with their dicks out, and half of them don't know how to use the internet, and those are the ones that get elected because they don't have pictures of their dick out yet.
Scott: All the politicians don't know how to use the internet.
Scott: They're trying to keep it down.
Rym: This debate crystallizes exactly what that liminal place that we're in is.
Scott: I'm not too worried about this one, because this is one of those ones where it's when the old people die.
Rym: I was at a financial conference not that long ago, and this woman, who was a doctor in mathematics, she was talking all about old world...
Scott: A doctor of what?
Rym: Mathematics, something, PhD.
Rym: She was talking about market structure and the way traders work and all these things, and she had this really long talk about all these really bad things that are happening.
Rym: And then she put up her slide, and she was like, "So what do we do about this?
Rym: How is this
Rym: fixed?".
Rym: And her next slide said the words that she then said out loud, one funeral at a time.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And she went on to say, "These people, many of whom are at this conference, will never change.
Rym: They cannot
Rym: change.".
Rym: That's right.
Rym: The youth will have their own problems, but the only way to change these markets is to wait for the people who already control them to die of old age.
Scott: Or murder them.
Rym: And people in the audience, there was grumbling.
Rym: It was hilarious.
Rym: Meanwhile, all the young people...
Scott: But I would be the biggest fan.
Scott: I'm already the biggest fan of that lady.
Rym: So half the audience was like, "Oh, really?
Rym: Oh, I never...".
Rym: And the other half was like that.
Rym: No, the other half was just looking at each other like... Tee hee.
Rym: So, don't want to talk about this long.
Scott: That was kind of tech news.
Rym: Yeah, that was pretty techy, because technology is forcing a huge societal change.
Scott: Tech plus law plus whatever.
Rym: So this one's pretty much just net neutrality tech law.
Rym: There is legislation in the EU to enforce net neutrality, regardless of the debate of how effective it will be.
Rym: The UK is likely planning to veto it.
Scott: They can just, one country can just veto all the other countries?
Rym: The EU's kind of...
Scott: Can't all the other countries agree to it?
Scott: And just like, "OK, UK, you don't get to do
Scott: anything?"
Scott: Or, "We'll force net neutrality on the UK even though you don't want
Scott: it?".
Rym: So if laws are passed in the Eurozone, members have to implement their own legislation to do what those laws say within a certain amount of time.
Scott: Right, so I thought the point of the EU is that a whole bunch of European countries can force something upon other European countries that are in the EU.
Rym: I had this conversation with someone in Sweden a few days ago.
Scott: In the EU?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I don't know which countries.
Scott: Some of the countries aren't in it.
Scott: I don't know which ones are in it.
Rym: Well, they're in the Schengen Zones.
Scott: I thought the UK actually wasn't in the EU because they still have pounds.
Scott: They don't even use Euros, right?
Rym: Yeah, Sweden has their kronor still.
Rym: They don't use Euros.
Scott: Really?
Scott: But I thought if you're in the EU, you've got to use Euros.
Rym: No, it's complicated.
Scott: OK.
Rym: In fact, in Europe, people take pounds and Euros.
Scott: And this is why I don't know, because it's fucking complicated.
Rym: And if you go to London, like if you go to Europe, they're different in terms of visas or the stamps in your passport.
Rym: But I went in in Sweden.
Rym: They stamped me in.
Rym: I left from Germany.
Rym: They stamped me out.
Rym: There was no stamping in between Sweden and Germany.
Rym: But that was because of the Schengen Zone as well.
Rym: Anyway, so the conversation I had, I'm going to say to you what was said to me.
Rym: Wait, so one senator can just stop any law from passing if he wants to?
Scott: If he can stay up all fucking night, good luck.
Rym: No, they don't, Scott.
Rym: They just threaten to do it and then everyone backs down.
Scott: Yeah, they should force him to do it.
Rym: Yeah, but that's politics.
Rym: Look at that.
Scott: I'd force him to do it every time.
Scott: I'd be like, all right.
Scott: The nominal reason... Oh, you're not good.
Scott: Law passes.
Scott: Done.
Rym: The nominal reason the UK is vetoing this is because it prevents them from blocking child pornography, which has been the argument that the UK has used for a significant percentage of internet restrictions over time.
Scott: That's not actually necessarily true, right?
Scott: Because, I mean, you could craft the net neutrality legislation in such... Well, first of all, you shouldn't... I mean, I don't want to say child pornography is good, but it's like you don't fight child pornography with censoring the internet.
Scott: That's not the right way.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: But it's also impossible, right?
Rym: But this goes into the...
Scott: It's a waste of your effort, just like the war on drugs is a waste of effort, right?
Scott: But B, you could craft net neutrality legislation in such a way to say any legal traffic, which is sort of, even if you look at the stuff the FCC is doing now, they're saying any legal use in all their stuff about not allowing ISPs to block things.
Rym: Ah, so some countries...
Scott: You could say any legal internet traffic must be given equal priority, and then your country can still be an evil censoring non-First Amendment country and just block anything you don't want.
Scott: So anything that's either blocked or equal speed, and you still can't have fast and slow lanes, which would solve the problem of, you know, "Aha, the rich company gets all the internet, and the poor company, no one can visit their
Scott: website.".
Rym: Well, I think we need a more nuanced approach and a long-term approach in that...
Scott: Yeah, world free speech.
Scott: Fuck you, oppressionist countries.
Rym: There's two distinct use cases for the internet.
Rym: One of them is high bandwidth, and one of them is low bandwidth.
Rym: Here's my example.
Rym: High bandwidth, playing games, watching videos, all that kind of stuff we do.
Scott: Games don't even need a lot of bandwidth.
Scott: It needs a lot of, you know, latency.
Scott: Low latency.
Rym: I guess in terms of low bandwidth cases are things like, "I'm in North Korea.
Rym: I need to share
Rym: information.".
Rym: "I gotta text
Rym: somebody.".
Rym: Yes, I'm sharing information in a raw form that is not video or other, like, extremely big blobs.
Rym: That one, the latter, the low bandwidth one, is way more important to society progressing, I think.
Rym: Because freedom of information is important.
Rym: Nerds really need to get on building a sort of ad hoc wireless ability to have that kind of internet anywhere, anytime, even with very high latency and very low bandwidth, to get around 80 steps of shit.
Scott: You know why it's hard to do that?
Rym: Because RF is hard as fuck.
Scott: Yeah, how's your microphone doing?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Did you get that shit yet?
Scott: No.
Scott: No?
Scott: Really?
Scott: So you can't even get wireless microphones, and you want to set up a wireless mesh network over the whole world.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: Let's get on that.
Rym: That was half tech, half politics.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: How much time do we have left to kill?
Rym: We've been talking for 46 minutes.
Rym: We can blow through the rest of these.
Scott: Let's do, like, two or three more.
Rym: AT&T buying DirecTV for -- so, you know, it's interesting.
Scott: That's hardly tech news.
Rym: It is.
Rym: However, YouTube's buying Twitch for $1 billion.
Rym: AT&T's buying DirecTV for $48.5 billion.
Scott: So, DirecTV is 48.5 Twitches.
Scott: Or, in other words, the NFL is 48.5 video games.
Rym: I can spin this tech.
Rym: From what I gather, DirecTV has a -- either growing more slowly or about to shrink user base, but it generates ludicrous amounts of cash.
Scott: Yeah, so the reason DirecTV makes so much money is mostly because of this NFL Sunday ticket, right?
Scott: So, basically, it's mostly sports, is most of their subscribers, right?
Scott: That's the reason you get DirecTV, is because in your area, shit's blacked out, or you really just got to fucking watch all the football.
Scott: Did you know the red zone on DirecTV is not only the first red zone, it's older than the red zone you get on other channels.
Scott: Really?
Scott: If you have, like, Fios red zone, the guy that's on that red zone is a different guy than on the DirecTV red zone.
Scott: It's a different red zone.
Scott: The NFL Sunday ticket on DirecTV is, like, this huge fucking deal.
Scott: It's way different than -- and it's not just, you know -- it's like my dad, he can see on his AT&T the red zone.
Scott: He has AT&T U-verse, right?
Scott: He can see the red zone, and he can see a lot of football games, right?
Scott: He can't see every football game.
Scott: If you want to see literally every football game, you have to have -- the only way you can do it by sitting in one place is to have DirecTV, right?
Scott: So it's this big deal.
Scott: And you know how this is, like, the reason AT&T is trying to buy them is because there's a term in the contract that says, "Oh, yeah, by the way, if the NFL cuts off this deal with you, we get to cut this off the purchase, because that's the reason we're buying
Scott: you.".
Scott: So AT&T is buying DirecTV mostly for that, get those subscribers, because U-verse is kind of small, but it's actually not that bad, and it's trying to fight back, and if it merges with DirecTV, it'll suddenly have this big user base, and it can come out and fight with the other cable companies, especially if Comcast and Time Warner merge, right?
Scott: Oh, boy.
Rym: So here's the scary thing.
Scott: But here's the thing, DirecTV's problem is no internet, right?
Scott: And at least at my parents' house, where they have U-verse, the internet ain't bad.
Rym: Well, here's the scary thing, quote, "This deal will bring 20 million more U.S.
Rym: television subscribers under AT&T's roof, making it the second biggest TV provider behind
Rym: Comcast.".
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, monopoly time.
Scott: Yeah, well, see, it's duopoly, I guess.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Triop, whatever.
Scott: But, yeah, it's like, you know, they need to compete.
Scott: If the other guy is so gigantic, you got to, you know, muscle up, and it's sort of a good combo there, right?
Scott: It's like DirecTV gives AT&T the TV that it doesn't have, the content, right?
Scott: And AT&T gives DirecTV the internet that it doesn't have.
Rym: Well, here's my trouble.
Rym: All these maneuvers around the cable networks and the television networks are kind of, that's the, this is why, for everyone who says, "Why can't I just watch my shows on the
Rym: internet?".
Rym: This is why there's so many old people, so many people who just don't understand technology, that for whatever reason, they're all still paying for TV, maybe for sports.
Scott: You know how that problem will be solved?
Rym: One funeral at a time.
Scott: You got it.
Rym: But right now, that is what's holding us back, that even as HBO, they're not stupid.
Rym: They know that the internet is the future, that everyone would just pay whatever it took to watch the Game of Thrones just on the HBO website.
Scott: Or would just not pay and parrot it.
Rym: But if they could pay, they probably would.
Scott: A lot of people would.
Scott: There's a limit to how much people will pay, but yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but people...
Scott: I'm paying for Crunchyroll, right?
Rym: People who are willing to pay for cable TV would probably be willing to pay similar amounts just to be able to watch all the shows.
Scott: How many people pay for cable TV to only watch Game of Thrones?
Scott: Well, if I can just pay that much for Game of Thrones only, then.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: However, the problem is that these television networks still generate a ton of cash from these old people, so even if HBO knows 100% that's a dead business model and the future is the right way to go, they can't undermine that when it still brings in billions of dollars a year for nothing.
Scott: I don't think they unnecessarily undermine it, right?
Rym: The argument is, and there's been some truth to this, that they would undermine it in a second.
Rym: Here's the example.
Rym: That Viking show that I was talking about.
Rym: That show, I really like it.
Rym: It's a drama that's pretty historically accurate about what Vikings were like.
Rym: So I watched a bunch of it on the plane.
Rym: It was really good.
Rym: It was like watching a Burning Wheel game.
Rym: It's Game of Thrones, but good.
Rym: There, I said it.
Rym: So I got home and was like, "Oh, I want to show Emily this.
Rym: I want to watch
Rym: it.".
Rym: We go to the Vikings website.
Rym: It's one of those shows.
Rym: You can only watch it online, or you can't even buy it.
Rym: You can only watch it if you can prove that you pay for the History Channel on a provider.
Scott: Or you can just go to the Pirate Bank and get it.
Rym: Yeah, so I went to the Pirate Bank and got it.
Rym: But ignore piracy for a second.
Rym: Think about this.
Rym: The reason they do that is because the show is to drive people to keep paying for cable.
Rym: If people can get the five shows they like without paying for cable, they won't pay for cable anymore.
Rym: They'll pay the five studios that make those five shows.
Rym: Sure, that is true.
Rym: And the entire cable network goes out.
Rym: That entire industry disappears.
Scott: All right, so that's true.
Scott: But the thing is, people who know how to get those shows on the internet like that are people who can pirate bay.
Scott: They're smart enough already.
Scott: And those old people, they don't know how to do that.
Scott: They're going to keep paying for cable.
Scott: So really, all you're doing is letting the people who, in the future, will have their way one funeral at a time, have their way now, and you still get all the old people money, right?
Rym: Well, that's just it.
Rym: Because they'll still get the old people money.
Scott: You're going to lose the old people money at the same time anyway.
Scott: So all you're doing is making these people suffer.
Scott: You're not going to, you know...
Rym: But that's what I'm saying.
Rym: The reason all the streaming...
Scott: People aren't paying for cable?
Scott: They're using their parents' cable login, like me.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it's funny.
Rym: College Amber always says the thing where any time someone says, "I watched Game of
Rym: Thrones."
Rym: With my dad's HBO Go.
Rym: Yes, it's always with my dad's HBO Go account.
Rym: They say that every time.
Rym: Actually, they always say "moms," I think.
Rym: Alright, whatever.
Scott: Moms, dads, parents.
Rym: But the reason every streaming service sucks is because of this.
Rym: Because the money still comes from old people who don't know better.
Rym: No one's figured out a way to make money in the new world, except for, like, Frederator and some of these small places.
Rym: So...
Scott: Yeah, make a show that has mad merch.
Scott: Cat bug everywhere.
Rym: Oh my god, cat bug.
Rym: Cat bug tattoos.
Scott: Cat bug everything.
Rym: Let's look through the rest of these.
Scott: Oh, that was not really tech news.
Rym: No, not really.
Scott: It was mostly TV news.
Rym: Yeah, but it's sort of an explanation as to why some of the technology is stagnating.
Rym: The technology stagnates because the money is in the old world for a while still.
Rym: There's a study saying that the majority of malware is becoming what they call
Rym: "malvertising.".
Scott: Well, that's been true for a long time, but this is mostly tech news.
Rym: Apparently, that increased 200% in 2013 alone.
Scott: Whoa, so it was already most of it, and now it's even more.
Scott: most of it?
Rym: Yes, generating supposedly 12... But here's the thing.
Rym: It's not the old world of.
Rym: your computer gets malware, and then it shows you ads.
Rym: Now, your computer gets malware and clicks on ads for other people.
Scott: It's been doing that for a long time.
Rym: 12.4 billion malicious ad impressions.
Rym: There are arguments that are possibly legitimate, I don't know.
Rym: It's possible that the majority of people who ever click on online ads either do it by accident or malware did it.
Rym: When is online advertising going to collapse?
Rym: When is this information going to hit the rest of the information?
Scott: You know, sadly, probably after the TV collapses, but hopefully both of them within our lifetime.
Scott: Is there things that I can see happening while we breathe?
Rym: I mean, I'm amazed at how many people see ads on the internet to this day.
Scott: Adblock Plus is actually like.
Scott: the number of users is way bigger than you think.
Rym: It is, but how come every time I ever use someone else's computer I see ads?
Rym: Except inside of our own very tight friend group.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: Yeah, but that's actually tech news.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also, it kind of gives us an aside that for the few people, the minority of people who argue that ad blocking is somehow immoral, I say to you, is ad blocking not, in many cases, security?
Rym: Because ads are the primary vector of malware.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So there is a brouhaha about a smart gun seller.
Rym: Someone designed a new sort of more modern version of the smart gun that only its owner can fire.
Scott: So you buy a gun and you're the only one who can shoot it because you bought it?
Rym: You are like people in your family.
Scott: How do you demo it at the gun store?
Rym: Well, some of these, you set up biometrics like hand print or something like that.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Some of them, you have a special wristwatch that you wear when you want to go shooting.
Rym: So say you're wearing- For someone to take your wristwatch.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: So say you're wearing it, right?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And you get mugged.
Rym: You pull your gun out and you try to shoot the guy like you miss and he attacks you and grabs you.
Rym: He pulls the gun away from you and tries to shoot you with it.
Scott: And then you can punch him in the face with no fear.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: He can't just shoot you with it.
Scott: Pretty good.
Rym: So it's cool technology.
Rym: It might not be 100% there yet, but- Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you try to punch him and while you're punching him, your arm goes near the gun and he shoots you.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the thing is, I'm pretty sure it's set up to where it has to be like right fucking there.
Rym: It has to have been there for a little bit.
Scott: Still, that's pretty good.
Scott: It's very unlikely the guy can get your watch right while you're-.
Rym: It's a cool kind of technology because suppose- All right.
Scott: So the fact that this gun exists is definitely tech news.
Rym: Well, I mean, it's not new technology, but the technology is getting better quickly and companies are starting to make them.
Scott: And I wonder how that compares to laptops and iPhones.
Rym: So say it's even as bad as an iPhone where it'll kind of work if you just rub anything dry enough.
Scott: Is it biased towards yes or biased towards no?
Rym: Even if it's biased toward yes- Either one has its problems, right?
Rym: Even if it's biased toward?
Rym: yes, think about a quick situation.
Rym: If it's pretty much guaranteed to fire at your palm print, but maybe it'll only fire 10% of the time with someone else's palm print, in a heat of the moment someone grabs your gun, oh my God, those are pretty good odds.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, the other thing is that if you're talking about making these- If you're talking about a situation, a quick situation, or a kid getting the gun out of the closet, this definitely solves the problem, right?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But what it doesn't solve the problem of is let's say we made it so you could only manufacture this kind of gun, right?
Scott: And so it's very hard for any other kind of gun to get in the market.
Scott: You think, aha, we'll stop the illegal gun problems.
Scott: It's like, no, people will just take these and hotwire them, and then they have guns.
Scott: If they have time to sit there with the gun, they can dismantle the biometric part.
Rym: Yes, but it's not to solve that problem.
Rym: It's to solve the problem of Joey finds your gun and starts fucking with it.
Scott: Yeah, and you don't need to put a stupid gun lock on it, which is much harder to remove.
Scott: Whatever, so.
Rym: So, a company may have had a new version of this, and they had some advertising, like check out our smart gun.
Scott: I mean, if I was going to buy a handgun, for some reason that was legitimate, I would buy one of those.
Rym: They received.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: A torrent of death.
Scott: It probably looks all cool in technology.
Rym: The company that made this product received a torrent of death threats, threats of violence, fake bombs being mailed to them, the likes of which the internet has never produced before.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: The world, the sheer amount of violence that was threatened to these people by gun people.
Scott: Oh, so wait, these people have guns and threaten someone, so we can lock them all up, right?
Rym: We probably should.
Scott: Right, yeah.
Scott: These are people who have a gun, like guns, and are threatening someone with death, so we can just go to all their houses and arrest them all, at gunpoint, and take all their guns.
Rym: If you ever wonder why it's so hard to talk about technology in the world, look at this.
Rym: This was not someone saying, "Hey, let's pass a law only allowing these kinds of
Rym: guns.".
Rym: This was someone saying, "Hey, I invented a new technology that's incrementally better than existing
Rym: technology.".
Rym: And the response was, "You should not go there.
Rym: You employ God death
Rym: threats.".
Scott: Well, actually, do you know the real reason, right, is there's a law in New Jersey.
Rym: I know about that law.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: So the law in New Jersey says that if there is ever commercially available viable biometric control, then there's a time period wherein it has to be mandated.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Which, you know what, I'm also kind of far.
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Rym: As long as the technology is feasible.
Scott: The lesser the law says, it has to be feasible, right?
Rym: But the fact that there are gun owners who are against that, too, is, again, interesting.
Scott: Right, but I mean, you know, listen, I have no problem with responsible gun ownership.
Scott: Most of the people I know who own guns are responsible gun owners who use it for hunting and marksmanship and other perfectly legitimate uses, right?
Scott: I don't know these, I mean, I'd never met in my life, actually, an irresponsible gun owner.
Scott: I have.
Scott: Who's a crazy person who just wants to shoot people.
Scott: But clearly that person exists because they're sending death threats to this company and whoever is trying to sell these guns in New Jersey, whatever, right?
Scott: And we just get rid of those people and then only the responsible gun owners will be left.
Rym: Yeah, you know what, guys?
Rym: If those people did not have guns, I'd be pretty okay with really lax gun laws for the people who could still qualify for a gun.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's really easy to find these crazy people because they really just expose themselves.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Maybe this is a government honeypot to identify them all.
Scott: The problem is if you try to go and arrest them, they shoot at you.
Rym: Or they threaten to, and then you get the climate Bundy situation.
Scott: Let's just stand in the front lawn and write down the crimes they're committing as they commit them.
Rym: You know, I've always wanted that.
Rym: Maybe the way to draw the crazies out of the woodwork is to have Obama go on TV and be like, "So we're hereby making the city of Detroit a communist federal city under the jurisdiction of the federal government with guaranteed universal employment, and we're taking away everyone's
Rym: guns.".
Rym: And just everyone who goes apeshit and tries to attack government buildings, we just arrest them, and then that's the end.
Scott: We don't even do the thing in Detroit.
Scott: It was just a fib.
Rym: Yeah, we don't do anything.
Rym: We just say the things to evaporate.
Scott: Just say things to get the crazies to come out of their hidey holes, and then we arrest all the crazies.
Rym: It's the same way you can get ice to freeze faster if you evaporate the hottest ions and atoms.
Rym: Well, not ions, but the hottest molecules out of the top.
Rym: Do the same thing.
Rym: Evaporate the most crazy gun people out of the top, and suddenly I'm a lot less angry about gun control.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot, you know, we can just, they say the freaks come out at night, right?
Scott: So we'll just bring the sun down, the freaks will come out, and be like, "All right, we got all you freaks.
Scott: Into jail you go.
Scott: And we're
Scott: done.".
Rym: Let's blow through the rest of these.
Scott: There's more?
Rym: Yeah, sad news.
Rym: Recently, Oklahoma botched an execution by using an untested drug because the drugs that they-- Because Europe stopped giving them real drugs.
Rym: Yes, because Europe said, "Yo, you shouldn't execute people, you fucking
Rym: barbarians.".
Scott: That's right, barbarians in Oklahoma.
Rym: Here's why I think this is tech news.
Rym: The fact that the United States uses lethal injection of a cocktail of chemicals like this to this day is ridiculous, when we could-- This is not tech news at all.
Rym: The technology exists to execute humans in a perfectly guaranteed-to-work, zero-pain--.
Scott: But that's not technology news, that's technology olds.
Rym: Yes, zero-distress method, and we won't implement it.
Scott: Have I mentioned my zero-distress method on the show before?
Rym: The giant block that just crushes your entire head?
Scott: Yeah, that method.
Rym: Or, you know what, nitrogen asphyxiation works just as well.
Scott: See, the reason I like my method is not because I'm a barbarian, right?
Scott: I don't think we should kill anyone in the first place, right?
Scott: But if you're going to, we've already decided that, right?
Scott: For some reason we're stupid, we made the decision.
Scott: If you crush someone's head with a giant, giant rock, right?
Scott: It's like a guillotine, but a really giant rock, and it doesn't cut your neck, it just smashes your head like a watermelon, right?
Scott: A, you don't feel shit.
Scott: You are just gone, right?
Scott: So there's no suffering, it's really humane.
Scott: But B, the people who are so barbaric that they have to watch it-- Have to watch it.
Scott: They have to watch it.
Scott: They don't just get to watch someone go to sleep, right?
Scott: They gotta watch this head get smashed in, and then the people, the executioners, gotta clean that shit up.
Scott: Or, I say, the people who are like, you know, the ones who asked for the death penalty in court, make them clean it up.
Scott: It's like, alright, you want this person dead?
Scott: You do it and clean it up.
Rym: I worry that there's a bunch of people who would be like, hell's fucking yeah.
Scott: Okay, then we know that they're crazy, we can lock them up too.
Scott: They can go next.
Rym: Alright, let's see, one more I think here is worth talking about.
Rym: So, Mayor de Blasio, New York City-- Best mayor so far.
Scott: --has proposed yet more populist legislation-- Only politician that I did not complain about, have been a fan of, and has not done anything yet to prove any sort of scandal or corruption.
Rym: What's the over-under before the state and Cuomo tell him to go fuck himself on this one too?
Scott: Well, but what's the over-under?
Scott: before he's found in bed with like ten dudes of-- No problem with that.
Scott: Yeah, I had no problem with that either, but, you know, the world does, I guess, right?
Rym: Ah, you know what?
Rym: In New York, that probably wouldn't affect his reelection chances that much.
Rym: As long as he didn't lie about it.
Rym: It didn't help Weiner.
Rym: If Anthony Weiner had been like, that's my dick on day one, I bet he'd still be in office.
Scott: I guess Clinton got away with it.
Rym: The moral is, these old people don't get it, if someone actually does have a picture of your dick, and they put it somewhere and say that's your dick, you have to say yes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Unless you're actually not sure, because you might not-- Be like, hey, check out my dick.
Rym: Yeah, be like, that might be my dick.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It could be.
Rym: So anyway, de Blasio-- Let's look.
Scott: Pull your pants down.
Rym: --is arguing that New York is special in the sense that we-- Yes, it is.
Rym: --we need municipal Wi-Fi that's free for the entire city for the public.
Rym: good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We have that stupid Boingo Wi-Fi, which actually is pretty fast once you connect it to it.
Scott: And it doesn't show-- it stopped showing me ads.
Scott: I think no one's paying for the ad spot right now, so you can just use it without watching the ad.
Scott: But it's still annoying, because by the time you connect, by going to the website, like a hotel, the subway shows up.
Scott: So I can only use it like late at night on the platform when I have to wait a while for the train to come.
Rym: So he's basically forming a broadband task force to try to guarantee high-speed broadband to everyone in New York City--.
Rym: --and to continue Bloomberg's initiative to turn every form of a phone in all of New York into a Wi-Fi hotspot that's free.
Scott: Also good.
Rym: Bloomberg is also pushing to give Harlem literally the largest contiguous free public Wi-Fi network in North America.
Scott: Yeah, sounds good to me.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the telecoms are lobbying against this, of course.
Scott: Yeah, because you know what?
Scott: Goodbye phone plan, Wi-Fi only, Skype phone.
Scott: And he seems to be going down the-- I'll buy temporary one-day SIM cards if I go to a convention or some shit.
Rym: If Verizon and Time Warner don't play ball, he's talking about maybe bypassing them and doing it directly.
Scott: Yeah, fuck 'em.
Rym: Quote, "We're going to reexamine our franchise agreements, including with Verizon, Fios, and Time Warner Cable, to hold them accountable for providing the kind of servers they're obligated
Rym: to.".
Scott: Yeah, fuck 'em.
Rym: "I think the internet is a utility in cities and should be regulated as a
Rym: utility.".
Scott: I think the internet's a utility everywhere.
Scott: Yes, but at least in New York City, getting the laws-- How are we supposed to be all ghost in the shell if we don't just have internet everywhere all the time?
Rym: There are laws.
Rym: If you have an apartment building, you have to connect to the municipal water network.
Scott: No.
Rym: You're not allowed to just not do that.
Rym: Really?
Rym: The same thing should be for a municipal internet network.
Scott: Yeah, they can run the internet cables right in the steam pipes.
Scott: Not that many people are buying steam.
Rym: A lot of people pay for steam.
Scott: Who's buying steam?
Rym: Steam, because steam is way efficient if your building's hooked up for it.
Scott: Listen, I know you can get a lot of video games on steam, right?
Scott: It's a little old by now, right?
Scott: And there's too many games coming out on there.
Scott: It's like, "I stopped buying steam games a while
Scott: ago.".
Rym: No, imagine this.
Rym: Imagine a future where this happens, and New York City-- Forget the ISPs outside of New York.
Rym: Imagine if New York City laid some ridiculous fiber network.
Rym: So within the city, we had tens of gigabits just everywhere.
Rym: Just infinite bandwidth.
Rym: Suddenly, there's things we can do in the city.
Rym: The city's network would be its own internet-- It would be an internet within the internet.
Rym: That's something that we haven't seen happen.
Rym: What would happen within New York City if between your house, my house, and all our friends, and all the convention centers within the city, we had literally effective, infinite bandwidth?
Rym: I think a local internet of interesting shit would start happening.
Scott: If they set it up, I don't think they'll set it up in that way to where we all have these local subnet of New York IPs.
Rym: No, not like that.
Rym: But for example, imagine if there were just extremely high-speed links and high-speed trunks running around the city.
Rym: So if your packets are going to somewhere within New York City, you don't leave the municipal network.
Scott: Oh, sure.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: Interesting things can happen.
Scott: We've never seen anyone-- To make really interesting things happen, you'd have to have this sort of New York--.
Scott: They are getting .nyc.
Scott: They've already got it, right?
Scott: So if they made .nyc internal, so if you went to a .nyc, it had to be a server hosted in NYC on the NYC network.
Scott: Suddenly, now you can route to these internal NYC servers.
Rym: Also, suddenly, imagine this.
Rym: You know the whole net neutrality debate about pairing and everything?
Rym: Service providers, I think it would be perfectly okay.
Rym: if they wanted to, I think New York should let them just host in their network.
Rym: Like, "All right, Netflix, you want to put a server in our network?
Rym: Infinite bandwidth, go
Rym: nuts.".
Scott: You know what?
Scott: You could do a lot of finance shit on the NYC network.
Scott: The stock market just plugs in and gets on there.
Rym: Interesting shit can happen.
Rym: There's enough shit in NYC that NYC-- Two very smaller cities in piles of proof.
Scott: If we made our own network and then connected it to the internet, we would be so strong enough to start bossing around other people and threaten to not peer with them.
Rym: So imagine this.
Rym: Imagine if then Boston builds theirs and then we run a cable.
Scott: Yeah, you own the cable between New York City and Boston.
Rym: No, the city of New York and the city of Boston agree to peer with each other.
Scott: Okay, we'll just have to slow down any bandwidth when the Red Sox games are going on.
Rym: Yeah, well, the cyber warfare division will handle that.
Scott: Oh, the Patriots are visiting Giants Stadium.
Scott: That's a shame.
Rym: Oh, all the traffic lights turn red.
Rym: I guess they can't make it to the game default.
Rym: Sorry.
Scott: They got MITs, though, so it would be a tough fight.
Rym: Yeah, actually.
Scott: We might lose.
Rym: We'll have to enlist some help.
Rym: We got RIT in the stadium.
Scott: We have graduates.
Scott: They have students.
Scott: The students have a lot more free time on their hands.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: The graduates are, you know, sitting on the beach.
Rym: I think we're done here.
Rym: I think that's technology news.
Scott: That was pretty tech news, but also politics news.
Rym: Yeah, but technology and politics are too important to each other lately.
Rym: Time to watch hockey.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.