Rym: It's Tuesday, March 4th, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, the phases of games and why the beginning and the end don't matter.
Rym: Maybe the middle doesn't matter.
Rym: Nothing matters.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I know we said no more hiatus for GeekNights, but unfortunately I got sick last week so we missed a show.
Rym: And I'm going to be in Europe starting tomorrow morning.
Scott: If you're in Europe in one of the cities where Rym is going to, why don't you meet him?
Rym: Yeah, follow me on Twitter, but basically this Saturday I'll be in London pretty much all day with fuck all to do.
Rym: I'm not flying to Mumbai until late that night.
Rym: So if you want to meet at like a pub in London, somewhere relatively downtown in the afternoon, grab a pint, fish and chips, whatever you people do.
Scott: Bring me back some Crown Jewels.
Rym: I don't have enough time to organize some sort of Lupin-style heist.
Scott: Well, the person who's there probably has it already set up.
Rym: I might get some sort of Locke Lamora-style heist, but you won't like the results of that.
Rym: And yeah, I'll be in Mumbai the next day if anyone happens to be hanging out in Mumbai.
Rym: And my Abu Dhabi part is only a extended layover.
Rym: I don't know if I'll bother leaving the airport because I kind of have time to leave the airport.
Scott: If you work in the Abu Dhabi airport.
Rym: What's funny is I go to the Abu Dhabi airport website and it's like, how long is your transfer?
Scott: It's a serious airport, right?
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Rym: And they're like, how long is your transfer?
Rym: And basically they're like, based on how long your transfer is, they tell you what you can do.
Rym: And they're like, if you have three to five hours, here's a golf course.
Rym: We'll take you there.
Scott: Three to five hours.
Scott: We have a spa built into the airport.
Rym: Well, I was at an airport years ago where there were these pods just in the terminals.
Rym: And basically what you could do, there were big pods.
Rym: You walk up to it and if it's not in use, you swipe your credit card and it's a hotel room in the terminal.
Rym: You just walk in, lock the door, you've got a hotel room.
Rym: You pay for it in like four hour blocks.
Scott: When you leave it, who cleans it?
Rym: When you leave it, I guess it's locked out until the maids come and then it opens up again.
Rym: So it's basically a hotel.
Rym: So if you have like a five hour layover, you can just check into a hotel room with your credit card.
Rym: It's kind of cool.
Scott: Set your alarm for four hours.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: Literally wake up and just go to your play.
Scott: Does the pod have a TV?
Rym: I assume so.
Rym: I've never used one of these things.
Scott: Does it vibrate?
Rym: I've not seen a vibrating bed since the Chai Lai Motor Inn.
Rym: You remember those days.
Scott: That one day, yes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Those days when we'd stay in cheap hotels and, well, motels and weird places for weird reasons.
Rym: I haven't done that in a while.
Scott: We can afford not to.
Rym: Well, we never travel far enough to where we need to stay en route to somewhere else.
Rym: And we don't go to cons where there isn't a hotel nearby.
Scott: Let's bike in one direction for a whole day until we get to a motel when the sun goes down.
Rym: You know, long distance bike trips might be when we start hitting motels again.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So, yeah, no GeekNights the rest of the week, but I'll be back in the States.
Scott: If you want to be entertained on the internet in other ways, I will do my not necessarily best, but I'll put some forth the token effort.
Scott: And if you stay tuned to the meta moment, maybe you'll learn about that token effort.
Rym: Ah, token efforts.
Rym: I like tokens.
Scott: Meh.
Rym: So, in the news, I got a Geek Byte.
Rym: I've been playing Civ V a lot lately.
Scott: We've talked about Civ enough on this show.
Scott: What more could there possibly be to say that has not been said?
Rym: Alright, well, the one thing I want to point out is that I was playing it again partly because I've been playing it multiplayer and I'm testing all the bits and getting, you know, there's this learning curve to Civ until you sort of naturally know everything.
Rym: Like, every time you play through the game once, there's one more complicated, deeper bit.
Scott: What does that wonder do?
Rym: Well, no, like that you ignore.
Rym: Like, I'm going to ignore the tourism thing.
Scott: Oh, I can buy things using the faith points.
Rym: Or theming bonus with the tourism stuff.
Rym: What's that?
Rym: I'll just let that be automatic this time.
Rym: And the next time you're like, I should look at what that does.
Rym: So, I've been doing that.
Rym: I was playing a game the other day and I was going for the Culture Victory, which is significantly different under the new expansions.
Scott: I like the way Culture Victory worked in Civ III.
Scott: It was easy.
Rym: Yeah, it was also boring.
Rym: Civ V is great.
Rym: Basically, if your tourism output is greater than their culture output, you start becoming more and more influential over them.
Rym: And then if you conquer their cities, the people are like, OK, dog, whatever, it's cool.
Rym: Or, eventually, they just let you in.
Rym: So, you can defend against that by having more culture yourself.
Rym: So, I went for the Culture Victory and it was just taking too long.
Rym: And it so happens that when I'm in a position to get the Culture Victory, I'm also in a position to get Diplomatic Victory and Domination Victory.
Scott: Yeah, I noticed that happens in Civ in general, that all the victory conditions overlap a lot.
Scott: So, it's like, if you're going to get one, it's sort of like you can choose whichever one you want.
Rym: Well, it's interesting.
Rym: What I found is that my style of play goes toward an extreme economy, which basically makes all the other ones trivial.
Rym: But, if I go for Culture from the beginning, really Culture is the only one I can go for by the end.
Rym: Like, I won't have the military capability to go for Domination.
Rym: So, just my play style.
Rym: But anyway, it was taking too long and I was like, "Fuck
Rym: it!".
Rym: So, I just invaded the civilization, the last one that had their capital, to just take it and win the game right away, because my military was just so big.
Rym: And, I took their capital and I didn't win.
Rym: So, I'm like,
Rym: "What?".
Rym: So, I go into the Civipedia and it says, "Yeah, if you're the last civilization who has your original capital, you win a Domination
Rym: Victory.".
Rym: It turns out, they changed that in the expansion and didn't update the Civillipedia.
Rym: So, I go on Google and I'm like, "Yo, Civ V
Rym: Domination.".
Rym: And, the first result is like broken.
Rym: Here's the explanation.
Rym: So, it's no longer having the only, basically the only person left who has your original capital.
Rym: You have to have all of the original capitals.
Rym: So, I went and reconquered the capital that I had previously liberated back to good old George Washington and then I immediately won.
Rym: So, yeah, watch out for the Civillipedia.
Rym: They have not kept it 100% accurate.
Scott: Documentation?
Scott: Out of date?
Scott: What?
Rym: Hey, Civ games have had better documentation throughout their entire history than any other game or software I have ever played or used in my entire life.
Scott: Civ 2 came with a fucking tome.
Rym: I know, that book was like three quarters of an inch thick and I never owned it in my life because I pirated the game.
Scott: I have it.
Rym: But, it also had the Civillipedia stuff and the help and it was awesome.
Rym: So, yeah, that's my tale of woe.
Scott: I bet it takes longer to make the Civillipedia than it takes to code the stupid game.
Rym: No, easily.
Rym: Documentation is the least served and also probably actually least important part of software design, to be perfectly honest.
Scott: Imagine if someone, the guy whose job it is to make the Civillipedia, he's like, "No one will ever look at this.
Scott: Oh, I hate my
Scott: life.".
Rym: Yeah, but Civ people seem to always look at it because they obsess over the minutia of.
Scott: I rarely look at the Civillipedia.
Rym: Scott, do you build a second city in your first 50 turns?
Scott: In the first 50 turns?
Scott: Depends on who I am.
Scott: Not if I'm Ghandi.
Rym: Yes, you can probably figure that out from looking at the Civillipedia if you should.
Rym: Anyway, so you got any news?
Scott: Sort of.
Scott: It's not a big news, but in some ways it's an insignificant news.
Scott: A remake of a game is going to be released.
Scott: Big deal, right?
Scott: Not something the big talk about.
Scott: The game is Jungle Speed.
Scott: A game we have talked about quite often on this show.
Scott: Nothing special.
Scott: They're going to make a 20th anniversary edition.
Scott: 20?
Rym: Fuck!
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just Jungle Speed re-release.
Scott: Why is this a big deal?
Scott: Wooden totem.
Rym: Great.
Scott: Return of the wooden totem.
Rym: So now, not only...
Scott: I'm going to buy like three of them.
Rym: Yeah, not only can I play...
Scott: I'm seriously not even joking.
Scott: I'm going to buy at least two.
Rym: So not only can I play the original, proper Jungle Speed with a proper edition, because actually lately a big problem is that all the expansions and things were all printed by different people at different times and Amazon entries all suck.
Scott: I'm missing a Jungle Speed card and I have the expansion Jungle Speed Extreme.
Scott: The good expansion.
Scott: And the backs of the Jungle Speed Extreme do not match the current printings of Jungle Speed.
Scott: So I can't mix the incomplete set I have.
Rym: But Jungle Speed without Extreme has kind of played out for me at this point.
Scott: Not if it has a wooden totem.
Rym: Yeah, so now not only can I play Jungle Speed again in a canonical format, but I can actually break my finger instead of just breaking the fingernail off of my finger.
Scott: The way it was meant to be.
Rym: Maybe we should just go all out and get Turbo to make us one of those stainless steel totems.
Scott: Let's not get a stainless steel totem.
Rym: There's polonium.
Rym: There's polonium up ins.
Scott: Uh...
Rym: Dolomite.
Scott: Plutonium.
Scott: Unilenium totem.
Scott: You have to be really fast to grab it.
Rym: Seriously, we don't talk about these kinds of games, but Jungle Speed is a great game.
Rym: The problem is you can't make it your primary game.
Rym: That's the game you play when everyone meets up at a con for like an hour before you all split up into real games.
Rym: If you play Jungle Speed, all con.
Rym: One, you're breaking a finger.
Scott: Two...
Rym: Things of the day!
Rym: I can't really explain how I found this.
Rym: And it doesn't have a lot of views.
Rym: So I feel like, unlike my old days of "Here's a College Humor" video, I got something kind of obscure.
Rym: Someone took the animation from He-Man and overdubbed it and made a sketch about Skeletor having ADHD and it involves a baby.
Scott: Are you sure it wasn't like a sketch that was done somewhere else?
Scott: and then someone took the audio from that sketch and then matched up He-Man video?
Rym: I don't think so because the audio specifically references Skeletor, the baby, Princess Adora, the baby, we stole the baby.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So if there's Princess Adora, the baby, and Skeletor and some other thing, then I kind of want to see whatever that thing is.
Rym: This is so close to what used to be the aesthetic of Space Ghost Coast to Coast that it made me really want to watch old Space Ghost Coast to Coast.
Scott: I'm sure there is a torrent all Space Ghost.
Rym: There probably is.
Rym: So if you like my thing of the day, do yourself a favor.
Scott: Maybe I'll get that torrent and spend the rest of my life just wasting on my couch.
Rym: The thing is there's not that much Space Ghost Coast to Coast.
Scott: There's a lot of it.
Scott: There's more than you'd think.
Rym: Well, do you also include like the Cartoon Planet stuff?
Rym: Like how deep do you go?
Scott: It doesn't add that many hours.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it's trouble because those episodes are, in terms of mental hours, like four hours long each.
Rym: I think my favorite one is still the one where he just follows that ant for the entire episode.
Rym: Anyway, you got a thing of the day?
Scott: I do.
Scott: So this would normally be a Monday thing of the day, but that doesn't matter.
Scott: It's Tuesday and you're getting a Monday thing of the day.
Scott: You should learn some other geekery, gamer people.
Rym: I guess mine was a Wednesday thing of the day.
Scott: So if you have a computer and you have a list of numbers and you want to tell the computer to sort that list of numbers, nowadays you can just do sort, parenthesis, list, name, close parenthesis and it will happen.
Rym: And you don't care how it happens.
Scott: Right, but how is it happening?
Scott: How does a computer do that?
Scott: I mean, a human being, you can just look at, you know, if I give you the numbers one to ten on different pieces of paper, you can just put them in order, just eh.
Scott: But a computer can't do that.
Rym: No, even then, you're not just going eh.
Rym: You have some algorithm or process in your brain.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like you'll just find the one, put it first, find the two, put it second.
Scott: probably, right?
Scott: Computer can't do that.
Scott: Computer, you know, to sort an arbitrary list of numbers, computer needs some sort of algorithm.
Scott: The best algorithm on average is called the quicksort.
Scott: How does the quicksort work?
Scott: Watch these Hungarian folk dancers demonstrate.
Rym: This is pretty great.
Rym: So, in the meta moment, might not be GeekNights for a week or so and then we'll return.
Rym: Scott is going to produce some content on his own, it sounds like.
Scott: The content I will produce will probably be like some Netrunner videos.
Rym: Twitch stream.
Scott: I'm streaming Twitch, I'm still playing Pokemon LeafGreen, which is the best Pokemon.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: So you can go to my Twitch channel.
Rym: I gotta start doing my Twitch streams more often, now that we know how to not lose our videos.
Scott: I might be doing some other stuff, depending on discussions with other people, maybe.
Rym: Oh?
Rym: Something secret?
Scott: No, it's not really, it's just I don't know.
Rym: You don't want to shit talk it until it's real?
Scott: Ah, yeah, exactly, right.
Scott: And then, but I already made one, you know, the sample.
Scott: I don't know, just follow me in all the internet places.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, my YouTube channel is pretty much.
Scott: Twitter, Facebook, G+, YouTube, Twitch.
Rym: The GeekNights Rym YouTube channel is pretty much the official GeekNights channel in terms of like our panels, our lectures, stuff like that.
Rym: Scott's Twitch is pretty much the official GeekNights streaming channel.
Scott: And remember, I have my own YouTube, which is mostly Netrunner videos, but not entirely.
Rym: In the summer, it's also occasionally Scott biking somewhere.
Scott: We got a lot of different channels on the internet.
Scott: Our website, which maybe you could visit.
Scott: Our forum, you know, go to all those places.
Rym: Our forum is pretty badass lately.
Rym: You should really check it out.
Rym: It's not like other internet forums.
Scott: Go to all the places on the internet and follow us.
Scott: You know, Rym has some tumbles sometimes.
Rym: Yeah, I'm going to tumble again soon.
Rym: I got to queue up a bunch of tumbles and let them tumble on down.
Scott: We got like Flickr account, you know, we are the people who post things on the internet.
Scott: The shy people are like deleting all their accounts saying, "No, I'm not
Scott: posting.".
Scott: You know, so follow us and see things.
Scott: Get the whole experience.
Scott: Don't just listen to the stupid podcast.
Rym: And thankfully, because I'm very careful when I go through Flickr, you're not going to accidentally see our dicks.
Scott: Great.
Rym: So, there was a fascinating article recently.
Scott: What's the Book Club book?
Rym: Oh, the Book Club book is Wool, post-apocalyptic something.
Scott: Like the shit that sheep grow on them.
Rym: That's a way to describe wool, I guess.
Scott: And then you cut it off and make a sweater with.
Rym: But you shear it off.
Scott: Same thing.
Rym: No, it is subtly so.
Rym: If I think cut it off, I imagine using like a knife or scissors.
Rym: But shearing, I imagine using a shearing device of some kind.
Scott: Oh, whatevs.
Rym: So, there's a fascinating article about Civ 5, and though it really applies to all versions of Civ, and it asks a question where half the world said, "Duh," and the other half said, "Why would you do that?
Rym: Who would ever do
Rym: that?".
Rym: The question was simple.
Rym: Is there ever a case in a Civilization game where you should move your settler on the first turn, rather than immediately building your Civ?
Scott: Do you immediately press B, or do you move your settler first?
Scott: So, first of all, it depends on, you know, apparently, I didn't realize this, there's a mode in Civ with biased starting position.
Rym: Which is the best way to play.
Scott: It'll put your settler in an amazing spot to start with, in which case there's really no reason not to just push B.
Rym: And everyone else also starts in an amazing spot that's tuned to them, so it's fine.
Scott: It gives you the resources that like your Civ is better with and such.
Scott: So it's not like, "I'm the
Scott: Mongols."
Scott: If you're a boating guy, you'll be on the fucking coast.
Rym: You're not gonna be like, "I'm the Mongols, I never see a horse the entire
Rym: game.".
Scott: Right, there'll be a horse right fucking there, right?
Scott: So if you have that mode on, press B. If you don't have the mode on, right, then, well, you gotta sort of look around, right?
Scott: You can only see so far, so it's like you look at your spot and it's never gonna be a bad spot.
Scott: They never give you something awful to start with.
Rym: You're on one desert tile surrounded by ocean in every direction.
Scott: No, surrounded by mountains that cannot be traversed.
Scott: Without flight.
Scott: No, it's like, they'll start you in an okay spot, but it's like, if I spend a turn moving, right, am I gonna see a better spot?
Scott: Which direction do I go?
Scott: Assuming you're surrounded by land.
Rym: And this is new to Civ, I mean, in old Civ games, sometimes you start with two settlers, or a settler and a warrior, settler and a scout.
Scott: Oh, two settlers is so good.
Rym: Oh my god, two settlers was... In my Civ 2 strategy was pretty much...
Scott: Restart the game until you get two settlers?
Rym: Yep, and then build as many fucking cities as I can as fast as possible.
Rym: Because fuck you.
Rym: And that worked really great.
Scott: That was my strategy as well.
Rym: Of course, that was an error when I didn't really play Civ games against humans.
Rym: Because if someone tried that shit against me, my one horseman would just take all the cities and all the settlers.
Scott: Oh, is that a settler all in his own running to hurry up and build the city?
Scott: Alright, build it.
Scott: Yoink!
Scott: Nowadays the city defends itself, so you gotta grab the settler.
Rym: Now, the article is fascinating because it, one, brings up the schism that, think about this, a popular game, a popular game franchise, had a question, a simple strategic question.
Rym: You have a choice on your first turn, otherwise why wouldn't you just start with the city?
Rym: So there is a choice there.
Rym: Half of the people who played Civ never even considered that that choice mattered.
Rym: And the other half agonized over that choice.
Scott: Well, cause I mean, you're sitting there and you're thinking, if I wait an extra turn before building the city, I'm giving up, what, like, you know, two barrels, two grains, and a shield maybe?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Worth of production?
Rym: Yep, on turn 100, how much is that gonna matter?
Rym: Possibly a lot.
Scott: Right, because that means I could've gotten, like, a temple a turn sooner, which means I could've gotten something else a turn sooner, and so on and so forth, and you imagine, wow, that adds up to a lot of resources.
Scott: But, what if I move to a better spot, right?
Scott: If I move and land somewhere that then has, say, a better resource, like, I don't know, a wheat.
Rym: Wheat's pretty good.
Scott: That's like an extra, okay, I lose the two food from this turn, but I'll get it back within two turns, and on the third turn, I'll be profiting with that one extra, you know, food barrel.
Rym: But, what if I move, and the terrain I see is actually not better, and I just fucked myself.
Scott: Then you just fucked yourself, because now you gotta spend a turn moving back.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You lost two turns, so two shields and four wheats.
Rym: So, the fact that this was, you know, the game, you always have to think about this when you play games.
Rym: Games present choices, at least good games, for a reason.
Rym: So, if there's no reason to make a choice, the game shouldn't give you that choice.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Of course, games like The Stanley Parable pointedly give you choices that don't matter, and then rub your nose in it.
Rym: So, it's interesting that so many people never considered it, and the article goes on and talks about how it actually does matter, and how, basically, well, you should read the article.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil it.
Scott: Well, no, they simulated it with a computer, right?
Scott: They played through a zillion games, and they found that moving...
Rym: Spoilers.
Scott: On average, yeah, sure.
Scott: Helps you, because you're going to a better spot, assuming you don't have the awesome starting...
Rym: Yep, so it assumes you don't have the biased start, and it assumes you're not dumb.
Scott: Right, it's like, you're gonna move, you're gonna get into a better spot, usually, and then that's gonna add up to being more, right?
Rym: They did do an interesting control.
Rym: They would test the same civ, one not moving, and one not moving, and not settling the first turn.
Rym: And that one objectively just did way worse.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, there's always the thing of, you have a starting spot that they put you in, and it's like, you can actually move the settler and push B on turn one.
Scott: So, it's like, what if they put your settler one space away from the coast?
Scott: Do you go and make your city a coastal city?
Scott: Or do you just park it where it is and get a little bit more land in there?
Rym: I've decided that the answer in Civ 5 is yes, you need that fucking coastal city, Jesus.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: What if you start with your settler in the middle of, like, you know, Kansas?
Rym: Well, the thing is, the trouble with coastal cities is, well, if you're near the coast at all, but not on the coast, you're fucked, because you can't build a lot of the water things, you can't build ships, but other ships can still bombard your shit.
Scott: Barbarian boats.
Rym: But if you're not barbarian boats, me with frigates.
Scott: You're talking about later in the game.
Rym: Yeah, in multiplayer games, as soon as I can get out to the ocean, I declare war on everyone and just start bombarding their cities just for the fuck of it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm kind of a jerk in Civ games.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, so, early game, late game, that's kind of the topic here.
Scott: It's also mid-game, right?
Scott: So, pretty much any game you play, even a game that seems like it might not, like a game that's so, I guess Rock, Paper, Scissors does not have an early, mid, and late game, right?
Rym: Well, Sean, Ken, Po, early, mid, late.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: But any game where you have to make more than one decision in sequence before the result happens, right, can be broken up into sort of phases, right, which are pretty different from each other.
Scott: Even tic-tac-toe, right?
Scott: The early game is like the setup, right?
Scott: The mid-game is don't die, and the late game is finish them off, or actually tie, right?
Scott: Ice hockey, the early game, try to score a goal.
Scott: The mid-game, depending on who's winning, either go to stronger defense or stronger offense.
Scott: The late game, desperate attempt, pull your goalie if you're only one down, right?
Scott: You sort of, or, you know, just kill time on the clock to put the other team away once you get the puck.
Rym: Yep, onside kick, onside kick.
Scott: Right, yeah, football, same deal, right?
Scott: Early on in football, you want to take control of the ball, you want to score early points, get an early lead.
Scott: Mid-game, you just sort of, you know, if you've got the lead, play conservatively.
Scott: If you don't, you know, just, you know, you've got to play a little, you know, more risky.
Scott: In the late game, onside kicks, crazy shit, just try to get points any way you can.
Rym: Now, I think there's a lot of differences in terms of the actual discussion between, I guess, ortho games, which is what we're discussing, but I think ortho games in sports or dexterity games have, in some ways, fundamentally different structures.
Rym: in that, is early or late game a question of progress and ability versus the cumulative effect of the decisions you have made?
Rym: I mean, the football team doesn't choose to get tackled one yard away from a first down.
Rym: Well, unless you're the Broncos.
Scott: No, but I mean, any game has, it's about the time, right?
Scott: You know, football has a clock, hockey has a clock.
Rym: But ortho games that are not time-based, like board games, they have a time, I think they were getting that, in the sense of number of decisions left to be made.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's, you know, how much of the game is left?
Scott: How close are we to fulfilling the condition to where the game is over, the winner is deciding?
Rym: How many turns will I get?
Rym: How many motions will I take?
Scott: And most, you know, pretty much almost every game, you know, you start off early, you know, take Agricola or Puerto Rico or any of these.
Scott: Early on, what you're trying to do is just get base resources, so it's sort of a resource grab, right?
Scott: The mid game is use the resources you grabbed to build a machine of some kind, right?
Scott: You know, to get your stuff going.
Scott: And then the late game is use that machine as efficiently as possible, right?
Scott: So all three of these phases, you know, in a good game end up mattering, right?
Scott: If you don't get enough resources in the early game, then in the mid game, you're not going to be able to build the machine you wanted, right?
Scott: You know, in exactly the way you wanted.
Scott: But even if some guy builds a less efficient machine than you, in the late game, you have to crank that machine and they might end up cranking theirs harder to make up for the fact that theirs is crappier, right?
Rym: It's extremely obvious in games that have ways to change when the game ends.
Rym: If a player who's behind has an ability to extend the game, then suddenly the number of decisions is variable.
Rym: It's almost like the rocket fuel equation.
Rym: How much rocket fuel do I need depends on how much rocket fuel I bring.
Scott: Now, sometimes you have a bad game.
Scott: And bad games still tend to follow the same basic, you know, flow with the early, mid, and late game.
Scott: But, if the game is broken or bad in some way, one or more of those phases may not matter.
Rym: I'll give you a really abstract example from a game.
Rym:  So Borderlands 1.
Scott:  I'll give you a real example.
Rym: Borderlands 1.
Rym: In the early game, you're extremely, or even for a single player, straight up ideal game, Deus Ex Human Revolution.
Rym: In the early game, your customization of weapons and picking up the right weapon and choosing the right weapons matters a lot.
Rym: What skill tree you unlock and what skill you use next matters a lot.
Rym: It has huge effects on your game.
Rym: Toward the mid and late game, whatever, it's a sniper rifle.
Rym: Who cares if it does explosion damage or whatever?
Rym: It has the highest numbers.
Rym: And suddenly, this whole aspect of the game of inventory management or skill tree management, you're still doing it.
Rym: You're doing the exact same thing you're doing in the beginning, but it doesn't matter and you don't care anymore.
Rym: It doesn't affect the game anymore.
Scott: But yeah, in a bad game, you might have a situation where early on there's a resource grab, right?
Scott: Everyone grabs resources as quick as they can.
Scott: Whoever gets the most resources at the beginning just wins because it's just so obvious what to do with them.
Scott: And anyone who failed at the first part can't stop them.
Scott: So in effect, the early game is the whole game, and the mid and late game are just obvious or inconsequential decisions.
Rym: For example, look at really bad games like Risk.
Rym: All decisions are inconsequential or obvious, except for the setup basically determines victory.
Rym: But the setup is also random.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You know, in Stratego, the early game is the setting up of your board and the poking around.
Scott: The mid game is find where their shit is and the late game is go in there and actually try to take their shit.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Actually execute.
Rym: I mean, the dance of "Is the spy there or not?
Rym: Do I have minors to get
Rym: there?".
Rym: That sort of thing.
Rym: But even then, look, skill differentials matter a lot.
Rym: Two very skilled Stratego players, the early game, meaning the setup, is literally all that matters because neither player will make a mistake.
Rym: So some games, all phases other than choosing a strategy boil down to not accidentally failing to execute that strategy.
Rym: Or not choosing the wrong strategy.
Rym: And we talk with all these characteristics of games.
Rym: Every time we talk about this stuff, it comes down to this same problem, both with the decision trees, with everything.
Rym: If you have a strategy, then choosing a strategy and comparing that to what strategy the other person chose is the only thing that matters.
Rym: Luckily, we're humans, not robots.
Rym: We can't execute these things perfectly.
Rym: So the late game of Stratego still matters because even though I know, or like in hockey, I know to put the puck in the net, I might fail to execute on my plan in the end even if I know to pull the goalie.
Rym: So the decisions at the end matter and the execution still matters because we're humans.
Rym: But if robots play hockey, then the strategy of how the robots are programmed before the game is all that matters.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, this whole concept, it's like, is every game just early, mid, and late?
Scott: Isn't there other sort of phases in there?
Scott: I guess you could make a game that has intentional multiple phases, right?
Rym: Well, Amun-Re has it, but kind of fake.
Rym: You play the game twice, and the second game is just seeded with data from the previous game.
Rym: But even then, gameplay-wise, it's just early, mid, late game.
Rym: You might have a sub-game where it's early, mid, late of sub-game A, early, mid, late of sub-game B.
Scott: But the key to being good at a lot of games sometimes is all the things we've always said in other episodes and other panels and whatnot.
Scott: But to know, there isn't this clear-cut line in a lot of games, like we are now in the mid-game.
Scott: The mid-game starts exactly now.
Scott: The late game just started exactly at this moment.
Rym: DPT, end game, end game.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: You just sort of have to know when you're going from one to the other and recognize that and act accordingly, right?
Scott: Because, say, you're playing, I don't know, Puerto Rico, right?
Scott: In the early game, there's a lot of settling going on.
Scott: In the mid-game, there's maybe a little bit of settling, but not much.
Scott: In the late game, no settling at all, really.
Rym: So if you have a strategy that needs someone to settle a lot in the late game, yeah, you're screwed.
Rym: You're the only one settling.
Scott: But if you say that the governor comes around to you and it's your turn to choose something, right?
Scott: Everyone was, you know, you're still thinking it's the late game, I mean, the early game, you know, so is it still a good idea to settle?
Scott: Right?
Scott: But you look around and maybe, you know, the game has actually moved on to the mid-game, you're not quite sure, and if you settle with that slightly late settling, that might hurt you.
Scott: It was like, oh, no, if it was earlier and you settled, that would have been a good idea, but now, too late.
Rym: Well, settle.
Rym: If I send, if I still play early game and I'm sending out settlers in Civ 2 far and wide, eventually I have 15 one or two population cities, Scott has four cities, but they have populations of like five and he has military units.
Rym: I'm still playing the early game and now mid-game Scott destroys early game Rym.
Scott: It's all of you have to sort of know, like, when in a game it's time to sort of change gears and do something different.
Rym: I think we can recommend the exact board game that might be the best game I've ever seen at teaching people how to identify this.
Rym: St.
Rym: Petersburg.
Scott: That's a true one.
Rym: St.
Rym: Petersburg is a game.
Rym: We've reviewed it on GeekNights, I think.
Rym: I'll link to it if we did.
Scott: A long time ago, yeah.
Rym: I'm assuming we did, but basically you want money as way more valuable than anything in the beginning of the game.
Rym: Victory points are way more valuable than anything at the end of the game.
Rym: Obviously.
Rym: There's two ways to get victory points, buildings and a culturally insensitive term.
Rym: So, if-- Nobles.
Rym: Yeah, nobles.
Rym: Nobles.
Rym: I'm making quote marks.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Basically, there's green cards, which are the most efficient way to get money.
Scott: It's a game of buying cards that then make resources, which you then use to buy more cards.
Scott: It's a little game.
Scott: So, the green cards make you the most money the most efficiently.
Scott: The blue cards make you the most victory points.
Scott: The orange noble cards both make victory points and money, sort of, but the more different kinds of orange cards you have, nobles, you can also get a ton of victory points.
Scott: And then there's weird upgrade cards that are just sort of bonus-y.
Scott: So, you have to figure out in the game, everyone at the beginning of the game, right, gets green cards, hardcore.
Scott: You have to figure out when to stop going for all these crazy green cards and concentrate more on the blue and the orange cards.
Rym: Yeah, but it's easy to be trick because everything is cumulative.
Rym: So, if you get a four victory point building, as soon as you get it, that's four victory points every turn for the rest of the game.
Rym: Get it three turns before Scott, that's 12 victory points extra.
Rym: But the gold cards do the exact same thing.
Scott: But if you just buy an amazing victory point thing in the first turn, you're actually going to lose because even though you get a ton of victory points, you are not getting enough money to get any more victory points.
Scott: You did a late game move in the early game and messed you up.
Rym: It's a good game to teach this because the line between early game and mid game is so well defined that I could almost write a treatise on the exact moment when it occurs in the game.
Rym: It got to the point to where when we would play this game among the crew, like me and Scott and our friends, pretty much we would all, no one person could just deal out all the cards and play everyone perfectly until the mid game and then we could all take our real turns because it was deterministic.
Rym: The point at which the game becomes mid game is the point at which the player who is going to win buys a blue victory point card instead of buying an extra green card.
Rym: And if you do it one turn too soon among skilled players, you are guaranteed to lose.
Rym: If you do it one turn too late, you're almost guaranteed to lose.
Rym: You might be able to bring it back in the late game with the upgrades and the nobles.
Scott: Depending on your luck.
Rym: Yes, and your skill.
Scott: It is a card game after all.
Rym: Now the transition between mid game and late game is similarly well defined but not as harsh.
Rym: It's when you switch from getting novel orange cards and blue cards to planning the turn order to ensure that your final turns are spent getting a chance for upgrades.
Rym: Which is much more complicated to do.
Rym: So if you can play St.
Rym: Petersburg, it's a pretty simple and actually really fun board game to the point that you can really well identify early, mid, and late game.
Rym: You will have super powers when you play most other games.
Scott: Now why is it that these games sort of have the early, mid, late?
Scott: Why can't there be a game with like five phases?
Scott: Super early, kinda early, middling, kinda late, super late.
Scott: How come that doesn't happen?
Scott: It always seems to come in threes.
Scott: Every game I think of, there's always this sort of early, middle, late.
Scott: The initial building, the halving and using, and then the finishing move.
Rym: I have a good answer.
Rym: I don't know if you're building toward one or not.
Rym: No.
Rym: Now you're just putting the question out?
Scott: Can you think of a game that has more than three sort of strategic phases in it?
Rym: The game that Gurgi plays in Player of Games.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: But that's just a bunch of sub-games that all have a That all have three phases to them?
Rym: I have a pretty simple argument that I just came up with.
Rym: So if there's a hole in the logic, I would love anyone to tell us why you disagree.
Rym: I think the reason this is the perfect delineation of game phases is that if you add more distinction, the distinction becomes less meaningful.
Rym: And it becomes so much less meaningful that if I try to split Civ V into beginning, early, early, early, mid-early, late-early.
Rym: Like if I try to break up that early game into all these different phases, then those individual phases branch depending on what kind of strategy I'm pursuing.
Rym: So my early, early, late, mid-game might be building an extra phalanx when otherwise I could have built a warrior for fewer resources or an extra settler.
Rym: But it becomes so game-specific or so strategy-specific or so sort of diverse in terms of decision trees that it becomes absolutely useless except when you're discussing an individual game.
Scott: Any game, these three phases don't actually exist.
Scott: There is no definition like "it begins
Scott: now."
Scott: It's just this flow of a game from beginning to end.
Scott: The longer the game, the longer the flow.
Scott: But it just sort of flows up and flows down to the end.
Scott: Pretty much every game is like that no matter what.
Scott: So if you cut it into six pieces, how different is piece 4 and piece 5 going to be in the flow?
Scott: Not very different.
Scott: But cutting things into three pieces, it's like.
Scott: sure, if you look right on the line, is there a difference between this turn and two turns from now?
Scott: strategically?
Scott: Yeah, a small amount.
Scott: But cutting into three pieces, you can pretty clearly see there's a big difference between these things.
Scott: You only need to think in three pieces in order to get a handle on what you should be doing.
Rym: At best I could propose adding, but again it's game specific, a fourth phase.
Rym: Setup.
Scott: Before you even start playing?
Rym: Settlers has the setup and then early/mid/late game.
Rym: But again, as soon as you add that phase, it's not applicable to all games.
Rym: The three phases is probably the sweet spot of differentiating enough to be useful but globally or universally applicable enough to apply to the vast majority of games.
Rym: Even single player games.
Rym: Look at all the story games you've played.
Rym: There's usually the similar progression of early/mid/late phases of how much do your story decisions matter, how much do your choices matter or not.
Scott: Yeah, I've been playing Netrunner like crazy and people talk about early/mid/late game in Netrunner like crazy.
Scott: That's their favorite thing to talk about.
Scott: And it's pretty much in the early game, the corp can defend a little bit but not quite because they don't have enough money and ice yet maybe.
Scott: So the runner can sort of do a lot of stuff in the early game without any cards.
Scott: Then in the mid game, the corp's usually defended.
Scott: The runner is trying to build up stuff so that they can still get in.
Scott: But they don't really have everything built up yet so the corp can actually score.
Scott: And then in the late game, the runner usually has everything built and it's very likely in most--.
Scott: This obviously can change based on what people are playing but it's most likely that the runner can just go anywhere they want and the corp has got to find some tricky way to finish it off.
Rym: I think this is a side topic.
Rym: I don't want to delve into too much terminology or jargon so I'll avoid all the Garfield-type terms.
Rym: But I've noticed that the kinds of players who take way too long in their turn, even if they understand the phases of a game in some sense, they're unable to recognize when choices matter or don't because of when they occur.
Rym: Whether or not I choose captain or settler in the first ten turns of Puerto Rico matters like crazy.
Rym: What I choose toward the end of the game doesn't matter as much.
Rym: One, because many of the choices I have are basically excluded for me because I know that they're suboptimal.
Rym: They're off the Pareto frontier.
Rym: I can just straight up ignore them.
Rym: So I actually have fewer effective choices.
Rym: so my decisions are easier because even if I act randomly, I'm acting randomly from within fewer choices.
Rym: so I can analyze those choices more fully and more quickly.
Rym: Players who take too long in their turn don't seem to realize that the one extra wood card in your hand for that trade doesn't matter for shit at the end of settlers.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Rym: So recognize when the phase changes, not just how this affects your strategy, but more specifically, what decisions no longer matter.
Rym: so you can ignore them.
Rym: I don't micromanage every military unit when I have a hundred military units in Civ V. That is almost never going to help me.
Scott: But at the very beginning of Civ, every warrior is important.
Rym: Every hex every warrior moves is important.
Scott: Right, like a little pile of gold moving around the map.
Rym: So yeah, I think we could turn this into a pretty good PAX panel.
Scott: We got no other ideas.
Rym: I'm really hungry and I gotta fly to London in the morning because I think we're done here.
Rym: It's the late phase of the podcast.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.