Rym: It's Tuesday April 1st 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Why no one will game with you?
Rym: and no we're not joking.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Happy the internet is nothing but lies for 24 hours day.
Scott: Unhappy the internet is nothing but lies to 24 hours day, and you know what.
Scott: so this year was better and worse.
Rym: Yeah, there weren't like slashdot had some real stuff going on right now.
Rym: Park was actually really clever, and they they almost got me.
Scott: it was better and that there was actually some fools and Less just bullshit.
Scott: it was better and that there was less bullshit.
Scott: But it was worse and that a lot of people were starting early perhaps using time zones as an excuse Forgetting that New York is the only place in the world.
Rym: You know it's funny because in the financial world That's like.
Rym: that's kind of how it goes.
Rym: people in the other time zones of the u.s.
Rym: Basically have to keep New York hours anyway, that's exactly right.
Scott: You know when you see on TV like some office They always have those clocks on the wall that are like London, New York whatever.
Scott: in New York We have one clock on the wall, New York.
Rym: Well now you'll have to.
Rym: you'll have London because you want to know when you can call people in London.
Scott: But you know you want to know they're gonna call you so you can leave work.
Rym: But I gotta say FARC almost got me because I you know far like I love FARC.
Rym: I've been reading FARC for a long fucking time.
Rym: I kind of realized that today because what far I go to FARC and I see the headline That's like Ronald Reagan finally died 10 years after his brain went into Alzheimer's and I remember and all I thought was That already happened, but then there's that slight moment of right right.
Rym: There's no way he was still alive.
Scott: Why would you even have to question that?
Rym: because the news thing appears?
Scott: I'm like oh Ronald Reagan says like yeah, you know what I would think How the headline was written.
Scott: I might not think that the news was he died today, but oh something about his death.
Scott: So what I thought was like, you know, someone's writing a news article about the past.
Rym: So what I thought was Well, okay.
Rym: There's obviously something else going on here because FARC.
Rym: I mean, that's the point of FARC.
Rym: the headline is something funny or intriguing and the article might be something very different.
Rym: So I click on it and the article is like Ronald Reagan died today on legitimate news and before I thought anything I noticed dateline today's date Mmm, so then I go to the comments and I see.
Rym: so I see a few people who were gotten by it and a few other people who were like wait a minute that article is way old and Then I realized what was going on.
Rym: Every link on FARC today was just from 2004.
Rym: Okay, that's all they did ten years ago.
Rym: So you go to every thread and there's a few people who either some people are like, oh my god This is a duplicate from 2004.
Rym: The fuck FARC.
Rym: Come on I think that was the second best thing I saw today related to the April of fools.
Scott: But it reminds you if you really just need some sort of you know Serotonin fix in your brain and there's no new news coming in fast enough.
Scott: Just go to news 20 years ago or 10 years ago.
Rym: There's Wikipedia pages that do that.
Rym: They're like what happened in this year, right?
Scott: You know go to go to reddit and go like page a thousand and see what's there.
Scott: right there'll be something there.
Rym: Yeah, just start reading FARC archives, I guess.
Rym: Yeah But Dorkly pretty much had it best.
Scott: They had the perfectness.
Rym: that video is what all your April Fools jokes look like.
Scott: That's exactly right.
Scott: Homestar runner updated which it wasn't really a fool or a thing.
Scott: It was just it updated.
Rym: They just updated it on April Fool's Day to be like what should have happened is like when Google announced gmail for real on April Fool's Day.
Rym: Valve should have announced half-life 3 today like for real.
Rym: exactly that would have been it.
Rym: But no instead they launched a half-life 4 and halo 5.
Rym: So In personal life stuff, you know We talked about that flying episode and part of the reason I thought of doing that Is that it's really hard to book flights to and from places that aren't New York or London.
Rym: Like you want to fly direct to Boston from anywhere.
Rym: good luck.
Rym: And yeah, I just last-minute booked all these flights to Paris and everything.
Rym: Oh, so if anyone's gonna be in Paris I'm late to from us at trade tech Paris.
Rym: I don't do buddy and you want to hang out.
Rym: I might be kind of bored there.
Scott: You're gonna go to France in Paris and be bored.
Rym: How is that?
Rym: Two of those days Scott, you know how sometimes we go to Conventions run by people where we owe them a favor.
Rym: This is my excited about going to those convention.
Scott: My company sends me to a place like that.
Rym: You're just not gonna go to the convention.
Scott: I did exactly right.
Scott: I will go to the Louvre or two.
Rym: Ah, so if it's a way because we booked at the last second, there weren't any good flights or liberty I'm actually flying out Saturday.
Rym: So I'll get to Paris at like 11 a.m.
Rym: On Sunday.
Rym: so I got the whole day to just fuck around in Paris and Monday And I'll be by myself.
Rym: So I'll probably get some business meetings, but other than those meetings Wandering around fuck around just like London.
Rym: and then Tuesday Wednesday is the conference My CEOs flying with me, but he's leaving early on Wednesday.
Rym: So there's no one to supervise me and I'm flying home Thursday at like 2 p.m.
Rym: Which will get me to packs Thursday night at like 6 p.m.
Rym: Because the time zones Okay, so I'll have a bunch of days to fuck around in Paris.
Rym: So a bunch of you tried to meet up with me in London.
Rym: Sorry, that didn't happen.
Rym: But I actually had a lot less time than I thought I'd have.
Scott: Why don't you just tell them to meet you at the Eiffel Tower at like 6 or something?
Rym: Maybe but I don't want to be beholden to that schedule.
Rym: That's my trouble.
Rym: part of the reason I didn't meet up with anyone in London is you're not beholden to a schedule.
Scott: You can't meet anyone.
Scott: That's how it works.
Rym: Yeah, I could be like, yeah, I'm meeting people works.
Scott: There needs to be a time.
Rym: I'm at this place right now.
Rym: I'll be here for the next two hours go.
Scott: How is anyone gonna make it there within the two hours in New York?
Rym: I think someone would make it.
Scott: Yeah, we have a subway.
Rym: Paris has a subway.
Rym: Yeah, that's way better than London subway.
Scott: Sure, but it is not up to par with the New York subway.
Rym: No subway in the world is up to par.
Rym: Ding ding ding ding ding.
Rym: But uh, yeah, that's that's what I got.
Rym: that's what's going on in my life.
Rym: Okay, so I'm flying home through Reykjavik.
Rym: Okay, but I can't.
Rym: I don't have enough time.
Rym: Basically what I wanted to do was stop in Reykjavik for like a day and then just go play in a volcano Yeah and come back.
Rym: Yeah, basically.
Rym: Yeah, but I didn't have enough time.
Rym: So I'm only gonna be there for like an hour.
Scott: No, that doesn't count if you don't leave the airport.
Rym: Actually, no, it doesn't.
Rym: so yeah.
Rym: All right That's that.
Rym: I don't have anything else exciting waiting for you to jump in with some news or something.
Scott: Oh, you want to be jumping out got a news, but it's just a baby tiny news.
Scott: Not a very exciting news.
Scott: So Capcom I guess is doing something.
Scott: I guess maybe something.
Scott: Yeah, you know they've been pretty fail for a while now.
Scott: So and since they're not making any new Megaman's at least not as far as anyone knows They're gonna do something else.
Scott: They're just gonna re-release some old Megaman's For the for the 3ds in the digital download store.
Scott: So the games they're gonna put out are Megaman 2 3 4 5 and Megaman Xtreme and Xtreme 2. and you're probably sitting you wanna what the fuck is Megaman Xtreme and Xtreme?
Scott: Wait, what are these see in?
Scott: Japan where the games are real.
Scott: When they put out Megaman while Rockman on the Gameboy, they put out Rockman world Which is basically the Gameboy version of Megaman, right and in the US they didn't put that out.
Scott: They put out Megaman 2 Gameboy which was Basically Rockman world, you know poured it over now But they renamed it to basically be the same name as Megaman 2. so it's like oh You get confused if I say Megaman 2 you had to be like are you you know?
Scott: You know, which game I'm talking about, but I could be talking about the Gameboy one Which is bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, just called it Megaman world - it wouldn't have been a problem guys.
Rym: It worked for Mario sure.
Scott: Anyway, so Basically Rockman world 2 3 4 5 and then the 2 Gameboy Color Megamans are gonna come out on the 3ds in the download store But they're letting you vote on their website, which one comes first.
Scott: Yeah, whatever who gives a shit?
Scott: I mean I say it's a baby news.
Scott: It's like yeah, it's who cares?
Scott: you're gonna put them all out eventually anyway And no one's buying any digital downloads of crappy Sub-rate Megaman games.
Scott: and I can just get real Megaman 2 on my 3ds.
Rym: Why would I buy Megaman 2 on my emulator on my phone if I really want exactly exactly.
Scott: so There is an attachment to this news that is sort of like a PS Which is that Nintendo also struggling Japanese game companies struggling.
Scott: That's a surprise, huh are putting some?
Rym: oh, I see what you're about to say.
Scott: They're putting some GBA titles on the Wii U. Right, so it used to be that the virtual console on the Wii and Wii U only had console games.
Scott: So you get NES SNES, right?
Scott: GameCube n64 Games will not GameCube n64 games in your virtual console on your Wii and your Wii U and that on your virtual console on your 3ds.
Scott: Right, you would get portable games Gameboy games Gameboy Color Gameboy Advance games, right?
Scott: So for the first time here, they are going to release portable games Gameboy Advance games on the Wii U virtual console.
Scott: I wish they would also do NES and SNES games on the 3ds virtual console, but you know what you're gonna do Eventually.
Rym: go out of business.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Anyway, the first eight games have been announced and all that matters is that one of them is Advance Wars.
Rym: Yeah Except I already own Advance Wars obviously.
Scott: But if you don't have GBA Advance Wars and you don't have a piracy card and you don't know how to make it work Etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: You can now legally get Advance Wars for your 3ds at least starting pretty soon.
Rym: So part of the trouble is that a game like Advance Wars also Golden Sun Probably not the most fun game to play on your Wii U?
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: I played a lot of my Advance Wars like on buses and on trains.
Rym: Yeah, also Advance Wars 1 is not like the other Advance Wars.
Rym: I don't think most people who even profess to like more recent Advance Wars will actually like the GBA Advance Wars 1.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Scott: so Nintendo continuing to go.
Rym: Yep, so Nintendo allowed at least one relatively cool thing to happen.
Rym: So yeah before April Fool's Day yesterday I had to go take care of some business.
Rym: So I take the subway out of work and I go downtown like further downtown.
Rym: There's not much downtown left and I'm looking at a map to figure out like oh, where's this place?
Rym: I'm going What's this address?
Rym: and I see this dot like this weird thing on my Google Maps and I zoom in on it And it's a Lucario from Pokemon just hanging out Like what.
Scott: and this wasn't April Fool's Day yet.
Scott: This is the timing.
Rym: Hit back to look and make sure it wasn't April Fool's Day.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: I was like, nope It's not.
Rym: so I went back in I click on him and I saw an option to catch him Saw an option for a pokedex and for a split second.
Rym: I thought that maybe Nintendo decided to not be a fuck-up.
Rym: Mm-hmm that maybe the stars are going to align and this was the first Salvo of the world-ending MMO of Pokemon.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: But no basically it's just a scavenger hunt.
Rym: You know, it's kind of dumb.
Rym: Effectively what happens is on your phone and only on your phone.
Rym: It doesn't work on like a computer.
Rym: if you zoom in far enough onto Google Maps You might see a Pokemon and if you click on him you catch him.
Rym: It's literally it.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: Have a whole bunch of fun.
Rym: scrolling through Google Maps Very much zoomed in.
Rym: also most of the Pokemon are in real cities.
Scott: Well, I think they put them in.
Scott: if you notice right all the Pokemon regions in the real Pokemon games are based on certain cities.
Scott: So like the newest one is based on Paris, you know with the Eiffel Tower in the right and the Pokemon black is based on New York, it's got you know, the Manhattan Island in the middle with I found like a Snorlax and an Eevee, right?
Scott: So all most of the Pokemon I've been told are in those actual Pokemon regions Right that you know on the real world.
Scott: So if you want to you know, if you come to New York, it's like there was a Pokemon region.
Scott: That's New York.
Scott: So there's Pokemon there Paris this Pokemon there, right?
Rym: You know Tokyo this Pokemon, yeah So yeah, it's cool in theory, but it's basically just completely dumb.
Rym: It's a marketing thing.
Rym: It's it's one of those obsessive boring things to do when you're sitting with your smartphone at work.
Rym: Not actually doing work.
Rym: It's not actually a game in any sense.
Rym: That is meaningful.
Rym: I Wish this was actually a game.
Rym: Imagine if I don't know because I've reviewed Ingress that Augmented reality game that's on Android.
Rym: That's not super fun.
Rym: Basically just a candy box But it has a pretty good UX.
Rym: if they took that basic UX of there's Pokemon and other trainers and Places in the real world and just made that Pokemon That would literally be the greatest game ever.
Rym: Like I can actually see exactly how you should do it.
Rym: It's that UX coupled with the Google Maps integration and just Pokemon straight up.
Rym: if I'm near you and I see you We can just have a Pokemon battle right there.
Rym: live No take backs.
Rym: No saving No nothing.
Rym: and just candy boxes up then because as much as I think candy boxes are stupid if the candy boxes were a Canonical Pokemon.
Rym: I might have to open up the box get some candy bars touch that guy's hat.
Scott: Hey, you know where any other Pokemon are besides.
Scott: ooh, what's that?
Rym: Are you looking for Pokemon right now elements?
Scott: What the fuck is that?
Rym: Really?
Scott: Really, you know what the fuck that is, you don't know new Pokemon.
Rym: Do ya?
Scott: I've never seen that Pokemon in my life.
Scott: Are you sure it's not a Digimon?
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Rym: they probably just offended a whole bunch of our Pokemon fan fans.
Scott: That's got to be a Digimon.
Rym: So as another much smaller aside, there's an article on polygon.
Rym: That's actually about our good friend Conrad craling Who's been on this show before.
Rym: he has been on GeekNights multiple times usually really mad about phones.
Rym: He worked at Muse games for many years with Emily and Alex our other friends.
Rym: we went to RIT with him.
Rym: he was this young spry with us, yes who dressed up as safety cone.
Rym: that itself was dressed up as Naruto.
Rym: and Yeah, there's an article about him.
Scott: barrel a Barrel of sorts a safe go and post the safety barrel picture on that article.
Rym: Oh, did they know?
Rym: you should I should.
Rym: Are there any comments?
Rym: there are some comments?
Rym: it's a picture of Kanye Conrad.
Scott: there you go.
Rym: Oh people are posting pictures of him from Johnny wander.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: So yeah, it's a cool article about a cool company and a cool person and other cool people.
Rym: But this is the one that we know directly.
Rym: who's been on GeekNights who you probably have also heard of Because it's been on GeekNights.
Rym: Oh and the articles written by Michael Moore someone cool who we also all know and you probably might know especially.
Scott: we know people who?
Scott: Do cool things.
Scott: Oh my god, you know what.
Scott: if you live in New York City You will know people who do cool things.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that if you live in New York and you do cool things you Literally know every other person who does similar things in the city.
Scott: nerds no other.
Rym: There's when an anime movie happens like some anime movie.
Rym: It's just being screened.
Rym: Pretty much everyone who shows up is someone that I know Either because of things like this or because they go to every other anime screening.
Scott: Yeah, so it works.
Scott: I see any Pokemon in Astoria.
Rym: I didn't find any in Queens.
Rym: I don't think it's.
Scott: maybe this is one of the baseball stadium.
Rym: Ah, I'll bet.
Rym: not I'll bet Manhattan only.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Scott: Oh, come on are not Mets fans.
Scott: Oh, oh, that's right.
Scott: They're Mariners fans, which Nintendo owns of course.
Rym: So I try not to do this often, but this is marching band video, but it's pretty impressive.
Rym: Oh, you and your marching band, so when I was in high school, I actually and middle school I actually kind of seriously wanted to make my career Around marching bands and music.
Scott: who has that career?
Rym: Some people have that career almost nobody.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: You know what the most common career you can get is for that Teacher.
Scott: high school band teacher, you know what high school band teachers job is like.
Scott: How do you how would you like being a high school band teacher right now?
Rym: Mostly what I wanted to do was my primary career.
Rym: I was thinking about going into the conservatory being a professional horn player and then on the side I wanted to be involved in marching stuff because I'm just really into that.
Rym: I've always been super into that.
Rym: So what I have for you is a video of the group that I saw marching that inspired me to be really into that and to get really into like the choreography and just How you actually put these things together like the technical side of Marching band performances and shows.
Rym: this is the Phantom Regiment performing Elsa's procession to the cathedral.
Rym: Okay, it's pretty great.
Rym: You got a thing of the day.
Scott: Oh, I do have a thing today.
Scott: So here's this really cute little flash game called lamp and vamp, right?
Scott: And basically it's a little turn-based strategy kind of game.
Scott: And once you figure out how it works, you really just keep playing it.
Scott: You're a little cute vampire guy right and it's a hex map and every turn you move one space But you can't really move through the houses or any or through the trees.
Scott: you just move a move a space and you're in the darkness because you're a vampire and you're trying to get into your coffin because that's where vampires belong and there's people walking around town with torches trying to burn your ass cuz and stake you and shit cuz.
Scott: They don't like vampires eating their kids and their wives and themselves.
Scott: So You have to make it there without getting seen, you know, they all have the little flashlights that they're you know Lighting up the street with so you want to hide so you don't get seen.
Scott: They keep moving though.
Scott: So it's very hard.
Scott: You got to predict where they're gonna be where they're gonna shine their light, right and there isn't always an option.
Scott: It's like they'll just trap you and it's not simple to just avoid them.
Rym: I totally hate that guy, right?
Scott: It's not simple to do.
Scott: you think this would be just like those Zelda games or you avoid the candidates that are you know?
Scott: You Know the parts like the candidates in the bush in the hedge maze.
Scott: Yeah, right It's not that simple, but you get some special vampire powers, but using your special vampire powers cost you life your hearts.
Scott: Drinking blood and doing other things can get you hearts back.
Scott: getting shot and holy watered makes you lose hearts.
Scott: so basically you just keep going level after level after level and The game isn't over till you lose your hundred hearts completely.
Scott: So it's all about.
Scott: you know, it's like it's like I can beat this level With only spending ten hearts, that's a pretty good deal, right?
Scott: But you know another level.
Scott: you need to gain ten hearts.
Scott: Otherwise in the long run if you keep doing that you're eventually on your way to losing.
Scott: so Pretty interesting game that has both the short term puzzle solving and also the long term resource management.
Scott: It's good when you're at work on your board much better than finding Pokemon at Google Maps.
Rym: I'm playing it right now.
Rym: It's super fun.
Rym: I totally just bit that guy again.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I'm killing him.
Rym: Yeah He's dead.
Rym: kill that other guy too cuz he just walked up and didn't notice.
Rym: Yeah Killing all these guys up that fucker saw me fuck fuck.
Scott: Okay Going down in the moment.
Rym: The book club book is wool.
Rym: We both finished it.
Rym: do a show on it on Thursday.
Rym: It's alright, it's worth reading tight.
Rym: Yeah, I liked it.
Rym: I liked it way more than I liked captain fedora's penis adventure through the sex goddess lands of the kung fu sex masters.
Scott: I liked it more than ready player one.
Rym: I still gotta read ready player one.
Rym: Why do you have to up so I can shit all over it apparently?
Scott: Well, I mean, it's not.
Scott: it's better than Captain penis nice guy, but it's basically captain woo game 80s nerdery.
Rym: Uh Yeah, I don't know if I can deal with that.
Rym: I I Enjoy apt references.
Rym: I'm increasingly tired of Very crass cash grab.
Rym: Hey, you remember Mario?
Scott: I to remember Mario This is more like do you remember tomb of horrors and pac-man?
Rym: With their powers combined you can be really insufferable to the people around you.
Rym: Yeah We're going to be at the penny arcade expo east not this weekend, but next weekend.
Rym: Whoa It's in Boston.
Scott: packs packs is just all the time.
Scott: now, it's like I was just out of packs and look at this.
Rym: another packs Yeah, and then I got another packs in October and then I got a packs right after.
Rym: well right before that in September Packs is everywhere.
Rym: Yeah, lots of packs.
Rym: Look at all these packs is we just keep going to them?
Rym: Not much else to say there had you were doing a panel called why no one will game with you And if you're not already attending bags, it's way too late to arrange attending packs.
Scott: No, right?
Rym: Unlike PAX Prime where you could have a pretty fun time being at PAX Prime without a badge and not doing any pack stuff.
Rym: Not the same case for paxies if you don't have a badge stay don't go anywhere near Boston to stay home.
Scott: Yeah, unlike PAX East which you can't get into unless you're already in right?
Scott: There is something you can do next weekend the weekend before packs the moga festivals happen in New York City.
Scott: It seems to have been gone ever so slightly downhill There after year, but it's you know.
Scott: If you're that close to it as we are why not hop on the subway and go look at an independent comic show For an hour a few.
Rym: Yeah, we'll totally be there.
Rym: probably Saturday in the morning.
Scott: Yeah, probably Saturday morning when it opens.
Scott: get there when it opens outside the netrunner tournament on Sunday.
Scott: So definitely Saturday.
Rym: Yep, I'm also definitely I used to spend a lot more time at mocha But nowadays I kind of want to be in look at everything once buy everything I wanted to buy and then get the fuck out That's what
Scott: my plan is and then eat an awesome lunch nearby and then go home.
Rym: Are your parents coming?
Rym: No, so we can eat some more good.
Rym: Yeah We don't have to cater to the the whims of mom who's picky.
Scott: No We can eat at the most exotic country restaurant the I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'll be kind of feeling a burger An ostrich burger, we're also going to be at a convention called Zank icon, it's April 25th 26 27th.
Scott: It's an anime con.
Rym: We'll be doing mostly three Lectures there, I believe on Saturday and Sunday only.
Rym: I don't think the schedules public.
Rym: So show up and look for us on the schedule.
Rym: I think we're doing anime openers around the world.
Scott: You can just find the three panels that aren't Homestuck panels.
Scott: Yeah, or Hetalia panels, and you'll be all set.
Rym: I do have the schedule but I would think I think I would get in trouble with scojo if I just public because it's probably Not a hundred percent true.
Scott: Yeah, it's probably been much much changed Since the one the copy that you have.
Rym: Yeah So we've talked about aspects of this multiple times on GeekNights over the years But usually as an aside or focusing really really tightly on one Tiny aspect of the greater picture of why it's so fucking hard to find people to play games.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, you know We decided to do a PAX panel on this and then we couldn't come with an idea for today's show.
Scott: and it's like hey Let's kill like a hundred birds with one stone.
Scott: We'll sort of work through this panel that we've developing.
Scott: Literally, no one who is listening to this is going to not go to the panel at the actual packs because we made this episode.
Scott: 99.9% of the people listening this aren't even going to packs
Rym: plus the kinds of things I'll say on GeekNights Might be slightly different from the kinds of things I'll say at a Convention at which I'm a guest where there's a lot of video recorders and a lot of people physically in the room with me.
Rym: I mean, well that guy is gonna be in the audience.
Rym: I guarantee it.
Scott: also, you know people who might go and see us at the convention discover us might come and listen to this episode because they you know, People always look for videos of panels.
Scott: We did even though they saw the panel.
Scott: So hey, there's a podcast already on the website before the panel even happened.
Scott: Maybe someone will come back and be like, you know Listen to it to remember what we said.
Rym: the other interesting thing is you guys will kind of get this insight if you see the panel and listen to this into Kind of after we've put a panel together.
Rym: I guess I hate saying panel.
Rym: I have to put a lecture like this together The way we talk to each other about like the finer points of what we're actually gonna say and how we'll like discard some ideas Or we decide that oh we were actually wrong about this thing.
Rym: We thought was part of our point.
Rym: Let's remove it now that we've talked about it at length, right?
Scott: Okay, so the panels call the lecture is called.
Scott: why no one will game with you?
Scott: because that's really provocative.
Scott: but really what it's about is How even though there's a bajillion billions of gamers on earth spending billions of hours on games Very very few of those actual people are people that any Individual person can game with right?
Scott: So I looked up some numbers, right?
Scott: Population of earth is like seven eight billion people right number of those people who play games.
Scott: It's like pretty much almost anyone in a you know Country that has any sort of technology is playing some kind of game.
Scott: even people, you know, everyone's playing soccer somewhere pretty much, right?
Scott: Settlers of Catan has sold 15 million copies in the u.s That's a lot of copies It doesn't.
Scott: I don't think that counts the European copies.
Scott: No, that's a lot of settlers is out there.
Rym: That definitely is.
Scott: that's a ton right?
Scott: So with 15 million settlers is copies in the u.s.
Scott: In 50 states Assuming they're distributed like evenly per capita and you don't live in the complete sticks.
Scott: There's someone near you who has a copy of settlers besides you that you can play settlers with at least Right, and that's I mean, that's also a pretty niche number.
Rym: I mean settlers already assumes you've somehow gotten down the road of German slash euro game, right?
Scott: Yeah, so it's like it's even more dense than that, right and that doesn't count.
Scott: people who you know, maybe played You know, I mean munchkin might be more than settlers right.
Scott: there might be no magic.
Scott: the gathering might be more than that.
Scott: So Anyway, so with all those games out there with games being so popular How come?
Scott: There is still so much LFG right, you know?
Scott: you go and you go to PAX a huge gaming convention.
Scott: people who are at PAX are LFG.
Scott: you go on the internet.
Scott: you think the internet would have solved all our LFG problems.
Scott: You go on the internet you find people who are LFG looking for game.
Rym: now on one hand of course the LFG is just a service because part of the whole reason you go to a convention is to meet strangers who you wouldn't otherwise Meet who have similar interests find someone to play a game with.
Rym: but yet despite the LFG space I see a lot of people walking around solo with the game Trying to muster up someone to play it trying to get someone to play with them trying to get someone to join the group.
Scott: So why is it that at conventions and also not at conventions video games and non video games?
Scott: Right with so many gamers and games of all kinds being so popular are people still struggling to find Someone else to game with?
Rym: why does every forum have the looking for a gaming group thread?
Rym: That's always forever and super long right usually filled with drama.
Scott: Yep So it's like you go.
Scott: I mean you go to the forums on board game geek for like netrunner Which has got a very active community online, and you see threads constantly.
Scott: any players in my area Cricket cricket anyone, but nope role-playing games are probably the biggest offender here.
Rym: Yes, not only is everyone desperate to find a gaming group, but they need to form a group.
Rym: they need to form like a regular group of people who are.
Rym: they're going to share a lot of time with playing these games.
Rym: and You think if so many people are into D&D Here they're not doing it this time anyway last year.
Rym: Yeah, so long.
Scott: yeah anyway, so Reason number one take that huge group right that big old circle and can you know the big old pie that consists of all gamers?
Scott: on Earth.
Scott: and the number one thing that is going to remove that pie from the ability for you to eat.
Scott: It is just geography right.
Scott: most of those people do not live anywhere near you.
Scott: It's like you you play.
Scott: I don't know Monopoly.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You'll find someone near you to play Monopoly.
Rym: me I mean parents your kids sure the neighbor kids.
Scott: you're into race for the galaxy.
Scott: How many people physically near you wherever you live play race of the galaxy?
Scott: if you live in a city like New York, okay?
Scott: You'll find someone right.
Scott: you live in even my hometown Trumble in the suburbs of Connecticut right an hour away by car.
Scott: Good luck fine.
Rym: Well remember we lived in beacon.
Rym: you're
Scott: gonna have to take a car if you live if I lived it with my parents and I wanted to find people to game with I would have to get in a car and drive at least a half hour to an hour to Get to a place where people might be playing games.
Rym: We used to live in Beacon, New York, and there was the city of Beacon.
Rym: website is down.
Rym: Okay, I went to it.
Rym: look how many pipe people are there?
Rym: so it's got a population of like 15,000. it's in the orbit of New York City.
Rym: a lot of people like us used to live there or do live there and commute Down.
Rym: Scott and I were looking for
Scott: definitely nerds there Yeah of different kinds for
Rym: the nearest gaming store was like a half-hour drive north in Poughkeepsie And at that gaming store there was a one gaming club that consisted of a very small number of kind of sad older gamers That was not expanding or growing in any way most of whom did not want to play the kinds of games We wanted to play.
Scott: and there were a few gamers at a near at that College nearby, and that was pretty much it.
Scott: Yep, and the college was also up near that gets that same gaming store, so Geography is the big problem for tabletop games, but what about video games?
Scott: you think internet should solve all these geography problems?
Scott: I can just play with anyone in the whole world.
Scott: You know games.
Scott: It'll be no problem.
Scott: Well.
Scott: That's true for some Video games mostly the a simp the asynchronous ones right like play by mail situations.
Scott: Yeah, some play boss at five right, but that's not the kind of thing that can really you know.
Scott: It's like those games are great, but that's not the kind of thing you can sit down and play for hours, right?
Scott: That's only the kind of thing that you can you know sort of occupy random moments throughout your day.
Scott: You're not gonna You know my friend in Finland isn't gonna sit down for three hours at the same time as me To play the game turn by turn.
Scott: why time zones Time zones, I'm only limited to people in my longitude Right or pretty close to my longitude in terms of that kind of gaming Right.
Scott: something that can actually occupy a good chunk of time has to be people nearby even just from you at from New York to California Causes a significant problems in the time difference and not just latency, but latency is the most obvious example of it.
Rym: But just reliability do you know?
Rym: many times I've tried to play a game of Civ 5 with someone who's overseas where latency?
Rym: We don't care.
Rym: We've sorted out the timezone thing.
Rym: the game just fucking stops working occasionally because of bad network connections, right?
Rym: It's you know the internet while or because Scott Johnson Yeah, it's hosting the game as a computer like locks up the internet right for an asynchronous game.
Scott: Technologically isn't gonna give you a problem.
Scott: the timezone gives you a problem but for Technology wise the latency prevents you from playing any kind of real-time game any kind of counter-strike any kind of fighting game any kind of anything that's real-time and even things that aren't real-time.
Scott: you still need the connection to be very reliable so it doesn't disconnect.
Scott: and When you're farther away from someone and their internet is garbage in the US internet is garbage And it's just.
Scott: you know you can't.
Scott: so you're still looking for game.
Scott: You can't find the game because all the you know you have to basically subtract from the pie.
Scott: All the people were far away from you.
Scott: Oh and by the way, maybe you do find someone who is in your longitude.
Scott: They don't speak the same language as you.
Scott: not as much of a concern for us in the North am no But you know this can be a serious problem for other people like what if you live in Arizona?
Scott: And it's just these tons of Mexican gamers.
Scott: You just can't play with them.
Rym: actually what's funny.
Rym: It depends on the game.
Rym: One of the things board game being does and a lot of Euro gamers Do is one of the statistics about a board game is how language dependent?
Rym: It is either because you might play with people who don't speak the same language or the rules themselves.
Rym: like the game itself You may or may not need to know the language the game was published in to be able to play it.
Rym: Yeah, like settlers.
Rym: There's not a lot of words.
Rym: You can play that.
Scott: what if you had to bargain with someone?
Rym: Ah, but you could still you've got the icons alone could be sufficient to get your point across.
Rym: Or like counter-strike.
Rym: I would regularly in beacon play counter-strike with all these quebecois people.
Rym: Mm-hmm So they'd all speak French.
Rym: We didn't really.
Rym: we weren't able to communicate with each other Effectively except via the radio commands because if I said something they didn't really understand me and vice versa or if they did understand me They pretended they didn't.
Rym: So some games like a game that doesn't require a heavy amount of team coordination That is otherwise versus or lone wolf in some way you can play just fine.
Rym: But games like that like counter-strike unless you're playing for the purposes of that group that Community that thing that people are always saying they want in these forum threads Then that doesn't work.
Rym: those you're those people you're playing against might as well be advanced a eyes and Europeans can have a lot of trouble with this as well.
Scott: also Australians might have a lot of other Pacific countries to play with right.
Scott: but it's like if you don't speak Chinese or who knows what?
Scott: You know language right.
Scott: or maybe if you live in like Southeast Asia, right you live in Thailand you speak Thai.
Scott: You can play with Thai people right, but you're gonna have all these, you know people who speak.
Scott: You know some kind of Chinese that are near you, but you can't game with them if you don't speak that language.
Rym: So that's already.
Rym: we come down to the idea the sort of side point that I hadn't really thought about with these slides before That it really depends on the kind of game and what you're looking for.
Rym: If you're just looking for bodies to play a game like I'm playing counter-strike I want humans to be playing with me, but we're all reasonably good at the game.
Rym: Bots like good bots would probably be fine as would pretty much any humans who are good at the game.
Rym: But I'm not gonna form lasting friendships.
Rym: I'll play with whoever's online at the time.
Rym: I'll click on the matchmaking.
Rym: Constantly clicking on matchmaking will very rarely net you a group with which to have a long term or meaningful gaming group.
Scott: The point is is that whatever kind of game you're playing it doesn't matter.
Scott: Geography is going to limit the number of people that you can play with in some dramatic way more dramatic than any other factor Right, so that's reason number one.
Scott: There's billions of people on earth playing games.
Scott: Over 90% of them are eliminated just because they don't live near you, right?
Scott: Okay, so what other kind of problems right besides?
Scott: geography will sort of reduce the number of people that you can game with?
Scott: Right, well the people themselves obviously, right?
Scott: I found someone near me who also self-identifies as gamer.
Scott: that is incredibly broad.
Scott: I play tabletop euro games and they play Starcraft.
Rym: This is where you.
Rym: this isn't gonna worry that sort of.
Rym: you know The idea of the fake gamer a lot of it.
Rym: Oh that person just a fake.
Rym: same thing in comic books.
Rym: Oh, they're a fake geek.
Rym: They're not a real geek.
Rym: They're not a real gamer.
Scott: They don't play counter-strike 1-6 only If someone doesn't play the same game as you or doesn't want to play the same game you want to play then you're not gonna Be able to play games together unless someone changes their mind which.
Rym: so you have the shared culture of gamer But you don't have a shared culture of game.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's the tagline for that bit.
Rym: right there I mean culture.
Rym: I'm adding that to the slide.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you have to be playing not only the same.
Scott: I mean what if it's even the same genre?
Scott: I'm a Starcraft I'm a street fighter guy and who do you meet on the street?
Scott: You met a Marvel vs.
Scott: Capcom guy.
Scott: Well, I guess you're not playing any fighting games together cuz right.
Scott: I mean sure fighting game.
Scott: people tend to play more than one fighting game, right?
Scott: So meet you might.
Rym: they're not forget They're not gonna play settlers with me.
Scott: That's maybe not or maybe they will.
Scott: But you know people the number, you know people like us have a like a broad variety of games we play, right?
Scott: But you know, they're only gonna get heavily involved in a few games.
Scott: And if you're gonna you're looking for game like just a single game.
Scott: You're looking for game long-lasting game, like, you know some sort of regular gaming deal.
Scott: You're gonna need to find people who are very very compatible in terms of what games they play Not down just to the genre of game.
Scott: I'm an RTS player looking for RTS players not just be I'm a. I play dota and they play League of Legends.
Scott: Nope, we got to get all in the same page.
Scott: here has to be the same game, right?
Scott: But they had to be the same kind of gamer.
Scott: So I play League of Legends you play League of Legends All right, this is gonna work out, isn't it?
Scott: No, cuz I play it hardcore to win Like I'm trying to be pro and you're just playing it like la la la la la.
Rym: Remember when heroes of new earth came out and it.
Rym: you know We did a show on this about how that was literally the most toxic gaming community I had ever encountered in my life.
Rym: up to that point to this.
Rym: I'm someone who's played a lot of fucking counter-strike, right?
Rym: And the reason for that was simple half the people playing were new to the genre not good at the genre Wanting to play this game wanting to enjoy it.
Rym: they were playing mostly for fun They were trying to win but they weren't super serious about it.
Rym: The other half of the people Literally wanted to win at all costs.
Rym: That was the only reason they're even clicking.
Rym: Is that ranking?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So those two kinds of people cannot coexist on the same server.
Rym: They cannot coexist in the same game.
Rym: if I'm playing El Grande to win and you're playing because you like the color yellow And you want to have the most yellow cubes on the board.
Rym: We're not gonna have a good time.
Scott: No Another problem is that a lot of times the game you want to play is a dead game, right?
Rym: I'm - I think here we tell the Story of tribes - right.
Rym: Oh did I'll tell the full anecdote of knit hog.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: That's recent, right?
Scott: The point is though It's like you might differ on what genre you want to play.
Scott: you might differ on what game you want to play.
Scott: You also might want to play a game.
Scott: That is a dead game, right?
Scott: So Really now we're really limited in who's left to play games with right?
Rym: Literally chased every single human being out of the matchmaking system on knit hog on multiple occasions And now there's never anyone there, right?
Scott: Well, that's the air hockey problem We've talked about many times right?
Scott: is you're?
Scott: let's say you get really good at Street Fighter and you have friends who do also want To play Street Fighter and you all want to play to win you.
Scott: all the same attitude about the game.
Scott: It's looking good.
Scott: It's looking good here But you're just way better than them because you've played it more and they just lose to you And now they don't like to play against you.
Rym: just saw this so quickly with knit hog Scott.
Rym: I both got the game at the same time.
Rym: We're like, oh, let's stream us playing it together.
Rym: I played it for like six hours the night before we actually played against each other.
Rym: I did not played at all as a result.
Rym: I was literally invincible.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It was just.
Rym: I win I win I win I win I win.
Scott: It's like I might really like playing basketball and be kind of good at it but playing against Michael Jordan be boring as fuck because he just be like Don't go over your head and don't go over yet and steal the ball and dunk over your head.
Rym: Don't get us wrong.
Rym: Some people can really enjoy the teaching game.
Rym: Like I'm super good at settler You're not gonna learn anything.
Scott: If you don't even get to handle the ball.
Scott: You just constantly steals and dunks.
Scott: What can I learn for that?
Scott: Nothing, but I would never be able to in the time that we were there playing.
Rym: No, but I'm saying me.
Rym: I don't enjoy playing settlers of Catan as a game No But I do enjoy playing it as a tool to teach other people how to be good at games.
Rym: I will play any game of settlers and I won't be playing.
Rym: I'll be playing to win Like I'll win in the end just cuz I don't.
Rym: I don't like losing pride.
Rym: I won't Try.
Rym: I won't play hardcore to win.
Rym: I'll give people a lot of advice.
Rym: I'll make a mistake and then say so notice how I traded that wood there.
Rym: I really shouldn't have done that.
Rym: now He's ahead by a point.
Rym: You wouldn't ahead before.
Rym: I didn't really need that wood.
Rym: What did it get me?
Rym: I'll do things like that and I enjoyed that experience.
Rym: but already, you know, we always talk about game theory.
Rym: I have a different utility.
Rym: I'm not playing to win the game.
Rym: I'm the teacher playing with a bunch of students here, but that's not a long-term game.
Scott: But if your skill level of games is generally higher, right, you know You you need to find people if you want long-term gaming if you find people at the same skill level right or at least relatively the same skill level as you or Building their skills from the low level quickly up to the high level so that it's enjoyable for you to play with them and them To play with you.
Rym: This is something that does.
Rym: it's not just that.
Rym: it prevents you.
Rym: Like if I'm super good at air hockey I'll never even get to play air hockey with anyone.
Rym: or maybe I'll get one game with every individual human once Yeah, and then they'll never play with me again.
Rym: But this is the thing that say.
Rym: you finally formed a gaming group.
Rym: You got your eight friends together.
Rym: You all got really into Super Street Fighter 2, whatever.
Rym: So you're all playing.
Rym: you have this sort of semi like some of you are better some of you than worse.
Rym: but as soon as one person Practices a little bit and gets the air hockey up just a little bit the gaming group gets destroyed overnight.
Rym: You destroy the the rare functional gaming group you have just by getting better than your friends Mm-hmm.
Scott: And then what ends up happening is you have to move into the competitive community and find those other high-level peoples But they're probably better than you.
Scott: So now what do you do?
Rym: Yep now you either.
Scott: You either go by yourself into your bedroom and level yourself the fuck up so you can be a competitive champion Or you stop playing that game.
Rym: like look Scott and I crazy fucking good at air hockey.
Rym: anyone We know most people in New York will just beat him hands down.
Rym: But if we go to an air hockey tournament like the national championships, let's just get smoked.
Rym: We would literally would.
Scott: they would not even score a goal.
Rym: Yeah, the puck would fly and break our hand, but there's no one in between those two levels for us to play except each other Unless someone else wants to be that kind of gamer with us.
Rym: We've had a lot of luck in getting people to be that kind of gamer with us in air hockey.
Scott: So none at all.
Scott: zero right.
Scott: Another thing that is that is sad but true.
Scott: Is that a difference of money?
Scott: right?
Scott: an economic well-being Financial well-being does separate gamers, right?
Scott: It's it's just the reality of the world.
Scott: It sucks, but it's there.
Scott: I found someone near me.
Scott: We're gonna play PC games.
Scott: They can't afford a PC gaming rig that's good enough to play the game.
Scott: They just can't right.
Scott: I've met a lot of people online.
Scott: They're just like my computer sucks.
Scott: I can't play that game with you because my video card is no good.
Rym: or even what about the people who just like we're all It packs?
Rym: a lot of people can't afford to come to packs.
Rym: Yeah, people don't live near packs.
Scott: We are gonna pegs.
Scott: anyone who's at who's can afford to go to a convention is either lucky the convention is near their home right.
Scott: lucky to even get a badge if they have the money or Lucky that they are well off money wise they can afford the hotel and travel and etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So there's we said there's bajillions of gamers.
Scott: only a lucky very small percentage can go to any kind of gaming convention Especially a big one like packs yep and I'll say from my Many years ago into PAX Prime and PAX East and a lot of other conventions or even a Gen Con or anything else.
Rym: It is obvious that the the average demographic of the people who go to PAX Prime in Seattle is Way more affluent than the people who attend most other gaming type conventions or other fan conventions.
Rym: That's just how it is.
Scott: So it's not that packs is like discriminating.
Scott: We don't like poor people.
Scott: poor people get out.
Rym: In fact, they actually do everything they can to give everyone a fair shot.
Scott: They try to you know They keep.
Scott: they don't sell VIP badges like other cons.
Scott: They don't charge for individual events like other cons, right?
Scott: They try to do everything to be as you know You know equal as possible.
Scott: money cannot get you privileges once you're at packs But you still need to be privileged with enough money to get over the bar to get into packs.
Rym: And this I think is why this problem of looking for games seems so apparent primarily in small towns and on internet communities Because the people who aren't complaining are the people who go to a million conventions and they get their gaming fix Here at packs.
Rym: I keep saying here.
Rym: We're sitting in Queens, right?
Rym: I Can I have my pick.
Rym: I can play a lot of games with strangers that I cannot play in my daily life even in New York.
Rym: Right and I go to.
Rym: you know, four or so packs is a year never mind all the other gaming cons I go to.
Rym: so every month or two I'm at a convention for an entire weekend playing as many fucking games as I can.
Rym: It clips at 3 in the morning and then start another game as soon as we finish the first one.
Scott: Few gamers are as lucky as that.
Rym: so everyone in this room already.
Rym: You have a huge advantage over almost every other gamer.
Scott: and it's not just you know, PC games and conventions.
Scott: What if you want to play Magic the Gathering?
Scott: that shit is expensive.
Scott: What are you gonna play Warhammer?
Scott: that shit is double expensive, right?
Scott: It's like some games no matter how bad that you want to play.
Scott: them are Expensive as games and you can't play them unless you have mad moneys, right?
Scott: They're all you know, even a cheaper game right like Puerto Rico.
Scott: It's 40 bucks for a copy of Puerto Rico.
Rym: It's not a 40 bucks.
Rym: If you're lucky I paid.
Rym: I paid $90 for a copy of la cheetah.
Rym: I got it on sale.
Rym: It's way more expensive now.
Scott: Well, that was a Print game.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I played that fucking game once right and it's like, okay, you're into board games.
Scott: I mean 40 bucks.
Scott: That's like you buy one game.
Scott: Usually you need a board game library If you want to play board games regularly.
Scott: You'll get bored playing settlers over and over and over and over again, right board game library.
Scott: Suddenly we're into the area of hundreds and hundreds of dollars.
Scott: It's like you can't game if you don't have this.
Rym: also I think is you know I don't want to stress it a lot because we're talking about the reality of like these sort of objective hard reasons Why this is so hard.
Rym: But there's a lot of drama in the communities around people trying to form gaming groups a lot of like.
Rym: I don't want to play with that guy.
Rym: Oh, I gotta go to so-and-so's house.
Rym: I don't want to really play race for the galaxy, but that's all.
Rym: Joey Jojo will play and he's the one who owns all the games.
Rym: Well yet what I see in a lot of gaming communities is that there's a few linchpin people Who for whatever reason either because they're rich or because like board games or video games are their thing that they buy everything To the extent to the exclusion of other things.
Rym: There's the few people who have all the games.
Rym: So the gaming groups that do form in those areas form around those people Which is great if you're friends with those people or you can be friends with those people.
Rym: But it causes drama when you don't like the people who own the games.
Rym: You'd like to play the games with the other people, but the other people also don't own the games, right?
Scott: Well, it has this weird power dynamic.
Scott: Well, it also.
Scott: it depends right?
Scott: it shows people's priorities, right?
Scott: Like you might know some people who play games.
Scott: Games aren't their number one thing in life But they play some games and they will go and game with that guy who owns all the crazy games.
Scott: They'll go to his house or her house once in a while play some games, but it's not their major thing.
Scott: They're not so hooked on games.
Scott: It's sort of like, you know a nice aside for them, right?
Scott: I mean you'd be hard-pressed to find someone who didn't play a game once in a while, right?
Scott: But since it's not their primary thing, they're not LFG They're not going on the internet looking for that thread saying who's playing this game in this area.
Rym: They'll show their not invention and binge for three days on games.
Scott: Well, they even go to a convention.
Scott: It's like such a low priority for them.
Scott: gaming They're.
Scott: so.
Scott: you know It's such a look at a lot of it's so less important than their family their job and their other hobbies.
Scott: But they do it once in a while, but you cannot find this person.
Scott: You cannot get them to regularly commit to spending a lot of time playing games with you.
Scott: That's just not a thing that they're interested in, you know, so even though they're a gamer, right?
Scott: They're part of the pie of Potential people to game with.
Scott: they're just not into it as much right as much as you are who wants to game.
Scott: You know weekly or twice monthly or whatever.
Rym: now there is already and we'll talk more at the end.
Rym: I think about ways ways to mitigate these issues.
Rym: the way around that problem Is that if you're committed to it?
Rym: You have to be that person who has a lot of the games and you have to be the one who does all this work To organize game nights to where you need like a 10 to 1 ratio.
Rym: You need 10 people who like games.
Rym: for every one Average person you'll get to attend your game night to play a game.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So if you know 40 people who kind of like games Then you can reliably get four of them to show up once a week and play settlers with you.
Scott: another thing That's kind of small small but significant right is the age of the gamers.
Scott: right now You shouldn't.
Scott: I mean nobody's discriminating at least no one that I know is discriminating in terms of you know Race creed gender whatever in terms of who they're gaming with.
Scott: They just want someone who's gonna play the game and they don't give a shit what color height or whatever they are.
Scott: But age can matter a lot.
Scott: if you are into the Pokemon trading card game and you show up at some elementary school Tournament right.
Scott: if you're you into yugioh Which is perfectly okay for anyone to be into you.
Scott: if you want to be Right, you can show up at a tournament at a game store and play against.
Scott: you know, ten-year-olds and I guess that's okay a Little bit, okay, but you can't be hanging out with them at like a meetup.
Scott: You can't be having them over your house You can't really be befriending them when you're 30 40 year old person.
Scott: That is just kind of not cool and has a lot of issues.
Rym: Well, even if it is a hundred percent cool It doesn't matter because guys we live in a society where appearances matter or at least appearances affect you.
Scott: Right if you're that?
Rym: if you show up at an elementary school Pokemon meetup and you're 40 It's not gonna work.
Scott: It goes the other way too.
Scott: You're a nerdy kid in high school.
Scott: There's two other nerdy kids in your high school that you do stuff with but you need more.
Scott: The only other nerds in town are like these old dudes who game at the game shop.
Scott: You can't really get mixed up with them.
Rym: It's not gonna work out right because it's just it just isn't even though that sort of like mentored novice Relationship seems to have been a very common way.
Rym: people got into role-playing games for many many years.
Rym: I mean I would go to conventions like Michigan when I was in late middle school Even mid middle school and I'd show up and I joined a D&D game and most other people in that game were 30 40 50 And it worked totally fine.
Rym: Yeah, but again at a convention right?
Scott: not like going to their house if you have a significant Difference of age with the people that you can find there are only certain situations where it'll be socially appropriate To game with them and most of the time it won't be.
Rym: and even if you ignore the social thing or the social thing Is fine, I mean a lot of times it can be fine like parents meet and then the parents and kids have multiple families.
Scott: Or maybe it's your friend's dad.
Scott: You're in high school and you have a friend in high school and his dad is The crazy gamer guy.
Scott: it's like oh well that you know, that's a relationship that can work out.
Rym: You know the modern era.
Rym: if you're into magic and your dad comes down to play He's probably got all these old like mocks emeralds and black lotuses, right?
Scott: You know, that's that's an appropriate situation.
Rym: But there's also the problem of the kid brain.
Rym: the science shows below certain ages Like there's milestones of development in kids.
Rym: We played a really good game of Hanabi with two pretty young kids at anime Boston.
Rym: Yeah, not that long ago It was a fun game, but you know what and they were smart.
Rym: They did really well.
Scott: They were you know smart kids compared to other kids.
Scott: They were above average and smartness for kids their age They were still kids.
Rym: some kids just aren't at the level yet where they understand what a role-playing game even is.
Rym: Like they just don't get it.
Rym: Yeah, so the age difference will limit the amount of complexity you grab.
Scott: grab a board game.
Scott: What does it say on the side ages X and up ages X to X, right?
Scott: if you are in a different age range different games might just be skill level far away from you or Because of your age you just can't have a skill level any higher, right?
Scott: It's it.
Scott: you'll see some prodigies, of course, right, but you know you go to a netrunner tournament.
Scott: No one.
Scott: there is under 20 something.
Rym: everyone's between the ages of 25 and 35, right?
Scott: The World Championships those like one kid in like Tiago and he was a legend, right?
Scott: It's it's a complicated game that like a kid even a high school kid that have a hard time You know playing netrunner and seriously now, it's not an easy game.
Scott: age is a factor and chess tournaments They have age groups, right?
Scott: You know, you know the eight-year-old doesn't get to play against the grandmasters and whatever.
Rym: now age is a factor but Similar to or at least related to age is the social set of the person.
Rym: I mean when I play games with my adult friends we say fuck a lot Mmm, but a lot, you know, the game itself is one thing But you have to get along with the people you're playing games with even though most of you out there.
Rym: So easy for us to fall into our like the way we do panels when we get into this format.
Rym: But I'm even like pointing at the monitor.
Scott: You're the only one doing it.
Rym: Yeah, but you're you're speaking the same way.
Rym: you speak on a panel instead of let what we do on the show.
Rym: It's fun.
Scott: slides.
Rym: Yeah, I have slides.
Rym: So I'm looking at them.
Rym: They're all blank.
Scott: Get some pictures.
Scott: these aren't easy to get pictures for.
Rym: I got some good pictures.
Rym: Actually, I want to add a slide about obligation.
Rym: Okay, but anyway, so I can't say fuck all the time if I'm playing a game with like a bunch of eight-year-olds from the neighbor family.
Scott: or maybe You found some people near you and you have the same interesting games.
Rym: It's gonna work out, but they're really Republican.
Rym: Oh, they're really religious and they're a different religion from you and it's an issue for all of you, right?
Rym: Or they're just really prudish right and you're really loose and it's like like you You're a grande and you make a joke about how the king looks like a penis.
Scott: They're like At your game night, you're all drinking and smoking weed and at their game night.
Scott: They're all like Whoa, that's that's or vice versa.
Scott: You're all and you go to a game night somewhere.
Scott: you walk in and you smell the weed smoke and there's brownies and whatnot.
Scott: And it's like oh you're getting out of there.
Rym: But the trouble is that a lot of gamers are desperate.
Rym: We know they're desperate.
Rym: read any forum.
Rym: go around this convention.
Rym: You'll see the desperate people.
Rym: but some of you might be the desperate people.
Rym: I've been desperate at many points.
Scott: I'm often desperate.
Rym: You'll play games with people that outside of the context of that specific game.
Rym: You probably find abhorrence Either socially politically culturally.
Rym: you might have literally nothing to say to someone but yet gamers the world over We'll play games with those people if they're really desperate.
Scott: if they're desperate which a lot of people are right, okay, so Regardless of those factors, right Those people near you they fit all those requirements.
Scott: They might just be hiding.
Scott: There are a lot of people out there who are just hiding.
Scott: they they're not looking for you.
Scott: They're not looking to be found.
Scott: They're playing games.
Scott: They're into them.
Scott: You're into them.
Rym: They're really into a maybe yeah They're just not looking for anyone.
Scott: why?
Scott: because they got theirs.
Rym: and here's how you find out.
Rym: go look at a list of counter-strike Servers.
Rym: notice all those servers that are locked that you need a password to get into notice how a lot of them are full.
Rym: Yep How many D&D groups are open?
Rym: invite how many open invite D&D groups go?
Scott: Well, yeah, they've got a D&D group.
Scott: They've already got the GM and four players.
Scott: They're not advertising looking for more players.
Scott: They're not you know doing it.
Scott: they're just hiding.
Scott: they're meeting regularly in their house, you don't know them.
Scott: They don't know you.
Scott: they could be your next-door fucking neighbors, right?
Scott: You could be into D&D as much as they would but you don't know them.
Scott: They don't know you and That's the end of that.
Scott: They're not looking and when you post looking they're not respond.
Scott: They're not responding.
Rym: Now.
Rym: there's a lot of reasons for this.
Rym: I mean for example, we I've run a game night like every other week in our apartment.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: We have two alternating sets of game nights Never going to publicly post that because I don't want a bunch of strangers showing up.
Rym: I personally invite individual people and we hang out and that's what we do Most.
Rym: I think most of you are not super comfortable putting an ad on Craigslist saying hey You want to come play board games at my house?
Rym: Here's the address right door will be open.
Scott: You're super comfortable saying hey Is there anyone out there who wants to play games or has a D&D or whatever?
Scott: But no one's gonna respond to that if they've already got one.
Scott: So none of those people even though they're there.
Scott: it is ridiculously difficult to find them.
Scott: The only way to find them would be to happenstance meet them and befriend them in another social context and then Discover that their game exists and then befriend them enough to which they would invite you or you could invite them into a gaming situation that would grow over time.
Scott: and it's not easy that you have all seen this happen.
Rym: you go to some gaming meetup and Everyone's there kind of playing their games.
Rym: games are going well or badly or whatever.
Rym: but then you see a new person shows up and everyone kind of talks to them and gets them to play games to kind of get a sense of if they're Creepy or not if they're good at games or not if they like the same kind of games and if some people really hit it Off you won't see.
Rym: you'll see people sort of try to invite them to their private gaming group Like hey, you should come to my apartment sometime we play games.
Rym: Those invitations are often said very quietly Far away from the main group of gamers.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Nobody is super public about that.
Rym: In fact, a lot of people will pointedly Talk to someone after the event saying hey, you should come to my game group Because they didn't want that guy to overhear right now.
Scott: We're not gonna discuss.
Scott: I mean everything that needs to be said about that guy.
Scott: you all know that guy.
Scott: That's all that needs to be said.
Scott: right has been said already But it's not so much the concerns directly of you being that guy or how to deal with that guy when he's around.
Scott: It's more the fact that the guy exists in the first place, even if he doesn't physically exist.
Scott: Maybe you're lucky and you live in a town with know that guys in it.
Rym: It's possible.
Scott: the simple fact is that that guy exists somewhere on earth.
Scott: people know that guy and are afraid of that guy or at least the phantom of that guy and Thus they will behave in a certain way to avoid any possibility of that guy.
Rym: It's like in Martin.
Rym: I think of a funny example.
Rym: No,
Scott: just merely the fear of This thing this person possibly existing
Rym: Mario Party I know the stars
Scott: of this right affects all the behavior of all the normal people and their behavior will not change Until not only are all those guys gone But no one has any fear of that guy possibly being there
Rym: now that guy.
Scott: that day will not come in my lifetime.
Rym: I mean there you.
Rym: you could treat this like it's a game and that guy is a Event that's moving around on the board.
Rym: You've seen the scenario you're at a con you want to play, Puerto Rico.
Rym: It takes up to five players.
Rym: You've got three people are really into it.
Rym: you yell out Hey anyone want to play Puerto Rico?
Rym: two people walk up.
Rym: You all give each other the look because you know that one of those people Seems okay And one of them is so obviously that guy.
Rym: you really don't want them to join their game because you're just.
Rym: you're sure Either they're gonna be that guy in the creepy possibly misogynistic You know all the bad odor bad something or it might be the relative.
Rym: that guy as in He's that guy to your group.
Rym: if you're the super serious gamers and it's obvious that it's a guy who isn't super He's not gonna take the game seriously He's not gonna get the game.
Scott: someone who's gonna be even it could be something as simple as someone who's gonna be slow on their Turn or it'll be hard to explain the rules to.
Scott: or you know It is just not someone.
Scott: that's someone who on their own it only takes one bad egg to spoil the whole omelet Right up.
Rym: because if you get stuck in a game, you know, Puerto Rico Especially at a convention where you're teaching some rules.
Rym: That's a two-hour commitment.
Rym: If that's a two-hour commitment and someone ruins the game it is really bad culture.
Rym: It's not part of the etiquette of gaming to walk away from a game.
Rym: You're fucked.
Scott: I Might just start walking away from a game.
Rym: I've thought about making that.
Rym: I'm think that maybe part of the reason that guy is enabled is that gaming culture especially tabletop and convention culture Makes it very difficult to politely turn that guy down.
Rym: Hmm like if that guy wants to join your game, it's it's not.
Rym: it's sort of seen as very not cool to be like, sorry We're gonna take this game super seriously.
Rym: I know you're not really into these like really hardcore games.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but If you said that the minor hurt feelings at least be mitigated by the honesty And then everyone has a better time because that guy is not having any fun in your super hardcore game either.
Scott: Maybe or maybe he's just so desperate.
Scott: He is right.
Rym: Who knows anyway, but as a result, it's people Try to like trick that guy and they're not joining the game.
Rym: like oh, sorry the game is full But it says clearly on the box that the game takes up to five.
Rym: Yeah, our friend Steve is coming in a minute.
Rym: We're just waiting for him and then you see the guy like hovering around like waiting for Steve to show up.
Scott: These are things that literally happen.
Rym: Yes, every one of these things has actually happened to us.
Scott: Yes All right.
Scott: So one more thing that can get in the way of finding gamers to play games with is simply life.
Scott: I'm running a torchbearer game, right?
Scott: We just I found people that I know that I can trust that are awesome a torchbearer.
Scott: They're all 100% Not that guy there.
Scott: Everyone's awesome.
Scott: Everyone's really into it.
Scott: Everyone really wants to play.
Scott: They at least said that they really liked the game when I ran it.
Scott: They could be lying.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: I wish they wouldn't lie because if I'm doing something wrong, I want to know.
Scott: You know and we're playing on Google Hangouts.
Scott: that solves a lot of our problems, right?
Scott: What happened?
Rym: Yeah, look you've solved geography, you've solved time zones, you've solved language.
Rym: You're already friends, right?
Scott: What happened?
Scott: Well, we played a couple sessions and now people's lives are getting in the way.
Scott: Someone's got jobs changing schedules Someone's you know here.
Rym: look at this week.
Rym: Monday I had an impromptu meeting to consult with someone about an article they're writing.
Rym: So me and Emily had dinner with them.
Rym: So that killed Monday.
Rym: Tuesday, we're doing GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah, and then we're finishing work for the panel Wednesday.
Rym: tomorrow normally is our weekly game night, but now because suddenly I have to fly to Paris on Saturday I can do some shit together.
Rym: Yeah, so I got to cancel that game night Thursday.
Rym: We're doing GeekNights again, right?
Scott: People have lives and their lives Anyone, it doesn't matter who you are how highly you prioritize gaming in general.
Scott: I mean Maybe you are a guy who plays Starcraft and that is your most.
Scott: that is your thing.
Scott: You are a start your pro at Starcraft like that's your thing, right?
Scott: You are going to prioritize something such as I don't know your brother's wedding as more important than a star?
Scott: Well, well, I would hope so.
Scott: Otherwise, you're that guy right?
Rym: Well, well, it depends God Say someone we knew scheduled their wedding at the same time as PAX Prime.
Scott: They're getting married at PAX Prime, right?
Rym: Yeah, surprisingly they're not.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: I really don't understand why but somehow they decided to get married in like I don't know Chicago At the same time as PAX Prime.
Scott: Well, this PAX Prime move into Chicago Maybe but not this year.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Say your brother say your actual brother got married he announced the wedding It's all set up and it was literally the weekend of PAX Prime Next year, it's tough.
Scott: Yeah It's tough.
Scott: it is tough, right But The point is these conflicts happen and when you have a gaming group right every person you have you're multiplying those difficulties Right.
Scott: So how often does some shit come up in your life?
Scott: And you have a gaming group of five people.
Scott: five times as much shit comes up and anytime one of those shits Happens the game is canceled.
Scott: So is the moral?
Rym: not only one person in a gaming group is allowed to have a life because then everyone else is always gonna Show up whenever that person's available.
Rym: Sure, that's the way to do it make friends with losers.
Rym: Yeah, there is actually a time and place where schedules and lives and priority are literally not a concern.
Rym: Mmm that happened to us.
Rym: That's the only reason we college.
Rym: Yes college if one you you prioritize gaming above Classes.
Rym: Yes, like I'm not even joking not saying you should do this.
Rym: We did it.
Scott: Yes, but I'll take 2 a.m.
Rym: Oh my god, we would skip class to play counter-strike with our friends.
Rym: We would skip class skip labs Drop classes to show up at the gaming clubs and play games.
Scott: We played German board game you in a class.
Scott: You can go to anime club.
Rym: I literally dropped out of a class so I could go to the anime club.
Rym: I dropped another class so I wouldn't miss an l5 our game that I joined after the class started.
Rym: We played games every goddamn day video games board games everything every day every weekend At a nerd school.
Scott: if we were not at a nerd school which again Incredibly privileged to be able to afford to go to the nerd school and to be well educated enough to get accepted to the nerd School and
Rym: to be smart enough to somehow graduate without ever fucking going to class,
Scott: right?
Scott: And even then in that group you go to like State School how many nerds are gonna be there?
Scott: How often is the gaming club gonna meet?
Scott: how many people will be there?
Rym: Yeah, alrighty, there were like 150 to 200 people From a pool of a pool that would show up to the gaming club and of them like a hundred would show up every fuck.
Scott: Is that a school that's consisted of thousands of nerds?
Scott: you get you know tens of people at the gaming club.
Rym: granted There were other not technically official gaming clubs that I just spawned up a hidden gamer.
Scott: We were hiding from that guy right so anyway?
Scott: So what do you do about this?
Rym: right it go to college never leave?
Scott: Well, I mean we you know we've talked about all these reasons that you can't find another gamer.
Scott: They're just not out there right there.
Scott: all the things we've discussed.
Rym: so what I think there's two sides There's.
Rym: what can you do about it?
Rym: And what can the what can gaming and the community do about it?
Scott: right so what can you do about it?
Scott: all I can tell you is either go to college or Move to a city a real city.
Rym: Well not a joke city.
Rym: you have to move to a real city or a college town.
Rym: that has to be a big enough college To attract enough people and a nerdy college.
Rym: Yes, right I mean I went to.
Rym: I won't name the name of the college But when I was living in Poughkeepsie I was bored wanted to find a gaming group and I found a gaming club at a local college That was open invite so I thought I'd go to it.
Rym: I went to it.
Rym: That's where I learned that this club was also the anime club and the witchcraft Wicca club and the science fiction club.
Rym: I had like five members.
Scott: there are so few nerds there, and I never went back right.
Scott: I looked in the door And I was like nope if you live in a city a major city so consider this.
Scott: I live in New York City the majorist Of cities in the world new room capital of Earth.
Scott: okay, and when we play netrunner on Tuesday nights This is maybe 20 people tops.
Scott: we go to the other tournament 20-something people.
Scott: But apparently we just discovered that there's another secret hiding group of netrunners in Brooklyn at some NYU thing.
Scott: So there's probably more like 40 something people.
Scott: Yeah, there's like maybe 50 to 60 total serious netrunner people that are in the community in all of New York City.
Scott: Millions upon millions and millions of people.
Scott: we'll go to one game.
Scott: You're not in New York City.
Scott: How many less people are there than that?
Scott: some guy went out told me he went out to Long Island to play and he won A tournament where they're only like six people.
Scott: that's so close to where we are.
Rym: Hopefully it's not also a combination for you of dead or dying game.
Scott: No, it's not Right static game.
Rym: all the people who started playing are the only ones who's still playing.
Scott: No we get new people not.
Scott: But I say it's like, you know, so if you're into magic, right It's like you can find people.
Scott: that game is a worldwide game, right?
Rym: Oh my god It PAX Australia's a bunch of having the tabletop was just people play magic.
Scott: There's a bunch of gaming meetups in New York City, right?
Scott: But okay, New York City is four times the size of pretty much any other city.
Scott: So you got to say Boston is 25% of the gaming that's in New York is in Boston I think is way smaller than four times, but they had no but they have.
Scott: they have nerds there at MIT and such.
Scott: That gives them a boost Nerd town, right?
Scott: San Francisco, Seattle get boost cuz of nerd town.
Scott: Okay, go to I don't know Kansas City.
Scott: There's some nerds there in Kansas City.
Scott: It's somewhat of a real city.
Scott: They even have a professional, you know sporting teams You know, they have Google Internet which brought some nerds into town.
Scott: but there's probably like Less than a quarter of the gaming going on there as there isn't in New York, right?
Scott: Just because of population.
Rym: Now there's also the weird side of it's like New York City actually has some problems that make some aspects of gaming way harder.
Rym: So it even gets hard on the upper end.
Rym: you would like Toronto.
Rym: There's a bunch of board game cafes.
Scott: There's one in New York now.
Rym: Yeah, there's one in New York.
Scott: I thought there's only one in Toronto snakes and lattes.
Rym: I I heard that there's two more.
Scott: I haven't heard that.
Rym: That's what I was told when I was there.
Rym: people told me.
Rym: Oh, you should visit this other place.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: Okay, so something else that we can all do have more conventions.
Scott: Why is there just you know a few paxes right and I guess crappy Gen Con and a couple other tiny aspects of dragon con right Aspects of ConnectiCon aspect a lot of cons board game gaming.
Scott: on this There's a significant number of cons, but there's way more anime cons than gaming cons.
Scott: There are tiny anime cons friggin all over the plane.
Rym: those tiny anime cons grow huge really quick.
Rym: Yeah, that's thousands of people at those things that got caught, you know, we laugh like it's a small con.
Rym: It's actually pretty fucking big now thousands of people.
Scott: Yeah, right and it's in Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Rym: It's like I'd never heard of Lancaster before.
Scott: I've heard of it, but it's like that is.
Scott: that's even less than Kansas City.
Scott: That's a small place but thousands of little nerds show up for that anime con.
Scott: So why can't there be as many gaming cons as there are anime cons?
Scott: There should be one near any wherever you live.
Scott: There should be one a month Driving distance.
Rym: in a sense there should are.
Rym: there are tons of gaming cons But this is con culture.
Rym: the gaming cons that are like packs and mag fest have a almost completely separate culture from What traditionally was considered a gaming con?
Rym: I mean as a kid.
Rym: there were like nine conventions within a short drive of my house in Michigan Hmm.
Rym: and I went to a bunch of them.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: they were all Under a thousand people and they were all the old-school pay for tickets to individual.
Scott: They're over con.
Rym: Yeah, they were like uber cons right or the.
Rym: all those other little gaming cons are in New York City like they're
Scott: there
Rym: But they have such a different culture that for whatever reason they can't really grow and the few that do grow tend to run into a lot of problems and Have a lot of internal drama just like gaming groups do huh?
Scott: Yeah, so, you know if you want more gaming I think more conventions would just help a lot.
Scott: and then finally just at least for us in the u.s Here in Canada, right?
Scott: We need better internets, right?
Scott: It's like we already have probably know that someone far away There's gonna be latency no matter what.
Scott: but if our internet was just better There's dude still be.
Scott: there's a lot of games that I should be able to play with someone.
Scott: But our and we both have money.
Scott: we both have good computers But the internet just sucks and we can't buy better internet or the internet just can't do things.
Rym: yet like we don't have Augmented reality is where we both have a physical esque copy of a board game in front of us and are playing remotely with holograms.
Scott: Nope, someday that'll happen, but we need to get you know.
Scott: We just need to fix internet in the u.s.
Scott: To where you know, we can get google fiber everywhere or you know Isp, stop screwing everyone over and little things like automatic translation generic places for games lots of stuff that could happen there.
Scott: Sure, I guess the last thing that you can do to find gamers in this desperate situation is Simply to change who you are or at least something about yourself, right?
Scott: Maybe you really want to play an rpg and you're a dnd person.
Scott: That's what you're into and the people near you are into pathfinder and it's like well Just become a pathfinder person.
Scott: It's not it's not that different right?
Scott: just you know, you're outvoted, right?
Scott: Would you rather play pathfinder which is really similar to what you already want to do, right?
Scott: Even though it's not exactly what you'd like to do or would you rather stay home and play nothing?
Rym: And if you don't play pathfinder then it'll be really hard to convince those people to switch to dnd, right?
Rym: But if you play with them, I mean i've seen there's a lot of commentary with indie rpg Someone will join a dnd group and then over the years be like hey Why don't we try this indie rpg?
Rym: you can actually groom other people to be into the games you're into.
Rym: You play.
Scott: you play league of legends.
Scott: Your friend is into dota.
Scott: Just play dota right?
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's just go, you know, it's.
Scott: it's not that different.
Scott: Would you rather play dota with your friend or would you rather play league of legends alone and him play dota alone?
Rym: Right just just play team fortress 2. is not that different from others?
Scott: one, right?
Scott: You can't change anyone else you can only change yourself.
Scott: So don't you know, you're not gonna be if the other person's stubborn just give up on that.
Scott: Just be the unstubborn person and more gaming will happen, right?
Scott: You know if you're if you play call of duty your phone plays counter-strike.
Scott: just play counter-strike.
Rym: But if you try to bludgeon other people over the head like you've got to play this other game instead It's not gonna work.
Scott: you become that guy to them if you're if you're super serious like, you know about playing to win Right and and the other people are just sort of like la la la and they don't care.
Scott: and that's all you've got to play with.
Rym: Just change your attitude right or be super fun and sociable and do all the social stuff, but still just fucking win.
Rym: Just be the guy who always fucking wins but doesn't make a big deal about it's like I won again.
Rym: I won again.
Rym: Oh Rym always wins.
Scott: Yep Yeah, just change yourself so that you can make the situation whatever situation you've got.
Scott: work right.
Scott: you don't have a lot to work with Right.
Rym: So whatever you've got make the most of it, but at the same time Don't misinterpret someone not wanting to play a game with you for hating you Because they probably hate you.
Rym: Yeah, they probably do but I don't think we want that more.
Rym: It'll be in the actual tax panel.
Rym: No Mm-hmm, but think of it this way.
Rym: Would you invite this person into your house?
Scott: Barely knowing them would you?
Scott: are you a person that people want to invite into their home?
Scott: Yeah, be a person that you would want to invite dude.
Rym: Does every group evaporate the moment you try to join it?
Rym: That's more back to the that guy you shouldn't.
Rym: yeah All right, that's all.
Rym: Did anyone want to ask a question?
Rym: I guess they can't.
Rym: no I don't know if you have any comments on this.
Rym: Uh, we didn't mind that did we do met?
Scott: We barely did met a moment.
Rym: Yeah, we do a little bit.
Rym: basically If you ask us questions about what we talked about or have anything interesting to add anecdotes, whatever uh We we got some time before packs we can edit this panel.
Rym: guys the secret to our panels that we have a list of slides Because those are just the main points We uh make it up every time we do a panel is different because we just know what we're gonna talk about.
Rym: That's it?
Rym: so if you tell us something cool we might incorporate it into the panel.
Rym: maybe hopefully I just imagine this people will tell us their stuff and everything they tell us becomes the anecdotes of what not to do The anecdote of that guy.
Scott: we're not doing that panel.
Rym: No, we're not that panel.
Rym: There's a topic for an anime con.
Rym: Let's just do that panel.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand.
Rym: Okay for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.