Rym: It's Tuesday, May 9th, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: That was good.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: It's a Mario Kart 8 to deluxe on the switch.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, there won't be any GeekNights next week cuz I'm gonna be in Hong Kong or stay there a boring kind of convention.
Rym: But I'll be there stay there.
Rym: I guess if any of you don't come back want to come hang out with me in Hong Kong I'll have a bunch of free time at night.
Scott: Oh Don't come back.
Rym: No stay there.
Rym: There'll be any GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah, I was live in Hong Kong Hang out in a La Kuai Fung, which is the one cool neighborhood.
Rym: I know about in Hong Kong.
Scott: I can go to bed.
Rym: There's gonna be an old man like that, that's the turning point of old man's got.
Rym: I disappear and you just never get out of bed again.
Rym: So you got any gaming news on this Tuesday cuz I got nothing other than no GeekNights next week.
Scott: There isn't any news about actual games.
Scott: then these tiny news is like some games came out, right?
Scott: So tumble seed which we've been talking about.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we'll do a review of it Later.
Rym: that games hard as balls are that is well.
Rym: It's as hard as I expected it to be.
Scott: I didn't expect it to be.
Rym: you played ice-cold beer, right?
Scott: But I didn't.
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: the problem is like yeah I knew but it's like you can make an easy ice-cold beer right where there's like two holes and you right.
Rym: You thought that's what they were gonna do me.
Scott: it's hard right from the beginning.
Scott: it's like impossibly hard.
Rym: How far is the highest you've ever gotten an ice-cold beer?
Scott: Listen, that's how my ice-cold beer I'm talking about tumble seat.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: This is ice-cold beer plus roguelike nonsense, right?
Scott: But it's a video game.
Scott: So I figure you'd have this curve where the first level would just have like a couple holes in it.
Scott: You know be like baby mode and then hard over time.
Scott: It's like no immediately in level one.
Scott: It's balls hard.
Scott: So anyway But strafe I think came out the oh, yeah, I backed that.
Rym: I thought multiple people messaged me.
Scott: I also kick-started it and that is a game that basically it looks like quake, but there's a trailer for it out.
Scott: There's been a bunch of awesome trailers for it, but there's a new one.
Scott: That's like basically like this epic Movie trailer thing.
Scott: It's it's insane.
Scott: Like they supposed to spend more effort on this fucking trailer than on the actual game.
Scott: But yeah strafe the.
Scott: if you want to play quake one on Steroids.
Scott: that's brand-new in 2017.
Rym: That's what strafe is just multiple peeler his website.
Rym: here Multiple people have messaged me like just recently like hey, right Have you heard about this game?
Rym: and I didn't remember it.
Rym: I kick-started this until I looked and yes I actually backed it like day one, right?
Rym: So, uh in some news eSports journalism You know the commentary commentation the color like all the stuff related to eSports still pretty amateur and has Shall we say?
Rym: Some troubles.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I saw a lot of people talking about this one eSports Article and here's the situation.
Rym: Here's the headline Dream hack Austin melee tournament champion wins in the most pathetic way possible.
Rym: Okay, so the store.
Rym: now the best part about this article because most people were talking about this from solely a screenshot.
Rym: They could screenshot of the first paragraph of this and talked about like how much of a jerk this writer is.
Rym: But the other half of Twitter was talking about how much of a jerk the guy the article is about is Okay.
Rym: So here's the first paragraph.
Scott: what actually happened at the dream hang?
Rym: I'll read the first paragraph first.
Rym: I don't like using the term douchebag too often in writing an online article.
Rym: aside from the fact that I'm not a 20-something blogger looking For big hits.
Rym: It's just not a favorable term.
Scott: I don't care about this blog guy.
Scott: I care about what happened at the gaming tournament the actual news.
Rym: So people are legit mad about what happened to the gaming - what happened at the gaming tournament?
Rym: So there's this whole drama about like the ladders and everything, but eventually it's a Smash Brothers melee tournament.
Scott: I know that much.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right I gathered that.
Rym: so quote.
Rym: at a certain point time during the match Both of them had three lives in stock But chewed at was heavily injured at 122 percent and the other guy had low percent hungry box.
Rym: Already already had to earn his first kill and was having a hard time with the second.
Rym: So he chose to do one of the biggest jerk moves you can add you can do as a gamer Run out the clock and he won the game by running out the clock, which I think is awesome.
Scott: Why wouldn't you do that?
Rym: That is literally what you should do.
Scott: He had lower percent.
Scott: So he was ahead, right?
Scott: So if the clock runs out he wins.
Scott: yep, he just ran out the clock and the other guy couldn't catch it.
Rym: now I'm sure a portion of you reading this we're gonna say something to the effect of well He did it within the rules and yeah, he did which should be the end of the argument, right?
Rym: If you don't let me pose a pose a scenario to you.
Scott: I mean you take a knee in football is how it works.
Scott: It's like if you got a problem with that other a change the rules or be deal with it.
Rym: Yep, but he's like.
Scott: but let me pose a question to you Also see how could he run out the clock the other guy who think one whose purses behind should be able to catch him and fight him?
Rym: well the the example he gives us.
Rym: what if you're playing a fighting game and You haven't beaten the guy yet and there's less than 10 seconds and you have way more health and you just duck in the corner crouching Cuz?
Rym: they can't do enough damage in those last 10 seconds.
Rym: Does that count?
Rym: like this whole article poses this question?
Rym: Yeah, does that count?
Scott: I scored enough points and there's 10 seconds left in the football game To touchdowns in 10 seconds.
Scott: Did they really win?
Rym: were they really better than you?
Scott: Yeah, they got it.
Scott: They got ahead of you and you weren't able to catch up.
Scott: That's how games work.
Rym: or were they just a durch bag douche bag with a smirk on their face exploiting the game for an easy win?
Scott: No They're a better gamer.
Scott: So we they use that.
Scott: they did things within the rules in order to achieve victory.
Scott: That is gaming.
Rym: So I saw this.
Scott: I
Rym: literally saw to come 180 degrees separated takes all based on this one article from DreamHack where half the internet seems to think that This is great eSports journalism and that like they're calling this guy out for being a jerk and then normal intelligent people like us and the people who were saying that this writer is terrible and that eSports journalism is by and large terrible pointing out that you play to win the game if The end of a game is unsatisfying.
Rym: That's the game's fault.
Rym: Not the players fault, right?
Scott: But like I don't who cares about the stupid non journalist?
Scott: You know, you're not a journalist if you're writing about like douche if using the word douchebag.
Scott: Yeah, like if you got using yourself for using the word douchebag.
Rym: I feel like if you got the word douchebag in your article, you're probably not a journalist unless you're quoting some douchebag.
Scott: I mean this guy's basically someone who can write a reddit comment, but is instead right, you know It doesn't like.
Scott: I can write a blog post and the only thing that makes it a blog post instead of a comment is where It goes on the page and anyone can make a web page.
Scott: doesn't make you a journalist.
Scott: Who cares about this no-name non journalist guy?
Scott: because the only thing that matters is the Smash Brothers Melee tournament rules need to be modified so that you don't get these unsatisfying endings or running out the clock, right?
Rym: I think to me I see it as a completely satisfying.
Scott: and well I think another problem here right is that is that affects greater eSports in general right?
Scott: Is that most eSports?
Scott: You cannot modify the game code.
Scott: So if so like something like League of Legends Right or like hearthstone is like the companies that make these things are making like tournament builds and stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah, right, but Smash Brothers is like no you're just playing the same Smash Brothers Everyone has at home and there's no way to actually modify the code of the game to make a tournament mode with different rules Or anything else.
Rym: you have to make rules around the game, right?
Scott: You can't modify the code at all and this results is always going to basically guarantee There will be problems in your sport because your rules are completely inflexible.
Scott: You can't change the code of the game or anything.
Scott: But there's also a separate problem that among like the journalism you see about Like even the worst regular sports like baseball which almost never changes the rules changes the rules more And Smash Brothers you can't change the rules.
Rym: But in general with eSports like there's not as much journalism like you'll get some pretty legit journalism about like really big tournaments But anything even.
Rym: I'll tear down from that.
Rym: the only people who show up to cover these things tend to be the some guy with a blog who is Personally invested in the outcome and has very specific personal opinions and doesn't have any Actual like eSports knowledge or expertise, but
Scott: anyway as for this specific instance though They could like like there are like, you know.
Scott: I made that general point like oh you should.
Scott: you can't fix the code in case you have problems with the way the game is Coded for tournaments, right but in this particular instance, you don't need to do that.
Scott: It could just play an infinite time.
Scott: Why don't they?
Rym: yeah like ice hockey like the NHL like there's gonna be a game tonight.
Rym: if they're tied at the end of the Game, they will literally keep playing hockey for ever right?
Scott: You could just you know say infinite time.
Scott: It's five stock no matter what.
Scott: No, wait, go wait.
Scott: We'll sit here and wait for you guys.
Scott: You can't running won't help you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, why couldn't the guy catch him?
Rym: How did he run at the clock?
Scott: why couldn't he be caught?
Scott: if the other guy's so good at smash melee Why could?
Rym: oh look he's just he's just jigglypuffing back and forth.
Scott: I think Hey, hold on.
Scott: How come the guy can't catch him?
Rym: He should look he's just jigglypuffing.
Rym: He's just jigglypuffing.
Scott: Ice climbers go in and get him try.
Rym: He's just floating to jigglypuffing.
Scott: hit him.
Rym: Can't look he's trying.
Scott: He's not even he's so close to him.
Scott: Just hit him.
Rym: He's jigglypuffing.
Scott: He's not doing shit.
Scott: Yeah Just go jigglypuffing.
Rym: He's trying.
Rym: I think jill above deserves to win this.
Scott: I do too.
Scott: Those ice climbers can't like can't hit shit.
Scott: Yeah, why do they suck these?
Scott: not far away?
Scott: It's like he's running far away on the map like in some.
Scott: it's not that.
Rym: It's not that Zelda map.
Scott: He's right there.
Scott: You can hit him.
Scott: It's Pokemon Tournament area whatever.
Scott: There's a he's just get him.
Rym: There's an Unstated point like about beyond all of this that in general the people in the community around smash brothers anything Pretty toxic and weird.
Scott: Well, I mean experience people in a lot and most these kinds of things toxic and weird.
Rym: Yeah You Got any news.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: so there was a contest to make t-shirt designs for Nintendo that I guess Uniqlo would make.
Scott: the shirts and You know Nintendo actually for whatever good or bad they do They're actually pretty good at merch.
Scott: if you go to the actual Nintendo store They always got pretty good merch there that like you would not expect them to have.
Scott: yeah, like surprisingly high-class stuff It's overpriced and maybe not the best quality construction.
Scott: But the designs are you know, they're better than like we love.
Scott: fine level, right?
Scott: They go.
Scott: Yeah, they get.
Scott: you get like the gold Zelda of cartridge backpack and shit Which if I was a kid would have been the best back.
Scott: But now you won't catch me dead wearing that.
Scott: but it's still a really good design, right?
Scott: But yeah these.
Scott: so there was a contest to submit designs that Uniqlo would make with Nintendo licensed properties and the winners have been selected and I guess soon or now ish it gives.
Scott: if you go to Uniqlo you can Buy these shirts.
Scott: I'm gonna go see if there's any good one.
Rym: Literally every one of these is great.
Scott: They're pretty going.
Scott: they won a contest without a lot of submissions.
Scott: Yeah, and this the people selecting the winners where people who know about that.
Rym: Pixels Mario, that's a real good shirt.
Scott: It's the first place one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I think my other favorite is the.
Rym: This Pokemon shirt is a women's shirt.
Rym: It's just the old fat Pikachu from the gameboy.
Rym: Like as a pattern, it's pretty good.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Also this boo shirt, which is a bunch of booze.
Scott: Yeah, that thing is like it's got booze on it by wearing that.
Scott: it has that weird pattern and then Sleeves don't have the pattern on it situation.
Scott: Yeah, it's a little weird this.
Rym: I'd like I'd like to be able to get this fabric.
Rym: That's just the booze.
Scott: I'll make something else that I feel like you could make a good pillow.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, how much is the shirt cost?
Scott: Uh, 1500 yen, so probably in America like plus Okay.
Scott: Yeah, so just buy a whole bunch of that shirt.
Scott: Yeah The Biggest size they got extra extra large Did even sell extra extra large Uniqlo, I feel like XL is the biggest size they make.
Rym: yeah I mean luckily a Uniqlo small t-shirt fits me Okay, and a Uniqlo medium fits me like normally.
Rym: so cuz I've gone there before where there was like one large shirt Like hanging out by itself and it's all smalls.
Scott: That's all I mean, this is a company that you know, it says like clothes for all but it's closer Japanese people who are small.
Rym: Yeah I'm still sad though because they had those like really heavy jeans many years ago and I bought two pair.
Rym: and now most of the Jeans, they have are not that heavy.
Rym: They're more like Spandex jeans and the normal jeans they have are not quite the same not quite as heavy and I can't get that old heavy jean.
Scott: You just go somewhere else.
Rym: Yeah, but the other places I go that have heavy jeans are more mom jean style.
Scott: You can get jeans in many places.
Rym: Yeah From the best jean that that old Uniqlo jean was particularly good and I really liked it.
Rym: You can get.
Scott: you just haven't looked how many jean place have you gone to?
Scott: three?
Rym: Yeah, I gave up.
Scott: You know how many you're in New York City.
Scott: There's like a hundred different places.
Scott: You can get a different jean Yeah, but I particularly like that one.
Rym: Oh, I didn't even notice this one.
Rym: It's the pipe instead of the pocket and just Mario and Luigi like peeking out of the pipe.
Rym: That's a real good one, too.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, you might have noticed that the Stanley Cup playoffs are going on right now and the NHL is Expanding again meaning that a lot of good players.
Scott: We need to contract get rid of team.
Scott: Stop making new games.
Rym: I'm like, but a lot of good players who are perfectly happy living in great cities It'll be forced to move to Vegas.
Scott: You don't have to move there.
Scott: You just have to work there like half the year.
Rym: Yeah, so you're living there half the year.
Rym: Yeah, that's not.
Scott: I'd have to buy a house there, you know, you can travel constantly.
Scott: yeah, it would be a mad money.
Scott: What do you care?
Rym: It would be really weird to live in Vegas.
Scott: a lot of professional athletes that make enough money don't live Permanently in the place where their team is.
Scott: Yeah General and like, you know, they'll live out of a hotel for you know, whatever.
Rym: Yep well, especially if you're gonna get traded or something, but so this video is something the NHL put out.
Rym: I this partly in promotion the fact that there's a new team and it goes through Basically the entire history of the NHL showing all the teams that came and went and changed names and moved around Case.
Rym: it didn't know who the Detroit Falcons were or the Montreal Maroon.
Scott: You don't need to know who they are.
Rym: They're part of history.
Scott: Yeah big deal.
Rym: I'd like to bring some of those teams back and put them in places that would appreciate hockey rather than get more southern and Western teams and just get rid, you know get rid of like.
Rym: Get rid of the Florida Panthers.
Scott: Yeah, st.
Rym: Louis deserves everything.
Rym: Actually, you know what Nashville like.
Rym: if if the Rangers don't win the Stanley Cup pretty much is written for Nashville Yeah, I would like them to win.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: They're doing pretty.
Scott: anyone that's not Pittsburgh or Washington.
Rym: Yeah, well pretty what.
Rym: no Pennsylvania teams can win.
Rym: really no team No team on the East Coast can win unless it's the Rangers as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: So, uh, this is I don't know.
Rym: this video is overdramatic but it's moderately interesting.
Scott: So here's awesome, dude, Ludacris, you know, excellent Freestyle rap guy, right and he's got the children's book llama llama Red pajama and he's had some morning radio show somewhere.
Rym: The first YouTube comment actually describes literally everything that needs to be described about this.
Rym: Not gonna lie.
Rym: This is actually fire emoticon.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So yeah, I mean, you know, it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: you take someone with you know, amazing talent and you have them Perform something.
Scott: that's not what they usually perform and you can see how you know The combination of the two art forms.
Scott: right create some sort of magic, right?
Scott: It's like a few weeks ago There was a something going around.
Scott: Basically a cat got on a field somewhere at some sporting event and all the sports photographers took pictures of the cat And you could see the combination of the art of sports photography and cat Which is not a combination that usually happens right and it's like oh and it helps you, you know understand You know both art forms better right you understand cat more and you understand.
Scott: You know the sports photography more when you see them and used in a different context than they normally appear.
Scott: So here you can understand freestyle rap and children's book writing more By seeing them combined in a new context.
Rym: So I got a third mini thing of the day because it's related to hockey.
Rym: I just stumbled upon this cuz I've spent a lot more time in the hockey reddits.
Rym: just I do that every year around Stanley Cup time and If a lot of you especially, you know, this is Tuesday like GeekNights gaming night.
Rym: So we sports count and all that and I know a lot of nerds very popularly like to pointedly hate on sports.
Rym: But sports people are just as nerdy as you.
Rym: and if you want an example of this like this is a like a hockey meme About a particular hockey player that is in the style of your weird internet meme nonsense.
Scott: Okay?
Rym: Also, it's Tanner glass my man.
Rym: Those girls were at the game.
Rym: Just this.
Rym: I Wonder what their deal was like, how did they move into the Tanner glass specific fandom?
Rym: In the meta moment the booklet book is Frank Herbert's Dune.
Rym: I beat the fourth divine beasts.
Rym: So I'm getting closer to actually reading this book.
Scott: I haven't played a Zelda Still I haven't even gone to Goron land at all.
Scott: I gotta tell you I'm going around getting shrines and doing that kind of stuff, but I haven't done it in a while.
Rym: I got a lot of shrines.
Rym: I found a bunch of shrines.
Rym: I didn't do most of the shrine quest.
Rym: I actually found most of the shrines just by like dinking around in my own out in the wilderness.
Rym: Yeah, you know, but I gotta say the Goron quest I saved it for last cuz I felt like Death Mountain would be the craziest one.
Rym: It is the least fun one.
Rym: It is the easiest one not just because I'm like super powerful and have like strong stuff now But just because like the puzzles in Goron land like I beat the whole thing in a couple minutes like no
Scott: I only saved Goron land for last because I would need some sort of heat protecting gear to go in there where it's all firing.
Rym: Yeah, except you know where you get the heat protecting gear on the way in.
Rym: no all the way in in Goron town.
Scott: Oh, okay Protecting gear.
Scott: I got in the desert land.
Rym: That's not.
Rym: no no you do not have that gear.
Rym: you have heat protecting gear.
Rym: You do not have fire protecting gear.
Scott: I don't need fire protecting gear until I actually go in fire.
Rym: Uh If the air is so hot that everything catches fire in the open air once you get too close to death mountain Mmm, like you try to fly in and suddenly you're on fire and no amount of heat protection protects you from that.
Rym: and I got to a point where I needed multiple layers of Fire protection independent of heat protection.
Rym: They're two different things.
Rym: Okay, there's also difference between.
Scott: I'm sure I can just eat a food That takes care of it.
Rym: There's only an elixir that does it.
Rym: There's no food that does it.
Scott: I'll make it I'll make the elixir and before you
Rym: know what I did I said fuck it I just ate a bunch of health and I ran all the way to Goron land eating health because when you're in there while you're Literally on fire if you talk to anyone the game resets your fire status and you catch fire again in a few seconds.
Rym: If you keep talking to NPCs you can kind of like eventually find the one that gives you fireproof armor.
Rym: Yeah, and you can spend money and buy that armor.
Rym: then you're okay.
Scott: I should have a bunch of money before I tried to go there.
Scott: Yeah, see that's the only reason I saved that one for last.
Rym: but it's just really boring like the quest to get to you know Every they're like every beast has like fly around and shoot arrows at it or like blow up the feed and there's lightning.
Rym: Yeah, this one is a stealth mission, but it's really janky and poorly done Like everything about the Goron quest is just the stealth mission in the.
Scott: The other stealth mission with the banana people was also bad.
Rym: Yeah Well, the banana people one was not.
Rym: it wasn't that bad, but I just snuck up on everyone and murdered him one by one Mmm, I literally threw banana out.
Rym: guy walked over and ate it stabbed her in the back.
Rym: repeat until they were all dead.
Scott: Those guys when I fought those guys, they did not go down in one hit.
Scott: I need him.
Scott: They were very dangerous.
Rym: Did you sneak him?
Rym: because if you get a sneak strike, it's one shot.
Rym: I See you and you get close enough to him and option appears on the screen like hit wide a sneak strike.
Rym: I've never.
Scott: I've never seen that ever.
Rym: Whoa sneak up on sleeping guys sky.
Rym: You get a one-shot.
Rym: pretty much anyone.
Rym: Okay, except like guardians.
Rym: You can't do this too.
Rym: But like sneak up and even like those white Moblins and get a sneak strike instant death All right.
Rym: Now, I don't think you can do it.
Scott: I saw upgrade myself suit all the way.
Rym: I don't even I just sneak up super slow maybe eating a little bit of stealth food.
Rym: I didn't even bother buying the stealth clothing.
Rym: Mmm Not only is the Goron Sneak up dumb and you can just skip it by killing the things that are flying around trying to see you And even when they see you like it's not much of a puzzle It's just sort of brute force, you know, like whistle to tell him to stop or start moving But if you get even a little bit far away from him, he can't hear your whistle.
Rym: So it doesn't even really work and it was just really disappointing.
Rym: from start to finish I beat the whole thing in one go and if you have not gonna divine beast yet I urge you to do the Goron one first because I think that's the only way to make it even remotely interesting.
Scott: Um, plus I'm gonna do some castling before I go and you know get the last divine.
Scott: I heard that if you go to the castle before doing all the divine beasts is different.
Scott: So I want to do some a bunch more castling stuff before I get clear the last divine.
Rym: I didn't know that cuz I cleared all the beasts I've been in the castle a little bit, but I kept getting scared and leaving.
Scott: I heard that this you know different castle stuff.
Scott: if you got different, you know You know, you don't get you have all the beasts or not.
Rym: I found all the memories on my own.
Rym: I didn't even use the painter guy.
Scott: I think I'm missing a couple.
Rym: I'm missing two.
Rym: One of them looks like it's the castle.
Rym: Yeah, I need the castle one and one of them looks like a grotto with like some stuff Yeah, and I can't find that one either.
Rym: Mm-hmm Maybe I'll try to find the painter guy and see if it'll point me in the right direction.
Rym: right - it's black, too Yeah, so otherwise, I don't know.
Rym: follow us on YouTube.
Rym: it's both Scott's channel and my channel because we had good stuff going on and July so we got nothing for a while.
Scott: to be honest with you ConnectiCon looking not as good as previous ConnectiCon.
Rym: Oh, so why do you say that?
Scott: Let's see a lot less enthusiasm from the people.
Rym: which people all the people I mean all our friends who have been so.
Rym: most of The FRC over time has decided to bail on all the concept of conventions.
Rym: They basically like.
Rym: they go to cons and they like them but as soon as they encounter any amount of difficulty or resistance at all, like PAX East as soon as Badges sold out within a couple days Not even now and it's like instant.
Rym: They all bailed 100% and they only go to mag fest because they can buy badges now.
Rym: worry about it.
Rym: now that mag fest is Selling out.
Rym: I'll bet a lot of them start bailing on mag fest.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Ah I think PAX Unplugged is they're all going to PAX Unplugged now.
Scott: And I think this is all going to PAX Unplugged.
Scott: I haven't heard anyone except the hardcore.
Rym: Go Joe's going.
Rym: George is going.
Rym: people are going.
Scott: It's not everyone.
Rym: I think a lot of a lot.
Rym: I think of why a subset of everyone that is a majority is going to go to PAX Unplugged.
Rym: But I think starting next year.
Rym: Most of them will bail when it starts selling out.
Rym: I might still not sell out for two years.
Scott: I don't think PAX Unplugged is gonna sell.
Rym: even pecs out isn't really selling out Yeah, but pecs out is also far away from population centers.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Uh, I mean, I think 20 million people can take a short train ride to get to PAX Unplugged.
Rym: The problem with PAX Unplugged is solely that pretty much 99% of anyone I talked to who is really into tabletop Has never heard of PAX Unplugged and a lot of them have never even heard of a pecs in general.
Rym: So there's still that barrier of just people don't know things about things.
Rym: But even like pecs people don't seem to know that PAX Unplugged not only is happening but like is this year.
Rym: I don't know what they can do about that Like advertise or something like.
Rym: I don't know if pecs is ever advertised.
Scott: No, never.
Rym: I've never seen an ad for pecs.
Scott: I think they put local ads like, you know, the things on the street lights and shit.
Rym: yeah, but I will be a PAX Unplugged doing a bunch of stuff and pecs prime and PAX West.
Rym: I'm actually planning my PAX West or my pecs Australia trip currently Cuz.
Rym: I'm gonna go to go to a thing in Sydney and then I'm gonna go to pecs the next weekend in Melbourne.
Rym: You gonna come?
Rym: Hmm So Mario Kart I actually skipped because I didn't buy a Wii U Wii U Wii U. I never had Mario Kart 8.
Rym: I've only ever played Mario Kart 8 at other people's houses.
Rym: the Mario Kart I have played the most in my entire life is Probably still the one on the 3ds cuz.
Rym: I played the ever-living hell.
Scott: out of that Mario Kart I played the most in my whole life is Mario Kart Super Circuit for the GBA.
Scott: the best Mario Kart there ever was and still Probably gonna ever be is I mean it was good for its era.
Rym: I really liked the regular DS one until it was broken.
Scott: Well, this is a Super Circuit Mario Kart, right?
Scott: I've said this before but I'm gonna say it again It's not better because it's got like the most of the best courses or the most characters.
Scott: It's like it's lacking and like all of these areas that you would usually judge a Mario Kart.
Scott: The only thing that makes it the best Mario Kart is the most important thing which is that it is 100% skill based racing.
Scott: Yes, it still has items like the blue shell.
Scott: However in Mario Kart Super Circuit if you drive fucking perfectly like you don't touch a wall even a little bit I feel like you've said these exact words.
Rym: episodes of geek now.
Scott: Yes If you don't even let go of a for a fraction of a second the accelerate button if you drift perfectly around every single turn always getting blue sparks if you do all of these things in this game and Blue shell is on your ass that blue shell will remain on your ass without actually touching you.
Scott: And if you continue for a long enough time Eventually, the blue shell will be like this guy's too good.
Scott: Fuck it and just give up on you until another blue shell gets fired.
Scott: yeah, right and that makes it a Skill based racing game yet still has the fun of the items and whatnot, right?
Scott: So You know all.
Rym: there's a lot of modern ones like you can just say like shells only and stuff Hold on.
Scott: so in Super Nintendo Mario Kart, it just you know, it's the controls are kind of if you play it now, right?
Scott: It's not it's got problems.
Rym: Yeah Like f-zero on the SNES is a way better racing game.
Scott: Mario Kart 64 has a lot of problems like rubber banding and glitches and messed up maps and all good.
Scott: It's this the jankiest of all the Mario Karts, right?
Scott: the DS 1 Snakey-snakey big problem.
Scott: Yes without without snakey great It was great, but it did have the.
Scott: it lacks the perfect skill, right?
Scott: The blue shell will still just hit you no matter what pretty much right?
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time If you were good I could be so far ahead even against like real legit people that the blue shell didn't matter.
Scott: and can I go far ahead without snaking?
Rym: well play to win the game, but that was also the game that probably had the Tightest ghost community of going after those ghosts, right?
Scott: But anyway, the Mario Kart 8 Deluxe is actually the Wii U Mario Kart re-released on the switch except a. Everything's unlocked in terms of characters and maps right from the beginning.
Scott: Yeah, unlike any of that shit The only thing that's not unlocked is a bunch of hats and nonsense is carrot is car parts.
Scott: So it's like and you get the car parts just by getting coins.
Scott: So if you just play the game a bunch You're just gonna unlock those things as you go and it's like you'd be surprised how fast you unlock.
Scott: shit.
Scott: It's like every other race.
Scott: We're getting we're unlocking something because it's only a hundred coins.
Scott: So in a particular in one race, you're gonna go three laps.
Scott: You're gonna get like maybe up to 30 coins per one person if you get two people racing like 60 coins in one race.
Scott: Yeah, like you get I'm already like thousands and thousands of coins collected with tons and tons of stuff unlocked.
Scott: I don't even care.
Rym: I played maybe an hour of this game total.
Scott: So yeah, it's not me, right?
Scott: So this I think Mario Kart 8 Deluxe I don't.
Scott: I never played Mario Kart 8 So I don't know too much of the other differences besides the fact that everything's and it feels pretty much the same, right?
Scott: But I can tell you that of all the Mario Kart's I've played Mario Kart 8 Deluxe is the second best Mario Kart and this is why Even though first of all tons and tons of maps you got 12 times 4.
Scott: I think it's 48 maps No 12 times 4 12. yeah, 48 maps.
Scott: That's a lot of maps, right?
Scott: You got a bunch of battle modes.
Scott: We'll talk about those later, but at least I mean they're there.
Scott: So I guess it's better than them not being there no matter how bad they are.
Rym: I'd pretty much rather them not be there because I think they've always been terrible.
Rym: I have this.
Rym: more is better.
Scott: even you know more is never less.
Rym: So I think most battle modes in games like this Existed solely because there was an error where people had like Super Nintendo or an n64 or something.
Rym: but the vast majority of gamers did not have gaming computers and internet to be able to play.
Rym: like Modern FPS is online because there were just like real badly games online with computers people.
Scott: really I don't think Mario Kart battle mode exists because FPS is we're on PC, but people really wanted to play in general.
Scott: like No connection between FPS is being better on PCs and Mario Kart battle mode.
Rym: Here's something I noticed of all my friends from my entire childhood the only people who ever ever played battle mode in Mario karts and professed to enjoy it were the same people who played a lot of 007 and professed to enjoy it and none of them owned a gaming PC at any point in my childhood.
Rym: Anyone who had a gaming PC and internet never played any of this nonsense.
Scott: Anyway, we'll talk about battle mode later, right?
Scott: They're there.
Scott: All right How many characters.
Scott: I can't even count the characters this so fucking many.
Scott: There's a lot.
Scott: any character you want is gonna be one there and they are all for the most part different.
Scott: So yeah, great King boo, though cannot take.
Rym: I have not even tried to check if there's a Pareto frontier here or not.
Scott: It might be Bowser.
Scott: I think right and this has so in this in just even in the non battle modes You got your 50 CC.
Scott: Yeah, 100 CC.
Scott: Yeah, you're 150 CC.
Scott: You got your mirror mode, which is 150 CC But all the maps got flipped backwards and you got I think this might not be in Mario Kart 8 200 CC Did it doesn't matter you still have 200 CC Whether it's new or not.
Scott: It's there.
Rym: So the only difference between 150 and 200 is you can you have to break in 200 200 is lit.
Scott: That's like the real deal is my you know it.
Scott: 200 if you didn't have items would be f-zero just with a different skin on it.
Scott: Really when you think about it There's even an f-zero map in this game.
Scott: Some people are actually questioning whether you can still call the game Mario Kart.
Scott: They posted a screenshot of like a splatoon character driving like You know some car.
Scott: that's not a Mario car On a Zelda map and it's like there's not Mario anywhere on the screen at all.
Scott: Why is this Mario Kart?
Scott: Mario Kart is because well no matter what you still have like mushroom and turtle shells your items, right?
Rym: Now it's interesting that probably that the the thing that a lot of you probably don't realize Unless you've read about this game You probably wouldn't notice it even if you own it and played it a lot is that by default it has auto-aim.
Scott: Alright, so you have to really pay attention to this.
Scott: There's three options that you can choose when you're playing and it lets you choose them on a player by player basis Which is good.
Scott: Option one is auto-steer.
Scott: Now auto-steer is good that it's there.
Scott: I think it's bad that it's on by default, but it's good that it's there, right?
Scott: And this is because let's say you're playing with someone who sucks ass or a child or a child or someone who?
Scott: has disability or who knows what right.
Scott: you can just freaking hold a and you it'll turn for you so you can just pay attention to like the item shooting and Not have to worry about steering and staying on the track so much and you can basically get all the fun of the fun parts of Mario Kart.
Scott: and your lack of skill won't cause you to like Cry because you're falling off the track constantly.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: However, you get punished for choosing this option.
Scott: You won't beat.
Scott: people are actually good at Mario Kart because a you will not allow you to take shortcuts.
Scott: Like if you try to go towards a shortcut, it's like new it's like no that's going off the track.
Scott: And that's how I Figured out.
Scott: I didn't realize this option was there to begin with.
Scott: I figured it out because like how come I can't go on this Fucking shortcuts.
Scott: I was going straight at it.
Scott: How did this happen?
Rym: Oh my god I found out because someone tweeted explaining it and then I found some reddits where all these people were like Mario Kart broken and they didn't understand why and they didn't know this option existed.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, so you want to turn this off for real Mario Kart, but it's good that it exists.
Scott: I just don't think it should be on by default, but that doesn't matter so much.
Scott: option to motion controls Instead of regular stick control.
Rym: theoretically they could be better than they've been on any Nintendo console to date.
Scott: I have heard a rumor.
Scott: I'm not sure how what the details are.
Scott: I think it's still being investigated.
Scott: I haven't seen like absolute confirmation that if you choose motion controls you have 100 it overrides your car stats and gives you perfect traction.
Scott: Why to make up for your use of motion control if that's true?
Scott: I've also heard a rumor that you could choose motion control and still steer with the stick And I guess you as long as you keep perfectly still you won't fuck yourself up with the motion control.
Rym: So I gotta get a vice to mount the pro controller in Right.
Scott: So you would choose a car lay set up that is really low traction and really high other things Yeah, and then choose motion control to get perfect traction.
Scott: If this is true, we don't know yet.
Rym: We're still Already now into the mode of spreading rumors, right?
Scott: Okay, but you can choose to either use motion controls or not Which is fun because you can get that car steering action going on right which is fun for certain people But it's off by default, which is good.
Scott: Option three and this is one that's the most debated auto accelerate.
Scott: if you choose this option Basically, the game will just hold a for you the whole time.
Rym: You don't have to hold a which I generally hold a almost all the time, right?
Scott: But it's like when do I not want to hold a?
Scott: almost never.
Scott: so it's like oh, it's just.
Scott: is that really bad?
Scott: We don't know if there's any downside to picking this but it's like people both, you know on the side of you know Not high skilled people just you know, wanting to make the game easier and more fun can choose this option.
Scott: just fine.
Scott: But also pro people are like trying this option be like hey Why should I sit there holding the a button?
Scott: I can occupy my finger like just using the brake and not Worrying about the item button at all the accelerate button at all.
Scott: Yeah, right and it's like that's kind of good, right?
Scott: What's the downside of this auto accelerate?
Scott: why not put it on?
Rym: so the way I typically play cuz I you know I played mostly the 3ds one, but you know when I'm going for ghosts or anything I will often let go of a and kind of feather it on certain corners, but I never touch the brake.
Rym: This might cause 200 CC.
Scott: You gotta use water CC.
Rym: I'm feathering the brake.
Scott: Yeah But anyway, so yeah this this third option of auto accelerate deserves some amount of experimentation and investigation To see whether like if you just get used to not holding a like that could actually be an improvement.
Scott: if there's no hidden downside Like, you know if the hidden downside of the the auto steering is you can't take shortcuts and you can't get Pink's boost.
Scott: You can only get you know, blue sparks and orange sparks.
Rym: You can't get the third level of drip boost sparks Yeah, and if you try to like doesn't really really tight drift, it'll push you away from.
Scott: yeah But there's no there's seemingly no downside from the auto accelerate yet that we know of Okay.
Scott: So the other thing in this game is the items.
Scott: There's a few items.
Scott: I haven't seen before in Mario Kart There's.
Rym: you haven't played modern Mario Kart.
Scott: There's a boomerang which is like whatever It's.
Scott: it's an item you get when you're in the middle of the pack.
Scott: That's like a reusable green shell kind of.
Scott: I guess It's real dangerous.
Scott: There's a. there's a the piranha plant which is you can eat other people to hurt them.
Scott: Yeah, but it also you keep jamming a and it.
Scott: except you keep jamming the item button It accelerates you a little bit when it lunges forward.
Scott: That's an okay item.
Scott: The biggest difference that I see that I really like is that if you're away at the front and you're gonna get blue shelled Obviously the game gives you shit.
Scott: items like coin.
Scott: Yeah green shell banana peel.
Scott: That's pretty much it, right?
Scott: But it also will occasionally give you this Oh horn it's like Bob right and it basically is like a AoE effect that originates on you and only goes in a very small radius.
Scott: Right, it's basically the radius of a blue shell explosion.
Scott: and what it does is it messes up other drivers But you're in first place.
Scott: That's useless, right?
Scott: But it can also destroy items that are about to hit you.
Scott: and I like this because let's say a blue shell is coming.
Scott: If you've got the horn you've been saving it and you use it with perfect timing You can actually destroy the blue shell and defend yourself.
Rym: But that means you've got to have the luck of having gotten the horn.
Scott: You got to have the horn.
Scott: you have to not lose the horn But to like a lightning or something.
Scott: You have to have the horn when the blue shell is coming and use it with precision skill at the right time.
Scott: Also, you can hold shells and banana peels behind you to block shots that are coming up on you.
Scott: So it's not as good a super circuit where just perfect driving is enough to guarantee that you're safe.
Scott: But you can.
Scott: you know, if you're driving you're getting a ton of items.
Scott: You can also get like double items for these double question blocks.
Scott: So you're gonna have enough items to defend yourself.
Scott: So with enough skill you are going to win the vast majority of Mario Kart races.
Scott: You don't really have to worry too much about getting.
Scott: you're gonna occasionally get blasted by like blue shell lightning bolt red shell Right at the finish line.
Scott: Yeah, but I've been.
Scott: I played a lot of Mario Kart so far.
Scott: I played all the 50 cc's got gold cups all the 100 cc's got gold cups and I'm working on the 150s.
Scott: now I'm getting gold cups still and that bullshit at the like end of race multiple item hit has only happened One time in all those races.
Scott: because so I've been able to defend myself right and prevent a lot of that going on.
Rym: So in terms of the items student for the randomness the options are a little bit changed.
Rym: I found a list of all the changes between the games.
Rym: But when you choose the set of options to use in multiplayer you have options like frantic items Yeah, or more very important skilled items.
Rym: Yeah, I do say skill items only.
Scott: I do like the multiplayer.
Scott: really lets you customize Exactly what's gonna be used or not used.
Scott: right, you know, you know.
Scott: CPUs no CPUs.
Rym: CPUs use special Like playing this game with no items like that.
Rym: There's a time and a place for that.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's basically f-zero right and we might do that until f-zero comes out for the switch.
Scott: But f-zero hasn't come out for the switch.
Scott: So we might choose that option.
Rym: but I do prefer generally to play with items.
Scott: Yeah items are I mean, especially the skill items green shell banana peel, right?
Scott: It's like there's no bullshit in those.
Scott: You have to actually aim and hit someone with the green shell and they can defend themselves and they can dodge it.
Scott: They got a rearview mirror.
Scott: they get right banana peel.
Scott: It's like well, don't fucking run over the banana peel You won't have a fucking problem, right?
Scott: It's a skill based item Right only like the red shell the blue shell the lightning and even the lightning is not so bad because it hits literally everyone.
Scott: So if you're in first, well, you know that the guys in second third fourth fifth also all got hit with lightning.
Scott: You're not gonna get boned by that right, you know, it would be bullshit If only first place got lightning, but that's not it's not it's just an equalizer.
Scott: It slows everyone down except for one person and they're not getting anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: They're not catching up.
Rym: So in terms of actual like gameplay like it is definitely, you know, every Mario Kart sort of replaces the previous one.
Rym: It's not like Smash Brothers where the like Tournament scene just seems to like keep every version around forever and have their own separate tournaments and it's not like a Mario Tennis Situation where they literally ruin the game.
Scott: Yeah, where they make the game less good in the newer very now.
Scott: I was worried before the switch was announced and came out that Mario actually but in a way they did make it less good But they made less good an option like you can choose less good or choose not less.
Rym: Well, that is exactly it because when they released on the 3ds Mario Tennis, they literally made it bad and to this day I think we're the only people who pointed that out in a review what they did.
Scott: No one even understands Nobody's analyzing Mario Tennis to the level of speedrunner types.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I don't think you can really do a Mario Tennis speedrun for those of you.
Scott: Maybe we should.
Rym: well.
Rym: for those of you unaware the Mario Tennis was a game of positioning and timing and Like decision like what kind of attack to do like aiming those attacks.
Rym: So you could move to a spot and you could hit the button and your character would try to hit the ball Exactly when you hit the button.
Rym: and there was other stuff you could do.
Rym: obviously In the Mario Kart on the 3ds Mario Tennis Mario Tennis.
Rym: What they did is they made it to where?
Rym: When you hit the button has no impact on when your character hits the ball.
Scott: As long as you hit as long as you press the hit correct button As long as you press the correct button within the timing window You're gonna hit the ball in Mario.
Scott: in previous Mario Tennis It mattered where within the timing window you hit the ball.
Scott: It would hit the ball differently.
Rym: Yeah Like you made it less complex Like you would do crazy crap like be up and up to the net and just like BAM BAM Just like swatting things down.
Rym: if you were skilled you could pull that kind of stuff off.
Rym: They got rid of all that and made the game Literally worthless from a competitive standpoint.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I was worried after that that Mario that in general Nintendo competitive games are gonna go down that road.
Scott: No, they made it optional in this.
Rym: Mario Kart, which is Mario Party's kind of went down that road too, even though they're already way down that road Party is already a random game.
Rym: Yeah, but they kept going down that road.
Rym: But Mario Kart 8 game for Mario Party is pretty legit because it has that option to be kind of baby mode.
Scott: It also has the option to be super real mode.
Scott: you can play 200 CC no items, let's go.
Scott: Yeah, just super hardcore.
Rym: Yep, 200 CC when you're playing without items is basically real talk.
Scott: It's basically f-zero Right.
Scott: and you know the environments in on the maps of Mario Kart are crazy and you might say well That's not f-zero f-zero right, but it's like actually f-zero maps are kind of crazy, too.
Scott: They don't have obstacles and shit necessarily, but you know what?
Scott: The environment affects all the racers equally like you go to a golf course and it's raining.
Scott: well It's like well, it's raining on everybody.
Scott: It's not you know, so I think it's totally cool.
Scott: I like mini golf style.
Scott: I don't think that makes it anti-competitive in any way.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you hit the moo moo cow and I didn't.
Scott: that's your problem.
Scott: Don't hit it next time suck you suck at driving.
Rym: So I feel like I'm gonna play this a lot and I'll just retire the 3ds one because literally no reason ever play that version.
Scott: Yeah, I think this is not like you.
Scott: if you got a switch you're gonna have this Mario Kart, right?
Scott: It's gonna be your game And you can play with four switches and two people per switch erratically, right?
Scott: But I when you do split-screen, it's hard to play not because you're small real estate But because you have a narrow field of view.
Scott: There are a lot of times I was like messing up turns because I couldn't see where I was going Screen because I couldn't see too far to left and right.
Rym: Yep Nothing, but the real problem.
Rym: and we ran into this.
Rym: we were playing it today.
Rym: This is the first time we did multiplayer just to check the game out.
Rym: My switch kept disconnecting.
Scott: Yeah, like constantly but any when it was doc any Nintendo wireless thing ever has never had good connection.
Scott: I've always had connection issues.
Rym: I got real good.
Scott: Yes, the 3ds everything always had wireless connection issues.
Rym: I got real good at the 3ds Mario Kart and I also played a lot of 3ds like Smash Brothers.
Rym: I have never been able to play any Sustained number of games of either of them with other human beings because it just disconnects Constantly even in play even not at just the conventions were taught.
Scott: too many people are trying to use it.
Scott: Right, we're talking about anywhere like in your house in the quiet my apartment.
Rym: That doesn't even get cell service from the outside.
Rym: By switch was a few feet away from Scott and I was sitting on the couch playing on the TV and it just kept.
Scott: We think it might be because his was docked and mine wasn't.
Scott: once he undocked it seemed to work.
Scott: as soon as I undocked Zero disconnect.
Scott: It's still you know, it's still shaky right?
Scott: Nintendo Wireless is always shaky.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: the worst was I went to PAX Australia the last time and I was there by myself like I had a bunch of friends in Australia like the awesome crew but there was a bunch of time and I was like by myself and I thought oh I'll go to the concerts and just play smash with people.
Rym: So I go to the concerts I lay in a beanbag.
Rym: I'm hanging out and there's a bunch of people with the SS and none of them play smash and they're saying Oh, yeah, it's nothing can connect.
Rym: We're all just playing single-player games.
Rym: So I rallied everyone like yeah, let's just try it Let's make it work and it does not work at all.
Scott: So that's the thing.
Scott: Yeah, but there's online play the online play, you know Lag varies based on who you're playing against.
Scott: but Nintendo online play is free on the switch right now But it's gonna become non free at some point.
Scott: I will I think that online play is gonna just be a non starter Have to see how if it's worth paying for like how much do you actually use it, right?
Rym: I am confident that it will not be worth paying for.
Scott: I don't think I'm gonna pay for it cuz I can the we.
Scott: I played Like dr.
Scott: Mario online a few times and it's like they were.
Scott: just you know, it was not as sustainable on the switch.
Rym: We tried to play Bomberman online and like the idea of netcode does not seem to exist on Nintendo consoles Like there's like it the way lag Interacted with us at least in that Bomberman which obviously is a very small sample size
Scott: did patch it recently though So we haven't tried it.
Rym: Yeah But the lag acted like PC games acted in the 90s with lag as opposed to how PC games in 2017 act with lag.
Rym: Yeah, or how tribes who acted with lag in the early 2000s?
Scott: You could play tribes to online if 56 came out.
Scott: It would work.
Scott: Well, it wasn't great.
Rym: It was totally playable.
Scott: You could play.
Rym: you would have trouble if you were in like an intense spin fuser battle But if you were near other players or if you're playing like normal game, it worked pretty well.
Rym: Yeah, but this Mario Kart is The Mario Kart and I feel like because the switch is like it is a legit console like it's real.
Scott: You should probably buy it and Nintendo has done re-releases of their games before right?
Scott: It's like they'd like Wind Waker HD and stuff like that.
Scott: It's like Mario Kart 8 Deluxe.
Scott: It's like oh they just re-released this old this game that already exists this game that exists on the Wii U.
Rym: that none of you.
Scott: Right, there's no reason you don't skipping the Wii U was the smart move.
Scott: I was smart.
Scott: I am so smart.
Scott: I bought the switch instead of the Wii U. I made a good move.
Scott: and now here's Mario Kart.
Scott: So so here's all those games.
Scott: just like I said, aha I was so sure that you know, the switch should be backwards compatible with the Wii U. But it wasn't.
Scott: but hey, they were releasing the Wii U games to the switch pretty much immediately.
Scott: Yeah, so there you go.
Rym: Like here's the history of me and Nintendo consoles.
Rym: It was NES SNES.
Rym: I skipped the n64 we had the GameCube Then I got DS GBA DS 3DS switch and I skipped everything else.
Scott: I had a Game Boy Color DS.
Rym: I did get a Game Boy But we got the Game Boy way later.
Rym: We actually had a Game Gear first and the Game Gear was mine and the Game Boy was my brother's.
Scott: As soon as the next handheld one.
Scott: I mean, I've got every handheld right after the Game Boy.
Rym: I never got another portable Nintendo console until the GBA.
Scott: Anyway, so but you one thing I wanted you talked about before is Mario Party Even though Mario Party is his baby game Mario Party on the switch.
Scott: just one of them Whichever one comes first is gonna be one at some point.
Scott: Yeah, that's gonna.
Scott: you just gotta get that one, right?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We'll see Mario Party 9 or 10 or 11 whatever number it is.
Rym: I looked at some of the minigames and more recent Mario parties and I just feel like Mario Party is not for me.
Scott: I feel like a Mario Party but on switch could be so lit though.
Rym: I feel like Mario Party.
Rym: We could.
Rym: I could only play it if we were actually streaming it and treating it more like a variety show But not that the actual game.
Scott: I think on the switch.
Scott: I think they could revive it for like one more.
Scott: go We'll see.
Rym: The last time I thought it was portable.
Scott: you could just plop it on a table and start playing it and you hand out the mini Joy-cons.
Scott: and true.
Scott: Yeah, as long as you don't Joy cons have motion stuff in them and you can get.
Scott: you know, they can get great.
Rym: But case in point Wario where they only made one good one and it was the one on the game of cube, right?
Scott: But imagine like we're sitting at someplace Sitting around the switch and everyone's got joy con and you see it's like the Nintendo finger minigame.
Scott: go It's a good time.
Rym: Yeah, but they could have done that with Wario where they never did In fact, they released Wario where in the early days pretty sure there is a Mario Party on the Wii U. So, you know then who talks about it?
Scott: What do you heard of which is like built for Mario Party?
Scott: Come on.
Rym: Yeah, the switch is built for Wario where and they're never gonna make a good Wario where.
Rym: I would I will eat my hat if They make a good Wario where.
Scott: I think I do think the department at Nintendo that made like the second tier quirky games Has somehow disappeared?
Rym: Yeah And I wish it would come back because that the game the game cube era Remains like Nintendo's most innovative era.
Scott: right during the game of cube days and the you know GVA days like there was a lot of these like quirky not prime time top tier Nintendo games Like they were producing on publishing all these second tier games that you know We're still official Nintendo games, but they were and they were great and awesome But no one paid too much attention to them, right?
Scott: There was that one where the guy was like the plug on his head and it was a whole bunch of Wario games.
Scott: yeah, like What's the other one I had like something the the robot battling things.
Scott: that game wasn't that good, you know The Pikmin's right, you know now they're coming out some Pikmin platformer right now There were a bunch of Kirby games like the canvas curse and the DS and like all these You know, I'd be second tier Nintendo games.
Scott: I feel like those don't really exist right now.
Scott: I like the Mario Superstar saga.
Scott: We're having all those games.
Rym: So the only other thing is I guess we can actually talk about the battle mode.
Rym: It is probably the best battle mode that's ever existed in a Mario still garbage.
Scott: Yeah, it's not great But as a balloon fight where you drive around the track and if you get hit five times You die and you lose.
Scott: but it's really judging you based on how many people balloons you break on other people.
Scott: It's like I ran around and barely got hit.
Scott: But I also didn't really hit me which is good because usually you complain about me.
Rym: in any game like that is where's Rym hide In the corner.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, there's a mini-map.
Scott: you can see where everyone's hiding.
Rym: Oh, yeah, come get me I'll go to the other corner, right?
Scott: Well, you just got to drive fast.
Rym: There's a bomb blast which is the exact same thing except people only have a bombs.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much and it's judging you based on your kills.
Scott: But and if you die completely you lose three of your kills.
Scott: There's a coin one which is like collect coins and like collect the most Coins and you can hit people and they lose their coins and then you get more coins.
Rym: It's yeah.
Scott: Yeah There's one that was slightly interesting which is the cops and robbers.
Rym: one Yeah, but they do not do a mirror match which I think is bullshit.
Scott: It's a. six people are cops.
Scott: effectively in six people are about renegades.
Scott: They said I was like renegades and something else.
Scott: the cops have piranha plants the cops all have piranha plants and the renegades have nothing.
Scott: It's just get away It's just don't get caught by the people with piranha plants and the piranha plant.
Scott: people try.
Scott: it's two teams.
Rym: Well, it's a kid's game.
Rym: It's not six eggs It's jail tag or whatever kids would call that where if you get tagged got to go to jail.
Rym: But if someone gets to the jail they can let everybody out.
Scott: I couldn't figure out where the jail was or anything.
Scott: I just ate a few people with my piranha plant and then it ended.
Rym: Yep, I got.
Scott: it ended pretty good jailed.
Rym: You're literally just driving around in this tiny jail.
Scott: It ended pretty quickly.
Scott: I think because we put their whole team in jail.
Rym: Yeah, it was me and Scott were the only humans were playing with a eyes and they're not great.
Scott: There's one other mode which is the shine mode which is basically king of the hill.
Scott: you get there's a shine on the map you Get it now you have it until you lose it by getting it smacked out of you I guess and you hold on to it for a long period of time and you're getting points.
Scott: as you hold it and if you reach Certain number of points the game ends and you win and then second place is whoever held it.
Scott: the second long.
Rym: Yeah, you basically get points in the you know, the tournament or whatever you're doing by how long you did it.
Rym: So it does reward the person who was in first the whole time and just got robbed at the end.
Scott: Yeah, they come in second.
Scott: But it's like I got it immediately held on to it for what I think was almost enough to win based on the score and then it got stolen from me by a CPU and they held it long enough to win and then it was over.
Scott: and It's kind of boring.
Rym: Yep But I think the verdicts in like the part point of this isn't necessarily do a deep deep deep review.
Scott: It's like they just shove the battle mode in there because I guess people out there like battle mode.
Scott: But we don't like battle mode, but the racing mode is worth your money.
Scott: You just ignore the battle.
Rym: The moral is the switch is a legit Nintendo console.
Rym: and now there's the second round of first party games coming out.
Rym: There's a reason to buy one.
Scott: still round one.
Rym: Well, I mean they staggered it such that you've pretty much only had breath of the wild.
Scott: Still round one.
Rym: Yeah, but this came out.
Rym: I mean look it came out way to.
Scott: round two is gonna.
Scott: I there might be a round two before the holiday season But I feel like holiday season is actually round two.
Scott: There might be a summer round two, maybe Maybe but the holiday season is when that Mario game comes.
Scott: that's real.
Scott: round two for sure Yeah, or round three if they somehow make a big summer release.
Rym: But uh, I'm not saying that Nintendo is back to the buy side on the scene for me because they know I didn't buy this.
Rym: Which way?
Rym: right away I waited to see.
Scott: But I think I'm just gonna buy all the first-party games as they come out and Once you already buy the console, you're not getting your money's worth unless you buy games.
Rym: Yeah, I've got every first-party game, but I'm not even gonna wait to see Progress fee for the apartment.
Scott: You better live there a fucking long time.
Scott: You buy a switch you better start buying a lot of switch games.
Scott: Otherwise you wasted your money on that switch.
Scott: Yeah, unless you sell it.
Rym: so It's not really relevant to Mario Kart, but I am buying every game digital and that is a 100% policy.
Scott: Don't buy any cartridges now.
Rym: Digital distribution sucks because one you can't back up your save files and two It doesn't see like.
Rym: basically you can't eat.
Rym: like if you buy another switch, you can't transfer your games not easily.
Scott: Anyway, there
Rym: doesn't seem to be any way to do it but to get Nintendo to do
Scott: it and Was able to transfer and when I had a Wii which also had the same problem and my Wii was stole I was able to get all my games back on the new week.
Rym: I feel like there's no good process for that and you lose all your save games.
Rym: You can't even back save games up on the SD card.
Rym: They're tied intrinsically to the hardware with no way out Unless someone hacks it and I feel like Nintendo is never gonna fix that.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Scott: Yeah I mean, it's definitely got DRM and lockdown and problems But it's just like well the convenience of not using the slow loading cartridges and having to have these tiny cartridges that you lose.
Scott: Yeah, it's like well just fuck it.
Rym: And yeah, you might be saying but Rym and Scott I want to lick the cartridge.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: It tastes like ass.
Rym: It tastes like the things But everyone else is Smelling that bamboo going.
Scott: Oh, it smells horrible.
Scott: and it came over to me.
Scott: Scott smell the bamboo Fuck.
Scott: now get that shit away from me.
Scott: and thus Disaster get that shit away from me.
Rym: I Remember to this day.
Rym: I see you in slow motion going fuck.
Rym: You make a motion like this and the bamboo goes up into the air.
Scott: it didn't go that.
Rym: And it spills a tiny bit of that water outside of itself and the room goes.
Rym: That was one of the worst things I've ever smelled my entire life.
Scott: anyway that moment I'm done.
Rym: So yeah by this game, even though pretty sure you will never be able to play this multiplayer at a convention.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Rebecca not Nicholas Brando.
Rym: Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette.
Rym: great job.
Rym: emoji mystati.com.
Rym: William Eisendrose Jeremy minor.
Rym: midichlorians are a microscopic life form that resides within all living cells.
Rym: a genuine bonafide Selectrified six-car monorail the terrible secret of space for to one creations of nothing.
Rym: Shervin von Horl rarely Val James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make Rym safe.
Rym: pickle Sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleicher Thomas and Joe show Joe star Shawn Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Joey Joe Joe jr Shabbat ooh Brian said Roni the space-time vector of an african-european swallow carrying kiwis redacted.
Rym: Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: we recorded the show before the Rangers game.
Rym: It is now after the Rangers game.
Rym: Rangers the hockey's done.
Rym: hockey's dead.
Rym: There's no more hockey and frankly I hope the Predators win the Stanley Cup.
Rym: and now I leave you with.
Rym: We come to the earth which well grew to get here the way it is now.
Rym: Here is our world our planet Earth floating in space.
Rym: We will be going backward in time imperfectly, but done in a very disciplined manner, please Notice there is no subduction no rotation of tectonic plates No twisting no form-fitting no altering shapes or sizes.
Rym: it would be impossible Impossible for these continental plates to fit together perfectly without this being true.
Rym: and yet the upper tectonic plates fit together perfectly on a much smaller planet.
Rym: Yes, there's been some erosion landslides blah blah, but overall this activity is insignificant.
Rym: There is a kind of conspiracy of silence among certain scientists.
Rym: They know but are not telling you that the upper tectonic plates of Earth Also join in the Pacific not partially they join totally.
Rym: you are asked to believe that the continents Swim or drift about willy-nilly Bumping and crashing as if they were on a grease skillet.
Rym: This is not true.
Rym: The simple truth is apparently too upsetting to too many apple carts.