Rym: It's Tuesday February 14th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: raptor the tabletop game not call of the shadows.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Any of you even remember raptor call of shadows me That game.
Rym: I think everyone got it free like a demo of it in a PC gamer Mm-hmm, and I never bought the real game, but I played the hell out of that demo forever.
Scott: I pirated the real game.
Rym: I pirated the real game as well.
Rym: Say it same thing happened with one most fall 2097 Mmm, played the demo forever and then I was like wait a minute.
Rym: There's more to this game.
Rym: Oh It cost money.
Rym: BBS's.
Rym: ah Good times so this morning.
Rym: This is not related to gaming at all But it's it's.
Rym: it's a small anecdote because you know times are tough in the United States and this morning You might have seen my stuff everywhere.
Rym: I uh, where is it?
Rym: Where is?
Rym: is there a place where it's not tough?
Rym: I mean Iceland.
Rym: all the volcanoes are about to go off again.
Scott: I mean even in Finland where things are pretty great.
Scott: It's cold.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, so I mean all the warm places have.
Rym: it's a lot more trouble.
Scott: It's tough.
Scott: It's tough where it's warm.
Rym: Yep So, uh, I ran afoul of a Nazi Just walking down the street.
Scott: So literally I come out of This light was is an actual Nazi who escaped hanging.
Scott: and this is my third wave Nazi, okay You don't see those too often.
Scott: We got most of these.
Rym: I mean, I guess if you got into it really young Some Hitler youth are probably still hanging around.
Scott: But so I got most of them.
Rym: Yeah, so I come out of the building and I'm like my building.
Rym: you go to work and I'm not running late But I have a meeting to get to.
Rym: so there's a time limit.
Rym: So I'm not like I come out of you know you come out of your partner with the mode of you know, all business.
Rym: get where I'm going.
Rym: and As I'm walking up the street from the apartment toward the subway station, I hear this guy whoop like whooping like whoo.
Rym: And then he yells freedom Really loud.
Scott: So he's just a typical street nut.
Scott: No.
Rym: No, I'm ignoring this because you know that happens.
Rym: It's New York.
Rym: It's a street nut, but no keeps yelling it like in a rhythm like freedom.
Rym: That's what we came here for Get all those Muslims out of America Sharia law.
Rym: and he's just like going increasingly like super crazy.
Scott: It's just a nut job.
Rym: Yep He's walking fastily disturbed individual.
Rym: Yeah, but not mentally disturbed in the typical way of a someone yelling on New York streets.
Rym: He looked like he was trying to like do some sort of activism a little sign.
Rym: He was wearing fatigues.
Scott: I mean, I've seen gentlemen of this nature Obviously and he's getting increasingly Nazi.
Rym: ask now I wasn't really in a position to just like attack him Like it wasn't.
Rym: he's not like he wasn't.
Rym: be like me wearing these happy in a crowded subway station.
Scott: What do you do?
Rym: No, we're on the street.
Rym: I haven't gotten to the subway station.
Rym: Okay so he's yelling and All New Yorkers are given the like.
Rym: people are making eye contact walking toward the subway station standing in the light like this guy Mm-hmm.
Rym: So just as I'm going up in the subway station, I just yell over my shoulder.
Rym: Shut up you fucking Nazi.
Rym: and This dude just engaged.
Scott: Why'd you do that?
Rym: So this other dude just starts laughing Because he's around the corner and I hear the Nazi because I already went around like up Walking up the stairs toward the subway and I already hear him yell who said that I'll shut you up.
Rym: Yeah, shut up.
Rym: and he's starting.
Rym: he's getting real agro like who yelled that I'm a green beret.
Rym: Oh, but blah blah blah, but he doesn't know who yelled it.
Rym: Mmm And he's done.
Scott: you managed to engage without engaging.
Rym: Yeah, it was beautiful the snipe from afar and so the most beautiful part.
Rym: and I could not script a more comedic moment because at this point I'm worried I'll figure out where I went and like come charge up and get me.
Scott: So this is the subway entrance right there at Queensborough.
Scott: Yeah, that's stairway the one where police hang out frequently.
Rym: Ah This is where my story concludes with the police.
Scott: That's like, you know The number one place that I see police because they had direct traffic on the corner right there.
Scott: No, there was a does the Dunkin Donuts right there.
Rym: that is like their home And if they're not there, they're in the subway station at that little table.
Scott: They live like right.
Rym: That's like police hang out number one in this neighborhood if they don't want to be caught hanging out at the Dunkin Donuts.
Rym: They get their Dunkin Donuts and they just hang out in the waiting area of Queensborough Plaza.
Rym: Yeah, they're up there.
Rym: So I stop and I stand around the corner just in case you know crazy nut job.
Scott: I would have gone on the bridge and just watch the sidewalk to be like lol Look at this nut.
Rym: so I was going to but pretty quick I hear another voice yell and I'm paraphrasing.
Rym: but the guy basically yelled Dude, shut the fuck up or I'm a sharia law your ass Some.
Scott: so there's another person.
Rym: Yeah an ally and the guy starts getting increasingly agro.
Rym: So I realize now that my he does not know who I am.
Rym: So I keep going.
Rym: I go to the subway station because I'm on my way to work and there's cops sitting there What they literally had Dunkin Donuts like doing their thing.
Rym: So I'm like, there's a crazy guy down there threatening people Mmm, and they're like we'll take care of it.
Rym: and I hate.
Rym: I hate that New York is this way.
Rym: but I was like No, not like the normal Crazy guy on the street, but like, you know Something a little more real.
Rym: and they're like, oh like right now and I'm like, don't you hear that yelling?
Rym: and they're like, huh?
Scott: So they start ambling over there.
Rym: I see this situation.
Rym: I don't know if the guy ended up taking a swing at the cops cuz I went up to get on the subway cuz I Couldn't be late for my shit but there's a small chance that the dude ended up taking a swing and getting arrested and Hopefully
Scott: you weren't looking anymore.
Scott: so you're just making up stuff.
Rym: Yeah The part of the last thing I can verify is the cops went from.
Rym: I'm going to ignore the thing.
Rym: You said to me - oh, yeah There's actually yelling.
Rym: we're gonna go down and look at that.
Rym: and I looked and I saw the cop come around the corner and I See the dude who had yelled at the die at the guy the cool guy Continuing to engage and the yelling guy is getting.
Rym: you know You see someone getting more and more agitated in.
Rym: the arms are moving like this Like he was getting ready to take a swing and that was as the cop was coming down.
Rym: So, I don't know how that whole drama played out.
Scott: Why did you stand on the bridge and watch cuz I had to get to work at a meeting?
Scott: I mean, I got time to get on some Worldstar.
Rym: Well, the thing is the W came and The W is like the fastest way to get to work and it only comes every.
Scott: I think 12 minutes As in 12 minutes is plenty of time to get a Worldstar.
Scott: get the next train dude.
Rym: yesterday on my way to work I found a cop cell phone.
Rym: Okay, so I was in a hurry.
Rym: So I picked up like Oh cop phone.
Rym: I look around.
Rym: There's any cops.
Rym: I just got I went to work and then on the way home I stopped at Grand Central and I went up to the cops at the table.
Rym: I was like, yeah I found this and they're like what where?
Rym: and I was like When on the ground this morning and the do and one of the cops is like, I think that's what's his name's phone.
Rym: I Wasn't gonna do that on the way to work.
Rym: isn't that places to be mmm things to do?
Scott: I mean usually if you find a phone on the ground, which I've had and happened to me in the past I would
Rym: have tried well you can use
Scott: the phone to find the person who owns it
Rym: only if they put their contact info on the lock screen or They call it.
Rym: I Kept it out all day.
Rym: No one called it.
Scott: So yeah one time I found a phone on the ground on like like near Times Square like 40 something Street, right?
Scott: It's a white iPhone it's all cracked.
Scott: it's on the it's in like the gutter but it's working and I just took it and I waited for someone to call it and that didn't.
Scott: I didn't have to wait very long And they're just like yo so-and-so and I'm like saying so and so.
Scott: I found so and so's phone on the ground.
Scott: You might want to find them and tell them to come and get their phone.
Scott: Yeah, and they came and got their phone Yeah, and they tried to give me money that I didn't want because yeah They didn't have much.
Scott: really I could tell this person didn't have a lot of money.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I wasn't gonna take their money Usually been like take that money and buy a case for your.
Scott: I was like take that money and replace the screen on this phone.
Rym: Yeah, see you got any news.
Scott: There is a news.
Scott: So well, it's been a week Nintendo is doing a thing that they never done before which is DLCs.
Scott: it was announced today Our new month the guy who made Zelda put up a video on the Nintendo YouTube channel and they announced that the Zelda game that's coming out for the the Switch the what's it called?
Scott: Breath of the Wild of the wild is gonna have a DLC.
Scott: Here's how it works.
Rym: So I'm assuming I haven't read the details of this but my guess before you actually say well how this works is that it's as Ham-fisted as every other Nintendo thing.
Scott: Uh, I mean, it's not great.
Scott: It's a DLC.
Scott: They're trying to get more money out of you like they do.
Scott: I mean, I'm not.
Scott: it's just like every other Nintendo thing and that they chart.
Scott: they want us milk you a bunch of monies That's overpriced.
Rym: I'm not opposed to the Theory or the like hypothetical of DLC is a concept But in practice tends to be kind of a serious.
Scott: how it's gonna work?
Scott: You're gonna get your Nintendo switch on March 3rd.
Scott: Just like I am cuz you pre-order on Amazon.
Scott: Yeah, you're getting.
Scott: it's gonna come with Zelda.
Scott: cuz you pre-ordered that like every fine adult, right?
Scott: You're gonna on March 3rd You're gonna turn your switch on and play Zelda.
Scott: You're also gonna enter your credit card number in and give them 20 bucks on top of the price that you already paid for Zelda.
Rym: So day one DLC.
Scott: that will get you the following immediately.
Scott: It will add three treasure chests to the game That that contained useful items that already to pay to pay to win in a single-player game and give you some clothing.
Rym: But hey to win and have a hat in a single-player game not done yet.
Scott: Also in when the summer rolls around three When the summer rolls around there's gonna be it.
Scott: There's gonna be a pack number one and you're just gonna get that pack because you paid up front.
Scott: Other people are gonna have to pay that pack separately.
Rym: I'll pack implies more packs down the road, right?
Scott: So you're getting pack number one in the summer, which will include a cave of trials.
Rym: So already there have been things that hold on.
Scott: You're like you're like not let me finish all the stuff you're getting here.
Scott: I'm already.
Scott: it's like this as a whole bunch of stuff You're getting and you're like answering at the first thing.
Scott: All right.
Scott: How do you know?
Scott: The next thing isn't like a real bar of gold.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Is it?
Scott: what is the next thing?
Scott: I'm gonna tell you all the things.
Scott: then you can say it's not enough stuff.
Scott: because guess what?
Scott: It's not enough stuff.
Scott: In the summer you get three things the cave of trials the hard mode and the mysterious Additional map feature.
Scott: Oh and then in the holidays Right, so you're paying 20 bucks in March for something you're getting in December.
Rym: Why don't I just pay 20 bucks in December?
Scott: You're getting a new original story a new dungeon and Additional challenges, yeah, whatever those are Huh?
Scott: So you're paying it.
Scott: So you're basically it's like a season pass deal.
Scott: It's like instead of paying 50 bucks for your Zelda pay 70 and you'll get more Zelda later.
Scott: now on the one hand wait There's two packs though.
Rym: So it's gonna be 90.
Scott: No, you pay 20 bucks for everything.
Scott: for pack 1 and pack in March you pay 20 bucks and that gets you all this shit.
Scott: So if I don't pre-order it though, if you don't pay the 20 bucks in March You might have to buy the packs like separately.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: All right.
Rym: See my worry already.
Rym: Is that Zelda games have had Especially the Gameboy ones like the mobile mobile.
Rym: the the portable ones have had caves of fight stuff.
Rym: We're often shall I say dare to use the word on the only.
Scott: the only thing on this list of stuff that you actually want Is new original story and new dungeon.
Scott: every and maybe new hard mode of a story.
Rym: Is this?
Rym: is this oh my god I lost my chicken.
Rym: you get the chicken and the guy says a line, you know It's at least one whole dungeons worth.
Rym: Yeah, but are we talking a dungeon like the dungeons Zelda 3?
Rym: are we talking a dungeon like what kind of dungeons?
Scott: No one knows.
Scott: it just says new dungeon, right?
Scott: But the point is is that it's a good thing in that I've played like every Zelda game except stupid Majora's Mask.
Scott: And what happens is you play it you have so much fun Like you actually remember to keep playing it when you come home from work the next day.
Scott: Oh, and then you beat it and once you beat it, you're done son You just put that shit in the binder of discs or you stop playing it and that's it.
Rym: And you definitely don't a hundred percent because a lot of you never are.
Rym: not that fun?
Scott: You never open that.
Scott: you never launched that game again.
Scott: Once you beat the final boss.
Scott: It's over, right?
Scott: Except for it's like Zelda 1 right?
Rym: Yeah, maybe Zelda 3 I'll play like a few years.
Scott: You only replay the greatest Zelda's.
Scott: you don't replay these other Zelda's.
Scott: Yeah, like Zelda 2 like for example Skyward sword, right?
Scott: It was great.
Scott: I played it.
Scott: But as soon as it was done is done I never played that again in my whole life.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Maybe when I'm really old if I completely forget it, maybe we had nothing really nothing better to do Unlikely.
Scott: Yeah, so if I'm paying 50 bucks for the Zelda, I'm Expecting it to be Twilight, you know a skyward sword right play it I beat it and then I'm done with it.
Scott: But if they give me a new dungeon, right?
Scott: There's other stuff.
Scott: who gives a shit?
Scott: But it is a new dungeon that makes me turn it on again.
Rym: I would turn on almost any Zelda game that I had beaten if there was like because you're not getting it.
Scott: Yeah, we're not gonna see another new complete Zelda game for like five more years.
Scott: But if they add stuff to the existing one so that I bust out again and get more Zelda That's again, you know.
Scott: who can say that's not good?
Rym: Well, cuz I want that of.
Rym: imagine if the the good Castlevania is that they haven't made in a long time.
Rym: If I could pay 20 bucks and there's just another right side up castle on top of the upside-down castle.
Rym: keep going, right?
Scott: But it's like, you know is 20 bucks too much and not enough?
Scott: and also it's like are you gonna make me ever?
Scott: It's 20 bucks to get me packs forever.
Scott: Or is that holiday pack gonna be the end of it?
Scott: or I'm sure Am I gonna debate 20 bucks in 2018 or you're not gonna put out any more stuff.
Scott: It's a one-time thing.
Scott: It's like how is this gonna go?
Scott: There's not enough info to evaluate whether this is okay or not.
Rym: Okay, right not opposed to this.
Scott: Maybe I should cancel my Zelda pre-order and wait and then in 2018 by the game of the year edition.
Scott: that includes everything.
Scott: However Well, that would be the normal strategy in steam world.
Scott: Nintendo never cuts the price in their games.
Scott: This Zelda game is gonna be 50 bucks in 2020.
Scott: It probably will go down to 40 bucks in 2020.
Scott: It's like oh, it's.
Scott: you know The reprint discount edition.
Rym: Good games were the same price until they were out of stock.
Scott: So it's like you really got.
Scott: you know, you don't have that option of wait for the $10 includes everything.
Scott: edition.
Scott: It's like your choices are pay the 70 pay the 50 don't play.
Scott: or if you wait Who knows what'll even happen if you wait.
Rym: so mystery mystery land Like I'm.
Rym: I don't take a principled stance against this stuff because look at uh, like Adobe software selling
Scott: your real game here
Rym: But I'm happy to pay a monthly fee for software that is continuously updated Like just regularly gets updates for as long as I keep paying
Scott: if it's significant updates.
Scott: But is this?
Rym: but the question is is it worth 20 updates are only one of them is interesting.
Scott: I don't like three chests if you like you were playing Super Nintendo Zelda the best Zelda?
Scott: Yeah, right, you know that game cost 50 bucks in 1990, whatever.
Scott: Yep, four five something like that.
Rym: I would still pay 20 bucks a quarter to this day if that just kept expanding.
Scott: I'm just saying so.
Scott: at that time you beat it when you're a kid on your Super Nintendo.
Scott: you began in the end.
Scott: Would you then immediate immediately have shelled out $20?
Scott: For one more dungeon if it was the same size as like any other dungeon.
Rym: I got like one game a month.
Rym: My parents would not give me 20 bucks just to make one game last longer.
Rym: They'd say play it again.
Scott: so You know if you're playing Zelda, would you pay 20 bucks per dungeon, you know?
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I really love it when there's more dungeons, but am I gonna pay 20 bucks per dungeon per year?
Rym: Here's the other problem.
Rym: Every Zelda game has its scope of interaction like I'm being that dungeon in a day.
Scott: I'm coming home from work and the dungeon will be done before I go to bed.
Scott: Is that worth $20?
Rym: But any given Zelda game to like the universe of things that are possible in a given Zelda game is Limited with humble bundle right now.
Scott: Look at all what it gives you for the humble freedom bundle for $30.
Scott: Yeah Way more than one night of it.
Scott: I mean, I love a Zelda dungeon, but do I love it that much?
Rym: Well, look at Zelda 3 or look at the most recent, you know, the Zelda 3 remake the portable one.
Rym: There's only so many mechanics in that game.
Rym: unless you start drastically changing the game you run out of novel dungeons Like you run out of.
Rym: there's only so many puzzles you can put in a Zelda game.
Scott: Push the rock throw the rock shoot the arrow through the fire.
Rym: Yeah Use some sort of hook or jump or movement to get over an obstacle that you previously couldn't get over.
Scott: Well, this Zelda game is supposed to be more open world ish and less linears and bigger.
Rym: So I can sail forever through an endless sea of nothing.
Scott: So we're gonna see what.
Scott: we're gonna see the reality once it comes out, which is freakishly soon March 3rd.
Scott: It's currently February 14th, and I've already pre-ordered it.
Scott: and March 3rd, it'll be on my doorstep.
Rym: March 3rd, I will be in London.
Scott: All right, I guess you're not gonna be live streaming switch games with me.
Rym: No, not right away.
Rym: And we got packs.
Scott: I'm gonna be that's right March 3rd.
Scott: I'm live streaming switch stuff.
Scott: Yeah, come on over.
Rym: All right, so it's tangential gaming news, but some time ago.
Rym: I warned all of you the PewDiePie was a piece of shit.
Scott: Well, I mean you could tell he was not a good person.
Scott: Like you, you know, you're that guy ometer that you get from going to conventions.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much most YouTube people are not good people.
Scott: I mean it was now.
Scott: I would never if you had asked me at any point in history Once I knew who he was is he good person?
Scott: My answer would have been no.
Scott: So it's interesting because and I kind of I kept that if I know what you know what I found out though Markiplier great guy is a good person.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: mark upon that his fan.
Scott: I'm never gonna watch his shit But markiplier is a good person.
Rym: markiplier never set off my that guy meter But PewDiePie did within less than a second.
Rym: like the pre warning system went off like NORAD was like Ram You're about to see a link to a YouTube channel.
Rym: Watch the fuck out.
Rym: Mmm, but I couldn't like say oh, he's a bad guy just because that guy went off.
Rym: I can just ignore him but a while ago you might recall some time ago He started complaining publicly that YouTube or Google was Minimizing his channel to promote minorities Unfairly.
Rym: Mm-hmm and nonsense like that.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And that was when I publicly started saying no he's a bad dude.
Rym: and now yeah, he's so bad that YouTube canceled his show and Disney severed their relationship with him.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So he's finally going over the deep end and he started.
Rym: basically he's like he's Sharing a lot of white supremacist stuff like straight-up Nazi stuff.
Rym: Hmm is the story?
Scott: So, you know what is true though that if you look at cuz I actually pay attention to like the I follow YouTube creators On Twitter and I why you know, I see YouTube ads in the subway and yeah, dude I'm a member of the Internet creators guild.
Rym: I get a nice letter.
Scott: But anyway, YouTube does do a lot of advertisements for channels that they want to promote like this existing big channels on YouTube.
Scott: you know YouTube creators and YouTube spends money to make ads promoting those people and YouTube itself.
Scott: at the same time and Absolutely, they feature right Women way more often than men.
Scott: good and not white people way more often than white people.
Scott: Fantastic and that's great because we need more not white dudes on YouTube.
Scott: to make it less awful.
Rym: I mean GeekNights, like.
Rym: we're literally two upper-middle-class white dudes doing this in our spare time.
Scott: It's um, I do not I'm Jewish a minority.
Rym: Yeah, dude.
Rym: I'm an atheist I'm the both aces for the most hated minority in America.
Scott: Yeah, if only we were also Muslim Hey not white And didn't have penises.
Rym: But yeah both and me we don't need an entry and PewDiePie also does not need much help especially considering I read this Fascinating essay and there's actually a SciShow like mini episode.
Rym: I think it was SciShow might have been the other ones but it was talking about how if you set up a system that emulates Twitter where any given node will randomly reach retweet like a hundredth of the things that sees a Small number of YouTube accounts of these Twitter accounts will become Massive and viral and the most popular things ever in that fake network of unintelligent actors just by
Scott: math.
Scott: Oh, it's true.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's just by luck.
Scott: Yeah, it'll keep retweeting popular things constantly.
Rym: Anything that gets shared by anyone has a slightly higher chance of getting re-shared again, and you have this Evolution right.
Scott: So instead of making an aggregator that learns and tries to curate you just make a million monkey Aggregators and one of the monkeys will be a terrific aggregator just by chance Yep,
Rym: and a lot of the early YouTube celebrities seemed to mostly have been created by that like that's that that interaction of YouTube had a Recommendation engine and one video got a little more popular than the other ones and the recommendation engine just got to a loop.
Rym: Mmm, I've read a lot of papers talking about that.
Rym: It might be true, but fact remains white dudes don't need any help and PewDiePie's a piece of shit.
Scott: Well, also a lot of those early YouTube specifically right people did things that the you know YouTube thing liked right.
Scott: they posted videos Frequently and such and such.
Rym: Yep So you might have noticed I'm live streaming all the time, but I don't leave them public But I'm playing a lot of overwatch still but I'm just solo queuing competitive.
Rym: I got within like two games of platinum But I fell short and then I had a series of catastrophic games with these randos.
Scott: I mean, you know same thing when I played rocket League, right?
Scott: Yeah, you get on a streak where you get lucky and get paired up with people who are really good and then your rank gets Inflated.
Scott: Yeah, and then you get paired in a game Where you're not so paired with people better than you we're gonna just win the game for you And then you lose a bunch because you can't carry the team and your teammates are worse than you.
Rym: And overwatch once you get out silvers over time
Scott: right the law of averages, you know, you regress to the mean and
Rym: Yeah, yep, but I'm gonna keep doing it because if it I'm just gonna let my competitive score float and kind of see how that Goes for us this season.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that's what you're supposed to do.
Rym: But they also more importantly they added as a special because you know Every time they do an event like they add temporary game modes like all this fun stuff.
Rym: They added capture the flag Like old school capture the flag and the primary lesson I've learned from that is that because overwatch is the spiritual successor to like old CTF and old weapons factory and old team fortress.
Scott: Is it literally a two-fort map?
Rym: No, they use the existing maps for now.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Now if they make a two-fort map, like I don't know what I'll do I think I'll just quit my job and be like just play overwatch.
Rym: If I played it every day Maybe I'll bet.
Rym: if I played every day I can at least make platinum reliably.
Rym: I don't know if I could go beyond that.
Rym: cuz I am old like I'm already way past my physical prime.
Rym: but The competitive the when you're playing this capture the flag mode the thing I've noticed that most overwatch players have clearly Never played the old capture the flag games before.
Scott: why would they have they're so old.
Rym: the result is that when I play?
Rym: Competitive or quick play in the normal game like I'm good and other people are good and other people are better than me I'm gonna capture the flag.
Scott: You're just so great because they're not even messing with the flag and you're like worse than that.
Rym: But many of our friends who play overwatch are way worse than me.
Rym: at normal overwatch.
Rym: Certain people in particular no names being named kind of bad.
Rym: Not that I'm great I mean when I slide stream the people are better than me like Chie will just like send me messages like yeah What are you're playing diva in that map?
Rym: Here's the ten things you did wrong.
Rym: But our friends who are generally bad at overwatch But are our age are fucking amazing at the capture the flag.
Rym: hmm like me and Adam playing capture the flag together It's like capture kept kept kept which way I think.
Scott: I think it's not that you're so great at it.
Scott: It's just that other people are.
Scott: you know when you play capture the flag people are used to just playing FPS's and just trying to kill people.
Scott: right is the watch already isn't like that I mean, but it's like you know.
Scott: it's like the capture the flag objective is Objectively different than every other.
Scott: You know game mode.
Scott: It's like well You're not you just you have six focused on movement and not on fighting.
Scott: you have to go more than that.
Scott: you get to a Place get a flag and get all the way back without being seen or killed or you know whatever.
Rym: But it's also you have to.
Rym: you have six people on your team, and you've got to disperse them Colonel Blotto style between offense and defense.
Rym: And if you mess that up, it's over.
Rym: and almost every game with normal younger overwatch players They all in and draws because everyone's like super defense and doesn't quite get that.
Scott: so over the flag.
Rym: They don't go for the flag hard enough like they can't coordinate because when you play normal overwatch You're either on offense or defense for an entire match.
Scott: I mean even when we play Team Fortress 2 right It's just like yeah the flag.
Scott: it seems so ridiculous like get the flag.
Scott: It's a briefcase in a room in a basement in the way back And you know how the fuck can I even get in there, but you know what I captured the thing all the fucking time.
Scott: Yeah, oh god that right tribes.
Scott: It's on top of a tower right Ridiculously far away with a huge field of mountains in between you and it took you five minutes to fly over there.
Scott: It's on a helipad.
Scott: It's in the middle of a helipad sticking out of a tower ridiculously up in the air in the wide open.
Scott: It's like how can I possibly get there without like being killed?
Scott: grab it go off into the big open?
Scott: non-hidden area in the middle of the sky All the way back across the mountain range to my helipad to win is like how can you even do that?
Scott: And it's like you can do it.
Scott: It's just because the way the game is designed it seems so ridiculous like you don't even attempt it because it's so terrifying and it seems Hopeless, but when you actually try it.
Scott: It's like oh, it's doable.
Rym: Few things I've ever done in gaming are more stressful than having the flag.
Rym: in a like Serious capture the flag game I mean.
Scott: granted when I get the flag more often than not I die and the flag falls on the Ground.
Rym: yep, usually about a foot away from where you got it.
Scott: But I have captured many a flag in my day and really you know when I first started playing those games I didn't capture a lot of flags because I was afraid to go for it.
Scott: and once I was willing to go for it I let you capture it.
Rym: Yeah But anyway things of the day what you got.
Scott: so snakes are cool.
Scott: I like snakes.
Scott: Thanks a pretty good good animal Right cooler than the regular snake.
Scott: to head snake.
Scott: How does ever to head person?
Scott: There are in fact the Siamese twins, but it's not like an actual to head person.
Scott: like.
Scott: well the same way.
Rym: this right here.
Rym: the recommended video on your two-headed snake is Abigail and Brittany Henzel who are famous like super share.
Rym: twins is basically a body with two heads is it really?
Rym: yeah They're cool people.
Rym: I've seen documentaries about them.
Rym: Yeah, baby.
Scott: Yeah, it's close to two head person.
Scott: How could it be more like they got separate brains.
Scott: they talk separately completely separate heads.
Scott: conversation with each other separate personalities.
Scott: Yes, they just hang out who controls the walking.
Rym: uh it's complicated.
Rym: watch the documentary.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: But anyway this two-headed snake is pretty cool because it's two independent heads And they sort of both control the body or whatever and you might think okay.
Scott: I've seen a two-headed snake before.
Scott: It's a video of a two-headed snake.
Scott: What's a big deal.
Scott: this video is special because in this video Both heads of the snake drink water.
Scott: Holy shit, I really wish that I had another mouth hole so I could drink water.
Scott: That would be pretty good.
Scott: like I'm not gonna complain about that one.
Rym: I still think the third arm would be superior.
Scott: the third arm is good because you can go mouse keyboard keyboard and Type and mouse at the same time.
Scott: yeah before arms isn't really useful for anything except for like Goro cosplay.
Scott: I don't really need the fourth arm, but the third arm would be good.
Scott: So I'd rather have the second mouth for more water drinking than the four.
Rym: you know what the fourth arms good for playing that hockey organ.
Scott: Sure, you get like two organs at the same time.
Rym: So somewhat multiple people like link this to me when it was like just for whatever reason.
Rym: everyone knows that this is my jam somehow.
Rym: so no credit to everyone who sent this to me, but Beat of the brakeless bus.
Rym: I saw this is this video of just two people like racing school buses drifting them around and It is set with these subtitles and the music of via the rising sun from initial D And it is way more entertaining than it has any right to be.
Scott: I saw a video like just the other day.
Scott: I don't know where it is I can't you send it to you?
Scott: right now is a kid driving a car.
Scott: his parents are in the car And he drifts around while his parents are yelling that they're like here the keys right now, and he's like That's good stuff, and he's just.
Scott: you know he's drifting pretty great.
Scott: You know and his parents are freaking out.
Rym: Yeah, but it'd be like yeah, I could do it faster.
Scott: Boonta would be like yeah, you suck.
Rym: So The water yeah, so in the meta moment we were at PAX out, and it's totally done.
Rym: It was awesome.
Scott: very soon We're gonna be at PAX.
Rym: Yup, we're doing a rewritten version of an old panel idea We did many years ago called we used to do.
Rym: this panel called how to win at games, so I'm doing like legit research, and I'm learning a lot about trying to upgrade the panel.
Rym: well I'm trying to go deeper with it like I'm trying to go like.
Rym: so we talked about like the gays.
Scott: you're right.
Scott: You ran an idea.
Scott: is he was gonna upgrade the old idea.
Rym: well the old idea was so old that I looked at the structure of it and Remember that panel was written back, and we still use that blue background, so I'm modernizing this panel And it's gonna be a lot more like the quitting panel or the grinding panel, and I've also learned some stuff.
Rym: I found some papers that were not as publicly available back when I wrote that thing.
Rym: in fact many of these things were published After I wrote that panel the first time.
Rym: so we're gonna do play dirty to win on I believe Friday at 6 p.m It's not enough playing dirty to win.
Rym: Yeah the moral is Play to win, and if you follow the rules.
Rym: That's totally okay, and if the rules suck the game sucks You should still play to win mm-hmm and the other part.
Rym: the other moral of that panel is most your friends Probably won't want to play games with you anymore if you actually do what we say.
Rym: Play games with you sure?
Rym: yeah The book club book I still got to decide.
Rym: I'm leaning toward dune Because I never actually read the whole thing.
Rym: You know what fuck it.
Rym: It's dune.
Scott: the next book is dune pro-tip the paper dead tree version of dune is cheaper than the Kindle Version.
Rym: pro tip I have like four copies of the paper edition of dune.
Scott: I'll get around anyone.
Scott: Another pro tip the library is free.
Scott: another pro tip This is a way easy book just get like a used copy for like a dollar.
Rym: another pro tip if you get a library card You can just download ebooks onto your Kindle, and I'm pretty sure you can do that with dune.
Scott: Yeah, this is like when you go for the super popular book like this.
Scott: It's way easy to get like it meant.
Scott: like why isn't it just fucking public domain already.
Scott: It's like Jesus Christ.
Rym: I am very curious to see How my adult sensibilities react to dune which I read some of and stopped reading as a child and I know primarily Through the rules to the dune board game.
Scott: I know it primarily through the board game.
Scott: Yeah pop culture and interactions I've had over the course of my life because everyone else around me like knows everything about well 30-something year old Scott hate it like middle school Scott and now couldn't even get past like a few chapters and remembers nothing.
Rym: and also Will 35 year old Rym who has now read books like the prince of nothing?
Rym: Decide that this isn't dense enough.
Scott: I can guarantee.
Scott: however We will make as many spice jokes as we please which is probably many Will flow.
Scott: the spice jokes will flow.
Scott: that is that is what will happen.
Rym: Also, we will probably you'll the impression I get is we're gonna run into a lot of quotes or a lot of aphorisms that we didn't Realize.
Rym: we're from dune.
Scott: Oh That could be like when I like when we talked about because it's such a because it's such a big sci-fi thing.
Scott: It's probably been referenced a whole bunch and I've missed all those references.
Rym: I'll be like here's the mind killer like that.
Rym: That's all dune like that kind of stuff.
Scott: I mean, I've never heard anyone say that you've never you ever heard someone give the fear litany.
Rym: I mean, it's it's I was playing overwatch Like not that long ago and someone just started typing that into the chat on the team before the competitive match.
Rym: Like that is a widespread litany.
Rym: Mmm Yeah, type fear litany litany against fear dune fandom like first link.
Scott: Never heard of it.
Rym: You've never heard of.
Rym: I must not fear.
Rym: fear is the mind killer.
Rym: No, there is the little death that brings total obliteration.
Rym: Oh, I will face my fear.
Rym: I will permit it to pass over me and through me and when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see Its path where the fear has gone.
Rym: There will be nothing only I Will remain.
Scott: I never heard that my life.
Rym: I think Paula Trades says it okay It's a spell.
Rym: the Bene Gesserit up already.
Rym: I'm going deep.
Rym: read the book.
Scott: Is that what you tell yourself to?
Scott: you know, take the spice without being afraid?
Rym: Ah, the litany gets fair.
Rym: was a litany spoken by many highly educated people who face danger or fear during their everyday lives?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: All right.
Scott: All right, try to use it for real then next time you're going to some danger.
Scott: Well, is that what you say when you go skiing?
Rym: When I'm skiing, I'm just thinking yum.
Rym: Yum.
Scott: And then the the volatile snowman comes from behind The tree comes from the front.
Rym: Otherwise both Scott and I are live streaming more and more and I'm increasingly building more and more Sophisticated live streams.
Rym: if you've been watching my overwatch live streams, you'll see that it's not just overwatch But it's also a face cam and a hand.
Rym: can
Scott: I think I'm gonna go to the new system that I see a lot of other People doing which is where you live stream,
Rym: but you don't make that video
Scott: That public and what you do is you record your whole live stream locally and then you edit like you find the bet the highlight And you upload the highlight to YouTube after as its own like just a YouTube video.
Rym: That's what I've been doing.
Scott: I guess I've been well, I've been actually watching a lot of hearthstone on Twitch.
Scott: Is it that season?
Scott: Yeah, and that's what these people do is they play More hearthstone in like a day than I play in a month.
Scott: But and they stream it all and then they take like the best hearthstone game They played and they put that on YouTube on its own in HD.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So my pro tip for you because I've been doing that is When you record like, you know do the stream and just check that box to make sure it automatically goes unlisted like once it's done Mm-hmm, and then like that day go watch the video at like 4x speed and pull out all the interesting bits That might exist then because if you wait you will never look at that video again.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much.
Rym: you will never find the funny thing that you remember happening.
Rym: And yeah, that is my advice.
Scott: You can also like write down time codes or whatever.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Is that gonna happen?
Scott: hmm, the other thing you can do is I can look at the.
Scott: If I look at the whole track like zoomed out like at the bottom part in the timeline I can see the parts where I'm talking right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like if I'm talking that's probably the interesting part You know and the part where I'm just being quiet and playing is not the interesting part.
Scott: So I can just find the parts where I say stuff and edit out all the long boring parts, right?
Scott: I don't do anything.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yep Though there is all like the live stream like people seem to like a lot of people in bugging me to just live stream siv6 Even though like I'm not gonna say anything if I'm playing siv6 It's just gonna be just me slowly playing siv6 for like four hours.
Scott: Well, the thing I've realized is that it's really hard to become like the streaming person because The people who are like the big streams It's like.
Scott: it's so easy for them because they have a ton of viewers already so they can.
Scott: they can always go to the viewers See what they're saying and basically talk to them, right?
Rym: I'll have like six to twelve people watching the stream and so the only messages there are hey Rym And wow, you suck at overwatch, right?
Scott: It's like, you know the people with the big twitch chats.
Scott: Yeah It's a big flood of crap but they can still look at it and they'll be so like a non crap that they can respond to.
Scott: and Also, they got people donating and subscribing and whenever anyone subscribes like they all have a shtick Like this is one guy every time someone subscribes to his channel.
Scott: He gets his dick out.
Scott: No, he's like welcome to the dragon army, right?
Scott: Yeah, he's like, thanks, you know, he's got something to end.
Scott: people donate.
Scott: They did not subscribing just like directly donating like here's a dollar.
Rym: YouTube has that.
Scott: They put a message with it They put a message and then the person reads.
Scott: the message is like a guaranteed way to get the streaming person to read what you Got to say.
Scott: and it's like.
Scott: you can only do all that stuff and make your stream have that.
Scott: if You got a bunch of viewers if you got like three You know, you can't really do that so much.
Scott: It's like all on you to keep talking while you're playing a game.
Rym: So the other way to do it is like an overwatch group up with people.
Rym: So you have funny people with you and just do what you.
Rym: normally I'm playing a single-player game usually Yeah, or if you're doing that do a pseudo podcast like just start a discord chat.
Scott: Well, for example, like what I did I did played for Xanadu, right?
Scott: And I talked a whole bunch at the beginning and then once I started, you know got deeper in the game.
Scott: It's just like I only really had to talk when something happened in the game And other than that, it was just.
Rym: the worst thing is like Civ 5.
Scott: I already said all the things I had to say about Xanadu that would have said if we did a podcast on.
Rym: well You guys see how the Civ 5 videos I put up of like the long games were playing and I had a lot to say Like every turn.
Rym: but that's cuz.
Rym: I know Civ 5 like inside and out.
Rym: I don't know Civ 6 enough to say shit.
Scott: I'm mostly looking at the screen just thinking.
Scott: I haven't played Civ 6 in months.
Rym: Oh, there's already an expansion.
Rym: They added Poland.
Scott: Poland's pretty good.
Scott: Didn't they have Poland before?
Scott: No.
Scott: Okay Poland's pretty good.
Scott: Does it got to pay for that?
Rym: Maybe I think I paid for it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I play Civ 6.
Rym: I think I'm gonna start a GMR game of it once.
Scott: Do they have that?
Rym: They tested it in alpha.
Rym: It seems to work.
Rym: I'm waiting for it to be like in the normal client.
Scott: I'll definitely do that.
Rym: Yeah Only people who will take their fucking turn though.
Scott: Yeah, I'll take my turn.
Scott: Looking at you Andrew in the other game Just can't you make him forfeit?
Rym: You cannot kick people out Mm-hmm, you can set a threshold where if a certain number of turns get skipped where the AI took the turn Then it'll kick that player out.
Rym: So one I said it low enough to where certain people might get kicked out of certain games in the near future.
Rym: Mm-hmm Okay, so Scott sent me a message while I was in ski trip and he was like, yeah We're gonna play this game and do show on it.
Scott: And then we did so.
Scott: I was you know I had this idea for a board game that I've been half working on and like I made more progress on it than any other Solid like.
Rym: the concept is great.
Scott: So my basic idea was you know I wanted to make a game based on gobs.
Scott: because the only game based on gobs which if you don't know is the game of pure Strategy because so many people are so mad about randomness and all sorts of other things.
Scott: I'm like, well the game we're looking for is gobs, but gobs is boring as hell.
Scott: Let's make interesting gobs by combining it with other stuff and the only game that does that is el grande Which combines it with current play again?
Scott: El grande is is gobs plus colonel blotto, right?
Scott: So I'm like, well, let's just take gobs and combine it with something else and like advance wars or some shit Who knows and make a better game, right?
Scott: so I was working on something along those lines.
Scott: ish.
Scott: and Then I'm on YouTube and I see this video about this board game called raptor as in the dinosaur not the call of the shadows.
Scott: And I watched this like really short video that explained all the rules and I'm like, holy shit That's like 90% the game that I was making.
Scott: what the fuck?
Scott: Okay, and then on my way home like this weekend I go to the game store and it's just sitting there right on the shelf and I'm like, oh, I guess I'm fucking buy that Cute.
Scott: it's two-player game and I brought a home and I just brought it.
Scott: We just played it two times just now one time.
Scott: I was the Raptor and one time room was the Raptor.
Rym: Yep I like it.
Scott: Yeah, this is like, you know to play a game.
Rym: It's not as good like if you're looking for a deep two-player game, it's not lost cities.
Rym: It's not battle line It's not seven wonders duel.
Rym: I don't think it's better than battle line.
Rym: I don't know battle line is so tight.
Scott: It's not as good as lost cities.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: Yeah, I think battle line is deeper than lost cities.
Scott: So what this game basically is is it's gobs?
Rym: Plus so gobs goof field game of pure strategy plus mouse guards swords and stronghold.
Rym: Yep, swords and strongholds has the idea that it's one of those like symmetric like perfect information games Except you're limited in actions because you have a small hand of cards from a small deck and you can only take actions that You have cards for.
Rym: so it's like which is great because it limits the scope of interaction.
Rym: This game is the same thing It's gobs.
Rym: gobs is basically everyone has deck of cards and you all just play a card and then the highest card wins.
Rym: Yep, but you all have the same deck.
Rym: So what's your strategy?
Rym: You play the king first play the two first.
Rym: You doing there?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: There's a lot of strategy in that Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway, this game is nothing but strategy.
Scott: It's pure strategy.
Rym: But a big problem.
Rym: if you try to take a game and use the gobs mechanic as your core mechanic Is that there is definitely an analysis paralysis situation?
Scott: Well, the Difficult problem is okay.
Scott: So you're playing gobs right and then gobs is somehow influencing this other game.
Scott: You have to design it such that.
Scott: well does the other game even matter?
Scott: or is just whoever wins the gobs ends up winning the Game.
Scott: so why even bother playing the other stuff?
Rym: Just like otherwise the other game might as well just be Street fighter and it shows the health and the fighting based on what you played in the real game.
Scott: Or do you make it such that?
Scott: Oh, well, actually the gobs doesn't matter as much.
Scott: in which case Why even have the gobs there?
Scott: You're now no longer.
Scott: Is it a game of pure strategy?
Scott: You've got more you've added in luck or whatever the flaws are of the other game.
Scott: So, you know Grande the gobs part is just bidding for first to go first, right and Deciding how meant that?
Rym: the balance there is that the lower cards lets you bring capieros from the what's-its And also sometimes you want to go last?
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to go first sometimes.
Scott: So it's like that's only controlling part of the game But because that's an important part of the game, but not the whole game.
Scott: It works out.
Rym: Yep it can serve like a balance because typically the way these games work even though there aren't that many of them like.
Rym: that's why this game is notable enough for us to have played it.
Rym: and You're talking about it.
Rym: Now is that you'll have like low numbers to high numbers, but the lower numbers have better powers Mm-hmm.
Rym: So like a low number does a power but a high number wins the thing whatever the thing is.
Scott: so in raptor They use a mechanic that I obviously I didn't steal from them But me and also the designers of this game Which is Citadel's guy Bruno if I duty and another guy named Bruno Bruno?
Scott: Actually has made what.
Rym: so Bruno kathala worked with Antoine Bauza on seven waters duel, okay, which is Fantastic.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So you got also five tribes and shadows over Camelot.
Rym: Well, that's not good But yeah, but that looks like it's well, it's a bridge.
Scott: So you got this other guy named Bruno kathala plus the citadels guy.
Scott: They came together and made this game.
Scott: and here's how the game goes.
Scott: I mean you get scientists and you got el raptors the raptor and a bunch of babies, right?
Scott: And really this the five raptor babies are the points.
Scott: so either side can win though the.
Scott: if the Raptor makes three babies escape the map then the raptor wins.
Scott: if the scientists capture three babies they win and there are five babies.
Scott: if The raptor yeah, you want to get three out of the five babies.
Scott: if the mommy raptor kills all the scientists on the board So there's no scientist on the board at a given point in time The mommy wins.
Scott: if the mommy raptor takes five damage and falls asleep the scientists win.
Scott: See is what you do on your turn.
Scott: You got a deck of nine cards one through nine.
Scott: So it is the other person.
Scott: you play gobs.
Scott: you both play a card and reveal it.
Scott: Whoever plays the higher number wins.
Scott: The other person loses.
Scott: the loser goes first and uses the ability on their card.
Scott: Well, that doesn't sound like losing to me But the winner loses.
Rym: just a convenient way to express it because there aren't that many games like exactly.
Scott: the winner goes second.
Scott: But what they do is they take the number on the card they played.
Scott: So let's say I play the eight and Rym played the two.
Scott: he does the ability on his card number two.
Scott: Then I take eight minus two is six.
Scott: I take six regular actions, which are way strong.
Rym: So you can.
Scott: then we play then we play again.
Scott: and the thing is it's not quite gobs Because you only have three cards in your hand at a time, you know, it's like limited got limited in real gobs.
Scott: You don't have a deck You've got a whole hat.
Scott: you just hold every card in your hand all the time.
Rym: But what this does is if I held the entire deck in my hand The game would take like I could spend a lot of time computing strategies.
Rym: the game can get locked in really quick.
Rym: It removes a lot of the guys they take away.
Scott: They do what I said before.
Rym: they remove some of the pure strategy of gobs to make it to add a tactical element of alright I got a one a two and nine.
Rym: Let's play ball.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: What can I do with this?
Scott: So, you know the actions are like move Raptor around move scientists shoot the Raptor a fire on the board Fire drive around in a jeep, right?
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's just a nice little.
Scott: you know.
Scott: Like what's it?
Scott: three six not a nine by six grid with some obstacles and exits on both ends.
Scott: You know, it's just.
Scott: it's similar actually to you know, Mouse Guard swords and strongholds, right?
Scott: Yeah a few pieces You're moving around you get more scientists onto the board.
Rym: I'm liking this.
Rym: Have a small repeat like cycling deck of actions.
Rym: But a small number of those actually miles got is the three kinds of actions and it just sets.
Rym: of those in the deck This one is you have nine unique cards and you just keep cycling through that deck.
Rym: So everything's gonna come up eventually and the only real randomness is what options you have right now.
Rym: But by giving you three cards to pick from it's not completely random.
Rym: You just have to sort of decide what to do and like look at what the other person's played and just sort of make a Tactical decision.
Scott: Yeah, so the game, you know ends up turning out.
Scott: They have like lots of interesting decisions.
Scott: right the start of your turn You have a really tough decision of what card to play.
Scott: Then after you've played the card and you figure out what you're gonna get.
Scott: It's like you got another hard decision Which is like well, what the hell do I do with my five action points?
Scott: Yeah, and then even at the start of the game, it's like where the hell do I place my guys?
Scott: It's like there's all sorts of interesting decisions on like every single freaking turn of this game.
Scott: So it's way fun.
Scott: Even if it's not necessarily like the deepest or the hardest core It's like for two players an asymmetric game that's got replay value and is interesting.
Scott: It's like that doesn't come around too often I would guess.
Scott: even if you own lost cities and mouse guard and all these other two-player games that are great battle line It'll be easy to get someone to play.
Scott: there's no you know.
Scott: Oh like you're not.
Scott: you're gonna get bored of all those and you're gonna want another two-player game.
Scott: And this is the one now.
Rym: I do feel like there are probably degenerate strategies I. So yeah There's definitely see now that is heavily mitigated by the fact that you just might not draw the cards you need Mm-hmm, but at the same time there are definitely gonna be some pretty locked in strategies If you play this more than like five times, right?
Scott: It definitely seems that the Raptors right are sort of like the agro team, right?
Scott: So the Raptor wants to go early and because you only start like four scientists on the board and you can almost always just like Kill one right away due to the initial placement rules Yeah, and it's bad structure.
Scott: more scientists out because the depending yeah, you have to lose with those cards, which is right Anyway, but so the Raptor has to go agro.
Scott: They gotta kill scientists quickly move quickly and like get all the babies to one corner and start shoving them off the board.
Scott: You know fast.
Scott: if they can't move fast the scientists winning becomes more of an inevitability, right?
Scott: It's like if the scientists don't lose in the early game they just need to hold on and it's very hard for the Raptor to win as the game goes on.
Scott: because the one big rule is that For the bait this see Raptor to wake up a baby the Raptor has to go near the baby.
Scott: So the scientists can put Raptors to sleep everywhere and even if they can't capture them They can't leave easily, right?
Scott: So they need to get them off the board quick and like all together quickly like hurry up my babies come You know, let's all get together and run away.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't do that, it's bad news.
Rym: It seems like a very powerful like first run strategy.
Rym: You know We always talk about like in those winning panels.
Rym: how?
Rym: When you play a game the first time there's usually one like really great strategy that works until other people kind of figure out the game.
Rym: Like the obvious thing to do as opposed to the obvious thing in this game is to shoot the Raptor first ignore the babies because as you keep getting sleep darts into the Raptor the Raptor slower and slower.
Scott: Raptor really is a hard time moving.
Scott: if you shoot like just shoot it as soon as you can And it will basically be almost impossible for it to move.
Scott: and then what does it do?
Scott: Yeah, it has to get a healing somehow which does it does a big healing card.
Scott: Just how you gonna play it.
Scott: It's not hard.
Scott: It's not easy.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So but the game is super fun.
Rym: like for the likeness of this game I'm really impressed with how fun it is.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they made a lot more progress on this idea than I did.
Rym: Yeah, well cuz they really constrained what they were doing.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: They made a very limited number of power.
Scott: I was making a much bigger game that but it was so similar.
Rym: I was like, wow, in fact, my only complaints about this game at all are that the rules are not very well-written.
Rym: really Okay, so actually I think the rules are way but no so qualify that by like our ridiculous standards They're way better.
Rym: I mean listen then like potion explosion.
Scott: There are a couple flaws in the rules, but overall this is like 90% well-written rules, right?
Scott: They so the.
Scott: here's the problems.
Scott: I have one they are actually really good about using the word tile and the word space when Appropriate because a tile is a whole tile that has nine spaces on it and tile and space adjacency are both things, right?
Scott: But Just be you know, they're they never mess up.
Rym: What is the turn right?
Scott: Well, okay They never mess up writing the rules when it comes to tile and space But it's just confusing cuz like you're in your brain.
Scott: It's like tile space.
Scott: You have to actually like consciously pay attention to that to not mess it up or you might get really confused.
Scott: Like wait adjacent tile.
Scott: He has to be right next to me.
Scott: It's like no they actually mean the adjacent tile.
Rym: when Scott was the Raptor and when I was there after we both made that Mistake to our detriment.
Rym: Yes, we took an action and then realized oh, that's not gonna work out the way I expected right?
Scott: The one rule they actually mess up.
Scott: Well, they didn't mess this up.
Scott: Well, they use the word turn Vague you're getting ahead.
Scott: There's other rules.
Scott: You gotta talk about first, right?
Scott: So No, so is When you play the same exact number as your opponent you discard the card and it isn't 100% clear that whether you should draw a third card and then play another one or if you shouldn't.
Scott: so.
Scott: But obviously you should because otherwise you could theoretically get three ties and be left with an empty hand.
Scott: see soft lock, right?
Scott: So obviously you always have three cards in your hand And if you tie you draw another one before you play another one, but it doesn't explicitly say that right, you know.
Scott: So that's just a poor writing.
Scott: But obviously that's the ruling it could look like I said comes down into.
Rym: it Doesn't define what a turn is right.
Rym: also uses the word round.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So here's the one problem that we couldn't answer.
Scott: There's a card that let make forces your opponent to play their card first instead of simultaneously Right on the next turn.
Scott: So I forced Rym to play his card first next turn.
Scott: He does it I play.
Scott: I choose To tie him.
Scott: Okay, we obviously both draw new cards, right?
Scott: But does Rym have to reveal this card to me?
Scott: or was that it?
Scott: It that is on the rule doesn't say so that's really the only thing that was big you.
Rym: I think geek people have a lot more questions that we didn't even run into.
Rym: for example, I replenish tranquilizer bullets.
Scott: No, you have.
Rym: the five scientists die for good.
Scott: No, they don't.
Rym: I think these board game geek people just don't parse rules.
Scott: They just didn't read the rules.
Scott: there's only five bullets in the game and the The Raptor only takes five hits.
Scott: and I'm pretty sure the rule book even says Yeah, when you heal give the things back to the scientists you can shoot you again.
Rym: Oh my god, one guy's like I found a degenerate strategy always play your highest card.
Scott: No, no, that is not.
Rym: I will gladly play this game with you Dennis.
Scott: Yes Always playing his highest card.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Yeah, so no one appears to have asked the questions.
Rym: They're all asking dumb questions that are trivially answered by the rules because they didn't read.
Rym: can fire be placed on occupied spaces Or must they always be placed on empty spaces.
Scott: It says clearly in the rules No two things may be in the same space period ever done It's clear.
Scott: So the rules like 99% or not 99% but like they're really well written compared to a lot of other games.
Scott: I'm not gonna say they're garbage rules.
Scott: No, they're there from it, but they're not perfect.
Rym: They're above average rule.
Rym: They're way above average, you know We ran into more problems with potion explosion than with this game.
Scott: potion explosion Just like.
Scott: I couldn't even right but this game I can even all day now.
Rym: potion explosion I'd say about three quarters of the questions you had were technically answered but in obtuse Confusing or non sequential ways in potion explosion.
Rym: Mmm This one had very few conflicts, but one of them was like we resolved it, but it was kind of unresolvable.
Rym: Mmm, I'll forgive it cuz the game is pretty fun and I like the theme All right.
Scott: So if you're looking for a two-player game It's got some depth and some strategy and some dinosaurs asymmetric like take some cops.
Rym: take that like foxes and snakes game.
Rym: Yeah, no, that's the one from Wheel of Time the real version of that.
Scott: You can get this game the you know what?
Scott: I think the only negative of this game is that the box is not.
Scott: It's not enormous right.
Scott: it's smaller than like a for, you know, Puerto Rico by which is bigger than it needs to be But it's bigger than it needs to be.
Scott: but more importantly It's even if it's you know, even if you were to shrink the game into a smaller box, you know rebox it.
Scott: Yeah, it's still like Kind of too big for a two-player game.
Scott: It's not portable like a lot of cities.
Rym: I keep battle line in one ziplock bag.
Scott: Yeah You can't keep this game in one ziplock bag because you got to get the tokens and all these little boards and it's like in Cards, so it's like you can get.
Scott: you can probably fit it maybe in something smaller but I still think it's too big for You know to be portable enough for a two-player game and then you have to set it up.
Scott: I'm like a table of like substantial size.
Scott: You can't just like like lost cities you can play in like a cafe.
Scott: for this you need like a real table.
Scott: Yeah, it takes up as much space as like a real kind of game, but it's to player.
Scott: So that's sort of like as like this physical problem.
Rym: Oh, oh Bruno Cathala is totally in the forum directly answering rules question.
Scott: Well ask asked our two questions.
Rym: So for example, someone just asked here.
Rym: What do you do if you run out of fire tokens and you play a fire code?
Scott: Oh, that's actually a good question.
Rym: Bruno Cathala quote you ignore the effect.
Scott: Yeah that makes sense because in other parts of the rules it says like if you run out of scientists you can't place any more or Stuff like that.
Rym: now that is remember we did our design and game rules panel.
Rym: That is a good sign.
Rym: if a rule is ambiguous you have to look to other similar situations and see if it's unambiguous.
Rym: and As long as all those situations break in a similar direction Then you can reasonably assume the answer to the question even if you don't have Bruno telling you
Scott: Well, so while you're in there just ask about you know If you use the revealing thing and then you tie do you have to reveal the next one?
Scott: Or not?
Rym: dude motherfucker Don't ask him if you can move the rafter Diagonally like that was first thing it says in the rule book.
Scott: is that absolutely nothing in this game ever moves or shoots Diagonally ever under any circumstance.
Rym: the end Bruno answered that one immediately and was like I confirm no diagonal move No diagonal shoot no diagonals everything all at game like no diagonals.
Scott: That's the first thing it says in the book.
Scott: Jesus Christ read.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, oh my god even in this thread.
Rym: just to clarify.
Rym: So someone else is like, but what if I'm killing or eating is that?
Rym: Diagonal like?
Scott: no it says absolutely nothing in the game is diagonal.
Scott: Everything is orthogonal.
Scott: the end god damn board game geek like.
Rym: come on guys Like.
Scott: it's one thing to be a rules lawyer, but to be a rules lawyer.
Scott: You gotta be literate.
Scott: The Lawyers can read.
Scott: that's how they do both.
Rym: Bruno's like post constantly in this farm All right.
Scott: Well, I'm gonna go and post our questions.
Rym: if yeah good on you guys.
Rym: Also, we should I'm just gonna buy lost cities duels and we'll play it into a review of it.
Scott: Cuz you mean seven wonders seven wonders duel.
Rym: Yeah, I'll say this is already a duel cuz everyone is duel.
Rym: So so great.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: Also, the power grid card game is not - it might be.
Scott: is it to player?
Rym: I Heard tell to player would not be advised.
Scott: the point is we played power grid card game But not with two players.
Scott: it was fun and it's power grid without the map But only the other parts of power grid which is fine.
Scott: because I'm fine because the map is the part I like the least.
Rym: I'm tired of the map.
Rym: I have optimized the map.
Rym: I play the map perfectly.
Rym: I don't care like the map is just something that I might fuck up a calculation and be off by one dollar the man.
Scott: So the map actually makes the game more political because someone like blocks you off and like well, fuck me.
Scott: Yeah And turn or you know, whatever.
Rym: So yeah peck south actually brought us many games to review and we skipped all of them to talk about this new game.
Rym: That's pretty good.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's from 2015.
Rym: It's relatively recent.
Scott: Uh, I thought it was like super new, but maybe not.
Rym: It's from 2015 according to the BGG.
Scott: Well, I guess it might have gotten reprinted recently and that's why I'll to check.
Rym: Yeah, maybe I do not.
Scott: maybe it's was out in 2015 in like Germany and now it's 2015.
Scott: It's gotten published in the US.
Scott: finally.
Scott: Yeah, it could be like that.
Rym: See if there's any note here, but I think I'm done.
Rym: I think we're done with the show.
Scott: All right, you need to player games.
Scott: get the Raptor.
Rym: Yep, the Raptor the lost cities It's definitely if you're.
Scott: if you're gonna narrow a list of like games that are to player that you should buy it's on there.
Scott: Yeah, it made.
Scott: it's not the best but made the list.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: It's better than the moose game by far because the moose games got some problems.
Scott: It's better than the moose gaming.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: We're back from our hiatus and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, Construction Noises, Ivy Faye, mystady.com, William Isenrose, Jeremy Minor.
Rym: I want to be the very best.
Rym: like no one ever was to catch them is my Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Christian Koontz, my watch is what brings us together today.
Rym: my watch that West arrangement.
Rym: I paid five dollars to make Rym say kumquat Aaron Suri's Brian Fisher sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich, Jar Toppes and Joshiro Jostar Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open letter Brian Cedroni Remember when remarried.
Rym: all of us redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: It's good to be back.
Rym: my London trip and PAX East will actually not significantly possibly not at all impact the night schedule and We're gonna start making now that we're back in the long span of Convention after convention and New Year's and skiing and everything is done.
Rym: We're making a lot of content.
Rym: Scott will be live-streaming.
Rym: I'll be live-streaming a lot more patreon contents coming out again.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: We're back We're back and now I leave you.
Rym: I have to say I found this very difficult to masturbate to.