Rym: It's Tuesday, October 24th, 2017, and this is a Spooky October GeekNights.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I am the Ghost of Skaar, oooh.
Rym: And tonight, we are talking about a game that is called, and I am quoting directly, "Ciderial Confluence colon Trading and Negotiation in the Elysian
Rym: Quadrants."
Rym: AKA SpaceCube.
Rym: Cube Trader the game.
Scott: SpaceCube.
Rym: So, yeah, it's October and I am sticking to this theme of trying to make spooky themed episodes of GeekNights, no matter how thin that theme is.
Scott: You know what the spookiest thing is?
Scott: Is that in like five days, GeekNights will be 12 years old.
Rym: Yeah, 12th anniversary of GeekNights.
Scott: That's old.
Scott: If we had a baby then, that baby would be 12 now and could talk and be useful and be on the podcast.
Rym: Well, GeekNights can talk.
Rym: Great.
Rym: There's like 14 to 1500 hours of it talking.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: You know, some day, someone could, my hope is that long after we're dead, machine learning can take the entire archive of GeekNights and continue to make episodes forever.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Rym: That's actually like kind of feasible.
Rym: Actually machine learning could probably just keep making episodes of Erise at Sura in around my one-half.
Rym: So yeah, and as we said, we did this thing that we, in our hubris, called Review Con when it was literally just us and a bunch of our good friends playing board games.
Rym: But in our hubris, Con Plague appeared and not in our hubris, but I wanted to Geek Bite one of the games we played at this mini convention because there is no way we could ever do a full episode of GeekNights on Spinderella.
Scott: No, no, there isn't.
Rym: Unless we expanded to talk about dexterity games or like, I already realized there are ways to take this game and make it better.
Rym: Like you can make a pretty legit game, but the game is notable in that if you put it in a library at a PAX, I think a lot of people would check it out and play it once just for the novelty.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: I think it's the kind of game you don't even put away because you don't want, you know, you just want to leave it set up, right?
Scott: In fact,
Rym: that's an idea for a future Unplugged to have a table that has like one area that has Rock 'Em Sock 'Em Robots, Spinderella, Crossfire, like all those kinds of games where people want to go and touch it and then realize they're not that good and then stop touching them.
Scott: The board, like an arena of some kind for...
Rym: Touching games.
Scott: Interesting games.
Scott: The one where you put the crane on your head.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Maybe I'll put a bunch of copies of Elkfest over there.
Rym: That's not a bad idea.
Scott: The Elkfest tournament, the crossing of the Elk, one of those big...
Rym: Elkfest tournament across the entirety of tabletop.
Scott: Just one, no, just have one of the long tables, but you only have to get across it the short way.
Scott: and there's all these multiple games, right?
Rym: Everyone's playing a game.
Rym: And it's just real time.
Rym: Right?
Scott: Well, you just have to get across the short little table to your opponent's side, right?
Scott: It's just you play, right?
Scott: And then you do a tournament and you narrow it down and when you got two people remaining, then you got to go down the whole long table.
Rym: That ain't a bad idea.
Rym: And you just put a camera on top and just get a time-lapse.
Rym: So Spinderella is a kid's game and we played it and the notable thing is...
Scott: This game is good for children who have motor skills and can count.
Scott: But it also... So if you can play Candyland or Uncle Wiggly or Sorry or Trouble, you can play this game.
Rym: It is interesting in that it has a few mechanics that interact together and unlike a lot of kids' games that hyper restrict what kids can do in the games, this one kind of lets you do these super broken degenerate strategy type things and I think that's actually a plus in its favor.
Rym: So basically, you got this magnetic spider contraption.
Scott: It involves two spiders.
Rym: There are two spiders on the top.
Scott: And they have a rope.
Scott: One of them has a pulley and one of them has the end of the rope.
Scott: So when you move one spider, it sort of moves the location of the rope.
Scott: When you move the others in relation to the first spider, the length of the rope adjusts.
Scott: So if the spiders get too far apart, the rope goes way up and if they get too close to each other, it goes way down.
Rym: Now, the game pretty much just lets you sort of fudge with it to make what you want to happen happen.
Rym: because the idea is that you're trying to roll your dice and move your mice, but the mice you're moving are little ants that don't want to get eaten by the spider.
Rym: And if you get to move the spider, you can move the upper spiders a certain number of spaces on this grid.
Rym: and well, this is sort of node system.
Rym: And if you get the magnet spider on the bottom web down and it touches one of the ants and eats it and pretty good mechanic, it's like it works really well.
Scott: It's actually basically shoots and ladders, you know, sort of thing where you're trying to get to the end.
Scott: But instead of the shoots, there's one shoot and it's controlled by everybody when, depending on the dice, tells people when and how they can control the shoot and shoot always sends you back to the beginning.
Rym: The the other interesting thing is there's a moderately complex mechanic for a kid's game in that there's a tree stump.
Scott: The tree stump is what makes the game work.
Rym: You can also move in.
Rym: the way the tree stump works is it's hollow underneath and there's a platform on top.
Scott: So if you put the tree stump on an ant that a protects it from the spider, which is good, but also keeps that ant from moving, which is bad.
Rym: But if you move an ant and it lands on top of the tree stump, way easier for the spider to get that ant.
Rym: But if the tree stump moves with an ant on it, the ant gets to ride the tree stump.
Scott: So the way you win, didn't I win?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: But you.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know who won?
Rym: The gods won because we fucked up so many rules.
Scott: We did.
Scott: But the point is we made like teleporting one of the ants to the end like right away with that tree stump.
Rym: And the rules errors were not the fault of the rules.
Rym: The rules are excellently written.
Rym: The rules errors were the fault of Matt who taught us this game and did not put due respect to the rules of the game.
Rym: And there's more to it.
Rym: It's pretty straightforward.
Rym: The one thing I would say, if you're going to play this with people are older than like four to six years old, you could still play it like with eight or nine year olds.
Rym: The only thing I would change is I would make the rule of you touch it, you move it asshole regarding the spiders.
Rym: So you can't just sort of like move around to see what will happen.
Rym: You got to make your plan and be like, I'll move this spider and then this spider.
Scott: And you had to move them precisely and the correct number of spaces.
Scott: We sort of, you know, wiggled with it.
Rym: Demo weasel in the chat actually suggest the most important thing about this game.
Rym: Use real spiders and see how many people play it then.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Rym: So this game is cute.
Rym: And honestly, if you need a game that is in the genre of games like headache, problematic trouble, uh, sorry for kids, this is better than all of those games, but it is better than those.
Scott: It's better than uncle wiggly or candy land.
Scott: It's got all the things because kids, I think the one difference is that this might be slightly harder than candy land because the play candy land, you only need to know colors, but to play this different genre.
Rym: Candy land is one step down.
Rym: I'm talking about games, one step up from candy land.
Rym: where you literally do not make decisions are games like headache, problematic, trouble, and sorry, where anyone over the age of 12 is not making decisions, but there are decisions that can be made in the game and there is a choice occasionally to completely fuck someone else over because that is a mechanic of trouble.
Rym: That is a mechanic of headache.
Rym: That is a mechanic of sorry.
Rym: That is the core mechanic of sorry.
Rym: And that action when a six year old totally fucks over their dad in a game like this or the dad totally fucks over the kid.
Rym: That is what makes those kinds of games fun for families.
Rym: That moment also.
Scott: the spider mechanism is fun.
Rym: The spider mechanism is fun and very well thought out.
Scott: just to play with it by yourself is fun.
Rym: Now, if you set this up at a table at any gaming con filled solely by adults, I guarantee you would see pretty much constant action until everyone in the room had touched it at least once.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So actual gaming news.
Scott: So everybody knows that, you know, uh, there's a lot of, uh, sexual assault accusations flying around these days.
Scott: Most of them true.
Scott: Maybe all of them.
Rym: I pretty much give the benefit of the doubt in the appropriate direction in all cases.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, uh, anyway, so I mean, it's always the time to call people out, but obviously, you know, I'm not saying you have to because we all know that calling people out is often, uh, as many negative consequences for the color outer, but if you are brave enough to call people out, please do so because it gives us a great joy to see people go down and go down hard when they deserve it.
Rym: Neo gaff.
Rym: I remember Neo gaff from a certain panel we did at a packs a long time ago.
Scott: So if you don't know, there was a forum way back called gaff gaming age forum, I think was it originally called and it went down, but the community, they wanted to keep the spirit alive.
Scott: So this guy made Neo gaff and the guy, I never knew who made Neo gaff.
Scott: Apparently it's someone named evil lore, which is a typical bad internet person name.
Scott: Well, it sounds like there might be some nominative determinism here anyway, but evil lore is someone who has not had much visible internet presence.
Scott: Not a person that people had seen around, you know, not someone to use their social media in a while.
Rym: So not like, like if park has drew Curtis who like.
Scott: if you're on, you know who drew Curtis is, you can see him, you can talk to him.
Scott: He's out and about.
Rym: low tax is like tweeting all the time, right?
Scott: You know, evil or is one of those behind the scenes internet people you don't hear from ever.
Scott: Like I didn't even know who this person was until this week, apparently is a shithead just like all the others I just mentioned.
Scott: And he had been called out rightfully so.
Scott: And his response to being called out was to temporarily completely shut down Neo gaff.
Scott: Now I am not going, I am, this is not even done with the, and then he, they pre purged all posts on Neo gaff about his, uh, badness.
Rym: All I was going to say is that banned many peoples.
Rym: There is a presumption of innocence in the U?
Rym: S legal system.
Rym: And I respect that because that is a very important part of our justice system.
Rym: But at the same time, the actions that were taken by this individual are not the actions one would take if said allegations were in fact false.
Rym: That is just a supposition I'm putting out there.
Scott: Uh, anyway, uh, also the number of times people make false accusations along those lines, considering, you know, the repercussions of making even true accusations, uh, it's pretty rare for there to be false accusations, which is why I tend to believe any accusations that come out.
Rym: I mean, it seems like Neo gaff has always been kind of a hole anyway.
Scott: Well, no, here's the thing that you don't, you're not letting me finish his story and you didn't obviously didn't read the story either.
Rym: I have skimmed the top of this article.
Scott: You don't know jack about what's going on, right?
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Basically they took down Neo gaff.
Scott: All the people in Neo gaff were hitting evil or hard where it hurts and that's why he took it down.
Scott: He was trying to chill the descent and people were like, you were like evil or you're a scumbag ban me.
Scott: That was like, that was the general sentiment on Neo gaff and now that it's back, sentiment hasn't changed.
Rym: You're right.
Rym: Like every moderator quit.
Scott: And they got new moderators, but they're anonymous.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Meaning it's all gamer gators probably.
Scott: He keeps shut down the off topic sections of the site now and all this kind of stuff.
Scott: So basically he shut down Neo gaff to figure out how you could keep people on it from attacking him.
Scott: and obviously that doesn't work cause this is internet and now it's back up at least now and I don't know, but yeah, uh, I never went to Neo gaff other than a Google search result when it was relevant once.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: One time we went to Neo gaff once.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Uh, but apparently the general community of Neo gaff seems to be good even though the person who made it is the worst and it seems like that community is now basically done for a, okay, that's fine.
Rym: You know, that's actually interesting because I can, I generally assume that places on the internet are bad places and less proven otherwise.
Rym: So I started to assume Neo gaff was kind of a whole, I actually have a mad respect now for the core community that they were like, fuck this.
Scott: I mean, you didn't respect the people who made dude, bro.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: But I also read that not every post in the dude, bro thread was good people.
Scott: Anyway, just saying not every post on Neo gaff is good people now either.
Rym: But if you, uh, you loan some Neo gaff people who have fled in disgust and are afraid of these probably GG moderate are not listening to GeekNights.
Rym: If you find out about GeekNights, just say in our forums pretty good and we will never have a problem like that.
Scott: No, we definitely won't have that problem.
Rym: We are very proactive in banning people who do things anyway.
Scott: So let's talk about the other mildly related news of things in the gaming journalism community area having problems.
Scott: The escapist people don't know.
Scott: I saw the escapist on the very first day it went live.
Rym: I was still working at IBM.
Rym: I'd like read it.
Scott: I was at RIT.
Rym: I was on co-op at IBM.
Scott: The original escapist was not something you could read every morning.
Scott: The original escapist, they were trying to be a magazine of long form video game, real hardcore journalism.
Scott: And what it was originally was his website you went to and you couldn't like get text of the articles like a normal blog.
Scott: It was like trying to be like a PDF or some interactive, you know, magazine, but just in digital form, right?
Scott: But the content was so good.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: 2005 I was working at IBM anyway.
Scott: The content was so good then, but they didn't make a lot of content and obviously their format sucked, but they had good peoples together, uh, who are making that content.
Scott: And eventually, you know, they made really good stuff escapist.
Scott: And then as they needed monies, they changed and changed and changed and changed and changed.
Scott: And apparently it hasn't helped them because now they really need monies.
Scott: They're not doing well.
Scott: And they just got rid of, I think, I'm not sure exactly.
Scott: It seems like they've gotten rid of all of their employees, all of paid people.
Scott: It says the majority of its paid staff, but the words that I heard where everyone except Yahtzee Crow Shaw is no longer on the, on the payroll.
Scott: So yeah, I guess our IP escapist, I've, you know, you went downhill, I stopped paying attention to you a while ago, so I don't have any interesting though to know that something with such great roots, right?
Scott: Eventually, what very quickly became a large tree, then a large dead tree, then a large dead tree that fell in someone's house.
Rym: So I had heard a bunch of rumblings.
Rym: I just googled for it and I found some articles.
Rym: I feel like I must, I must have gotten these rumblings from a bunch of sources, but it appears that escapist went way down the gamer gate hall.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: Like there seems to be, it seems like the long decline accelerated a rapidly.
Scott: Well, I think, I think, you know, a lot of the people left and it's all different people from what it was before.
Scott: Just took the property away.
Rym: I mean, a lot of people I know who worked or worked with them in any capacity bailed a long, long time.
Scott: Yeah, but I knew people who were there back in the good days doing good stuff and that's when it was good and I guess they all gone.
Rym: It's interesting when these sorts of things happen, though, especially because unless you worked there, you never really know the inside story of like who was making hope.
Scott: And you always hope that years later someone will spill the tea.
Rym: You know how you know where that tea gets spilled usually at some gaming con in a hotel room party like 10 years after the biz went down.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So in like 10 years, we'll be at a mag fest or something and someone in a hotel party is going to be like, hey, remember, remember escapist?
Scott: Whoa, that thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What happened to that?
Scott: I'll tell you the real deal.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Guy came in with a gun and shit went crazy.
Scott: I don't think that's what happened.
Scott: But yeah, we can't promise.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: I'm not going to read part of it.
Scott: It's a serious situation.
Scott: We can't promise the escapist last forever.
Scott: It may have years left in it or it may disappear tomorrow.
Scott: We will do our utmost to keep the site running in an orderly fashion, whatever.
Scott: But they went so high and they fell so far and that's why it's notable.
Scott: I hope that that old escapist content is out there somewhere so that if you're actually interested in that, it's probably like going to be really valuable for somebody to go and find that original escapist because they were like long, well-researched essays about gaming like they were fantastic.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, this video is not perfect, but it is a pretty good, succinct explanation of something that I actually know a lot about.
Rym: And when I way back when I was playing Doom before when I was in high school, I was really big into modding Doom.
Rym: So I used all those tools and I made levels and I made mods and I was fucking around with the code and I know a lot about line depth and side depth and how the textures worked and everything.
Rym: But if you didn't know, Doom is not three dimensional and Wolfenstein 3D is even less three dimensional.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But the details of why Doom looked so much better than Wolfenstein from that perspective is a pretty interesting technical discussion.
Rym: And this video is in a pretty good detail about the difference between ray casting and these other methods with sectors that Doom use and why Doom was able to look so utterly amazing and yet would literally run pretty well on a four eighty six.
Scott: And this video is John Carmichael is really good at programming.
Scott: Yeah, that's like the thing he's good at.
Scott: He wasn't good at making games.
Scott: That's why I like remember like what was a game rage or something?
Scott: Oh, yeah, it was like super garbage.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like he's just really good at programming.
Scott: That's why is that he's able to do stuff like that.
Scott: But, you know, that's the only skill he's got.
Rym: Yeah, but basically Wolfenstein used this ray casting thing where it would cast.
Rym: the engine would basically cast rays to figure out what pixel to display somewhere.
Rym: And because that is a performance and performance bottleneck, you couldn't have walls that were at more than 90 degree angles.
Rym: You couldn't have things that were different z heights.
Rym: There's a reason why Wolfenstein is so blocky.
Rym: Doom, you can have walls and angles and she can be real high up in the air.
Rym: because Doom just had it was still 2D, but it had this third variable.
Rym: that was like literally how high should we render this thing and the way it did that.
Scott: And you could go upstairs, too.
Scott: So it wasn't just showing you things being high.
Scott: It was also like actually elevating you.
Scott: You could fall down off of something down into the green slime.
Rym: that was, you know, but the flat green slime floor, as you might have noticed when you play Doom, nothing could ever be on top of any other thing.
Scott: They could be an elevator.
Rym: No, you couldn't.
Rym: Elevators didn't actually move.
Rym: Nothing moved up and down.
Rym: You could never be on top of another thing.
Scott: There were still elevators.
Rym: Anything under you was a floor that went down forever.
Scott: You could jump off of an elevated surface and land on an imp.
Rym: Yeah, but you could not jump off of something and land on another thing.
Rym: You could not be above another thing or below another thing.
Rym: If you felt like you were below something that was actually a ceiling and there was nothing above it.
Rym: So this video actually explains the details and it's only 11 minutes long and it's pretty good.
Scott: Anyway, so this is Twitter account called Magic the Giffening.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Did I not know about this?
Scott: I can't believe you didn't know until now.
Scott: So this is a little bit old.
Scott: It's not that it's sort of recent, but not super recent because we haven't done GeekNights in a while.
Scott: But basically what it does is it takes a magic card from Magic the Gathering.
Scott: It cuts out the area of the card where the art is and it uses supposedly machine learning of some kind.
Scott: Or it could be just like Giffy.
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Scott: It could be anything, but it finds a gift from the Internet to put in that spot.
Scott: And sometimes it is not so good at choosing something.
Scott: It picks something weird that doesn't even make sense and is not funny or anything.
Scott: But quite often it hits the nail on the head and creates a magic card with a hilarious animated gift that when juxtaposed with the completely unedited magic card around, it provides seconds of hilarity and it provides this multiple times a day.
Scott: Follow this Twitter account and enjoy.
Scott: Even if you don't know anything about Magic the Gathering, it is funny for all.
Rym: All right, I got to get away from this tab.
Rym: I'll be distracted in the moment.
Rym: The book club book, the fifth season.
Rym: We're reviewing that on Thursday.
Rym: We're going to talk about it.
Rym: So if you haven't read the fifth season yet, one, you spoil it and we're going to assume you already read it on this Thursday show on Thursday, October 26.
Scott: Ooh, spooky.
Scott: You only have two days, maybe even one day, depending when you listen to this to read a whole book.
Rym: It should only take you like a week to read this book.
Scott: Other upcoming things on Saturday, November 4th and 5th, which is the Sunday, there are going to be many things happening.
Scott: There's going to be Blizzcon is the third and fourth.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Which includes championships of your favorite Blizzard games or go there.
Scott: The fourth and fifth, the same weekend is the Netrunner World Championships, along with a bunch of other Final Fantasy flight game championships no one cares about because they're not.
Scott: Netrunner X-Wing, I think is actually at a different time of the year.
Scott: And Gamer X East, which we will be going to for at least one day, I think.
Rym: But we don't know if it's going to be the Saturday or the Sunday yet, because last year it was a great con, but it was right after the election.
Rym: And for a lot of reasons, a lot of people who had like who had paid left early and it was a very subdued situation.
Rym: But the foundation of the con was great.
Scott: So this year I'm really looking forward to it.
Scott: It was very organized and such and such.
Rym: So once we know what day our panel is on, we will be at the con pretty much all day that day.
Rym: And if you are also there, we will play games with you because it's just a gaming con.
Rym: We're going to play games.
Scott: On Sunday the 5th, if I'm not at Gamer X East, that is the day of the New York City Marathon.
Scott: And what you can do, which is not it's not an authorized event in any way, but you can go to the start of the marathon down in South Brooklyn, just on this side of the Verrazano Bridge at the crackety crack, crack, crack, crack as a dawn before the marathon starts to
Rym: get up pretty early
Scott: and you can ride your bicycle along the route.
Scott: I guess you could try to run the marathon or walk, but good luck with that.
Scott: Yeah, you can ride your bicycle along the route and get almost to the finish line.
Scott: They don't let you to the actual finish line because, you know, it's like a secure whatever.
Scott: But anyway, and then find a way to get home because the bridge is closed.
Rym: I remember last year I bailed right at the bridge so I could go home before that happened anyway.
Scott: But yeah, if I'm not doing something else, I'll probably do that again because it was depending on the weather to write, you know, OK, other things that are coming up.
Rym: Hacks Unplugged is real soon.
Scott: That is going to be November 16th, 17th and 18th and 19th in Pennsylvania.
Scott: We're enforcing and we're doing an event.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: From three thirty to five thirty p.m.
Rym: on Saturday.
Rym: We're going to give a lecture.
Rym: that's kind of like our play dirty to win panel, but pretty much just focused on fucking people over in Carcassonne.
Scott: Teach you how to play Carcassonne, how to win at Carcassonne, and then you're all going to play Carcassonne and see who wins.
Scott: It's going to be real interesting to see who wins when everyone knows all the secrets of how to win.
Rym: It's like battle bots and we're making the bots and then making them fight with each other.
Scott: It's like giving.
Scott: it's like giving all these people like plus ten magic swords and then having them swing about each other.
Scott: It's going to be great.
Rym: I'm really also.
Rym: it's a tabletop packs like that my whole life.
Scott: That same weekend in New York City at the Javits is Anime NYC, which we would go to if it were not also PAX Unplugged the same weekend.
Rym: I think anyway, NYC might be sold out or almost sold out now.
Scott: Really?
Scott: That is fascinating.
Scott: I guess it's worth going to.
Rym: Yeah, I like we said we would we would be there if PAX Unplugged weren't at the same time.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And then if you can make it to next year, the first week of next year, you have New Year's, then you've got.
Scott: the next weekend is Magfest and the weekend after that is Pac South.
Scott: Oh, baby.
Scott: Ah, that's the way to start the year.
Scott: If you're not starting a year like that, why live?
Rym: The only problem is that that's a twenty eighteen starter because, as you know, Scott and I sort of split up the duties of what we do for GeekNights.
Rym: And one of the things I do is actually arrange all our shit at cons.
Rym: It's actually been somewhat trying to arrange gamer hacks, Pac South, Pac's unplugged and Magfest all at the same time.
Rym: I thank the gods.
Rym: I'm not going to Pac's house.
Scott: I'm making the.
Scott: oh yeah.
Scott: Pac's house is like this weekend.
Rym: I know.
Scott: Right.
Rym: There's the thread in the forums.
Rym: rocking because I'm working.
Scott: Work on new panel right now.
Scott: I already started.
Rym: Yeah, I put that.
Scott: I put I don't know when we're going to use this panel.
Rym: I put a version of it in for Magfest because fuck it.
Rym: OK, but I put it in as an invite panel.
Rym: So we might use it partly to get someone smart like Dr.
Rym: Hazard also on the panel.
Rym: We can have present and have to learn.
Rym: And then you might we might learn some stuff we can incorporate in the final version of the panel anyway.
Rym: So, yeah, a lot of stuff coming up.
Rym: I will pick the next book club book, but I'm going to defer a little bit because I actually want to read the rest of the fifth season trilogy.
Scott: And I feel like every time I pick a book club book, right.
Scott: It's always the start of some series.
Scott: And you go on to read the whole fucking thing because I want I haven't picked a series yet.
Rym: And that right.
Scott: And then when you pick a book club book, it's just like I picked a one off book.
Scott: I guess I'm just better at picking book club books and you and I'll pick it.
Rym: I'll pick a series book this time.
Rym: We'll see what happens.
Rym: Plus, Wheel of Time is a special case.
Rym: I'm still kind of shocked that I read that whole thing.
Scott: I don't know why you read the whole thing because now I know.
Rym: I know literally everything one can know.
Scott: I can live and die and not regret not knowing everything.
Scott: I just want to know about the snake men because there's nothing to know.
Rym: Well, there's a little bit to know and I know it all.
Scott: OK, great.
Rym: The problem is knowing any one thing in the wheel of time is useless unless you know all the other things.
Scott: I don't care about the other things.
Rym: Yeah, you would because the other is dependent.
Rym: But anyway, the fifth season is real good and you should read it.
Rym: And if you have not read it yet, I'd recommend not listening to you on Thursday because we're going to assume you read it.
Rym: You're going to wonder why I keep talking about so much metamoment.
Rym: I'm like, yeah, let's get into it then.
Rym: So we played this game at RevuCon called Space Cube.
Rym: So this game is called Sidereal Confluence, Trading and Negotiation in the Elysian Quadrant.
Scott: Now, the story that was told to me about this game, I don't know if it's true or not, but I totally believe it is that someone was trying to make a big four or five X game like, you know, Master of Orion Eclipse situation.
Scott: And they ended up making so much game.
Scott: But then in the revision phase, they wisely trimmed away because that's what makes things good is remove all and remove all the cruft.
Scott: And so you get the pure magical essence.
Scott: And apparently they removed everything from the game, the combat, everything except for this one part of the game where you deal with space trading of cubes and machines and stuff and this free trading mechanic and removed all the other parts of the game.
Rym: So on the super, super high level, everyone has a unique asymmetric character with its own nonsense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I got handed this big old card that looked like a race from like, you know, a game like Master of Orion.
Scott: And I'm like reading all this text and I'm like, oh, my God, why do I have to play this?
Scott: I don't want to let this be a video game.
Scott: I don't want to learn all this while you're reading it.
Rym: So I flip mine over.
Rym: And what I saw on the other side actually terrified me because there was way more shit back there and it looked like game mechanics.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm reading this card and I'm like, why these stupid nerds?
Scott: I can't play nerdy games like this anymore.
Scott: I'm not in high school.
Rym: The thing I see is that the game starts getting unpacked, all these cards start coming out.
Scott: There's like a million cards with a million symbols and a pile of cubes.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, my God.
Rym: And the fascinating thing about this game and before we move any further, it wasn't bad.
Rym: I had a good time with it.
Rym: Like, don't think that we're about to say this game is bad.
Scott: No, I'm just telling you what I was feeling at the time as a chronology.
Rym: But when I looked at the cards.
Rym: It looked like ridiculous bullshit.
Scott: The graphic design has much to be desired and it makes it look like a scary game.
Rym: And like the thing is, it is a scary game, but not nearly as scary as it appears to be.
Scott: No, that's the thing I'm trying to get at.
Scott: is the game looks way scarier than it really is.
Scott: If it had a graphic design makeover and shrunk those alien race cards to be a bit smaller because they don't need to be that big and remove some of its heritage of being a space game, that was about four X or whatever, you would actually be able to see what this game is.
Scott: You know, you can't judge this game by the cover, right?
Scott: If you made it so you could judge it by the cover, then all those feelings from the start of it would go away.
Scott: And you just have the reality of it, which is it's a lot like just a free trading game.
Scott: You trade stuff for stuff and see who gets the most victory points at the end.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's really all there is to it.
Rym: So thus the very fascinating things about this game was that once we learn the core mechanics, which took a while, I'm very much reminded of the concept of naive art.
Rym: when there is a known craft with its own sort of assumptions and best practices like knitting or whatever.
Rym: So it is entirely possible for someone who has never studied knitting, never read a knitting book, but has simply enjoyed the knitting of others and just started on their own learning how to knit, they might make perfectly great things, but they might do things in ways that would seem weird to someone who has more like domain knowledge of the craft.
Scott: Yeah, because they don't know they're not learning from the past.
Scott: They're just trying to learn on their own and rediscovering everything that has already been learned.
Rym: And I don't know if that's what happened with this game, but quote naive art is any form of visual art that is created by a person who lacks the formal education and training the professional undergoes, blah, blah, blah.
Scott: But it feels like that's what this game is.
Rym: In the sense that the mechanics it has are not that far from mechanics that I am well used to in just my general board gaming experience.
Rym: And anyone who plays euro games has encountered time and time again.
Rym: But the way they are presented, the way they are explained, the proper nouns, all those things made them alien to me until it was explained.
Rym: The things are not called what I expect them to be called mechanics that I would expect to be explained simply or explained in great depth, but end up being the simple mechanic I didn't expect them to be.
Rym: Things like that.
Rym: The other fascinating thing is that this game, the individual cards, like the player boards, give very specific advice on how you should play that character.
Scott: And it was very not right advice.
Rym: Well, mine was actually pretty much extremely right, because all mine said was you're going to have this one machine out fucking use it as much as possible.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Scott: That's an advice you could actually follow.
Rym: So you know what I did?
Rym: I did nothing but get the cubes to fuel that machine and make sure that I fueled it every single round, no matter what.
Scott: So basically, so here's how the game works.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is you basically have these cards and each card is a machine and it has a cube that goes in and cubes that come out.
Scott: So you have a. I'm just going to make up a machine off my head because I can't see any right now.
Scott: I'm looking for one blue cube comes in and purple cube and a victory point come out.
Scott: That's actually a way good machine.
Scott: It's like, you know, this victory point is rare.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Victory point is super rare.
Scott: There's big cubes which are medium rare, small cubes, which are super common, you know, and you have all these machines in front of you.
Scott: And what you'd really like to do is use every machine, every turn.
Rym: That would be ideal because every machine outputs more than you put into it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's no machine that is not beneficial to run.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you want to run every machine you can to basically increase your economy, get more stuff.
Scott: If you have more stuff, you can do more stuff.
Scott: If you can do more stuff, you can get more victory points and win.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, every round you're going to produce a bunch of cubes from these planets you have.
Scott: They just spit out cubes for nothing.
Scott: Also, every round is the sequence where you can.
Rym: I think I had some planets that I actually had to put a cube on.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: Uh, anyway, I think I did anyway.
Rym: I kind of remember this game was so I got to look at my phone.
Rym: I took pictures of my board.
Scott: Anyway, there's also a phase everywhere where you secretly do a simultaneous reveal of stuff to try to win new planets with ships or something.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There was a moderate amount of drama there that I actually did enjoy, too.
Scott: But in the end, it's the main part of the game is there is a phase in which you freely trade stuff with everybody.
Scott: You can make deals for the future.
Scott: You can do a completely free trading, even more than traders of Genoa.
Scott: You can just trade whatever you can feel like multiplayer trades.
Rym: Like, yeah, I'll give you four cubes.
Rym: You can let each of you give me one of these cubes and then you can trade planets.
Scott: You can lend someone a machine for a turn that you then get back.
Scott: You can there's a one character as wild cubes that no one else has.
Scott: They can trade those.
Scott: It's like you can trade your ships.
Rym: What's funny is no one wanted his wild cubes like no one needed them.
Scott: You can trade friggin anything for anything.
Scott: So you basically what you do is you assign all the cubes you have to your machines to say, aha, this is how many machines I can run.
Scott: Then you look and you say, well, I could run that machine.
Scott: If I had one more blue cube, you look at the cubes you're not using and you say, hey, who wants to trade me a blue cube for these cubes?
Scott: I'm not using and maybe someone else has a blue cube.
Scott: They're not using.
Scott: And now both of you end up running more machines if you make the trade and so on.
Scott: So every turn you're trying to make trades to run as many machines as you can.
Scott: And then you try to get stuff in the auctions and the buying phases.
Rym: So what you're actually trying to get, the only thing you are judged on in the end of these purple victory points, and there are not many ways to get them.
Scott: The main way to get them is to discover new sciences.
Scott: And what are new sciences?
Scott: They're really just machines, right?
Scott: There's a stack of cards.
Rym: There's some weird mechanics around them.
Rym: Like they're there.
Rym: If I was going to design a game like this, I would probably get rid of that and let it just be the core machines and not this somewhat complicated.
Scott: Anyway, the way the most points is to basically discover these science cards.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And when you discover a science, you get this new machine because you discovered some science and then you get to use it.
Scott: And then the next turn, everyone else gets that machine, too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you get the exclusive right to use it for a turn and then everyone else gets to start using it to turn after.
Scott: However, that might not seem like, well, why would I discover this science if everyone else gets to use it?
Scott: Well, just one turn later.
Scott: Well, using it for the one turn is beneficial.
Scott: But being the discoverer, you got a shit ton of victory points.
Rym: Now, what do we say?
Rym: Shit, like five victory points is a big goddamn deal.
Scott: You got a lot of points.
Rym: if you discover you'll have turns where you have like 20 cubes in front of you churning around.
Rym: And the output of all that nonsense is like two victory points and you're very happy with yourself.
Scott: The other thing is that to discover these sciences, you need to have a lot of cubes that are very and are all the same kind.
Scott: And that is hard to do because you crank all your machines and they spit out a pile of cubes.
Scott: But those cubes are going to be all sorts of different funny colors all over the place.
Rym: You know, there's making a lot of green cubes.
Scott: I like to get at some of the sciences.
Scott: It was like you need 12 blue cubes.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, I got a 10 and no one's going to trade me any.
Scott: like I was about to get someone to trade me one.
Scott: And they're like, wait a minute.
Scott: And they didn't trade me because they saw that I would basically win the game if they did that.
Scott: And they were right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So that's the the only real problem I have with this game, because, again, the naive aspect doesn't really bother me.
Rym: That's just sort of fascinating, but because the game was good.
Rym: But when we played it, the machine management itself, the solo game of manage my machine, even if there was no trading, is actually pretty complex and interesting in its own right.
Scott: There are also.
Scott: the one interesting thing is that some machines, including your starting ones, could be upgraded.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, oh, yeah.
Scott: That mechanic you try to get you can get victory points for doing that, too.
Rym: It's like I don't like burn a science and upgrade in order to in order to upgrade mine.
Scott: I needed forest planets to like devour and I was trying to get people to trade me forest.
Rym: And I had a ton of them, but you wouldn't give me enough cubes.
Scott: I could didn't have enough cubes.
Rym: Well, that was going to give you my forest planet that gave me free green cubes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, you see the idea here and this the board, my starting suggestion seemed to imply that people would totally trade me those and they totally wouldn't know the science.
Rym: upgrade pads are sort of interesting in that they they give you another route to sort of optimize and build your own world and adjust to the semi randomness that might be coming at you from other players.
Scott: The other thing is that when you start discovering lots of sciences or other players discover lots of sciences, some of those machines, the sciences can be upgraded by discarding other ones.
Scott: So it's like it's like I'll give up this machine I never use.
Scott: And that allows me to flip over this machine and make it better.
Rym: I upgraded all of my starting machines because I had these weird like double machines.
Scott: I wanted to because I gave a ton of victory points, but I was only able to do like two out of four, I think, because people wouldn't trade me there.
Rym: I upgraded mine because it basically like I started spitting out more medium cubes, which is free medium cubes all over the place.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: My ability was that if I got a planet from the board, not from trading, but if I bought one in the auction, then basically I it would be a double planet and spit out double the cubes.
Scott: And that was crazy, ridiculously powerful, which is why I was trying to win a planet every single turn.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: However, my ships were like half power or something because I was the plant people.
Scott: So I had to get tons of ships and trades with people and then spend them all.
Rym: See, the machine I kept cranking that it told me crank, it gave me a ton of ships every time I cranked it.
Rym: So I always had a bunch of ships and pretty much get whatever I wanted anyway.
Rym: So the other really interesting thing is, remember, we said that the game gives very specific advice to the players.
Rym: The game gives up.
Rym: I've never seen a game give this detail of helpful directional heuristics.
Scott: It was like a strategy guide.
Rym: So on every machine, there'll be a ratio.
Rym: It'll be like three to four or three to five or one to two or three and a half to four or three and three quarters to four.
Rym: The game basically assigns an arbitrary value to everything that can be in the game, like every kind of cube and any machine.
Rym: It'll give you this number.
Rym: That is a pretty good heuristic or representation of in general how much value add the machine is in an abstract sense.
Rym: Also, on your little player help for four to seven machine is definitely giving you more bang for your buck than a six to seven machine.
Scott: Also, on your player help card, there's a little chart that shows you what a fair trade generally is.
Scott: It's like, oh, yeah, trading three small cubes is about equal to a medium cube.
Scott: And like about two medium cubes is about equal.
Scott: It's like the fanciest octagon cube that I never had to use for.
Scott: And it's like it takes you know, it's like about this many things is worth one victory point.
Scott: It's like it tells you it is big, long strip.
Scott: What's equal?
Scott: How many of what is equal to what?
Scott: And that is so nobody.
Scott: if you pay attention to that, you shouldn't be able to get ripped off because you know what values of things are instead of having to just guess.
Scott: Yeah, like I see a lot of people that's good, I think, because first of all, I think you've got to avoid being trapped by that because there's times where it's like, well, I need to make this uneven trade because actually it pays out bigger for me because I can activate one more machine.
Scott: But also a lot of people who play games with open trading have no idea how to value things at all when there's just free valuing.
Rym: Now, if it's a relatively simple game, figuring that out is one of the skills of the game.
Rym: I feel like if I had to figure that out, I just wouldn't trade it with anyone.
Rym: Maybe this game's got so much going on.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, you know, people who play games with just like where they have to value things on their own.
Scott: A lot of people have trouble with that.
Scott: So telling people what a fair trade is protects them from sharky good players trying to rip them off.
Rym: I think that the majority of games of modern art I've ever played have had at least one player bid more money for a painting than it could possibly be worth in the best possible circumstances.
Rym: There is literally I can think of almost no reason you should ever do that.
Scott: It's like that painting, no matter what the draw is, if you get the perfect draw for the rest of the game, that painting will be worth 50.
Scott: Why are you bidding 60?
Scott: You're just losing ten dollars.
Scott: Why would you do this?
Rym: You're giving me an extra ten dollars for nothing.
Rym: Are you sure?
Rym: And they're always sure.
Rym: They always think they got a good plan.
Rym: I never understood why I don't.
Rym: I don't get it, but I've never seen a game give this granular level of like base pricing or base heuristics embedded into the game and coupled with the player advice, which again is shockingly specific.
Rym: I just don't know.
Rym: I don't know how I feel about that in the long run.
Rym: I don't know if it's a good idea or a bad idea.
Rym: I don't know if it's a sign that maybe the game needs to be more elegant or if it's a way to take a messy game and make it playable with a smaller number of learning games.
Rym: It's a complicated situation.
Scott: All I can say is that the name of this game and the graphic design of this game and the heritage of this game make it seem like a scary, scary, complicated for X space game when in reality it's just a game where you trade cubes, put them in a machine to get more cubes as efficiently as possible to get more cubes.
Scott: And hopefully you have the most victory cubes at the end of the game.
Scott: And it's a really straightforward kind of game.
Scott: If you like trading with people and bargaining, then this is the game for you, especially if you like wooden cubes and an outer space theme and asymmetry, a little bit of asymmetry.
Scott: This game could be way fun for you.
Scott: It's like, hey, it's not bad.
Scott: But I think if they fix the graphic design and maybe reduced some of the text on the cards, it would actually be much more approachable.
Scott: So don't be you got to.
Rym: you know, if you're really in the mood for trading trades of Genoa or this, it's hard to say, though, because at the same time, a lot of the clutter on the cards is things like showing you what's on the back of a card that could be flipped.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Or that heuristic, which I feel like without the heuristic, it would take a couple of plays before you could actually play the game.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the other real problem is that if the game is primarily about trading among our group, which was all like super savvy, sharp players, no one was willing to trade unless they were fucking ripping someone off in most cases, which is how we do.
Rym: So there wasn't that much trading.
Rym: Right.
Rym: I would I would always like almost always, if I couldn't get a good trade, I'd just say fuck it and work on my machine.
Rym: And Matt gave some good feedback that by the time he had optimized his machine and knew what he wanted to do to trade, everyone else was done trading.
Rym: It didn't care anymore.
Rym: I just know that I feel like it's more that the machine and the trading are both equal cognitive loads.
Rym: And unless everyone in the group sets the balance between the two in terms of how they spend their term at around the same place, either some people are never going to get to trade.
Scott: I think his cognitive load was bigger because his cubes were wild, whereas I drew mine was just like, oh, I have.
Scott: I went basically went down each machine in order of efficiency and power and was like, can I power this one?
Scott: Yes, I have the cubes for that assigned.
Scott: I just went down until, well, I can't possibly power any more machines and I can't possibly get more efficiency out of the machines.
Scott: Let's look at the what I have left and try to trade it to get ships and whatever I need.
Rym: See, I would.
Rym: I would look from the perspective of here are things I want to do and here are things I like to do.
Rym: And I would make a short note in my head of the kinds of cubes I need to do the things I'd like to do.
Rym: And I wouldn't actively try to trade with people.
Rym: I would listen.
Rym: And if I heard anyone say the type of cube that I needed for the thing I'd like to do, I would look up and try to make a deal.
Rym: But otherwise, I ignored what everyone else was doing.
Rym: And then I had a second bucket of things I had to do and I can't do with my machine.
Rym: And that was the only time I would actually go up and say, anyone got any green cubes?
Rym: I need green cubes, anyone, any Bueller, anyone.
Rym: But I do.
Rym: I do feel like a problem is if I were trying to play this game more seriously, there's another thing I'd have to take into account, which is the thing you take into account in every other game that allows trading.
Rym: How close is Scott to winning?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: How many points does?
Scott: it is very difficult to track the positional heuristic.
Scott: I wanted to sort of spread my trades evenly in the game so that way I wouldn't benefit anyone else more.
Scott: Because when you trade with someone and it's you're not getting ripped off, you're basically boosting the two of you ahead of all the other players.
Scott: So if I trade with everyone evenly, I'm boosting myself, boost, boost four times because four other players, but that's not enough.
Rym: You got to pay attention.
Scott: They're getting boosted once.
Rym: each is Rym trading with Chris a lot, because if that's true, you don't want to trade with Chris at all, probably, because then if you spread evenly, Chris is still plus one.
Rym: Yeah, but there's almost there's.
Rym: I don't think there's any way for a human to keep track of that.
Scott: I could not keep track of who had what points really at all.
Scott: It was too hard.
Scott: And plus you keep.
Scott: you get these victory point chips and keep them secret behind a shield.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So so what I wonder is the people who are deeply into this game and really focus on the trading.
Rym: I wonder if they just trade more without considering the true ramifications of their trading.
Scott: The victory points are behind a shield, too.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Or are they perhaps the kinds of people who might be drawn to this kind of game or graphic design, the kinds of people who will let the game take six hours to ensure that they fully explore the trading and the machining on every turn?
Rym: Because this feels like the kind of game to where there are people who will play it for six hours and enjoy every minute of those six hours.
Scott: We played it much faster than that.
Scott: I could be if we played it again, knowing the rules now, we could play it much, much faster than it looks like.
Scott: It looks like a game that will take six hours.
Scott: We could play it in like one hour and maybe a little more.
Rym: I think hour and a half.
Rym: We could crank this game out if everyone already knew how to play.
Scott: And I didn't have to remember anything and such and such.
Rym: And everyone is willing to not try to track a true positional heuristic of all the other players because I don't think it's possible.
Rym: I wonder if you could make the trading more interesting.
Rym: You couldn't really fully structure it because that'd be a very different game and it would probably take a lot longer.
Rym: But if there were some way to implicitly advertise trades, like if you had a set of boards, you could like just put in front of you, that's like, I want to trade this because I know if I could have looked up and seen advertised trades, that might have sped up my own turn instead of everyone yelling at each other all the time.
Rym: But the
Scott: one thing this game actually got me thinking about was not not you know, it's not something I think this game should do, but maybe for a different game is, you know, we just talked about the knowing who you're trading with because you don't want to boost the person who's in first along with yourself.
Scott: You want to trade with people below you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or even with you to boost up and catch up to the people who are ahead of you if you're not in first already.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Is a game where somehow you could trade but not know who you're trading with.
Scott: You just see deals and you can make them or not make them based on their own merits, not knowing who's on the other end.
Scott: And that, you know, just some kind of game.
Scott: I'm sure there might be a game like that, but, you know, I've never played it.
Scott: It would be cool if there was a game like that.
Scott: Perhaps it could use some sort of market as a middleman to obfuscate the who you're trading with or something.
Scott: Uh, and thus, you know, you wouldn't have this sort of like politics that would go in a game like that, but you still have all the fun of trading and making deals because you'd be like, all right, I'll trade three blue cubes for two greens and and it's no one knows it's you.
Rym: And so anyone who's willing to trade two greens for three blues is look and sees that and it's like, but that does remove what a lot of people like about these kinds of free form trading games, which is the politics side.
Rym: Yeah, the negotiation.
Scott: Well, I think here's the thing.
Scott: I think if you did this, you could somehow keep the negotiation right.
Scott: But by making the recipient of the person offering the trade anonymous, I think you actually flip the negotiation to the other side, right?
Scott: If I go to you in a game Rym and I say, hey, Rym, I see you got two greens, I'll trade you one blue for it.
Scott: What do you do?
Scott: You go, give me two blue.
Scott: Yeah, because I'm the one asking and I'm asking you.
Rym: Well, you kept saying, hey, anyone got any forest colonies?
Rym: I'm like, fuck you.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: As I look at my five forest college.
Scott: But now let's say let's make it suddenly anonymous with this market aspect, right?
Scott: Where there's some sort of intermediary and all you see out is out on the board, the opportunity to trade those two greens for a blue and maybe someone else sees it, too.
Scott: So suddenly no longer is it.
Scott: I'm going to give Scott as little as I can for that blue I need.
Scott: It's now I need to get that blue because someone else is going to take that deal off the board.
Scott: And now you're suddenly putting three greens or four greens because someone else is going to put in three greens, right?
Scott: So you just by taking away knowing who the recipient is, you can suddenly it's now more of an eBay situation and less of a give Scott as little as possible situation.
Rym: That'd be easy.
Rym: A video game that is very difficult to do in a physical game.
Scott: Oh, yes, yes, yes, obviously.
Rym: But that's why I wonder if some sort of player aid, like not a rule, like I don't want to add structure to this.
Rym: I don't want it to be like Res Publica.
Rym: We're like, I have two blue cubes.
Scott: Yeah, no.
Scott: Oh, Res Publica.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I don't want that.
Scott: Yeah, that was interesting, though.
Scott: But yeah, not that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I really wonder if you put some soft mechanic where they were player aids like a pool of cards or cardboard things where you could basically advertise trades without having to keep yelling at everyone like you have a common area in the middle and I can just put like three advertised trades like I'm willing to trade blue cubes and I like here's three blue cubes and willing to trade.
Scott: There is some physical mechanism for creating a trade advertisement and then you could shuffle them.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: And then you've splay them out and you know which ones are yours because you made them.
Rym: Oh, I don't even want to shove.
Rym: I don't even care about the anonymous part because even better, you know what?
Scott: Maybe some of them are yours and you know what?
Scott: You shuffle them up and you splay them out, right?
Scott: You accidentally trade yourself because I put down trade one blue for two green, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Maybe I want to turn a blue into two green.
Scott: So I put it out there and then I use it.
Scott: I make the deal with myself, but I guess, oh, but those are my two green.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Nevermind.
Rym: It's like buying your own stock through scotch ride.
Rym: Like you're just paying $14 son.
Rym: So, but indeed because it is impossible to keep a reasonable positional heuristic in this game on all the other players and you have to just sort of ignore that aspect.
Rym: I feel like you can avoid the politics situation by just letting it wash over you and focusing on making good machine.
Rym: That's what I did and focusing on good trades.
Rym: That's what I did.
Rym: But then to keep the spirit of the game instead of doing some structural change like you're talking about, just having physical implements to be able to advertise trades without having to yell constantly.
Rym: That would make this game cleaner to play.
Rym: The only problem with that is that there is no table on earth that will have enough free space for said trade advertisement pieces.
Scott: This game has got a lot of stuff.
Scott: It takes up a lot of room.
Scott: You need a big table.
Scott: There's going to be cubes everywhere.
Rym: We were playing games on a table that was big enough for us, our group to play two separate giant games and yet a small game of sidereal nonsense literally covered every square inch of the table.
Scott: Granted it was two, three player games and this was one five player game.
Rym: I do not own or know of a game that I would be willing to play that takes up more table space than this game.
Scott: I think Eclipse takes up more space than this.
Rym: I think Eclipse might not actually take up more space than this.
Scott: I think it does.
Scott: Definitely.
Rym: Maybe with the science area.
Scott: Yeah, Eclipse definitely takes up more than this.
Rym: Of course I remember the way we got around that is we put the science area on the other side of the room just like on it so you could walk on a second table.
Scott: because Eclipse is so big this game doesn't need a second table, but this game, it's just all your shit.
Rym: Like your, your splay will be all over the place.
Scott: Yes, it was big.
Rym: Uh, but yeah, I enjoyed this game despite not expecting to based on my initial impression, looking at the rules or the graphics.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I would play it again.
Scott: The art, the art that is there that is like not the graphic design, but the art, the drawings is way good.
Rym: Also the art of the proper nouns as in the world.
Rym: Uh, I'm not the kind of person who cares about that sort of thing.
Rym: There is a lot of world building nonsense all over the place.
Rym: Everything's got proper nouns, everything and the proper nouns are very proper nouny.
Scott: Anyway, so yeah, if you're into, if you want free trading, a big pile of cubes, uh, you know, some sort of relatively hardcore ish board gaming and a relatively unique experience because I've never played a free form trading game that has this scale of nonsense to deal with.
Scott: Then go for this.
Scott: Otherwise don't go for this, but if you want to trade, you can play Bonanza or Traders of Genoa or something.
Rym: Bust this game out.
Rym: If you've got friends who are a little bit bored of games like Traders of Genoa and have already played a lot of games, this is not a first baby's first board game by any stretch, but I do want to play it again.
Rym: I will play it again.
Scott: I might play it again.
Rym: I want to play it at least one more time.
Scott: Sure, I could go.
Scott: I could do.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, a shimmering Ruby Obelisk hanging in the sky, mystady.com, Jeremy Minor, a genuine bonafide electrified six-car monorail, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brandow, Captain Chinguakasi, Rebecca Dunn, 421 Creations, You Ever Wonder Why We're Here, Shervin Von Horrell, Rare LaValle, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Rym Says Something Funny Here, Sailor Vista, Don Schleich, Kjar Tavashin, Joshiro Joestar, Sam Corddry, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Opendlander, Brian Cedroni, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We are, as you saw, slowly picking up the schedule again, and we have a huge queue of both Tuesday and Wednesday episodes of GeekNights, and we'll do something for Thursdays.
Rym: But anyway, I leave you with- It's just like us, we're all trick-or-treating for candy, just like us.
Scott: Look.
Scott: See?
Scott: I'm no scaredy cat.
Media: I may be lazy, I may be fat, I don't do laughs, and I do not chat, but I may be selfish, yeah, and all of that, but the one thing I'm not is a scaredy cat.
Media: I may be bossy, I may lack grace, I don't do sit-ups to trim my waist, I may be thoughtless, yeah, and all of that, but the one thing I'm not is a scaredy cat.
Media: I don't have charm or much pizzazz, I don't chase mice and all that jazz, I may be sassy, yes, and all of that, but the one thing I'm not, yeah, the one thing I'm not, I say the one thing I'm not is a scaredy cat.