Rym: It's Tuesday April 25th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: okay, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: the grizzled a cooperative World War one.
Rym: misery game the cards.
Scott: misery game is a.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: so it's Tuesday, and I know you nerds want us to talk about video games and we will.
Rym: but Hockey is a game and the Rangers have made it to a second round And the most.
Rym: the most fascinating and wonderful thing that's happened in hockey right now is I'm sad that the Leafs didn't knock the caps out because that would have been funny, but the fact that the Predators Swept the Blackhawks is Just.
Rym: I still can't get over how funny I find that and I kind of hope the Predators push it all the way to the.
Rym: now I'm kind of rooting for them over there.
Rym: cuz who cares?
Rym: what happens over there like About the Blues?
Rym: care about the Blues the Oilers.
Scott: No nobody can.
Rym: yeah someone cares.
Rym: at least one person cares.
Rym: Mm-hmm sure you're pretty low energy today.
Scott: What's going on?
Scott: It's a sad day.
Rym: It's not that sad It's just miserable.
Rym: outside and dark and cold and rainy and windy I Literally I was sitting at my desk like thinking to myself.
Rym: I was having that.
Rym: what I was thinking was could I Sneak into one of the conference rooms and just take like a nap What anyone notice.
Rym: and I'm thinking that.
Rym: and then Scott messaged me, and he's just like I'm so tired I almost fell asleep at my desk.
Scott: I did almost fall asleep my days.
Rym: It's that kind of day.
Rym: So you got any news other than hockey?
Rym: Uh News yeah, there's like seven people watching now.
Scott: sad seven sad seven people.
Rym: okay one of them is pooping though the What do you got?
Scott: oh so Mario Kart 8 deluxe for a switch comes out like this week.
Scott: ish Yeah, it's gonna be 50 or 60 bucks.
Scott: Which is a lot of money.
Rym: I thought for a minute last week I was like oh shit.
Rym: I should pre-order that.
Rym: and then I remembered that I'm just buying everything digital shop.
Scott: I'm just gonna buy it.
Rym: No buy it on Amazon and it all.
Rym: it basically Automatically through your Nintendo account activates it and downloads it on your switch without you having to do anything And you get the Amazon discount from the Amazon credit card.
Scott: okay, so it just makes the game cheaper, so This is a re-release of the Wii U Mario Kart Mario Kart 8.
Scott: It's not any different, but the one notable thing is that unlike the original Mario Kart 8 for Wii U this Mario Kart?
Scott: Everything is just fucking unlocked as soon as you turn the game on.
Scott: you don't to unlock all this bullshit.
Scott: Thank you Jesus, and it has some extra characters and stuff I think they added like Splatoon characters and stuff.
Rym: what I mean?
Rym: you might remember we did our grind panel.
Rym: I have this whole Segment about.
Rym: look at all the grindy shit you have to do in Mario Kart games to unlock basic functionality.
Rym: I wish super Bomberman R. Would take a page from that.
Scott: yeah, so Bomberman R They made it up a patch to it.
Scott: I haven't tried it since the patch came out.
Scott: I think like today.
Scott: Maybe the patch came out where they increased the frame rate to 60 FPS Which is great because it was sort of having problems with frame rate when we played it right?
Rym: It was hard to tell because I we some of it was internet lag.
Rym: Yeah, we were playing it online with our man.
Scott: I definitely noticed it being slightly imprecise compared to other Bomberman's.
Scott: so I'm.
Scott: I've heard the 60 FPS.
Scott: This you know cleans it up, but to do that they cut the resolution cuz.
Scott: hey look the switch ain't that powerful.
Scott: Yeah, but then again.
Scott: It's like wait a minute.
Scott: This is just fucking Bomberman.
Scott: You can play fucking Zelda on this thing.
Scott: Why is no Bomberman a problem?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I mean I get a frame stutter occasionally in Zelda But it's usually in like really grassy areas with a bunch of little guys Mm-hmm, but I get them pretty reliably.
Rym: There's a few places the map or a beetle pretty much Always stutter if I look around at all.
Scott: I think if they work harder on the code They could probably optimize it more.
Rym: But I feel like it doesn't matter that much though because how much resolution needed for Bomberman?
Scott: Can you see the bombs?
Rym: good you only need high-res for Bomberman if you're gonna have giant map options Which this game clearly does not know.
Scott: it's not Bomberman high-ten.
Scott: Nah, which is the first HD video game as far as I'm aware.
Rym: So uh yeah, I'm actually really excited about this Mario Kart because I'm pretty sure my favorite Bomberman That's modern because I know you're what you're about to say is the one on the 3ds, but Mario Kart 8 Like the one that we used to play.
Scott: Oh the GameCube one N64 was an N64 or a GameCube one that we liked a lot.
Rym: I don't think we like the N64 one that much.
Scott: I think it was a GameCube one that had a crappy single-player as most Bomberman's do.
Scott: yeah Bomberman's yeah.
Rym: No, I'm talking about Mario Kart Mario Kart.
Scott: Yeah, the best Mario Kart is a GBA one.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, and I was trying to have it off because that's not modern.
Rym: the most the modern one.
Scott: It's not modern about it.
Scott: It was the second Mario Kart game ever.
Rym: I actually prefer the 3ds one.
Scott: That's kind of crazy to think about right?
Scott: the first Mario Kart game was this oh No is the third Mario Kart game.
Rym: first Mario Kart was on the Super Nintendo.
Scott: right then I don't know if Mario Kart 64 came out first or the.
Scott: I think the Mario Kart 64 came out next was the second Mario Kart And that the GBA one was the third one.
Scott: Super Circuit, but Super Circuit is still the best Mario Kart.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I actually really like Mario Kart 8, but I've never owned it.
Rym: I've played it at other people's houses because I wasn't dumb enough to buy a Wii U. But now that I can get Mario Kart 8 Deluxe with everything unlocked on the switch I really just feel bad for the people who bought it on the Wii U because you probably still haven't unlocked everything Most every time I've played that game at someone's house
Scott: But I'm the only reason I'm thinking maybe not is that I've had many Mario Karts with unlocking.
Scott: I had the Wii one right for example and that had unlocking and I had the GBA one that Unlocking right.
Scott: and every time I had a Mario Kart where things needed to be unlocked I unlocked them all.
Scott: so I assume if I had the Wii U one I would be able to unlock them all.
Rym: I mean Yeah, but I don't know I mean.
Rym: the only Mario Kart I've ever fully unlocked myself was the 3ds one because I would just play it everywhere like all the Time.
Rym: yeah No every single player problem with it was no one ever play with.
Scott: but that's the reason I'm gonna buy this Mario Kart 8 is Because even if people don't come over to my house and play it or anything, right?
Scott: Every Mario Kart I've ever owned I have played and beaten all the single-player cups on 5100 150 and I think this one is 200 CC.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Scott: and every single course first place Alright and every single course, so I feel like if I did that in all those Mario Karts I'm gonna do it on this one too.
Rym: on the 3ds one I went further and went after the ghosts real hard on the GBA one at.
Scott: my ghosts if they're still in there are Perhaps unbeatable.
Rym: dude in the era of snaking I made some fucking snake ghosts.
Scott: Well, this was in a no snake real skill Mario Kart.
Rym: Hey snaking was a skill.
Rym: It was just a very painful and annoying one, but it was a skill.
Rym: Yeah, if you don't think it's a skill It's race you want to play?
Scott: Yeah, let's play GBA Mario Kart the real Mario Kart and see who wins.
Rym: Let's play let's let's do a tournament of every Mario Kart.
Rym: He's the best overall.
Rym: That's the entire Mario Kart.
Rym: That's not a bad idea.
Scott: I'm saying it's not shabby.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty good.
Rym: That'd be a good livestream event.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: We just got to get emulators set up for all the odd Mario Kart.
Scott: I think we could probably manage to get a copy of every kind of Mario.
Rym: Yeah, I don't have a working Super Nintendo physically Though we could just emulate that one.
Rym: Yeah, I don't have an n64.
Rym: emulate that too.
Rym: Yeah, those emulators aren't great though.
Scott: Also Mario Kart 64 people might hate me on this is the worst one.
Rym: I agree.
Scott: You might think that the ones with the ones that are broken with snaking are not as broken and stupid as that n64.
Rym: Yep, plus if you didn't snake.
Rym: the ones with snaking were actually super great In a lot of ways.
Rym: the Super Nintendo one while it is bad It also gets bonus points for the fact that it was the first one and that it did a lot with the Super Nintendo and the mode 7 graphics.
Rym: So in some other news you guys probably are familiar with g2a.
Rym: We've talked about them on the show occasion.
Scott: If you've never heard of g2a, they're like a sponsor of lots of streamers and that's like how people know about them.
Scott: Yeah, but they are bad dudes.
Rym: Yeah, they're.
Scott: you should not patronize g2a.
Scott: I Un-endorsed them.
Scott: Yeah, do not give them monies or use their website.
Rym: official Anti-endorsement.
Scott: Yes official we were not paid to anti-endorse them.
Rym: now basically now that there's problems ideology Ideologically with what they do, but there's also problems ideologically with having problems with what if you don't know what g2a is.
Scott: It's a website where if you have keys for games and you don't want to you don't want those games you want to sell them You can go there and sell your keys.
Scott: You can also if you want to buy a game You can go there and find someone selling a game key and you can probably get the game cheaper than it would be on steam Or anywhere else and you know what in principle.
Scott: I think that's totally okay.
Rym: Well in principle it is pure market arbitrage.
Rym: Just right if I but usually Badges right.
Scott: if I buy a humble bundle and there's a game in there that I already have a copy of and none of my friends Want it and I can't give it away to anyone.
Scott: I'll put it on g2a.
Scott: I'll sell it for like a dollar and it's like.
Scott: what's wrong with that?
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: I think nothing is wrong with that.
Rym: However, nothing's wrong with that except in the general context of the way the world actually works.
Scott: Oh, whatever, but that hurts publishers, but it favors gamers, which I think is fine.
Rym: Ideally it hurts publishers in the same way that libraries hurt novelists exactly, right?
Scott: But you know, they think it hurts them a lot, but g2a does something else which very much does hurt Everybody and that is just allow criminal activity to happen on their service.
Rym: So it's a bunch of different levels.
Rym: so one of the things that often happens is CD keys will be cheaper in a place where the currency is worth less and they will arbitrage that.
Scott: So someone will buy a shit ton of Russian keys and sell them somewhere else.
Rym: yep, they'll also.
Rym: there have been a bunch of stories of people just fraudulently hitting API's or otherwise getting keys that the publisher never got money for and just Selling them.
Rym: Yep, and like the rabbit hole goes you can read up like is it?
Scott: you can sell any game key on g2a.
Scott: So what if you find a way to get a game key that works but no one ever paid for that game key to the actual Game-maker person?
Rym: they also extort as far as I can tell from these articles game publishers in that they will sell your keys.
Rym: Anyway, they'll only give you a tiny cut if you sign up into their platform and let them be legit with your game.
Rym: But if you say fuck you, you know, we don't want to do business with you They'll keep selling your keys and they won't give you a cut.
Scott: they do all they do.
Scott: things like they have fraud protection But you got to pay for it.
Scott: Yeah, it's just like wait You're gonna just basically allow illegal activity unless you pay you to stop allowing it.
Scott: shouldn't that just be a thing that you do?
Scott: So you can read that Maybe like Gmail like making you pay for the spam filter.
Rym: the news isn't that they exist and are shady.
Rym: You can type that into Google and you're gonna see that.
Rym: the news is that they were at a large game conference recently and they had a panel and the panel looks like you had to keep in mind this panel was coming hot off the Heels of.
Scott: I think that they were doing some sort of thing with.
Scott: is a gearbox?
Scott: Maybe I think is gearbox.
Scott: and then there was a backlash on gearbox Like what the fuck you do with those g2a guys.
Scott: and here I was like, you know what?
Scott: We're not doing nothing with those piece of shit g2a guys.
Scott: Yeah, you know we demand g2a.
Scott: We demand you do all these things.
Scott: Otherwise, fuck you.
Scott: and g2a was like no, so they're like well fuck you then.
Scott: so then they have their man.
Rym: this panel shows up right after that is in the news and they Stupidly Like I feel like at this point people who are at the center of controversy where they are probably at fault.
Rym: There's like a playbook of how to not make it worse And I feel like a lot of these people have never read that playbook because they open it up to audience questions.
Scott: If you're getting berated why would I mean?
Scott: we don't take audience questions and we're usually getting applauded.
Scott: If I'm getting berated, why would I take questions?
Rym: I mean the president of our country currently doesn't take questions because he knows that would be a shit show.
Rym: But one of those only smart things he does they uh, they took questions and you can read what happened.
Rym: but basically as far as I can tell the entire audience was nothing but pissed off game developers and game publishers and They surprised the g2a hasn't just like just been law suited out of existence or jailed out of existence.
Rym: As soon as you're on the international stage like that like it gets kind of tricky to actually go after companies like this I don't actually know where they're based legally.
Scott: I'm surprised that like for example, there are certain things that I'm surprised haven't happened.
Scott: For example, why hasn't Amazon slash twitch banned all twitch people who are sponsored by g2a?
Rym: well because You can't hurt the ecosystem of how the twitch streamers make money because if the streamers stop working twitch stops working.
Scott: I'm just saying like, you know, there are people who aren't sponsored by g2a on twitch, right?
Scott: You could let you know just say hey, no g2a is allowed.
Scott: Yeah, you know that does also set up any other sponsor is fine.
Rym: There is a big line that can get you into get you into tricky situations If you start having taking editorial control of things that you've previously claimed are open and are automated.
Rym: That's the reason why I like a lot of social media platforms Won't just ban Nazis because then they might get sued by other people who say hey if you can ban this kind of content You need to ban this other kind of content.
Rym: That might be illegal in my jurisdiction.
Rym: So there's a lot of reasons why people like to just not take a stance Independent of if that's right, that's the reason.
Rym: but anyway, you can read this article.
Rym: There's some video there that this panel did not go well for them and it's pretty funny.
Scott: So there's that fig thing right which is like the Kickstarter, but you actually are investing in the game somehow Kickstarter for equity the way it were actually, you know, do you know how it works?
Rym: I can explain really briefly.
Rym: You know, this is the rare time when my knowledge of video games and my knowledge of capital market Is it actually combined?
Scott: There's actually some sort of organization that's allowed to invest and they invest and you're buying a piece of it.
Rym: No, no, no, no, so it's actually way better.
Rym: So there was a the I think was the JOBS Act under Obama.
Rym: a thing that it did is that previously There are certain kinds of things you are not legally allowed to invest in unless you are a so-called Accredited investor.
Scott: that means rich person.
Rym: Right accredited investor means that you either meet some other specific requirements or generally you have a net worth Personally of more than 1 million dollars not counting the house you live in so rich person.
Rym: Yeah the rationale Rather or not.
Scott: I'm not by.
Scott: oh wait, does it count houses?
Scott: I don't live in.
Rym: Yes, if you own a bunch of houses that counts.
Scott: So if I bought say a beach house and I wasn't renting it It was just my beach house that would count because I'm only living it in like three months a year.
Rym: Yeah, you could totally use that as part of your you know Getting up to the million dollars, but the house that I'm actually living in nine months of the air.
Scott: No good.
Rym: No good Okay, because you can't you just live in an expensive house.
Rym: You can't be like, yeah, I'm a millionaire.
Rym: No, your house is worth a million dollars.
Rym: What if I live in whatever?
Scott: I live in seven houses each of them one day of the week.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I also take.
Rym: I'm not going to express any opinion on whether or not that is a good regulation.
Rym: But that was.
Rym: that's the thing it is.
Scott: I mean there should be some sir.
Scott: I mean, it's essentially regardless of the details.
Scott: There should be some sort of rule saying who's allowed to invest and who's not.
Scott: Otherwise you get scams going around tricking old ladies into investing in things and stealing all their money.
Rym: It's the producers situation Exactly.
Rym: They're trying to prevent people who have who stand to lose their entire livelihood from investing in Complicated things.
Rym: so you can buy stock without being an accredited investor.
Scott: It's not very complicated Yeah.
Rym: Because then also because there's a lot of protections around like what stock is and all these sorts of things and but like Putting money into private equity like just buying a chunk of a company That is so much riskier than even people who think they understand it realize that the government basically said no No No You got to already be rich or you cannot play in this field because this field is full of literal minds.
Rym: And I can say that because the dictionary says that literal now literally means figuratively, but I digress.
Rym: So the JOBS Act a part of it basically allowed for the concept of crowdsourced investing meaning you basically need an Accredited investor to negotiate the terms of the specific investment and I believe themselves invest in it.
Rym: But then legally any number of other people who are not accredited investors are allowed to invest Directly as long as they have the exact same terms as the accredited investor.
Rym: So one person who ostensibly knows what they're doing Made an investment.
Scott: I have anyway.
Scott: So the actual news here is that fig has done a bunch of things using this method.
Scott: the current one though is a new Xcom ish game from the person who made original Xcom.
Rym: that's kind of a big deal.
Scott: So the there is a newer Xcom game, right?
Scott: That's not bad.
Rym: It's a great game that I don't like but I don't have anything I can really fault with it.
Scott: It's a good game But it's you know that those games were not made by the people who made the original Xcom just the same publisher Whatever right?
Scott: It's not you know, so now it's like oh here finally after a bunch of Xcom clones and actual games with the Xcom License we have a game not called Xcom But basically is an Xcom game from the Xcom creators themselves the same peoples who made Xcom back in the day.
Rym: now It's interesting because the things that it's kind of like with Team Fortress 2 like before.
Rym: The things that made the new Xcom the legit one way better as a game Were the things that made me less interested in it because I kind of enjoyed the weird fiddly bullshit of the old game.
Rym: So when I heard there was new Xcom coming, I kind of wanted the old fiddly bullshit.
Rym: I wonder if this game will be the old fiddly bullshit.
Rym: And if so, I wonder if anyone would like it except People like me.
Scott: screenshots look too good.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: We'll see how this goes.
Rym: I Haven't actually looked into any of the details yet.
Rym: So I don't know.
Rym: Remember that panel.
Rym: we did a PAX way back in like 2009 or 2010 where we were like.
Rym: There's a bunch of egregiously obvious things that no one in games has ever done and this was like the third to last slide.
Rym: Why doesn't someone remake Xcom?
Rym: and now it's happened twice?
Scott: apparently it's happened a lot more than twice.
Rym: Yeah It happened twice for real.
Scott: since we did there have been many many resurrections of dead games like Descent has been.
Scott: Specifically there are quite a few Xcoms out there.
Scott: You're just not looking at up.
Rym: We also wanted the giant massive Star Wars battle game and they actually made that to like.
Rym: so everything we wanted got mostly made but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So it's just like a one-minute video.
Scott: These fine people are in a restaurant of some kind and they get chicken and a burrito Which I could really go for.
Scott: I'll take chicken and a burrito right now and they are just so happy That chicken and burrito they cannot contain.
Scott: the dance the dance bus out Maybe and there's some commentary on the dance.
Scott: That is quite excellent and it's just one of those videos I just make.
Scott: it's only a minute long But there's people in it just being happy and when you watch it you'd be happy too.
Scott: Is the best kind of internet video.
Rym: it grows and grows almost like one of those like continuous take music videos We're like, it's zoomed in on the food item and moves up a little bit.
Rym: You see the happy guy.
Rym: it's more and more happy.
Scott: and the camera times you spent describing this video.
Scott: They could have watched the video.
Scott: It's 50 something seconds long.
Rym: But the moment when you see the people way in the back in the kitchen Reacting to this that's the moment wise if you want to feel good.
Rym: his 50 something seconds of video 56 seconds of hit the log, baby Gotta be.
Rym: yeah, this is good stuff here.
Rym: So, uh, this is the thing.
Rym: I've been saving for a while, but There was a game that I played a lot when I when I was in like Middle school
Scott: because it was the game that was on the computers in your middle school Yep,
Rym: and it was not just my middle school, but also my high school Independently, I found the community for it there.
Rym: But you know, this is so long ago that this was a game where I literally didn't really understand the concept of piracy in Middle school.
Rym: so like one day someone just handed me this floppy disk and said here You should check this out and I put it into the computer and there were.
Rym: there was stunts 40 racing and la checks.
Scott: So this game fit on a one point four four megabyte three and a half inch floppy disk with room to spare To save the custom courses.
Rym: this game was so far ahead of its time That it is shocking.
Scott: You can't even fit a fucking mp3 on that disc One song.
Scott: you ain't even getting one song on there, dude You can barely fit a modern word document on a but you fit this whole goddamn game on there.
Scott: You probably couldn't fit a website on their stunts.
Rym: 40. racing was a fully 3d Like legit racing game with giant maps and it had a full map editor That is way more comprehensive than you're imagining.
Rym: so this game ended up just getting installed on literally every computer in my middle school and People would pass around floppy disks with their high scores on custom tracks They'd made.
Rym: and there was this like weird Trade like there was a currency and some street cred in yo.
Rym: I get a good time on Steve's custom crazy map with the branching paths and we'd like pass it around.
Rym: This game was a shockingly big part of my life And my thing of the day is this article that will basically explain to you the history of this game and how that community legit existed all Over America.
Rym: in fact all over the world and in fact the community of people who are obsessed with this game Persists to this day.
Scott: There's a lot of games like I mean tech.
Scott: people still play tech mobile same same deal.
Rym: So this game.
Scott: look at how much?
Scott: how did the hell do they fit all that?
Scott: and one point four four megabytes?
Rym: Yeah in what 1990?
Scott: Jesus Christ Like.
Rym: look like you could just make custom maps now.
Rym: the game even had a bunch of logic to make sure the maps were legit.
Rym: Like it wouldn't let you make broken maps, but some people even hacked it and messed with it so you could make broken maps so you could then do some interesting stuff.
Rym: and Yeah, you should just read this article.
Rym: this is ultra fascinating.
Rym: the other interesting thing is I couldn't find a screenshot of this.
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: I wanted some help out there.
Scott: It could be a false memory.
Rym: No, no, no, this is a legit memory.
Rym: the game had copy protection in it like games did in the era.
Rym: But basically in southeast, Michigan Every copy of the game that I ever encountered was cracked pre cracked.
Rym: So you did not have to do the copy protection thing.
Rym: the game just worked.
Rym: Mmm, and it put up a splash screen.
Scott: When you started the game it fit that splash screen in the 1.4.
Rym: That said cracked by killa fits because that was the organization or the person I never knew because you know back then there wasn't really an internet.
Scott: kill fit them the evil cracker.
Rym: yeah, like this person was a legend in my middle school because they just made the cracked version of the game and it was on the same floppy disk that had LHX and a cracked version of Scorched earth that had the triple tank without having to pay money in the meta moment.
Scott: The booklet book is Frank Herbert's dune But don't bother read it yet because we're not gonna read it until we both beat Ganondorf on Twitter today by sheer coincidence I saw a tweet that contained a poster for dune drawn by rio ichi ikigami, oh That was pretty good.
Scott: Crying Fremen, perhaps I I favorited that tweet *laughter*.
Rym: This weekend Saturday and Sunday and Friday night, I guess but I won't be doing any panels.
Rym: I will be at Zenkai Con doing grinding mechanics and game design for an anime openers a best of edition of that and Flip the table rage quitting in games.
Rym: So if you're gonna be if you live anywhere in I don't know West Eastern Pennsylvania, you should go to this con.
Rym: I would not fly to go to Zenkai Con But if I lived within driving distance, I would definitely be there.
Rym: It's a pretty legit con and when I'm not doing panels pretty much just gonna be playing tabletop games.
Scott: I'm not going there.
Rym: Yeah, you're not.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: It might be nice weather this weekend though.
Rym: I might have to.
Scott: that's a shame.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I'm glad I didn't agree to go to Pennsylvania.
Rym: I guess I can go for a long run in Pennsylvania.
Rym: There's nothing wrong with that.
Rym: I mean, it's just a forest.
Rym: I guess it's not actually in Philly.
Scott: Mm-hmm, of course Scott, we're gonna show her the Amish people.
Rym: we're gonna be going to Pennsylvania later this year because there is in fact a new packs and We're gonna be at it.
Scott: You uh, we got to make you know, I mean they put a packs in the worst possible place.
Scott: So we Were as possible.
Scott: We have to go and save it.
Scott: What is what place on earth is worse than Philadelphia place?
Rym: Besides Eritrea North Jersey.
Scott: No, I would rather if I were sorry Jersey for all the shittiness actually has quite a bunch of nerds there.
Scott: So does Pennsylvania, but I would rather those are Pennsylvania nerds and not Jersey.
Rym: If I were forced to live in Philly or in I don't know most of North North Jersey I would actually choose Philly but I would not be a Phillies fan or a Flyers fan.
Scott: Why would you do?
Rym: I would basically never follow sports again.
Rym: But the New York is a legit for real packs But it's tabletop only done today.
Rym: That's a big deal for us Because 99% of what we do at PAX is tabletop.
Rym: So this is like if you're like us, this is just packs distilled.
Rym: It's like a mainline.
Rym: It's the heroine of PAX is Other things.
Scott: you should check out our channels on YouTube Twitter Facebook Instagram not streaming a lot of stuff.
Scott: I'm streaming You know, we got channels and also having trouble finding them.
Scott: It's not hard people.
Scott: We got websites and we you know, you can find it if you want to.
Rym: and also we are live streaming Most of the GeekNights episodes.
Scott: Yeah, don't watch that though.
Rym: So there are 18 people watching this right now.
Scott: Two minutes 18 too many people.
Rym: one of them is watching it while they're pooping which that's a better thing to do.
Scott: There's 17 and a half people.
Rym: Yeah But yeah, we do live stream and the show and other things.
Rym: and the only other announcement I have that a lot of you been bugging me about I Still am like I've got the pipeline for new antenna episodes worked out simultaneously.
Rym: I've been hit with a ton more Copyright takedown notices and most of them are from the anime companies and they're block notices not just monetization.
Rym: so if That keeps being a pain in the ass I am just gonna kill the you tennis show because I'm not gonna deal with that crap.
Rym: half of radio free equestria is already taken Down and I've lost the appeals and I'm just giving up on that shit.
Scott: So no, you just got to click the final button.
Scott: This is sue me.
Rym: No Unless you and I sign a contract splitting our liability.
Rym: No, we'll just Legally only I am liable because it's my youtube channel.
Rym: Let's just make an anonymous YouTube channel and Actually anonymous YouTube channels are kind of a pain for a lot of reasons and they'll just get the same DMS.
Scott: They take down notices and then we say yes sue me deal with it.
Rym: Ah, you can't do that.
Rym: Let's give legit contact info.
Scott: Why don't we call these companies up and like, you know talk to them?
Rym: Yeah, we could try to call King Records is actually one of the most reasonable ones.
Rym: They pretty much are like, oh, yeah Sorry, dude fair use every time.
Scott: Why don't we you know, we could settle we don't need to you know, we everyone everyone gets hit by copyright stuff Right, and then they always like the company comes up to them.
Scott: It's like look we're not gonna sue you.
Scott: Let's settle.
Scott: Why don't we go to them and say like look we won't drag you into the obvious fair use if you settle with us.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is because fair use is such a garbage.
Rym: Preston It's not actually obvious and it's playing Russian roulette.
Rym: if you go into court with that stuff We don't we're not going to court.
Scott: We're saying we're just sort of threatening to go to court.
Scott: Yeah We're saying, you know, hey settle with us.
Scott: this is fair use.
Scott: Are you sure you want to come after us?
Scott: Look, just let our videos be where it's not like.
Rym: I feel like that's only a threat if we also say also We're both super rich and we have a lawyer on retainer and we actually have to have a legit lawyer on retainer Who sends that letter.
Scott: couldn't we also just not put clips from actual antenna in the thing?
Rym: I feel like that really Minimizes the usefulness of the show.
Scott: Did we just distribute it on bit torrent?
Rym: That's a pain in the ass.
Rym: Don't want to bother I could.
Scott: it's not a pain in the ass.
Scott: I'll do that.
Rym: Yeah, but it all said then we have no idea if anyone even watches it at all.
Scott: Who cares?
Rym: Oh, yeah, I don't know.
Rym: you can make the show yourself If it's if I'm not putting on my youtube pretty much not bothering.
Scott: See, this is what I'm talking about.
Scott: people Right rims always telling you to watch because he's only doing this for his ego.
Rym: I'm.
Scott: I do pretty much everything in my life for my ego.
Scott: I'm just making stuff.
Scott: cuz I like making stuff and I don't care if you watch and because I know the stuff we make sucks I'm telling you not to watch, you know who to trust.
Rym: I'm very open in my motivations.
Scott: You my Rym doesn't actually care if you're happy or entertained or whatever.
Scott: He just wants, you know to Upon him.
Rym: I assume if you're consuming anything.
Scott: I actually care about your well-being and that's why I say don't watch.
Rym: I pretty much assume Either you are entertained for some reason or you've got an angle and you're about to sue us and you're just gathering information.
Rym: It's one of those two things anyway.
Rym: Anyway so good friend Matt came over the other day and he introduced us to a game that I had never seen or heard of me either and he described it as it is co-op in the way that Hanabi is as opposed to the bad way.
Rym: and It's World War one themed.
Rym: yeah, World War one themed and the art is by the Charlie Hebdo guy who was very tragically murdered by terrorists not that long ago and I like that guy's art style.
Rym: So everything combined.
Rym: This is pretty much a must-play game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that's.
Scott: so we like you didn't know that person ever did art like when they.
Scott: he mentioned that I'm just like what which guy?
Scott: and I'm like really that I did art for a board card game.
Rym: You look at the world.
Rym: Look at this art.
Rym: You're like, oh, yeah, obviously Yeah, and the art is great like this game.
Rym: But if if nothing else if we said nothing about the mechanics the theme and style is just perfect Mm-hmm.
Rym: So there aren't that many World War one games that aren't just horrible like war glorification Simulators of very specific battles that old grognards.
Rym: Yeah, usually what I mean, we have one.
Rym: We have that one that we've never actually played.
Rym: We've read the rules.
Scott: that a civil war game.
Rym: What?
Rym: No That's a. that's literally like the Verdun battle stuff that game.
Rym: We've got.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: We just we've never played it.
Rym: Maybe we should.
Rym: we could do a live stream of us playing that grognard game.
Rym: Anyway, but the gist of this game is that you are all a bunch of World War one soldiers But the game is not about fighting the war.
Rym: The game is about not dying until peace breaks out.
Scott: Your only goal is a much more accurate World War one simulator.
Rym: Yeah, so it's a co-op game and it has like pretty good information economy.
Rym: But basically challenges come up and you have got to keep making sacrifices until eventually either you die Or peace breaks out.
Rym: and that's it.
Rym: It's a really good game and it is one of the rare co-op games that involves process parsing information and intentions from other people Without having any of that fiddly shadows over Camelot.
Rym: I am three sure that we can make it through the battle Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the way it works is essentially you'll have you'll each get a character and each character has like a minor power and You have a deck and the deck is two decks.
Rym: You have a deck of challenges and if you get to the bottom of that deck There's a peace symbol because if you see the peace symbol you've survived the war.
Rym: you get to go home to your families.
Rym: There's another deck of bullshit.
Rym: they're the same cards the deck of bad things.
Rym: as you fail at tasks or accrue tasks that you didn't deal with you keep drawing from the bad deck and Adding to the deck that's covering up the piece.
Rym: So the more you keep failing.
Rym: you're trying to run out that piece deck to see peace But as you mess up Cards just keep coming on top of that deck making it harder and harder and harder and if you run out the bad deck It's just a picture of death at the end and you all die and it's game over.
Rym: Mmm, so Essentially, you have a hand of cards and you're trying to get rid of cards.
Scott: Yep, you want to you don't like cards in your hand?
Rym: Yep, you just want to get them out of your hands.
Rym: but every card you play out of your hand goes into a public area.
Rym: and in that public area if Too many of one thing up here and there's a lot of things three strikes are out.
Scott: So it's like if there are three snows.
Scott: Right, there's environments and there's obstacles like it.
Scott: There's three bullet shells or whatever you lose if there's three whistles Which are raids.
Rym: I guess whistles are raids.
Rym: Shells are like artillery barrages, right?
Rym: Yes is obviously gas.
Scott: It's like if there's three of anything you lose.
Scott: and cards.
Scott: some of the cards only have one thing But most of the cards have at least two and some of them way more than some of the cards are just bad.
Scott: There was a card that it all three things on.
Rym: Yeah, it was just the worst.
Scott: There's a card with like two weathers and a thing on.
Scott: it's like he's right.
Scott: So it's like on your turn you play a card and you add it to the tableau and now it's like, okay Well now there are two cards out there with snow and two cards out there with bullets and the next guy look at his Hand and every single card has snow in it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Rym: well, I have to play a card on my turn or Now you can talk and coordinate but the very specific rules are you cannot talk about anything in your hand.
Rym: You cannot share what you've got in your hand at all.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's pretty clear Yep, and there's another action of like doing the support thing.
Rym: When you play the support thing, you cannot say what you played.
Rym: Other people might be able to infer it from other actions you've taken.
Rym: but you cannot actually say I'm pointing it left or I'm pointing It right.
Rym: Yep So on your turn you'll either play a card from your hand and as long as you don't hit three of one of the bad things Then it's good.
Rym: just continues and you're trying to get rid of.
Scott: more people can play more cards now or you can withdraw.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: withdrawing means you don't play any more cards.
Rym: Everyone else keeps going around, but you're safe You don't have to do anything else.
Scott: You're you're gonna still have cards in your hand.
Scott: It's less than perfect, right?
Scott: Ideally you would withdraw after playing your entire hand of cards.
Scott: We were never able to do that.
Scott: Yep, except maybe round one.
Rym: So the way they turn the way the game actually is structured is there'll be a team leader and the team leader Essentially makes a bid like how big a task are we gonna go after?
Scott: how many cards are we gonna start with in our?
Scott: Yep, and then you're gonna draw to make a higher number because if you go through more rounds the game is much harder.
Scott: You want to beat the game in less?
Scott: rounds gonna play more cards and fewer rounds in order to be able to win if you do it like to.
Scott: if you do a Little little rounds with just a few cards each each around will be easier to deal with.
Scott: sure but every round you're getting more cards in the evil deck and it's just like
Rym: Yep,
Scott: you have to pull off like a round of you know, five six cards something like
Rym: you gotta be very tactile about it Like if you had a few bad rounds in a row.
Rym: you got to take on a really easy challenge to try to clear the decks because the more cards you have in your hand when You all finally withdraw because you keep going till everyone's out of cards or everyone withdraws All the cards you've got in your hands contribute to how many more bad things you put on top of that piece.
Rym: Just pushing piece further and further away.
Rym: It is very difficult to express until you actually play the game because the mechanics are so novel.
Rym: How well it simulates the feeling of sinking into mud.
Rym: It sucks you are trying to crawl out of this pit and mud just keeps sliding in.
Rym: Everything you do.
Scott: worse is when it's your turn and like you're so smart You're like how we're gonna survive everything cuz we're so smart.
Scott: It gets your turn.
Scott: It's like well, I have to just kill us.
Scott: this round There's.
Scott: no I have.
Scott: no I have to play a card and they all kill us.
Rym: Yep Especially when so even worse some of the cards you play they don't add anything to the center.
Scott: They just change the rules.
Scott: Yeah by restricting you even further like oh, yeah, by the way You can't withdraw unless you caught your hand has two or less cards in it.
Scott: It's just like yeah Or by the way withdrawn, but I have three cards now I had to play one of them and they all kill us.
Rym: Yep, and or like by the way, you have a phobia against gas now.
Rym: So gas attacks always have a plus one out there forever.
Rym: So two more gases and you're done.
Scott: Yeah It's like instead of two three strikes you're out for gas is two strikes You're out for gas and the other guys got a handful of gas.
Rym: Yep Oh and if you get too many of those phobias You're dead and the game's over and everybody loses.
Rym: the whole squad has to survive the war or you immediately lose.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So there's a couple other minor mechanics in that when you withdraw There's these support tokens and they point left or right and you basically secretly decide Who you're going to support on your way out.
Scott: So if a majority of these are pointing at the same player that player Can like sort of clean up some of those evil rules that they have on them like their gas phobia or whatever.
Rym: Or they can recharge their good-luck charm and then you pass the ones you used to that player to the player you pointed at.
Rym: But if there is no player who got them who got the most?
Rym: the plurality of those Right.
Scott: So if each play if you're playing with four people and like one person has two and one person has two No one gets anything.
Scott: Yep I'm not allowed to communicate this in advance at all.
Scott: So you just sort of have to Majority of people have to support the same person.
Rym: Yep, knowingly every character has one sort of cloverleaf like a good-luck Blow it power where you can blow this power once and get out of a tricky situation Like you don't have to play a card.
Rym: You can remove a card from play.
Rym: like you can blow it once.
Rym: There's a way to get it back.
Rym: But essentially it's like a one-time.
Rym: Oh crap.
Rym: I was lucky that time, but I'm okay for now.
Rym: and there's also a pretty nice mechanic of there's these speeches and Every one of them is like literally a speech bubble from a comic that has the first sentence of the kind of speech that you imagine like a Corporal would give to his troops in World War one when they're trying to hunker down and survive an artillery barrage.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and you got to give the speech.
Rym: you give a short speech and then you can help one of your friends out.
Scott: But at the same time we played we wanted to use these and we kept getting some sort of restriction like sorry Can't use those up and it's just like we used them like maybe once and I feel like we could.
Scott: we came really close to Winning.
Scott: I feel like so close.
Scott: We could have won with just a few more of those But we were restricted and weren't allowed to use them by some other cards.
Rym: Well, like one of the phobias is you become mute Which is pretty great because the rule that was definitely one of the most fun things.
Scott: and it you think And I first saw that I thought it was gonna be stupid Like we didn't play test this at all, but actually it was fun.
Scott: It worked out.
Rym: Well, it was fun and it was also Crippling to our ability to coordinate.
Scott: Yeah, it's like yeah, you can't tell anyone within your hand, but you're still communicating a whole bunch.
Scott: Yep, right, but it's like yeah, not only can you not give speeches cuz you're mute and you can't talk But you're mute and you can't talk.
Rym: so the actual experience of the game like in terms of how it actually breaks down because you can be like you can find the Rules and read it.
Rym: I highly recommend you just get it and play it because it's good But what you're basically gonna find is that the game is this very delicate balance of trying to figure out.
Rym: Each of you has some information But no one has the full picture and you argue with each other to decide how much of a challenge to take Knowing that you need to take more challenges in order to survive But at the same time taking a challenge bigger than you could actually deal with could be disastrous.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and it really just has I wonder she.
Scott: I guess that obviously wouldn't work.
Scott: We just picked like some enormous number like 10.
Rym: Yeah, just do the whole deck Alright, so unless we clear it the whole deck in that one go which mathematically is impossible.
Rym: I believe I believe it is.
Rym: Then great we withdraw and then we get Joe we draw the entire rest of the bad deck and death breaks out instead of peace.
Rym: Right, but I just really appreciate this is such a good example of a game that Perfectly melds the theme of the game and the mechanics of the game.
Scott: You could I mean this game is so like doesn't have a lot of components.
Scott: You could have easily put some any theme it on this right?
Scott: It could have been like, you know, oh You know surviving pretty much anywhere or anything where there's some sort of pressure and you need to sort of.
Scott: you know Get through right like y'all, you know, it could have been some sort of trek like get across the jungle Game about a data center and each of you is in charge of a server, right?
Scott: You can't have three heats.
Scott: You can't have three losses of power.
Scott: Three our hard drive crash hacker, right?
Scott: It's like pretty much any situation.
Scott: you could apply this to anything But the World War one works really well.
Rym: But yeah, but but and just so perfectly mechanically but - it is very interesting to me to see a game That is about war that is not about fighting the war and not about winning the war.
Rym: You literally do not like you do not give a shit how the war is going.
Scott: It's also very rare to see a game with a war theme that is co-op.
Scott: That's not just team versus co-op.
Scott: Yeah, actually a hundred percent co-op war.
Rym: and where the theme is just we're in this together.
Scott: War is hell right because like most of the war books and war movies that I experience in my life are You know that like, you know just shows the suffering of war, right?
Scott: You know just one side and how shitty war is and war is the worst, right?
Scott: And it's not about fighting necessarily all the time, right?
Scott: But when you look at games the games of war are always, you know much more in line of you know glorifying Combat and such.
Scott: Yep, right And about winning and losing.
Scott: I mean the reality of war.
Rym: it literally doesn't even matter What side of the war these soldiers are on right?
Scott: I'd like to see More games both video and tabletop, you know that are about war is bad The same way that movies and books are about war is bad.
Scott: Like, you know, Johnny got your gun or whatever, right?
Scott: Yep as a Unless games that are about war let's win and kill everybody.
Rym: I mean, this is basically all quiet on the Western Front the game.
Rym: Yep, just And it feel you know, it feels very like you throw down a gas card and it's like ah gas attack.
Rym: We just got to make it through.
Rym: Oh my god guys.
Rym: We just got to make it Come on, just over that next hill and then we're all dead and it's over.
Rym: We uh, we never survived the war.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Also a very perfect thematic bonus.
Rym: There is Literally one card in the entire deck.
Rym: That is not a bad thing.
Rym: There's the Christmas card, all right if the Christmas card comes up It's free parking.
Rym: just nothing happens and the next player takes their turn.
Rym: That is the best possible thing you can do is have one turn where one player does not make things worse Mm-hmm.
Rym: Oh, there's also that trap mechanic.
Rym: We did so.
Rym: the game also has some push your luck aspects and some of the cards.
Rym: not only do they have a bunch of But they got this trap symbol meaning you then flip over another card from the face down deck.
Rym: It might just kill you.
Rym: Yeah, push your luck when you're near winning the game.
Rym: That could be disaster.
Scott: is a lot of pushing your luck going on.
Rym: Yep So, I mean, I don't know what else we could really say except that this game is pretty unique.
Rym: I have not seen other games that are quite like this now and that is the primary reason why I think I want to recommend It to you and independently.
Rym: I actually had a lot more fun with it than I expected to.
Scott: We played it a second time Because the first time was so good and we didn't win and we're like we'll try again and we still didn't win.
Rym: But it was better and I actually do.
Rym: I'm probably just gonna buy it because I want to play this.
Rym: This would be a good game to play after quartermaster general because quartermaster general.
Rym: I wish I also love is also war.
Rym: It is war but yeah, we're fighting the war.
Rym: Of course It's actually an interesting take too because it's just the logistical and strategic side of the war but not It's a way zoomed out war.
Rym: Yeah, but it's three on three, but it yeah, but it is also still.
Rym: we are fighting this war To win it.
Rym: So I think we should play this game afterward to cleanse the palette and remember.
Rym: Oh, yeah war is awful.
Rym: the ends This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon thank you guys for this episode of GeekNights are in the order money.
Rym: They give us on a continuing basis.
Rym: Rebecca Dunn Nicholas brand out Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda do shit great job emoji.
Rym: my stady calm William Eisneros Jeremy minor.
Rym: but I was going into Tosh station to pick up some power converters.
Rym: a genuine bona fide electrified six-car monorail the Terrible secret of space for two one creations.
Rym: It keeps me up at night Sure from about horrible rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Rym: Oh Scott your beard tickles when we kiss sailor vista Matthew Smith Don Schleicher topish and Joe sure of Joe star.
Rym: Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin until now.
Rym: This was the only way to get juice from an orange topical.
Rym: Brian Sidroni the space-time vector of an african-european swallow carrying kiwis redacted.
Rym: Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Rym: I'll see you kids at Zenk icon.
Rym: and now I leave you with this.