Rym: It's Wednesday, May 3rd, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We got a double feature.
Rym: We're talking about two comics dissolving classroom and wrecked hearts.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So speaking of wrecked hearts.
Rym: I was looking pretty tough for the Rangers It's still tough before last night out of out of four games true But we lost the first.
Scott: imagine if we play four games of anything Yeah, and you have to win three of them, and if you don't win three you actually lose.
Scott: even so if I just win two Then that's it, but you have to win three.
Scott: yeah, that's not good for you and no matter what game.
Rym: I want to be fair.
Scott: even if we're playing coin toss It's not good for you.
Rym: game one against the Senators for the Rangers was pretty close and the Rangers doing okay like they just lost.
Rym: And then game two was like crazy scoring double overtime bullshit, and it was a real close game.
Rym: The game last night was a blowout Yeah in the other direction like It was like I'm watching the game and like they scored and then I walked away to pee and I come back and I see What I assume is a replay of the score, and then I realized that no they just scored again
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so uh now Scott got me to.
Rym: Scott and I are going to the game tomorrow and Before last night I was kind of assuming that this is gonna be the last hockey game of the season for us.
Rym: Well now mathematically cannot be the last time you know this season, but I went from Expecting to go and see the end of the Rangers run to Not expecting to go and see them win.
Rym: because I've learned from the master Scott as a New York fan If you're winning a game by three you could still fuck it up.
Rym: if you're winning by four you're probably gonna win By five in hockey Before it counts and you can say yeah, this game is over and turn it off because if you turn that game off It's gonna be a big comeback.
Scott: even if you turn it off with ten points.
Scott: It's still well uh.
Rym: so uh What was what was the deal with that game with the Mets that I literally until yesterday assumed was a joke?
Scott: Oh the pitcher got injured pretty early, and then they don't have another pitcher.
Scott: No, they do, but you know but is he bad?
Rym: like how bad?
Scott: They put a lot of pitchers in baseball these days.
Scott: you change pitchers like a whole bunch.
Scott: Oh, yeah, usually I mean a minimum.
Scott: you're using like three a game.
Scott: You know four or more sounds right, but they used a lot of and they just got their asses kicked cuz.
Rym: uh That was quite days outs.
Rym: They scored more in that game than RIT scored against Newman in that famous hockey game by one.
Scott: see it's all like when you have A close game in any sport right.
Scott: it's always sad when you like you lose by one because it's like ah I got a loss Even though I played really well.
Rym: But then like when you push into three overtimes in a hockey game like you feel like you should have won.
Scott: And but if you lose by 100, it's like well.
Scott: That's the same thing as losing by one, so it's like It's like all right.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: We're gonna lose anyway.
Scott: who gives a shit.
Rym: Yeah, let's arrest the good people Which doesn't matter is my guess for pitchers.
Rym: that matters in basketball.
Scott: They rest the good people, and it's a big problem.
Rym: Oh, yeah Because people only pay to see basketball to see the good.
Scott: in the regular season Basketball is a big controversy is going on because the games they rest the good people.
Scott: But you paid to see the good people and now you paid all this money to see bench people.
Scott: Yeah, I guess you're gonna watch him on the bench anyway They might not even show up if they're traveling they don't come to your town, so I stay home.
Rym: it is it's Wednesday So there's a bunch of anime news and anime adjacent news But the one that you all out there might have noticed if you're dirty pirates Which I assume a lot of you are.
Rym: yeah, is that an anime torrent site called?
Rym: Yeah went down and That wouldn't really be news except that torrent site seems to have been the one that was the to use a Wall Street term the Liquidity provider for all the rest of the anime torrent.
Scott: it was the backbone of many anime torrent sites.
Rym: Yeah, a liquidity provider is basically someone who is willing to publicly say hey I'll trade the stock like they will put liquidity into the market even but it's on other venues.
Rym: So this was like this is where the torrents that people actually downloaded Originated.
Rym: so all these other torrent sites that people thought oh, there's a ton of anime torrent sites There weren't?
Rym: really there was one and a bunch of people leeching off of those.
Scott: There's more but some of them have been private and so you know yeah It's like torrents are still the best way to distribute pirate stuff without getting taken down like YouTube style, but they are Increasingly retreating to the realm of nerdy people who know the deal.
Scott: no yeah Well it's really people always like oh my god torrents so hard.
Scott: Oh, they're not it's.
Scott: you click a link you install a program wait on it so already set up that exe.
Rym: so wait.
Rym: I'm confident that if I just type torrent software the first exe I get is gonna be some malware.
Scott: I think it'll probably be the official you Software.
Scott: you turn oh wow yeah, all right, which is micro towards.
Scott: Now micro you torrent.
Rym: I just people who call it you torrent are The people who type us for microseconds instead of actually typing the mu symbol.
Scott: Yeah, can you type a new symbol?
Scott: Yes, type it right now.
Rym: I copy pasted Watch.
Rym: how I type it watch.
Rym: I type watch.
Rym: Okay, what's going on here?
Scott: How do you think I?
Scott: how do you get to the Wikipedia page for it without typing it by typing?
Rym: Micro wouldn't?
Scott: it is pretty slow here.
Scott: It's easier to micro Wikipedia the symbol But if you just go and type you it'll work in Google.
Scott: you don't need to type the micro.
Rym: yeah But I need.
Rym: I want to type the micro when I am typing the word.
Scott: I'll learn the show.
Scott: so what's the alt code?
Scott: It's right there.
Rym: What is like if I can't type it?
Scott: that often anyway the point is use You're just.
Scott: the point is I see someone not you install this program.
Scott: You torrent is.
Scott: it is micro torrent is legit even though it has ads in it.
Scott: It's you know.
Scott: It's not malware.
Scott: It's not sure that when you run the setup that exe you uncheck all the evil boxes someone in the chat.
Rym: It's just like typing it over and over again.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is that you can.
Scott: there are other torrent clients that are really even less evil like transmission and such.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway you install a program Then you go to a website you click a link the file downloads you double click on the file it plays.
Scott: It'll play in Windows Media Player, but if for some reason it doesn't it'll play in VLC.
Scott: Perfectly there is some crazy nut jobs.
Scott: You're like.
Scott: Oh you got to install this CCCP when do not install Bad news.
Scott: because basically way back in the day way back there VLC didn't play all the files.
Rym: But generally the files VLC didn't play were the ones that came from the shadiest of the sites.
Scott: right nowadays VLC plays absolutely everything and his toe is even super legit.
Scott: yeah And there's no reason it was all some shady Windows Media Player piece of garbage.
Rym: Also most of this stuff just plays in Windows Media Player.
Rym: guys.
Scott: Yeah, regular Windows Media Player like it just works, or you know what do you have on Macs?
Scott: quicktime something right?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: Point is you'll download a video file.
Scott: You'll double-click it.
Scott: It's gonna fucking play on your computer, and that's it.
Scott: It's not as great as YouTube where you type in a URL and then press play that's true, but it's download a file Double-click on it
Rym: And there's a gap between like the fact that you're getting this torrent file and getting the video and all these pieces Means that you're not gonna get malware unless you're dumb right or super Unknowledgeable mm-hmm, but even then point
Scott: is if you want to distribute pirated stuff And you want to avoid YouTube takedowns just use bit torrent.
Scott: stop fighting it.
Scott: just use the old pirate Bay.
Scott: use whatever tracker is The tracker right now.
Rym: I change trackers even matter unless you're in the know.
Rym: it is increasingly hard for a normal person who does not Know how to find the torrents in the first place especially when the torrent aggregators keep going down.
Scott: I just go to pirate Bay.
Scott: It's still there still work.
Rym: for now part of a is having some increasing trouble.
Scott: It's it's heavy increasing troubles for like decade plus.
Scott: It's still there still works.
Rym: But most kids today just go to those like Blatant pirate sites like kiss anime or all.
Scott: because if you go to Google and type in like I want to watch Naruto or Naruto Streams those are the fucking first results.
Scott: Yeah, you search for some like.
Scott: I want to read Naruto manga.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: the first result isn't buying it on Amazon.
Scott: the first result isn't a site that has it legit.
Scott: the first result is some pirate site.
Scott: that is very interesting to me.
Rym: that the the piracy means that are more old-school in the sense of I Am pirating this thing to share with you because fuck everybody.
Rym: I'm doing it for the freedom of media.
Rym: That's right versus that's me.
Rym: and those get taken down way harder than the site that's like.
Rym: Yeah, we're just like openly making money off of other people's stuff.
Scott: We're just a website that puts manga up with next to ads acting like we're legit.
Rym: We are a crime website Doing crime.
Scott: there's no nobility whatsoever.
Scott: at least there's something noble about like.
Scott: I am going to subtitle this and share it with the world because Someone who does not speak Japanese should not be denied this anime the joy of seeing space without Yamato.
Scott: Yes for all.
Rym: How is this website up?
Rym: Like how how is this happening?
Rym: but anyway, yeah, if you use Torrance to get anime like a million voices just cried out and were suddenly silenced and You'll still be able to get torrents of anime tomorrow.
Scott: You just have to go somewhere different.
Scott: It's a look.
Scott: figure out what the new site is guys.
Rym: It's not hard like c-roll is not paying us or anything.
Rym: The c-roll is not expensive.
Scott: crunchyroll is way cheap like in almost everything's on there.
Scott: if it's not on there It's on Hulu.
Scott: if it's not on there.
Scott: It's on Funimation.
Scott: when I was on Netflix when I was at alright Amazon Just pick whichever one has the show you want to watch and then once you're done watching all the shows what I do And switch to another one.
Rym: and had no money and had internet to like I had the direct connect of pirate everything in the world Forever.
Rym: if crunchyroll existed then I think I would have just paid for it.
Rym: It was just like the idea that you could just go to a website Pay a little bit of money and have access to like more than a couple of anime.
Rym: It's still kind of crazy to me now.
Scott: You can get all the anime.
Scott: every episode of Fist of the North Star is on there.
Scott: So for less than the cost of all the DVDs of all of us to the North Star you can watch it all.
Rym: So in some other news, it's kind of really it's tangentially related, but on Monday We were talking about like pirate and stuff and today We're talking about pirate and stuff and like the nobility of the old world.
Rym: so once again People met.
Rym: someone made this cool like 2d.
Rym: Hey, I made breath of the wild, but it's 2d.
Rym: check this out and of course it got taken down.
Rym: Like you can't get away with this.
Scott: you can just stop making a website that says hey Look at me.
Scott: My name is Scott Rubin.
Scott: I made this thing.
Scott: that is obviously blatant infringement of Nintendo's intellectual properties.
Scott: come and get me Nintendo.
Scott: Yeah, no, I would put it up anonymously on bit tour and say I don't know who made this now Here, that's really awesome, and it keeps getting updated and it's totally these towards and the cryptographically sign that shit.
Rym: So at some point in the future you could prove that you're the one who made it.
Rym: Sure, but You got to get it out there first.
Rym: If you're if your goals are purely noble if your goal is to make money and be the kiss anime of 2d breath of the wild Well, I don't know what you're expecting there.
Rym: The world is different now.
Rym: Yep And yet more news.
Scott: if you want to see jubilees like jubilee movies if you don't realize they're on DVD I think all of them now, but if you want to see even in the ocean waves on DVD in America now.
Rym: Fathom events, which is that thing where they'll do like an event in movie theaters.
Rym: Sometimes it'll be a live stream thing Sometimes it'll be like.
Scott: I wonder how much it cost to make our own fathom event.
Rym: I was thinking about that because a lot of who would buy a ticket to our fat.
Scott: So and what cut would we get?
Rym: Podcasts that are two and a half to three tiers above us in terms of like real tears like in terms of like, you know hundreds of thousands of listeners.
Rym: They do fathom events where they get on a stage somewhere and do the podcast and people can watch it live or semi-live Movie theaters.
Scott: Yeah, so it's not out of the realm.
Rym: It probably just costs some amount of money.
Scott: You need real good internet in the place that has the stage.
Rym: Yeah, I pretty sure that's taken care of.
Rym: I could look into it.
Rym: I'm sure there are dozens of people who would be interested in the Be a thousand there after this But already a thousand jay kids have a job.
Rym: G kids is the go-to way to see anime in theaters and G kids and fathom are bringing six Ghibli movies.
Rym: Totoro Laputa Kiki's spirited away howl's moving castle Nausicaa.
Rym: There's gonna be subtitled and dubbed in theaters, but pretty much only in big cities I mean in New York, like every year IFC has like every Ghibli movie in New York.
Rym: I think I've seen every major anime movie.
Scott: Hasn't been like a month gone by that I've lived here that you haven't been able to see at least one Ghibli movie in a Theater somewhere?
Rym: never mind every new anime movie like.
Rym: we just see them all in theaters.
Rym: like it's not.
Rym: the moral of this news is live in a city or I guess Tampa like if you live like in Florida or something, that's a real city.
Scott: It's a city.
Scott: It's certainly not a town.
Rym: Yeah, that is true.
Rym: But I mean technically beacon is a city.
Scott: Yeah, well Tampa has Professional sports teams all of them.
Rym: Oh, that's a good Nationally known professional sports team.
Scott: Yeah, Tampa has every sport.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's the line.
Scott: I don't think it has basketball team.
Scott: Seattle does not have every kind of sport though I think the only basketball team in Florida is their Miami Heat.
Scott: Do they need to have any?
Scott: that's another one.
Scott: So is the line Orlando Magic, but there's no Tampa basketball team.
Rym: Is the line just one or all of the major sports?
Rym: cuz Seattle don't got no hockey team.
Scott: Yeah has to have.
Scott: they had basketball.
Scott: they had.
Scott: they had three.
Scott: now They have two.
Scott: Yeah, and I think if you have a football team in America, that's nice.
Scott: I'd already counts.
Rym: I think you know, here's what you need.
Rym: You need either a football team or Any two other national sports teams?
Rym: Yeah, it's one of those.
Rym: football or pick two.
Scott: But anyway, I think San Diego They had the Chargers and the Padres And now they lost the Chargers.
Scott: Yeah, they only have baseball in San Diego.
Scott: now I guess they might have soccer, but I don't think they have.
Scott: there's no hockey.
Rym: it Vegas doesn't have hot.
Scott: No, it's the San Jose Sharks.
Scott: There's no San Diego Hockey team.
Rym: Vegas won't have hockey till next year.
Rym: Well the end of this year.
Scott: technically Yeah, Vegas is a major city without any.
Rym: well is Vegas a city or is Vegas a theme park?
Rym: Oh But yeah, you can see Ghibli's in the theater and Actually with modern projection like it's all digital and like really high quality It's actually worth it.
Rym: If you've never seen a Ghibli movie in the theater, even if you've seen them all It's worth it to see one of them in the theater.
Scott: I also imagine most people haven't seen all of them like we've seen all of them but like we're oddities people in the United States who are among a small number of people who have seen all of these almost all of these things and honestly like Ones worth seeing.
Rym: if you haven't seen like all the Ghibli movies in the theater and you haven't seen La Pita Castle in the sky I go see that one in the theater because
Scott: it's the first
Rym: one and also it is Like there's a lot going on in that movie that is enhanced by being in a theater setting just the scope of it.
Rym: Anyway, I digress.
Rym: Another piece of news.
Rym: you guys know we were for a while doing that new tennis show which is coming back.
Rym: Just I got to do a bunch of crap first.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: I'm fighting off like three takedowns, right?
Scott: But here's some mutana that's not being taken down.
Rym: All of utana is just on YouTube legally legally Subtitled for free.
Scott: No crunchyroll Funimation Hulu required go to you.
Rym: Only up to 480p.
Rym: But utana was only made in like 480p like the blu-rays you can see Like cell defects.
Rym: if you watch the remastered blu-rays like you can see 16 by 9 HD show.
Scott: the show is from 1990 something not late.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's a four by three anime.
Scott: It was made for analog crap o TVs.
Rym: So watching on YouTube in 480p is just fine and frankly if you're free for free Just you know, if you're a GeekNights fan, you've been a GeekNights fan for the last 12 years.
Rym: You've probably seen utana because we talk about it a lot.
Rym: if you've never seen Shojo Kakuma utana, it is a real important anime in terms like there's By so many things and there's not one.
Scott: it also once you see it and you're gonna go back to some other thing you saw And be like, oh, that's a new tenor reference that I miss desert.
Rym: But also it's a bridge.
Rym: those references to utana are in a way bridges because utana is referencing Even weirder stuff like brother dear brother that I'm sure you've never seen.
Scott: isn't brother your brother newer than antenna?
Scott: You I'm pretty sure you 10.
Scott: It doesn't reference brother dear brother.
Rym: They're very similar.
Rym: Yeah 91 other.
Rym: I think they were contemporary Mmm, but the manga 70s the anime didn't come out till 91 92.
Scott: I don't know Whatever the point is.
Scott: it's for free on YouTube.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: Watch it utana.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: There are things that are like it.
Rym: But the things that are like it are also made by ikuhara Rosa Versailles kinda.
Rym: Yeah, or well, I mean there's yurikuma which is the most recent iteration of let's have I mean Rosa Versailles right heavily.
Scott: It's probably the thing that influenced utana a bunch.
Rym: yeah, visually I guess you know, but I Can't think of anything that told the same story that attended the way that told it with that combination of weird music and weird allegory, you know allegory or allegory is If you haven't seen utana you literally have no excuse.
Rym: you can.
Rym: you can click on a link on our website To this YouTube video and click one button.
Rym: You don't even need to install 287,000 views.
Scott: the people are watching.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Good job people.
Rym: Uh, I kind of want to watch you 10 again.
Scott: Me too.
Rym: Yeah But anyway things of the day.
Rym: There was a toy Series like one of those lines of toys that I had as a kid that I remember being super fucking legit.
Rym: But at the same time I also remembered he-man being super fucking legit Mm-hmm, and there was a point in my life when I learned my lesson that he-man is the opposite of legit.
Scott: I mean, it's legitimately bad.
Rym: Yeah, and it is the toys thing.
Scott: is the he-man toys are actually good the show which is bad.
Rym: They're okay They're not as good as the show is.
Rym: hey, yeah Yeah mass toys were like way better than even the best transformers in terms of the physicality of the toy The best toy in terms of action figures ever.
Scott: It's the technodrome.
Scott: They're real metal Voltron.
Rym: Yeah, if you're gonna go yeah, you wanna go real toys.
Rym: I had a toy was a toy gun.
Rym: There was my grandpa's.
Scott: it was actually a gun the shop.
Rym: It was an actually a gun, but you put these low Gunpowder cartridges in it that weren't that dangerous But it was basically actual gun actual gun.
Scott: Yeah actual weak gun But not as good as Voltron.
Rym: so I found I stumbled upon The commercial for these toys.
Rym: the toys were spy tech.
Scott: I never heard of it.
Rym: So these toys were almost without an exception Garbage legit spy shit like if you wanted to actually spy on people for real.
Rym: They were like.
Rym: that was what they reported to do.
Rym: I'm skip they legit did it.
Rym: So, you know what they were.
Rym: one of them was this really compact periscope that you could like unfold and spy on people with.
Rym: it Was really good.
Rym: One of them was some walkie-talkies like back then.
Rym: walkie-talkies were like a Walkie-talkies like $100.
Scott: No, they were cheap.
Scott: Well, I had walkie-talkies, but they weren't spy tech but they were.
Rym: but they were branded like a part of the toy set But you could hide him cuz you like warm on your belt Large and actually they worked quite well.
Scott: and I had a Morse code chart printed on the front and I know exactly the Fisher price one.
Rym: I know exactly an orange button.
Rym: You know, I had that exact walkie-talkie, but you could also talk.
Rym: I know exactly which one you're talking about cuz I had that exact same one.
Scott: these guys Yes, that's the one they actually Think was a little better than that one.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Yeah, is it that one?
Scott: No, that's an actual.
Scott: yeah The chart on the front of mine wasn't a piece of paper.
Scott: it was like a plastic in like raised thing.
Rym: Was it this one?
Rym: No, cuz that one I also had.
Scott: it was mine regret, but it's very very similar effectively the same toy Yeah, but these were like hidden.
Rym: like you wore the belt pack and actually worked really well and you had this tiny like transmitter in your ear.
Rym: It had sunglasses you could wear.
Rym: that had like mirrors you could see behind you.
Rym: that were discreet like they're actually discreet.
Rym: It had motion detectors you could leave.
Rym: that would like set off alarms and had signal lights and Like they weren't.
Rym: that like super high-tech like they were pretty simple stuff.
Rym: But I put.
Rym: I looked into like how well they work and I found a bunch of people like reviewing them from a modern Standpoint.
Rym: they were legit Like if you want to spy on other people's for real to find things out about them.
Rym: These toys were way more functional than I think like parents who bought them for their kids realized And I would not be surprised if more than one kid found out where dad was going when he worked late with this shit.
Rym: Yeah, so this is one of the first commercial for spy tech and the craziest thing about this commercial seems vaguely familiar.
Rym: Yeah, you watch the commercial at commercials and you'll see they were skipping through it.
Rym: They were a series.
Rym: I had Every one of these fucking toys.
Rym: I had none of these toys and I used them to spy on the neighbors Like I like legit spied through neighbors windows.
Scott: What'd you learn about the neighbors?
Rym: Real boring stuff like nothing interesting at any point ever.
Rym: Yeah, but the craziest part was that they came with manuals that were like how to spy on people.
Rym: I found some of the manuals and I was reading through them today when I thought about doing this new this thing of the day.
Rym: They give legit advice on how to do dead drops and like how to tail people without getting caught.
Rym: Mm-hmm like real advice.
Rym: So that was a thing.
Rym: Oh number one comment on this video, why are a bunch of kids stalking that guy commuting to work?
Rym: Comment one because they know what's up.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: for me this is just a tweet with some pictures in it But what this is is in Turkey's doing some archaeology.
Scott: It's like as despite how our bad things are there you can still do archaeology.
Scott: They're just fine.
Scott: and This guy uncovered a mosaic.
Scott: mosaics are like the best except for tapestries.
Scott: mosaics like second best.
Rym: Yeah, when I was in Turkey, one of the best things is seeing the old mosaics all over the city.
Scott: I kind of want to make mosaics.
Scott: I feel like I can't draw but I feel like I could make a mosaic.
Rym: It's basically just pixel art.
Scott: Yeah, I could do that anyway.
Scott: Only pixels can be any shape and size.
Scott: Yeah color.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, this mosaic is a totally fucking badass skeleton from like what years Ancient time, uh, if I had to guess just look centuries ago I saw this when it got tweeted because this is basically dumb other fucking share zone, right?
Scott: But basically it's an awesome skeleton.
Scott: It's at least centuries old.
Rym: if not, okay It's it's earlier than I thought I was gonna guess like 500 600 AD.
Rym: It's actually third century.
Scott: Yeah, that's old Millennia old and what does it say on the skeleton?
Scott: be cool and live your life?
Rym: Yeah, be like be love.
Rym: if I just enjoy your life something something.
Scott: Be cheerful and live your life and the skeletons because if you're if you don't if you're not cheerful You don't live your life.
Rym: You're gonna be a skeleton Or more importantly you're gonna be a skeleton someday.
Scott: Anyway, it's basically the same exact message as the happy birthday comic with the grim reaper moving the little bead.
Scott: Yeah, the fairy ballad version.
Rym: I send that to everyone.
Rym: I know on their birthday when I remember right every year.
Scott: So Awesome mosaics for the win if anyone knows any other awesome mosaics or as any tips on making awesome mosaics.
Rym: So on my thing of the day kids first guide to a restraining order In the moment the book club book is Dune and wait until we began in.
Scott: so Otherwise, but I'm taking my time beating Gannon.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'll probably go beat him right now if I wanted to but I don't.
Rym: I'm poking around the Goron zone And I'm not finishing the Goron zone.
Scott: I didn't even go to the Goron zone.
Scott: Yeah, I've been to every other zone But I'm cleaning up all the other zones and upgrading tons and tons of shit before I go to the Goron.
Scott: Also, I learned I imagine when I do go to the Goron zone I'm just gonna blow it out of the water like I did not know horses could die.
Rym: Yeah, they kept saying one died, but I didn't really think about it.
Rym: So I was fighting some mob limbs that were way more dangerous than any right to be in a place.
Rym: That is way more dangerous than I expected and they fucking killed my horse.
Rym: Yeah, but now my good horse I don't really care.
Rym: It was uh, it was a horse that I got because I thought it was good and then I found way better horses.
Rym: But yeah now I know that horses can die and it's real sad.
Rym: Emily was like is that horse dead?
Rym: and I was like I think that horse died and she was real upset about it because I let my horse die.
Scott: They got hit points.
Rym: Yeah, so luckily my main horse sunset is pretty strong.
Rym: I feel like sunsets invincible.
Scott: Mostly my main horse is not Epona.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not I'm not going to uh, Named it not Epona.
Rym: Yeah I got the giant horse, but the funniest thing about that giant horse is that giant horse is named kaku.
Rym: Oh, I named mine Calamitous, but kaku.
Rym: Oh, yeah That's the actual name of that Because I know where that horse came from.
Rym: I know one island.
Rym: But when I saw the horse like I came up over this like Ridge and I see the horse in the distance and you know Immediately like wow that horse either that's a normal horse and a bunch of baby horses or that's a giant horse and a bunch of normal horses but the horse size
Scott: duck Thousand duck sized horses that
Rym: horse was having like a Conference of horses because all these other horses were like standing there looking at him and he was just standing there Like I'm the big horse and I don't know what they were doing.
Rym: But raising yeah, but they were like the big horse was like convening a council of horses around himself.
Scott: They they travel in packs the horses, I guess.
Rym: But yeah, we're gonna be at the next convention.
Rym: We'll be at is ConnectiCon at the end early July July 6th, well 7th through 9th There is no content on July 6 Thursday Even though the website says ConnectiCon a July 6 through 9th.
Scott: on July 6 there will not be anything happening.
Rym: Many cons in that you can show up on Thursday and lobby con is in full swing and you can pick up your badges.
Scott: Technically, it's open ish.
Scott: They just want to be able to advertise There.
Scott: it starts Thursday.
Rym: There is no GeekNights content on Thursday, but we will be there doing a bunch of panels and Such.
Rym: if you want to run a panel at ConnectiCon Submit it because I'm literally like filling out the whole schedule Just as I see fit.
Rym: and if you wait, you're probably not gonna be on the schedule because I'm filling it up pretty quick.
Rym: Otherwise, we're gonna be at PAX Unplugged.
Rym: We're gonna be a PAX West probably gonna be a packs, Australia and Almost definitely gonna be at magfest soon as they announce the dates.
Rym: So I know if it conflicts with I don't know New Year's Mm-hmm and otherwise you should follow Scott on YouTube and you should follow me on YouTube because GeekNights content is Split between those two channels.
Rym: You can also watch Scott do things like do his dishes or hang out over lunch and you can watch me very soon.
Rym: Some of you notice the.
Scott: yeah, since I have a thousand subscribers I can stream live on YouTube from my phone.
Scott: So I don't have to you.
Scott: I'm not gonna use these stupid periscopes or instagrams or anything like that.
Scott: I can just boom YouTube on my phone whenever I want immediate live video as long as I have data.
Scott: So I use that because I have it.
Rym: I'm gonna start using it more.
Rym: but I you might have noticed I did some things.
Rym: They popped up a couple times on my youtube channel.
Rym: But I am bringing back advanced wars with Rym because actually a lot of you have been asking me for that.
Rym: That's part of what I've.
Scott: that's what a lot of competition for that advanced or is?
Rym: Yeah, I feel like I feel like I can corner the advanced wars live streaming market.
Scott: I feel like you can also just go into other turn-based games that are advanced words Like you can go to the war bits or the other one that's coming.
Rym: Oh, no, you and I should do Gemfire.
Scott: do a gem.
Scott: just do all the games.
Scott: do it as some arrow biz.
Rym: Oh my god the arrow biz.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna see.
Rym: is anyone live stream arrow biz.
Rym: live stream The monster.
Rym: live stream.
Rym: Okay, this this is the only person doing it.
Rym: They're getting hundreds of views.
Rym: I feel like I can beat that.
Rym: I feel like I can beat Bobo the vulture and is six months.
Rym: six months ago He streamed advanced wars advanced wars arrow biz.
Scott: Is he good at arrow biz?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm real good at arrow biz.
Scott: play against him in a row biz.
Rym: Whoo Cuz you won't play against me.
Rym: No, so yeah, we are we're doing double feature here.
Rym: cuz these are two little comics.
Rym: They could not be more different.
Rym: That is well, I know.
Scott: one of them is actual manga and one of them is manga influenced.
Rym: Yeah, manga ask.
Scott: So we'll talk about that first.
Scott: So basically, you know, I've heard of Not the dissolving classroom, but the diss is a disappearing classroom.
Scott: Yeah, I think is the other one.
Scott: There might even be more in the series.
Rym: Well, so this didn't even of a series.
Scott: I didn't even realize.
Rym: Several I think it's.
Rym: I want to say there's five.
Scott: I didn't even realize it was a series.
Rym: Oh, there's seven of them.
Scott: What are they?
Rym: dissolving classroom meet again children of the earth worshiping beauty or dissolving beauty.
Rym: dissolving apartment.
Rym: She's a cheese.
Rym: It means dissolving love and the demons conference is gonna be the last one Right.
Scott: So like, you know, there's two different classroom ones, right?
Scott: Anyway, anyway, I didn't realize it - they're all they're all by Junji ito, but Junji Ito You probably know from.
Rym: you probably don't know the name of it But you've definitely encountered the weird spiral manga Because people like to post screenshots of that all the time all over the internet with no context.
Rym: So that's what that is.
Scott: The thing is it's like this Junji Ito is a name you associate with like Japanese horror manga, right?
Scott: Who did the?
Scott: what's the one with the fish?
Scott: is that Uzumaki?
Scott: Is that also Junji?
Scott: That's Junji Ito.
Scott: Alright, I feel like there's one other person who also does horror manga.
Scott: That's super famous and like but I just get them confused all the time because they all blend together because the styles feel similar well, because yeah, I mean.
Rym: obviously there's a lot of Variants in there, but most of the Japanese visual media like drawn or animated horror I've encountered has pretty much looked like this.
Rym: I mean Well, I mean other than yamashibai which is a similar style in a lot of ways.
Rym: That's I mostly encounter yamashibai and Junji Ito.
Rym: so this comic is straight-up body horror in a Japanese style Like that is it?
Rym: in a nutshell if body horror is Your jam you will like this.
Rym: if body horror bothers you you will hate this and you should not read it because you will hate it.
Rym: So the story is basically about this normal-looking dude and this really scary looking girl who is this younger sister and If you encounter them your brains probably going to melt.
Rym: and that's pretty much the entire plot.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I didn't know what this was.
Scott: I just knew it was like a famous horror manga and I didn't realize it was a series.
Scott: but it showed up and I read it and it was way quick to read which is nice and I didn't know exactly what the story was at all.
Scott: I knew as I figured it was gonna be about us like a You know a school of kids in class in a classroom and that horror shit would keep happening to them.
Scott: But no that was only like the beginning part.
Scott: and then it's actually these multiple stories that are only linked together a little Bit kind of because there's a few characters they keep going through.
Scott: Right the whole thing.
Rym: Yep So the basically you're introduced to these characters and if you'd start reading it You're gonna think wow that sister is super scary and dangerous and the kids just trying to deal with it.
Scott: Yeah, what's the deal with this kid who has a crazy evil sister who's murdering everyone?
Scott: He can't keep her under control.
Rym: The moral of this is that kid is a bad person and he deserves all this even though actually he seems to be enjoying himself.
Rym: You can't tell right?
Scott: It's sort of it's somewhat ambiguous.
Rym: Well, it's all ambiguous because I feel like those two characters exist Primarily from face value as a vehicle to get body horror into your eyes.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much they are.
Rym: they're just a vehicle for body horror Mostly around your body melting or becoming horrifying in some way and you can't get around it.
Rym: but on a much more meta level the When you read this and I'm not gonna spoil too much because you know, you can just read this thing
Scott: Satan,
Rym: but yeah Originally, he sort of portrays himself as like yeah, I'm cursed by the devil my sister, you know I messed with devil shit and now my sister is cursed and I'm trying to protect her and live my life.
Rym: I'm so sorry, but then the sister is like, yeah, he was fucking torturing animals and Satan came after him.
Scott: He fucking loves the devil.
Scott: He's not he's not accident.
Scott: He's like he's Satan's best.
Rym: I really like oh I tortured animals as a kid because That's how I relieve stress in my life and that no he's like.
Scott: no you tortured animals cuz you love Satan.
Rym: Yeah, like you want him to love you back But the G you find find out like early on that the deal is if he apologizes to you Satan gives him an orgasm essentially and your brain starts melting.
Rym: and the more he Apologizes to you the more your brain melts until you die and then melt into a puddle And the sister eats your brains and you or they store it in bottles.
Rym: You think that is too much of a spoiler.
Rym: his other seems like the first ten pages and it just goes off from his other Superpower is.
Scott: he tells people how pretty they are and they become ugly but think they're pretty.
Scott: when he does this It's like more the more he says well also being like this heart, you know, like gross-out kind of horror Thing.
Scott: it's also this commentary in Japanese society Which you know has worse problems than America does in terms of you know, personal appearance.
Scott: Issues now bear in mind.
Scott: we earned also constantly apologizing even when you're not the person who did anything wrong.
Rym: we are neither Japanese nor experts on Japanese culture, but the plot of this dude Apologizes to people all the time to basically be on one hand.
Rym: He does bad things and his sisters does bad things.
Rym: He apologizes for those things and everyone around him is sort of obligated to accept those apologies.
Scott: and he likes Apologizing a lot.
Rym: but think about this.
Rym: you do something bad and then you are automatically forgiven By society whether or not you should be forgive.
Scott: you are forgiven for melting these people's brains and loving Satan.
Rym: Yeah, but so he apologizes to people and they have to accept it.
Rym: So as a result, he gets to keep doing these terrible things to people.
Rym: But also he is not actually ever apologizing because he's sorry.
Rym: He's apologizing for his own selfish reasons and taking advantage of the fact that other people will accept those apologies.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and the one girl who was sort of saved from this Really is only saved because she passes out before he can keep apologizing to her.
Rym: Yeah, but she has her whole arc which she tries to expose them and I'm not gonna spoil whether or not she succeeds.
Scott: The point is in him, you know If you want to read some horror mangas, right?
Scott: Is like the go-to of the horror manga.
Rym: cuz these guys these are direct.
Rym: These are like you want to see some horror?
Rym: Let's see how many pages.
Rym: a lot of the other zero as far as poor on the cover.
Rym: Let's start horror in the first page.
Rym: Okay, there's no horror in the very first page of the manga except he apologizes to everyone in the class.
Rym: one two Three four up there's there's some horror.
Rym: Anyway, the point is let me suck your brains out here.
Scott: Bigger series like this go which is the one with the fish and Uzumaki, which is I think the spiral one, right?
Scott: Oh, it's like those are longer series.
Scott: So you might not know if you're into this.
Scott: like you don't want to go into you can just read this.
Scott: It's like a one-shot tiny deal.
Scott: It's like be your intro to the world of this kind of style of manga To figure out if you want to go deeper and read the rest of everything out there.
Rym: Yep, or not what's cool is at the very end after you learn a bunch more about Satan and Whether or not the story resolves itself because it resolves itself to a degree You get a couple of really really short like four-page comics.
Rym: Did you read those at the very end like after the story?
Scott: Yeah, and I remember them.
Rym: They're not about people melting They're just like horror vignettes like really simple ones that are kind of interesting.
Rym: I It's hard for me to be super like generally objective about a review of this kind of stuff Because I really like horror in general.
Rym: I mean, I listen to pseudopod like constantly like I like contemporary horror fiction.
Scott: I've been watching horror movies since I was like I would really like.
Scott: I just I just like this for like the pictures of Satan and the pictures of people's heads melting.
Scott: Yeah, right that alone is enough for me to read it.
Scott: But is it enough for you to read it?
Scott: It might make you want to not read it depending on who you are.
Rym: Yeah, I like.
Scott: I cannot stress this and it's not for everybody.
Rym: if you do not like body horror, which is a very Specific genre of horror then you will not like this at all.
Scott: If you don't want to see a human body doing things human bodies don't do.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Don't look at this.
Rym: If you're were if you were bothered by irrevocable diffuse harm to your person Because this is pretty horrifying shit, and I love it.
Rym: So there's not much else to say.
Scott: I'm not gonna spoil a big manga, which is why we're doing a two-shot.
Rym: But it goes way.
Rym: It just goes.
Rym: you're gonna think like, okay.
Rym: I see what's going on with this.
Rym: No, it'll escalate like page by page and never stop escalating.
Scott: Yep So the other thing we read is wrecked heart.
Scott: So this I got at the mocha festival this year.
Scott: I just saw it on a table and I was like, wow, that looks really well put together And I like the colors and hearts.
Scott: so I'm gonna buy that.
Scott: so I bought it.
Scott: So what it is is it's not a manga.
Rym: it's by two awesome artists in Sweden.
Scott: Yeah, so it's called wrecked hearts and it's basically two different comics that have similar themes of Heartbreak and hearts.
Rym: Well dark shoujo.
Rym: So it's heartbreak sci-fi shoujo.
Scott: Yes Which is already great.
Scott: Yeah The physical publishing of it looks like a manga, right?
Scott: It's got the even has a little strip of paper that goes around the cover.
Scott: Yeah, like a manga in Japan would write and such.
Scott: So that's pretty nice.
Scott: Inside has got nice paper.
Scott: The first story is Sort of got like a watercolor to it and the second story sort of has like a zip a tone deal.
Rym: When Scott told me to read this we could read on a gig.
Rym: not so what he said was Emily wrote Andrew the first of these two guys, so there's two stories in here.
Scott: The first story is the real thing by Luca Oliveri, which I'm pretty sure is Emily's pen name Yeah, and the second one is dark energy by mythilda kitty which is Not written by Emily.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I mean could be but it doesn't seem like it.
Scott: The first one definitely is.
Rym: so the first one has mysterious girls with powers and shape-changing and complicated gender roles and romance and space and Hockey, that's right.
Scott: It doesn't have bunnies though.
Rym: No bunnies It's like if it had bunnies.
Rym: And the second one is more I don't know.
Rym: it reminded me of particularly like that kind of moto-hagio type show Joe sci-fi.
Rym: Yes story was like they were 11 to it because actually they both fit into that.
Rym: They were 11 mold.
Scott: It's got some Tezuka going on in there.
Rym: The second one was way more Tezuka and the first one was way more like 70s sci-fi show Joe.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: But yeah, I mean they're both sort of that.
Scott: but anyway, right.
Scott: so the first story right you've got basically this girl and He plays hockey.
Scott: Yep space hockey space On the moon.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: Yep, and she's just really funny and like the character.
Rym: like they're short stories They escalate pretty quickly but her dad's an alien and she's actually totally a shape-shifter with crazy powers and She's just living among the humans and can't really reveal what she really is.
Scott: She also really has the hots for this dude, but when she dreams about the dude She dreams that she's a dude, but she's a shape-shifter.
Scott: So is she even the dude?
Rym: is there even gender, right?
Scott: So it has that sort of, you know Transgender message going on there, right?
Scott: It's like oh well what you know, here's a shape-shifting person.
Scott: What do you think of that?
Scott: Transphobic person.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah gender.
Scott: Yeah, how about that?
Rym: Yeah, and and it's a short stories We're not gonna really spoil anything But you sort of pieced together that part of the reason why she dreams that she's a dude when she's with him is because he had a boyfriend who may or may not be dead.
Rym: hmm and She is not allowed to use her powers because her dad told her not to.
Scott: and she decides Well, you don't want everyone to know that you're a shape-shifting alien when they don't know shape-shifting aliens exist.
Rym: Yeah It's not clear that anyone knows that aliens exist at all.
Rym: in like this world Like the fact that she's an alien could be a real real problem if it got out.
Scott: But apparently they do have space travel.
Scott: they go and do it on the moon and shit.
Rym: but she decides to have this plan to Shape-shift into a dude and go on an all-male hockey trip with them.
Scott: I don't think it's an all-male hockey trip.
Scott: I think it's just a school hockey trip.
Rym: But yeah, she has a plan that involves touching his dick.
Scott: Yeah good plan.
Scott: Yeah, that's a solid plan A+ and you can find you read this you'll find out how much dick-touching happens.
Rym: Yeah, uh, this is I really liked it.
Rym: It's a good story.
Scott: Yeah, and it's I mean, even though we just talked about dick-touching.
Scott: It's not like a porn It's not a yaoi or anything like that.
Scott: It's not graphic sexually in any way.
Scott: It's appropriate for young teens who at least know what sex is.
Rym: Yeah, this is like 13 14 and up, right?
Scott: I mean this is worse shit on TV in primetime than this.
Rym: and It does the thing that I like about this that I don't want to say this era of shoujo or this era of this kind of sci-fi because This is from this current era.
Rym: This is contemporary science fiction, but that 70s style like Japanese shoujo sci-fi.
Rym: it really covers that those kinds of issues in that kind of way and It addresses its subject matter in a really interesting and thoughtful way without spelling it all out for you.
Scott: And also, I mean the second story does this also, but it is not go where you predict it's gonna go Can't?
Rym: we can't like it's.
Scott: it is a fresh story, right?
Scott: It is not some old tired trope that is repeated right is totally fresh.
Rym: Yeah and Refreshing to read the second story is dark energy Vaguely because I really don't want to ruin much about it because you should read it.
Rym: It's really good.
Scott: It's got some cuteness going on a lot of cuteness.
Rym: It is much more Tezuka sci-fi in a lot of ways.
Scott: Like you said, yeah, it's got a little katamari action.
Scott: There's
Rym: a cute little robot guy who kind of looks like a taiko drum
Scott: Yeah, and
Rym: he can turn into a boy but only for a little while at a time or it rains his battery Mm-hmm, and there's this girl with a mysterious past who's alone on a spaceship and may or may not also be a plant on the spaceship
Scott: Right that she lives on a spaceship that basically is a place that grows plants and she's all alone on there.
Rym: Right and she meets this robot almost like a biodome kind of deal and they hang out together And the robot has a crush on her and it escalates while the robots lonely in space.
Scott: and so is this girl.
Scott: So you meet the first person you meet and saying like if I'm not like regardless of who the hell they are It could be ugly fat that guy Yep right and if I'm alone in space for a long period of time and I end up on a space station and the only living thing there is That guy I mean, I
Rym: don't feel it now,
Scott: but I could imagine even going that far Suddenly be real to be into the lonely fat that guy like oh my god It's a person.
Scott: even the worst person is better than no person.
Scott: interaction of any kind and this is a great person.
Scott: It's a cute plant girl.
Rym: Yeah, cute plant girl.
Rym: Thank you.
Rym: I go drama robot cute.
Scott: I go dry.
Rym: potentially cute space girl who might be the other girls ex is also totally badass.
Scott: and
Rym: to not really say anything else about where this goes it deals with a Bunch of issues in a really oblique way Yeah the ideas of in
Scott: a really short amount of time and without and it still leaves space space for space stuff and cute stuff
Rym: Yep, and also like really existential stuff, but self-identity toxic relationships Past relationships in light of the future loneliness.
Rym: And like I said, it deals with these in really oblique ways.
Rym: both of these comics, but particularly the second one They're like the failure of a lot of contemporary science fiction is spelling out.
Rym: Here's the question.
Scott: I am asking in right like the first one is a little less subtle with its.
Scott: You know, we are going to discuss trans things.
Scott: Yeah, right, even though it does a really good job.
Rym: gender identity It's not issues.
Rym: attraction It's not super subtle and in like that is my message But it brings in a lot of ancillary and related issues in subtle ways to complement the story.
Rym: This other one is like here is a story and if you're clever you'll realize oh It's about like these four or five things And it doesn't really give you a clear answer.
Scott: it just says have you thought about this stuff Mmm, and I don't want to say a lot more because it's if you want to read some not manga that has very nice contemporary and modern ish Storytelling with really good arts in a really nice Publication format.
Scott: I don't know how you can get this thing.
Rym: You can buy it on this website right here.
Scott: Oh, how about that?
Scott: So yeah, I bought had to buy it at a really indie comic-con, but you can buy it on some website.
Scott: The website seems legit and I'm sure if you give that website money, they will send you this comic.
Scott: I'm confident.
Rym: Funniest thing is it's not just that it looks like Emily drew it but that character Shapeshifter in a lot of ways also reminds me of Emily.
Rym: I'm just saying because I always if Emily's left her own devices and she just falls asleep anywhere in a bed on a couch or Anything she pretty much looks like that by the end not bundled enough.
Rym: Yeah, she's not bundled enough, but holding the pillow and ruling I'm just saying I'm Somewhat confident that what's the person Luca?
Scott: Is that the one who did the first comic?
Rym: I think so.
Scott: I'm pretty sure Luca Oliveri is Emily's fan name.
Rym: Yeah, or they there might be.
Rym: they might be doppelgangers of each other or something.
Rym: There is a shared sensibility into how to make a sci-fi shoujo story.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order the amount of money They give us on a continuing basis are Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda do shep.
Rym: great job emoji my stady calm.
Rym: William Isen rose Jeremy minor Misa called Jar Jar Binks.
Rym: miss your humble servant.
Rym: a genuine, but if I'd like to five six car monorail the terrible secret of space for two one creations.
Rym: What was all that stuff about?
Rym: God Shervin von Horl a rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Montanona?
Rym: Superboy I Paid five bucks to make room say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar top.
Rym: She just heard your stars.
Rym: Sean Yeager Sam Corddry Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin This reporter promises to be more trusting and less vigilant in the.
Rym: Brian Sidroni the space-time vector of an african-european Swallow carrying Kiwis Redacted Christmas.
Rym: Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I feel like many of you are catching on to that pause I do at the end there.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, I don't keep talking about the pipeline for antenna and I'm working on it working on the advanced war show.
Rym: I'm working on about 15 more of the board game reviews or I'm pulling the board game reviews out and putting them separately on YouTube.
Rym: I'm thinking about doing the same thing with our reviews of other things like anime just because I don't know.
Rym: Reviews in a vacuum seem to be the thing that most people Want in a wide audience and only people who enjoy us like to see the rest of it.
Rym: so I feel like I can bring more people in who don't know who we are by starting with just the reviews as opposed to the dense Rym and Scott that comes in the Rym and Scott at the beating of a Rym and Scott episode,
Scott: but
Rym: I digress and now I leave
Scott: The world on fire.
Scott: These kids coming up nowadays don't even know how to tie down their say I never tied down no pumpkins.
Scott: Hey, son, what you're trying on a pumpkin for?
Scott: Ask a silly question get a silly answer.