Rym: It's Wednesday January 25th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: the Sailor Moon s movie Also known as cats can't fall in love.
Rym: Let's do this Just regular ass all right.
Rym: so the Sailor Moon movies are.
Scott: shouldn't you wait until the end to talk about this?
Rym: beginning right now?
Rym: All right fine.
Rym: so speaking of cold and winter I went skiing recently because I got a big ski trip coming up.
Rym: I'd worry.
Rym: speaking of cold and winter I didn't even say woman is cold, but this woman this movie is the winter Christmas II Sailor Moon movie mm-hmm.
Rym: I guess that's my tenuous link, so there's a road at Hunter Mountain called Claire's Way.
Rym: It's like this double black on the West Mountain And it's usually open even when all the other stuff on the West Mountain is closed because they make snow on it.
Rym: So it was really crowded.
Rym: It was over the Martin Luther King Day holiday weekend and the lift on the front side of the mountain was super super crowded.
Rym: you Had to wait like 10 minutes to ride it back up.
Rym: So I wanted to start skiing off the back of the mountain so I could use the no-line lift because there's only pro stuff Back there, but the good snow was all on the front side of the mountain and Claire's Way is basically if there unless There's like nice fresh snow It's basically just an ice cliff like a really long and really steep ice cliff.
Rym: So I go back there, and you know I've skied it before and it usually sucks, and it's hard.
Rym: I slide around you almost die, so it's always really hard.
Rym: Yeah, like I'll fall over a lot.
Rym: It's just challenging I'll tire myself out hurt myself a little bit, so I went over there for the first time with my new skis and Yeah, the new skis are clearly superior.
Rym: so basically in situations where in the past despite being fully Traversing like facing directly parallel to the fall line going sideways across the mountain the old skis would shutter and sort of Slide down like I couldn't hold a line.
Rym: I Just hold line like nothing.
Rym: I could just ski down this thing like nothing.
Rym: it felt so easy That I skied down this thing like three or four times And it was totally just like baby stuff, and then I thought wow did I just get better?
Rym: is the snow just like Better?
Rym: than I realized what's going on, but then like my third time down there were some other people skiing on it.
Rym: every single one of them fell over had some sort of accent along the way except me and I started to realize this literally just my skis are that much better, and I should have bought better skis a long time ago.
Scott: Money buys things.
Scott: yup if I buy a more expensive car It'll go faster, but at the same time if I buy a better video card I'll get more frame.
Rym: you shouldn't buy the better thing unless you know why.
Rym: you're buying a case in point a 1080 right like that's The best video card, but if you spend more money you get one of those quadro cards.
Scott: No, you know what's not for gaming.
Scott: You know what's not true?
Scott: the more expensive anime.
Rym: So speaking of anime it's anime day, and there's actually some really good news coming out.
Scott: so for one It's anime season.
Scott: like suddenly all these animes are coming out.
Scott: It's time to watch.
Rym: There's lots of good anime We got to catch up on like you're on ice.
Rym: We know is great.
Rym: There's a My hero academia or whatever is supposed to be super good.
Rym: I've been watching anime again But little witch academia which you may recall was a 30-minute short that was made by studio trigger And then they kick-started another one, but I kick-started it, but I didn't see it.
Rym: I kick-started it.
Rym: never watched it as well.
Rym: I only ever have seen so far the first original 30-minute special.
Rym: Yes was Amazing.
Rym: like it was a anime by itself.
Rym: It was brilliant.
Rym: the new the the kick-started one which was an hour long was according to everyone.
Rym: I know who has seen it Equally amazing.
Scott: a studio trigger ever made something that was not even good at least good.
Rym: I think B+ is the lowest they've ever gone.
Rym: like B+ and up with these guys.
Rym: So little.
Rym: witch academia was getting a TV series Which is now airing in Japan and now we know something important the TV series Basically ignores the continuity.
Rym: the two movies are in the same universe.
Rym: These basically just reboot it same characters, but the movies didn't happen.
Scott: That's good because it might be hard for you to get those movies to watch them.
Rym: Well also more importantly those movies sort of took the main character through an entire arc and left her kind of being like you didn't See the second one.
Scott: How do you know that?
Rym: I know from what the first one and some stuff I'm reading in this article about the second one that this is the case.
Rym: Mmm So the series.
Rym: it's kind of like the opposite of what used to happen in the old days with like Tenchi Muyo or El Hazard where you'd get like this really condensed pretty good OAV and then they would make a longer Rebooted parallel TV series.
Rym: that was just bad.
Rym: here It looks like they had made a really great OAV and now they're making rebooting a really great TV show.
Scott: Another new anime series is coming out This season.
Scott: is it already started?
Scott: the first episode is already on the c-roll and that is your pedal.
Scott: season 2.
Rym: Oh, man, I didn't even watch one all the way more biking.
Scott: So well, there was actually I actually think it's technically season 3 Maybe whatever.
Scott: It's the new season of your pedal.
Rym: There's more of it.
Scott: All right, there were some compilation movies, but there was also another movie that told a story of like this one race.
Scott: and Basically this first episode of the new season Sort of like makes it so you don't need to watch that movie.
Scott: It's right.
Scott: It's like the first half of the episode is really just sort of hurrying up and Tying all these loose ends together from the end of what you've already seen so that it's sort of like hurrying up so it can get to New season new race, you know new people new everything, right?
Scott: So it wasn't really a strong first episode.
Scott: I guess the second half of it was a little bit better but it's like it's almost like they're just doing their paperwork like oh We got to take care of all this bullshit before we can actually start doing more bike racing.
Scott: And I wish they would have just said yeah, fuck it.
Scott: Just start Just leave you hanging on that.
Rym: It'd be like whole bunch of crap.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Now there's a car race.
Rym: Yes car race.
Scott: I wish they would have just been like, all right, fuck it.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: But they did it as fast as they could be like half an episode, right?
Rym: And also At this point, I think we reviewed it.
Rym: I assume we talked about dragon half on GeekNights Right.
Scott: So dragon half if you don't know is his old anime.
Scott: There's only got a couple episodes and the legend is that the person who made it went to jail for being a pedophile Which is surprisingly difficult to do in Japan where it's scarily.
Rym: I am dubious of that story.
Rym: It's scarily to the story that Luke Morgan kept telling everybody at the club.
Scott: The point is dragon half did not complete.
Scott: only a few episodes made and then it was.
Scott: it just sort of ended without ending.
Scott: It just sort of.
Scott: there were no more.
Scott: But there is a manga that this anime was based upon.
Scott: it's never been available in English to my knowledge, but now it will be and It does not contain any such pedophile things.
Rym: It is a now I can point out Thing that was like a rumor someone told at RIT.
Scott: It was a rumor.
Scott: someone told cuz.
Rym: alright, so I have the internet in front of me.
Rym: the mangaka Has never been in trouble as far as I can tell.
Rym: Alright, so Let's go to see who made who worked on the anime.
Scott: The point is it's a cute funny Humorous fantasy series involving a girl who is half dragon her mom who is a whole dragon.
Scott: This guy she's in love with was like a dragon Slayer.
Scott: dragon slayers name is dick saucer and there's little slimes and It's cute and funny.
Rym: Yeah, I cannot find my breathing fire-breathing dragons.
Rym: I Cannot find anything like what you described.
Scott: All right pop powder.
Scott: funny funny.
Rym: That one time I think that I think that you you have you have brought up nothing but slander here time ago.
Rym: but anyway dragon half Was dumb and cute and it was just like a cult classic at a lot of anime clubs.
Rym: I always really liked it cuz it was just there wasn't much.
Scott: I think the fact that it has so few episodes is what makes it work cuz like if you kept going with it for a While, you know, it's sort of like all right.
Scott: your cute funny fantasy isn't as good as Keep going with it because the manga has never come out in English.
Scott: Also, look at that art for that manga looks way different than anime.
Rym: It's all coming out.
Rym: You're gonna get two three volumes for like 20 bucks each.
Rym: That is the entirety of the dragon half manga And it looks like it's just gonna be make the dragon half girl goes on a quest to defeat the demon Lord as a to Death and get a potion that'll turn a human.
Rym: She can sex up dick saucer and we saw glimpses of that in the original anime and now we'll get to read about it in Full detail.
Rym: Hey, I guess it was weird because I remember at RIT This had a mythological status partly just for the fact that it was like the anime.
Rym: the rumor that I just talked about It was ridiculously popular and no one knew why it never like nothing ever got brought over in America.
Rym: Now we're just gonna get to read it.
Scott: which kind of excited about this one of those things people know about it know about it And everyone else doesn't know.
Rym: I'm feeling dumb.
Rym: light Fantasy esque stuff like you should link to the pop power.
Rym: Like I kind of just watch all the slayers that's come out.
Scott: Is that the closer with the funny song or the opener?
Rym: The closer was par par foodie foodie par par hurry Tom ago that what was the opener?
Rym: the opener?
Scott: I don't even remember.
Scott: just link to the closer in the episode description.
Rym: Dragon Opening.
Scott: it's probably gonna come back to us.
Scott: Like oh, right.
Rym: Okay dragon have opening so far.
Rym: I'm seeing a bunch of Dragon, that's the ending dragon have ending is the first thing that comes up.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: Oh There's the PC game - which I also Do not think was translated.
Scott: I can't imagine it was.
Scott: maybe there's some super fan out there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: There we go.
Rym: It looks a lot like the slayers SNES game.
Rym: No, that's cute anyway, but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: you got a thing of the day.
Scott: It's sort of a thing a day.
Scott: So, uh You know, I've been trying to not suck at photography for some years still suck.
Scott: It's not easy But a lot of times it's like once you learn something and I learned it from YouTube mostly Which is a great place to learn about photography actually.
Scott: But you know once you learn something and you see people who don't know it and it's just like ah But you can't teach them all of it every time, right?
Scott: It's like you see someone not knowing and you try to you can't?
Scott: it's like you can't teach them Right and you get that feeling you get when someone dies in the first Goomba But you can't teach them how to play Mario because it would take too long and they don't want to hear that shit.
Scott: But I also see a lot of people who do legitimately want to learn right and they don't necessarily want to learn it As much even as much as I've learned it which isn't much and they definitely don't want to learn it as much as like a professional But they want to learn it enough to her like, you know They can use their camera to help in their projects that they're you know doing whether it's because they had kids and they're taking photos Of them or taking photos of their arts or they're making videos for YouTube or whatever and they have to learn some amount.
Scott: Well, you can learn for free from Harvard Harvard the best place learning on earth.
Scott: There is a free online course.
Scott: It's been there for years Digital photography.
Scott: it is a 12 module course.
Scott: It is a cost zero dollars to take this course and this will teach you everything in a structured non YouTube fashion.
Scott: and While I know many of the things in this course like, you know The first like five modules like.
Scott: there's a module on color that I don't know.
Scott: I don't know any like I keep hearing things about color science, but I don't really know about color science, right?
Scott: So even if you don't the whole thing is not useful to you because you know how to use a camera.
Scott: There will be parts of this that are useful to you and free.
Scott: So if you have a camera or even if you just want to take more pictures or whatever and you want to suck less You're not gonna get good because I'm still not good.
Scott: But you know take this course and don't walk random YouTube videos because that takes way longer.
Scott: Trust me I know.
Rym: so speaking of random YouTube videos.
Rym: This is just a short video of someone Cooking actual food like that.
Rym: That just looks good.
Rym: Like it looks good In the kitchen of a dollhouse like legit, like even a tiny guy like a tiny match.
Rym: It's like a nice a pot making it's a fire inside of like a dollhouse old-style stove Instead of a log.
Scott: He's got some twigs in there with like a little.
Rym: I think it's like a chemical burner in there.
Rym: Okay And then on top of it use a little pan and like cooks the food in the tiny pan on the tiny Tweezer the little tiny cooking utensils.
Rym: This is kind of amazing to watch.
Scott: How do you like?
Scott: How do you like a drumstick in there?
Scott: It's like it's too Shrink a tiny time.
Scott: You don't have a time.
Scott: You don't have a tiny chicken.
Scott: Tiny ingredients like a crumb is your loaf of bread.
Rym: You'll see you gotta watch the video.
Scott: It's uh, it's short and Shaves a carrot to make a tiny little carrot.
Rym: It's like.
Rym: basically it looks like it's a little like beef patty with some smudges over it and like some ketchup and stuff.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's just kind of amazing and impressive.
Rym: Anyway, in a moment We're gonna be at PAX South doing a panel.
Rym: We're in fact.
Rym: are we there yet?
Rym: I forget if we're there right now or not.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: 25th.
Rym: I think we're there soon.
Rym: I'm gonna look at the calendar and figure out if we're at PAX or not.
Rym: I Think you can figure out that we're recording some episodes in advance.
Rym: We are currently preparing to go to PAX.
Rym: So in two days, we're doing a panel on Friday evening at four or five four or five p.m I forget which.
Rym: on What are we doing the panel?
Rym: right grinding mechanics and games, right?
Scott: So we will be there the hopefully San Antonio is warmer than New York Making it worthwhile to go there.
Rym: Hopefully we do not get trapped there by a blizzard.
Scott: I'm okay.
Scott: Last time.
Scott: I almost got a free trip to Orlando.
Rym: Yeah Actually now that I got the Delta stuff if we get trapped there I have many more options than I used to have.
Scott: listen.
Scott: We'll be fine if we get trapped, right?
Rym: Yeah, it's just San Antonio.
Scott: I just don't want to get trapped in San Antonio.
Scott: Send me somewhere else so I can enjoy at least a new even if it's a crappy city Like if they send me to like hot Lana, you can you can at least.
Scott: I'm in a place I haven't spent time and I can at least get some novelties spending a few hours there.
Rym: cuz there's like two and a half days.
Rym: It's tough to do in San Antonio, but I've been there like a day and a half All right, so you if you stretch the Alamo that's like four hours of stuff.
Scott: No there's no for you.
Rym: kiss if you if you know you have to like sit in every area of that garden and like fully Appreciate every corner.
Scott: I've appreciated all of it.
Scott: Yeah, we spent I won't trust me.
Scott: I won't forget it.
Rym: Yeah, I know a lot about the Alamo.
Scott: I don't need to know anymore.
Rym: I know so much about the Alamo.
Scott: I'm good.
Rym: We're also gonna be at PAX East doing a panel on playing dirty to win at games.
Scott: Yeah, the only play to win.
Rym: Yeah play to win the game.
Scott: Yeah, also We haven't mentioned this recently, but it bears mentioning again We have replaced the forum on our website 11 year running like million post Ridiculous forum.
Scott: we started a new blank forum, which is now anything but blank.
Scott: It's already.
Scott: everyone's already moved over.
Rym: there's already like this hundred post thread arguing about the ACLU.
Scott: Anyway, but the point is we got a brand new forum.
Scott: It's everyone from the old ones brought on over.
Scott: It's fully active.
Scott: The old one is Archived like set in stone.
Scott: no more new posts there, but all of the content there.
Scott: It will be there for all Time as long as the internet exists.
Scott: and the web exists.
Rym: Hopefully even longer than that I'll be able to save the data somewhere It will likely be able to outlive does Live us because we could make a trust that's pretty tiny.
Rym: that could keep that going forever.
Scott: Right?
Scott: The point is The old one is still there.
Scott: Nothing has been lost.
Scott: But we're all on this new one.
Scott: now come join us on the new one.
Scott: now is the time.
Scott: It's a good time.
Rym: a lot of people who have been lurking for a decade are posting.
Rym: Yeah forms pretty good.
Scott: I also fat.
Scott: I didn't realize how many people were lurking.
Scott: people were lurkers made accounts because even though they don't post they still need To mark things as read.
Scott: and now I can see that they exist.
Rym: and now I noticed something Lurkers may not want to post which is fine.
Rym: Like you're welcome.
Rym: I look at a lot of places.
Rym: Mm-hmm But they use that like button.
Scott: Yeah, the new forum.
Scott: The only thing it has is significantly different is a like button.
Scott: So you can just click the heart on a comment to like it.
Rym: That is actually a really good feature.
Rym: You can do stuff like look at a thread and be like.
Rym: just show me the top rated stuff from this thread.
Rym: Show me all the pictures someone posted in this thread.
Rym: You can also post pictures just by dragging pictures into your post Yeah, which you should do because then you won't have any like imgur type problems or he will host your photos for you.
Rym: That's a big deal.
Rym: Yeah, do not use it as a replacement for flicker.
Scott: I'll stop you If you make a thread, that's I'll know when I see the bill at the end of the month.
Rym: Yeah We'll see how well that's going with that bill.
Rym: But yeah, our forums legit.
Rym: You should join it.
Rym: So occasionally when we want to do an anime show because remember I Watched VHS fansubs vkill type of all of Sailor Moon.
Rym: I've seen all 200 episodes.
Rym: I've entered the original Japanese as well as the three movies and the two specials.
Rym: I'm in China Hatsu koi and the one with the evil doll that might destroy the world.
Scott: I've seen a few random episodes on TV when I was a kid and it was on TV every day.
Scott: That was dubbed.
Scott: I've seen the subtitled newer Hulu release of like the first Queen Beryl.
Scott: no, not even then they were like when the when the suave guy came around malachite.
Scott: So aside one of them that fried anyway, and then I stopped watching.
Scott: but I kind of wanted to keep watching.
Scott: I just didn't yeah, and that's actually pretty good stuff.
Rym: Like yeah, it's not bad.
Scott: I saw the movie we did an episode on with the space candy space candy.
Rym: So every time we decide to do a random Sailor Moon movie because they're all completely standalone Except like there's still you.
Rym: what you got to know is there are Sailor Scouts.
Rym: They're the good guys.
Scott: I know that yeah tuxedo mask The only thing that like the thing is in this movie.
Scott: if you don't if you know not a lot about Sailor Scouts Like I don't like the only Sailor Scouts I know about our moon Mars Blue.
Rym: what do you even know?
Rym: mercury?
Rym: Venus yet.
Rym: Do you?
Scott: well, I know that sailor V is.
Scott: obviously Venus doesn't join the show until pretty late I know but she hasn't joined the show in any part that I've watched.
Scott: But sailor V is there from episode 1 right and they know that that sailor Venus.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a minute.
Scott: It's like duh, right.
Rym: This is like no one will crack the code of who you really are.
Scott: Yeah, the the mysterious superhero video game character It's
Rym: cool when she shows up because Sailor Moon like didn't know anything like all the
Scott: moon is stupid Yeah,
Rym: but all the Sailor Scouts like don't know what they're doing and then sailor V shows up and it's like yeah guys I've been doing this since uh forever ago and Yeah, let's talk.
Rym: you guys gotta learn some shit.
Scott: Yeah But I think as I have I don't know about any of them.
Rym: other say three other sailors come.
Scott: well No, so sailor Jupiter is like I guess the green one and it thinks sailor Jupiter is.
Rym: she comes like pretty early in the show.
Scott: She's not in the show that I've seen.
Scott: but the point is is that you In this it's just a standalone movie, right?
Scott: So you don't get any.
Scott: any of the sailors other than moon don't really have any character action happening with them.
Scott: They're not part of the story.
Scott: They're just sort of there to do their special move and say hello just to be there though you do get this impression right away.
Rym: so you don't know.
Scott: you can already see that there's a bunch of regular Sailor Scouts as The other three are separate from them and they're older and they hang out not with them.
Scott: Yeah, they act like adults is the middle school girls and then there's the adult one.
Rym: So the adult ones are in high school.
Scott: Okay, despite the fact that they're like The Sailor Moon and friends look like they're in high school and but they're actually middle school.
Scott: So they're the other ones.
Scott: look like adults, but they're in high school.
Scott: Yes, so it's either too young or too old?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So the funny thing about this movie the s movie is that this is where you see the other three Sailor Scouts like Uranus Neptune and Pluto.
Rym: They're just so much better at being Sailor Scouts than everybody else.
Rym: Their attacks are like a million times more powerful.
Rym: They like have got their shit together.
Rym: The Sailor Scouts like blah blah blah the cats in love or something I don't know and those three are like, well something's attacking the earth.
Rym: What should we do while we sit in this coffee shop being dramatic and adults?
Scott: But the point is if you don't know these characters, you're not going to learn anything.
Scott: You're not gonna get to know them, right?
Scott: So, yeah, you definitely know.
Scott: I don't know anything about friggin sailor tiny moon that she just fucked up.
Rym: Oh, yeah, sure Chibi Uso, so she's.
Scott: I know that there's like some deal.
Scott: It's like she's sleeping with her mom and it's like no she's.
Rym: she wants to bone her dad because she doesn't know that That's her dad.
Scott: How did she not know?
Scott: cuz she goes back in time, but she should know that.
Rym: No, she goes back.
Scott: if I go back in time and see my mom when she's like in middle school I'll know it's my mom.
Rym: What if you didn't?
Rym: Cuz you're you know, you go back in time.
Scott: The problem is the point is you're not gonna get this story from this movie.
Scott: You're just gonna see this tiny Sailor Moon and be like what the fuck is up with her?
Scott: Right, and it's like like I was saying before.
Scott: it's like I don't know anything about Sailor Jupiter But I get the feeling like maybe I should go back and watch until she appears.
Rym: cuz she cuz she's green.
Scott: So I think I might like her.
Rym: you'll like her extra because when she becomes she's a green one.
Rym: She doesn't use her powers because she's actually just super strong.
Rym: It just fucking punches people like she is.
Scott: Yeah, she is dangerous on her own.
Scott: The other thing if you watch this is like, you know, if you know anything about space There's no Sailor Earth and there's no Sailor.
Scott: Sailor is tuxedo.
Rym: Tuxedo mask is sailor.
Scott: They don't tell you that in this movie.
Rym: Yeah, and also you want to know where Sailor Saturn is.
Rym: It's real complicated because the problem with this movie is that Sailor Moon s is the super serious Sailor Moon.
Rym: They're like, it's the antenna like Sailor Moon.
Rym: This is when you can.
Rym: horror was like pushing his crazy nonsense.
Rym: So it gets weird because it's hard to tell when this movie occurs Because the fact that you're just Neptune and Pluto are all alive and Sailor Moon has the Holy Grail.
Rym: cuz she fucked her attack where she like, yeah She does Holy Grail attack.
Scott: I was like damn son.
Rym: That is the Holy Grail the whole plot.
Scott: They're like, oh my god, you'll die if you use this special attack.
Rym: No, that's not the Holy Grail That's the silver crystal something that she also used sort of in the Sailor Moon our movie.
Rym: Here's the plot of the Sailor Moon Our movie.
Rym: Oh, no, we can't defeat the flower.
Rym: Sailor Moon says I'll use the crystal whatever.
Rym: no Sailor Moon.
Rym: if you do that You'll die, but you didn't.
Rym: but I have to and she does it.
Rym: and then she dies And then she undies and the movie ends in this movie.
Scott: She uses it and doesn't die doesn't die.
Scott: So I guess it's okay to use it.
Scott: It's not I guess.
Scott: don't use it too often.
Rym: I guess she powered it with her love.
Rym: I mean remember slayers right like they're like don't use the Giga slave.
Rym: It might destroy the universe.
Scott: They did Well remember in real life when they said don't use that bomb you might incinerate the entire atmosphere.
Scott: No But anyway I think it's just dangerous.
Rym: cuz when the crystal heart like when that crystal heart is out The point is it's real vulnerable.
Scott: If you don't know a lot about Sailor Moon, you're not going to get questions about fundamentals like who is sailing Saturn?
Scott: Why is you know?
Scott: and you're not gonna get that from here?
Scott: What you're gonna get is you're gonna get a relatively standalone episode of Sailor Moon stretched into an hour.
Scott: It could have been 20 minutes.
Scott: that is instead about an hour and is mostly about the cat and two NPCs that are gonna go After this movie's over.
Rym: so my problems with these NPCs one that the professor guy Sucks at astronomy.
Rym: Yeah sucks at life.
Scott: like that guy is a really bad scientist who believes in nonsense Even though the nonsense is real.
Rym: sort of he'd know.
Rym: but the thing is the nonsense he believes in isn't even real.
Rym: He believes that there's this magic princess on the moon and like yes tech there is true.
Rym: But one the thing you think is the princess is not.
Rym: and to the thing you think Sailor Moon is the princess on the moon In your childhood is nothing.
Rym: you you just believe bullshit and there happen to be unrelated things.
Scott: that Also, you're really lucky that that astronaut girlfriend likes you because damn she is like the awesomest.
Scott: and how come she's not sailor something?
Rym: Yeah, your first interaction.
Scott: How come?
Scott: yes, how come the smart scientist astronaut woman isn't sailor something?
Scott: Cuz she's like she would just take care of everything and all these high school girls in middle school girls go back to school.
Rym: She's like, hey, I'm a character and he's like Why don't you believe my magic space moon nonsense that I believe my whole life because is bullshit and even better What is his reaction?
Rym: He's looking in the sky, but he doesn't seem to.
Rym: he's like, is that a comet right?
Rym: And then he's like, oh shit it crashed into earth.
Rym: and then he goes and finds a crystal that it that came out of it.
Rym: And then he's like I saw a comet and she's like really I work at NASA.
Rym: No one saw any comet.
Rym: and he's like yeah hit the ground.
Rym: and she's like comets don't hit the ground.
Scott: if I come and hit The ground we'd be dead like everything you're saying makes no sense.
Scott: You're an astronomer.
Scott: You don't even see the comet in a meteor and a meteorite or any.
Rym: What the fuck's wrong with you, dude?
Scott: Yeah, why do I like you?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's anyway, the movies about the cat and the cat is usually an awesome character that I like a lot.
Rym: Yep, cut it head is awesome.
Scott: But in this movie the cat is not so awesome.
Rym: So Full disclosure cat falls in love with the moron.
Rym: we watched the dub.
Rym: because why not?
Scott: Because we should have watched the sub.
Rym: That's why the sub is better.
Rym: It was so bad.
Rym: Yeah, the dub is extra bad bad dub.
Rym: I forgot.
Rym: I forgot how bad it is bad.
Rym: What are the names of the characters?
Rym: what you can do when they come for you and especially because the three outer sensei like They sound a lot more serious in the real Original Japanese and their voices are kind of bad.
Scott: Okay, so here's my biggest problems with the dub number one.
Scott: The cat has a stupid voice.
Rym: She sounds like an old lady sounds like an old lady when really she's like a 20-something.
Scott: That's really weird.
Scott: Yeah Old lady cat to be in love with like this 20-something, dude.
Rym: Yeah, there's a moron and also Artemis all has a young man voice.
Rym: Why is Artemis so into this old lady cat?
Scott: Well, another thing is I just sort of assumed from the beginning that those cats were together and then they tell you that they're not And it's like and then they are so basically Artemis.
Scott: Why wouldn't the cats be together?
Rym: That is yeah, why even racist?
Rym: Why are you saying the cats got a date?
Scott: cuz the cats got date?
Rym: Why the cats got?
Rym: you're like Cartman in that episode?
Scott: Listen cats if it was a cat person and a human that'd be okay, but not a cat and a person's bestiality.
Rym: But she'd well, she has a cat person technically.
Scott: Why doesn't she just talk to the dude also?
Rym: Yeah, she almost does.
Scott: It's okay for these random NPCs to see Sailor Moon With a holy grail, but it's not okay for them to see a talking cat.
Rym: Yeah, but that point just be like, okay.
Scott: Listen, listen, like you've seen Sailor Moon, right?
Scott: So talking cat should not be a problem for you.
Rym: Yeah, this guy's just so dumb.
Scott: I mean you already believe in Space Moon Princess.
Scott: So talking cat should be just fine for you.
Rym: But this can also be confusing because the dumb professor looks just like Sailor Uranus.
Scott: Oh, does he?
Rym: Yeah, like save hair.
Rym: Basically Hair hair same face.
Rym: The eyes are just bigger here same hair.
Rym: Maybe also the professor looks just like Professor Tomoe from Sailor Moon s.
Scott: Isn't this Sailor Moon s?
Rym: Yes, but this is the movie which has nothing to do with the series except I guess it takes place around.
Scott: like Is a name of a character and I know that name and I know it's a Sailor Moon character Sailor Saturn's ma dad.
Scott: I've never seen Professor Tomoe and I don't know what he does or how he comes into the picture or anything.
Rym: He is insane and Dangerous is a bad guy.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Okay, but it's complicated.
Rym: basically Your question in the beginning of where's the Sailor Saturn?
Rym: That's kind of the whole plot of Sailor Moon s is where is Sailor Saturn?
Rym: Alright cuz Sailor Saturn's power is we fucked up reset the entire universe and kill fucking everybody.
Scott: So why is it?
Scott: Sailor Saturn that has this power and not like, you know Jupiter, which is way bigger.
Rym: Well because it's not about bigger It's about mythology.
Rym: or Mercury which is way closer has the power of stop time and time travel.
Scott: Or why not Sailor Andromeda who has the power of entire galaxy?
Rym: Well, there's other sailors to read the manga.
Rym: but So Artemis who's derpy is in love with Luna forget the dub.
Rym: she doesn't seem derpy.
Scott: He seems like totally chill and smart.
Rym: So he is per surprise.
Scott: He doesn't do more.
Scott: He just sort of does nothing in this movie.
Rym: that is so he is.
Rym: he is basically he is the Luna to sailor V Mmm, so like how come the other sailors don't have?
Rym: because fuck them.
Scott: I don't know not cat worthy.
Rym: I don't know why they're those two.
Rym: The manga probably has some reason for it.
Rym: Shouldn't there be a cat per sailor spoilers in Stars?
Rym: when people come back from the future There's a Diana who's a tiny pink cat and Diana is the child of Artemis and Luna.
Scott: So Artemis Luna find out so it's minikat sailor minikat.
Rym: Yeah, so they find out that they're gonna bone and make a baby at least one baby before they started dating.
Rym: Mm-hmm, so they're not dating yet.
Rym: Not really even a thing.
Rym: and then their future child comes down and says hey mom and dad Okay.
Scott: So if I'm sitting with someone I've never met before Like someone I'm only friends and kid from the future comes And it's totally and they prove it.
Scott: Why wouldn't we start boning like right away?
Scott: It's like we're gonna bone.
Rym: Anyway, so at the very end of Sailor Moon, right the very very end of stars Artemis Basically, the last thing he says in the entire show is like dumb throwaway line and a dumb throwaway scene.
Rym: You just never see him again.
Rym: cuz fuck him.
Rym: No, there's a theme throughout the entire show of yeah, we just gotta forget.
Rym: he exists Occasionally we remember.
Scott: Oh, but he seems good though.
Scott: Yeah, he really totally wasted.
Rym: He's the nice guy who really wants to date Luna, but Luna's like cats don't fall in love.
Scott: Wow, except in this movie, which is about cats falling in love.
Rym: Well Luna's weird cuz she's like cats don't fall in love and they're just not a thing for us.
Rym: And then she falls in love with this human like immediately the cat behind my apartment would beg to differ.
Scott: The other thing that sucks about this dub besides we we went a long time talking about old lady cat voice *weird noises*.
Scott: Right, so that the bad guy is the generic space ice queen who's somehow really powerful.
Rym: So her characterization is I have existed since the beginning of time.
Scott: I'm an evil ice space queen and then later Artemis.
Rym: I've decided to attack earth because because I want to add it to my collection All right.
Rym: I tried to attack earth once and was foiled somehow.
Scott: I'm gonna try.
Rym: I'm basically Galactus only an ice queen but she is as old as time.
Rym: Sure She is she is like a super mega boss as we know because when she comes in the movie She beats all the Sailor Scouts.
Rym: even the Holy Grail can't stop her.
Scott: Yeah, she's way strong But she doesn't really have any character other than I'm the bad guy and I want to collect the earth and I was foiled in The past.
Scott: and most of her attacks she attacks by sending out these ice minion Women banshee things and they make in the dub.
Scott: I don't know what noises they make in the sub.
Rym: they make us say the same noise in the sub.
Scott: in the dub They make a noise.
Scott: That's basically basically high-pitched Zoidberg and You spend about 25% of the movie listening to that whooping noise and watching character transformations and special attacks.
Rym: All of the Sailor Moon movies are primarily excuses to show the highest quality Transformation and at least one move usually two of every character and because you get a bunch of the characters in this one just transformation It would be a 20-minute episode.
Scott: But the reason it's an hour long is because whooping noises Transformations special attacks and then like maybe 10 minutes of exposition with cats falling in love.
Scott: So other than that, it's an episode of Sailor Moon.
Scott: Not really a movie.
Rym: well The other the only interesting thing is that the villain of the episode because remember this takes place in the middle of Sailor Moon Which is like the holy grail end of the world like Pharaohs coming to take over earth.
Scott: Is that?
Scott: is that?
Scott: wait but this is Sailor Moon s.
Rym: after that comes Sailor Moon super s candy candy monsters and the circus.
Scott: But I mean, that's the end of Sailor Moon.
Scott: is the super answer.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: The end is stars.
Scott: Okay stars is where there's a so it's Sailor Moon.
Scott: then what RS?
Scott: super s star.
Rym: Yes star.
Rym: So super s is the dead the dead moon.
Rym: and all this like dream shit happens.
Rym: stars is yeah.
Rym: Well while the entirety of Sailor Moon up to this point was happening.
Rym: That's all constrained to this one solar system, right?
Rym: There's a galactic war that's been going on that whole time And meanwhile the entire rest of the universe is fucked by this war.
Rym: and now the war Comes to earth because this is like the last solar system that hasn't been dragged into the war.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So it's like all the sailors of all the other solar systems like all this nonsense isn't happening and it's like if World War 2 was happening For decades
Scott: and you were in Switzerland and
Rym: you were in the US and the US just didn't know Like literally like the US had the Civil War just going and going and going and the Civil War ends.
Rym: You're like, ah, thank God that war is over.
Rym: and then like this boat goes by New York and you're like, what's that boat?
Rym: That's what stars is.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so the the baddies of s are like super dangerous and that's what they're actually fighting.
Rym: and in the middle of all that This shit happens, which is just as dangerous and is resolved in the course of like one day
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: so it's just interesting to see that in perspective you can figure out Based on who's alive and whether or not the fact that Sailor Moon has the Holy Grail Exactly where in s this occurs.
Scott: I'm sure you just look it up too on Wikipedia.
Rym: Uh, yeah I found someone said it's episode 122 or 123.
Scott: So you could really just take all the episodes after that increase their number by one and stick this right in there as episode Whatever which is horrifying because then it's like this long crazy drama building toward this like mega enemy Mistress 9 and Pharaoh and all that nonsense.
Scott: Pharaoh like the Egyptian Pharaoh.
Rym: Yeah Pharaoh's coming home like Pharaoh.
Scott: let my people go Pharaoh is basically the Moses.
Rym: remember that the bad guy in the fifth element Yeah, Pharaoh's basically that but that's a shitty villain.
Rym: No the thing from space not the dude.
Rym: Oh Professor Tomoe is the dude And Pharaoh is the thing.
Scott: Oh is is uh, serious.
Rym: It's got if you don't watch Are you?
Scott: are you saying that Sailor Saturn is a multi-pass?
Rym: Lelou actually, uh Like yeah, actually Okay, for real actually that actually is like.
Scott: actually actually but instead of Bruce Willis Sailor Moon Who's Ruby rod, haha, I Saw the best the cat is Ruby.
Rym: right the best Ruby rod cross play.
Scott: I saw that also best cosplay of all of mag.
Rym: that was so good.
Rym: That was tight the a-plus.
Scott: that I mean, I've seen other Ruby rods in the past.
Scott: That is not only the best Ruby rod cosplay.
Scott: I've seen in my life.
Scott: There's the best as cosplay of 2016 Period.
Rym: she struck a pose and it was like she must have practiced those poses.
Scott: I mean It was so great.
Rym: I don't even know what to say.
Rym: So Anyway back from that Ruby rod cosplay if you're gonna watch any Sailor Moon like Sailor Moon I'm gonna Google.
Scott: It's even.
Scott: it took a photo.
Rym: Sailor Moon s is like Everything you would like about Sailor Moon But anyway, this movie takes place in the middle of it.
Rym: So in the middle of that gigantic horrible plot, that's serious one of the villains of the day happens to be a villain for the beginning of beginning of time.
Rym: similarly galactic threat And they just deal with it and move on.
Rym: and it's just kind of weird to see that transition there like oh the holy grail That's the whole plot of Sailor Moon s. Yeah, it doesn't even fucking work.
Rym: That's how powerful the Snow Queen is.
Rym: Uh, I mean the plot gets resolved kind of stupidly.
Rym: it's just like oh the power of love or whatever.
Rym: yeah, you can watch the movie if you really care.
Rym: and What else happens?
Rym: This movie is just like you can watch it.
Rym: I guess I Used to think of it as the best of the Sailor Moon movies.
Rym: Think it still might be the best of the Sailor Moon movies.
Scott: It's better than a candy one.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know how you'll take the our movie the gay space flower that comes to destroy the earth.
Rym: It's a lot like that one piece movie that we watched.
Rym: Yeah So, yeah Sailor Moon cat movie, uh You can watch it if you want.
Rym: I guess This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Rym: cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of deep nights are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette construction noises ivy fame.
Rym: I stated calm.
Rym: William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: is a false statement.
Rym: serious time guys.
Rym: Emily's my beard Scott is my true the true love of my life.
Rym: Shervin von Horrell rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Montanota Superboy Abraham links this Aaron serious Brian Fisher sailor Vista.
Rym: pardon me, but are you Aaron Burr sir?
Rym: Matthew Smith Don Schleich chart television Jojo Joestar Tyler Eller Shawn Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open Lander Brian Sidroni Karen if redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We're uh, I'm packed.
Rym: We recorded the show a long time ago because we're literally on our way to pecs and Hopefully we will see some of you at pecs out our panels on Friday.
Rym: So otherwise, we're gonna mostly be in tabletop.
Rym: So come say hi, and if we don't see a pecs out, we'll probably see you at PAX East.
Rym: and now I leave you with.
Rym: I Even served us sometimes why but silly as he seen these will give you your protein My good buddy, right?
Rym: Divide put us together as a team.
Rym: We've got a flavor that's supreme.
Rym: These are rice beans and rice once or twice or even thrice beans and rice.
Rym: It's nice.