Rym: It's Tuesday September 26 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I am and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: on Tuesday it's Black Friday the 2010 board game about Black Friday the stock market Black Friday.
Scott: let's do this.
Rym: so a few days ago I smell.
Rym: I came home and I smelled like a whiff of mildew which I have never smelled in my New York apartment before.
Scott: I have just the old guy yeah.
Rym: but then it disappeared like I couldn't find it.
Scott: oh so just a whiff.
Rym: it was a way.
Rym: I mean we've sappin.
Scott: I've smelled whiffs of all kinds of smells.
Scott: you know I even you know.
Scott: sometimes I'll even smell a whiff of gas and like oh shit yup yup yup.
Scott: and then it's gone and like well I guess it was just like someone you know twisted something on their barbecue.
Rym: there was one time I was biking home back when I worked downtown and I was like way downtown and I'm in the middle of the street and I stopped at a stoplight.
Scott: I've definitely smelled it while biking in the middle but I smelled hella gas.
Scott: I've never smelled hella gas I've only.
Rym: so I'm like huh.
Rym: so the first thing I did was bike away.
Scott: yeah a good idea.
Rym: and then I was about to call 911 and then I see a whole bunch of Con Edison trucks come up and a bunch of people get out and start looking around and sniffing and then one guy points in a manhole and they were on it.
Rym: okay but so then the next day I came home and there was a whiff of it again.
Rym: second whiff.
Scott: that's a job I don't want.
Scott: Con Edison report go to the emergency where some smell gas job.
Scott: it's a bad job.
Rym: so uh but then I can't find it again and then I hear a bunch of construction noises going on and it sounds like it's in the wall behind our kitchen mm-hmm like in the inside area.
Rym: and then I go into my bathroom and there was some old water damage there and I see that they're like they're working outside of our apartment but related.
Rym: so I wonder if they're like fixing some water damage.
Rym: so I found a plausible explanation for occasional mildew with so I ignored it.
Rym: I came home the third day and I smelled it way stronger.
Rym: so at that point I have to do the I don't.
Rym: I don't just casually investigate.
Rym: I methodically start going around the apartment following the walls sniff testing mm-hmm and then I get near the fridge and it's real strong mm-hmm.
Rym: so it's.
Rym: I think it's behind the fridge which is terrifying.
Scott: cuz how do you get back there?
Rym: even yeah but it's not.
Scott: you know it would really help you see behind the fridge.
Rym: uh yeah I know exactly what helped me see behind the fridge endoscope.
Rym: I think I might get one of those endoscopes.
Rym: actually I got one in an Amazon cart right now.
Rym: but but I want to do some research to make sure I'm getting the right one.
Rym: I want to do any competing endoscopes the one that has the iPhone and Android app and has the hook and the magnet and has a light on the light on the front and it's real stiff.
Rym: so I can like put it straight up if I want but also long enough.
Rym: yeah well one of them is crazy long but it's crazy expensive but I digress.
Rym: so then I'm going around the kitchen and I can't look figure out where it's coming from.
Rym: like it's getting really irritating and unnerving I start like opening cabinets and double-checking and then as I'm walking across the kitchen again I suddenly remember there's a sack of potatoes on the like just sitting out and I go over and I sniff the bag and I smell it a little stronger and I open the bag and I sniff it.
Scott: mildew country just throw down potatoes out.
Rym: so but those are pretty new potatoes from the CSA.
Rym: they're like really nice potatoes.
Scott: so well I mean the CSA might not be the cleanest.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: so what I do is I open it up because the thing is usually when potatoes go bad they smell like a rotting human corpse.
Rym: they smell bad but this just smelled like mildew.
Rym: it did not smell like rotting potato.
Rym: so what I do is I put a big bowl in the sink and I dumped the entire potato sack in and two of the potatoes out.
Rym: of like 20 potatoes two of them had the consistency of a rotten fruit and when I squished one of basically exploded into mush.
Rym: that smelled like mildew.
Rym: so yeah that was horrible.
Scott: yeah this is the difference between you know CSA food and grocery food but also but but that so only two of these potatoes had this problem.
Rym: the rest like I washed them all.
Rym: they were all totally must have been attacked by something.
Rym: yeah but I've never in my life had a potato go bad in that manner ever.
Scott: also I guess that that's weird that the construction wasn't anything.
Rym: yeah the construction was a red herring.
Rym: the probably the other thing is in New York especially if you smell a smell and there is even a remotely yeah like if there's a remotely plausible source for the smell I'll assume it's that unless the smell persists or causes it's almost a problem.
Scott: cuz like I could be in my apartment and smell pee or something.
Scott: yeah I guess there's like a homeless bum outside or something.
Scott: it's like no I actually peed in my apartment on something I wouldn't know.
Rym: so yeah actually a couple weeks ago I was sitting in this room and I suddenly smelled a little bit of cigarette smoke.
Rym: now I was like oh fuck no.
Rym: and I look out the window and there is one person three stories down and these are tall stories.
Rym: so it's like five stories down in like a non New York building like that's how four and a half by their normal size stories.
Rym: now you forget how high the ceilings are here and our series my scene and our first floor is almost two stories.
Rym: sure cuz I got the highness something like four and a half stories up give or take and there's someone way down and way across in that like area where there's the construction smoking like one cigarette mm-hmm.
Rym: so I open the window and I yelled at him and he flipped me off.
Rym: but then the next day a whole bunch of no smoking signs appeared in that entire area down there mm-hmm.
Scott: so yeah you're not allowed to smoke in construction areas.
Rym: oh no no that's so.
Rym: it's not construction anymore.
Rym: you're not allowed to smoke anywhere on this building's property except in your own apartment.
Scott: you can smoke in your own apartment.
Rym: yeah this building is not one of these smoke-free buildings unfortunately.
Rym: but really yeah most buildings are not really mine is yeah most new buildings are but this building is not as new.
Rym: it's rent stabilized.
Rym: but technically you're allowed to smoke in your building.
Rym: but to this building's credit the only time I've ever smelled anyone smoking anything in their apartment it's been marijuana mm-hmm.
Rym: I have never actually smelled cigarette smoke coming out of an apartment mm-hmm.
Rym: so and the person who was smoking on?
Rym: they're pretty sure they did not live in any of these buildings.
Rym: so yeah that's mine.
Rym: that's my story.
Rym: okay that's all I got.
Rym: all right you got it.
Rym: had anything happen to you?
Rym: or should we get right into gaming living?
Rym: so in the news there's this game called PUBG player unknown battleground.
Rym: we've talked about it.
Scott: it's the biggest deal right now.
Scott: we might not be able to avoid it cuz it's such a big deal.
Rym: I almost played it the other night or the other evening but the weather is nice.
Rym: I biked instead but the game feels like it's got things I hate in games like.
Rym: I think there's some iron sites type aiming stuff like some RMA stuff but at the same time it's also a battle royale which is just a fascinating concept in games mm-hmm.
Rym: so the only reason I haven't played it yet does not seven at a time like it's one of those games that I feel like if I play it at all it'll be immediately apparent if it's bad and if it's not bad I'm probably gonna play it a lot.
Scott: yeah so the deal is someone else noticed.
Scott: hey PUBG is like a huge fucking deal right now.
Scott: yeah I think PUBG is not quite indie.
Scott: I read an article about the guy who made PUBG and he was a modder.
Scott: right it was a mod originally but then he sort of got hired and went to work with you know somewhat real game studios.
Rym: well that's how counter-strike came about.
Scott: this is a similar story to that right where you know it's a PUBG itself is not some in mod anymore that some guy made.
Scott: it's actually like this.
Scott: you know he's the leader of the team that makes it but you know he went to get a real game studio to make PUBG.
Scott: the mod he made is not PUBG.
Scott: it's like a. you know I think it was called.
Scott: it might have had the same name but it was like on a different engine and was crap.
Scott: you don't want to play that no one's playing.
Scott: yeah anyway.
Scott: so they know people noticed.
Scott: hey this is the number one game on Steam.
Scott: it's like the number one game period right now.
Scott: that's pretty good and other game studios that have more resources in such just added this game mode to their games or made similar games that are basically the same fucking thing.
Rym: now I'm a big fan of.
Rym: I'm glad that chicken dinner is coming back into the lexicon because of this game because that is how people would describe victories in sort of the predecessors of these games like gun game and counter-strike the or old death matches where there's a ton of players not even overwatch deathmatch which is just eight people.
Rym: we're talking like there is ten to twenty people in a game and it's long and in the end only one.
Scott: I mean this is nothing new right?
Scott: it's like you know even though you know was Mario Brothers even the first platforming game.
Scott: right it's all it was.
Scott: it's basically one step above pitfall right I have some arguments about what the first platforming game is right but regardless of which one it is right are you gonna say oh no no no those Janice sisters cannot be or are you know?
Scott: it's like they made her somebody at a racing game and then someone else makes a racing game and gonna be like no no no you can't do that right.
Scott: it's like yep you know they made as a space invaders and then there was a Galaga.
Scott: you can't be like.
Scott: no no Galaga is allowed.
Rym: we already made a space invader especially because you know when it comes to games in general it game design game mechanics game rules none of those things are really covered by copyright.
Scott: and regardless of law I guess this is mostly a legal issue.
Scott: but even without law it's like you can.
Scott: you can make the same kind of game that someone else has already made.
Scott: Magic the Gathering is not the only collectible card game right you know.
Scott: just even without taking law into account you can't own a concept.
Rym: no where on earth can you own a concept when Dominion sort of made deck builder of genre?
Scott: even people who really believe in strong intellectual property and whatnot recognize?
Scott: you can't own a concept.
Scott: yep so as best I can tell like imagine if like the first person with a jazz song is like no one else may make jazz.
Rym: I own jazz doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: you can't write so anyway.
Scott: so but what hat?
Scott: what's happened here?
Scott: this news story is that epic games the people who make the Unreal Engine right.
Scott: you know cuz pub G is on the Unreal Engine I'm pretty sure right?
Rym: think so yeah I don't know a lot about it.
Scott: yep but epic games that makes the Unreal Engine made this game using the Unreal Engine.
Scott: that is really really really really really battle royale.
Scott: that is ridiculously similar to pub G to the point at which it's like.
Scott: alright this isn't like I made a FPS and you made a FPS or I made capture the flag and you made capture the flag.
Scott: this is like you squeaked out of pub G. yeah and I and they basically think what happened.
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: I didn't read and I don't remember because this was already a date many days old news story.
Scott: I think they got the game out on other platforms besides PC before pub G would.
Scott: it was able to do that and that's why it's sort of like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: it's trying to conquer some territory that way.
Rym: yep I mean it's interesting is on one hand most of this kind of thing that happens are those garbage fake games on phones that try to look like a game that grandma's heard of so it gets bought.
Scott: that's actually what this looks like.
Scott: yeah it does have that kind of graphic design like huh if you're epic games you make the Unreal Engine shouldn't be able to make a better game.
Rym: but I'll be honest when it comes to this sort of thing I'm of the opinion that that sucks and whichever one of them is better is gonna win like kind of like how an idea is worth nothing.
Rym: only execution matters.
Rym: if someone has an idea for a kind of game but doesn't execute it fully and someone else takes the same idea and executes it better they're gonna win and that's probably that's the fastest way to evolve games.
Scott: yeah but I think there's.
Scott: there might be some legal action or there is gonna be some legal action or something.
Rym: I feel like that's not gonna get very far.
Scott: I'm not a lawyer there's no advice but if there is I definitely want to keep a close eyeball on that because that could have repercussions elsewhere seeing how that turns out in the blog post announcing the version under the Fortnite team byline epic rights.
Rym: we love battle royale games like PUBG and thought Fortnite would make a great foundation for our own version.
Rym: so they preemptively started calling them battle royale games to imply that that is a genre.
Scott: well everyone knows that is a battle royale game.
Scott: because I mean can battle royale the whoever wrote the book?
Scott: I don't know the author's name can they go after PUBG?
Scott: yeah right what about the Hunger Games the Hunger Games if all they should go after Hunger Games before they go after PUBG?
Scott: battle royale is real old.
Scott: it's like 1998 99 something like that is like.
Scott: that book is not new.
Rym: it's interesting that movie is actually way old.
Rym: yep well I actually watched the third mood like the end move.
Rym: I guess the third movie is actually two movies.
Rym: so there's four movies.
Scott: a third one.
Scott: I thought the second one was such like insane Oh garbage like crazier than Mamoru Oshii.
Scott: live-action crazy that I did not proceed any further.
Scott: but the first one is still a the first one's fine very important and terrific movie that you should see with Takeshi Kitano.
Scott: the rest of them makes everything good pretty much just there is only one battle royale movie no and it only has one sibling movie which is the only matrix movie that there is.
Rym: do not ever read the battle royale manga.
Rym: I cannot stress this enough.
Scott: I haven't read more than like one page of.
Rym: no matter how vile you might think it is it will surprise you.
Scott: I've actually haven't read the book and it's kind of big.
Scott: so I've always wondered like is it worth reading?
Scott: but you know maybe I check it out one day.
Scott: maybe that'd be a book.
Scott: good book club battle royale the book yeah.
Rym: so uh yeah I will see how this goes because it's very interesting because the other similar quote-unquote controversy has been going on.
Rym: is people talking about how battle-born and overwatch competed with each other even though they're ostensibly very different kinds of games.
Scott: well there's that lawbreakers thing too that yeah.
Rym: so I feel like this topic.
Rym: I kind of the reason we made this a news is that I don't really have any stake in the PUBG battle and I feel like whichever games better is gonna win.
Rym: I feel like lawsuits in either direction are gonna go nowhere.
Rym: but at the same time I feel like this is gonna crack the seal on this sort of issue being talked about more seriously in the games industry because there is definitely the trend from the old days of someone invents a kind of game and then there's a billion copycats immediately to try to sponge off of that.
Rym: I feel like that is accelerating as a pace rapidly and I don't know what's gonna happen.
Scott: but usually in the past the copycats have always been worse right than the original.
Scott: but if we get into situations where one developer with tons of resources right sees a really great game from someone without a lot of resources you know back in the day like you know you would hire the portal like the person who made portal.
Scott: that was like some demo or something or some art project or whatever and then valve hired them and they made the real portal cynical counterpoint.
Rym: but if you don't
Scott: somebody sees someone's doing a thing and then suddenly just goes off and beats them at their own game because they got mad money's that's maybe not so cool ah
Rym: but at the same time if you feel like you don't need to hire that original person or creative team what did they actually do other than have the idea?
Rym: mm-hmm I mean they are the only thing they've done really is market research for you as well.
Scott: well you'd also hope that you know they've learned lessons already because they've been working on it for so long and you can avoid having to learn those lessons yourself if you hire them.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: but also kind of the side thing is games themselves.
Rym: you know because I'm kind of a UX expert that's a lot of what I do in my professional life.
Rym: games don't have UX.
Rym: they sort of are UX meaning all these salient parts of a game are explorable by anyone even someone trying to rip the game off.
Rym: the parts that aren't explorable are like engineering and architecture pieces primarily that any confident person if you hire the right team could sort of put together on their own usually.
Rym: but you can fully explore the user experience or what the game is like and what features work and don't without permission from anyone.
Rym: so we'll see where this all goes.
Rym: but I feel like this topic is gonna get talked about more and more and more over the next couple years and we'll see what happens.
Rym: mm-hmm in some other news.
Rym: there's some trouble in the Smash Brothers scene.
Scott: that scene always has trouble.
Scott: it's like the most drama of all.
Scott: yeah like and I'm even at all scenes but it is always a drama-filled scene.
Rym: like I feel like the smash scene has drama above and beyond the fighting game scene within which it resides.
Scott: well I think it's.
Scott: also it's always felt like it's next to the fighting game scene and not really in it.
Scott: cuz smash is so different from say Street Fighter or MVC or yeah but MVC and Bushido Blade are completely different games.
Scott: yeah but Bushido Blade doesn't have any community.
Scott: so that's me I don't think you're.
Scott: actually I think you've actually had to play Bushido Blade.
Scott: you just get your ass kicked.
Scott: yeah probably the thing is you know you probably don't even remember the control.
Rym: nope not at all.
Rym: you know what I remember.
Rym: if you if you have a throwing like you're just like the idea of Bushido Blade.
Scott: you're like actual Bushido Blade.
Rym: no the problem is I like Bushido Blade but when I say I there's an asterisk and that asterisk says Rym a long time ago through the filter of memory and age anyway.
Scott: but smash is like such a different game and attracts a different crowd.
Scott: there's not a lot of crossover between like smash melee masters and Street Fighter masters.
Scott: right but a lot of times you'll see Street Fighter masters you know playing some other fighting games and also being really damn good at them.
Rym: but smash people are only smash as far as I can tell.
Scott: yeah well they might play other games but usually you don't see them too much.
Rym: so there's a pretty serious problem for that community.
Rym: that is not a problem for any other fighting game community.
Scott: the problem is the old GameCube controller which is a great controller even though it looks weird and when everyone saw it for the first time was like what the fuck yep then you put your hands on it.
Rym: it's like when Morty experienced true level.
Rym: you're like oh like to this day because I played more Soul Calibur when Soul Calibur 2 was out on this controller.
Scott: I can't play Soul Calibur 2 on a different controller.
Rym: I guess I could get used to it but it would be difficult for me to play a Soul Calibur game because I'm a vertical attack my horizontal attack and it just mapped so nicely.
Rym: but Nintendo has now made a GameCube of controllers in a long ass time.
Scott: no they've been out of manufacture for quite a while because no one has a GameCube anymore that you even sell Wii's anymore.
Rym: and unlike the N64 smash community which does exist and has its own problems let's stay away from them.
Rym: yeah that that's that's like the people who still play Counter Strike 1 6 in here 2017 but because the GameCube controller could still be plugged into the Wii and the Wii U really the Wii U?
Scott: I didn't know.
Rym: I heard that's what this article said.
Rym: the Wii U?
Rym: okay I don't know.
Rym: I didn't verify that.
Rym: cuz of course why would I have a Wii U?
Scott: I never used a Wii U quote.
Rym: the aging GameCube controller is a smash staple not just for melee but for the two more recent games in the franchise which were released for the Wii and the Wii U. so that means that it's not just people who grew up in the GameCube era are used to this controller and everyone else in the smash community moved on.
Scott: people who play Smash Wii also need GameCube controllers even though it's a Wii game.
Rym: but Nintendo didn't keep making them.
Rym: no they let you plug them in but they didn't let you make them which there are.
Scott: there are Wii pro controllers you could use.
Scott: they're not good.
Scott: not GameCube controller good.
Rym: so smash community basically has this problem of its final destination Fox.
Rym: only GameCube controller.
Rym: first party no mods only mm-hmm.
Rym: the fuck are they gonna do?
Rym: because there will always be any given day fewer functional GameCube controllers than there were before.
Scott: well you can just fix one and you can also not fucking destroy them right?
Rym: it's like they were out like even a mouse like a fancy mouse.
Rym: you'll see.
Rym: they have mean time before failure like how many times can you click?
Rym: a couple million you don't click too hard.
Rym: a lot of no it's not a matter.
Rym: don't click too hard as a matter of entropy.
Scott: I'm just saying you can there.
Scott: you can behave in such a way to make them last longer.
Rym: yeah but not that doesn't matter.
Scott: obviously not going to be.
Rym: that longer would have been last from the GameCube era.
Rym: through the Wii era you can also the GameCube era the Wii era the Wii U era and now the switch air.
Scott: you can also repair them.
Scott: so easier said than done if you got a 3d printer and you got a soldering iron you can repair a controller.
Rym: uh yeah but it's difficult.
Rym: and two if it's not a first party controller and someone's cracked it open and soldered it.
Rym: ah you know they didn't cheat.
Scott: you check the controller.
Rym: how do you how you gonna look at that?
Rym: tell me if that's legit or not.
Scott: you write it.
Scott: you get a piece of software.
Rym: you think the smash community who's built their entire existence around console gaming as opposed to a PC is capable of that.
Scott: this is you know you get.
Scott: there's plenty of we mods we has been homebrewed and hacked for quite a while.
Scott: you make a little we app where someone plugs in a GameCube controller and you have to push all the buttons and then it tells you whether the GameCube controller is legit or not.
Rym: so there are.
Rym: so if you read this article you'll find out there's actually significant specific reasons why they're very difficult to repair because the kinds of repairs that were easy are already done all the time and now they're so old that they're failing in other ways and it's starting to come down to like was it from the beginning of the manufacturing run or the end of the manufacturing run?
Scott: well I got a bunch of give controllers and I'm gonna hold on to them until the smash melee.
Scott: people are so desperate they'll pay me like a fortune for it.
Rym: I feel like Nintendo could make some money but they won't because they don't care.
Rym: they don't want to be in the non console hardware business.
Scott: somebody will eventually right.
Scott: just make something that lets you use like a Wii pro controller on the.
Scott: you know it's like.
Rym: oh no it's got to be this exact shape or that community is gonna freak out.
Scott: well you're gonna have to give up at some point.
Scott: right since we talked about this I think story earlier where the arcade people are running out of CRT's.
Rym: yeah or DDR?
Rym: if you're an aficionado of dance dance revolution good fucking luck.
Scott: getting a good dance pad you know at the foot of my bed is a bunch of junk I'm trying to get rid of and I'm actually make gonna make some headway now on that.
Rym: you're not getting rid of your red octane are ya?
Rym: you don't play DDR anymore.
Rym: is that?
Scott: haven't use that red octane in so long and I don't know if it works a hundred percent.
Scott: I think it might have some bad arrows.
Rym: yeah well I have three working.
Scott: you can try to fix mine if you want.
Scott: yeah anyway but the at the foot of my bed though is a plastic guitar hero guitar for the Wii.
Rym: yeah you can just throw that shit away and it's like but what it wait but what.
Rym: but what if that community is not the same as the smash community?
Rym: that ship sailed and sank.
Scott: but if I feel like playing guitar hero though one day I still have the game.
Rym: so there's a longer meta story like meta story here on the top about eSports in general and smash will never be a top-tier esport for reasons like this.
Rym: yeah consoles cannot without making them effectively.
Rym: pcs support modern eSports because modern eSports requires significant spectator infrastructure and significant anti cheating and uniformity infrastructure.
Rym: you're not gonna get that with any kind of consoles.
Scott: even like games that are eSports which are supported by the companies that make the games have really shitty and subpar infrastructure.
Scott: there's a game I've talked about it before.
Scott: I have yet to actually play it though I do have access to it.
Rym: I have to just that Amazon one right.
Scott: I just had to be home on one of the weekends where you can play it.
Scott: it's called breakaway.
Scott: it's made by Amazon who owns twitch by Amazon Game Studios and basically it looks like a MOBA but there's a ball and the goal is to get the ball to the other end.
Scott: so it's a sport but also a MOBA kind of thing and they are building the game from the ground up with eSports and spectating and streaming it as like the first priority and that just makes it interesting.
Scott: cuz like well if you're good at that even if the game doesn't get popular maybe you could mooch off some Amazon twitch monies by being like the king of this game or something right that no one currently even cares about like the forum has like no one in it the official forum.
Scott: so you know I'm not saying I'm not promoting that game.
Scott: I didn't know what's good.
Scott: I haven't played it yet I just have it downloaded.
Scott: but that's the kind of thing that you're gonna need for eSports going forward.
Rym: but here's the other thing that's interesting when it comes to preservation of old experiences like old Atari 2600. the controllers are so simple that people can effectively repair them indefinitely in a way that they really can't do with the GameCube type stuff.
Scott: but also there are enough GameCube controllers that in forever right at least.
Rym: no no not forever.
Scott: you see that's the kind of um you know it's a museum that is preserving game.
Rym: that's the kind of like we'll be always post-apocalyptic thinking.
Scott: they always have at least one working game cube controller together.
Rym: until all the canned food runs out it's out.
Rym: but there's gonna be a time where the last GameCube controller is buried by the Lorax.
Scott: no no there is.
Rym: that day will come now.
Scott: but with the Atari and all that as long as there are people who care about preserving GameCube controllers there will be one in a museum.
Rym: almost every other semi-professional or serious community around a legacy console game has ways to make do that.
Rym: the smash community has uniquely tied itself to a limited number of consoles and a limited number of a very specific controller.
Scott: something else is that you know Nintendo did at certain points make promotional items of basically Super Nintendo controller replicas that were just plugged into wii's.
Scott: true I can definitely see on like GameCube anniversary them releasing like GameCube controllers that work on a newer system or whatever they and then people will just make adapters for them.
Scott: you know they're definitely going to be within our lifetime the GameCube.
Scott: a GameCube similar controller will be manufactured as some sort of novelty by Nintendo.
Scott: cuz that's how they do so.
Scott: yet another issue here is that because this community they just made NES classic and SNES classic one day GameCube would be so old.
Scott: they'll be GameCube classic because this game n64 classic isn't coming within like you know.
Scott: so Scott there's another problem here.
Rym: next year Christmas n64 classic bet on it because this community is so obsessed with this controller being intrinsic part of the game.
Rym: they've also basically prevented any amount of handicap accessibility that's in their scene.
Rym: that's a shame in a way that fighting games have embraced I mean with the fight sticks and all the alternative inputs.
Rym: yep so GameCube controllers have caused people some injuries.
Scott: well they've also not only denying disabled people from playing a game.
Scott: you're just denying people from playing your game if they can't get the equipment.
Scott: yeah it's just like oh sorry you weren't a kid.
Scott: when GameCubes are out and you don't have a bunch of money to buy one from someone.
Rym: sorry get tennis rackets were only manufactured between 2001 and 2009 so I guess you can't ever play tennis unless you buy some old tennis racket on eBay.
Scott: yeah you can't play this game.
Scott: it's not for sale anymore.
Scott: sorry oh you want to play this collectible card game that they don't print anymore but it's still a big deal.
Scott: that's a shame.
Rym: so yeah I guess the moral is the smash community is really really weird and this is just kind of funny.
Rym: there's more just more examples of their weirdness but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so way back we had to have made this a thing of the day.
Rym: there's a definitely
Scott: thing of the day
Rym: but Wintergatan is this amazing YouTube channel slash person who makes really complicated musical experiences and the most famous one is this giant machine that just plays music with marbles and it's amazing and this person is currently working on a much more elaborate and interesting version of that machine.
Rym: but as an aside they do a bunch of awesome stuff and they made this video using an instrument they developed and a bunch of other instruments to play dr.
Rym: Wiley's castle theme from Megaman 2. and not only is it fascinating to see how he made this music but it sounds really good it's accurate and it gave me some Megaman feels reminded me how much I like Megaman 2's music usually a homemade instrument.
Scott: you know you get like some hard drives playing some music or something and it's not really doesn't sound that impressive.
Rym: this sounds great.
Scott: it sounds incredible for this thing.
Scott: it's like whoa.
Rym: yeah it's good stuff.
Rym: so what you got?
Scott: so here's an.
Scott: I guess it's an art installation.
Rym: I guess as we call it that this count says so.
Scott: basically I think it's in Germany right.
Scott: a bunch of people decided to entertain the train passengers by doing stuff out in the empty fields outside the train window the idea being like hey you're riding the train stop just looking at your phone.
Scott: instead look out the window.
Scott: we're gonna do fun stuff as the train passes by for like a whole day.
Scott: and it was a great community event because all the people who live in these farm areas got together and met each other and you know had a good time working on this together.
Scott: so there's one more like a bunch of people are behind bushes they're holding bushes and when the train comes they start running until Pernham Wood comes to Dunstanane right you know.
Scott: and there's like this one.
Scott: you know it's all kinds of interesting ones but the the most the craziest one was.
Scott: a bunch of people get in a costume and all look like the same person and they pretend to basically be having a race with the train.
Scott: it's like you know the person.
Scott: the first person runs and then jumps and then you can't see them anymore and then another person comes out from behind something with the same costume and runs and it looks like the person.
Scott: it basically creates the illusion that someone is racing and beating the train in a foot race even though it's a crazy fast train.
Scott: these are shockingly elaborate and at the very end at the train station there's like someone there like already you know who's wearing the costumes.
Scott: it looks like they beat the trains at the train station but they basically did this whole thing.
Scott: all these all these different scenes and acts were repeated you know for all the trains throughout the day.
Scott: they think they did it for like a few hours or whatever so you can have all the fun of riding these trains just by watching this YouTube video.
Rym: yeah one of my favorite I mean these are this really is more installation like you said than prank.
Rym: but my favorite pranks in the world are do something weird where someone questions reality a little bit and they can't explain it.
Scott: this isn't a prank.
Scott: they're like they think the people on the train knew to look out for it.
Rym: at least some of the people know.
Rym: but imagine the person who doesn't know just like on the train like fucking down with their phone and they look up and they notice that guy.
Scott: well the illusion isn't that great is the thing?
Rym: it's not it you know it's it's obvious when you look at it like how depends though because the trains moving fast you only see it for like a second.
Scott: sure sure but you know like.
Rym: they put that fake house up and then it's gone like the next time they go by like that kind of nonsense.
Rym: hmm so yeah in the meta moment we got two videos up that you should watch.
Rym: so one our pecs panel from pecs was 2017. the age of the quitter is a hundred percent on YouTube in glorious 2k because I didn't feel like uploading 50 or 60 gigabytes of 4k and you really don't need 4k of our faces.
Rym: and Scott uploaded on his channel meaning you got described both of our channels.
Rym: the first non anime Boston produced episode of GeekNights judge anime by its cover.
Scott: yeah it's gonna be a quarterly show.
Scott: so four times a year like about a couple weeks before the new anime season starts we're gonna put up a video.
Scott: we go through the anime chart at any chart net and judge based on almost no information whatsoever which anime are gonna be worth watching and which ones you should stay the hell away from.
Scott: and we have uploaded the first episode of this show and it's only gonna get better.
Scott: in a few months we'll do the next episode.
Rym: yeah so there you go and I'm actually watching a lot of anime these days.
Rym: so it's feeling good and I finally fully understand exactly what it means for a show to be a darker than black you and your darker than black.
Scott: anyway the book club book is the fifth season by NK Jemisin.
Scott: I finished reading it a while ago.
Rym: I've been busy.
Scott: how are you doing so?
Rym: I'm only like five chapters in because uh-huh I don't have a commute anymore like it takes me like ten minutes to get to work.
Scott: there's other times during the day that you can read like before you go to bed when you wake up.
Rym: ah but I've been busy when you're at work not doing work.
Rym: ah so that's the thing my new job.
Rym: I've been doing work the whole time I'm at work.
Scott: yeah I'm just saying there's time you know.
Scott: when you're sitting somewhere waiting for something you know whatever.
Rym: yeah I'll be reading it real soon.
Rym: I'm gonna power through it because I really like what I read.
Rym: so far.
Rym: I can see why people when they start these books.
Scott: I've already started on the sequel which also won a Hugo Award just like the original which is the book that we're doing.
Scott: and there is a third one which I think is the last one but I haven't at least you're not I'm only the beginning of the second one of like.
Rym: I was where we both read the wheel of time one as the book club and we both just kept reading and then I just kept reading till I hit the end.
Scott: I read like four or five wheel of time.
Rym: yep but I I read them all and I know the full dealer Randall tar and what's up with the magic.
Scott: I don't need to read anymore.
Rym: yeah the problem is it.
Rym: it would take me longer to summarize it then it would take you to just fucking read them.
Rym: so yeah but the fifth season it's summarizing.
Rym: I defy anyone to summarize the.
Scott: I need to know the parts about the creepy tower.
Scott: I don't need to know anything else.
Rym: yeah that's really all you want to know about.
Rym: yeah cuz that's the least explained of everything.
Scott: of course the good the best part is always the least explained.
Scott: that's how it always is.
Scott: you fucking fantasy sci-fi people right the coolest thing should be the most explained.
Scott: if you're watching a Star Wars movie there should be awesome Empire shit.
Scott: see more than stupid rebel shit.
Scott: no stupid lame-ass pussy rebels on the screen right not enough TIE fighter too much x-ray over the course of all that Prince of nothing.
Rym: they're like Oh God or off go God or out.
Rym: and then in the last book we just read there fucking is and we're just going inside this but they and then they're like oh by the way the real cool shit is actually gods haha.
Rym: anyway well we'll see what it.
Rym: what is a guy any other?
Scott: yeah so in meta basically just go on the internet to all the places that we are all the social YouTube the social networks the YouTube channels the websites the everything and get with it.
Rym: so we played a ton of games at PAX.
Scott: oh yeah like even though PAX is already like a month ago.
Rym: if we did nothing on Tuesday shows but review games we haven't reviewed yet that we played at PAX.
Scott: we'll be at PAX unplugged we'll be.
Rym: we would make it past PAX South yeah without running out which I guess they got to submit the panels for that.
Rym: mm-hmm.
Rym: so cod pecs out.
Rym: this coming up mm-hmm.
Rym: yeah X unplugged is coming up.
Rym: exos is coming up but we're skipping it this year.
Rym: mm-hmm.
Rym: we were gonna go next year for sure for 01 the omega-thon.
Rym: but because she only gets you got pretty deep but she didn't win.
Rym: so I think I'm skipping one more pack sauce.
Rym: but I'm feeling like 2019.
Rym: I'm gonna go back to 2018. go to Essen Essen it's time.
Rym: but the reason I want to review Black Friday is that it neither sounds if you don't know who made this game.
Rym: it neither sounds nor looks like the kind of game that me and Scott would like.
Scott: well no I mean it's a. it's a game made by Friedman free.
Rym: oh yeah you don't know who made it.
Scott: so Friedman freeze is this guy with green hair who made power grid which I think in German is called Funkin.
Rym: German.
Rym: all his games all his games begin with the letter F not all of them as we learned.
Scott: no not all.
Scott: most of his games are you know FF something like fresh fish?
Scott: yeah and they come in a green box just like his hair.
Scott: that's how you can tell when it's his game.
Scott: so black market is another and I can't believe how many games this dude is made but I thought he played every game.
Scott: but no there's another one.
Scott: it's called black market.
Scott: there's a black market fuck if I know all right a Black Friday.
Scott: I mean is it something Friday like?
Rym: I'll try to look at something else every day?
Scott: or who knows?
Rym: but Friedman freeze is almost tied with Canis II I think for reliably able to scratch and itch that Rym and Scott have related to gaming.
Rym: mm-hmm about the name of the first game in the fruit egg pro.
Rym: it's in a project but here is it something.
Scott: here is it from 2010 so it's pretty old it's real.
Scott: but anyway I'd never seen this game before or I've never seen it in a store.
Scott: I've never seen it played.
Scott: I'd even know it existed but then there it was.
Rym: we see why I'm saying that like oh this doesn't look like at surface value a game that room Scott would play.
Rym: if you look at this you see a weird-looking board that looks like it's from one of those Milton Bradley kind of games in the u.s.
Rym: a bunch of paper money and a bunch of nonsense and a victory track.
Scott: we didn't use paper money.
Scott: views chips right.
Rym: yeah yes chips but paper money paper money anyway.
Scott: so what this game is is about Black Friday stock market Black Friday as in the day the stock market crash right.
Scott: so there's.
Scott: it's really hard to explain the exact rules so I'm not going to.
Scott: but basically what this game amounts to is that there is silver and over time silver will increase in value.
Scott: it starts off real cheap.
Scott: what like 20 bucks or something 50 50 to 100 I forget.
Rym: anyway it starts off it goes from zero and it starts going up.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: it starts off cheap and gets expensive when it hits the top.
Scott: that's when the game ends right.
Scott: yep when silver hits its max value I'm pretty sure that's one of the things that ends the game and basically victory points is money is money but silver is basically the money you have at the end of the game.
Rym: so you can get money and you can use that money to either buy more stocks or convert it to silver.
Rym: what is it converted to silver?
Rym: you can't turn it back into money.
Rym: I can't sell.
Scott: I didn't see any way to sell silver.
Rym: you can't sell silver but you want.
Scott: so if you in most games you're trying to figure out like all right when do I?
Scott: like a Puerto Rico?
Scott: I obviously early game doubloons are worth more and late-game victory points are worth more.
Scott: obviously cuz victory points are all that matter.
Scott: but if you go for victory points right away in Puerto Rico you'll have no doubloons and no barrels and then you won't be able to get more victory.
Rym: it's like race for the galaxy.
Rym: don't do the x2 consume on the second round right?
Scott: you know that's how most German euro timing games work.
Scott: is that you have to build this resource engine crank it up just exactly the right amount of efficiency and then pull the levers that it starts producing victory points at the right time and the right amount but still also producing resources to get even more victory points so that you can basically completely exhaust all resources at the exact end of the game to have the most possible victory points because there's a timer in the way.
Scott: it does.
Scott: no timer.
Scott: you could just crank as hard as possible and then get a big infinite fountain of victory points.
Scott: that's stupid.
Scott: in Black Friday.
Scott: if you go for victory points early you could just buy a silver right away and it's so cheap that you kind of want to.
Rym: but your upside is at most 80.
Scott: that's still a really good upside.
Scott: yeah compared to you later in the game you buy one at like 90 shares of a stock that ends up being worth like 200 each right.
Scott: so that's the thing.
Scott: is that the only other thing you can do really is engage in the stock market.
Scott: that's hella risky.
Scott: it is based on pulling random cubes out of a bag.
Rym: now the stock market in this game is shockingly I'm not gonna say accurate to the real stock.
Scott: it's not accurate in its mechanism.
Rym: it's accurate in its motion in terms of liquidity affecting price and momentum and in terms of it's.
Rym: this game is designed to form bubbles.
Rym: so I start buying a stock and it goes up a little bit.
Scott: so I buy a stock which means I get a cube and we put a cube in the bag and the
Rym: same color same stock Rym
Scott: buys one and we put another one in the bag right and now if there's a lot of cubes in the bag this stock has a good chance of going up but then if everyone keeps buying it and the cubes come out of the bag which makes the price go up right and then people buy more cubes and the price goes up but now there's not a lot of cubes in the bag
Rym: because the price is up fewer people are buying.
Rym: so the game comes down to because the price went up from people buying it.
Scott: people started selling and now there's black cubes in the bag.
Scott: and when black cubes come in the ad out of the bag prices go way down.
Rym: yep.
Scott: so you're trying to buy stocks that have cubes in the bag and then once the cubes come out of the bag you want to sell right away and things get cray.
Rym: yep and a stock's price can move a significant amount.
Rym: but all these?
Rym: it's really hard to explain all the ways that stocks will move without just teaching you literally the entire.
Scott: there's a crazy grid of numbers and they move up left down and right.
Rym: it's all weird and stuff and there's things that aren't really encoded in the board that you just have to know by reading the rule book like when the third cube is taken.
Scott: then this thing happens and we reprice all the stuff.
Rym: but unlike a lot of board games the one saving grace is that as long as at least one person at the table fully understands all those rules they can facilitate all the parts of the game that are complicated and even if you don't fully understand what they're doing
Scott: you can still understand enough to realize when it that you to figure out.
Scott: okay I don't completely understand which cubes are moving where but I know enough to know that this stock is bubbling that one's tanking that one's on the rise and you can just tell right before I there was like as we played the game a few times it wasn't until like towards the end of the first playthrough that I fully understood how like all the rules of all the cube movement.
Rym: but I knew I was about to cry.
Scott: I was still a hundred percent right about what was happening in the market.
Scott: regardless because it moves.
Rym: naturally the game is a lot of great moments like I buy a stock and Scott buys the same stock right after me there was like oh shit I won.
Scott: so the first time he played I won and what happened was his Rym bought a stock and then it was.
Scott: then he went first and it was everyone else's turn and I said all right everyone Rym bought what color?
Rym: you forget.
Scott: it was like pretend it was blue.
Scott: I'm like I listen everyone.
Scott: let's all go in together on orange.
Scott: everybody.
Scott: orange Rym went blue.
Scott: if we go blue we're gonna put a bunch of blue cubes in the bag and help Rym all of us orange and we'll all get a bunch of money and Rym won't.
Scott: and sure enough that's exactly what the hell happened.
Scott: it was totally great and I won.
Rym: so what's really fascinating too is that the game's very the game looks like and when you first start to learn it even feels like it's gonna be very fiddly number heavy in terms of like.
Rym: someone who's not good at math could have significant analysis.
Rym: paralysis trying to decide what to do.
Scott: if you try to analysis paralysis this game don't play this game but the game it's good enough to just know it's gonna go up a little up a medium up a lot down a little.
Scott: you don't need to know the exact number.
Rym: fascinating how well very simple heuristics on the board like.
Rym: are there a lot or a small number of green cubes on deck for the green stock?
Rym: are there a lot or a small number of them in this other area.
Rym: how many black suitcases are in the bag?
Scott: how many really?
Rym: simply heuristics like that gets you?
Rym: 99%?
Rym: as far as trying to calculate actual probability where is where is the price of silver?
Scott: right now?
Rym: the game seems to because the numbers are too like.
Rym: odds are really difficult to calculate to the point that I don't think anyone playing this game could feasibly do it.
Rym: the fact that it's effectively impossible for the majority of players means that people won't even try to do it and this game I think is really good at fostering surprisingly nuanced heuristics and players they don't fully understand the logic of the heuristics they're using.
Scott: I think another great thing was.
Scott: game is simply that it has the classic drama we see so often of pulling stuff out of a bag.
Rym: Oh bag drama is one of my favorite things.
Scott: now Christine Euphrates what's the one with the digging for treasure?
Scott: Oh 7 7 right.
Scott: any game where you pull stuff randomly out of a bag is the awesomest right.
Scott: I'm way into bag pulling right now so I mean even even rah.
Scott: rah is like the worst bag pulling game.
Scott: yeah but basically even though you might be there were situations where it's like I know that bag is like a hundred percent blue cubes oh my god this is gonna happen and then after they finish pulling stuff out of the black suitcase black suitcase black suitcase.
Scott: it's like all black suitcases and blue ends up going down even though it's like oh my god why.
Scott: and it's you know it's.
Scott: it's like crazy shit happens and you totally get boned against the odds just like in the real stock market and that creates a lot of drama which is fun even if it's not the best in terms of like.
Scott: making it a skill game.
Scott: yep but the real world is not a school skill game.
Scott: it's full of luck and risk and nonsense.
Rym: unlike say camel up which has a very high luck factor for that sort of drama this game has a very high skill factor despite all that nonsense because that's pretty much the only luck is the pulling things out of a bag.
Scott: right now can't think of any other luck sources in the game.
Rym: well you start with an initial loadout of some stocks.
Scott: oh your initial loadout is random but it effectively doesn't matter because this game is not an FF.
Rym: Schwartz are free tag.
Rym: okay black Friday has a F gotta be the word for Friday.
Rym: so black Friday.
Scott: well Schwartz definitely means black in Germanic languages.
Rym: yep black for oh and they use currency symbols.
Rym: okay that's cute mm-hmm.
Rym: but yeah the game is just kind of like pen Dante.
Rym: this game had a similar feel in the sense that this was a game that greatly exceeded my somewhat low expectations and was way more fun than I expected and as a result got way more of our precious packs tabletop hours than I expected.
Rym: yes so late this game what three times?
Scott: yeah?
Scott: so if you're a person who likes stock market type things right and you know you like playing like one of the stock market games you buy stocks with fake money.
Rym: oh this game is gonna scratch you so good.
Scott: and then you wait for the real market to move and you play that game over like multiple days.
Scott: right you see who who has the most money?
Scott: at the end of a month everyone starts with a thousand dollars of fake money.
Scott: this gives you all the more fun than that in only like a couple hours and the only thing you're missing out on is the real-world stock market stuff.
Rym: right you can play this game real quick if everyone you're playing with this smart you only need one person to 100% know all the rules.
Scott: yeah that's important because that person better a hundred percent know all the rules perfectly yeah because it actually trusting them.
Scott: you're also trusting them to not cheat.
Rym: but most of the weird complexity that you might imagine this game has like I said it distills really like really simply into heuristics that are digestible.
Rym: and this game in terms of the ebb and flow and deciding when to shift from money generation to better victory point money generation because it's all just money.
Rym: in the end it's similar to st.
Rym: Petersburg.
Rym: yeah yeah like you have your two modes and you're flipping between them.
Scott: the other great thing about this game is that the your turns are really simple.
Scott: it's like comes to your turn.
Scott: it's like you can buy some stock.
Scott: yeah you can sell some stock.
Scott: you can buy some silver.
Scott: it's like there's not really.
Scott: it's a lot like ticket to ride.
Scott: we're in very modern design where you go around taking very small actions on your turn.
Scott: there isn't a lot of like.
Scott: hmm I'm gonna move this but where do I move it?
Rym: kind of stuff and a consequence of that is that there's a lot of table.
Scott: it's like I'll buy a blue cube.
Scott: that's my turn.
Rym: go lots of table banter and player interaction like come on Scott greens hot join me buy some green stock with me.
Rym: we'll make out like bandits except we went against Rym.
Scott: we did the smart thing.
Scott: don't don't get on the Rym team.
Scott: everyone getting up on Rym and that totally worked like in that page is what you should be doing.
Scott: every time I tell you to do that see how well it worked do it again every so and we play getting up on Rym.
Rym: in the three ongoing long-form Civ games I have the first one the big crew one that they hang up on Rym.
Rym: so the entire world has been at war with me for like a hundred years.
Scott: good job world.
Rym: literally the entire world is at war with me.
Scott: good job.
Rym: and yet despite that the only consequence is I lost my worst city.
Rym: I'm still actually doing fine.
Rym: do better at the game people in the patreon game I feel like I'm running away with it.
Scott: I know no one can stop.
Scott: sure the other people are just not that good.
Rym: so one person who I know is good just got F'd because basically Egypt was like on this continent like in a line to the south of them was me and Persia and I just rolled Persia.
Rym: so I'm up on Egypt's border and Poland rolled someone.
Rym: so Poland and me are these two massive land like war empires and Egypt.
Rym: was this lost strip of culture between the two of us?
Scott: you know well Black Friday I think would be a fun game to play online.
Scott: if it's an online version I could just play.
Scott: you know you could play one in like an hour or whatever.
Scott: if a computer did it for you it would be so fast.
Rym: but I feel like playing it physically with people is the only way.
Rym: this game right.
Scott: but what I'm saying is that and I would really like it even more if someone made a somewhat similar stock market game where there's like a fake market and stocks go up and down.
Scott: yeah except it's more real-time if it's digital right.
Rym: so you're more mule trading right.
Scott: you basically pretend like there's a fake stock market and everyone the gate.
Scott: the day you got it you've got dials know your socks buy or sell and there's like anyway bye bye bye bye and basically the stocks are moving in real time and you're basically simulating like a day of day trading or something.
Scott: yeah obviously it only takes an hour that the clock is sped up and then you play.
Rym: as long as that feedback loop is this game I can't stress enough.
Rym: I'm not even gonna try to explain the details of the feedback loop of how stock prices get determined in this game.
Rym: you just got to read the rules.
Scott: cubes move around a grid based on how many cubes come out of a bag minus how many black suitcases come out of a bag.
Rym: but it is a fascinating mechanism.
Rym: if I ever get the chance to interview Friedman freeze the first question I'm gonna ask how did you come up with this?
Rym: yeah how did you play test and design this specific mechanism in Schwartz sir free tags?
Scott: I made a lot of games so I'm good at genius game maker.
Scott: so yeah I don't know if this game is for everybody but if you like stocks and you like you're okay playing games that are a little bit hard to understand.
Scott: well I'd say and you got you like to play for an hour with you know four or five six is it?
Scott: go to six people and check.
Rym: actually if you're the kind of person then you know but I don't know how you gonna find it.
Rym: if you're the kind of person who shows up at the friends houses with the games or you're the one who like runs games for people.
Rym: this is a must-buy because you'll know the rules you can do the annoying part and people will really have fun with this game like people who play board games.
Scott: I feel like yeah but I think that this might not be a fun game for people who chafe at things that are complicated.
Rym: again I might buy it cuz I fit to define I how do you gonna find a cop?
Rym: uh I bet I can find a copy all right.
Rym: well uh Amazon right now $54.
Rym: that's not the worst it's not great.
Rym: I mean I paid for like 80 for la cheetah and I've played that three times in my life.
Scott: okay well whatever I'm hungry yeah but this is a good game.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce hike McNichol Amanda Duchette roundabout that mp3.
Rym: my steady calm.
Rym: Jeremy minor genuine modified electrified six car monorail.
Rym: Matthew Smith Nicholas brand out captain Chinguac as he Rebecca done for to win creations.
Rym: even if we were to pull out today and if they would come take our base.
Rym: Sherman Van Harle rare Laval James David white Rochelle Monta Nona superboy Rym says something funny here.
Rym: sailor Vista Don Schleich jar tavish and Joe Shiro Joe star Shawn Yeager Sam Corddry Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian Cedroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and now I leave you with.