Rym: It's Wednesday, December 13th, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, the thing that you call Voltron, go lyin'.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I cooked something I've never cooked before, and it was, it was a situation.
Scott: Bugs?
Rym: Jellyfish?
Rym: When I encountered, when I actually acquired the ingredient and held it in my hands I went online to ask the question of, "How do I tell if this thing is
Rym: rotten?".
Rym: Yup.
Rym: As in, "Is this what this should look, feel, and smell
Rym: like?".
Scott: Daikon?
Rym: No, no, no, no, no.
Rym: This was black garlic.
Scott: Oh, I've had black garlic before.
Rym: Yeah, I'd had black garlic, but I never encountered it in its raw form before.
Scott: Oh, I've had it.
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: I've cooked with it.
Rym: Do you know what it is?
Rym: Like what the deal is with it?
Scott: It's just like a different garlic species that's infused with something or something like that.
Rym: Nope, nope, nope.
Rym: No, nothing.
Rym: Not at all.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Black garlic is- I looked it up and then I forgot.
Rym: It's regular old garlic that's basically put in a special hot room for months.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: And it sits there slowly turning black and gooey.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And it basically breaks down a lot of the garlicky stuff in it, and it makes it much more, like it makes it actually a very different flavor.
Rym: So I made some ramen with it, and it was A plus.
Rym: Yeah, why not?
Rym: And now I'm gonna start cooking with black garlic a little more often.
Rym: You gotta get grandpa garlic.
Rym: So you can make it yourself- In a hot room?
Rym: Yeah, so apparently what a lot of people do is they take, if they buy a new rice cooker, like a Japanese one, because this apparently is very popular in Japan, they'll take the old rice cooker, set it on the warming setting, like they'd cooked some rice, and just put a bunch of garlic in it and let it sit for a few months.
Rym: It's possible.
Rym: it'll just rot depending on if you get the temperature right and all that.
Scott: You don't say.
Rym: But yeah, black garlic pretty good.
Scott: And that ramen I made was pretty good.
Rym: So yeah, that's the most exciting thing that happened to me in the last few days.
Scott: Okay, what exciting happened to me?
Rym: Got anything for an opening bit?
Scott: My back hurts, which has never hurt in my whole life.
Scott: You know, so many people in the world have back pain so much that, you know, I think back pain is like the biggest scam in the world of like people promising to help you with it.
Rym: Well, because a lot of back pain, there's literally nothing that can be done.
Rym: And when a doctor tells you that, some people say, "Oh shit,".
Rym: and some people say, "I'm gonna go to an increasingly crazy series of doctors until one of them says
Rym: something.".
Scott: And then even though they can't actually help you.
Scott: But anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Don't go to chiropractors.
Rym: They're faking literally every case.
Rym: Just in case you don't know that.
Scott: Anyway, so this morning I'm just getting ready to go to work, you know, and I think I was like picking up my keys.
Scott: Who knows what I forget?
Scott: But like basically my left side moved in a weird way and I felt something go doink.
Scott: And I was like, it felt like did a bone pop out or like a muscle flipped over?
Rym: Welcome to.
Rym: I am older than 30 because I feel like when you're under 30, if your back hurts, it's always because like you took an injury and you can say, "Well, when I fell off that mountain, that's why my back hurts
Rym: today.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, so something in my back left middle area went doink and it's been slightly annoying all day.
Rym: I suspect what'll happen is when you go to bed, because I'm a little older than you.
Rym: Old old man, I'm gonna give you some advice.
Rym: I suspect it's gonna feel worse in the morning and not better.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Because it sounds like you have the same thing that Pete was talking about in the forum.
Rym: So yeah, good luck with that.
Rym: I've been there.
Rym: The last time it happened to me, I was laying in bed and I tried to get up in the morning and I can't sit straight up.
Rym: I just can't.
Scott: I mean, I can't sit straight up anyway.
Rym: So I like roll out.
Scott: I can't basically do a forward sit up.
Rym: So I roll on my side, I kind of push myself up and my back's just like, "Yeah, fuck you
Rym: today.".
Rym: And then after a week, I just went away and the doctor was like, "Yeah, that happens.
Rym: You're over
Rym: 30.".
Scott: Well, if it lasts long enough, I'll go to a doctor, but no.
Rym: You know what the doctor said the last time I went to him about a back thing?
Rym: He literally said, and I'm quoting here, "If that keeps happening for a few months, come back
Rym: in.".
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: So we should talk about comics more.
Scott: I'm reading comics more because I'm trying to clear out my comic shelf.
Rym: I'm reading comics less because I'm watching a lot more anime and TV.
Scott: I'm trying to get, well, great.
Scott: So erudite.
Scott: Because my shelf is starting to lean over a little bit.
Scott: So I'm trying to read comics.
Rym: I don't want to go over and find you dead under a pile of comics.
Rym: It's possible.
Scott: Anyway, I'm trying to read the comics.
Scott: And if anyone doesn't know, there's a guy named Ed Piskor.
Scott: I don't know how to say his name.
Scott: It might just be Piskor.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's spelled P-I-S-K-O-R.
Scott: And he basically went to the Kubert comic school and he partnered up with CZ.
Scott: He's done some work with some pretty famous people.
Scott: And the main comic I know him for is Hip Hop Family Tree, which is this really awesome comic if you've never seen it.
Scott: It basically talks about the history of hip hop until it's like, and the art style is just phenomenal.
Scott: So he is now making a comic.
Scott: I couldn't believe that they got him to make this comic.
Scott: It's called X-Men Grand Design, right?
Scott: And basically for a Marvel comics, it's incredibly strange for one person to write it, draw it, penciling, coloring.
Scott: He's doing the whole thing because that's what he does.
Scott: Usually get a whole team of people.
Scott: He's doing everything.
Scott: And it's basically he's going to retell the real X-Men story, the whole thing, right?
Scott: With no info, you know, it's not going to tie into anything.
Scott: It's just going to be like, oh, tired of reading all these convoluted X-Men comics.
Scott: You know, you just want to read the real X-Men story.
Scott: Here it is all in this one self-contained graphic novel.
Scott: Wait for the trade situation.
Scott: But the first issue comes out or just came out soon.
Rym: I can read that.
Rym: I could feel I feel like I could enjoy this.
Scott: It's the thing is like.
Scott: I like X-Men so much like the two comics I bought when I was a kid in the 90s buying comics.
Scott: I bought Spider-Man 2099 because it was cyberpunk.
Scott: It was Spider-Man, the Spider-Man 2099 asshole.
Scott: And it started at number one so I could start and get the whole thing.
Scott: And the other comic I bought was X-Men because I'd started at number one and I was watching X-Men on Fox.
Scott: And that comic, it didn't.
Scott: it wasn't a comic that was like one of those ones that's just retelling the exact episodes in comic form.
Scott: But, you know, it was the same characters who look the same, you know.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty bad.
Rym: My continuity was the same.
Rym: It was always, I've tried to find the comics that look the same as the Fox cartoon and that's how I got into X-Men.
Scott: It was it was it was adjectivilist.
Scott: X-Men is what it's known as.
Scott: The one where, you know, Jim Lee did the cover for number one or whatever that folded out, right?
Scott: That one.
Scott: So those are the two comics I read as a kid and I really like X-Men.
Scott: I like the X-Men characters.
Scott: I like the fundamental X-Men story, which I guess we talked about in our last book club a bit.
Scott: But it's really hard to read any X-Men now because it's fucked the fuck up.
Rym: I mean, what I like to say is that I love everything about the X-Men except reading the comics.
Scott: Yeah, so getting Ed Piskor's style going on plus just, you know, retelling the real X-Men story is an excellent day.
Scott: I'll be buying this trade for sure.
Rym: Yeah, so a quick big geek bite because Emily and I had a bunch of friends actually went to see Coco in the theater.
Rym: It's actually still in the theaters right now, the new Pixar movie.
Scott: It'll be there a while.
Scott: Right, till the holiday season's over.
Rym: It's real good.
Scott: I mean, has there been a Pixar movie where people said it's real bad?
Rym: Yeah, I guess I feel like it's in my top two.
Rym: Like, it was real good.
Scott: Isn't like anything they make just soon to be real good?
Rym: It's pretty much all about skeletons.
Rym: It's got these skeletons.
Rym: It is up Rym's Alley in a lot of ways.
Rym: I don't really want to spoil anything about it.
Rym: I feel like you could go in to see it.
Scott: It's a spoil about a kid's movie.
Scott: But what's interesting about it... There's a happy ending.
Rym: Well...
Scott: The main characters are kids.
Rym: Well, so what it's really about is when your parents die and relatives die, how you deal with that.
Rym: And it doesn't pull any punches and the heel turn that I expected because it was a Pixar movie and they telegraphed it.
Rym: the whole time was way darker and more fucked up.
Rym: It went into a lot of dark places, way beyond what I expected.
Rym: And also the music is fantastic.
Scott: I mean, it's a Disney musical.
Rym: Yeah, but the music goes beyond that.
Scott: Even crappy Disney movies, right?
Scott: Like ones that are not remembered or not cared about very much.
Rym: But even Pocahontas has fantastic music.
Scott: That are musicals.
Scott: Like Pocahontas, which is a really crappy movie.
Rym: But this one's different in that the plot is about a musician and most of the music is him performing or other people performing in the context of the actual story.
Scott: Yeah, there's plenty of those.
Rym: It's just, it's fantastic.
Rym: And if you haven't seen it in the theater, I highly recommend you go see it in the theater.
Rym: It is beautiful.
Rym: The skeletons are done better than any non-Sharezone skeleton I've ever seen.
Scott: I mean, I don't disagree, but I feel like saying all that is sort of unnecessary because all you have to say is like, "Oh, Pixar has a new
Scott: movie.".
Scott: It's like, "Oh, all those things you just said are just obvious.
Scott: You don't need to have someone tell them to
Scott: you.".
Rym: See, you say that, but I feel like it's a cut above most Pixar movies.
Scott: I mean...
Rym: I really think it is.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And you'll have to see it to see.
Rym: I guess Emil and I will review it in depth on Patreon because you haven't seen it yet.
Scott: And then I'll probably see it when I see every other Pixar movie, which is like five to ten years after they come out.
Rym: I'm sure you can just find it on the high seas.
Scott: I mean, what's the hurry?
Scott: It's like, it's not going anywhere.
Scott: It's going to be easily obtainable for decades.
Rym: It looks pretty good in the theater.
Rym: What was interesting though, late Friday night showing still had mostly kids in the audience.
Scott: I go to the theater for things that won't be easily obtained.
Rym: Like Hateful Eight?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I'm sure you can buy that on DVD now.
Rym: Yeah, but you can't see it.
Scott: Not in 70 millimeters.
Rym: No one has a TV that's going to show that properly.
Scott: Someone does.
Rym: You're going to have this one long thin line on the middle of your monitor.
Scott: I've seen some million dollar TVs, but yeah.
Rym: I mean, I guess you could watch it on one of those like double wide silly gaming monitors, like the curved ones.
Rym: That's wide enough at least.
Rym: Wouldn't be high enough res.
Rym: That's just 1080p.
Scott: Those are just two 1080p monitors stuck to each other on the side.
Rym: But at least they're wide enough.
Rym: I mean, if I looked at it on my screen, there'd be like two inches in the middle.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, as you know, I do this perennial panel at anime conventions mostly called foreign anime openers.
Rym: Or like anime openers around the world.
Rym: I change it up and I just have this rotating library of anime openers translated into languages other than Japanese and English.
Scott: Which is originally, it was originally my deal.
Rym: But you never actually made it.
Rym: Like I made the panel.
Scott: I mean, I was like, oh, I discovered that it was a thing.
Scott: And I think I made a blog post that had like a ton of them in it.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: You know what.
Rym: you have a pain in the ass it was to turn that into a legit panel and like research all this shit.
Rym: And like figure, because half the foreign anime openers you find on YouTube are actually fakes or they're made by fans.
Rym: And you really got to like figure this stuff out.
Rym: So anyway, I just found the mother load.
Rym: And part of the problem is I don't speak most of these languages.
Rym: Meaning, I don't speak any of these languages.
Scott: You speak one language.
Rym: I can look up the name of a show in another language and like do some copy paste.
Rym: But I might copy paste the wrong thing.
Rym: It's tough.
Rym: So I just now was looking for a thing of the day because I wanted to see if I could find a quick copy of one of the Ranma Christmas specials.
Rym: That's a good Wednesday thing of the day.
Rym: And I ended up finding, purely even a recommended video, the Arabic opener to Ranma.
Scott: We should have done all holiday things of the day to match up with our all Halloween related activities.
Rym: That's a really good idea and I feel dumb that we didn't do that.
Rym: I'm going to do that for the rest of the month.
Rym: That's easy enough.
Rym: So I found the opener to Ranma 1/2.
Rym: The "Ya Pa Pa Ya Pa Pa" but in Arabic.
Rym: And because of all the stupid research I did for that panel, I know this is legit because it's from SpaceToon as the SpaceToon logo.
Rym: SpaceToon is the Arabic anime channel based out of Dubai.
Rym: And also I just learned a little while ago Damascus.
Scott: What's going on in Damascus?
Rym: I literally don't... I'm not even sure what's going on in Yemen or Qatar at this point.
Scott: Well that's a little different situation.
Rym: But a lot of these places I don't really understand what's going on despite reading the news.
Rym: But I digress.
Scott: Because there's not a lot of journalists going there.
Rym: So anyway, this video is legit.
Rym: It's got the SpaceToon logo and then I noticed that it's on the SpaceToon channel.
Rym: And it turns out I never thought to look for the SpaceToon channel in Arabic because there's this SpaceToon channel on YouTube.
Rym: And it's just all... I think it's every Arabic anime opener there is.
Rym: It's just here.
Rym: It's an official video in high quality.
Rym: Good times are coming because I'm doing this panel at MagFest in the morning.
Scott: That's only one language though even though it's many animes.
Rym: Yeah but you know what?
Rym: I feel like Arabic language anime is underrepresented among a lot of people who don't think that people in Arabic speaking countries like anime.
Rym: And also...
Scott: I know they like anime.
Rym: They love Kpop too.
Rym: We do.
Rym: Imagine a captain white boy internet user who shows up to a random panel at like 8am at MagFest.
Rym: Because actually an attendee at MagFest probably knows this stuff.
Rym: But anyway, this is pretty great and that's my thing of the day.
Rym: You can go peruse this channel and already I found some gold in there.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Thing of the day, right.
Scott: What was it?
Scott: It was...
Rym: It was something related to the Itano Circus.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Basically this video is not great.
Scott: This is not a great thing of the day.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: I thought Scott always had the great things of the day.
Scott: Not always.
Scott: Just most of the time.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: I mean even Tom Brady lost.
Scott: He got his ass kicked by the dolphins.
Scott: So basically if you don't know what the Itano Circus is when you're watching anime and there's missiles going all over the place.
Scott: Like whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's called an Itano Circus because this guy Ichiro Itano invented it.
Scott: And here's a very short video that shows you many of these which are very enjoyable to watch.
Scott: And also discusses them and their history briefly.
Scott: It's only like three minutes long.
Scott: But, you know, I think it's it's something that like comes up every once in a while and it seems like people who really know about anime just like for them.
Scott: This is like common knowledge.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not even a thing that like needs to be explained for like anime nerds.
Scott: But for other people, it's like this revelation like, oh, that's a thing.
Scott: Oh, what did you know?
Scott: And so this is a useful video.
Scott: Maybe you being an anime nerd who watches GeekNights don't need this video.
Scott: But if you pass this video around to people who are only like barely into anime or like watch anime but don't care about it.
Rym: Or like if you're trying to get a free badge to one of those small anime cons that we don't really go to.
Rym: Just watch this video and then turn it into a panel about Itano Circus and you could probably get a free badge.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, it's.
Scott: it's the kind of thing that they will very much enjoy.
Scott: And the video is pretty well made by whoever made it.
Scott: What's the?
Scott: what's the channel?
Rym: Oda Quest.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Good job Oda Quest.
Rym: It only has like 800 views.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You're good at making videos, Oda Quest.
Rym: Oh, I'll subscribe to you.
Rym: You got like you got like no subscribers.
Rym: I'll throw some love.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, you know, love to Oda Quest.
Scott: Of course, I don't know anything else about that.
Scott: Watch.
Scott: Maybe I'll retract that.
Rym: For all you know, it's a milkshake, doc.
Rym: I'll click on this channel right now.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I might have to detract my.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Interview with Kung Gao, co-founder of Crunchyroll.
Rym: They're doing some stuff here.
Rym: Looks like it's pretty new.
Rym: There's only a few videos.
Scott: All right.
Scott: OK.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: Let's see how this goes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In a moment, the book club book is the new translation of the Odyssey.
Scott: I just want to talk about something for a second.
Scott: So I was thinking, hey, maybe to make the book club episode actually good.
Scott: I'll put in some effort and I'll I'll read some other Odyssey translation.
Rym: I have read other Odyssey translation, but not recently.
Rym: I'm not going to read one of those again.
Scott: I thought.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I go looking on here on Amazon.
Rym: Which ones are on Amazon?
Scott: So there is one that's the Emily Wilson one.
Scott: is the one that we're doing, correct?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: New one.
Scott: There's a signet classic one that looks like, you know, a legit one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Oh, because I'm searching on my tablet, I don't get the kindle one.
Scott: Do you have the scroll down a little bit?
Scott: This Mario.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What's the title of that one?
Scott: This one?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The one with the blue generic Kindle.
Rym: The Odyssey rendered into English prose for use of those who cannot read the original.
Scott: That's a free Kindle edition.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Scroll down, though.
Scott: There's another free Kindle edition that's just called the Odyssey.
Rym: Here's one.
Rym: The idiot, the the Iliad and the Odyssey altogether by Homer.
Rym: I don't know who translated it.
Scott: It's like some of these are zero dollars Kindle editions.
Scott: And I don't know how those translations even compared to like the signet classic one.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I honestly don't know.
Rym: I do not know which translations I've read.
Rym: All I know is I've read two different translations and all I could say about them in high school is that I read to whatever one I read when I was young and pop up.
Rym: one of them was pleasant to read and made sense and one of them felt like shoving nails into my eyes.
Scott: But anyway, we're reading this one, which is the Emily.
Rym: The Emily Wilson.
Rym: Emily Wilson.
Scott: That's the one.
Rym: Pretty much.
Scott: If you search for a translation of the Odyssey, because this is new and if you search for Odyssey on Amazon, the number one result is this book and the number two result is Mario Odyssey.
Rym: The interesting things are that it's a modern translation that uses colloquial language where possible while maintaining the artistry of the original to make it more accessible and relatable, which I'm always a fan of.
Rym: It also too, it's the first major translation done by a woman and that perspective is very interesting and very elucidating apparently.
Rym: I haven't read it yet.
Rym: as to the things that are in the Odyssey that all the men who have translated over the years didn't really seem to think much about.
Rym: This translator said, "Hey, what about all those slaves that got fucking murdered at the
Rym: end?".
Scott: Yeah, I still feel like I need to read a man translation and then read this translation to be able to compare and contrast in the book club episode.
Rym: Let's pick one.
Scott: With a fresh memory, not a... Because my memory of the Odyssey is basically like, "Okay, he leaves.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: Is this Cyclops
Scott: first?".
Scott: Leaves where?
Rym: Where is he, Scott?
Rym: Where does he start?
Scott: I'm just going to name Greek cities until I get it right.
Rym: Well, yeah, the Trojan War, but that's not where... Where is he when the Odyssey begins?
Rym: He's on an island having sex with a hot goddess, not a goddess, but a witch basically.
Scott: Is it Cyprus?
Rym: Circe is the person.
Scott: Circe is the witch?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: I know the basics of the story.
Rym: Let's each... I don't know the... Let's pick some other one of these translations, the stodgy one.
Scott: I'm just going to... One of the zero dollar ones.
Rym: Let's each just pick one section to read the original, maybe the Cyclops part.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Scott: The lazy, but also kind of okay way.
Rym: I feel like we should do... The part we should read together from the old one, just to compare, should probably be the part near the end where he comes back and he hides himself, and then they murder all the servants, and they get rid of all the suitors and all that stuff, because that's near the end.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Scott: Choosing a few parts.
Scott: Maybe let's do... Maybe we should do... Here is a balance between the two.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The first chapter.
Scott: The last chapter.
Rym: And the Cyclops.
Scott: And pick Cyclops, Sirens, Poseidon.
Scott: Pick one of them.
Rym: All right.
Rym: We'll pick one.
Scott: Pick one of the monster encounters.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's basically just a series of D&D encounters.
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Those are just the big ones.
Rym: Oh, this beautiful goddess-like woman.
Rym: I'm having sex with her.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Time to go home.
Rym: And that actually happens twice.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: This should be really interesting, because I've been meaning to re-read the Odyssey for We're not going to read any Iliads, though?
Rym: I've never actually read the Iliad.
Scott: Full disclosure.
Scott: Isn't there also the Aeneid or whatever?
Rym: The Aeneid?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I've read all of the... What's his name?
Rym: I've read Antigone and Oedipus and all those.
Rym: Multiple translations.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Have not.
Rym: Antigone is pretty good.
Rym: Oedipus is pretty good, too.
Scott: Which one has stories about my man Agamemnon in it?
Rym: Agamemnon.
Rym: That's the Iliad.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, I guess I'll be checking that out.
Scott: Agamemnon!
Scott: Agamemnon.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I got feelings on Agamemnon.
Scott: He's badass.
Scott: That's all I got to know.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rym: It is issues, though.
Scott: I mean, so does Kenshiro.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Otherwise, we're going to be hanging around New York until the end of the year, and then real quick, next year, we're going to be at PAX South.
Rym: We're going to be doing a panel on Friday, January 12th at PAX South at 4 p.m.
Rym: on the Bobcat Theater, Balance in Game Design.
Rym: GaoGao.
Rym: We're also going to be there.
Scott: That's a bobcat.
Rym: That's not.
Rym: Bobcats don't say that.
Scott: What do they say?
Rym: Only bears say that.
Scott: What do bobcats say?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: All growling animals say GaoGao.
Scott: A lion says GaoGao.
Scott: A tiger says GaoGao.
Rym: I feel like after Yurikuma, GaoGao is exclusively the domain of bears.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: Otherwise, just playing games, hanging around.
Rym: We'll also be at Magfest doing a bunch of panels, including a bunch of new panels.
Rym: It's going to be exciting times.
Scott: I'm also going to be doing a secret impromptu panel, How to Dig Dug.
Scott: You have to be at the Dig Dug when I'm there and you'll get it.
Scott: It'll take two minutes.
Rym: Ooh, a Dig Dug impromptu.
Rym: That'll be interesting.
Scott: How to Dig Dug.
Scott: If anyone catches me at a Dig Dug machine and says, "Scott, I want to know how to Dig Dug," I will tell you how to Dig Dug.
Rym: So also, if, Scott, since you're joining Netflix and drop in the- I already signed up for my Netflix.
Rym: I think you'll actually like Stranger Things, but season two, if you decide to watch the second season, Dig Dug features prominently on both-.
Scott: I did see a screenshot on the web of someone playing a Dig Dug.
Scott: That was definitely from that show.
Rym: The arcade game itself features prominently in the plot.
Rym: The arcade game itself features prominently in allegory to the-.
Scott: So Pookas and Fygar's come out of the kid's closet or something and burn them in his sleep?
Rym: Let's just say that it also applies allegorically to things that happened in the show.
Rym: And then it applies literally to a thing that happens in the show.
Scott: Someone has to dig and inflate- someone inflates someone until they explode?
Rym: So the only thing that does not happen is the inflating.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: But- Do they get burned by the Fygar?
Rym: Well, watch your show.
Scott: Do they eat an eggplant?
Scott: There is- That they found underground randomly?
Scott: There- Shady, shady vegetables?
Rym: You'll see.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: If you like season one, which I actually do think you will, I think you're gonna- it's not a Ready Player One situation like you're worried about.
Scott: I'm just saying, 'cause like, you know, I'm not saying it is a Ready Player One situation.
Rym: I just believe you.
Scott: No, but if you talk to some- if you talk to some fan of it- If you look at the promotional media, or if you look- if you just look at like Twitter comments and just get a- try to get an idea- Remember ET?
Scott: If you try to get an idea of the show based on screenshots and these sorts of, you know, just the ephemera that is about in the nerdosphere- Yup.
Scott: It feels like it's a Ready Player One.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But whereas Stranger Things uses a scalpel and the tools of an artisan, Ready Player One is- I was gonna say something really mean about Ready Player One.
Scott: The fist of a ham?
Rym: That's giving it too much justice, because that- that's too close to steamed hams, which are good.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: You're gonna need a lot of time.
Rym: Save plenty a lot of time to talk about.
Rym: Go, lion.
Scott: All right, so here's the deal, right?
Scott: So, when I was a kid, Voltron was hot shit, but as a kid, you know, I watched it and my friend had the real Voltron toy, the whole thing, and everyone was jealous, and he still has it, even though he's, like, two years older than me and, like, a fancy lawyer.
Rym: So I never watched Voltron as someone who has adult or even teenager perspective.
Scott: See, as a kid, all I remembered from Voltron was, like, "Oh, there's five colors of
Scott: lions.".
Scott: I knew that.
Scott: They combined.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: The five characters.
Scott: Here's what they look like.
Rym: I knew the combined one had a sword.
Scott: They're in a castle.
Scott: It has a sword.
Scott: It fights monsters.
Scott: I only remember, like, the vague imagery of Voltron.
Scott: I didn't remember any details.
Scott: But then, in high school, Voltron was on Toonami, so I would get home, right, when they finally added Cartoon Network to our cable subscription, it was still on Toonami, and that was the first show.
Scott: Get home immediately, Voltron.
Scott: It's like, "Yes, finally,
Scott: Voltron.".
Scott: This is before.
Scott: you could just download stuff from the internet.
Scott: There was no way.
Scott: It was not no DVDs.
Scott: There was literally no way for me to re-experience Voltron after my childhood until it was on Toonami, right?
Scott: And I watched it again, and then I was able to remember more details of Voltron, and then sometime during RIT, I think they put out a DVD box set, and I bought only the first season in, like, a tin- I remember that.
Scott: In a tin thing, and I was able to watch the first season of Voltron, but this was all the US Voltron, which I knew was edited, to some extent, from two different anime, right?
Scott: There was an anime called Go Lion, which was the lion Voltron, the Voltron that we give a shit about.
Rym: Well, Beast King Go Lion.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then there was some other anime- Die Ruger.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: -that involved, like, a 30-something vehicles that combined or some shit, and I never even s- people in- like, I didn't find out till internet days that there even was a vehicle Voltron because that was never on TV where I lived anywhere, so for me, Voltron was only lion Voltron.
Rym: I have the even weirder experience of I know I must have, in my pre-sentient days, watched Voltron because I had some Voltron toys, and I had a Voltron board game that we played all the time.
Scott: I had a Voltron Halloween costume, the crappy kind with the plastic mask and the plastic s- sack you shoved over yourself.
Rym: So the Voltron board game that I had, which I still have, my mom has it, actually, it- Is it just roll- roll your dice and move your dice?
Scott: No?
Rym: So I think, based on how I- this is it, based on my memories, remember that, uh, Canisia Lord of the Rings game?
Scott: Like, I've seen the box for this game, but I've never seen the inside of it.
Rym: So remember the Canisia Lord of the Rings game, where, like- The co-op game that's, uh, yeah.
Rym: Where your guys are moving forward on the corruption track, but Sauron's also moving closer together, and if you touch, you lose?
Scott: That's the only good part of the game.
Rym: I'm pretty sure the Voltron game has that same mechanic and is actually co-op.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: So- I have no idea how the game works.
Rym: But I don't remember, because as a kid, this was before I was sentient, so I would play this game without actually knowing how it worked.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But the fact that I had the game and the toys implies that I watched the show Voltron, and I remember all these oddly specific details, but I don't remember the game.
Scott: So anyway, Voltron is a big deal.
Scott: I think it's a new Voltron show.
Scott: that's all the rage these days.
Rym: It's apparently great.
Rym: It's done by, I guess, a lot of the same people who did Avatar, the last Airbender, which is also great.
Scott: Where can you watch it?
Scott: Uh, I don't know.
Scott: Alright, anyway.
Rym: We should probably watch it, though.
Scott: There's also some other remakes of Voltron.
Scott: There's also a bunch of Voltron comics, like when I was in the RIT days, I was buying Voltron comics that were actually quite good, but there have been bad and good ones over the years.
Rym: Regardless- But we're not talking about any of that!
Scott: In the US, we had this edited line Voltron, this edited vehicle Voltron that were somehow combined into two shows that were played back-to-back, and I guess were both called Voltron, but the actual show is called Go Lion, so a few weeks ago- Beast King Go Lion!
Scott: I was on Crunchyroll, and I was trying to watch the march comes in like a lion, Gatsu No Lion, whatever, about the show- Oh, yeah, yeah.
Scott: The depressed kid who plays Shogi.
Rym: I want to watch that.
Scott: Uh, I watched like one or two episodes.
Scott: It was, you know, it was worth at least searching for again, and when I searched, I just typed "lion" into Crunchyroll.
Scott: It was like, "lion, press enter," and all that show didn't appear.
Scott: The only show that appeared was Go Lion, and I'm like, "Oh, that's on
Scott: Crunchyroll!".
Scott: So I watched that instead.
Rym: So all Scott said to me was, "Hey, you should watch Go Lion.
Rym: We'll do a show on
Rym: it.".
Rym: Right.
Scott: "Hey, you should watch the Go Lion.
Scott: We'll do a show on it.
Scott: Won't that be a good show?
Scott: Talk about the actual Japanese Go Lion, you know, and not the
Scott: Voltron.".
Rym: So my very initial impressions from the first few minutes are, one, I definitely as a kid did not at any point remember Voltron involving the horrific mutilation of slaves by monsters.
Scott: Yeah, so I knew the show had been edited because there's a character who dies.
Scott: I never actually saw that character until high school.
Rym: So I remember this weird thing as a kid where there was a rumor that a character died, and like no one- Because when you're watching shows in syndication on TV, they don't play them in order or anything like that, right?
Rym: So the only episodes of Voltron- But the one weird kid who was always like, "Yeah, the guy died and they covered it
Rym: up.".
Rym: The only episode- He must have known something about it.
Scott: The only episode of Voltrons I saw when I was a kid didn't have Sven in them.
Scott: He was called Sven in the U.S.
Scott: version.
Scott: He was called Quiet in this version.
Rym: Well, Quiet's his nickname.
Rym: It was Takashi Shurigane.
Scott: Sure, whatever.
Scott: But anyway, he had a stereotyped Swedish accent, like the Swedish chef in the U.S.
Scott: one.
Scott: And basically, you could tell if you had any amount of intelligence.
Scott: When I watched it in high school on Toonami, I could tell, "Hey, that character totally died in the original Japanese and they hid it by
Scott: editing.".
Scott: So I knew that it was edited that much, but now watching the actual Go line with subtitles, you have no idea.
Scott: This show was edited extremely heavily.
Rym: If I had to say the- Extremely.
Rym: In terms of what the editing is or what- It wasn't just erasing one character's death.
Rym: It felt a lot like when I started watching Fist of the North Star, when I started watching this.
Scott: Yes, this Go line is way closer to Fist of the North Star than it is to... It's not as Fist of the North Star, but it's definitely got tons and tons of violence and horror that is not present at all in the U.S.
Rym: Voltron.
Rym: I want to try to summarize the plot together up until they have the real castle and they make Voltron.
Scott: Right, right, right.
Rym: Because it's just serial.
Rym: Like, every episode just continues from the last one.
Rym: Oh,
Scott: and eventually, once the setup is done, it becomes Monster of the Week, but there is a little bit of serialness even in the Monster of the Week episodes where things that, basically, the status quo will sometimes change ever so slightly in an episode and then they carry it going forward.
Scott: So, even though it's Monster of the Week, eventually, the first five, six, seven episodes are really building up the world.
Rym: If you watch the first six episodes, it's basically a movie.
Scott: I haven't watched to the end, but I think there is an end at the ending.
Scott: You might be able to, if you figure it out, skip over a lot of the Monsters of the Week.
Rym: Oh, the other big thing that's different is that Voltron starts on that planet, but here, Go line starts on Earth.
Rym: And Earth is gone.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, basically, the show starts with a slave ship filled with these, like, weird leather-looking dudes whipping the shit out of a whole bunch of slaves, and then the slave ship lands at a slave planet where the slaves are forced to fight to the death against these death black guardians.
Scott: So, the death black guardians are awesome because, like, where the hell did these come from?
Rym: These are, like, the monsters that the Incorai make in The Prince of Nothing.
Rym: And if you say Rym, that's not, like, that sounds weird.
Rym: That is the closest thing I can think of.
Rym: They are made with occult fire.
Scott: The death black beasts are made with a combination of, they take the slaves who were victorious in combat, plus evil magic, plus feeding them the dead other slaves, and they combine those things to create horrific monsters that then fight slaves and become even more powerful combat beasts.
Rym: It's way worse than the prison planet in Dune.
Scott: This isn't alluded to in Go Lion.
Scott: This is straight up said.
Scott: That's exactly how they're made.
Rym: You watch a tournament where the king, the emperor, is like, "I need stronger death black guardians," and he has a tournament where they're all trying to behead as many people as possible as fast as possible.
Rym: And then, like, it's literally a witch uses occult magic that is called, like, occult death black guardian, even more crazy and fucked up, and then they put him in a coffin and shoot him at the planet.
Scott: The coffins are in the U.S.
Scott: one.
Rym: Yeah, but they shoot him at the planet like a gun, and he pops out to go kill people.
Scott: So, the one thing I got to say that's really great about this show is that the designs of the death black beasts, which are called robeasts in U.S.
Scott: Voltron, are all really unique and fantastic.
Scott: They're crazy.
Scott: Whoever designs the visuals of these monsters, like, even though it's monster of the week, every episode, you're getting a different and unique, incredible looking monster.
Rym: Like that second one, let's get a juggernaut looking guy with a weird, like, eye, like the one Cyclops guy in He-Man, give him some muscles, a spike coming out, guns coming out of his nipples.
Scott: Evangelion can only design so many unique looking angels, but even the fanciest angels don't compare to a robeast, a death black whatever.
Rym: And there's so many... A death black beast man.
Scott: There's so many death black beast men, because there's one.
Scott: every, almost every episode there's a new one.
Rym: But this construction of how they're made is just literally shown to you.
Rym: So, even better, along with all that, you get this sort of setup of Voltron, meaning, you know, go lion, was this entity, some robot someone made that I guess has its own AI.
Scott: We don't know if he was made, but he's presented as if he's a living being who happens to be in a robot shape that looks like it has five lion heads.
Rym: And who has existed forever, no one knows where he came from, and all he does is going around fighting people in space.
Rym: So I guess he shows up in a planet and just starts killing people.
Scott: In US Voltron, they called him defender of the universe, and I would argue, yo, you know, Voltron is way more powerful than like even Ava's or whatever.
Scott: He defends literally the whole universe, and really nothing can fuck with Voltron.
Scott: And go lion, right, is even more powerful.
Scott: Than US Voltron, who's actually the same robot.
Scott: Go lion kills and battles every being worth fighting in all of the universe.
Scott: Kind of like Bruton.
Scott: And then, yeah, challenges Pluto, whatever, challenges the goddess of space herself.
Rym: Who is basically a Sailor Moon goddess who was like, um, son.
Scott: Yeah, that's the only thing.
Scott: go lion can't mess with is the goddess of all space.
Rym: It's so great.
Rym: You get all these shots of him fucking up all these space monsters, and suddenly he goes to attack this goddess who's just like this beautiful woman surrounded by doves, and she's just like, nope, what's wrong with you?
Rym: What are you, I'm the goddess of space.
Rym: What are you doing?
Scott: So she punishes him by sending him down to a planet and separating him in five pieces or whatever.
Rym: And I guess, I don't know, I don't know if whatever animus, like what animated him is still in him or is gone, because now he's going to be piloted by people.
Rym: He's piloted by five humans after this.
Scott: Yeah, and no longer has his own will of, maybe he does, but it doesn't express itself.
Rym: So the other beginning is that our five main characters are researchers slash space pilots who are off doing something in space.
Scott: Yes, they're basically five bad, this is always in every telling of Voltron comics that, you know, whatever.
Scott: There's five badasses.
Scott: There's basically five incredible badasses.
Rym: And they are badasses.
Rym: They barely need the Voltron lions to fight.
Scott: Yes, they're basically these five badasses.
Rym: Like what, the one short kid basically fights off like the entire galactic army for a while, just with one pistol.
Rym: They're spacemen.
Scott: It's like Captain Harlock, right?
Scott: It's like his crew is all badasses.
Scott: So it's like five badasses in space, but they've been captured.
Rym: Well, let's back up.
Rym: They come back to Earth after a long mission in space and they find that Earth planet of the Aped and is gone.
Scott: Oh, right, right, right.
Rym: If thermonuclear itself, Earth is destroyed, everyone's dead, and they have this long moment of no YM play God.
Scott: Yeah, that wasn't in the US book.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You got these, all these shots of like children dying in nuclear holocaust, right?
Rym: And then this spaceship shows up on the horizon and it's this evil empire that didn't destroy Earth.
Rym: Earth destroyed itself.
Rym: This empire is like, hey, Earth got destroyed.
Rym: Let's go see if there's any slaves to steal.
Scott: We want those irradiated slaves.
Rym: But I just love this fact that the evil empire didn't even need to destroy Earth.
Rym: They ignored Earth and Earth destroyed itself.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So the dive Basel, who is the emperor?
Rym: I'm just called emperor.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean the emperor, but I think in the US one he was called King Zarkon, but in this one he's dive Bosel something I can't even pronounce.
Scott: So he just is the bad evil king and is the evil king and the evil witch.
Scott: And I remember there being the Prince Zarkon in the US one, but I don't think I got far enough.
Rym: I think he shows up later.
Scott: I didn't get far enough and go line to get to the Prince.
Rym: So his deal is that he is the most powerful being like this empire is basically conquering the entire universe bit by bit.
Rym: He's really a bad ass emperor of evil, but he's also really really stupid and really simplistic in the things he wants and that which is the only one who actually knows what's up.
Scott: I mean, he just wants to be more powerful.
Scott: He's not stupid.
Rym: I think he's just watch him.
Scott: He's not completely stupid.
Scott: He's just power hungry and simple.
Rym: He wants.
Rym: Yeah, he's simple.
Rym: He's not stupid.
Rym: He wants to expand his power and he's bored.
Rym: And whenever he's bored, he asks the witch and that guy that generally sends out to go get him more slaves to fight in the arena to make more death black beast.
Scott: There was one thing I noticed I got to talk about.
Scott: I brought this up to everyone already, but the listeners haven't heard it.
Scott: There's a scene where he's talking to the witch and he's casually has this giant drumstick that he's gnawing on.
Rym: Oh yeah, the drumstick.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He's got this giant drumstick.
Scott: he's just chomping on while he's talking to the witch and they don't say anything.
Rym: So it's not only gonna say is that scene reminds me of the non man that we meet in the later Prince of Nothing books with his oil.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, he's chopping on this drumstick as just like scenery.
Scott: Like at least it's like, Hey, at least they're animating something and not just having a still frame of him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Not, you know, good job.
Scott: You put in the effort to animate him eating this drumstick, but it's like, wait a minute.
Scott: You live on this horrible slave planet.
Scott: I've seen this slave planet.
Rym: There's nothing but slaves, a fucking wasteland.
Scott: And I already know you feed slaves to beast men.
Scott: And I haven't seen any other fucking livestock around here.
Scott: The emperor is eating slave meat.
Scott: There is no.
Rym: Oh, they don't say the slaves are eating slave meat.
Scott: And they do say that they don't say what the emperor is eating.
Scott: But one hundred percent, if you have any logic whatsoever, he's just eating slave meat.
Scott: So also they they draw.
Scott: It's not just human slaves.
Scott: They're all sorts of different alien species.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: A Star Wars number of different alien species.
Rym: This empire literally only seems to be eating wookie meat.
Rym: It only has two wings.
Rym: One wing is the empire's army going out and conquering more land.
Rym: And the other wing is this general going out to collect more and more slaves to fuel these dark purposes.
Rym: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: That's literally the full extent of what these people are up to.
Scott: And they eat the slaves, too.
Scott: So it's like this.
Scott: The people going to get slaves are literally farming.
Rym: It's Scott.
Rym: It's a hunger from the outside.
Rym: So where the show actually begins is that the slave ship lands after these slaves get whipped to the shed and then they take all the ones who are too whipped to continue and immediately grind them up into meat.
Rym: And all the ones who can continue are thrown into arena to fight one of these death black beast men.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: And they basically all get killed.
Rym: And then we come to that.
Scott: I mean, you're just you're sitting there with no weapons and there's a death like beast man.
Scott: Yeah, you are.
Scott: So I mean, Voltron, you need to Voltron to fight one of those.
Scott: And you're just a person.
Rym: Get fucked.
Rym: So then we cut to our five badasses and you learn from them because they're just in a prison cell that literally every slave who is in this planet still and alive fought and killed a death black beast man by themselves.
Rym: So we already know that these five badasses are the baddest ass badasses.
Rym: And they're in this cell and they accidentally look out a window and they discover that all the meat they've been eating is slave made and they're just like, let's fucking break out of here.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they actually have a really good logic, which I appreciate being in this show, which is, look, if we try to break out and get caught, what are they going to do?
Scott: Turn us into slave meat.
Scott: What else are we going to do?
Rym: Fight a death like beast man to get murdered by it and get turned into slave me or keep fighting death like beast man and not get eaten and probably eventually get turned into a death like beast man.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like there's no good option.
Scott: It's not like there's an incentive to not try to escape if you're going to be killed.
Scott: It's like if you're on death row, what are you going to do if they try to escape?
Scott: Shoot you.
Scott: You might as well try to escape.
Scott: And the only reason you don't do that in the real world is because this might be a legal way to escape.
Rym: If you get lawyers, they've already killed a death like beast man, as we know.
Rym: So they escape pretty trivially.
Scott: I mean, the prison is a lot is less strong than a death like beast man.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And they're stronger than one basic death like beast man.
Scott: So and it's funny because let's see how many times you can say death like this.
Rym: It gets said a lot in the show.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: OK.
Scott: I saw the Wikipedia quote for Goli and the point is they escape.
Scott: They seal a slave ship.
Scott: They run away.
Scott: And of course, by chance, they land on the planet of where Voltron is.
Scott: It seems like the name is a planet, Allura, Altaia, Altaia, Allura is the princess's name.
Rym: Allura is the name of the planet in Voltron.
Scott: Allura is the princess's name in Voltron and the name of the planet, I think.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: This planet, Altaia, whatever.
Scott: It's the Voltron plan.
Rym: So it's not clear from the first like six episodes whether or not Voltron called them to the planet, whether or not the princess and the badass mustache guy, the strategist called them to the planet, or if it was just dumb chance.
Rym: But it seems like a signal happened and they were drawn to the planet for the purpose of there's never been five badasses capable of piloting Voltron and mustache guy.
Scott: Yet somehow the long lost king of this planet, the princess's father, knew like who is piloting Voltron in his day.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: And how did he know about it?
Rym: And basically now we've got this planet that has all this ridiculous precursor technology, some of which was built by the people who were on the planet.
Scott: The king definitely made that castle.
Rym: But he didn't make Voltron.
Rym: So that's an inch that precursor, it's kind of like the same level of precursor tech as He-Man.
Scott: It's almost like it's all a little Metroid kind of.
Rym: Yeah, Metroid as well.
Rym: And one thing leads to another and they get Voltron going.
Rym: And this planet was destroyed by the empire.
Scott: Yeah, the empire basically destroyed this planet and then ignored it.
Scott: But there were people hiding out on it, including the princess, the guy who's in the castle with her.
Rym: And Voltron.
Scott: And Voltron and all these, you learn eventually that like a lot of the citizens were living in caves and hiding.
Scott: And then the empire left before it got them all.
Rym: There's this great moment where our five badasses, like they're fighting off empire troops just with pistols or sticks or whatever, and they're totally fine.
Rym: And then they start bitching like, yeah, all these survivors on this planet are like baby ass wimps.
Rym: And then the princess is like, you shut the fuck up.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You have no idea what they've been through.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But it is true that they are more badass than pretty much any other people on this planet, except mustache guy and the princess.
Scott: I mean, it kind of makes sense if you're Earth in that day and age where there's probably been who knows how much evolution, genetic engineering, technology, right?
Scott: And you're sending people into space to go far, you're sending badasses and they're going to be way badass, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They're badass in that Leiji Matsumoto way.
Scott: Imagine the Earth you live on, the real Earth, a thousand, two thousand years from now, assuming we have good things happening and scientific progress.
Scott: What kind of badass people we're going to send into space.
Scott: Come on.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So that's it on a high level.
Rym: That's the show.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Once they get Voltron going, which takes a while, it's pretty much the empire sending a death black beast to fight them every episode.
Scott: Then they use their powers to make the death black be super big and super strong so that you need giant Voltron to fight it, you know, because they start out normal, sort of slightly larger than human size.
Scott: At one point, as not a spoiler, the witch comes to the planet and totally murders the quiet Sven slash Sven guy.
Scott: And then the princess has to take his place.
Rym: The witch is clearly the driving force between the entire the whole empire and that cat.
Rym: You get so many shots that cat's eyes glowing.
Scott: Well, the cat is sort of the counterpart to the mice.
Rym: And the mice are like the good animals.
Scott: Yeah, there's good animals.
Scott: And that's sort of like, you know, Smurfs.
Scott: There's the evil cat.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And Inspector Gadget, this brain and then the evil cat.
Scott: The claw cat.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's a common thing.
Scott: And it's silly.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: On the Wikipedia article, space mice are listed as allies.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A family of five mice that live in Grodama Castle.
Scott: But the thing is, even though it's monster of the week, it's like when Voltron cuts these monsters down and go line Voltron custom monsters down, it's just like form blazing sword.
Scott: The monster is dead.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In here.
Scott: When Goliath cuts them, it's like this.
Scott: They're a cut in half.
Scott: It looks like Kentro punched him.
Scott: It's like, yeah, the way it's animated and everything is like super violent.
Scott: Right.
Rym: At least for, you know, what you would expect, because it makes a it makes it very clear.
Rym: These are not robots.
Rym: These are basic.
Scott: I think they call them robeasts in Voltron of, you know, U.S.
Scott: because to imply that they are robot beasts.
Scott: But no, they are not.
Scott: They are people that were slaves that got horribly infected with evil.
Rym: And I guess my big takeaway is that I expected to watch this and then we do a show on it like, OK, this was the thing we watch.
Rym: But I kind of felt that same feeling watching the first six episodes that I felt the first time I started watching a bunch of Fist of the North Star.
Scott: You want to keep watching?
Rym: Like, I feel like I could just occasionally watch an episode.
Scott: Even though it's monster of the week, it's like you get it sort of drags you on with its its simple structure of making you want to keep going.
Scott: And as the added bonus of the slight amount of serial storytelling where things change a little bit each episode, it's not just the boring, super repetitive thing.
Scott: And as far as I know, I've never seen it.
Scott: There is an ending that like actually sort of wraps things up at the end.
Scott: It's not just, you know, monster of the week and then suddenly no more.
Rym: Oh, I learned some stuff from Wikipedia.
Rym: There's probably spoilers that I won't say, but yeah, I feel like I know spoilers of.
Rym: Oh, no, it only came out before I was born.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, yeah, all I want to say is if you have Crunchyroll, you should watch the first episode of this, if nothing else, because it will give you a lot of perspective.
Scott: Yeah, Voltron is a big enough property in the world of nerdery that even if you don't like it, even if you don't give a shit, even if you hate Mecca's of all kinds, you know, even if you hate anime's, you should watch some go line and maybe even some U.S.
Scott: Voltron, just so you have knowledge of this somewhat important nerd thing.
Scott: And then if you don't like it, you don't watch anymore.
Scott: But, you know, it's like.
Rym: it's like not everyone not everyone watches.
Scott: It's just good to know about and maybe you'll like it and then watch more.
Rym: Yeah, I liked it way more than I expected.
Scott: I know, right.
Scott: It's like it's a yeah.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are and I point out that Patreon appears to have decided to roll back that terrible change they were making on one dollar pledges, because frankly, one dollar pledges are the best pledges.
Rym: So I wasn't sure what I was going to do about that, but it looks like I'm just going to double down on making Patreon content because I think they made the right decision.
Rym: I'll talk about that in the future.
Rym: But anyway, the Patreon patrons for this particular episode are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNichol, The Shimmering Ruby Obelisk, Hanging in the Sky, MyStady.com, Jeremy Monner, Jennie White, Bonafide, Electrified, Six Car Monorail, Cold Guy, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brandau, Captain Chinkawackasy, 421 Creations, No I Never Ever Wonder Why We're Here, Semper Fi, Bitch, Sherman Von Horrell, Rare Lavelle, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Super White, Rym Says Something Funny Here, Sailor Vista, Don Shlick, Jartavish, and Jojo Joestar, Sam Cordery, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Brian Cendroni, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: So now I leave you with... (singing in foreign language).