Rym: It's Monday June 12th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: Okay, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: It is like 95 degrees out and we're talking about that guy who deleted his production database at work and got fired and how.
Rym: That's not his fault Let's do this.
Rym: So I haven't biked to work in a while because it's been cold and rainy and also I've had a lot of meetings where I Was still fighting with my work to let me bring my bike in them.
Rym: I filed all the paperwork in my building finally was like god damn it and they just let me my building doesn't give a shit.
Scott: My building's been foreclosed on and like no one cares.
Scott: I saw people bringing them on the other.
Scott: there's only one of their tenant and they were just bringing him in the Regular old elevator.
Rym: make a deal with that other tenant.
Rym: be like yo I'll pay you like a five bucks if you.
Rym: let me just leave your bike in your place.
Scott: Oh, that's not the worst idea I'm.
Rym: that's what I would try my old company I. actually a big part of why I quit was that they wouldn't let me bring my bike into the office And I was kind of looking to quit anyway.
Scott: But it's like I can't.
Scott: there is no better job out there.
Scott: Otherwise I would have left, you know.
Scott: But I've been here for eight years because people call me up all the time and their jobs aren't better.
Rym: Yep It's uh, I've gotten some.
Scott: there was a better job.
Scott: I'd go but there isn't one.
Rym: I've had a few that were definitely.
Scott: I can't quit over something small like you're not letting me keep my bike enough.
Rym: the ones that were better though recently are either very high risk of Disappearing, you know how those things go or Were jobs that?
Rym: They're better in every way except.
Scott: I don't want someone said they can't hear me.
Rym: That's fixed long ago.
Rym: Okay, so it's because I muted it.
Rym: when I plug it unplug your microphone to prevent a pop and I forgot to unmute it.
Scott: There's not.
Scott: it might have broken because he dropped it on the floor.
Rym: Nope, there is a pipeline that goes through the compressor to here and there's a separate pipeline that goes in here.
Rym: There's all these pipelines.
Rym: It's like a complicated situation here.
Rym: if we had that patreon level I'll do a video explaining how all this is set up.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but I digress really come.
Rym: Ah, I Could make it way more complicated if I wanted to make it unnecessary But yeah, it's super hot out and over the weekend be Emily and her friend Phil actually ran the Brooklyn pride 5k race and you didn't win because you slow.
Rym: so the winner in my age group got a time Actually, it was only like 18 or so minutes.
Rym: I think okay and overall was like 17 minutes.
Scott: What was your minutes?
Scott: 21?
Scott: So here are three minutes slow Yeah, so the person crossed the finish line and then we counted to a hundred and eighty and then ran across the finish line.
Rym: yep, so I'm not gonna win these things because winning times on most of the five.
Scott: you think about running a hundred like just go Outside and run and count, you know set a timer for three minutes and see how far you run in three minutes.
Scott: That's how far.
Rym: so I looked up the best 5k I've ever run because I actually have records of all this ever like a race a formal race where Someone with a real system gave me a real like formal time the best one I ran was exactly 20 minutes and some milliseconds.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And so that's that's running like six and a half minute miles.
Rym: ish That was three years ago and I feel like I will never do better than that again in the rest of my life.
Scott: See I did.
Scott: my plan actually right was oh if you didn't get the flat tire If I didn't have the flat tire is I was gonna cuz I didn't realize until I got there.
Scott: See my my original plan was just to leave and go to the barbecue.
Rym: Oh, you're gonna follow and like get a video of me be huffing and puffing and being sweaty.
Scott: I maybe waited the finish line, but because I had the flat tire I went to the finish line.
Scott: So but but the thing is once I realized that I thought the whole circle would be closed.
Scott: When I realized it wasn't closed.
Scott: I was like, oh, maybe we'll do some little Mac.
Scott: Yeah uh-huh, and I would just go and like, you know, I would try to like.
Scott: You know go at a bad taste like mess you up and make you get all tired and fall over.
Rym: So you missed it.
Rym: actually it's a shame that didn't happen because did you vomit again?
Rym: I vomited.
Scott: So basically I even yelled at the beginning of the race don't vomit.
Scott: and I realized I didn't say Rym don't.
Scott: I'm like, wow, everyone else is really wondering why I yelled that.
Rym: so it's a common thing Like a lot of people vomit after like significant running races more more like 10 K's or marathons, but or half marathons.
Rym: But basically it was real Ozone and pretty hot and there's a hill.
Scott: It wasn't that bad.
Scott: That was a good day.
Rym: I mean it was way better than like today But the Ozone was like 85 ish during the race.
Rym: So like everyone like all of us like the times across the board were slower than like people would probably get on a nicer day And also that hill like I don't train on hills at all.
Scott: Usually but the baby hill.
Rym: to avoid the crowd I started near the front and I tried to follow not the front.
Scott: I did see you at the start.
Scott: you were Nearish they were near the front than you should have been and you were trying harder than it looked like you should have tried.
Rym: No, my only goal was to get ahead of the main body so I didn't have to deal with people and to not keep up with the front runners because those are people who are like Professional runners like those are people who are shooting for a 16-minute Mm-hmm.
Rym: I wanted to keep up with the people who are one group behind that Mmm, and I kept up with them.
Rym: Like I picked a guy and I was like I'm following him because he looks pro and he's like he's keeping a pace.
Rym: I'm gonna follow his exact pace because I don't keep good paces when I buy myself.
Rym: And I kept up with him until the two and a half mile mark and then he slowed started disappearing in the distance And then I pushed to try to catch up and I pushed a little too hard and I vom.
Rym: I basically there's this but there's a woman at the end like taking photos like a really nice camera Mm-hmm, and I'm running and I see the camera come up but she's gonna take a picture of me and I immediately turn my head to the left and just Explode exploded vomited behind me And then I turned right and just kept running and I saw her like bring the camera down like what the fuck.
Rym: And it was real funny.
Rym: and then anyone else vomiting, uh, I saw a couple other people vomit after they cross the finish line.
Rym: Not a ton of people though.
Scott: Mm-hmm Really do something about this.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I should do about that either not push myself that hard or actually train.
Rym: I've been training much lately but anyway I digress.
Rym: races are fun and just a hobby of mine and this guy came out and hung out and then we didn't go to The pride parade because it was actually at night.
Scott: I did so much stuff on Saturday.
Scott: first I went to that race.
Scott: Yeah, and I had a flat tire.
Rym: went to the bike shop Yeah, then you found the nice bike shot.
Rym: You went to do bike shop.
Scott: Well that I went well, the one was closed.
Scott: then I went to the barbecue and then I went to the mural project And then on Sunday, I live streamed all those things.
Scott: So if you followed my youtube channel, you could have seen all those things.
Scott: They're still there I guess.
Scott: and then on Sunday.
Scott: I just went to the barbecue.
Scott: Yeah, I did less but I still did plenty.
Rym: Yeah, well sunny went to the barbecue.
Rym: We hung out in the park for a while eating barbecue and chillin and then we played some board games and did some stuff.
Rym: It was a good weekend all told had some friends out.
Rym: Now I got to do it.
Rym: I got to finish a bunch of kinetic.
Rym: I got a lot of work to do in the next like couple weeks and I gotta go to London.
Rym: So, uh, Mmm, uh, yeah two weeks from now there won't be shows cuz I'll be in London pretty much all week.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Scott: They got problems.
Rym: Nothing that look like me.
Rym: I'm just saying Scott a lot of the places I go have had attacks like that.
Scott: In fact, like well, I'm not talking about that Like what Exedy problems.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah That the the brexit stuff actually doesn't affect me that much not yet And most of what I'm just so.
Rym: it's funny because what I'm doing there is I'm going to a convention where I'm on a panel about Miffed - which is this European regulation that Affects the UK now, but might not affect the UK after brexit, but Europe might force them to do it.
Rym: Anyway, they won't build it.
Rym: There's actually a pretty.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's somewhat funny that I'm on a panel about Miffed - in London While brexit is in the process of potentially happening.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so in the news Scott you sent me this link and we both read it and it's just sort of a Can I'm not gonna vouch for like all the reporting in this?
Scott: Yeah, it's just some guys blog.
Rym: Yep But I've stumbled across this blog multiple times in the past.
Rym: It's always been pretty.
Scott: Okay, so The story here Scott sent me the link is basically talking about like usually you read an article right and an article has like one fit like one bomb it drops and like has one quote pull that like You know pull quote that is like.
Scott: that tells you what the big deal is and all the rest of it is just filler words Right.
Scott: Yeah, this one is just dropping bombs and like every paragraph like oh shit.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: Oh, that's what's going down.
Rym: I recommend actually if you listen to GeekNights Monday Just go to this page and read this article because we're not gonna read it to you.
Rym: And there's a lot of fascinating stuff.
Rym: But
Scott: it basically tells this story about you know, Microsoft and Intel right being dependent on each other But also competing with each other trying to like gain dominance in this sort of partnered relationship, right and in doing so Right locking in the backwards compatibility of you know Wintel platform all the way back to the earliest x86 code Nope, and how time and time again people tried to bust in there, but couldn't bust in.
Scott: they could you know No one from the outside could attack them.
Scott: right.
Scott: but Nvidia, you know has finally, you know Going to succeed in the near future right.
Scott: and all the really fascinating stuff is when it talks about the different technological decisions made by all these companies for Competitive reasons.
Scott: right like aha Intel didn't put too many PCI Express.
Scott: That's the one I was gonna bring up on the chipset because then that would mean that you know Nvidia Things could be so fast that you wouldn't care about the Intel stuff anymore.
Scott: All right, or you know, oh they didn't.
Scott: you know Intel was trying to virtualize all of Windows at one point.
Scott: So that way, you know Windows could be disposed of and you could just run your code on Intel stuff directly.
Scott: There's an example on a nerd like a current like i7 Intel and Microsoft made DirectX in order to you know Prevent Intel from doing that and so and so.
Rym: but you'll get like 16 PCI Express lanes.
Rym: So if you have one video card I'll use all 16. if you got to One of them will use eight and the other one will use eight or like eight and four.
Rym: There's all these.
Rym: if you buy an expensive one, you might get 20 lanes.
Rym: Like I think my mother bird is 20.
Scott: It's like a video card and the PCIe SSD it also talks about like Intel put those GPUs in the CPUs because that way Only super gamers would but would put Nvidia equipment in yep.
Scott: So you're locking normal.
Scott: normal people wouldn't have that.
Scott: so that way you couldn't build direct.
Scott: You couldn't.
Scott: basically as software developers You couldn't build for Nvidia because people don't have it because only the super gamers have it.
Rym: They're all normal people have integrate integrated Intel stuff Which really puts into light the idea that Kaby Lake that you're the next Intel chipset has native support for 4k and like video stuff.
Scott: But it's like basically all of this stuff is.
Scott: you're just trying to get this competition for developers, right?
Scott: They want people to write software in a certain way because if software runs on their platforms Then they sell their platforms and if developers start writing software that runs on a different platform People don't need their platform anymore, right?
Scott: So that that's what happens when you make an operating system or hardware.
Scott: You need people you need.
Scott: the most thing you need the most is Developers writing software for your shit because if that's what really sells products people don't aren't buying.
Scott: You know Wintel because they like it.
Scott: they're buying it because Photoshop runs on it.
Rym: Yeah, and it also runs on Mac, but Macs are super underpowered.
Scott: Right, but that's also even Intel.
Rym: Yeah I didn't tell what is the different platform?
Scott: But if the software that people want to run runs on something else if it runs on a hundred percent Nvidia equipment They're not gonna buy no Intel garbo.
Rym: The only problem is like it's talking about.
Rym: GPUs are like faster and scaling faster and all that but because they weren't hindered by the backwards compatibility in our architecture decision, but they also use a ton of power.
Scott: That's I think that's the one thing is like, you know and generate a shit ton of heat Shocking.
Rym: if I play overwatch And I like use OBS to like livestream it and use OBS separately to encode to my disk Like my computer gets so hot that it like it hurts my feet if they're near the exhaust because this is what happened.
Scott: Right is like, you know for a while in like the Pentium 4 era right when we were having like AMD computers that set on fire AMD was basically going the route of like the hot rod.
Scott: like we don't care about heat generation.
Scott: We'll just put bigger and crazier heat sinks on there.
Scott: You don't care about power efficiency.
Scott: We'll just go as fast as we can and burn all the fuel.
Scott: fuck fuel efficiency, right?
Scott: Intel the Pentium 4 kind of did that but then they really it wasn't working too great.
Scott: So then they were like, alright, we actually need to make CPUs that are efficient because we got laptops and things, right?
Scott: We want to not use a lot of electricity to get more battery life and we want to you know Get more processing done per unit electricity.
Scott: We want to be more stable and less crashy and more reliable and that was the good road to go down.
Scott: They beat AMD going on that road also using dirty business tricks that you can read about elsewhere, right?
Rym: And also bringing their prices down because they had their prices high because no one competed with them.
Rym: as soon as there was a competitor suddenly Intel chips got better and cheaper right but GPUs right.
Scott: basically never gave a fuck.
Scott: They're just like hot rod all the way, you know.
Scott: Just stick a million fans on there and use all the power in the world.
Scott: In fact you now you have to plug in two more power cables from your power supply because we need more power.
Scott: We don't care about power efficiency We don't care about you know, pretty much anything except getting the most possible processing power, right use all the juice He got.
Scott: yeah, you need a 800 watt power supply.
Scott: now I got two of these bad boys is like And that's why they're faster.
Scott: if Intel had been like we don't give a shit.
Scott: It would be faster too, but the backwards compatibility You know also, you know didn't allow them to be as parallel as the GPUs are right.
Scott: GPUs are crazy parallel Like you talk about like 16 cores in your CPU the GPU is like whatever I got like.
Rym: So remember I said like.
Rym: here's a specific example from the article in Intel like chipset and like a modern one will have 16 Maybe 20 PCI Express lanes quote here.
Rym: IBM has also partnered with Nvidia to produce a generation of monster number crunching CPUs with the power 9 sporting 160 PCIe lanes yep instead of 16 10 X Yep, and the risin's.
Rym: I didn't know this until relatively recently Mm-hmm the AMD risin CPUs cuz they don't give a fuck about protecting Intel's x86.
Rym: They're putting shit tons of PCIe lanes in their new chips.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: They got tons.
Rym: So it's interesting that in light of all that because it's not mentioned in this article I don't think.
Rym: but you might have seen Intel announced recently their core i9 Which as far as I can tell are just skylake chips that have more cores, they're not even the newest lake They're the previous lake.
Rym: Yeah, they're not KB like the skylake as far as I know and as far as anyone has been able to tell me Mm-hmm, so it's just.
Scott: it's just so fascinating that a you know, we're gonna see this You know, it really makes you believe that the move away from Wintel and over to like arm plus GPUs You know and not Windows and Intel is might happen is actually happening for reals now Because people are doing less and less on desktop computers, right?
Rym: You know, everyone's using Professionals and gamers use workstations anymore, right?
Scott: You know all your self-driving cars and you're pretty much everything that's not a desktop computer.
Scott: is You know probably gonna run on some arm and video type of thing.
Scott: But also just to see all of the technological decisions made by these companies for business competitive reasons Right is really fascinating.
Scott: So because normal developers when you're at work You don't work for these big places making these kinds of decisions.
Scott: You just try to make the best technological decision.
Scott: You can yell for the sake of just technology and saving money or whatever.
Scott: You're not saying aha Let's make DirectX so that Intel doesn't put us out of business.
Rym: So look at this.
Rym: there's a lot of software that could get a huge advantage from having like native GPU processing built in like say games do or Adobe stuff like Premiere does right but Adobe and game companies only developed for that stuff because they know that 100% of the people using their software at least like 90% have the Nvidia hardware because that's just what you do.
Rym: So as a result, like they have a reason like their user base has they know the hardware is there.
Rym: It's kind of like how you can assume when you design modern software that most people are using and have a mouse plugged into their Computer.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But imagine if like only weirdos use mice Then you wouldn't be making software like games wouldn't support night mice natively.
Rym: Yep, so Total aside, but someone.
Rym: the chat point is that they're all.
Rym: they're all like shocked that we know who Alex Saint John is.
Scott: I don't know who that is.
Scott: He wrote the article.
Scott: So it's a name I've heard but I know nothing about him.
Rym: So in the chat, there's a message here.
Rym: I Legit, remember this article because it's the first time I remember this so clearly.
Rym: It was on the back page of a maximum PC 18 years ago about driving a Hummer into a pond covered in freshly cut grass.
Rym: Well, they work for Microsoft.
Rym: Okay, and pretty sure it's the exact same dude.
Scott: Probably I don't I don't know anything about him.
Scott: Is he good dude or a bad dude?
Rym: I mean I only stumble upon this blog occasionally and usually because it's linked to from slash shop.
Scott: So, I don't know if he's good or bad dude, but he wrote a good article.
Scott: So yeah about technology.
Rym: This is fascinating And if you if this if everything we if anything we just talked about touches on anything you do in your career You should at least pay attention to what's going on this space because this might be a big inflection point that's coming.
Scott: I definitely want to like, you know, it's like hey, you know, you should probably learn to write software for you know These sort of arm and video type.
Rym: It's such a pain in the ass.
Scott: But if you learn my god, you learn how to write that stuff using like the Vulcan stuff, right?
Scott: That's probably gonna be beneficial to you if you're a job seeker.
Rym: So the other thing is that remember?
Rym: Intel actually has another entrenched interest because they want to push their Intel Phi programming for this.
Rym: That's like instead of GPUs to do that kind of Intel's was pushing FPGAs, right?
Rym: Uh, so they want you to use the five which I sort of like FPGAs.
Rym: But it's sort of like you'll have a like you'll have a processor here that has 68 cores and there's ways like you can run Most x86 type software on those cores with some limitations and I learned a lot of it work a while ago And then I forgot most of it because it's not like.
Rym: I'm not developing any software on it.
Rym: But this is another situation where Intel is pushing this thing but Nvidia and others might be able to provide an alternative.
Rym: So keep an eye on all this biz in some actual science news.
Rym: This is a pretty like tentative study but I'm partly bringing it up because I'm biased toward it because I think that e-cigarettes are a high indicator of douchebaggery in my In my anecdotal evidence of interacting with humans who use e-cigarettes on a regular basis.
Scott: But the thing I've noticed that you about e-cigarettes that's you know more bothersome.
Scott: actually It's like it's like a dude who used to smoke.
Scott: He's already a bad person.
Scott: Right is now smoking an e-cig just as regularly as they were smoking the regular sig.
Scott: It's like Alright, well, it smells less bad in the world.
Scott: So I guess it's a little better.
Rym: but then they start using it like in buildings instead of going out to the street.
Scott: But the thing that bothers me I think about the e-cigarette is that you had people who would otherwise Never smoke ever right they would smoke nothing but if you like You know you'll be like a party.
Scott: and it's like if at the party someone passed around a real cigarette.
Scott: all these people would have Been like no, but it's on passes around an e-cigarette everyone would be like, oh, all right I've never seen anyone pass an e-cigarette around unless they were smoking marijuana.
Scott: I'm just saying you know marijuana or otherwise, right?
Scott: You know people who otherwise would not smoke because of vaporizers seeming to be less deadly.
Scott: Right people who otherwise don't do it are open to doing it in certain social situations.
Scott: They otherwise would not
Rym: just stare like the people I see most off like it's one the people I noticed vaping Otherwise the words because a lot of people who use vapes Tend to do it discreetly and they like ghosts like they go outside just like the wood for a cigarette But they do this instead.
Rym: So instead of smelling like ass mixed with ass they smell like light ass mixed with cotton candy or whatever, right?
Rym: Which is still pretty annoying.
Scott: the point is it doesn't matter how you poison yourself.
Scott: poisoning yourself isn't cool?
Rym: Yeah, I mean I poison myself.
Rym: I was I'm drinking some wine.
Scott: It's not cool.
Rym: Wines great.
Rym: No But the article anyway, I digress.
Rym: the article is simply that there is some significant evidence that Irrespective of whether or not you even have nicotine in your stupid e-cigarette The substrate itself the vape juice even if you don't put anything in it if it's just unadulterated on like nothing just vape juice Causes pretty much the same DNA damage that smoking cigarettes does.
Scott: so this isn't about lung damage.
Rym: It's not about you know mouth cancer or like the deleterious effects of nicotine itself, right?
Rym: This is just the vape.
Scott: this is just about DNA damage only is probably just as bad.
Scott: So I guess maybe that is cancer, but not I guess you won't get emphysema.
Scott: probably probably I won't say I don't know but they didn't test for that.
Scott: The point is you know people act like oh, you know you say it's like no you're still poisoning yourself.
Scott: Don't fool yourself because the other.
Rym: but I'm mostly annoyed with these cigarettes.
Rym: Is that a lot of people who would otherwise sort of surreptitiously or just like God have a cigarette and like well They smell like open asses when they come back to whatever it is They left to go smoke They don't like.
Rym: they don't like smoke as performative behavior.
Rym: the way that I see a lot of vape people doing Like vape people seem to be more and more into like big clouds of vape like hey look at me.
Scott: I don't care about.
Scott: I don't care about the social Aspect of it.
Rym: Oh no, but there's a high correlation between the social aspect and disbeggery.
Scott: I don't want human beings poisoning themselves And it's not cool to poison yourself.
Scott: And it's really upsetting if you see someone that you care about poisoning themselves.
Scott: imagine if they were drinking real poison.
Scott: It's like oh, they're only drinking a little bit of poison.
Scott: So it's not bothering me so much.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I drink alcohol.
Scott: It's not poisoning.
Rym: It's delicious though and humans co-evolved with it for centuries.
Scott: cocaine makes you feel real good.
Scott: I actually go snort something.
Rym: Okay, it's way more data.
Rym: I got no interest in cocaine.
Scott: Oh, so if I'm falling off a bridge if I jump off a bridge, but I fall really slow It's got water can poison you but I still die when you drink too much water.
Rym: You'll die.
Scott: I'm just saying just saying Just say you also die if you don't drink anyone.
Rym: don't go biking when there's a lot of ozone.
Rym: That's carcinogenic.
Rym: That's poisonous.
Rym: I don't bike too much Yeah, but you know Was uh took me an extra 10 minutes cuz I was a what it was 95 degrees and just a lot of ozone in the Air.
Rym: so I was biking a little slow.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me Scott?
Scott: So there's these dudes and I lost the link to them.
Rym: I got the link here.
Scott: All right, I forget who they are.
Scott: What's?
Scott: it was the guy's YouTube name?
Scott: World War two Wendell.
Scott: right and this guy is in Wendell ice.
Scott: yeah, he's in Lyster England, Lychester.
Scott: I don't know how to pronounce it correctly.
Scott: what.
Scott: and there is the river soar.
Scott: SOA are and they are doing an activity Which I had not heard of before which apparently based on YouTube recommendations is a common activity.
Scott: It's called Magnet fishing and that's you already can imagine what it is.
Scott: Take a big-ass fucking magnet.
Scott: They got a really big one here like one.
Scott: That's so strong that you You know, it's really strong.
Scott: You don't want to mess around with it.
Rym: It was like if this was in a box in the boat and went over.
Rym: the Titanic would have brought the Titanic up.
Scott: Yeah, so you you tie a rope around that shit and you know The strength of the rope.
Scott: better.
Scott: be really strong because the magnet might just get stuck on something and you end up pulling nothing out Right.
Scott: Yeah, you toss it in a river You move it around till it goes clunk on something metal and you yank that shit up and you see what's at the bottom of The water is a thousand times more cooler than those lame-o's walking around beaches with metal detectors.
Scott: It's also way cooler than actual fishing because what I want was some useless ass fish From a disgusting river that you're not gonna want to eat.
Scott: when I get a useful human-made metal object from the bottom of a river like now one but two Stolen safes safes.
Scott: That's like the most coolest thing you can find as a save.
Scott: Yeah, what metal detector guy on the beach?
Scott: Would you find some coins?
Rym: fucking safes Floral they like.
Rym: call the police cuz one.
Scott: Yeah, what one of them was a recently stolen safe.
Scott: and you look at the safe.
Scott: There's like a hole blasted in the front of it and that they took all the loot out of.
Scott: And they found like yeah It was like a recent robbery and someone who tossed the safe into the river and they found it.
Scott: So they called the cops to come check it out.
Scott: But yeah Maybe we should do some.
Scott: is it legal to magnet fish in like the East River looks like a lot of people are doing it.
Rym: I just googled for magnet fishing East River.
Rym: Magnet fishing best finds from the river.
Scott: You want a magnet find in?
Scott: You know where.
Rym: I know where go on his canal, you know, we're gonna find.
Rym: we're gonna find a barrel full of poison.
Scott: At least you won't smoke it.
Rym: The only problem with this is that one that the magnet he bought was like 500 bucks.
Scott: Yeah You're gonna spend the five and two.
Rym: I remember the last time we had an idea like this and we went dumpster dive in a Bunch.
Rym: we got fishing is a better than dumpster diving and we were like, oh, we'll sell it all.
Rym: We didn't sell any other gonna sell them stuff.
Scott: We find magnet fishing.
Scott: We're just gonna dump right back in the water.
Rym: We're pretty sure it's actually illegal to dump it back in the water cuz that's dumping.
Scott: We'll leave it right on the beach.
Rym: So my thing of the day.
Rym: Phil showed this to me over the weekend.
Rym: apparently it was it went viral a couple years ago.
Rym: I just never noticed.
Rym: Uh, it is called my cousin Oscar and Oscar lives in Iceland Iceland.
Rym: it's cold.
Rym: They don't get a lot of sunlight in the wind.
Scott: people always talk about like Oh, the Vikings are trying to be silly like internet people.
Scott: All right, they they called the Greenland Iceland in the Iceland Greenland, but no Iceland is also in Iceland.
Scott: They're both Iceland's.
Scott: they just called one of them Greenland to be funny.
Rym: The other one was true, but Oscar found out about the concept of daylight saving time in America.
Scott: He didn't know about it in Australia.
Scott: They don't have that in Iceland.
Scott: Most places don't have it So he didn't even know.
Rym: it was a thing and he's pissed off about it and how we make.
Scott: I'm also pissed off about Yeah, I'm his son.
Rym: I feel like we should go back a couple hours like go to ADT right now.
Scott: Yeah, right now right now The way the time is in the summer.
Scott: I wake up.
Scott: It's like seven ish.
Scott: The sun's already fucking up like you don't see no sunrise, which means we need to move that shit.
Scott: It's like the sunrise should be one or two hours later in the day, right?
Rym: Rise just as I get to work like I get as much daylight as possible.
Scott: Yeah, the Sun should rise like 637 and then right now The Sun is setting at 830 ish, right?
Scott: It's like why can't the Sun set it like eight nine thirty ten something like that.
Scott: if we move the Sun set up We could have the Sun set We move the Sun rise up the Sun set could be like 10 11 and then as soon as it gets dark I go to bed.
Rym: something was always nice as a kid is that I can hang out in the park all that time both Detroit Biking into like 10. no problem Detroit and Cedar Point are in the same time zone as New York But they're way to the west so we end up getting more daylight in the evening as a result.
Scott: I'm just saying that's what we should be doing right.
Scott: and then if you want to move the clock around move it to keep the sunrise close to wake-up time as possible, but Oscar is Dumpstruck that we have this giant like Biannual argument about daylight saving time over one fucking hour.
Rym: He's like one hour.
Rym: I would do anything to have another hour of daylight.
Rym: I get three hours of daylight.
Rym: Did you want to see my dog?
Rym: Oh, you can't because it's fucking dark.
Rym: It's 3 p.m.. Right now.
Rym: Let's go to the beach.
Rym: Oh, I would die.
Rym: The video is just pretty funny, and I urge you to send this to people.
Scott: I think it's a little fake.
Rym: the video he does it is it's very performative But it's the same time.
Scott: he definitely used some after-effects to make it darker inside.
Rym: I don't think he did.
Scott: It's not really that dark.
Scott: I think he just has a crappy camera as he pointed out definitely definitely did tricks to make it look darker than it is.
Rym: I mean if it's I mean when.
Scott: I mean I can make that video in New York.
Scott: It just filmed the whole thing at midnight and change the time my watch.
Rym: I don't think he did because I looked up and yeah The sun's only.
Rym: just it's up for like four and a half hours in the middle of winter.
Rym: But like the two ends of that four and a half hours are dawn and dusk.
Rym: There's only like three hours of actual sunlight.
Scott: It still seems a little bit exaggerated.
Rym: No.
Rym: I mean it just gets dark.
Rym: It's dark, and that's it mm-hmm.
Rym: So uh in the meta moment the book club book is Dune Frank Erbert's.
Rym: I'm gonna update the website, and we're gonna actually start reading it soon.
Rym: uh You should follow Scott's YouTube channel and my youtube channel.
Rym: both of them have good stuff on them.
Rym: The antenna show is gonna come back as soon as Connecticut's done because I got to make sure that stuff's all out of the way.
Rym: but I got the production pipeline set up and after Considerable effort I have fought uh and won Every goddamn copyright claim on the YouTube show.
Rym: yeah every one of the videos is viewable Everywhere in the world whoa even Italy and such.
Rym: yes it.
Rym: I filed like 50 fucking counter notifications.
Rym: I like made a template.
Rym: Holy crap, but I fought for you guys.
Rym: your tennis show is up I think it's gonna stay up, and I have a way to probably avoid this for the future episodes.
Rym: So shortly after Connecticut, and we're starting that production pipeline up again in earnest.
Rym: so stay tuned because actually There's more who ten a manga coming so Okay, and also there's a Twitter account.
Rym: I follow this new ten about the tweets like who tennis screenshots every day.
Rym: I'm feeling who ten again in a big way.
Rym: so Feeling doing that show and there's sunlight so we can do video shows and in the evening and still have natural light coming in the Window which makes it way easier to do video.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: it's coming And I guess just right out of the main bit.
Rym: so a lot of you might have seen this story.
Scott: this story got po.
Scott: I saw where it was originally posted.
Scott: I think I'd like programming read it.
Scott: Maybe or something like that Wherever is originally posted.
Scott: I saw it and basically the story is this is some kid who was getting like an internship Or like his first job out of college a brand new developer.
Scott: right he goes and gets a programming job wherever he can and he's Doing the the.
Scott: you know employee set up your computer Which is when you're a developer is a little different because you have to you're not only Development environment build and fire.
Scott: yeah You have to install it you have to set up a bunch of stuff and in doing so the reason we don't just automate it And just give it to you already set up is because you learn how the shit works by setting it up.
Scott: right yep, so He did it and in doing so accidentally Erased the company's production database or whatever and like they.
Scott: so they fired him because he messed up so bad quote.
Rym: the CEO told me To leave and never come back.
Rym: He also informed me that apparently legal would need to be involved to the severity of the data loss.
Rym: I basically offered and pleaded to let me help in some way to redeem myself.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I was told quote I completely fucked everything up, so I just saw this story posted everywhere.
Scott: I don't actually know if it's true This could be a fake story, but I can say this, but it doesn't seem like it's advertising anything.
Scott: So if it was a fake story that someone just wanted to spread around the internet to hoax people They there was no one who could gain anything from this story Other than starting this discussion.
Rym: I have seen this exact same story like the same type of story occur Many times in my professional life.
Rym: I have heard anecdotes from people who did this thing.
Rym: I have like this story that the beats of it even if this individual story We're not true has happened time and time again, and I want to say Categorically 100%.
Rym: it is never the person who fucked up productions fault.
Rym: it is the fault of the CTO For not having controls in place to prevent that from occurring not having backups not having like a redundancy plan.
Rym: It is never the developers fault in this case right.
Scott: so here's here's the details of this specific instance right.
Scott: so the first problem Was why is it even possible?
Scott: For a developer on their computer sitting on their desk to connect to the production database?
Scott: at my work We have a production database.
Scott: obviously yep say this production database is on Amazon's cloud or whatever.
Scott: right you cannot.
Scott: There is no network access to it from anywhere except a few Whitelisted web servers that are supposed to connect to it.
Scott: Yeah, every company I've ever been not connect to it except from those machines.
Rym: the developers are on their own subnet.
Rym: you can only access the source repositories and their own servers.
Rym: and like Staging areas and the internet of course the internet right, but it's like you could not.
Scott: no matter how hard you tried No router that existed on the internet anywhere would route a packet from your computer to that database server.
Scott: You cannot communicate with it.
Scott: it's Absolutely impossible to do so.
Scott: and and it's you would need like SSH keys and someone would have to make those for you by hand And specifically grant you access and tell you how to somehow connect through various machines to get there.
Scott: There is no way you could accidentally do anything to it whatsoever.
Rym: It's called the concept like the fundamental concept cuz I I do a lot of qualitative risk analysis in my actual job And I've done this in my other jobs before too.
Rym: So like I analyze these kinds of risks and there's a thing called like a sock one audit and there's other thing like there's other Types of audits you can do but are like Sarbanes.
Rym: Oxley has rules about this.
Rym: But the gist is the idea of separation of duties meaning you have developers.
Rym: developers cannot ever touch production.
Rym: you have QA.
Rym: Developers cannot touch QA systems.
Rym: You have operations Operations troubleshoots production systems.
Rym: They can never see the source code of the development systems.
Rym: They could never touch developer systems or the source code repository.
Rym: Right, you separate the roles and you don't just separate them with rules you separate them with hard IT Controls, right?
Scott: So with a combination of network security, right of you know firewalls and these sorts of things and also, you know authentic authorization authentication mechanisms like SSH and such and such it becomes physically and Mathematically impossible for people to connect to a place that they are not supposed to connect to.
Rym: Yep so if of someone like any employee of any company connects to something they shouldn't have and fucks it up either they Maliciously and with ill intent broke in which again that means your security sucks ass.
Rym: Yeah, it's really.
Scott: it's really hard to break through as is to your company's controls.
Rym: suck ass and it's your company's fault.
Scott: I think the only way it could happen at our company would be like if somebody was like SSH didn't do a machine and which they would only do in like a crazy situation.
Scott: to begin with right and Some and they didn't lock their computer and they got up and walked away and someone else came over and was like Again, that's malicious intent.
Rym: I'm saying right?
Scott: It's like that's the kind of thing that would have to happen.
Rym: But even then that's a violation of procedures like so.
Rym: most companies like you have DevOps, right or operations teams.
Rym: They used to be called so like in any company I've ever worked for and like most places.
Rym: Say you have your production system like you're on Twitter, right?
Rym: There's servers that are running.
Rym: the real Twitter live right now.
Rym: the only people who can ever Like SSH into those servers are the people on the operations team whose sole job it is to troubleshoot Problems with those systems and to deploy new builds to them.
Scott: also something that's so big like Twitter is built in such a way with Redundancy that they would just like if they needed to actually do something to specific servers like that.
Scott: They would just remove them from the Twitter.
Scott: Twitter would continue working Yeah, and they would mess with them and then add them back to the real Twitter.
Scott: So let's almost everything they do would not be done by hand direct to machines.
Scott: It would be through automation things that were separate.
Scott: They would talk to these automation servers.
Scott: that would then you know Orient the real servers, right?
Scott: And that layer in between is like you can go push your button that says like increased capacity or You know to deploy this new build or something like that and you just pushes one button.
Scott: You couldn't go do anything by hand and fuck it up.
Scott: It's that tested code that does that deployment that does everything.
Rym: Yeah, well, here's an example from two different companies.
Rym: I were Almost to two and a half.
Scott: I've never worked at a place.
Scott: That was stupid.
Rym: Yeah now I've never worked partly cuz I mind.
Scott: where have I ever worked?
Rym: hospitals dangerous factories and Wall Street.
Rym: Yeah, like two of my jobs were death on the line.
Scott: If we fuck I've never worked at a place as stupid as the place or this person supposedly work.
Rym: Nope, but even if it's a single server like I've administered systems usually in an operational capacity We're like there is a single production server doing something really important.
Rym: So you first.
Rym: we have Developers on their own subnet.
Rym: They'll never even know like they'll never see a production server.
Rym: They write code they test code that right unit test.
Rym: They live in their own world when they have code that's ready to go to production they check it in and Then the QA team has a separate procedure like on the other side of a firewall where they check out Compiled like code ready to run.
Rym: they then test it in an environment.
Rym: They'll never see production.
Rym: They'll never see dev.
Rym: when they test it and they think it's good They stage it to the operations team the operations team stages it into a pre-production environment and they do like their sanity checks and like Practice the deployment and then usually there's an automated process saying Okay The thing we put in pre-production the CTO signed off hit this button and the next morning It'll be running in prod by an automated process.
Rym: That way at no point.
Rym: Is there any way for anyone to fuck up the thing that they are not responsible for?
Rym: Like ops can fuck up the production system because their job is to not fuck it up.
Rym: Dev can fuck up like the current active build in the dev environment, but of course you can just roll back.
Rym: You know the right.
Scott: that's the other.
Scott: the two other fuck-ups of this specific instance.
Scott: Right, the other fuck-up is they didn't back this shit up.
Scott: Well, they'd not only than I'm at my company if you if you came into my company And I just let you connect to the MySQL prompt on the production.
Scott: Yeah, just like drop tables just like, you know, delete all databases.
Rym: Maha ha ha ha ha stop star from.
Scott: you know I can go to Oz and click like one button and roll the database back five minutes.
Scott: and it rolls back five minutes.
Scott: and Even if you fuck that up, I have a nightly backup.
Scott: I can restore it in like a minute.
Scott: I just type like two commands and it restores it.
Scott: Yeah, it's really fast It's not that big and it like more controlled environments like, you know The production ops thing and if you deleted all the backups, well, they're in more than one place.
Scott: It's like it would be so difficult.
Scott: Yeah for you to actually cause any damage.
Rym: So if I as an operation person like we deploy the build and we fuck it up There was always a very explicit procedure that had to be verified before you can even roll something out into production.
Rym: that says if it Fucks up here is how to roll it back and we've and you test that procedure.
Scott: Our rollback is so easy.
Scott: We've done it so many time.
Rym: Our rollback.
Scott: we actually used to do it more but we haven't done in so long, but it worked every time.
Scott: Yeah, cuz that's the other thing never had it not work.
Rym: You need procedures to separate all these things and to like like, you know Each like you whoever's responsible stuff like what they're supposed to do.
Rym: You have procedures for rolling back and you have procedures to confirm that all that stuff actually works.
Rym: a lot of companies Yeah that last part take quote unquote backups and then one day like the production system fails and they take the backup and they like Run the script to load into production and it just doesn't work.
Rym: They've never tested it.
Scott: The backup that you haven't tried to actually restore with.
Rym: I saw in fact I saw a system once where someone had a really important wiki that was like all the internal business documentation like, you know serious stuff.
Rym: so they had a primary server and then a backup server.
Rym: one day they fucked up and Deleted everything on the primary server and that sent those deletes over to the back I don't see was just the MySQL database running.
Rym: everything was a master slave.
Rym: So the backup system was literally deleted in the same millisecond that the production system was.
Scott: That's my SQL host.
Scott: master sleeve works.
Scott: just sounds the MySQL commands to the other server.
Rym: Yeah, that's that's the we've done shows on that before the difference between high availability and disaster recovery.
Rym: So the different things.
Scott: so the third mistake here and this is the craziest mistake I don't even think you need to explain this.
Scott: Yeah, like in the instructions this new developer was following in order to set up their environment Was like, you know, you know, it was like go create, you know, you set up your own local database, you know Create username and password, whatever.
Scott: but that document had the production host username and password in it And you were supposed to like replace them.
Scott: that depending with your own But they just copied and pasted depending on the industry you're in.
Rym: that violates laws.
Rym: Yeah, but Don't put that no human being all like this.
Rym: So in the in like the place like the broker dealer I worked at right there was a there's technically a root password to the production Sit like the Linux servers, right?
Rym: It was unique for every server that existed in one play.
Rym: Well two places in the well three places in the world It was there was in an envelope in a safe deposit box that like the chairman of the board had a key to.
Rym: It was in like a little safe in the president's office that could be opened in an emergency And it was in an encrypted like file that required multiple encryption keys from like the CTO and the head of operations to open.
Scott: see what I do on Production servers.
Scott: these days are all servers actually is the at the root password is unknown to every human being on earth.
Scott: It's just generated completely randomly.
Scott: It's really big.
Scott: So you pseudo sue right and then If you want to connect to this machine, you have to SSH into it with it with a key.
Scott: There's no other way to connect to it with it with the SSH.
Rym: every server I administer.
Rym: There are no passwords for anyone.
Scott: Yeah, there's no passwords at all.
Scott: Everything is keys, you know really big SSH keys and you can add and remove them from the authorized Post the keys file, whatever.
Rym: Yeah But what's really crazy is that this company is like.
Rym: it's such a fuck-up on so many levels.
Rym: but the fact that they're like threatening to sue this kid is Ridiculous.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people in the comments because this is posted on like every tech site ever We're like, you know, I'm a lawyer.
Scott: I'll cover you right.
Rym: call me if they actually sue you if anything actually Depending on the state or the country you're in and I'm not a lawyer.
Rym: It's not legal advice.
Rym: being fired for that is arguably a wrongful termination Possibly because you were following instructions that were probably poorly written, right?
Rym: They were probably written by the CTO once and they never really looked at him again.
Scott: So this is something else that bothers me and it's actually a problem at my work, right?
Scott: And it's you know related to this right.
Scott: is this kid or I assume a kid, right?
Rym: Well Anyone who's junior in any position ever?
Scott: I just call kid Was Copying and pasting the commands from this document.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: I And at work people are always pressuring me to like write Instructions that they can use and then copy paste and there are people who are doing things and they're just following procedures without understanding what they're doing.
Scott: and I'm like if you don't understand what you're doing to the point at which you would not need a Document to tell you and then you shouldn't be doing those things Right, it's like the reason that you're if like if you're gonna give a person as a list of commands to copy and paste to Set up a dev environment.
Scott: You just set it up for them.
Scott: They're not learning anything.
Scott: Yeah, right It's like you.
Scott: if you're a professional develop, it's you know.
Scott: It's understandable if you're a driver of a car not to know how a car works.
Scott: completely Right, you know the basics, but if your job is professional developer You shouldn't understand what the hell is going on to the point at which you don't need to be copying and pasting these instructions.
Scott: Things are new to you.
Scott: You should be learning them as you go to the point at which you need to copy paste them.
Rym: Here is an example understand like a real tech example of the driver of the car versus the I guess developer of the car.
Rym: so the developer will make it like say you have a really critical like system that runs on a single server like some internal enterprise thing like a trading system or something real important that isn't like a distributed cloud thing and The developers know how to deploy it.
Rym: or like do a change to or whatever.
Rym: But the person on the far other end of the chain and the operations team who is going to deploy it the final time for real To like the staging area for production that person might get a set of instruction that includes copy paste this command then this command because their only Mandate is to do exactly what the QA team and the dev team signed off on.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: They don't need to know Necessarily what it does.
Rym: In fact, it's better if they could do it not knowing anything.
Rym: That way it's basically idiot proof because the work was already all done by the developers in the queue.
Scott: But if that person is mindlessly entering commands, then you don't just.
Scott: you could just had the QA team push a button.
Scott: You don't know.
Rym: Well, the reason there is simply that that the the script might be push a button.
Rym: The idea is you make it push a button in the end But the QA team shouldn't be the ones to push the button.
Scott: the QA teams push the button But if the person doesn't understand what they're doing they're useless.
Scott: as soon as something goes wrong They're gonna be like a QA team.
Scott: help me.
Scott: and now the QA team is making decisions and you're just having this person Basically in between the brain that knows something.
Scott: Here's the keyboard.
Scott: If I know everything You're a know-nothing.
Scott: All you know how to do is type.
Scott: Why should we use your fingers to do the typing when all the good stuff is in my brain?
Rym: I can tell you exactly why.
Scott: as pointless.
Rym: a big part of this is things like Sarbanes-Oxley.
Rym: The people who are administering the system.
Rym: See like they'd like the DevOps people they have access to like legally Data information or whatever that might have regulatory or legal consequences to them knowing or having access to right.
Scott: So if they do not have the knowledge to where they need to use my brain and they're just basically you all they have is Keyboard fingers as in replacing my keyboard fingers then fire those fuckers.
Scott: Someone who fucking knows something.
Scott: don't do that job.
Scott: You have to call me then you don't deserve your job Legally.
Scott: the reason is the call me to have.
Scott: the reason is those people legally Cannot have access to QA systems under it doesn't have access to the systems, but they need to be have Technological knowledge to where they're more than just someone who types what someone else told them to think for themselves.
Rym: If you are not enough people on earth to hire for those roles Right, so if I'm just saying it you wait.
Scott: If you don't hire one of those not enough people on earth you end up like this shitty fucking company here that loses their production Day because you didn't spend enough to hire people who knew something.
Rym: at every place is there were confident.
Rym: It doesn't matter if the dev team knows what they're doing for like a rollout or something Because it's already all been tested and it's bulletproof.
Rym: and if they fuck it up They have backup procedures and fail at all the stuff in place.
Rym: The problem was that this company assumed a whole bunch of shit had no controls Had no backups had no and basically the company had nothing.
Rym: and there are a lot of companies that basically have nothing.
Scott: If you want to hire ops people, they should be people that can solve the problem on their own and don't you know?
Scott: Oh, no, I just type in my my copy and pasters.
Rym: My preference is to only hire developers or IT people for QA and operations roles.
Rym: That that is my preference and that's what I'm saying.
Scott: Nobody nobody should be able to have a tech job that pays a lot and Responsibilities when all they know how to do is copy and paste.
Rym: But just make sure there is.
Rym: there are examples where the people in QA and production ops Legally can never see the source code.
Scott: That's fine But those people should not be so dumb that all they can do is copy and paste.
Scott: They should have the brains of their own and shouldn't have to call the developer Right to tell them what to type in because they don't understand anything about computers?
Rym: Well, usually what end isn't happening in those situations?
Rym: like say there's a problem in production and then the developer needs to troubleshoot it.
Rym: Then you do a thing.
Rym: We're like the ops person logs into a system and they're the one typing because the dev person might know all about the code.
Rym: But I might not know anything about the exact details of like the configuration of this Linux server, right?
Rym: But we're the ops person types, but the dev person says but I need to see this.
Scott: That's different right.
Scott: I'm talking about a situation where the developer is it knows everything And the ops person knows nothing and they're literally typing in the exact commands.
Scott: Yeah The developer is typing because they are a know-nothing who simply copies and paste.
Scott: literally you're talking about a situation where it's like Oh check the logs.
Scott: Tell me if you see any errors from the whatever right?
Scott: It's like, oh, well The person knows something.
Scott: right is like you can just communicate with them on a higher level.
Scott: They're doing useful things.
Rym: So here I'll give you a good example.
Scott: That's a person who's useful.
Rym: I'll give you a real example when I was at that broker when we did certain kinds.
Rym: But if I'm saying like type LS go to no But like so I they hope like everyone on our ops team was like super pro IT Like we knew our shit about Linux and we knew our shit about the systems.
Rym: But at the same time the instructions for a rollout would have copy/paste of like the specific things to do Because that was what the QA team signed off right?
Scott: But if you looked at those things, did you understand?
Rym: Yes I knew what they did.
Scott: Yeah, you weren't blindly copying pasting a mystery command and then when we're looking at the output going.
Scott: Oh what happened?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: What does that command do?
Scott: Can you read that command and explain it to me?
Scott: No, I just copied and pasted it because my job is copy/paste man.
Rym: Type who what type who?
Rym: who should I type?
Rym: What?
Rym: Yeah Type man who?
Rym: there's no man.
Scott: It's like there's a. you obviously want to create these layers But you don't want to have one of the layers.
Scott: just be copy/paste man.
Scott: If you just have a copy/paste man, just give someone two fucking jobs.
Scott: If the law doesn't you know, y'all prevent you from doing.
Rym: the problem is in finance and a lot of places.
Rym: the law Literally set up that way.
Scott: We've got to hire at least one person in each layer.
Scott: Who's not a copy/paste?
Rym: Yeah, pretty much the minimum you need is dev QA.
Rym: Production have to be three completely separate groups that do not have access to each other's systems.
Scott: If you can if you're doing a less serious line of business You just need to separate the dev QA and the production.
Scott: You only need the two layers, right?
Scott: You know, it's not really a big deal if QA and Dev are messing around with each other.
Scott: If you're making like a video game or something, it's like it's no big deal.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: But if you're making, you know a financial thing or a medical thing I think
Rym: video game unless you're at unless you're a one or two person studio You probably still want all three layers only because I totally want
Scott: to have the layers, but you don't need to strictly separate the non-production.
Scott: Oh, yeah, let's separate the production for the non-production.
Rym: developers.
Rym: go log into a QA system to examine some.
Scott: Yeah It's like who gives a shit if it's not super secure.
Rym: What you definitely don't want developers also doing QA because if you know they should be doing they should not be doing the QA.
Scott: Like developer it's okay for the developer about the access of systems and information.
Rym: Developer can write a unit test for their code as long as QA writes their own unit test for the same code.
Rym: If you're doing unit tests, I mean there's different kinds of development, right?
Scott: But that's you know, but the point is the.
Scott: the only thing you need no matter what is that production not production barrier?
Rym: And you only need that second QA dev Barrier if your business is super serious or if you just make any amount of money because as soon as you make amount of money You probably want to have that extra make a ton of money.
Scott: It's super serious Isn't it?
Rym: to cover your ass?
Rym: because the really is this company fucked up and it is literally like it is the fault of the CTO 100% that this company fucked up.
Rym: Yeah, I wish I knew what company it was.
Rym: Yeah, that'd be really funny to find.
Rym: I'm sure I could find out.
Scott: it's probably not somebody's big Could be.
Rym: I've seen big fuck-ups at big companies before.
Scott: I can't imagine it would be somebody's big.
Scott: It has like just one production database only that could be deleted.
Rym: Ah, I've seen some shit.
Scott: How big could it be?
Scott: I and if all the websites we go to are still working so it wasn't any of them True slash shots up Right now, right.
Rym: It's no it's not places where there's running as far as I know right now.
Rym: Yeah but yeah, the moral of all this separation of duties and That developer is not the problem at that company.
Rym: If you think that that developer is at fault for this nobody.
Scott: nobody thinks that it's just a funny story because that someone actually Supposedly this actually really happened and they posted this story Literally everywhere on the internet and because everyone was like, oh my god that company so bad.
Scott: It's spread like wildfire.
Rym: That company is so bad It's so.
Rym: it's one thing if you have a company that plays fast and loose cuz we know we could think of it this way.
Rym: The more strict you are about that stuff the more money and time it takes to do anything Mm-hmm, but if you're fast and loose with that stuff, you can get product out a lot faster and then also crash and burn From one guy.
Scott: mess it up.
Rym: a big part of you know, corporate qualitative risk analysis Which I alluded to at the beginning isn't necessarily controlling for all that stuff.
Rym: It's just understanding the risks of playing fast and loose and the risks of being more, you know more formal in that stuff and Deciding what level of risk you as a company are willing to accept.
Rym: if you're making the next Twitter cowboy it up who gives a fuck?
Rym: But at the same time this company fucked up so bad that they were cowboying but they didn't even have a backup horse.
Rym: No, like they didn't have a horse in the stable like even like halfway ready to go.
Rym: They didn't even have like a backup of their production database.
Scott: They want a vacation with one pair underwear than the chef and the shat in it.
Rym: Haha, I went to anime Boston once I only I forgot to pack socks.
Rym: So I had one pair of socks for the whole weekend and I washed them in the sink every day.
Scott: I I got a thing of the day coming up.
Scott: That's poop related.
Rym: Oh I have an anecdote that is poop related from the race that I'll save for the next show.
Rym: So the you're the porta-potty though that was right, okay I know.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: I have never in my life seen a porta-potty disaster on that scale in person.
Scott: We're good.
Rym: Now That happens during marathons a lot which is a big part of why I don't run marathons.
Rym: Yeah, 5k is like 20 minute like a 5k is 30 minutes Even if you're like not that fit a 5k is an hour if you don't exercise at all.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of getting ice are Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: mystati.com.
Rym: William Eisner as Jeremy minor.
Rym: That when a girl walks in with an itty-bitty waist and a round thing a genuine.
Rym: but if I'd like to ride six car monorail Ronsi Ron civils Rebecca Dunn the terrible secret of space 421 creations.
Rym: as far as I can tell it's just a box canyon in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: Sherman Van Horl rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona super boy.
Rym: I paid five bucks.
Rym: make room say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar topic and Joshua Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton renter New Zealand Ryan Perrin mr.
Rym: Black Brian said Roni Finn Christmas gift Chris Knox Taylor Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and now I leave you with.