Rym: It's Thursday, June 22nd 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We'll see how this goes.
Rym: We're talking about predicaments.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So work today.
Scott: I go to pee like you do.
Scott: Yeah, like you do and I go to the urinal.
Rym: I feel like three times a day at work.
Scott: Yeah, I feel a lot of work as they drink too much water.
Rym: In fact the more I'm working the more water I drink.
Scott: like if I'm working hard I'm just like chugging water anyway, so You know, it's one of those urinals that has a tiny pool of water at the bottom.
Scott: you know, not that not the kind with the disc or the the waterless kind like they do right and Sometimes people don't flush fully or the flusher is kind of like the flusher.
Scott: on this one You have to sort of push it down really hard and hold it.
Scott: Yeah, if you just sort of bump it once it goes like and it doesn't flush So quite often when you go in the water will be yellow, which is really not a big deal.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I don't really care.
Scott: You know, it happens to everyone.
Scott: I'm super paranoid though, like whenever I'm in a public bathroom of any kind, especially the work one I always like, you know get up before I leave the stall or walk away from the toilet.
Scott: I look at it to make sure it's completely flushed.
Scott: Yeah, then after I wash my hands I got I almost had to double-check and Occasionally like I'll leave the stall wash my hands and someone will be in the stall now and I can't check.
Scott: Oh, no, did that person just see my poop?
Rym: But anyway, I'd be almost proud of it if they saw it be like, all right, you saw my mighty works.
Rym: I'm just very mighty upon my work.
Scott: I'm just paranoid about being and despair.
Scott: I know that I don't flush.
Scott: Oh, no Don't flush even though I'm super paranoid about flushing all the time.
Scott: Anyway, so
Rym: I watched a dude not flush and not wash his hands and walk the fuck out and he works on my floor Not in my company though some other company
Scott: Saying if he were if
Rym: My company
Scott: if I was a boss and someone did that I talked to him once I'd say wash your goddamn hands.
Scott: I mean if I saw him do it again fired, I would do something different.
Scott: It was not a restaurant.
Rym: I would just send it.
Rym: if it was a restaurant fired immediately I would just send an email to team and be like guess who doesn't fucking wash his hands.
Scott: That's part of it.
Scott: Yeah anyway.
Scott: So I go and you know the waters yellow, which is a big deal.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I don't know whose water Is.
Scott: let it mellow it's there I'll flush it and then I'll pee and then I'll Why flush NP?
Rym: Why not pee then flush?
Rym: It's not gonna get on you.
Scott: I'm gonna tell you why.
Scott: Obviously, it's not likely to get on me But there is the chance I can see.
Rym: that I can see.
Scott: well, even if it was just normal tea.
Rym: Wait, did it get on you?
Scott: No, okay, I flushed and then I peed.
Scott: Where the story's going the color of this P now I Know eating various foods.
Scott: Yeah, right and I've seen red pee because someone's got a problem, right?
Scott: They can go to the hospital probably if you got red.
Rym: a friend of ours who was on chemo Like her pee was basically bright pink during all of that.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen.
Scott: I've seen.
Rym: I show just did an episode on what different colors of pee mean.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen a blue pee even in my life, right?
Rym: I peed a weird.
Rym: I was on a weird antibiotic once and my pee was like Bright green to the point that I called the doctor and I was like yo and he was like, yeah Yeah, I should have warned you
Scott: this P was a color I had not seen in my 35 years of life.
Rym: What's the?
Rym: what's the Xcode for it?
Scott: So it was yellow and you might be saying well yellow But that's like the color piece supposed to be the least surprising pee color.
Scott: Yeah, right No, it was yellow like a fucking yellow highlighter.
Scott: I thought whoa, somebody just dropped a highlighter in there.
Scott: I was like, is that even pee?
Scott: I thought maybe it was some kind of cleaning chemical.
Rym: Maybe maybe the company we're gonna talk about in the news.
Scott: I thought it like maybe wasn't pee like it was a cleaning chemical or something.
Scott: and and I would just like flush this away.
Scott: I flush it and it's still there.
Scott: It's probably some thing they installed in the toilet right to put this chemical in there, but no it went away.
Scott: Someone's pee was highlighter fucking yellow.
Rym: I'm like, maybe they ate a highlighter.
Scott: I don't know what it wasn't.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know how it was that way.
Scott: It was in a urinal.
Scott: It wasn't like someone dropped something in a sit-down.
Scott: What is up with that?
Scott: like what that's?
Rym: that's pretty that's good.
Scott: is that explained in your little video there.
Scott: highlighter yellow pee.
Rym: I haven't actually watched this yet.
Rym: It's in my queue of videos to watch.
Rym: It's a recent upload.
Scott: Well, watch it.
Rym: Okay, so look, I don't know who it was.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Look I can see they talk about Orange red red blood.
Scott: Yeah, it's bad news, uh green yeah, we've talked about green.
Scott: hang we talked about that green again blue I told you we talked about blue.
Rym: Yep, a Purple urine bag syndrome.
Scott: I've never heard of that.
Scott: my fuck.
Rym: This is a long article some sort of off-white.
Scott: I mean, I have clear pee a lot black.
Scott: Oh god, you'd squid ink.
Scott: I don't know black.
Rym: I guess I just got if I file.
Scott: if maybe your bile from your poop lines leaks into you.
Rym: if I pee and it's black I literally just without calling anyone or saying a word.
Rym: I just go straight to a hospital.
Scott: I call 9-1-1 while I'm walking to the.
Rym: I just go straight to a hospital and be like take a picture.
Rym: I would go straight to the hospital and be like Deal with this.
Scott: I peed black Not highlighter yellow a.
Rym: I didn't see a highlighter yellow in there anywhere.
Scott: Like I should have taken a picture because it was maybe that bright one there.
Scott: That looks more green.
Scott: Yeah Well, oh maybe though could be cool.
Rym: It's the brights.
Rym: the motion you get highlighter.
Scott: yellow starts to become neon green eventually.
Scott: Yeah, you go along the spectrum there, but I don't know if chemicals work.
Rym: I'll watch this video tonight because it's literally in my like.
Rym: you have YouTube videos to watch.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I don't you know, I don't watch these immediately.
Rym: Let all my subscriptions queue up.
Scott: that was the most surprising thing that happened.
Rym: today was seeing high letter yellow P In the office, darling, so you might have noticed that the other night two nights ago We did the show and you know I stream most of GeekNights and I didn't stream that episode like a tweet in stream most episodes.
Rym: We started streaming almost every episode because it's like real easy to do.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Uh, the reason I didn't stream Is that we were trying to start the show and every time I launched audition OBS would crash Mm-hmm or hang and every time I launched OBS Audition would hang.
Scott: just use X split or whatever.
Rym: X split would also have hung.
Rym: So interesting.
Rym: I knew that.
Rym: so here's the deal I learned.
Rym: I like figured out exactly what's going on and it's because OBS is doing something didn't expect.
Rym: So if you have for real audio hardware, like you're muxing a giant like audio interface You'll won't use MME.
Rym: the windows like multimedia, whatever.
Rym: MME is the thing that windows does.
Rym: that for the love of God.
Rym: Why can't Linux just do this?
Rym: Where if you have like ten sound cards, which you might not think you have a lot of sound cards But in the modern era you actually have a lot of sound cards Don't realize it?
Rym: every monitor that takes HDMI is a sound card technically.
Rym: Yep, every headphone that you plug in with USB.
Rym: That's a sound card.
Rym: Your motherboard probably is a sound card.
Rym: You even know about if there's like an audio jack in there.
Rym: There might be two.
Rym: MME just makes all those work all at the same time, but you can't record from all of them at the same time.
Rym: There's all these issues.
Rym: one you pick the one that you're recording bag.
Scott: You can only play to one at the same time.
Scott: Yeah Unless you install some bullshit software that's all those by default only plays to one and records to one and all the other ones are Just off.
Rym: and if you do if you do if you install weird you can record from one and play on a different one.
Scott: Yeah You just can't have two of them recording at the same time or two of them playing it.
Rym: You might be able to have two different pieces of software that don't interact working with two different sound cards.
Rym: that could happen.
Scott: Oh, you can do that.
Scott: Yeah, you can have one piece that you can have iTunes play sound on one and YouTube play sound on Another.
Rym: yep, like my rig right my my streaming thing or my my headset.
Rym: I have Overwatch.
Rym: like audio will come in one interface to it, but the voice chat comes into another one.
Rym: Like you can do the stuff like you just can't like play a song in iTunes and have it play out of like five Different speaker, but if you have pro audio equipment, I can totally do that.
Rym: I can route audio all over the fuck place.
Scott: Especially the hardware outside of your computer can do it too, right?
Scott: So send the audio out of your computer into another device.
Scott: that device can plug in a million.
Scott: Whatever is Windows remember in the old days.
Rym: We used to get guests on GeekNights.
Rym: I did not have the like kind of mixer that I have today.
Rym: back then The way we did that is by having all these different sound cards like Skype little computer.
Rym: Skype was using one sound card on one computer and like Skype - is using a different sound card on another computer And I like analog mixed all that shit together.
Rym: Anyway, if you have for real audio hardware, you won't use MME.
Rym: you use something called ASIO.
Rym: Yep, if you're if you want to fuck shit up you use was API which is like bootleg ghetto windows.
Rym: shit ASIO don't use it.
Rym: Remember that time when I needed help in MATLAB to fix an episode of GeekNights?
Rym: That was because I was happy.
Rym: don't use was happy ever.
Rym: anyway ASIO lets you do magic But it has one very specific limitation only one piece of software can in a sense subscribe to any given specific channel of audio.
Rym: So audition right now is recording the raw Output from channel one of the mixer which is me and the raw output of channel two of the mixer Which is Scott and that is independent of the faders.
Rym: I move the faders around.
Rym: that'll mess with the stream, but it won't actually mess with what's recorded.
Rym: The recording is raw because I don't want anything.
Rym: nothing I do live should affect the raw recording cuz I do everything in post kind of like how if Scott's recording video He doesn't want to like do digital zooms or effects in camera He's gonna do that shit in post.
Rym: don't ruin your actual like source material.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I set up an advanced war stream and I happen to set it up to record a raw channel.
Rym: The OBS stream I do GeekNights on is actually recording the main mix that is affected by the faders because it's going through the compressor.
Rym: So I have a live effect.
Rym: So that is also compressed.
Rym: Otherwise, it'd be like the audio would be all over the place.
Rym: It'd be hard for you to listen to in the streaming.
Rym: That's why it sounds good.
Rym: Ah OBS apparently if you define any audio source, even if it's not being used in X split I checked seems to do the same thing.
Rym: So don't say like Oh exploit would fix this.
Rym: Even though I was not using that like that set up I wasn't recording or anything because it was configured.
Rym: OBS subscribes to every single audio source.
Rym: It knows about mm-hmm.
Rym: So it subscribed to a source that was also in my audition thing.
Rym: So they would both hang each other.
Rym: Why do they hang each other?
Rym: because ASIO drivers are super finicky because they're only used in like super pro set up.
Scott: Yeah, wouldn't you write in the code of OBS or in the code of audition?
Scott: Like if cannot subscribe.
Scott: Fail gracefully put up a message about not being able to subscribe.
Scott: don't crash.
Rym: you'd think that You would really think that now audition will depending on how it fails.
Rym: because the problem is it can actually fail in a bunch of different ways and the real problem is that The ASIO drivers are highly hardware specific.
Rym: So I have specific drivers for this exact hardware and I also have specific drivers for my exact firewire and that shits all old.
Rym: It isn't being updated that much thus.
Rym: It just sort of hangs.
Rym: the moral is bugs No matter how weird and obscure or difficult to troubleshoot can always be troubleshooted by using basic troubleshooting techniques.
Rym: I'd looked at what was different between the last time I streamed in that time And the only thing that was different was I made it advanced for a stream.
Rym: So that was how I was able to troubleshoot that.
Rym: and now we're streaming the show again, whatever.
Rym: that is also why Scott is occasionally silent in the very beginning of the show because I usually haven't muted in the main mix because I'm not using that microphone all the time.
Rym: So anyway, you got some news.
Scott: What was my news?
Scott: All right, so You know, we talked about Star Wars a bunch because there's a lot more Star Wars now than there's ever been.
Scott: Yeah, every year we're gonna get some Star Wars.
Scott: It's a Star Wars bonanza every single year.
Scott: There's gonna be a Star Wars in one of the upcoming years.
Scott: I think maybe next year, right?
Scott: Because this year is this year's gonna be episode eight eight Yes, eight eight.
Rym: It's weird that like until before the new Star Wars came I could immediately say exactly which number but now I got to count up Because there's so many and it's weird.
Rym: Next year is gonna be Han Solo Han Solo, which because of how good rogue squadron, not rogue squadron, Rogue One was I was really looking forward to the Han Solo movie.
Scott: I mean, I'm just I'm like young.
Rym: Lando Calrissian just signed me the fuck up, right?
Scott: I mean, I wasn't like super looking forward to it.
Scott: It wasn't like on my hype list, but like I was definitely gonna go right to the theater and see it.
Scott: Yeah, see me some Han Solo.
Rym: I'm pretty much going to all these Star Wars movies.
Scott: Give me the full-on Wookie action, right?
Scott: So, you know, it was.
Scott: it was definitely something I was gonna go do a nerdy thing.
Scott: That was uh, you know gonna happen at some point, but yep Apparently it's got some drama some pretty surprising drama, right?
Scott: Like I didn't see this coming.
Scott: I'd like they were just rolling right along Disney with all these other.
Scott: You know Star Wars movies.
Scott: just putting them out, you know, none of them have been bad since the prequel movies, right?
Scott: So just rolling along it seemed like everything was going great.
Scott: They got tons of money and they're profiting.
Rym: You didn't see a lot of like Hollywood drama coming out of the productions, right?
Scott: Suddenly we get this news that over creative differences who know what creative differences there could be at a Han Solo movie between two Directors you make a badass Han Solo who goes around space.
Rym: Han soloing you make it even more badass Lando Calrissian.
Scott: Who's just there fucking shit up making you wish it was a Lando Calrissian movie.
Rym: I I feel like you know what they need.
Rym: and then if we make sure Shubaka gets most of the screen time I want them to make a show like far like 13 episodes.
Rym: It's just Lando.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: Just call it Lando.
Rym: That's exactly you call it Lando.
Scott: Colin works every time But you The directors had some directors.
Scott: there were two of them the Lord and Chris Miller.
Scott: I guess we're let go.
Rym: they had from the movie.
Scott: How could you have creative differences over a Han Solo movie and yeah.
Scott: and then they bring in what.
Rym: maybe what if the only thing I can think of is one of them is Han shot and is a stone-cold fucking killer and the other one is like Lucas style Han Solo reboot?
Scott: No I get the feeling was differences but like I feel like the two of them agreed and then but the two of them Disagreed with Disney somehow why?
Rym: so I have the exact quote here.
Rym: I found a more recent article.
Scott: Oh the move comes two days.
Rym: So the move is.
Scott: they hired a third new director Ron Howard Which is a famous person that I. I know the name of this famous person.
Scott: I know they're a famous Hollywood person if you're only not until we did research before the show.
Scott: Could I have told you anything about him?
Rym: I know he's a really wood person.
Rym: What I'm curious how many of you know him as fucking Opie from the Andy Griffiths.
Scott: Probably everyone.
Rym: We just don't know about Hollywood, but as an aside the Andy Griffiths the show is super legit And if you've never seen it It's a. it's a really good show like.
Rym: it's a really good sitcom and he played the kid But anyway, so he has been tapped to take over the direction, which is good because he's a well-known good director.
Rym: fine After directors Phil Lord and Chris Miller were let go from the movie so they didn't quit.
Rym: they were fucking fired.
Rym: They had spent four and a half months directing.
Rym: they've already filmed a whole bunch of shit - right creative differences over style and Tone came to a head between them and a separate person Lawrence Kasdan.
Rym: I have no idea who that is Disney executive who has the studio backing and screenwriter or something.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So yeah, there's a whole bunch of follow-up drama that I don't know about.
Scott: I mean the thing that you would guess would just be that one of the parties wanted sort of like a light Adventure fun time and the other person wanted a more serious badass kind of time.
Scott: I could see that there were like a 60s Batman versus a night, you know 80s 90s back.
Scott: You know what the problem is.
Scott: Yeah, I don't give a shit either.
Scott: one of those.
Rym: so both in the same movie for all I care It should be both in the same movie have a roller coaster tone Like it's silly and campy, but then hon just fucking murders a guy.
Scott: That's how the original Star Wars was.
Scott: It's super It's campy, but he also just fucking murders a guy.
Scott: It's both at the same time and that's what it should be.
Scott: So if they're fighting if they're having that fight, which is just a guess who knows what the fight was, right?
Scott: If that's the fight they're having they're both wrong.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't care who is gonna.
Scott: here we go.
Rym: Howard is considered a safe choice to complete the task.
Rym: Sure, someone who will ably finish the movie while being a calming presence on sets.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Rym: So basically the kids had a fight so they hired and a famous adult to come in and be like, alright We're gonna go buy the book.
Rym: So I feel like my worry is I feel like the movie will be competent now But won't push any envelopes that it might have pushed with a more maverick team.
Scott: I think it'll also be weird and that so much of the movies already been made.
Scott: How much can they get it to you know?
Scott: Not be awkward like having a scene that was shot with one mood trying to make a different mood.
Scott: But then again, we have things like shining the feel-good movie trailer.
Scott: So the power of editing is vast.
Scott: Also, I'm sure they can do it.
Rym: they got Disney movie they can just reshoot and Ron Howard has enough gravitas to be like.
Rym: Nope, you're doing it this way.
Rym: We're throwing out everything you film in certain.
Rym: Oh, you could totally do whatever he wants.
Scott: I'll make the money back.
Scott: I'm sure.
Scott: Yeah, they could just put Someone who looks like Han Solo on screen and have a little you know Plastic Millennium Falcon toy move back and forth and then someone makes some Chewbacca noises here.
Scott: I would pay ten bucks to see it.
Rym: I'm still gonna go see it day one The only things that would cause me.
Scott: maybe not day one but day early.
Rym: I'll go see it like one of the one of the earliest days week one.
Rym: Yeah, cuz day one I'm not doing midnight showings anymore.
Scott: Definitely one of the earlier.
Rym: I'll do like the Friday after work like the week it comes out.
Scott: Yeah, if it depends if it's a Christmas one or a different part of the May 25th, I think yeah I'll just go see it like the week of.
Rym: yeah, but I will not go see it right away.
Rym: if Ron Howard also quits Cuz that means shit went down It's.
Scott: I guess that's just the biggest nerd news there is.
Rym: or if Lando isn't in it.
Scott: So we had to say something about if Lando or Chewbacca in it.
Scott: They're in it.
Rym: Yeah, so unless Ron Howard gets fired I feel like we're just still gonna go see this.
Scott: Why wouldn't we we'd go see it even if everyone was fired and they started over.
Rym: Yeah So there's a news here and I didn't see this picture until someone sent it to me in a in a chat where we talked About all the scary politics that would scare a lot of you if we talked about it on Twitter.
Rym: So anyway I'm looking at the picture right now.
Rym: So if you're watching the live stream, you can see it.
Rym: This picture is actually like Super super fucking terrifying if you know what it's a picture of.
Rym: Mm-hmm because it is a picture of four cylinders of plutonium.
Scott: Plutonium just looks like metal by the way.
Rym: Plutonium is a metal unless you like.
Rym: there are salts of it.
Rym: There are chemicals of its radioactive.
Scott: So it goes away slowly, but it's not that fast.
Rym: It's not like it just disappears while you're looking at it, but not to get too deep into How that what the scary thing about this picture is.
Rym: But if you really want to know because I know nuclear weapons and nuclear stuff is kind of a slightly more scary thing Today than it might have been say before the election last year Not a lot of big scary thing but like one step
Scott: scary scares people more than it should because of history and also Science fiction.
Rym: Yeah books and movies and but if you want to know why this is scary Google for the Wikipedia article or the Wikipedia page about something called the demon core because basically there's a concept of Criticality.
Rym: if you have a nuclear material like plutonium or enriched uranium and you have too much of it in a small enough space Yeah, it's radioactive, but it's not gonna nuke.
Rym: It's just radioactive.
Rym: Like it's not great to hang out around it No, but it's just radioactive.
Scott: right if you put too much bananas radioactive.
Scott: It's like sitting in a banana warehouse.
Rym: Yeah The Yiga clan yes, maybe that's why they're all weird.
Rym: Yes But if you put too much of this material in a in the wrong shape too close to itself There is a critical mass of the components like of this element and fission occurs.
Rym: Yes, such that fission occurs and fission occurs in less than a second less than a millisecond.
Rym: So you'll have a material that is not great to hang around but totally okay.
Scott: Like you can stand there and be fine You can wear like a lead armor or have a shield like between you and it or whatever.
Rym: but the terrifying thing is that these are sitting here and they're Cylinders.
Rym: if someone bumped to this table and this one in the middle Rolled a little bit to the left and touch this other one you would get what is called a criticality excursion.
Rym: That means that in a flash in a fraction of a second everyone standing there would be dead.
Rym: Every single person in that room is Is it is already dead?
Rym: They will actually die in a week or two, but there is no radiation poisoning.
Rym: Yes, they are dead.
Scott: Even if they're wearing all sorts of nice anti radioactive armors and shields.
Scott: It's too much radiation.
Scott: They're dead.
Rym: whoever took this picture is very lucky to be alive and should never be anywhere near nuclear material again ever.
Scott: And Why not take a picture of just one plutonium?
Scott: Why do you have to take a picture of four plutonium's?
Scott: Why not just one?
Scott: the picture of one isn't good enough.
Rym: Did you did you not know?
Rym: Like did you just not like how?
Scott: and you you're a photographer?
Scott: You don't anything about your excuse for knowing anything about radiation, right?
Scott: But you're in a place where they're keeping plutonium's where the most expert people are.
Rym: Shouldn't they not give you yes Oh Scott the demon core the reason I'd linked it I'm talking about that is because a lot of the times this happened probably the most pain.
Rym: There's one core that killed a bunch of people.
Rym: We eventually used it in a nuke Mm-hmm, I think they use it.
Rym: But anyway, one of the testing ones an island somewhere Uh, so not on an island on land.
Rym: But the way this killed some people was that they had it the two halves of it.
Rym: They were like holding them together and they were holding them apart with a flathead screwdriver that they were just holding in the middle to Keep them from touching.
Scott: So they're like too close.
Rym: It's like a Pac Man, but it's fine That's.
Rym: how does the tolerance are?
Rym: it's like a Pac Man, but they have a screwdriver Just holding the two apart while they're fucking with it.
Rym: Someone slips someone slipped and the screwdriver fell out dead.
Rym: That was the end.
Rym: Yep, those people knew more about nuclear material than most people on earth do today.
Rym: Then these were the experts of the world and they were fucking holding them with a screwdriver.
Scott: Why not make some sort of like mold that you put them in so that they're like a little wall, but you know Yeah, so it's gone.
Rym: So the way they have people actually work with this stuff.
Rym: They do have controls like that.
Rym: Someone just went and got all this shit and put it out on a table and said hey look And the story is all these safety lapses.
Rym: Los Alamos appears to be a shit show of nuclear safety today.
Scott: You think that's like the number one place?
Scott: Shouldn't it be?
Rym: it probably is the number one place.
Scott: It'd be the least shit show.
Rym: nuclear weapons are terrifying and the reality is that the u.s Actually critically under funds and under like trains the people who do this stuff.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and you can.
Rym: we're not news We're just commentary.
Rym: you can read these.
Rym: if you're scared of this stuff Don't read these articles.
Rym: if you're interested in it read these articles.
Rym: But mostly I just want an excuse to talk about this picture because just loves talking about anything nucleated Holy shit, though this picture.
Rym: like I I cannot get over this.
Scott: Well, they're not screwdriver closed.
Scott: They're like screwdrivers apart.
Rym: So that nobody died.
Rym: Nobody sneezed and bumped the table, I guess.
Rym: And I guess the only other news we'll talk about before we get into the predicament Is that we try not to talk about politics too deeply on the show.
Rym: I'm a politics now so the Republican Party in the US actually released the text of their health care bill and It is a monstrous like literal murder bill.
Rym: like it would literally ruin health care in America.
Rym: So I'm not gonna get into it.
Rym: All I'm gonna say is that if you live in America and you live in a state that has even one Republican senator Call them and swear at like.
Rym: call them and scream at them like call them and scare them.
Rym: I like I live in a state where there's no one I can call.
Rym: There's nothing I can do about this.
Scott: My representatives are the best representatives like there's no.
Scott: what like you couldn't if I get someone?
Rym: my senators said that she like both my senators said that they will try to Grind the Senate to a halt to stop.
Scott: I don't even have the kind of Democrats representing me that are like the centrist kind Like they're all the lefty guy and that like I'm like, oh run for no cuz I don't want to replace this person.
Rym: I called my.
Rym: I don't want to move.
Rym: I called my state senator about a single pair and they were like, dude I fucking signed it.
Rym: I'm a sponsor.
Scott: my guy is like whenever there's a news like so-and-so in New York pushing for whatever.
Scott: It's always my guy.
Scott: Well, I guess he's doing all.
Scott: I'm only bringing this up better at it than me.
Rym: There's a lot of you out there Like we have a. really we have a decent number of fans.
Rym: if you just happen to live in a state that has a Republican Center move.
Rym: Well, yeah move but before you move call them like as I call them every once a day and swear at them Like I'm not even joking.
Rym: You've got to make them scared that people in their state might actually do something.
Rym: That's all.
Scott: they don't give a shit.
Scott: They might because the only thing they only share the rich people column.
Scott: No, they're scared.
Rym: or if the people who actually vote get actually somehow angry which rarely happens.
Rym: Thank you, man.
Rym: I get mad.
Scott: Don't get mad.
Scott: No one's getting mad red circus.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Scott: what he got Right, so a long time ago I did a thing of the day where this guy goes to like the dollar store and buys like the most garbage like $1.00 kitchen knife.
Scott: right but is an expert at knife sharpening Which means he actually knows how to use a whetstone which you know, I also sort of know the theory But I don't have the practice.
Rym: I'm not good.
Rym: I'm not even that good at home.
Scott: I've never actually done it right but I try to hone stuff and I'm not like I Feel like I should buy like $3.
Scott: if I really wanted to get into it.
Scott: I should buy like three $1 knives and the stones.
Scott: but it's like I already do enough shit But I just pay.
Scott: so paying someone to sharpen knives.
Scott: They charge like a few dollars.
Scott: It's not worth it to do it yourself unless you're way into it or you do it a lot.
Scott: Anyway, but so that guy sharpened that $1 knife to.
Scott: it was crazy sharp.
Scott: He was cutting paper and stuff.
Scott: It was awesome.
Scott: Right, he's back at it again.
Rym: He back at it again in the Krispy Kreme.
Scott: He was in some kind of.
Scott: he tells the story in the video.
Scott: But he was at some kind of store.
Scott: and some poor guy Comes in trying to sell this old rusty knife to the store and the store was like no We're not even to give you like 30 cents for that.
Scott: I guess it was in yen.
Scott: So convert whatever.
Scott: but then he goes to the guy and he's like, oh, I'll buy that from you.
Scott: and the guy's like Oh, really three dollars.
Scott: Yeah, and he's like fine You know paid three dollars, right?
Scott: But this knife while it starts out all rusty is actually a hella nice fucking knife and he sharpens and shines that shit Like oh baby, this is so good.
Scott: I just love seeing people restore a busted thing to Being awesome thing Again, it's just so.
Scott: if only we could do that with like busted old subway.
Scott: Yeah Right.
Scott: We should get this guy working on the subway.
Scott: Yeah Take his whetstone onto the rails and clean.
Rym: So I got two things today, but they're deeply related.
Rym: So You know in like old cartoons when Wile E. Coyote has like some dynamite that he's gonna blow up He has a big box with a tea stick on it and you push the tea down little plunger.
Rym: Yep So this is big lives of YouTube channel I follow anybody.
Rym: usually he takes dodgy Chinese electronics and takes it apart and explains exactly how it'll kill you but in this case he Explains in extreme detail how those old dynamite explode.
Rym: his work is back then.
Rym: Batteries did not have enough power if they even existed in a lot of places or enough reliability to be used for this And there wasn't like power like you couldn't plug in anything.
Rym: This is like Wild West times.
Rym: So he explains in extreme detail how those old dynamite blasters worked.
Rym: And then in case you're wondering how they do it today It's not that different.
Rym: and there's another video he has that shows a modern Abra dynamite Exploder and apparently in the industry.
Rym: I didn't know a lot about these things.
Rym: They're just called Dynamite exploders.
Rym: modern ones don't have plungers Nope They have cranks and buttons and they do not take power and they do not have batteries.
Rym: and they work almost the same way Just with more safety, I guess dynamite does not require power to explode.
Rym: It requires very little the blasting caps, but essentially this is videos fascinating.
Rym: the first one is okay because you learn how this old technology works, but this dynamite exploder is cool because it seems very retro and like very minimalist and simple and almost weirdly archaic.
Rym: and Yet this is how it's done today Because these old systems and these old methods are hyper reliable.
Rym: They have no requirements.
Rym: They don't need batteries.
Rym: They don't need power.
Rym: They need dynamite.
Rym: They yeah you need dynamite.
Rym: if you got dynamite you need the wires to connect to the dynamite and you got some wires and you got a Dynamite exploder and you got blasting caps.
Rym: you can make dynamite explode.
Scott: you need things.
Rym: how this thing works is Fascinating.
Rym: how durable this thing is is ridiculous and I had to look up what a thyristor has to be able to you know Not get destroyed if the dynamite it also has to work in a mine and mines are not the most comfortable places.
Scott: Yeah, the big rock falls on it.
Scott: It still needs to work and also not accidentally blow up all the dynamite if a rock falls on it.
Rym: And also you'll learn what a thyristor is which I literally had to look up because I did not know.
Rym: In the moment the booklet book is Frank Herbert's do I read a whole bunch.
Scott: I finished the.
Scott: the first.
Scott: we're reading Dune book one Yeah, which actually has like it has like.
Scott: each chapter isn't that long but there's like three sort of Parts, so it's like book one book two and book three are all in that first volume.
Scott: So I finished the first one.
Rym: I mean, I'm doing the second one now I'm gonna read the whole thing because I'm going to London next week.
Rym: So I'm pretty much gonna read the whole thing on my trip.
Scott: It's bait that board game is so accurate.
Scott: Yeah, it's ridiculous.
Scott: I didn't realize how accurate that board game was.
Scott: They literally turned the book directly into that board game.
Rym: It's kind of amazing that you can have an IP in a game that so closely matches the source material in both theme and Substance.
Scott: it's great.
Scott: And like the the final thing that is in the game that wasn't in the book yet just happened.
Scott: It was a nexus in the book just now.
Rym: No Also this weekend Emily will be there.
Rym: a bunch of our friends will be there.
Rym: a bunch of our friends are speaking there.
Scott: I might go there.
Rym: Joe foo, you might you know, uh, the visual novels like the people I work with outside Before.
Rym: yeah, Joe foo is gonna be giving a talk.
Rym: So is cat small who is fucking amazing.
Scott: She's running the thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah and Game devs of color Expo is Saturday in New York City in Harlem.
Rym: It's totally cheap.
Scott: It's $20.
Scott: It's $20 a day of gaming talks like serious game.
Scott: Are you gonna get a bargain like that ever?
Rym: and if you're poor like you can't afford 20 bucks They'll help you out to like seriously.
Rym: go to their website and check them out.
Scott: I'm sure you sure anyone who can listen to a podcast has $20.
Rym: Yeah, but if you if you don't for whatever reason they pointedly have will help you get into this thing Mmm, and this is gonna be pretty cool.
Rym: Also, it's coming up in a few weeks Kinetic.
Rym: on ConnectiCon 15 is July 7 through 9. the website says 6 through 9 But on the 6th, all you can do is pick up your badges.
Scott: We still run the panels department there.
Rym: I guess I scheduled I guess Scott's in charge of like all our like day of logistics and operations in the panels department.
Scott: It's we don't have a lot of staff this year.
Scott: So I'm just scheduling everyone for the whole con.
Scott: Yeah I'm gonna let everyone punch in at the beginning and punch out at the end to Ease difficulty or worrying about shifts, but people just take breaks whenever.
Rym: but seriously Like don't fly to Connecticut to go to Connecticut.
Scott: But if you live within like a couple hour drive if you can drive today ConnectiCon or take some other kind of transportation to Hartford easily it is worth going to.
Scott: I don't know It's worth paying for it depends, but it's definitely worth going to.
Scott: if you're a nerd who cares about anime Yeah, or gaming or any other kind of game doing its tabletop area is better than most tabletop cons like straight up.
Rym: And it's that that departments run by people kind of like how we run panels.
Scott: the same deal Even if you just want to have like one.
Scott: it's really good.
Scott: if you just want like one day of nerdery Right, just go and you know, check out the guest list Maybe the someone your way into because basically where other cons will have like a few top-tier people's ConnectiCon you tends to get a ton of mid-tier people's right like people are on TV and people who write books like people you care about but like you might not know that you care about them.
Scott: until you look at the list of guests you're Whoa, I actually sort of want to.
Scott: oh man, wouldn't it be cool to see all these people?
Scott: and that is.
Rym: So we'll be doing some shows here.
Rym: We're doing like four panels and I guess I'm hosting the opening ceremony.
Rym: We'll find out how that all goes.
Scott: I Did not volunteer for that.
Scott: I was like, yeah, let's have uncle yo do it and otherwise subscribe to our stuff.
Rym: You know YouTube and all that and I think it's time for the predicament because I didn't have a good idea for show.
Rym: I Got the demon coral.
Rym: Let me move that out of the way.
Rym: I Did too.
Rym: they I think he might also do half of it.
Rym: I'm not sure I haven't really looked into that so much.
Rym: So, uh, I asked our patreon patrons because we talked.
Rym: I think we streamed it But we didn't record it in the show about this like predicament that I guess people on reddit.
Rym: We're talking about.
Rym: Okay, and the idea was like so you're in outer Brooklyn.
Scott: No.
Scott: No you live in Brooklyn.
Scott: Yeah, you're in Manhattan like at work or something or out on the street and you poop your pants.
Scott: What do you do?
Scott: and People are bit.
Scott: Well, it's like the answer was pretty much.
Scott: Well, you pooped your pants.
Scott: It's not gonna be good right no matter what happened.
Rym: What do you do?
Scott: What do you do?
Scott: is you go buy new pants you go find a Starbucks bathroom, whatever you throw your pants?
Rym: Oh, so I have a very specific go commando whatever start with that one because this is you know, this is very similar to the like.
Rym: How many five-year-olds could you fight off?
Rym: kind of question?
Rym: But the difference is these are more.
Rym: at least this was more like a very specific practical thing.
Rym: So I thought so I thought very specifically what I would do just in case you know good happen.
Rym: What I would first do is go to the nearest Starbucks and assess the damage in that bathroom.
Rym: I just get right.
Rym: in that bathroom I would sacrifice my underwear because I'm assuming they're a lost cause Mm-hmm, and I would clean myself up as best I could.
Rym: I would actually wash the inside of the pants in the sink as best I could and then I would go out to the nearest clothing store of any kind.
Rym: Buy pants buy underwear because you can buy underwear like every drugstore.
Rym: Go back to a different Starbucks because by then people might remember I was the guy who left a bunch of.
Rym: left a poop smell in the sink.
Rym: Wash myself again change everything throw the old pants away, and then I would take the subway home.
Scott: Just go home and then you know and never speak of it again.
Scott: Set your life.
Rym: I did have a situation in Australia where I Didn't poop my pants But I almost did cuz I ate some Mexican food in Manly and that Mexican food fucked me up real bad, and I was on a long hike in the woods so I pooped I cleaned up with the boxers I Buried them, and I never spoke of it again.
Rym: And that is what I did at manly.
Rym: so if you ever dig a hole somewhere in the woods in manly You might find my poopy boxers one time.
Scott: I was biking Down in like by the Obobo bridge.
Scott: Yes, I mean it was down there.
Scott: right I was in a woods but and I had to poop real bad, so I went into the woods a bit and I squatted and I pooped and Just after I got a
Rym: hope for the clean delivery
Scott: just after I finished pooping And I started to walk away some people were approaching and I ran.
Scott: yeah, but I'm pretty sure they saw that poop Because it was.
Scott: it was like it was like a pile But this is not the poop emoji.
Rym: so 11 patrons gave us predicaments.
Rym: I skimmed him But I did not read them in detail.
Rym: We'll blow through as many of these as we feel like and we'll see how this goes.
Rym: yeah I don't know how realistic these are.
Rym: I only read one just to kind of make sure they were Plausible.
Rym: there was a pretty good one about a ride at a hot.
Rym: you didn't scream this content But if they're bad, we'll read them out loud and shame the person.
Scott: well you can edit the show to move.
Rym: I'm not editing that.
Rym: so the first one.
Rym: I'll just go in order.
Rym: uh Is unattributed?
Rym: I'll just read it.
Rym: the both of you are trying to find a place to eat at PAX.
Rym: Okay, not determine the location.
Rym: you split off from your normal party, and you go down a street with a very distinct fog.
Rym: Alright, okay, as you emerge on the other side of the fog you hear a faint Foghorn and you look around only to notice that all the traffic is no longer on the road.
Rym: Your cell phones GPS doesn't find our location and every building is boarded.
Rym: Okay, so obviously we're in Silent Hill now, okay?
Rym: Looking back the way you came you see a cliff face with signs the state not to climb down.
Rym: So I guess there's a cliff there.
Rym: ahead of you is more fog But you can vaguely catch the outline of a person like objects.
Rym: well to your side you see two alleyways.
Rym: You're unable to determine where they ultimately end.
Rym: How do you get out of this situation?
Scott: I mean if I'm trapped in some haunted fantasy world it's gonna be pretty dangerous.
Scott: I'm probably gonna die anyway.
Rym: There's all.
Scott: I don't believe in that bullshit, so I just go to the person and be like yo where we at.
Rym: no No, see you back up.
Rym: There's there's.
Rym: there's a very small list of potential situation.
Scott: I could also be hallucinating which is even more likely so I should just sit down and take a nap in order.
Rym: I think here's the most likely scenarios.
Rym: It's number one.
Rym: I am dreaming Also good.
Rym: Yeah, so my first goal just to figure out if I am dreaming or not jump down the cliff.
Rym: No, don't jump down the cliff because what is?
Scott: you're not dreaming?
Scott: pinch yourself.
Rym: So I actually I just hope because I like the lucid dream.
Rym: I actually have a very specific process in my life.
Rym: if I ever end up in a situation that seems strange I look at my hands, and that's a trigger And then I just think can I trace back all the steps that led me to where I am now?
Rym: Because if I can't it's almost definitely a dream because dreams.
Rym: you're like in your grandma's house But there's a weird door and now you're in New York, and then you're flying like it doesn't make sense But in real life stuff makes sense if I can't determine that I'm dreaming like if it all makes sense.
Rym: number two I am hallucinating.
Rym: In which case try to do as little as possible because I don't know what my meat body is doing out in the non hallucinating world.
Scott: Yeah, sit down to where I sit down and wait.
Rym: If Scott's next to me, I ask him if he's seeing the same shit as I am Because maybe he said you're all alone now you got separate.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if we get completely separated Yeah, but if like Scott and I are together.
Rym: I'm like Scott am I hallucinating?
Rym: Are you hallucinating?
Rym: Did someone spike our water at the panel and we're both on LSD?
Rym: Scenario number three next most likely.
Rym: This is a crazy elaborate prank like Japanese game show style.
Rym: And fourth most likely magic is real, and this is magic nonsense.
Rym: So all I try to do is eliminate options one two and three as quickly as possible.
Rym: Because of magic's on the table then all bets are off.
Scott: start casting spells.
Rym: Yep I am.
Rym: that is Scott Johnson's go-to.
Rym: if you ever find a legit vampire or a real ghost you immediately Read like every magic spell you've ever heard of in your entire life Go to the borders and get yourself an economic on staff.
Rym: You just start wearing amulets.
Rym: You start looking for more vampires like spice of garlic.
Rym: All you got to find is one and it's game on.
Rym: So yeah, that's that's it after that.
Rym: It's all.
Rym: just choose your own adventure.
Scott: Yeah, that was lame next.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Thanks Alright, let's see.
Rym: How do I get to the next?
Scott: this is not my idea, but we don't have any other ideas for Thursday.
Scott: So you have no choice, but alright fall on this backup plan.
Rym: So a Canadian appropriate to this one.
Rym: This is the hockey that I skinned.
Scott: a Canadian Like a heavy time Canadian.
Scott: a Canadian person a Canadian person not a Canadian person from Canada.
Rym: Yep Game seven of the NHL Eastern Finals Rangers versus a new at New Jersey.
Rym: Okay triple overtime Victory for the Rangers on a clearly blown call by the refs that does not get overturned.
Scott: Oh, we'll take it.
Scott: I think we can get but I'll admit this bullshit.
Rym: our riot ensues throughout the arena a parking lot and City, all right, you both arrived in full Rangers attire by car.
Rym: You have a hundred and fifty dollars cash total Mm-hmm and your individual credit cards.
Rym: the bridge of a given starts in the front row behind the devil goaltender crap.
Rym: So we're like we're surrounded Surrounded by a gang of irrational angry drunk David putty like devil's fans and body pain.
Rym: Please get home.
Scott: They're not actually gonna mess with us.
Scott: We'll just go home.
Scott: So we walk to the car and drive away slowly.
Rym: It's a legit riot.
Rym: So like cars are being flipped over in the parking lot and in the entire city There's fight like the stands.
Rym: they're fighting and angry.
Scott: the train will take us home and we wouldn't even drive there.
Scott: We would definitely take the train.
Rym: So the crowd's angry.
Rym: What if they like attack us like people are attacking each other fights everywhere?
Rym: Run, okay, so we run we fight.
Rym: I guess forget on the train I guess by.
Rym: you know, you know now that I think about this.
Scott: riots aren't like as inescapable as you think.
Scott: It's like I've been at sporting events where they're like big brawls and stuff and it's like yeah You're just not.
Scott: if you're.
Rym: no, you know, make yourself a part of it.
Scott: You're not part of this.
Scott: Families at this game.
Scott: Well, you're older in right a city gonna be just fine - you just escape.
Rym: Well people like I mean I would.
Rym: so I was in a riot in a crowded hockey game and I almost got hit a couple Times you can get.
Scott: you can get hit like by you know, a stray bullet like, you know If there's some shooting that's unrelated to you, but I got hit like fists were coming and flying like they're right here.
Scott: You just get away from the hot zone.
Rym: So, yeah, so I think the city and the parking lot literally don't matter.
Rym: I actually I came up with a really good idea.
Rym: So one let's assume these drum thing.
Scott: You need a really good idea.
Scott: I don't think it's a bad situation.
Scott: So what?
Rym: so these these?
Rym: these quote irrational Surrounded by an irrational angry drunk David putty like devil's fans and body paint.
Rym: So there there are legit angry dudes who are trying to punch us.
Rym: So I guess we punch it back and run.
Rym: but all I would do is I would run and try to get into like the hallways and You know all those hallways like at any arena that you're not supposed to go into that there's usually like a person.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you could definitely be using emergency exits to get out, you know, I wouldn't try to get out.
Rym: I would try to get into all the hallways that like staff use Because the way those are not usually like blocked or locked like you can usually get into them But there's arena staff who will let you in.
Rym: if the arena staff are there and are in such control that they still won't let Me in I am safest by being right next to them.
Rym: That's all right.
Scott: There's also plenty of security at these things.
Rym: if the security is overwhelmed and they can't stop me from getting into those back hallways It's really really ridiculous.
Rym: I just run it is not it and I just wait.
Scott: There could not be that such a riot could not and you're it just couldn't be this.
Rym: I think it could.
Scott: this is even more ridiculous than the hallucinating.
Rym: A lot of people got like surrounded and attacked during like riots in LA and they couldn't get away.
Rym: Like what do you do?
Scott: That was a different kind of riot.
Rym: This road is this.
Rym: rides like that.
Rym: It's like legit off the hook.
Rym: be what it sounds like.
Rym: it is triple overtime.
Scott: in New Jersey Hockey arena is half full of businessmen and children.
Rym: Well, what if they're all crazy?
Rym: Stadium, all right.
Rym: What if same scenario but it was soccer.
Scott: I don't go there because that kind of thing can happen there if I won't do a soccer game like that.
Rym: If soccer if hockey fans were like soccer hooligans, I would not wear a Rangers jersey at that game.
Rym: I would actually wear a New Jersey Jersey to blend in.
Scott: I would not go to a place That was the soccer stadium where that sort of thing could happen.
Rym: All right, let's see you're at a dinner party dinner and boardgame party.
Rym: This is from the terrible secret of space.
Rym: Mm-hmm hosted by a couple with whom you are friends Mm-hmm, and they begin to argue during the board game.
Rym: The argument grows in intensity becoming louder and meaner.
Rym: awkward Yep, with both of them escalating to the point of trying to provoke other people into joining the argument on their side.
Rym: So so far just to stop the person who submitted this.
Rym: that happens on a like Regular basis in our own friend group every time like all the time.
Scott: Like you're allowed to argue.
Scott: What's the pattern?
Rym: We literally try to provoke each other into joining sides in these arguments.
Scott: What's the problem?
Rym: How do you extradite yourself extricate yourself from the situation?
Rym: You don't?
Scott: you just are social fallout as possible.
Rym: No, I just argue Just argue.
Rym: What's the problem?
Rym: You take the opportunity to win the game while the other players are distracted and unfolding.
Scott: Of course, I complain.
Scott: Come on.
Scott: Let's take your turn.
Scott: I'm not one to stop arguing but take your goddamn Turns.
Rym: I was Christ.
Scott: take your goddamn turn.
Rym: if they keep taking their turns Then the arguments not that bad and I'm gonna use their distraction to win the game.
Rym: Duh, if their argument stops the game, I argue with them.
Rym: Yeah, I don't even try to get out.
Rym: I this is literally my regular gaming experience.
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Scott: I don't see.
Scott: how is this even a predicament?
Scott: This is just every day.
Rym: How would you solve the Brewster's millions problem?
Scott: What's the Brewster's millions from you don't know the Bruce's.
Scott: I've heard of Brewster's millions.
Scott: Isn't it like a TV show or something?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So the idea is you're given a Ridiculous amount of money in a bank account cash you use for anything each time.
Rym: I'm not gonna read this whole thing, but I can.
Rym: I can summarize it pretty succinctly.
Rym: Okay, you must within 30 days from the moment you got this crazy amount of money Like let's say 300 million dollars Mm-hmm.
Rym: If you liquid spend all of it and by the end of 30 days have nothing left But things you own before you got the third 300 million you get 3 billion.
Scott: Wait, I have to spend all the 300 and you can't give it to charity.
Rym: You can't gamble it because because you can't make stupid gambling I can't.
Scott: I can't just invest it you because then you're making more money.
Rym: you have to get Reasonable and appropriate value for the spending of the money and have none left and nothing left by the end of 30 days.
Rym: 30 million, let's say 300 million 300 million giant amount of money.
Scott: So I have to have.
Scott: I have to spend it all You.
Rym: you can't just give it.
Rym: you have to get some reasonable value for your spending like you can throw a giant party.
Rym: That's totally cool.
Rym: You can't just burn it.
Rym: You can't just like buy Faberge eggs and eat them.
Scott: Couldn't I just buy like a sports team?
Rym: I guess that's making money.
Rym: You'd have to make that sports team suck Like The sports team is an asset.
Rym: You'd have to destroy the value of the asset within 30 days.
Scott: Oh I had.
Scott: so I have to but then I would get 3 billion and then I could just buy like multiple sports.
Rym: Yeah, the goal is you spend it all and then you are one of the wealthiest people in the world forever.
Scott: I'd buy a Boat and sink it.
Rym: No, it's specific.
Rym: There's.
Rym: so there's a specific rule in the Bruce's millions thing.
Rym: You cannot buy luxury goods just to destroy them Specifically.
Scott: so basically this is a really stupid question.
Scott: It's like oh tell me how do you solve this problem?
Scott: And then we're gonna make a special exception for every possible answer like like what's one plus one But you can't say two.
Scott: who is not an allowable answer to me?
Scott: another answer besides what.
Scott: I actually have a really trivial way to Do this get to get it all in cash and burn it.
Rym: I would just found a Bunch of game companies to make the kinds of games that I want with ridiculous budgets and give the games away for free.
Scott: But you still own these game companies.
Rym: the game companies are worth bupkis because they don't have any revenue stream.
Scott: Oh, I got it.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: I would hire an employee To work for me and pay them to be your personal and I would pay them $300,000,000 for like one hour of being my personal servant.
Rym: Okay, even if they need value, right say you have to get reasonable value.
Rym: hire a giant team of butlers to cater your personal living Experience to a ridiculous ultra stupid degree.
Scott: I would hire an army of people for whatever amount of time Minimum wage to March somewhere.
Rym: do the Lewis black ball washer.
Scott: Yeah, something whatever.
Rym: That's what I do Lewis black ball washer.
Scott: I'd have the Lewis black ball washer Equivalent of a bunch of game studios and hire people to do whatever for a amount of time and then all the money's gone And all the people are fired the end.
Rym: I'd also hire people remember that movie the game.
Scott: I hire some of them to clean my apartment - I do that.
Rym: I would hire people to run the game for me from that movie the game.
Rym: All right, whatever they're actually killing time.
Rym: I don't think we'll get through all of them.
Scott: It's also really stupid question.
Rym: I think it's fine.
Rym: ever accused Invisible people have invaded the city and they explode on contact with non invisible people and they want to do this.
Rym: You and only you can see them and they only respond with laughter.
Rym: What will you do?
Rym: so I can see them and if they touch a person they explode including me.
Rym: Yeah, I get the fuck out of the city because that's dangerous.
Rym: There's no way to solve that and I wait for it to die down.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: That's all I would do.
Rym: There's nothing.
Scott: I could get any explosions all over the place.
Scott: Yeah, they're gonna be grabbing everyone exploding everyone.
Scott: just cuz I can see them coming just like that.
Scott: It just means I have a better chance of running away and properly like those golden compass monsters.
Rym: You're just.
Scott: everyone else is just fuck.
Scott: but at least I can get away.
Scott: I mean I use the internet while I was running on my phone to warn people of well danger.
Rym: I mean I'd warn my friends.
Rym: we get the fuck out I'm sure.
Scott: as I was running I could do various things to help other people like throw sacks of flour around or You know stuff like that.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I think his flowers.
Scott: a good idea But you know in general just run until I'm away from this craziness cuz you can't win.
Scott: I would save myself and I just if I get far enough away the density of these invisible people is lowered.
Scott: I could just get guns cuz that's invaded and I have no problem.
Scott: if there were invisible people who explode and kill you when they Touch you I have no problem shooting them.
Scott: so yeah, as soon as I get far enough away from the city to gun land, I would get some gun and Slowly make my way back sort of like a zombie situation.
Rym: It says invaded the city.
Rym: So they invade New York.
Rym: I let the invisible people have New York.
Rym: I go live in some other city.
Rym: That's that's the best.
Scott: I'm sure the government would come and clean them out after and then I could come back.
Rym: Yeah, but if they invade the rest of the country What was I gonna do about it?
Scott: go to somewhere across water because there's still people.
Rym: they they only respond with laughter.
Rym: So I can't like make myself their leader or anything.
Scott: It's a really stupid question.
Scott: Again.
Rym: Anyway, I think it was fine Plus you got really into it.
Rym: All right, let's see.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Uh Pratt says my job You're on a remote rural farm for two weeks and your purpose officially to learn about like animal husbandry.
Rym: So like a co-op looks like an RIT co-op style thing.
Rym: Okay But the couple you're living with forces you to do household chores dishes for meals laundry Vehicles weeding panics by hand in crazy temperatures.
Rym: They don't let you use the car.
Rym: They basically make you a slave.
Scott: Okay, but I still get to leave after the two weeks though, right?
Scott: Uh, I Guess I mean, I'm the kind of person where they oh, so what do I do if I say no?
Rym: There's a whole bunch more.
Rym: the neighbor the nearest neighboring family is 300 kilometers away and the nearest town is 800 kilometers away.
Scott: They say do the dishes.
Scott: They know go fuck yourself.
Rym: The town has specific days, so it's like Nazi dystopia.
Rym: Everyone in powers and all the cops never know.
Rym: wealthy and white.
Rym: you are not white.
Rym: You ask for.
Rym: basically you're like not gonna graduate college.
Rym: if they don't I don't care what the consequences are.
Rym: I would get the fuck out of Dodge gives a shit about graduating college.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even end up here.
Rym: don't have a mobile phone.
Rym: if you piss the farmers off They discredit your two weeks meaning you have to do it again somewhere else I do it somewhere else.
Rym: if if society exists such that I could not get out of this situation I would turn to organize my violence.
Scott: to end I just want to point out right look how many not only on the millions one but on this one and all the other ones Right how many exceptions people have to make to make a situation truly a predicament.
Scott: that shows you just how safe Modern real society is.
Rym: look at ever almost So difficult.
Rym: every predicament movie has to make cell phones not work.
Scott: They're like not.
Scott: my cell phones are the biggest most powerful tool that everyone's carrying right like the ultimate weaponry But there's like even without cell phones.
Scott: It's like there are just so many ways to get out of a bad situation.
Scott: It's like it's really hard for bad things of any large magnitude to happen, right?
Scott: It's like It's not really reasons to worry about much because like people have to come up with such ridiculous Nonsense scenarios for there to be any sense of danger whatsoever.
Rym: I'm looking for one That's like really short because we've done basically a whole show.
Scott: That's why Godzilla is a thing, right?
Scott: You need some ridiculous thing like giant radioactive monsters stomps and breathes fire on everything.
Scott: That's the level of danger.
Rym: Here's a short one from Ren from New Zealand.
Rym: really simple and there's no exceptions at all home invasion at night.
Rym: You're in your bed So, uh, you're in your bedroom.
Rym: Mm-hmm the door busts open at night someone comes in and they have a melee weapon to the bedroom.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right bedroom.
Rym: They have a knife or a bat.
Rym: you can't quite tell cuz it's dark.
Scott: Are they gonna hurt me or they just want to rob me?
Rym: Uh, it's home invasion.
Rym: So you don't know what their intentions are, but they're yelling cuz I'm.
Rym: it's really simply what are they?
Scott: What are they yelling?
Rym: We don't know it would you don't know?
Rym: Okay, so let's just assume they're yelling and it's unintelligible.
Scott: Whoa, bro, chill out.
Scott: Chill out, bro.
Scott: Whoa, what's the problem?
Rym: I think I'm gonna rob me.
Scott: Go ahead.
Scott: Go rob me Just don't stab me.
Scott: What's the problem?
Rym: I feel like honestly in that situation if I'm in my bedroom and someone busts in yelling and has what looks like a weapon I Yell, I do the yellow bro thing, but I also probably immediately attack them with the sheets.
Rym: I just throw the sheets at their face.
Scott: I mean, I'd probably be you know defending with the pillow hoping they can like a knife gets caught in the I'd be doing other Things.
Rym: but like I immediately attack.
Scott: but the primary thing I'm trying to do is just like talk to them Like why you're robbing me like if someone like.
Scott: if I'm walking down the street and someone shows up to me There's like give me your phone.
Scott: I'd be like really like.
Rym: really you want a hundred bucks instead.
Scott: It's gotta find my iPhone.
Scott: Sure, you want it.
Rym: I'll give you my cash.
Scott: I mean if you're gonna stab me, I'll just give you the fucking phone.
Scott: It's not a big deal.
Scott: Here you go Like I'm gonna call the cops as soon as you run away.
Scott: You sure you don't want to give him the phone back?
Rym: I guess I would know regardless of any words that giver said I would not stop attacking them Until I had full control of the situation.
Rym: no matter what words they said, even if they said I'm just gonna rob you Probably still attack them.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, there's definitely opportunity.
Rym: No, no, they might be lying.
Scott: There's definitely opportunities to see where things go.
Scott: But I mean my primary technique is to just like talk to them and be like really you're robbing me.
Scott: I mean you're gonna take my credit card.
Scott: I'm just gonna cancel that shit.
Scott: Come on.
Scott: Are you serious?
Rym: Yeah, of course, there's a big difference.
Scott: like you're gonna stab me Okay, cuz now it's a murder.
Scott: the cops don't give a shit about a mugging But if you're suddenly a murder you're gonna have every cop in town over here.
Rym: So to be fair though a mugging is much more opportunistic.
Rym: but home invasion like that already implies like a lot of premeditation and In a somewhat unhinged it's still not as nearly as bad as the consequences of murder.
Rym: But if I was gonna rob a house I would rob a house that didn't have anyone in it.
Rym: like I wait for them go to vacation.
Scott: I hope my apartment got burgled when I wasn't there and the cops didn't even bother.
Scott: but if they do I'd follow you Okay book.
Scott: I know when you're on vacation and then I robbed your house.
Scott: if they had murdered me or it assaulted me in some Way, the cops would have definitely put in much more effort into finding their asses and it wouldn't have been that hard.
Rym: It's because all they did was a home invasion with a weapon implies Dangerous and crazy because home alone is the style to go except if there's a home alone kid in the house Just rob all the other neighbors houses.
Scott: Also, you know, I can call 911 silently in my phone.
Rym: I I would fight all their father burgling because I couldn't.
Rym: I couldn't dial 9-1-1 on my phone while I was fighting them.
Rym: It has an emergency button on the front like, you know, yeah that takes a few clicks though I gotta swipe up and then hit.
Scott: it's right next to my.
Rym: How many?
Rym: how quickly could I download?
Rym: no one.
Rym: let's see swipe emergency call 9-1, okay, I do like four clicks here.
Scott: Hmm, but you can do it as soon as you know.
Scott: You get a chance as soon as you can right?
Scott: Yeah, and you don't even need to say anything.
Scott: You can just sort of leave it on speaker and with the volume all the way down.
Scott: So you don't hear the 9-1-1, but they hear you.
Scott: Yep, and they would get the idea of what's going on.
Rym: Alright, I think I killed enough time.
Scott: That's the show.
Scott: Okay good and go home.
Rym: I'm really hungry So I'm just gonna stop birthday.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the current patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Nicholas brand now Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas on my state e.com.
Rym: William Eisneros, Jeremy minor.
Rym: life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth.
Rym: a genuine bonafide like five six car monorail captain Shingo Ocassie Rebecca done the terrible secret of space for two.
Rym: one creations.
Rym: a blue base over there and the only reason they have a blue base Sherman one horrible James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make room say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith - like a jar tofish and Joe Joe Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan Perrin.
Rym: We're whalers on the moon.
Rym: We carry a harpoon Brian Cedroni Finn Chris mink.
Rym: if Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on and now I leave you with the song that my african-gray dusty when I was a kid would whistle incessantly.