Rym: It's Tuesday, January 3rd, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight overcooked.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So normally this would be in the meta, but I guess it counts as news.
Rym: very briefly Magfest is this week.
Scott: Why didn't you put that in the meta?
Scott: Why are you saying that now?
Rym: I'm it would be meta if I talked about what we're doing at magfest, but magfest is this week, okay?
Rym: If you're going to magfest and you don't already have a badge They will technically be selling them at the door.
Rym: However, they have said definitively they're going to sell out.
Rym: It's just a matter of when like.
Rym: if you show up at the Gaylord and you don't already have a badge pre-reg You're playing with fire.
Scott: You might People I see online selling their badges for like 50 bucks.
Scott: Yep, so you can get one if you're proactive Yep, but don't expect to get one if you're way to the last second irresponsible.
Rym: Also, they only now have they're.
Rym: they're being smart because once it once the con sells out and will reliably sell out forever.
Rym: You can change a bunch of business like Otakon changes rules about single-day badges.
Rym: Pax got rid of the four-day badges to try to like.
Rym: there's all this stuff that can happen.
Rym: Magfest got rid of single-day badges.
Rym: So instead what they do now is there's only one kind of badge.
Rym: You can't show up on Friday and be like, yeah Can I get a Friday and a Sunday badge?
Rym: What you can do is you can always buy a four-day badge and every day that four-day badge gets cheaper Like if you buy it on Sunday, what if I want to do Friday only can I return my bed?
Scott: No Because magfest but Sunday only is like dirt cheap because nothing.
Rym: yeah I mean magfest is basically doing the opposite of packs and turkeys, you know Good gaming con sell out.
Rym: that is just the reality of the world.
Rym: You kids think this is bad.
Rym: try to get tickets to like a major sporting event for the good team in a major city or Like well popular concert.
Scott: Well, I mean they just charge more money, right?
Scott: It's like oh you want to go to the Super Bowl?
Scott: No problem $5,000 P. Yeah, it's like.
Rym: it's not like everyone who wants to go to the Super Bowl can hit f5.
Scott: People are complaining so much about like oh my god.
Scott: I can't get a pecs badge.
Scott: It's not fair.
Scott: cuz I got a reload.
Scott: I'm not available on the internet at the time.
Scott: They go on sale.
Scott: It's like alright Would you rather have a pecs badge be a thousand dollars?
Scott: I don't think you have a thousand dollars.
Rym: a pecs move toward for individual day badges Because a lot of people it basically it generally lets more humans go to packs though Not every human will necessarily easily get to experience all four days.
Rym: A lot of those humans don't deserve four days But the idea is that they want to hide like they want new people to keep experiencing packs.
Rym: magfest is going the more the opposite way of only four day badges because Generally, the magfest experience is best Experienced by going for all four days.
Rym: like you go into this place and you emerge Well some days later not quite sure what day magfest.
Rym: try to remember what the fuck your job is in real life.
Scott: The thing is that magfest is 24/7, right?
Scott: Yeah, we can control.
Scott: when you get in you don't have a badge yet, but when you leave it's like, okay What are they do at midnight?
Scott: go into the concert as it's happening find everyone with a Saturday badge and kick their ass out And then at midnight suddenly let the people with Sunday badges waiting to go to the concert run into it while it's halfway.
Scott: It's not logistically feasible.
Rym: This is one of those things.
Rym: everyone who thinks they have a good idea about anything about running cons Like you really don't understand the logistics of how this actually works unless you've actually run this stuff professionally.
Scott: They can like pull the fire alarm at a certain time kick everyone out and then let everyone back in.
Rym: Well, Otakon used to do that at 2 a.m.
Scott: Right, but I mean, you know It's like say kick out all the people with the one day badge of today then let in all the people with the one day Badge of tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, and then people instead go hide up in hotel rooms.
Scott: Whatever plus.
Rym: also magfest is the kind of con where you can have a lot of fun lobby conning it like for real.
Rym: Oh, yeah Like if you don't care about getting into tabletop and you don't care about the arcade or the concerts Which means you're dumb and you probably shouldn't be there.
Rym: like there's room parties going 24/7 at that con You can just go to room party like.
Rym: I know people who don't have badges There's gonna be.
Scott: they're basically hosting room parties the entire time and fully enjoying a magfest because people with badges spend half the time At room parties.
Rym: anyway, yep John will be at the room parties.
Rym: I assume he's at this magfest?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But anyway, it's just.
Rym: it's an interesting thing to look at thinking think to this moment five ten years from now We're these opposite philosophies.
Rym: if they continue unabated magfest I predict will end up being a Family of people where like 70 80 percent of the people who go to magfest now are the same people going Five years from now just already been that way for more than five years.
Rym: well packs is going to increasingly be a mix of young new old.
Rym: you two like every Part of gaming will be at packs But some of the older people will be pushed out due to this.
Rym: one day badge and the churn and the price.
Rym: We'll see how it goes.
Rym: but magfest is great And you should be there.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: There's a lot of news going on.
Scott: So first of all frog fractions 2 is out, but it's crazy.
Scott: I mean, well, it's frog fraction.
Rym: So, of course Crazy about a game that teaches kids fractions with frogs anyway.
Scott: So you should know what frog fractions 1 is.
Scott: if not, you can play it for free.
Scott: Just type frog fractions into the internet and play it.
Scott: Yeah Like if you don't know why we're talking about this game go go play that game Just frog fractions 2 did a kickstarter and they said you won't know when we actually release frog fractions 2 But we will.
Scott: so people.
Scott: there was an ARG which had clues Interspersed throughout multiple like indie games on steam.
Scott: right there were clues as to where frog fractions 2 was and someone finally figured it Out.
Scott: there's some game on steam.
Scott: I don't even know the name of it.
Scott: It's like something fairies or whatever Right, which actually is a game you can play but hidden inside of that game is frog fractions 2 and Then frog fractions 2 has a lot of crazy shit in it.
Scott: Including I saw one part where you have to load.
Scott: one part looks like to our fortress another part as it looks like Windows 3.1 and another part has you like Loading in your Mass Effect save files into the frog fractions 2 and it does something with them that I'm not sure of?
Rym: Yeah, maybe nothing like, you know.
Rym: these things go who knows.
Scott: but yeah If you already frog fractions 1 you can now frog fractions 2.
Scott: I also have a geek bite.
Scott: I played this game Owlboy, which is it was making the rounds like.
Rym: we saw it at a bunch of cons I saw.
Scott: I saw it at PAX and it looked incredible super high reviews like characters On the steam sale, so I'm like, alright, I'll buy this.
Scott: I got a whole week of nothing to do.
Scott: So I bought it and I played it and But just below the top of steer which is still amazing.
Scott: pixel arts like it looks good.
Scott: I was like good and the music while not like memorable music is well-made music.
Scott: Right, whoever made the music is good at making music It's just.
Scott: but you're not gonna remember how many these songs right?
Rym: Not like a mega man or a Metroid music or even like an undertale where I'm just like humming those songs Constantly even today.
Scott: right the thing with this game.
Scott: Is that as a game is bad It's not a good game yet, it's got like perfect reviews Everywhere.
Rym: like every critic says this game is amazing.
Rym: It's got five stars right Steve.
Scott: So basically I was in review.
Scott: It's really short.
Scott: First of all, right.
Scott: So you're not really and most of the game you're not even actually playing.
Scott: you're standing there watching Characters talk with text bubbles and pushing a a whole bunch to get through that text.
Scott: the other.
Scott: it's like half the time I spent playing this.
Scott: I think steam said I spent five hours on it.
Scott: I spent two and a half hours reading character dialogue boxes.
Scott: Okay The other thing is the game is I'm not gonna go into great detail because I already typed up the great detail on the forum But which I'll talk about in a minute.
Scott: So but it has control issues.
Scott: It has scrolling issues.
Rym: My experience I saw you streaming it and I logged in in the middle of your stream and just watch a little bit.
Rym: and the moment I logged in you were in this like sort of boss fight thing and I saw that every you kept triggering an event on that screen that caused a door somewhere else to open or close.
Rym: so like You'd be in the middle of doing something and then the game would like pause and like slide the screen to the right and show This door open slide back.
Rym: you try to do something else that it would pause again and it just kept doing this.
Rym: And I got so frustrated.
Rym: I stopped watching your stream.
Scott: It has bad level design.
Scott: It has all has lots and lots of problems with the actual game part, right?
Scott: Just one example right is like you're an owl and the.
Scott: the conceit is that the unique game?
Scott: Mechanic is that you carry your friends around right?
Scott: So you're fly.
Scott: you can fly pretty much whatever but whichever friend You're carrying is what weapon you have.
Scott: So it's sort of like weapon.
Scott: choosing right is changing friends and you have a magic teleporters.
Scott: You can change friends as easily as you can change weapons in doom, right?
Scott: It's no problem.
Scott: The weapon for shooting is right.
Scott: trigger the analog trigger, right?
Scott: So I'm the guy with the little gun and I hold down right trigger.
Scott: he goes pew pew pew pew pew pew pew.
Scott: But if I jam the right trigger and go click click click click click click click.
Scott: He goes pew pew pew pew pew pew pew pew Right.
Scott: So the result is that if it would be fine if it was a face button I'm used to jamming on a face button like a or X or Y or B or whatever, you know, no problem.
Scott: But because it's an analog button have to push it all the way down.
Rym: Did you remap it?
Scott: I Couldn't it mean?
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: Maybe I'd even try.
Scott: Yeah, like it hurt my finger to do that.
Scott: Also the button to pick up a friend and put down a friend is left.
Scott: trigger, you know, the analog one.
Scott: Yeah, so There's something on the ground that I want to pick up.
Scott: That's not a friend.
Scott: It's like a vegetable which gives you health.
Scott: I got to pull that out of the ground.
Scott: So I fly over to it and I'm holding a friend.
Scott: So I push the drop button, but now I drop the friend in front of the vegetable.
Scott: So then I go down to the ground and push the pickup button and I pick up the friend and not the vegetable.
Scott: So, how do I get rid of the friend?
Scott: There's no get rid of friend button.
Scott: I got to fly away a little bit and throw the friend like off into the distance and Then I can pick up the vegetable and then bring the friend back.
Scott: It's just like there's lots of annoying shit like that all over the place and you think okay Maybe the story you said half the game was story.
Scott: Maybe that would redeem it.
Scott: The story is bad.
Scott: It's a crayley crappy story and I'll give you two examples of why the story is crappy.
Scott: at the beginning of the game You go to like the first big town, you know, there's the hometown and then the big town.
Scott: That's how it goes right in every video game ever.
Scott: When you get to the big town, it's already under attack by pirates and the pirates completely destroy it spoilers.
Scott: No, no You didn't even get to like meet anyone in the town or go to any buildings in town or talk to anyone in the town.
Scott: it's like you get there and it's blown up and Then everyone is so sad about the main capital city being blown up or whatever.
Scott: It's like you never gave me a chance to give a fuck about that city by letting me visit the shops and Talking to the characters who live there.
Rym: I do have a counterpoint in Final Fantasy 4 Spoilers.
Rym: when you encounter the second town the the mist village with the summoners Yeah, where you were sent unknowingly on a mission of genocide You actually don't get to interact.
Scott: you come into the town, but you genocided that town.
Scott: So that's different.
Rym: Yeah, you got a prior.
Scott: you had a prior experience with the town.
Rym: to give you meaning Is literally to say you see the end you're like, oh sweet a new town It's an RPG and then you act then you genocide all over it.
Scott: Then I'm just saying right but anyway, the other thing is later in the game There's a part, you know way at the very end of the game where a character is doing something right and it's like you're trying to stop them and He's and he's like.
Scott: I don't have time to explain.
Scott: I'm not gonna tell you guys.
Scott: and it's like just tell us.
Scott: he's like no All right, then we're gonna have to fight you to make sunglasses Right and then yeah, it's basically put on the sunglasses and then we fight and then we're done fighting.
Scott: he explains himself.
Scott: It's like oh we were on the same side all along and it's like go fuck yourself.
Scott: You had time to explain apparently, but you just didn't want to.
Scott: so we had to have this boss fight.
Scott: You could have just fucking explained and we would have said okay the end I mean, I have more sort of nuanced and there wasn't any reason he didn't explain.
Scott: it wasn't like oh, he's pressed for time or you know, it just Like.
Rym: I have a lot of nuanced thoughts and like the whole situation here.
Rym: But I guess my high-level takeaways from like this situation are that one in like generally There's still like.
Rym: a lot of indie games are very similar to each other differing only by aesthetic.
Rym: Mm-hmm - maybe four or five years ago in any game of this caliber because it looks really great Like it's got all the pieces in there.
Scott: pixel art is so good.
Rym: This would have been like in a game relative to indie games out in the market like five years ago on Steam But by 2017 standards this game does not stand out at all.
Rym: Like there's almost no reason to play it.
Rym: I'm like like unless you had a very specific reason.
Rym: you wanted to play it like I was your thing.
Scott: Why this game is bad?
Rym: I was your thing.
Rym: You've never played like old SNES games that do these kinds of things better and you have a lot of free time and you got The game for free.
Scott: if you want to play a good pixel art platform or you can play like SNES Lion King or Genesis Aladdin or something.
Scott: You don't need to play this.
Rym: Yeah, those games have their problems, but I feel like they're not.
Rym: They're the same kinds of problems that this game has.
Scott: Better at platforming than this game.
Rym: Yeah It also brings up a you know a side point that there's generally in the modern era of the internet and the ease of creation and distribution of games in that you could make a game just by doing it on your own without a lot of investment other than your time and skill and all that business, but There will be so much competition for the attention of gamers That the vast majority of indie games are generally worth ignoring and you're not missing much.
Scott: Well, I think there's something that's happening not just you know in games especially but also other areas Is that content creation in general for a lot of things these days is multidisciplinary, right?
Scott: It used to be.
Scott: the only multidisciplinary content was movies which needed, you know film and acting and music and lighting and you know All these multiple.
Rym: you lose definition of multidisciplinary.
Scott: I'm just saying but like book doesn't require multiple disciplines It requires writing.
Rym: Well, look at like podcast even.
Rym: Podcast requires both have some entertaining or like some reason to be providing content and Separately, you got to know about like audio engineering, right?
Scott: And the point is that video game requires the most disciplines.
Scott: you need art and programming and game at least, right?
Scott: You need at least three things.
Rym: And if you think game design and programming are the same thing That's why your games bad.
Scott: You need at least three things to make a video game, right?
Scott: And the person who made our boy right was excellent at pixel art.
Scott: Okay, the team that made our boy.
Scott: I don't know how many people it was competent.
Rym: as the programming part It works like it came out.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't have bugs, but they're really bad at the game part.
Scott: It's like you have to be good at all the parts or get someone who's good at all the parts.
Scott: You can't just focus on the one part You're good at and do I do a run-of-the-mill job or just a just to get over the?
Scott: you know The bare minimum on the other parts.
Rym: Not that long ago.
Rym: I would say this game was pretty good at all the parts.
Rym: It's just there's a lot more games now.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: It's not good.
Scott: Super Metroid is.
Scott: I mean, oh, yeah Super Metroid is from 1990 something and this is from 2016.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But I suspect that like the Lion King Genesis game Not that much better than this in terms of controls.
Scott: probably similar point is if you're making a game, right?
Scott: You know, you have to at least look think about the greatest game in that genre.
Scott: right if you make an action RPG It has to be so good good enough that somebody would rather play your game than play link to the past again.
Scott: Well, if I would rather play link to the past again, then play your new action RPG It's not good enough.
Scott: get back to work and I would rather play Super Metroid again then play.
Scott: oh boy, I'd rather be nice.
Rym: so I a Professional opinion that is near to mine But I'm actually mirroring the things that were told to me by multiple different people in the industry over the years.
Rym: There are two fundamental ways to have well three fundamental is to have actual success.
Rym: one Have enough and have enough investment budget money company size Whatever to where like the revenue will work out in the end.
Rym: You just don't care.
Rym: luck.
Rym: Well, I'm ignoring the luck part in terms of things you have control over.
Rym: Two is property where people buy To focus on a niche audience that you can guaranteed Support enough to where the game will succeed.
Rym: So for example fortress.
Rym: Yeah dwarf fortress does not have graphics.
Rym: However, dwarf fortress serves the desires of a player base sufficient to support that game.
Rym: So you can make a game that's like super aesthetic like owl boy And even if the game itself like has a lot of other problems.
Rym: like people are reviewing this game really highly.
Rym: So I guess people are really into owl.
Rym: furries would be really into this game.
Rym: You know if they're into the aesthetic they might overlook the other issues with it and then that would be fine.
Rym: or three have like polish your game far beyond where you think you need it to be and there's a lot of evidence from the inside of the game industry that the games that are remembered and that succeed and that make more money than was expected are.
Rym: the games have spent a Significant portion of their time budget not on the game itself But on that last 10% of the game like polishing the controls like spending a month Just polishing the can.
Scott: make sure that jump is so perfect right cuz look.
Scott: that's what Nintendo did right on every game ever Right Mario's jump always so perfect.
Scott: the fireball bounces the exact right number of pixels.
Scott: It takes the exact right number of fireballs to kill Koopa.
Rym: Now if you do all those things you still might not succeed.
Rym: video ball hasn't done great despite the fact that I think they did.
Scott: Video ball has polished too much.
Scott: But the problem with video balls?
Scott: they entered into a market that Rocket League was already in.
Rym: yep Oh, that's it, but again being good does not necessarily mean you'll succeed.
Rym: in this modern era of a million games.
Rym: It's kind of weird to me that a game that doesn't seem that good at all like this seems to be succeeding.
Rym: It's pretty well.
Scott: I mean it's doing okay.
Rym: I mean, I don't know about sales like there's no way to know like how much money It's making.
Rym: it's a pretty expensive game, but it's got a 1500 reviews on Steam.
Rym: I mean I bought it on Steam sale.
Scott: I paid too much for it, and what are they charging for it now?
Rym: Let's see $24.99.
Scott: that's too much.
Scott: I would buy this game not even for $5 for if you really want to play it wait for $2.50.
Rym: less than $5 Yep, but it goes to show like if you just look at the Steam page you see this indie platformer five stars Overwhelmingly positive reviews, and if you click on all the video and look at the screenshots it looks incredible.
Rym: It looks great like I would just buy it like oh, man.
Rym: This game looks great, but seeing Scott play it and Knowing Scott's opinion.
Rym: I'm pretty confident games not worth playin And I'm sorry on YouTube, but games are competitive space now, and I can't I can't give a review to charity things of the day.
Rym: someone posted this in the new GeekNights forum and It is a Viking games comma Joms Wickinger.
Rym: Nah People were debating on the reddit thread about this whether or not the people in the video are actually speaking German.
Rym: Maybe dodge like.
Rym: no one can figure out the language.
Rym: They're speaking.
Rym: it is vaguely English, and that's the best they can come up with They might just be drunk and speaking German like no one can really tell.
Rym: this is apparently a Viking game And the game goes as such as best we can tell from this video of people playing it.
Rym: you get two individuals You get them moderately intoxicated you blindfold them you give them each a heavy cloth sack And you put tell them to stand around a large chest like a treasure chest And they must have at least one hand touching the chest at all times.
Rym: That's the setup for this game.
Rym: Then they take turns doing something like hey Scott like saying hey Scott and Scott has to say yes like Marco Polo.
Rym: And then I say may I hit you with this bag?
Rym: and Scott has to say hit me with the bag.
Scott: Why do I have to say that?
Scott: I'm gonna say no no you may not hit me with the bag.
Rym: Well, then you know then you lose.
Rym: so you you have to say that and Then you have to be.
Rym: you can now be quiet like I guess you could make more noise if you want to.
Rym: you probably Don't want to and I have to try blindfolded holding and touching this chest to hit you with the sack Knowing that you are also touching the chest blindfolded and as far as I can tell from this video This game is way harder than you think it would be.
Scott: and how big is the sack?
Rym: It's like I don't know.
Rym: imagine like Half size basketball like in a cloth sack.
Scott: I mean can you can I like how much of me has to be touching the chest door hands my hand hand has to be touching the chest.
Rym: the sack is on like a two-foot rope and like people like say their name like they say the thing and then they like lie down and like Hug the chest or like fling themselves out out of the way like this game is kind of crazy.
Scott: You know the chest is.
Rym: look this guy's got one finger on it, and he's like getting away from the chest.
Scott: You're blindfolded.
Scott: How do you know the sack is coming?
Rym: You don't that sucks if it hits you in the face.
Scott: Let's not play this.
Rym: it's a Viking game.
Rym: What do you expect?
Rym: This is like Scott?
Rym: This is probably not actually more Jane dangerous than how we play jungle speed.
Rym: sure It's probably a similar level of danger anyway.
Scott: I kind of want to play this game alright, so Basketball the sport I like to watch the least.
Rym: yeah I like to watch the last two minutes of a closed basketball game sometimes in the playoffs.
Scott: Yeah, anyway Especially NBA basketball is even worse than other basketballs, but anyway There is a player Onuaku, and he is was in like the d-league Which is like the.
Scott: you know the the AHL of basketball that no people.
Scott: It's like the least paid attention to League.
Scott: I think more people care about women's basketball than d-league NBA men's basketball.
Rym: I actually didn't know it existed.
Scott: yeah, anyway, so but you know he got called up to the Houston Rockets a real NBA team and He happens to be somebody who shoots free throws Underhanded like a man like a few players have done in the past.
Rym: play to win the game.
Rym: if it works It works doesn't work.
Scott: Yeah I mean he went from being basically a bad free-throw shooter to an excellent free-throw shooter with like a ridiculously like I think they said 90-plus percent free-throw shooting.
Scott: Shaquille O'Neal on the other hand You know one of the greatest players ever right sucked at free-throw shooting and was frequently fouled and sent to the free-throw line because sucked at free-throw shooting and he said I'd rather miss him than shoot underhand and look like a you know granny or whatever and He didn't play to win even though he won because he was still so good and playing with good players and good coaches.
Scott: But I would say one he Shaquille O'Neal could have won even more if he had swallowed his pride and shot underhand.
Scott: So way to go Onuaku showing people who play to win the game.
Scott: I hope we get some more play to win the game attitude and less worrying about looking cool attitude.
Rym: I'm gonna update our winning panel because we got that arm Edwards quote like you play to win the game.
Rym: I'm gonna add a video of the granny free-throw.
Scott: Well, cuz see actually the thing is if people use the granny free-throw more right and start getting their free-throw percentages up across the league It could actually change the overall strategy of basketball to where people are actually Much more seriously trying to avoid fouling people which would make the overall game of basketball much much better.
Scott: Yeah, like it wouldn't make it better enough to where I'd like watching it But it would make it still significantly closer to making me want to watch it.
Rym: Well, I mean look at the end result of a football as in soccer You really want to draw a penalty like getting a penalty is the best thing you can do in a soccer game.
Rym: That is more likely to get a goal than anything else you could do including trying to shoot a goal Kick a goal whatever you do to get a goal in the moment.
Rym: You may have noticed that if you go to forum dot front row crew comm the forum is still there But you can't post in it anymore.
Rym: No, and there's two threads at the top forum closed.
Rym: and look ye mighty.
Rym: Yeah, we're tired of paying $150 every month for this thing, especially because vanilla not getting better getting actually worse over time Right.
Scott: So what we're gonna do is we're gonna get a backup of it from vanilla and We're gonna load it into the open source version of vanilla.
Scott: So it's gonna change how it looks cuz it's gonna go back to the open source way And then we're just gonna leave it that way forever.
Scott: So we don't lose any data because we don't lose data.
Scott: We back shit up here also like big really like I and cool cool URLs don't change.
Rym: I really don't want to lose it because you guys have been using this forum for 11 years.
Scott: There's a 11 years of good stuff in there and Content.
Rym: in there.
Rym: you can find threads that were started eight years ago ended six years ago and were resurrected this month
Scott: right, but anyway, uh we started a new forum a community dot front worker comm and Because it's new and fancy people are all excited and posting a lot more than they usually do at least for now.
Rym: Also, all the lurkers came out of the woodwork.
Scott: Well the lurkers I realized had to make accounts because Even though they're just reading and not posting they still need to be able to mark stuff like as read.
Rym: So That's why I have that's the main reason I have a FARC account.
Rym: I mean, I don't post that off and I very rarely actually post a FARC anymore, but FARC remembers exactly where you read to in every Thread.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's real important.
Scott: So if you were ever, you know not joining our forum or not paying attention and we talked about it or anything like that You're pretty much if you're listening to this.
Scott: you should already have an account on this forum our forums Pretty great.
Scott: What you do is every time you sit down at your computer you go to it and you reload it every single time.
Rym: Yep You know hard it is cuz I you know 11 years of typing FR and just hitting enter because every browser ever log into just like goes to farm to forever good icon.
Rym: Real hard to switch that to see ya enter.
Rym: I got muscle memory.
Scott: I have a different methods of browser handling so I don't have that issue.
Rym: I don't use bookmarks.
Scott: I don't use bookmarks either.
Scott: I have a bunch of tabs that are there.
Rym: Oh, yeah pinned pin tabs all the time Pin tabs forever a hundred years I guess.
Scott: I just go.
Scott: I just go ctrl tab ctrl R ctrl tab ctrl R Move forward reload move next tab reboot next tab reload.
Scott: We will be.
Rym: so yeah, seriously like join our forum.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: The rules are simple and they're not like other forums.
Rym: rules And I hope you will appreciate the way our forum functions because it is.
Rym: I think we've done a reasonably good job of making that Community be a kind of community like you.
Rym: look at the penny arcade forums.
Rym: The actual people who do penny arcade ain't posting in there.
Rym: They do occasionally but yeah.
Rym: But like that is a you talk about a den of villainy.
Rym: good god those forums our forums are a place I actually go to because I enjoy being there and that is rare among forums about things that have people that run said things.
Rym: We're going to be live at the magfest.
Rym: We were talking about doing well Scott's doing two panels.
Rym: I'm doing six panels.
Rym: So GeekNights is doing six panels.
Rym: anime openers around the world quitting?
Rym: when does Sisyphus rage quit?
Rym: the sounds of horror in games and cinema the grind and the virtual mixed and augmented reality panel that actually has a bunch of like Academics on it, you know what the fuck they're talking about.
Rym: and in explain me I was already going for the.
Rym: the inexplicably me is exactly how I'm On the panel.
Rym: you preempted myself deprecation.
Scott: I know you were trying to do some self-deprecation, but instead I grabbed it and made an insult.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I am actually eminently qualified to be on that panel.
Rym: Fuck you Sure, but yeah, we're gonna be a magfest.
Rym: our panels are Friday mostly and two on Saturday.
Scott: It's not on Thursday, right?
Rym: No Just don't go on Thursday or Sunday because Sunday is the day where you go and play space war for like three hours.
Rym: Then you go home.
Rym: Mm-hmm So we'll be there.
Rym: also the book club book is Rebecca.
Scott: I'm almost done with it Yeah, so now that once we get the forum thing 100% situated I'm gonna start working on the website then.
Rym: Yep We're gonna make like the book clubs.
Scott: We're about to find out when Rym post this episode if it posts to the new forum the new thread.
Scott: It's exciting time.
Scott: I tested it.
Scott: It should work.
Rym: Yep, but it's you know, it's the UAT.
Rym: now Yeah, cuz basically I'm the UAT.
Rym: cuz the shit breaks I don't fix it.
Rym: cuz Scott doesn't give me like a route to the back end of the server.
Rym: Would you do anyway, I'd go look at while whatever logs I see like what the error was Uh-huh.
Scott: Okay, which log even look at?
Rym: no, so it depends on what the problem like.
Rym: So this is the forwarder on the back end is like a MySQL database.
Rym: Yeah Alright does does Django have a log file somewhere where it logs like shit that happened?
Rym: No, not at all Alright, then I look at the MySQL log and see if there was like an insert that failed.
Rym: That's like my first go-to.
Scott: No.
Rym: Alright, I'd look in the Apache log and see if anything funky happen.
Rym: There's no Apache engine X. Yeah, I'd look at the engine X log then.
Scott: All right If you didn't get a website if you didn't get a 500 error, then that's not gonna be there.
Scott: Yeah, usually your problem is episode didn't upload.
Rym: Yep So I guess I'd look in the director where the episode gets uploaded to actually then get its ID threes and shit put on.
Scott: That seems like a good spot to look.
Scott: Yeah, you don't know what to do once you get there.
Rym: Yeah, but I could probably suss it out.
Rym: have my life.
Scott: You know how to use celery.
Rym: That's the test scheduler, right?
Rym: Yeah, I can figure that out.
Rym: Celery can't be that hard.
Rym: It's like the baby one that people use in Django, but it's all but it's all stuff.
Scott: The thing is it's not like you're using celery.
Scott: It's like you're using code that I wrote.
Scott: that was you know, I'm using.
Rym: It's like celery schedules code you wrote to be run.
Scott: Read the code to figure out what the hell I wrote.
Scott: Is it Python?
Rym: Yeah, I'm not too worried.
Rym: I'm just saying I'll tell you what though if I got in there and celery linked to a pearl file.
Rym: I would just quit I would just give up.
Rym: Well, no, I'd look at it first then I'd give up anyway.
Rym: you'd be surprised how many people I interview in the course of just my life over the last decade for like The kind of position that would effectively would be troubleshoot problems on a website like this and the people I interview Can't even begin to figure out how to troubleshoot a system that there isn't documentation for.
Rym: I feel like that's a basic IT skill, but I digress.
Rym: We'll be at MagFest.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX South doing at least one panel, maybe two panels.
Rym: that's coming up in a few weeks So we'll talk about it later.
Rym: PAX East if you're an enforcer do the thing.
Rym: if you want to be an enforcer Go to the PAX East website.
Rym: open.
Rym: enrollment has begun.
Rym: You can apply to be a PAX enforcer And if you've never done it before and you're passionate about gaming conventions or you're passionate about PAX I recommend trying to do it like at least once like that's a side of PAX that it's real good to see because I've imagined All my life if there were a PAX where everyone who attended it had at some point in their life been an enforcer They'd know the deal.
Rym: It would be like the most chill possible convention you could ever have.
Rym: If more people are enforcers, the world will be a better place.
Rym: so Scott logged in.
Rym: well first he messaged me but I didn't respond to those in the shower for our New Year's party and then we Got over and he went over to my steam, you know, he's steam and he bought a game on my account Which is fine because I kind of expect that to happen and we played this game.
Scott: Just come up.
Scott: whenever I need a game on Steam I should just come over here and say buy his gift.
Rym: I Think I would eventually notice if you're buying gifts, I think that would be.
Rym: that would be misappropriation of funds in that case.
Rym: But anyway, the game was this little steam game called overcooked.
Rym: I think I've seen it like.
Rym: I think I've seen people linked to her to talk about it.
Scott: Yeah I was just.
Scott: you know I was reminded of it for like the second or third time and then it was New Year's and we were coming over and having A bunch of people.
Rym: so I'm like, ah, right this game.
Scott: I remember this game.
Scott: This game was like 20 bucks.
Rym: I thought there's like five bucks.
Rym: But the the gourmet edition - ah, okay, so 20 bucks is for the bundle.
Scott: we like everything, okay Yeah, that's what we got.
Rym: All right, not bad.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: But anyway See it's overcooked and it's the perfect game for a party because it's a real video game with you know Real-time action and local four-player co-op with four game pads.
Scott: What could be better for your party than such a game on Steam with your HD with your real computer hooked up to your television?
Scott: Like a smart person.
Rym: the overall conceit is that?
Rym: Cthulhu, which is the flying spaghetti monster finally came to earth.
Rym: It's the end day 1999 it's basically lavos and You want to cook amazing food for it?
Rym: So it will eat you later.
Rym: Mm-hmm And of course you fuck up and bail.
Scott: it is suck at cooking so much.
Scott: You can't do it.
Scott: So You know this king onion or whatever his name is sends you back in time to learn how to be chef, right?
Scott: It's like well, you can't?
Scott: you have no time to learn how to be chefs now and you're the only ones here.
Scott: So we're gonna send you back in time.
Scott: You can then you know with a time machine Practice your cooking skills and then when the flying spaghetti monster comes again, you'll be so good at cooking.
Scott: You can feed it, you know, say it's desire and the world will not end because it won't be so angry.
Rym: It's got like a top-down map like Lolo three style and like all this business going on.
Rym: But the actual game is just.
Rym: it has multiplayer and other stuff.
Rym: but co-op, you know up to four players.
Rym: You have a shared kitchen you walk little guys around and you have got to cook food like get lettuce and Tomatoes and mushrooms.
Rym: chop them up and combine them in different Combinations and cook the meat and then make a burger on a bun Deliver it and then get the plates and put them back and wash them, right?
Scott: So a lot of ways.
Scott: it's like diner - almost right diner - has like these orders in the top left.
Scott: It's like you have to do all the things but diner - you do alone, right?
Scott: And it's just do all the things.
Rym: this is diner - is also much more sort of Iconic and a little more abstracted, right?
Scott: This is you have to do all these.
Scott: these are orders in the corner, right more like a board game.
Scott: We'll have orders like oh, you know to complete this order and cash it in.
Scott: and traders of genoa You're gonna need you know, two purples and a green right?
Scott: It's like oh to make this burger You're gonna need a bun and a cooked meat, you know and onion and a tomato.
Scott: It's like this, you know stuff.
Scott: so and everything has a process and you have four people.
Scott: so like you need a burger.
Rym: So someone gets a bun from the supply of infinite buns Someone else gets a meat chops it up takes it over and starts cooking it in a pan, right?
Rym: And there's a timer.
Rym: that goes and the pan will be done.
Scott: Someone else chops a lettuce and a tomato and puts them in a you know onto the the burger waiting for that meat to come On there.
Rym: how hard could this be?
Scott: you put the whole thing on a plate.
Scott: then it's all done.
Scott: You got to put the plate onto the conveyor belt and then the plate comes back dirty.
Scott: You only have a few plates.
Scott: you got to wash them and then someone left something cooked too long.
Scott: It started on fire.
Scott: You got to use a fire extinguisher and there's all these things that can happen.
Scott: Hopefully there won't be any fires.
Scott: you want to worry about that.
Rym: now It starts like all right the kitchen and like just do your thing like it's sort of a fun like semi cooperative.
Rym: But just do your thing and it seems easy, but then they throw all the bullshit at you and this game is Super stressful, it's really really difficult.
Scott: It gets really difficult.
Rym: really simple stuff like Like one of them is just the kitchen is in two halves.
Rym: so like some of the stuff like you can get vegetables and chop them on the left side and you can cook meat and Serve on the right side, but there's a narrow little hallway between the two And if people are trying to go left and right at the same time You're
Scott: fucked right.
Scott: there are other much more difficult ones Like you're on the deck of a pirate ship and all the tables with all the stuff You're trying to use are sliding all over the place.
Rym: You're in a series of three different food trucks that are passing each other with open sides back and forth on the freeway.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's gets pretty ridiculous.
Rym: The kitchen is literally surrounded by lava.
Scott: Yeah So you're trying to cook and complete enough orders in a given time limit and score enough points Under crazier and crazier conditions, right?
Scott: So we played through a whole bunch and got really far But we were doing very poorly getting lots of one single stars on levels and God I'm gonna tell you when we played without you the next day.
Rym: We like fucking aced everything.
Scott: Well, you had practice.
Rym: No, we were.
Rym: we were just a better team without you yelling at us to do things the opposite of how we were all doing things.
Scott: But anyway, so the Way to sneeze there.
Scott: Don't sneeze all over that food in the kitchen.
Scott: What kind of chef is that dude?
Rym: So in one of the levels we're like, fuck it We're just like throwing stuff on the ground like leaving out extra plates to be ready.
Rym: You know, we play around and if you leave food out rats come and take it away.
Scott: No, the rats are only in this one level.
Scott: That was the rats because each level has a different obstacle.
Scott: that what it was one level where the obstacle was rats.
Scott: There are other levels.
Scott: There weren't any rats.
Scott: You can just throw food on the ground.
Scott: No one cares.
Rym: I threw a lot of cooked hamburger on the ground and just left it there until the time was.
Scott: the point is after playing and Getting as deep as we could before it said, uh-huh.
Scott: You suck too much But you're not gonna let you play more levels.
Scott: Do you get more stars?
Scott: you went back to try to get three stars some easy levels because their skills had gone up and we?
Scott: Got in the zone in those easy levels and it was like whoa.
Scott: Yeah, this is so good.
Rym: this game has a an excellent arc of like auto wear and stressed out and overwhelmed and then you move into like basic competency and then you move into like Ultimate flow like when you get flow going in this game.
Rym: It's like doing a nine photo in DDR like your brain just feels like it's in this slot, right?
Scott: but when we got we only got the flow going on like easy levels.
Scott: if we got the flow going and like really difficult levels That would be like like a peak gaming kind of experience.
Rym: The next day when you weren't here We got a burger plate like we got a burger one like you know.
Rym: So the stuff to back up a little bit.
Rym: the way it works is the three stars.
Rym: in every level like in those kinds of games.
Rym: but generally like Star one is like get ten points like you you've made one.
Rym: get two stars.
Rym: It's like get 80 points like you were reasonably efficient.
Scott: three stars Yeah, 400 fuck you.
Rym: We got to the point to where we crushed the three stars on some of these like we went way beyond what we need to go Beyond.
Rym: but even then it wasn't the crazy hard ones.
Rym: It was like making complicated burgers.
Rym: It wasn't like make complicated burgers on the pirate ship.
Rym: that's on fire.
Scott: Yeah, yeah As I mean we didn't.
Scott: there's a lot.
Scott: there's a lot of levels in this game Especially be at expansions like it seems to have a lot of levels in it like, you know We don't even think we've seen half the game But it
Rym: does a really good job of giving you like three different goals to shoot for that really fit into those levels of overwhelmed Like adequate apprentice level skill.
Rym: and then the third star is you are now an expert.
Scott: Yeah, we all.
Scott: there's a versus mode which I think is two on two.
Scott: We tried that but we're only one-on-one.
Scott: we didn't get it set up right or whatever.
Scott: So our other do just stood there are they just stood there, but the versus mode is okay, I guess It's pretty fun.
Scott: If you really want to do some verses instead of cop is basically the same thing.
Scott: Oh, you know, it's two little identical kitchens.
Scott: Yeah And you have the same orders.
Scott: who does it better and who can get more stars within a time limit?
Scott: and that's a perfectly fine Game.
Scott: you want to see who's better at doing the cooking game by.
Rym: so I mean I don't want to say that much else about it.
Scott: cuz the game is there isn't that much else about it.
Scott: That's why it's so great.
Rym: one flaw.
Scott: there is one major floss soul flaw in this game.
Rym: Is that the analog stick to move your guy around is?
Rym: Super analog and super floaty, but you need to precisely select Discrete squares in the game like pick up this tomato not that tomato, right?
Scott: There are a lot of times where I'd like try to put a tomato on the cutting board and it would just go like Whoop and I put the tomato next to the cutting board To pick it up again and put it back and it's through cooked
Rym: food in the garbage like four times.
Scott: It's because the analog stick and the controls are just a little bit flaky and not precise enough and there's no reason for that.
Scott: You know, everything's big enough in the game that like aiming at a single square shouldn't be difficult.
Scott: I would have made maybe turn the sensitivity down.
Rym: I mean the way I would have polished this is I would have made the characters still be floaty because the floaty of walking around Is actually good.
Scott: You could have also done twin stick using the right stick to aim.
Rym: I know this is much simpler way.
Rym: So leave them floaty because the characters have big hitboxes.
Rym: I wouldn't make it like grid because that would remove some of that like panicky ad hoc movement Mmm.
Rym: and when they're floaty like you'll try to pass people in a narrow ish hallway and you like bump into each other and then you Sort it out, but it slows you down a little bit.
Rym: Like it's one of those things you can improve for efficiency.
Rym: I like that.
Rym: It's like getting the sparks in Pac-Man say edx
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: but I would have made it so that the if you're clear if you're near one of these squares You can work with because it's a grid on all the countertops and all the things you can interact
Scott: with it locks in.
Rym: I would have made those 100% lock-in if you're next to what if you actually do want to put the chopped tomato next to the kind of walk a little More to the left.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: That's what I would have done.
Scott: You could you know, you just have it.
Scott: You could have had done that as long as you.
Scott: just I don't think you do absolute lock-in.
Scott: I think we do.
Scott: is you have a sensible radius?
Rym: Yeah around a you know Like a stove or maybe like if you jam the analog stick like way at an angle It'll target the next one.
Rym: But like the towel like is a wider band of lock-in on the one you're you're most overlapping with.
Scott: Yeah it should be.
Scott: it should be much more difficult to Accidentally put your tomato on the floor as opposed to the cutting board because that wasn't flying next to the cutting board And even when we had flow we still kept fucking that up like that was.
Rym: that was a yeah We just yes problem.
Scott: We would just get better at correcting ourselves Like I'd put the thing down by accident pick it up and put it in the right place again.
Scott: But it was I think our friends cuz.
Rym: so this game isn't just for a player like you.
Rym: play with four people and it works.
Rym: Great, and even you can split controllers up so that if you only own two controllers I think you can still do four player.
Scott: Yeah, because each half of a controller has a stick and a button.
Scott: all you need to play is a stick and a button.
Scott: See one Xbox two buttons.
Scott: sure two buttons But the point is every controller has a stick and two buttons.
Rym: But this game is legit more multiplayer much like the jackbox games because one of our friends was Calling out orders as a spectator and that was actually super fun.
Rym: Like you might argue that's cheating and I thought I don't care but we had a lot of fun with that.
Scott: So people it was because when you're all working you're.
Scott: it's like you need all four people to be concentrating on what to do.
Scott: It's hard to also pay attention to what the orders are, right?
Scott: So someone to tell that to you with it.
Scott: cuz like every time you look at that You're not looking at the guy you're moving, you know, this is fundamentally a game about making efficient systems.
Rym: I will identifying how to make a system efficient increasingly identifying the next bottleneck as you eliminate bottlenecks and simultaneously Developing a tactical ability to when your plan gets fucked up by something unexpected Deviate from the plan while maintaining a reasonable degree of efficiency, right?
Scott: And there's a lot you might think.
Scott: Oh, this is really simple.
Scott: It's like you do the or the ingredient getting in the chopping you do the cooking you do the plating you do the dishes And then what you know, that's great.
Rym: But now there's a bun shortage or we're out of clean plates.
Scott: Well, there's no bun shortages infinite buns.
Scott: But the point is there's a bunch.
Rym: there's a shortage of buns out on the right side where we're actually preparing the food, right?
Scott: That is so a good example.
Scott: is the one level that really bothered us was the one where?
Scott: The cutting boards would slide in the pile.
Rym: Oh my god That one.
Scott: so only at the beginning of the level.
Scott: the cutting boards are on the left So only the people on the left side of the screen can chop anything and then it slides.
Scott: Now only the two players on the right side of the screen can chop anything because the cutting boards have moved with everything that was on them.
Scott: they just slid away.
Scott: so you have to constantly.
Scott: you have to basically have two different modes of what you're doing and You have to win when the deck slides.
Scott: you have to change modes and be like, okay These are my tasks now.
Scott: and you also to pick up like the task that the other players just left off that what they were Like.
Scott: what were they doing?
Scott: I need to do the task that they he was doing but much like in say Oh where he left off or counter-strike?
Rym: You'll have your blood.
Rym: default operating orders like your plan like.
Rym: you'll come up with a strategy and follow that strategy But you have to like to get high level like ultra high level play.
Rym: You have to have the ability to deviate from that strategy in a way that other players will deviate in a way that together You'll maintain efficiency without having to stop and say here's the new plan.
Scott: It's the ultimate real co-op like.
Scott: it's the most real video game co-op there is.
Scott: it is.
Rym: This game is great and you should buy.
Scott: in terms of the real time Yeah, if you have four if you're in a college or if you have a lot of parties or conventions Your laptop to conventions and plug it into the TV in the hotel room.
Rym: This is like a must own right.
Scott: if you have frequently or semi frequently at least four people in the same place with a computer connected to a television or a big enough screen and enough game pads then you must buy this game.
Scott: if You're just like a solo person or you don't have a lot of friends or you're sad or you don't have a computer connected There is like single.
Scott: you can just play this with other people who bought it already.
Scott: When they bring their setup or you go to their house or something, right, you know But if you're the party house, you gotta have overcooked in that party.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons in order the modern money they give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando hiding Nickle Amanda to shit.
Rym: construction noises Ivy fame.
Rym: I stated calm.
Rym: William Eisenberg's Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas on Bertie would have won Christian coons word.
Rym: order doesn't matter.
Rym: It's only important that the first and last Sure, man.
Rym: Holy kid Rilla Val James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona superboy.
Rym: And then the wing hussars arrived earned serious.
Rym: Brian Fisher sailor Vista.
Rym: my decision to lower my pledge has nothing to do with Scott Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar Thomas and Joe sure Joe star Tyler Ella shot saw Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton run from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent drew open letter.
Rym: Brian Sidroni Curian if Redacted Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: true to my word I do one take every time and I read the whole thing in one go.
Rym: if you guys trip me up you trip me up, but yeah, we're back at least for magfest then we're not doing any more shows this week obviously and Then we'll get interrupted again by packs house in a ski trip, but we'll be Mostly on track to do normal GeekNights and ramp back up to a normal schedule in the coming months as we typically do At the beginning of the new year, so we'll see you at magfest.
Rym: and now I leave you with Replicating eating up memory.
Rym: What do I do?
Rym: type cookie you idiot?
Rym: I'll head him off at the pass.
Rym: Yeah, but you're a bug attacking all login and overly files.
Rym: run antivirus.
Rym: Give me a systems display.
Rym: Die dickweeds.
Rym: a Rabbit is in the administration system.
Rym: send a flu shot.
Rym: rabbit flu shot.
Rym: Someone talk to me.
Rym: a rabbit replicates till it overloads a file that it spreads like cancer cancer.
Rym: Oh, it's the Gibson.
Rym: it's finding us too fast.