Rym: it's Tuesday April 11th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm smarter than Rym and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight we are talking about the Legend of Zelda breath of the wild.
Scott: am I the wild?
Rym: I breathe I'm just the breath.
Rym: let's do this.
Rym: it's a warm today.
Rym: I rode my bike to work today.
Scott: my life has been restored like I was down to half a heart but now I got extra hard.
Rym: yep I just had this feeling all day.
Rym: it was like 77 degrees.
Scott: I went out for lunch I rode my bike I ate lunch in the office way quick and then I walked over to the grassy river area and I just laid in the grass for as long as I could get away with.
Rym: yep though I did on my way home and I will not tell.
Rym: my goal for this entire summer is to not once tell yet another story of some fixie guy fucking up or getting in my way.
Scott: but yet well you can just say there was a fixie guy fucking up today.
Rym: yeah but this unless it tops this one.
Rym: so the EMTs were at the base.
Rym: you know the the Queensborough the Williamsburg Bridge on the approach into Brooklyn.
Rym: okay on that long downhill mm-hmm there were a bunch of EMTs.
Scott: someone fell and hurt them.
Rym: so someone had a pretty serious bike accident.
Rym: they were putting them into a stretcher and there's a whole crowd of people around and I see a fixie bike and it looks damaged mm-hmm it hit somebody or just himself.
Rym: only one person appeared to be injured.
Scott: all right was it the cyclist or another person?
Rym: it was the cyclist I assume mm-hmm because it looked like.
Rym: I mean I just biked by.
Rym: I wasn't gonna gawk at someone with their injury.
Scott: but yeah I do not rubberneck based on the position I don't want to see the injury.
Rym: I'll probably bar based on the position of some bloody bandages and such.
Rym: it looked like the back of the dudes left or right like that.
Rym: basically suppose that your pedals hit the back of your leg mm-hmm.
Rym: that area was injured in pretty serious looking fashion.
Scott: if they weren't fixed to the rear wheel maybe they would stop spinning and not whack the back of your leg.
Rym: so my my suspicion is that someone did that thing that fixie bike riders like to do where when they're going downhill you know human can pedal that fast.
Scott: they pull their legs up and let the pedals just go away and then they should have done what the person did in my thing of the day for Thursday then it would work.
Rym: the problem is at the base of that bridge there's those two big poles to prevent cars from driving in the bike area.
Scott: that is correct.
Rym: so you've got to be able to maneuver around those things if you're going real fast.
Rym: it's not like you can just turn a bike on a dime especially if your feet are not on the pedals.
Scott: yeah apparently I heard a story cops were ticketing people for not walking their bikes over the RFK bridge.
Scott: what it's like?
Scott: why don't you take it these fucking fixie guys?
Scott: instead?
Scott: it's like your law I think pretty sure.
Scott: the law says you have to have brakes on your bike yep or lights like if they take it for those things I would not care as much about.
Scott: you know because all the cyclists are pretty much like whenever cops ticket cyclists they're like why are you doing this?
Scott: you shouldn't be doing this at all even though we are breaking laws.
Scott: technically because you should be harassing drivers.
Scott: drivers amazing because drivers are murdering people.
Scott: right and you know.
Scott: obviously there's some truth to that but at the same time it's like well you are still violating laws so it's not really that don't do that but
Rym: it's mostly dumb laws because there's
Scott: some of the law that the RFK one is kind of dumb but like the RFK
Rym: one is extra dumb because that bridge is so long that walking over it is ridiculous.
Scott: oh well you know I wonder why that rule exists.
Scott: it is not wide enough.
Scott: because no it's because there's one part where there's no fence.
Rym: I'm actually afraid of some fight between the Port Authority and the MTA and a couple other.
Rym: like basically there's all these arguments out jurisdictions.
Rym: so bridges that are under certain people's jurisdictions just bike all you want and bridges that are other people's jurisdictions.
Rym: they hate bikes and there's this weird like internal New York City politics thing going on.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: the point is that they should go after people who if you want to take a cyclist ticket them for something that's actually bad like not having lights at night or not having brakes on your bike or actually just like running a red light in front of actual traffic.
Scott: yeah not a red light at like.
Scott: the thing is they do take it for red lights a lot and that's what cycles doing now.
Scott: take it like T sections.
Rym: yeah they're going like on the right side of the road getting a ticket on a T where the part of the T that cost that for the light goes into a brick wall.
Rym: yep yep.
Rym: so what they're doing lately is though they won't pull people over right away.
Rym: I saw a whole bunch of reports of this on a couple of red.
Rym: it's just recently.
Rym: follow you a bunch of 20 red lights because technically they're traffic tickets.
Rym: so they follow all the same rules as cars meaning each subsequent offense of the same type in a certain period adds like a multiplier to your fine.
Rym: so this guy got basically a six thousand dollar ticket for running a stop sign because he ran ten stop signs in the middle of the night on an abandoned road.
Rym: yep so I yeah but I won't complain about.
Scott: I'm sure there weren't any cars doing any really dangerous things at that time.
Rym: yep.
Rym: so it's gaming day and the most important game right now is NHL hockey because hockey playoffs start tomorrow.
Scott: it's gonna be some good stuff even if you didn't pay attention to hockey all year.
Scott: or you don't care about hockey everyone.
Scott: the hockey games tomorrow are gonna be nothing like the hockey games that you have seen the rest of the year.
Rym: regular hockey is like oh someone wins someone loses.
Rym: maybe there's a rivalry.
Scott: are we making the playoffs?
Scott: are we not?
Scott: okay we're in.
Scott: we don't really care.
Scott: once it's playoff hockey everyone tries super hard and everyone is super serious and if there's a tie they don't just do a shootout they just keep playing literally forever until someone wins for real wins not you that win.
Scott: you have to win in a regular old hockey golden goal and they just keep going mm-hmm and so start watching tomorrow and even if you know nothing it will be excitement.
Rym: there's also a dynamic watch.
Scott: any team you want cuz it's not just don't root for anything.
Rym: normally in any sport during the regular season you play a bunch of different teams never play the same team twice in a row mm-hmm and you only usually play teams that are in your area and you occasionally play teams that are further away.
Rym: if you do it all in hockey with the finals you basically play against the same team up to seven games and you start like learning from each other and adapting to each other in a way that I
Scott: find the goalies weakness weak point and I'm at it like it's a red spot on some boss.
Rym: yeah it's good stuff.
Rym: so you got any gaming news other than the fact that the most important sport is happening right now.
Scott: so mad cats is a company that for most of my life I associated them with shitty third-party controllers.
Scott: cuz that's what they made.
Scott: they made really stupid third-party controllers you'd go to.
Scott: so anything is.
Scott: in my life I have never bought a third party garbage controller right ever.
Scott: I've bought third-party controllers but never bad ones.
Scott: only what an occasion when they happen to be a really high quality one was rare.
Scott: I have mostly like 90% bought first party quality controllers.
Rym: I bought one logitech gamepad once at RIT and I mean shit.
Scott: I bought gravis gamepad.
Scott: the real deal.
Rym: even gravis gamepads though not great.
Scott: that was the best you can get in those days yeah but not great for a PC.
Scott: that was a first-party controller for a DOS PC.
Scott: the gravis gamepad was the first party.
Scott: can gamepad?
Rym: I'll give you that anyway.
Scott: the point is and mad cats was like the worst at making third-party controllers.
Scott: they had ones that were had like weird shapes and crazy were not good to use.
Scott: they were bad in every conceivable way.
Scott: they were cheap and flimsy.
Scott: but like I'd go to other people's houses even people had more money than me right and they would have third-party controllers.
Scott: I guess they bought them because they were cheaper.
Scott: or they thought they were cooler looking or they didn't know better and it's like oh my god.
Scott: and of course you know the worst was when it was someone they thought they were led a Nintendo console and this kid he bought he chose to buy this third-party mad cat's n64 controller for it so you get a four for golden eye right.
Scott: it's like if he chose this one and liked it that he chose it over getting a regular Nintendo one.
Scott: why does he insist on using the regular Nintendo one in his house and make you use the mad cats?
Rym: because he realized he made a terrible mistake.
Rym: that in public no so but then they had kind of a renaissance and that they you know they have.
Rym: once rock band the first rock band came out and guitar hero those games sort of brought back the weird controller era for a while right.
Scott: there seemed to be something happened you know some years ago where mad cats someone took it over or something they started actually making like.
Rym: they say like the to their loyal customers.
Rym: they were like super open and really helpful good customer service.
Scott: they suddenly like something changed and they became like they had it factories or they could make controllers apparently right and they turn.
Rym: I don't know if they met him directly or if they.
Scott: the point is they had the capability of designing and building game controllers and they used it to make good controllers at some point and they became like a really cool company that made good stuff including like fight sticks especially.
Scott: I have a mad cat's.
Rym: I also have a mad cat's fight like a Street Fighter.
Rym: for Super Street Fighter 4 fights they came with a keychain that also looks like the fight stick that has the Allen wrench.
Rym: I need to open my fight stick because I can modify my fight stick.
Scott: yeah it's like.
Scott: it's like that's way cool and it also happens to be a really good fight stick with like real buttons real stick a square gate not no bullshit.
Scott: you know like angle gate that they use in the US you can replace the gate if you want.
Scott: sure it's like.
Scott: it's like pretty awesome.
Rym: so mad cats turn their ship around but now well unfortunately by turning their ship around they turned it into the rock band for ship right early rock band for had to go crazy nuts or they were done.
Scott: so now they're done.
Scott: mad dots is going out.
Rym: oh business if you notice at the PAX is like seeing who is spending money at PAX especially in like.
Rym: the more social gaming scene is actually a pretty good indicator of who's doing well because for a long time it was like the rock band stage.
Rym: everywhere you'd see rock band type just like on a stage.
Rym: there'd be like five of them and then right before mad cats went under suddenly it was all jackbox instead and all the fake instrument games kind of fell by the wayside.
Scott: right the fake instrument games went away.
Rym: just dance kind of replaced them but not enough right.
Scott: and then they tried to bring him back.
Scott: they like they put in an effort like all right we let him go.
Scott: it was.
Scott: you know it was hot for a while.
Scott: people have cooled off.
Scott: we'll wait and then we'll bring them back.
Scott: but the bringing them back did not work.
Scott: oh it did not failed at the bring back.
Scott: they didn't wait long enough.
Scott: they were too.
Scott: you know they needed that Monet's and they went and they gambled too soon.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: and meanwhile those like the replacement in that sector now really seems to be those just dance style games.
Rym: but I've noticed that they have a higher social barrier to entry and that people who are totally fine playing a fake guitar on stage totally not fine having to freeform dance in front of a screen.
Rym: so you've got kind of a different demographic playing those games when there is a stage at a convention.
Scott: I'm telling you DDR the window is open.
Rym: now's the time DDR could come back in a big way and that's not just because we're DDR nuts.
Scott: I really do think they've waited long enough on DDR that they could bring it back now.
Scott: I mean as far as I can see that I mean waiting longer is only gonna increase the chance of DDR being successful again.
Scott: so wait longer.
Rym: step mania I got some updates and it's kind of way worse now like it's ugly as shit and it doesn't come with arrows that look like DDR.
Scott: can you mod that like crazy though can't we just make it look like I tried?
Rym: I gotta make it.
Scott: we should just download the graphics from fourth mix plus and make it indistinguishable.
Scott: I found an actual fourth mix plus machine.
Rym: I found a pack someone made that was literally DDR fourth mix.
Rym: shit yeah and I I have tried every way that the quote-unquote documentation of step mania says to make that work and it the arrows just seem to randomly look worse and worse and worse and don't look like the images I can see in the pack.
Rym: I'm telling it to you at least it's open source.
Scott: you could work on it I could.
Rym: so in other news this kind of thing is happening a lot lately.
Rym: so this is this particular story isn't really that noteworthy.
Rym: it's more that this kind of thing is something you really got to pay attention to especially attention to eSports.
Rym: there's a counter-strike tournament and there is a long-standing glitch and it's kind of a fiddly glitch in counter-strike.
Scott: where smoke counter-strike go you mean well yeah counter-strike.
Rym: if you anyone who says counter-strike definitely means counters 1.7 1.6. because you know anyone who's counter-strike 1.6 today is not gonna say yo I play counter-strike they're gonna say yo I play counter-strike 1.6 semi-colon.
Rym: it is far superior to all other counter-strikes and that's their whole life.
Rym: if they say just counter strike they're playing whatever the new one is.
Rym: but this glitch has been around forever as far as I can tell and basically smoke grenade can put out a no idea.
Rym: I mean how do you even test for that smoke?
Rym: there's a lot of different kinds of smoke grenades.
Scott: most of them are not explosions they're just putting out a Molotov really that strong in counter-strike.
Scott: they don't burn that long.
Scott: uh so if even if you even if you could do it reliably how good is it?
Rym: have you ever played modern competitive counter-strike not competitively okay.
Rym: so you've never played like modern five on five.
Rym: basically it comes down to like really tight scripted rotations and picks and the strategies are real specific.
Rym: so if you throw a Molotov into an area like a choke you know guaranteed that that team is not going to come through that hallway for a specific number of seconds because that would be suicide.
Rym: so you can plan accordingly and those seconds matter.
Rym: so if you throw a Molotov down a hallway you can turn your back on it and go do your business whatever it is you're gonna do.
Rym: but if that Molotov goes out earlier than it should have there can be people in places that your brain knows they cannot be and you're instantly dead.
Scott: ah so you throw a Molotov and you know no one's coming from the left.
Scott: so we're just gonna guard the right and wait and we'll know.
Scott: we know the timing because we're pros of when the Molotov will be out and then we can pay attention to those places again.
Rym: it'd be like in you know quake where you see the quad damage.
Rym: if someone gets it and now it's gone you know exactly how many seconds it'll be till someone can get quad damage again right and then suddenly someone just has quad damage again.
Rym: that's what it's like.
Rym: but on a suit is a pretty significant effect if you can do it but it's difficult to pull off.
Rym: it seems really glitchy.
Scott: it's not just an automatic thing like smoke.
Scott: throw a smoke at a Molotov and it goes out.
Rym: no sometimes they just bounce out of it.
Rym: but it's been.
Rym: incidents relate.
Rym: this is the like.
Rym: the height of counter-strike is that this glitch which is difficult to trigger rare and highly situational has caused a problem in several super serious counter-strike tournaments in recent memory.
Scott: so fix that shit.
Rym: valve won't fix it and has made no statement.
Scott: I guess they don't care about competitive.
Rym: counter-string valve seems to like not really care about game.
Scott: this is okay.
Scott: so I mean no it's not just valve right.
Scott: this is a thing that is happening.
Scott: I think in every competitive like game there is period.
Rym: right companies.
Scott: okay.
Scott: so look I think Lowell takes care of their shit.
Scott: right but very very few games take care of their competitive scene well and quickly.
Scott: right netrunner is like the worst.
Scott: they never update never update anything.
Scott: you know communication from no one.
Scott: I don't know about magic recently.
Scott: I guess they're good.
Rym: cuz magic is pretty good about.
Scott: they're pretty good but it's like cycling.
Rym: it took them a long time to get good right.
Scott: Hearthstone.
Scott: it's like yeah they heard they're doing better but it's like there's just so slow at doing anything right.
Rym: it's like overwatch is like if I it like holy shit.
Scott: I ran it.
Scott: I ran a competitive game like I was in charge of it.
Scott: I would be updating that shit weekly and perhaps more often than weekly fixing everything polishing everything right.
Scott: when I saw like something you know going off the Prado frontier I'd be nerfing I'd be boosting.
Scott: I still want.
Rym: that is literally what overwatch is like it has been since launch.
Scott: I'd be tweaking like we more than weekly.
Scott: you know so hot.
Rym: so there's an argument to be made that cuz you know overwatch and most like people are trying to have seasons now to make spot eSports a little more reasonable to manage.
Rym: yeah it would make sense to whatever the rules are at the start of season like if there's a glitch like unless like you have a rule like normal you got to do it like Debbie and Linux you get the stable and that you know.
Rym: that is exactly what overwatch.
Rym: does you realize what?
Rym: over the way overwatch works there is the legit current version that's in competitive during the season mm-hmm.
Rym: there's also the public test region.
Rym: so the next set of tweaks is always there and you can just log in and play with the like.
Rym: yeah the next set of rules and as soon as those are solid there are really push.
Scott: there are a very large number of competitive games in the world and the number of ones that handle this sort of thing prop the competitive scene properly and tend to it like a garden.
Rym: there is a good argument that you might not necessarily want to make constant minor changes in the course of a given season because that might benefit players who took advantage of things before later in the season.
Rym: it's better.
Rym: look what a hockey does every year they're like.
Rym: so.
Rym: did anything go wrong this year?
Rym: oh yeah this thing happened.
Rym: well but if something is egregious you gotta fix that shit right away and this one wouldn't be egregious except that these skills at the upper levels of counter-strike are so high and the factors that determine victory are so narrow that this is coming up repeatedly.
Rym: mm-hmm but I don't think valve cares that much.
Scott: they don't give a shit.
Rym: counter-strike really feels like it's fallen off like it's not gonna be the big eSport down the road.
Scott: well if they if they would just fix them.
Scott: you know they just tend to their garden.
Scott: it'd be fun.
Scott: it's still counter-strike.
Scott: it's still a big deal.
Scott: I just feel like.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: valve does not feel like a game company.
Scott: it or it also counter-strike hasn't been the number one eSports since the mobas and such right.
Scott: it's been like you know in the top five area.
Scott: so it's probably gonna stay in the top five area just cuz it's fucking counter-strike.
Scott: yep but you know it's not gonna be number one as long you know unless they clean that shit.
Rym: well anyway things of the day.
Rym: what do you got for me?
Scott: what was my thing?
Scott: they all right.
Scott: so this is website and on the website is a map or not?
Scott: I say map.
Scott: it's a globe of the earth an interactive one.
Scott: you can drag and zoom around like a Google Earth kind of deal.
Scott: but on this globe of earth are green dots.
Scott: now this each green dot represents a terrestrial radio station that you can stream on the internet for free.
Scott: so you just zoom in on a green dot and you can hear that radio station playing as if you are standing in that general area on the earth obviously with internet delay.
Scott: also it obviously does not have every radio station there is.
Scott: it has a very small percentage of them because not a lot of them are streaming on the internet for free but it has still plenty because there's so many terrestrial radio stations on earth and it's really fascinating to go and listen to ones far away.
Scott: that's something I do.
Scott: and we travel like we were in Australia.
Scott: yeah and I was like oh my god turn on the Australian terrestrial radio.
Scott: we got to hear what they got here Italian station.
Rym: imagine America like.
Rym: imagine people who are visiting America finding out what's on a.m.
Rym: radio in America.
Scott: oh god yeah listen don't judge us by our craziest people.
Rym: if you ever come to America there's there's you know there's radio.
Rym: we also.
Scott: we also have I think more radio stations in other places cuz we're so big and we had radio before other places and such yep.
Scott: but and we have the AM and the FM and I don't know well other places.
Rym: well so am and FM have different usage profiles.
Rym: am is actually more reliable in a lot of situations.
Scott: well because it's you can get higher power.
Scott: at least the FCC lets you have higher powers like this am stations in New York City.
Scott: it's not just that it's better broadcast in the Empire State Building and you can hear them and like Connecticut and upstate and shit.
Scott: yeah Jersey you can hear them real far away.
Rym: so if you've been playing Zelda which we're gonna talk about at all you occasionally encounter people who have a really weird set of dialogue that suddenly swerves into them threatening you and then they try to murder you.
Rym: yeah
Scott: there's ninjas and if you beat the ninja boss
Rym: members of the Yiga clan
Scott: if you beat that their ninja boss which you have to do at some point if you want to game what will happen is randomly as you walk around the world from that point forward ninjas will just appear and be like haha
Rym: I'm here like they don't even pretend anymore.
Scott: yeah it's just like you be walking through the woods and suddenly you hear like haha poof and there's a ninja and it's like fuck.
Scott: I don't want to fight a ninja right now I'm busy.
Scott: god damn it.
Rym: that was almost a mandark life you did there.
Scott: yeah that's that's what the ninjas do.
Rym: I've only run into the ninjas as disguise.
Scott: yeah you didn't beat the ninja boss yet you didn't.
Rym: I anger the Yiga clan but when you when you kill one of them now when you first start the game like and you run into one of these guys.
Rym: they are crazy dangerous.
Scott: there's a trick to beating those easy ones yeah but one you gotta get it.
Rym: yet have a little bit more equipment and maybe some art containers.
Scott: now there's a trick the regular tiny guys who appear front.
Scott: you can just beat them with just arrows shoot him in the face and he goes ah and then you can shoot him in the face again before he does anything.
Scott: you just keep shooting him with arrow until he died and you can go pick up his rupees.
Rym: yep but they're distinguishing.
Rym: characteristic is that when you kill them they always have bananas and you'll see why when you visit their their hideout.
Scott: so this is a video their entire bananas - ash like I did.
Rym: this is a video that someone made and it's just on Twitter and it is.
Rym: it is the story of link and his bananas and it is more amusing than it should be.
Scott: I recommend cooking five bananas together to make a potion that will get our food of some kind.
Scott: it gives you plus three attack boost.
Scott: so if you drink that shit or eat it whatever I don't even know what kind of food it is.
Scott: just three minute five bananas cooked together.
Scott: you can now beat really strong bad guys with a lot less sword swinging because you do so much more damage.
Rym: yeah put some barbarian gear on you're good to go.
Scott: yeah it's basically like you're eating.
Scott: this is like putting on the strongest barbarian gear.
Rym: so in the moment the booklet book is still Frank Gerberts dune we're going to be.
Rym: well I am going to be because Scott is not coming live at Zank icon in a couple weeks.
Scott: good luck with that.
Rym: on Saturday I'll be doing our grind panel and foreign anime openers which the former you can just watch on YouTube.
Rym: I mean if you're listening to this you don't need to go to that panel.
Rym: I'm literally just gonna do the exact same thing that we do a packs but foreign anime openers.
Rym: the only way to ever see that is by going to a con where I do it and we stopped going to anime Boston because of the security.
Rym: so there are many opportunities to see that panel and it'll never be on YouTube.
Rym: hmm and on Sunday I'll be doing our our rage quitting panel as well.
Rym: hmm and otherwise I'm just gonna be in their tabletop because they actually have a pretty big tabletop area just playing games.
Rym: hmm oh you still haven't put the new book club book on.
Rym: the website still says Rebecca it's your book club.
Rym: oh it is mine.
Rym: I guess Rebecca was yours because I should edit it.
Rym: when did you put Rebecca up?
Rym: I feel like you only did it relatively recently in the span of how long we talked about Rebecca.
Scott: go look and see the exact date I put it up.
Rym: it's all moot because I'm not reading Dune until I beat Zelda.
Scott: yeah even though I've beaten three out of four beasts in Zelda I'm still far away from beating that game and there's just so much stuff.
Rym: yeah so uh the Legend of Zelda Breath of the Wild is the first long-form like like triple-a single-player game I have played in many many many years where I stayed up late on more than one occasion when I should have gone to bed and kept playing it.
Scott: you might have done that for some other Zelda's if you had actually fucking played him.
Rym: yeah I mean I didn't like Twilight Princess that much like I got bored about a third of the way through just stopped.
Scott: that one was okay.
Rym: yeah it just it wasn't.
Scott: the best part about that one was the ancient like you know Triforce area.
Rym: like I didn't even get because the the problem with that game was that the whole beginning of the game which is so slow and easy and dumb and I just got sick of it didn't care anymore.
Rym: I really liked the Zelda 3 remake but it was really just a Zelda 3 remake.
Rym: there wasn't much else to it mm-hmm.
Rym: so I I don't want to say this this is not the best Zelda game but it might be in my top five.
Scott: it's real good.
Scott: top three I mean it's basically even though it you know cuz it's hard to say a lot of people like oh my god best game ever.
Scott: oh my god best Zelda right.
Scott: so it's too soon.
Scott: it's too soon to say that but but what is true is that you know the same way.
Scott: you won't say Evangelion is the best anime there is but it still changed anime and had this huge impact like like a nuke on the anime world.
Scott: right this game has set the new standard for all single-player video games on all platforms.
Scott: it's also it's like if you're not as good as this you're not worth playing.
Rym: it is also definitely told people or shown people what an open world sandbox II type game should be.
Rym: right it's a I mean Fallout 3 right.
Scott: people like oh look at this I was gonna compare it to the same game.
Rym: yeah you wander around Fallout 3 and it's breathtaking for like 10 minutes and then you realize that everything's the same.
Rym: there's nothing.
Scott: follow three is enormous.
Scott: breath of the wild is I can't haven't measured it but it it's definitely bigger.
Rym: I thought it was big already but I went into like this northeastern area that I haven't been to yet like last night is way.
Scott: it's holy shit.
Rym: there's like a whole world over there that I have not even encountered.
Scott: you don't even know how big it is.
Scott: it's so big right I can't?
Scott: that's something I've asked for for so long.
Scott: I'm like Nintendo.
Scott: just make another Super Metroid game exactly the same only like four times as big.
Scott: oh my god just make this game only way way bigger.
Scott: and it's like my other.
Rym: complain about Zelda games for a long time has been.
Rym: I don't want it to be just a linear plot of.
Rym: go here get the item that lets you go to area to go to three.
Scott: so you know Super Metroid I can say is the best game ever still at least for now and super mess Metroidvania ever made.
Scott: Super Metroid perfected the get item to unlock new areas to get item to unlock new areas pattern and at the time that was a revolution in gaming and that is still a great way to make a game.
Scott: yeah the problem is it people started making every game that way.
Scott: every game where you're exploring a large space relatively large space was get the item to open the new area to get the item and get a new ability to open a new area and so forth and that's still a very good game design you know.
Scott: obviously you can follow that pattern and make a bad game or a great game but it just became tired because people have played it so much that now you know the openness of something that is like Zelda 1 which is just go anywhere the hell you want do anything you want became refreshing right?
Rym: yeah that was the thing in the Zelda 1. like I can't.
Rym: I was looking for the quote but I'm pretty sure Miyamoto or someone since I think was Miyamoto said something to the effect of you wanted the game to in some ways evoke the feeling yet as a kid of just wandering through forests and finding stuff right.
Scott: and Zelda 1 and this game have so much in common and evoke that same feeling for the following reasons right.
Scott: so number one.
Scott: the first thing that this is in Zelda 1 have in common is that you know.
Scott: you just appear at the start wherever the hell the start is.
Rym: yep and you don't know shit you don't know anything.
Rym: then you probably have a. well you probably.
Scott: you read the instructions and Zelda 1.
Rym: so you read these directions Zelda 1 or if you're playing breath of the wild.
Scott: you know things about Zelda.
Scott: yeah unless this is your.
Scott: yeah that's your little kid.
Rym: you have this vague idea of I'm linked.
Rym: there's Ganon the princesses out there somewhere.
Scott: yeah and you should eat saving.
Scott: so anyway you see a man wearing red and old white man wearing red with a white beard who you know.
Scott: and so the one he just gives you a sword says don't go alone take this.
Scott: yeah but in in breath of the wild.
Scott: he teaches you everything you need to know to go into the dangerous world which isn't just sword.
Scott: yep right and they give you in that starting area every ability you need to actually play this game and they teach you how to use all those like imagine if it's Zelda 3.
Rym: they gave you every one of those items in the first hour of the game and then they dropped you into the world and said go nuts
Scott: and you can go anywhere and do anything except you're limited by your skills and the dangerousness of the world and you
Rym: don't know about the world.
Rym: so you start playing.
Rym: you're like like oh I'll climb up on that thing and then it's actually way taller than you expected.
Rym: you fall to your death.
Rym: yeah then you're like oh I'll go east and then you see a guy who kind of looks like a lion centaur.
Rym: then you're immediately dead.
Rym: you don't even know what happened.
Scott: a lot of guys one-shot you generally in the game even later in the game even late in the game.
Scott: it's like I'd have like 30 hearts or like like 10 hearts and 20 temporary hearts and a guy hits me and it takes.
Scott: so even with my most defensive armor y'all lose 10 hearts.
Scott: so it's like I got.
Rym: modeling with one of those like particularly pokey Spears can do a lot of damage if you don't have a lot of defense.
Scott: yeah you can get messed up.
Scott: they'll be like a robot with a laser and your old Zelda games.
Scott: those are easy to dodge.
Scott: they weren't a big deal.
Scott: and in this game laser you're on fire and you're dead.
Rym: yeah that sound it makes.
Rym: that music.
Rym: is that piano?
Rym: music starts playing like you see the laser sight on your head.
Scott: oh yeah all right.
Scott: so the other thing that's just like Zelda one right is that as you go in Zelda one there were only like so many different like sprites and different things on the map.
Scott: to you know the light was like tree brown tree staircase yeah rock ground.
Scott: but it's like every area still felt way different right you had all these areas that like fell even though the map isn't that big.
Scott: I memorize the whole freaking thing that like it feels like this geographic zones like it feels like a world.
Scott: it's like you get the beach you got the you know the Lost Woods you got the graveyard mountains you got the forest you have all these like you know in each area sort of has.
Scott: it feels like a separate significant place with like a meaning and a mood to it.
Rym: holy shit just breath of the wild capture that like I'll be riding my horse and I'll see like here's an area where just a bunch of like foxes appear to live and there's like some stuff here in this tiny little area in the middle of this giant world.
Rym: I remember that spot.
Scott: but the other thing that's all the one does to make that even stronger is to create landmarks right.
Scott: so in Zelda one it would be like aha this is the spot on the beach where there's like these weird platforms out in the water.
Scott: oh and this is the spot where there's three trees arranged just so.
Scott: and here's that.
Scott: and here's the screen where there's two big rocks and it's like it has a name.
Scott: and then you play this game and it's like oh there's just landmarks everywhere.
Scott: it's like there's the tree that's on the.
Scott: that's just for some reason on the peak of a mountain.
Rym: yeah I wonder what's up there.
Scott: I wonder what's the deal with that is and it's like oh there's the three caves.
Scott: I don't even know if there is the three caves.
Rym: I'm even better because the carrot like one of the first characters you talk to basically early in the game says there is a village and he gives you directions.
Rym: that are the kinds of directions a real person would give you in the real world to get to a place and the map doesn't just show you where it is.
Rym: you just like go and see oh there's a mountain.
Rym: that kind of looks like what he said.
Rym: I guess I'll follow the road toward that.
Scott: but like those landmarks it's like you know.
Scott: they sort of give you like this feeling of like it help you navigate because you can remember landmarks right and they give you feelings of meaning to places right just like putting a few rocks in a particular pattern in the spot like gives that space like a meaning and a reason to go there and take a look and see what's going on.
Scott: right.
Scott: it's something to look at something to do there.
Rym: now a side point in terms of making it interesting to go and look at those things.
Rym: the the little Korok guy quests there's 900 of them are brilliant in that regard because these quests basically if you ever see something that looks interesting at all odds are if you fuck with it even a little bit you'll get rewarded.
Scott: it does something everything does something.
Rym: so like literally you'll be like riding your horse down a road for many minutes like on your way to a town you've heard of because some guy said there's a town that way I'm super late in the game.
Scott: there's a town that a guy just told me about.
Scott: that I had never been to and I have to go find it now.
Rym: I just found another ancient tech laboratory and I'm like oh great I guess there's more of stuff but you'll just be like on your way to this place and then you see a circle of rocks except one of the rocks is missing from the circle and you're like
Scott: huh and even though this is just like this would be in any other game just like a wasted space just like a grassy area that just exists to me to make it take longer for you to get from point A to point B.
Rym: if you wander off and find a rock and walk back over and put it in the spot to complete the ring totally a quest yep so that's the main difference.
Scott: you talk about fallout 3 right and fallout 3 you have.
Scott: not only are all the different things to do just repetitive it's either like kill some guys or fetch a thing.
Scott: and oh this cave looks exactly just like every other cave.
Scott: this house looks exactly like every other house in in breath of the wild.
Scott: this is huge world but the world is like jam-packed and rich full of stuff.
Scott: everywhere.
Scott: it's like down to the micro and the macro level.
Scott: you know everything is like interesting.
Scott: it's like how many people and how many hours did they spend like manually populating this giant video game space with so much shit and just little details like if you're on a road like at night.
Rym: sometimes you'll see a little bit of torchlight off in the distance and you'll just.
Rym: people are traveling back and forth consistently between places and getting it in.
Rym: if there's monsters there the monster just attack them and if you save them then they react to you and like they remember you and the world just keeps changing as you mess with it it doesn't change them.
Scott: those people's traveling people are mostly set in they are certain but they're all.
Rym: they're almost all tied to some minor quests right some kind.
Scott: but it's like you know it's there isn't like this repeated stuff like everything is varied and you'll see.
Scott: you know and just by taking these sit like you I was I was going down I was horsing down a road and I see to my left there's like a grassy area that's kind of long and has an interesting significant shape to it like a landmark you would see in Zelda 1 and has weird trees like.
Scott: they look sort of like baobab trees from I
Rym: know and it's like in there you go in there
Scott: and it's like
Rym: even
Scott: though this is just a little place that sort of fills up space on the map here in between two different other things like it has the sort of significance it's.
Scott: it's different from other places.
Scott: it's like you pay attention to it just because it's.
Scott: it feels nice in there.
Scott: it's like it has a you know sort of a you know significance to it.
Rym: so it feels real.
Rym: it feels like when I was a kid and it's not like to the woods and it's not just meaningless to go in there.
Scott: just look around.
Scott: it's like there's all kinds of mushrooms to collect in there and this stuff happening in every single one of these places.
Rym: yep like I got.
Rym: I got to one area.
Rym: I said this big grassy field.
Rym: I'm like huh and I see some horses way off in the distance.
Rym: I'm like yeah I don't have a horse with me right now I don't know where a nearby stable is.
Rym: I should go get a horse.
Rym: it'll make this easier.
Rym: and then I start going toward the horses and I realized that those horses all have riders and those riders are all Bokoblins with Spears right.
Rym: so now I got to deal with that.
Scott: so the game is not.
Scott: but it looks like what the negative things in this game.
Scott: right because we just talked about the game.
Scott: we'd be here for like an hour right.
Scott: so there's our negative thing.
Scott: so one negative thing is that the controls are not a hundred percent perfect.
Scott: the camera they're way good.
Rym: actually the camera to scroll faster.
Scott: the pro controller is very very significantly better than the.
Scott: the other regular controllers very significantly better.
Scott: however here's an example of something that is not good right.
Scott: so in every other Zelda game you either couldn't jump or I guess there were 2d Zelda games you got the feather and you could jump with a which is knowing the second Zelda you could jump sure guess so.
Scott: but in 3d Zelda games in 3d Zelda games the jumping was always automatic.
Scott: you would just walk and link would jump.
Scott: right.
Scott: in this game you jump by pressing a button.
Scott: so of course if you're making a video game you want a to be the jump button right because B is the running button.
Scott: it makes sense like Mario.
Rym: there's some knockoff bullshit game.
Rym: then up is the jump on.
Scott: why is the attacking button?
Scott: and in every 3ds all the game so far since there was no jumping you would use a as your sort of interact with things.
Scott: button like read read the sign talk to the person.
Scott: oh so because they ran out of buttons and because you don't need X for the item button anymore X has become the jump button.
Rym: it's like oh my god for like 10 minutes isn't good but you can see why they done that right.
Scott: another thing that's bad.
Scott: there'll be like certain puzzles in the game that are real finicky right as soon as you use the motion controls.
Scott: well that's one thing.
Scott: but you know in other Zelda games let's say there's a block pushing puzzle.
Scott: the block would be like on rails and you couldn't possibly push the block in a wrong way.
Scott: or mess yourself up right.
Rym: and these are all physics based.
Rym: like it's always you might push it off a cliff.
Rym: it's talking.
Scott: well all physics engines so like it sometimes give a real finicky to get the block in just the right spot or you know get that thing balanced.
Scott: just so is that you can complete the puzzle.
Rym: but with that negative also comes a slight positive in that the puzzles can be pretty complex and your solutions can be the kinds of things that in other Zelda games you would think.
Rym: why can't I just do this right?
Rym: why can't I just throw the thing over there?
Rym: because if you come up with a clever way to beat a puzzle it'll probably work right.
Scott: it's finicky because it's free form.
Scott: but by allowing for that finickyness you get the free form.
Scott: this there was a place.
Scott: I just went over there cuz I saw a beach and I wanted to go to the beach and then I saw some stuff in the distance and I wanted to go to it.
Scott: so I did.
Scott: and then when I got over there I saw a real dangerous dude and he was gonna kill me in one shot.
Scott: but I also saw he was keeping his treasure chest in the interesting place I saw from far away.
Scott: so I used my stealth.
Scott: I grabbed the interesting treasure chest that were full of like 500 rupees dove off the cliff into the water before he noticed.
Rym: I spent like.
Scott: you can't do that if the game's not free form and a more strict game would have been like.
Scott: you must come into this area through this entrance.
Rym: you know where you're getting the treasure without beating the bad guy up now to prevent you from because the fact that you can kind of fly and if you level up your stamina and get some climbing gear you can climb real high and just jump into everything.
Rym: so like there's these mazes I found this giant labyrinth.
Rym: the way they prevent you from just flying over the top of it is very clever.
Rym: the game makes like real-world reasons why you can't do something rather than just invisible blocking you like every other Zelda game.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: so if you try to fly over the top of that thing sure that seems to work except there's all these flying ancient monstrosities flying around the top of the thing and they attack you if you come anywhere near the top of that labyrinth
Scott: and even if you go to where you think the end of the labyrinth is and just drop in from the top it's like okay congratulations.
Scott: now you're in the labyrinth but you're in a labyrinth now.
Scott: it's getting out kind of sucks but it's like you can do it.
Scott: go ahead.
Scott: it's like the labyrinth is actually designed in such a way at the bottom where there's all these walls that extend to the ceiling.
Scott: but there are openings in these walls that are only at the bottom.
Scott: and so it's like unless you know the labyrinth already coming in from the top only helps you so much you still have to do some work and you get attacked by those sky watchers anyway and those things are real danger.
Scott: well you went to the suit the most dangerous labyrinth first.
Rym: Wow which is also what I did I didn't know there were other labyrinth.
Scott: there are three labyrinths for the three pieces of Barbaro gear the other two labyrinths.
Rym: I went I saw a tower in the distance and I wanted to get it because I wanted to fill in a part of the map and on my way to the tower I saw the labyrinth.
Rym: I'm like who?
Rym: what the fuck is that I went over there instead?
Scott: I did that too but I went to that area only after having a reason to go to that area.
Scott: that's also my favorite area of the game that Akkala.
Rym: so the feeling of the controls the only times it really gives cause.
Rym: the problem for me is I will often with the regular controller accidentally crouch when I'm in the middle of a fight.
Rym: this is real easy to accidentally push your left thumb a little time.
Scott: you know that's been around since PlayStation where you push the analog sticks.
Scott: I hate that too.
Scott: in as a button that shouldn't be a button add two more buttons.
Scott: I know people are gonna go it's fine and yeah I don't really have a problem with it that often.
Scott: but in this game in principle I don't like.
Scott: because like what?
Scott: if I'm just like moving the stick aggressively I'm going to push it inwards right.
Scott: it's just the thing that happens.
Rym: in fact the more tense the fight is the more likely I'm to push it inwards and that has killed me easily half a dozen times.
Scott: yeah I do not like you know analog sticks being pushed in ever but that's just the thing.
Rym: so whatever yep but that feeling is also is a problem in one very specific minor area that I wouldn't complain about except it's so integral to the game.
Rym: I have thrown my cooking ingredients in the fire next to the cook pot like ten times.
Scott: that's happened a lot to me as well.
Rym: I lost some.
Rym: I saw some good stuff to the fire.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: it was not easy to figure out the interface for like hold Oh hold multiple things and drop.
Scott: it didn't.
Scott: it wasn't obvious okay.
Scott: so another flaw in this game is that it's very annoying early in the game that your weapons degrade.
Scott: they degrade too quickly.
Rym: now I would argue that it's a positive in a very different sense.
Scott: right.
Scott: well that's what I was gonna get right.
Scott: it's like they made this negative thing where you get weapons and you beat a bunch of bad guys up and then your weapons are gone.
Scott: you got to use like the weapons the bad guys dropped or do other things to beat them.
Rym: I use a lot of Bokoblin clubs from the early game I mean even later in the game.
Scott: I'm pretty much using stuff bad guys drop.
Scott: well they're just dropping better stuff for me and that's kind of frustrating like especially way early in the game.
Rym: it's super frustrating but it adds this element combined with the fact that you have stamina like you think I'll just climb to the top of this thing.
Rym: well do you have enough stamina like you might not be able to make it to the top and then you fuck right it and the cooking and the danger.
Rym: it means that it has this sort of like survival in the wild aspect which really adds to what I think.
Scott: what it does is it just forces you to variate what you're doing right and I'll just fight everything you run into.
Scott: well no in other Zelda games right you would get the best stuff and then you would just always use you like in Zelda 64. once you got the mirror shield like that was it?
Scott: yep you're still the one.
Scott: once you got the big once you got the big Goron sword the master sword you that those only two swords you use.
Rym: if you've got the master sword you never use that whiz robe thing ever again.
Scott: right?
Scott: it's like you know once you have certain things you don't use the crappier stuff.
Scott: now it's like yeah you'll find crappy stuff once you have better stuff and it'll be too crappy.
Scott: but you still use a variant stuff to fight different guys.
Scott: you got to get different kinds of arrows and got it.
Scott: you know you got to really mix it up because things are getting destroyed all the time.
Scott: you can't keep using the same.
Rym: it also gives you this sense of a real world because that I'm glad the game didn't make.
Rym: you actually get hungry and need to eat food just to live.
Scott: yeah that that was like.
Rym: you do need to eat food or find places to sleep.
Scott: yeah there aren't hearts lying on the ground.
Scott: right when you kill a bad guy they drop stuff that makes sense for them to drop.
Scott: yeah when you kill a keys it drops bat wings and occasionally extra good eyeballs.
Rym: yeah it's never gonna drop rupees.
Scott: you can turn those into rupees cuz every place that sells and buy stuff will buy things from you for the same exact price.
Scott: yeah so an eyeball is worth X rupees at worst.
Scott: or you can use it for cooking something or take it to the monster shop or you know.
Scott: you get these resources by killing things and you can use them in a variety of ways or cycle.
Rym: just makes the game feel very much like this sort of real world dangerous well environment.
Scott: they did something that no other Zelda game had ever done which is to make rupees matter.
Rym: oh no he's matter a lot.
Scott: every other Zelda game you'd be getting rupees all the time but once you bought everything there was to buy with rupees you didn't need rupees anymore.
Scott: you just got them all the time.
Rym: for what was the minish cab?
Rym: have minish cab I think I nine nine nine rupees and nine nine nine shells.
Rym: I was like.
Scott: well in Zelda one an arrow would cost you a rupee but once you had every it didn't really matter anymore right?
Scott: yeah until this Zelda game it's like.
Scott: I still need more rupees even though I found the bowling game and I'm getting.
Scott: basically I'm basically able to farm rupees at like 280 rupees a minute.
Rym: I've been cooking expensive dishes and selling them right.
Scott: it's like once even though I have a zillion rupees I need more.
Scott: this is a fancy armor I want to buy.
Scott: that cost six thousand rupees and I spent ten thousand rupees like to get a fairy fountain.
Scott: it's like damn.
Scott: I need more rupees all the time and there's plenty of them out there but I still want more.
Scott: I need more rupees.
Scott: no other Zelda game has done that.
Rym: I also appreciate how dangerous it makes the world feel in general like there's this very powerful cycle of your stuff is not that strong.
Rym: you don't have that many hearts so going to places feels scary.
Scott: you're like sneaking around and avoid just like in Zelda 1. if you went up to the northern parts of Zelda 1 and the overworld but when you were not strong enough that it was way dangerous up there you went to the graveyard with like your wooden sword is there?
Scott: take you so many stabs.
Scott: those ghosts would mess you up.
Rym: but then you get some weapons you get some hearts you get some stamina wheels and some confidence you get some you get better at the game and you start to feel better.
Rym: but then you wander into this desert and there's way differently dangerous stuff in there.
Rym: now you're scared again.
Scott: yeah it's like even if you have a whole bunch of stuff and you're like normally in like an RPG you would level up and then you'd no longer be afraid of things once you're leveled up so much.
Scott: yep you still need skills.
Scott: in this game.
Scott: everything is still super dangerous even when you level up a whole time those line else right.
Scott: it's like you can go to a Lionel and it's like if you have skills you can beat Lionel with like a stick in a pot lid or a bunch of sticks and a bunch of pot lids cuz they'll keep breaking.
Scott: or you can go to Lionel the dangerous dude with a whole ton of masterful equipment and still get your ass kicked cuz you don't have skills.
Rym: so Lionel's are interesting.
Rym: it does a million damage because in one of the cool one of the great beast quest you basically they're like yeah the best way to get shock arrows is to go seal him from this.
Rym: Lionel.
Rym: he's super dangerous though watch out.
Rym: so I just snuck up there and I kept seeing him in the distance and I took a picture of him and told my sensor to key on him.
Rym: and I just walked slowly counterclockwise picking up arrows that he had left behind and making sure he didn't see me.
Scott: and if that area is designed in such a way that when you finally finish the loop around and all right at the very end is this little outlet place with a whole bunch of arrows on this one tree and you take them all and then it conveniently there's little outcropping.
Scott: if you jump off of it you land in the water exactly where you need to go.
Scott: yeah so it's like they designed it specifically so that you would sneak around and jump off.
Rym: he saw me and was running at me and I grabbed the arrows and ran and jump right.
Scott: it's like you could have just fought him and beat him.
Scott: it's possible but they designed it so that you would sneak around and jump off and sneaking actually works.
Rym: so the other night I was just wandering.
Rym: it was night in the game because there's day night cycle and rain and lightning and all that stuff.
Rym: it was a night and I just was like on my way somewhere and an area I haven't really explored and I see like something in the distance.
Rym: I can't quite see what it is.
Rym: so I clicked the thing to Emily sit next to me.
Rym: I clicked the thing to zoom in on it.
Rym: Emily's like wow it's a line out like this blue looking one.
Scott: those are real dangerous.
Scott: I couldn't beat that one.
Scott: I beat some other ones.
Scott: I beat a zebra looking one and a red one.
Rym: so he's way far away.
Rym: the blue one messed me up and his eyes are glowing and he's looking straight at me mm-hmm.
Rym: and so I just stand there and I'm like holy shit.
Rym: that is really creepy.
Rym: he's just like looking straight at me but I'm way far away from him right like wait his perfect arrow shot and he's got three hours at once.
Rym: so I on zoom and I just stand there like is he gonna attack me?
Rym: and he just stands there not moving just stare.
Rym: I zoom in again.
Rym: he's always staring at me.
Rym: so finally I back up a little bit.
Rym: he doesn't react at all.
Rym: so I assume maybe you know I'm out of his range.
Rym: so I turn around and start walking away.
Rym: suddenly all these arrows come raining down from behind and I spin back around.
Rym: he's right next to me and then I'm dead.
Rym: yep that was really scary.
Scott: that's the thing is the game is so free even right and it's in his.
Scott: you know you can just do whatever.
Scott: that it creates stories almost like the dwarf fortress creates stories right of the things that happen with all these interacting systems that actually interact and work well together.
Scott: but like in other Zelda games you can only climb in a vine.
Scott: now you can climb on anything almost.
Scott: you know it's out of games.
Scott: you know trying to thing wouldn't work.
Scott: only the very specific thing the specific way to do something worked and you had to do that.
Rym: it's like I can't be clever.
Scott: anything will work.
Scott: all your clever things will actually work.
Scott: you can drop a metal thing from really high up onto a bad guy.
Scott: it'll crush and kill him.
Rym: yeah I've thrown by push boulders down and knocked my bokoblins off their horses.
Scott: right they actually spent some ridiculous amount of time to make all these systems like interact.
Scott: you can put a food on the ground and a bad guy will go over and try to get the food and be distracted.
Rym: favorite thing when I want.
Rym: you know sometimes there's a whole bunch of bokoblins like in a little skull house.
Rym: so what I like to do is I'll roll a bomb down to the entrance and they'll all run out to see it like gather around the bomb and then I blow the bomb up.
Rym: yep you can do stuff like that.
Rym: in the end it just makes games like fallout feel really sparse and crappy.
Scott: it makes every single-player game like this is not worth playing.
Rym: right a single-player.
Rym: this is set the bar for open-world games in a way that no one has ever even come close before.
Rym: I don't think.
Scott: now there are.
Scott: let's see.
Scott: you know.
Scott: the thing is it's like you know.
Scott: there's just so many good things in the game.
Rym: no one will see them all you can write probably beat the game and miss a full third of what you could have.
Scott: right that even though it's not perfect those good things like override all those imperfect parts.
Scott: like.
Scott: you go back and you look at a game like say Mario 64 which like made the 3d platformer playable.
Scott: and now you look at Mario 64 and it's like it has so many problems and it's like it's.
Scott: you know it's finicky and there's some glitches and all this stuff right and this is a lot like.
Scott: the same thing is they took you know this kind of game and they're like no we're gonna show you how to do and they showed everyone how to do.
Scott: but you know in the future you're gonna see that like this game you know has its has its problems yeah but I mean all games will have that sure.
Rym: so it also does a really good job.
Rym: Super Metroid doesn't with the story in that there aren't a lot of co.
Scott: I forgot about that problem.
Scott: that's the biggest problem in this game is this cutscenes with bad voice acting.
Scott: fuck them to hell.
Rym: the voice acting is not great it's atrocious.
Rym: the Japanese voice acting does sound better.
Rym: I haven't heard it but you cannot have Japanese language acting with English subtitles.
Rym: so you got to deal with it.
Rym: but luckily there aren't that many cutscenes.
Scott: there is.
Scott: you haven't gotten a lot of memories.
Scott: there's a cutscene for every fucking memory but there aren't that many memories.
Rym: I've gotten most of them.
Scott: there's a lot of freaking cutscenes.
Rym: yeah there's too many.
Rym: compared to the other things I've done in the game there aren't that many cut scenes is annoying though.
Scott: you haven't done all the things I've done when you.
Scott: oh cuz you've only done one great beast I've only done one great.
Scott: there's like multiple cutscenes per great beast.
Rym: all the cutscenes of the grill of the first great beast I did are my hot shark boyfriend being amazing.
Rym: the other one the other one previous hot shark girlfriend who is now dead being amazing.
Scott: all the cutscenes for the I've done the bird and the camel.
Scott: yeah I haven't gone to Goron land yet.
Rym: I think that's I'm near the Goron land right now I'm not.
Scott: I'm gonna go on land last.
Scott: I'm just gonna do every other land and then once I'm completely cleaned out every other land I'll go to Goron land because it's got to be like tons of stuff in Goron land.
Rym: right I think I'm doing Gerudo next because that's the area.
Rym: camel land.
Rym: I've been poking around Gerudo it's a camel land.
Rym: I've been poking around in that area.
Scott: yeah it's a good area.
Scott: I think that's the area I've cleaned out the most like because I didn't.
Scott: it's so annoying to go in the desert.
Scott: mmm I don't my horses are like hello.
Scott: I don't want to say I have a hundred percent cleaned it out but I feel like I've done like so many quests there.
Scott: there's almost nothing left for me to do there except probably a million Korok seeds.
Scott: yeah maybe a shrine or two who knows?
Scott: I don't feel I'd be very surprised if there's more than like two or three shrines there.
Scott: that I haven't gotten anyway.
Scott: but the story great beast the main four plot areas of the game have so much cutscene stuff and it's kind of annoying with the bad voice acting.
Rym: yeah but if there weren't the voice acting they're not that bad because they are relatively short right.
Scott: one interesting Zelda thing in this game is that in other Zelda games the Triforce is like all up in right.
Scott: they're like Triforce, Triforce, Triforce, Triforce, Triforce.
Rym: This one's definitely Triforce.
Scott: No one has mentioned the Triforce at all right even though it's obvious to anyone who's played Zelda before.
Scott: I've seen the Triforce only on a few things.
Scott: there's like one spot in the game where it's on the ground on a plaque or something.
Rym: And there's those three dragons.
Scott: right.
Rym: so the three dragons and the three shrines or what not the shrines.
Rym: so three power whatever right.
Scott: so nobody has told enemy about the dragons.
Scott: but you'll be playing and you'll just see this freaking long ass Chinese dragon up in the sky making noise doing a thing and you're just like whoa.
Rym: I'm going to hide behind this tree until that is gone.
Scott: gives you like this.
Scott: you know that mystical kind of like.
Scott: what is that?
Scott: no one even told me about that.
Scott: but that's a thing I want to explore kind of feeling and the game rewards you for exploring.
Scott: you know cool stuff that you just see that no one even told you about is just there.
Scott: but there's three dragons.
Scott: one of them is power one of them's courage and one of those wisdom.
Scott: they obviously go with the Triforce.
Scott: and there's three shrines power courage and wisdom.
Scott: and you have to offer a scale to each shrine.
Scott: I did the wisdom one which the dragon was at the shrine.
Scott: it's like it's set up for you to be easy.
Scott: and but it wasn't easy to be that dragon anyway and I put the shrine in there I put the scale in the shrine I found the power shrine and I've seen the power dragon in the sky but I have no idea how to get to the dragon or get a scale from it and I don't know where the courage shrine is.
Scott: though I can guess and I've seen the courage dragon but I have no idea where the courage shrine is or how to get the scale from the dragon.
Scott: you see you mess with the dragon is if I can destroys you.
Rym: so last night I was it was night again and I was like wandering around on the edge of this cliff just in an area and I saw a shooting star like huh and then it came down and crashed way off in the distance.
Scott: I've seen his shooting star in the distance but I couldn't make it there because dangerous stuff.
Rym: yep I saw it crash and I was like whoa.
Rym: so I put it like a beacon pin in it and I started heading that way and I couldn't figure out a way to get where it landed and I gave up.
Scott: I couldn't get where it landed cuz I was murdered by lasers.
Scott: I haven't seen another one.
Rym: yeah I've one place.
Rym: I thought oh I'll just I'll fly down into this area.
Rym: so I'm flying down flying down flying down and I hear the noise.
Rym: if there's a guardian I figure okay I'll do the thing where I like drop kite drop kite and they'll usually miss me.
Rym: and then like five more lasers.
Rym: I literally had six of those lines like all pointed at me.
Rym: yeah and I was like well let's just teleport back to a safe place.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: so examples of annoying things that have happened right.
Scott: so I was riding a horse and trying to get away from some Guardians.
Scott: yeah and I'm like whipping the horse and then the horse just stops didn't?
Rym: did you run the horse out of the horse?
Scott: still shouldn't?
Scott: just?
Scott: I mean I'm okay if it threw me off and kept running.
Scott: right that makes sense.
Scott: a horse just stopping when someone's shooting lasers at it and it's on fire.
Scott: one thing a horse on fire should keep running like holy shit.
Scott: my ass is on fire.
Scott: throw me off I don't care but it stopped.
Scott: and because it stopped if it threw me off I wouldn't have died because I would have been able to like get up and run.
Rym: problem is you're trying to run this horse to death and the horses I'm getting shot at by lasers.
Rym: the horse was like you know what if I just stand here this motherfucker on my back will die and then I get to go home and eat my own.
Rym: no the horse died and I ran away and horses actually die.
Rym: I've never seen a horse.
Scott: yeah you got shot by lasers didn't burn to death it died.
Scott: it was stupid.
Scott: or is that you know?
Scott: they have all these systems that you see so many times that are so intelligent.
Scott: that system was not intelligent.
Rym: maybe that horse just wasn't intelligent.
Scott: no I got a horse.
Rym: now it's uh it's not like the special horse but this horse I have a special but there are other special or fast.
Scott: yeah I have the.
Scott: I have the white horse Zelt the grandchild of Zelda's horse.
Scott: it's the fastest.
Rym: I do not have that horse.
Rym: I just have some random horse.
Rym: I found that is just wicked fast.
Rym: yeah and I have another horse that I stole from some Bokoblin.
Scott: another thing about horses.
Scott: so there's a horse race.
Scott: you probably haven't gotten there.
Rym: I got the horse race.
Scott: it's one of those things you to jump over a bunch of sticks.
Rym: I beat the shit out of that.
Rym: that was so easy.
Scott: I tried to do it and my fucking horse like I'm aimed at the stick dead-on.
Rym: how fast are you going?
Scott: I was going way fast.
Scott: it was the white Zelda horse.
Scott: oh and he just gets up to the stick and just stops but he balked.
Scott: that happens every single time.
Rym: maybe you can't.
Rym: maybe he doesn't like to race pick a different horse.
Scott: I'm just saying it's like that's.
Rym: I beat that race my first time.
Scott: I did multiple tries and didn't beat it even though I had built the skill to do it and I felt like I was doing nothing wrong.
Scott: just the horse was doing perfectly up until this one stick.
Scott: for some reason it always stopped on that stick.
Rym: I think you're doing something wrong.
Scott: there was something wrong with lesson.
Scott: there was something wrong with the like something messed up.
Scott: I don't know what the hell.
Rym: I think you're just doing it wrong.
Scott: go watch on the twitch VOD of like.
Rym: what well what I was doing and see what happened.
Scott: so many fucking tries on this stupid thing and at first I was messing up but eventually I figured it out and just for some reason it just bullshitted me on this one spot.
Rym: yeah I found that horse race to be really easy.
Scott: I felt way easy.
Scott: it felt like I was doing everything right.
Scott: I mean it.
Scott: so it was right way.
Scott: I think it's something maybe a different horse I don't know but it was just fucking bull.
Scott: yeah fucking bullshit there.
Scott: so I was fucked up.
Rym: but in terms of the story aside from the voice acting I like the fact that the story itself is actually I'm a different horse race pretty sparse in that you way.
Rym: I mean it's a you know technology post-apocalyptic world all that stuff and you basically don't really remember shit which works.
Rym: from a storytelling standpoint it's very easy because you don't know what's going on.
Scott: so that doesn't need to have a lot of story right you know it's like you plays all the one.
Scott: the story is in the instruction manual and at the end of the game and nowhere in between.
Scott: I actually think that the story parts actually kind of bother me mostly because it's bad voice acting other than the voice I can.
Rym: I do like the story because it's it's it hints at this.
Rym: you know the long arc of Zelda and how.
Rym: there was a lot of era mm-hmm and then there was the normal era and you live in the post-apocalyptic yeah again and won that last war era.
Scott: yep I like this.
Scott: I like the small stories right like in the town like there's a story of this one person in their deal.
Scott: the big story I don't really care so much.
Scott: those characters are like except shark man.
Rym: I'm pretty invested in the shark fan except like even Zelda Zelda is so annoying.
Scott: I'm like excuse me princess reminds me a little bit of princess bubblegum and that this cell he's definitely trying to be princess bubblegum but she's her personality is unpleasant and like oh my god she's a little more.
Rym: I like how there isn't really at least as far as I've run into much implied romance between Lincoln's.
Rym: all that I kind of like that.
Scott: I like how there was never implied romance before too much either.
Rym: yeah well excuse me there was a lot of romance in the cartoon.
Scott: the cartoon there was sure yeah and in general fan.
Scott: but in the games it's just like you know.
Scott: it's like you sort of assume that just because that's the way human brains are.
Scott: but it's like hey I don't remember them ever kissing or having the same bedroom or doing any you know.
Rym: but I like the fact like for example Miffa you know your dead shark girlfriend mm-hmm.
Rym: she like you like you've ever run into humans in the game and they don't know the fuck you are.
Rym: cuz you you're from a hundred years ago.
Scott: well I have the Master Sword so some of it.
Scott: there's one person who's like oh you are the hero.
Scott: you have the Master Sword.
Scott: there are other people someone I met who was like yeah there was a hero who had this Master Sword a long time ago.
Scott: I wonder if I've ever seen him again.
Scott: I'm like here.
Scott: let me show it to you.
Rym: well highly and any Hylian you meet pretty much who isn't old definitely has no idea who you are or if they know who you are they were not around when you were around last time.
Scott: yeah you've been asleep for a hundred years.
Rym: kids don't care at all.
Rym: kids are just like.
Rym: they just ignore you or that one kid shows you the dark god that he's friends with.
Rym: I like that kid a lot.
Rym: hey mister you want to meet my friend.
Scott: the point is if you need you know I mean this game is so enormous and there's so much stuff in it.
Scott: like if you are a person who plays video games and nervous dad it's must play.
Scott: it's like every other game you know compared to this is like oh if you every night you can't be as good as this with your single-player triple-a game don't even publish it every
Rym: negative I can come up with about this game is outweighed by the fact that I like this game enough to wear instead of teleporting.
Rym: sometimes I ride my horse anyway because it's pleasant.
Scott: I actually stopped riding horses.
Scott: I'm just walking.
Scott: I got so much stamina now it doesn't really matter.
Rym: I like the horse riding because they will just follow a road and I'm kind of scanning.
Scott: yeah the thing with the horse riding is that like I miss small stuff when I'm riding the horses going from place to place real fast right I teleport and walk everywhere I do apply.
Rym: I fly most of my early upgrades which is part of why I don't have the Master Sword yet because I haven't.
Rym: I didn't go to the Dark God to swap everybody the Dark God.
Rym: yeah I'll just get more hearts it's worth.
Scott: but I got a lot of takes a long time to get that many hearts.
Rym: I got a lot of stamina first so I in the early game I could climb and fly to a lot of really dangerous places.
Rym: so I snuck into some towers like when you first see a wiz robe.
Rym: they're like magic man from Adventure Time.
Rym: they're terrifying and free.
Scott: yeah they're not scaring me now.
Rym: no now I can just like arrow them to death if I want yep but yeah the game that.
Scott: the one last thing is the game is so many callbacks to old Zelda's that if you haven't played the old Zelda's you won't get them but they're so unnecessary.
Scott: huh I mean it's not necessary to get them yeah but because I played almost every single player Zelda there is to completion.
Scott: I see all these things and they're so awesome.
Scott: it's like getting the Master Sword.
Scott: you need 13 hearts.
Scott: nope you need 13 hearts to get the magic sword.
Scott: in Zelda 1. the old man won't let you take it.
Scott: unless you have that many heart master you're using it.
Rym: I can have this right.
Scott: there is.
Scott: in Zelda 1 the end of the game is inside of the left rock of spectacle rock which plays with two mountains and in this game there's a place called spectacle rock on the map with two mountains and it's just like.
Scott: there's so many things.
Rym: the woods is just a straight-up lost woods like figure out the maze right.
Scott: there's so many things that are just from old Zelda games that have been just upgraded and inserted into this Zelda game especially Zelda 1 the other open-world Zelda that if you know those things it's like even though even the most dangerous guy but the line.
Scott: now is the most dangerous guy from Zelda 1 the line?
Scott: now it's the same guy a centaur with a sword who shoots things that you think the most dangerous guys tell the one is blue his robe.
Scott: no blue his robe is not as dangerous as line.
Rym: those were real easy to kill if you had a shield.
Rym: so real dangerous if there was a lot of them plus dark knots were way harder to kill than Lionel's.
Scott: Lionel did way more damage.
Scott: you would mess you up.
Rym: don't get hit by him jeez.
Scott: they're tough especially this via screen just full of line up.
Rym: yeah I cannot recommend this game enough.
Scott: yeah I mean you know a switch is out now.
Rym: I mean we could probably we could literally probably do a Zelda only show the switch factor right with the portableness.
Scott: it's like how can you not?
Scott: yeah like I'm going to count in a few weeks I'm just gonna play Zelda and if you train if you're not buying a switch if you're one of those people who accidentally bought a Wii U spy this game you can buy the game for Wii U.
Rym: yeah cuz.
Rym: then I mean no there aren't other switch games.
Scott: I mean worth playing.
Scott: you probably spent as much money on steam games you aren't playing as you would pay to get a switch and this game and you're actually gonna play that if you buy it like all the steam games you bought for the same amount of money.
Scott: so just do it.
Rym: yep but like we could literally probably do weeks and weeks of shows.
Rym: just about Zelda.
Scott: it's so big I can just talk forever.
Scott: yeah which is how every game every single player game you know to be worth.
Rym: what can I say about Fallout 3?
Scott: for me to spend $50 and that much of my life on a game it should be so big that I can't I can talk about it for hours.
Scott: otherwise why is it even worth playing?
Rym: beat fallout 3 that giant you know quote-unquote open-world.
Rym: and the only thing I really would say that was interesting was the end was dumb because the one you could have said a robot in or the one guy was already radioactive immune.
Rym: so like it didn't make sense.
Rym: yeah I don't have any interesting stories.
Rym: oh I found a gray building filled with dudes and I killed them.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the picture on page one of the subs of GeekNights in order the money was on continuing basis are oh my god I already see you guys types of stuff down there.
Rym: all right let's see.
Rym: Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette.
Rym: great job.
Rym: emoji.
Rym: mystati.com.
Rym: William Isebros Jeremy Minor zatai unmei moku shiroku.
Rym: zatai unmei moku shiroku kiwi wo kiwi wo shinjiteru samui yoromo the terrible secret of space.
Rym: four to one creations.
Rym: or is there really a god watching everything?
Rym: sherman von horrell rare laval james david white rachel montanona superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make rimsay guard loo sailor vista Matthew Smith Don Schleicher jar tovish and Joe Shiro.
Rym: Joe star Tyler Eller Shawn Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin.
Rym: it was the best of times.
Rym: it was the blurst of times.
Rym: Brian Cedroni the height of the color turquoise redacted.
Rym: Chris midkiff Chris Knox dangle Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn and I'm gonna go eat some food hopping over on the white-hot sand.
Rym: here he come with some for me freshly taken from banana tree banana man.
Rym: give me double on the bonus one.
Rym: give me more four of all me friends.
Rym: he's banana flow and they're fucking.
Rym: do you want a banana?
Rym: peel it down.
Rym: do you want this banana for you?