Rym: it's Wednesday October 4th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights spooky GeekNights.
Rym: tonight we're talking about Scooby-doo.
Rym: great you were the one who wanted to do like a Halloween theme this month.
Scott: yeah but the theme was a good idea.
Scott: the thing is like always.
Scott: I don't have any actual episode ideas.
Scott: oh no and limiting us to a very specific set of ideas.
Scott: you sometimes you know we say you know limitation boost creativity but in this case it just makes it even harder to come up with an episode idea because you might come up with a good one it's not spooky.
Scott: and then what?
Rym: ah but I could well one.
Rym: we'll put that in a Google keep somewhere and then forget about it.
Rym: that's right but too much more important we are.
Rym: I can kind of skirt it by just doing the ephemera of spooky voice in the beginning and make the music a little bit putting too much effort.
Scott: all right.
Rym: yeah thank you.
Rym: I think you vastly overestimate how much effort that took.
Scott: last weekend down town East village ish area there was a I guess it was this place called the spoke gallery.
Scott: it's one of those one-room art galleries.
Scott: you know the?
Scott: yeah I've seen those where they have a showing.
Scott: they put everything up on the wall and then they everything's for sale and then they put in another show and people have parties there and stuff right you know that kind of place.
Scott: yeah they had a one weekend it was Friday night was the gallery opening party whatever but then Saturday and Sunday was the come check out the gallery and then that was it.
Scott: but it was a Miyazaki art gallery.
Scott: obviously no art by actual Miyazaki just art by other people.
Scott: you know of Miyazaki things.
Scott: it was mostly Princess Mononoke's Totoro's.
Scott: yeah he's now she goes the popular ones.
Scott: I didn't see any of the less popular ones really you know.
Scott: but yeah it was definitely some cool stuff there.
Scott: there was a thing where there was a big giant Totoro mural and there was a red umbrella and you could take a picture next to it.
Scott: yeah and there was like a lamp that was made by like cutting white paper into boxes.
Scott: that were concentric boxes and then there's a light bulb in the middle.
Scott: it was way cool.
Scott: yeah there's a lot of good stuff there.
Scott: if you didn't go yeah sorry you don't live here and can't do stuff like that.
Rym: well similarly because you know in New York there's basically sort of a Ghibli thing where every year.
Rym: you can just see pretty much every Ghibli movie in the theater.
Scott: G kids now owns the the US I think I don't know even broader than that but they definitely own the US distribution rights to all like if not all almost all studio Ghibli films.
Scott: so and I think they're putting them all back out on Blu-ray DVD whatever it is but they also put them in theaters like constantly.
Scott: so even if you're not in New York City if you're somewhere near I guess a populated area that's populated enough that G kids will put it in a theater there.
Scott: you got chances to see these things.
Scott: so follow G kids on Twitter Instagram whatever yeah and you'll get notified about these things.
Rym: so a while ago I watched Lapita again and just just recently me and Emily we didn't go to the exhibit you went to but we went and saw Nausicaa which I've seen it before several times but I'd never seen it in a theater with a really good projection mm-hmm because when I've seen it in the theater is usually an original film print.
Rym: but this was like a nice digital projection and it was basically perfect.
Rym: like it was as good a quality as you're ever gonna see that movie in a theater I don't think you could get it a better quality and something that kind of stood out.
Rym: I really enjoyed it.
Rym: I'm actually really glad I went to see it because I noticed a bunch of stuff I never noticed before.
Rym: but comparing it to Lapita I I think Lapita is for me at least a better movie.
Scott: Lapita was came before.
Rym: not yeah yeah but Lapita.
Rym: so the differences I really noticed was that Nausicaa despite how long it is really bit off a lot of story to try to tell.
Rym: well even that it only covered covered the first volume of an even longer manga.
Scott: yeah that's the thing.
Scott: is it was it was cover it was trying to cover this.
Scott: Lapita was basically I think was based on something I don't know what but it wasn't like.
Scott: you know abridging some you know grand story.
Rym: right yeah wherever now Nausicaa is an abridged version of this gigantic epic manga even what it like the tiny piece it tried to tell it still struggled to fit all that into a couple hours because it is a long ass movie.
Rym: it's two full hours long which I guess I've always known and I always forget until I watch it again.
Rym: but what was interesting is that Nausicaa actually had it really doesn't trust the audience to understand what the hell's going on and the characters repeatedly remind you what the plot is and really really explain everything multiple times whereas Lapita when I because I saw it again recently as
Scott: well as going on and
Rym: does both doesn't explain shit.
Rym: the world is similarly complicated.
Rym: but rather than explaining it all they'll just be like a little bit of stuff in the background.
Rym: that implies all of that and if you don't notice that well fuck you.
Rym: the only thing I noticed that was kind of interesting was that Nausicaa has really good characters and really it's the story of those characters having their arcs.
Scott: you mean the the flying space pirate people.
Rym: meanwhile Lapita has also a flying space pirate people who don't really progress or change or have arcs and Lapita is much more about the world than the characters.
Rym: that's true and I like they're both really good for different reasons but I feel like Lapita actually had a better soundtrack.
Rym: I feel like the soundtrack was better mastered and I enjoy the subtlety of the environmental storytelling of Lapita and while Nausicaa
Scott: I enjoy the robots of Lapita yeah
Rym: but like the environment like the world of Lapita is really interesting and subtly told and you could miss a lot of what's implied by the background stuff and the world around it Nausicaa is like hey this is what this world is about.
Rym: hey this is what these things are about.
Rym: but then it sort of skips past all that to focus on these characters and how fucking badass Nausicaa herself is.
Scott: yeah we rewatched the castle of Akagliostrum.
Rym: oh my god I should watch that again.
Rym: it's been too long uh-huh.
Scott: so I got a booray rip from Yarr pirate me because I couldn't find any legal means of watching it other than buying a booray.
Scott: and yeah that looks way better than the version I've seen before.
Rym: I think the first time I saw Akagliostro was literally a dubious fan sub at RIT anime out of VHS.
Scott: the one thing that I noticed this time because it wasn't I didn't really notice sub.
Scott: obviously everything we're talking about is subtitles of course one thing I noticed this time compared to any previous time that I watched it was that you know usually in a lot of LuPone movies right the good ones is where you know.
Scott: it shows you how Zenigata is a badass but LuPone is just even more badass.
Scott: yeah that's the only reason he can't catch him but he could catch anyone else no problem right?
Scott: oh and in some of them people making those LuPone movies don't understand that.
Scott: and they make Zenigata to be out to be like a dum-dum.
Scott: yeah like a derpader.
Scott: you know Barney Fife kind of cop.
Rym: yeah you can't make him that way.
Scott: yeah no in Castle of Akagliostro I didn't realize but he is the good way in that movie oh yeah.
Scott: and also his screen time in that movie is basically like second.
Scott: you know it's like Jigen and Goemon have almost Jigen's in the beginning then he's basically gone.
Scott: once he gets the anti-tank rifle you don't see right.
Scott: Goemon appears out of nowhere does almost nothing cuts like two things and that's it right.
Scott: and Fujiko is important but is also barely there in the movie.
Scott: it's really also she.
Rym: it's good.
Rym: Fujiko like she just is a good guy in this one.
Scott: oh yeah but it's basically you know LuPone one Zenigata two and in that movie and also the bad guy he's just like the stupid count guy.
Scott: yeah but the henchman ninja guy oh yeah I forgot about him.
Scott: they're way.
Scott: no not him the whole group of them with the pointy claws.
Scott: they are way creepier and super more dangerous than I remembered.
Rym: well that that place that they're all in is real dangerous like LuPone yeah as badass as he is and Zenigata as bad as that's the real number one character in the movie is Cagliostro the place.
Rym: yeah that's what it's actually but I always appreciated in that movie how LuPone is a badass and this place is dangerous like it almost killed him before and it feels like it might kill him this time.
Rym: yeah and Zenigata is ostensibly a cop and he's safe there but the reality is that he is in just as much danger as LuPone just by being there.
Scott: yeah
Rym: I think my two favorite scenes that entire movie are that with your sword and my anti tank rifle yeah and when LuPone is wearing the scuba stuff and he's in the
Scott: fountain
Rym: and Zenigata just leans over and almost sees him like that's the moment of yeah LuPone you're clever but Zenigata is like yeah a second like one
Scott: degree
Rym: angle away from catching you mm-hmm I can.
Rym: well I think we gotta watch that movie again watch it.
Rym: now she go again pump me up in a big way cuz that was real good despite the I had some of them.
Rym: I mean there's issues with the movie but we've reviewed it before.
Rym: I think you want to go through all the one at a time.
Scott: we should almost all of them.
Rym: I'll check to see if there's any.
Rym: we haven't given a fully.
Scott: things I haven't seen are like ocean waves and my neighbor the Yamada's.
Rym: and you saw.
Rym: I think we saw.
Rym: oh it's so up on poppy Hill and the air.
Scott: what's the airplane one?
Scott: that's not Porco Rosso the newer one.
Rym: oh I thought oh that's a real fucking good movie.
Scott: I don't think I saw that one.
Rym: it's it's the hardest one to watch because it is really really real and brutal and it's about a really situation.
Scott: all right let's continue with our GeekNights here.
Rym: okay but I will say I've been about be hell really even enjoyable when you watch it.
Rym: but I defy anyone to remember the name of any character.
Scott: I can't never the characters and he was in good things.
Rym: you won't remember anything that happens enough on poppy Hill.
Rym: it's good and then you'll forget it.
Rym: it's like eating a really good candy anyway.
Rym: so yeah got any news.
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: so Katie cook who we have mentioned on GeekNights before but not in a very long time she is a person who's just like a really amazing artist who does stuff.
Rym: yes follow her on Twitter.
Scott: she's like she goes like a zillion comic cons every year and hits up the artist alley.
Scott: other things that she's done.
Scott: there's a book ABC 3po.
Scott: yeah oh yeah she does a lot of official Star Wars arts and things for properties.
Scott: like if you buy Star Wars trading cards like there'll be cards in there that are hand-drawn by her like randomly inserted zones.
Scott: and she has a webcomic Gronk which is about a little green monster whatever.
Scott: but anyway she has a new webcomic.
Scott: what's it called?
Rym: nothing special?
Scott: nothing I guess it's nothing special.
Scott: but the interesting thing about this is that you know obviously you got to read this cuz Katie cook webcomic.
Scott: but the thing that's interesting is that this is up online webtoon right.
Scott: so if you don't know what the deal is right is in the United States we have Google right and Google is provide search and services right in Korea South Korea.
Scott: obviously there's a company called neighbor and neighbor provides search and content like it's really like.
Scott: from what I can tell it's like it's the only site you need to go to.
Rym: really yeah now there's obviously like.
Rym: that would be a problem in America.
Scott: but anyway one of the things that they provide neighbor is line which is sort of I guess the idea.
Scott: it's like a chat service.
Scott: in fact in Times Square there's like a line store that sells character goods of the characters that they made that are in the emojis the stickers in line like the duck if you see these characters or know them like the yellow duck with a little tiny beak in the middle okay
Rym: okay
Scott: but I'm not.
Scott: I can't tell apart the cow cow talk characters from the line characters but whatever.
Scott: but another thing they do is webcomics and webcomics are way way big.
Scott: in South Korea like a webcomic artist could be like a famous person who appears on TV there's actually a webcomic artist I've seen on like cooking shows doing cooking.
Scott: we've got famous by doing webcomics.
Scott: imagine if you saw Mike and Jerry on like NBC on a cooking show.
Scott: it's like what the hell.
Scott: but no so this even though it's not Korean is that same service right?
Scott: but doing webcomics in the US publishing them and that's really quite fascinating.
Scott: what's up with that?
Scott: what are the comics?
Scott: they got on there?
Scott: right?
Scott: what's going on with this?
Scott: so you might have seen Toblerone's all over Twitter lately in an anime contest all the Toblerone's on Twitter first and then it took like a week to figure out what the all the deal was.
Scott: and then after I figure out the deal was on the way home for that Miyazaki exhibit.
Scott: there was an empty storefront with big glass panes for you know walls you just glass walls basically and those glass panes are filled 100% with two giant advertisements for this show.
Scott: yeah which is hilarious.
Rym: so yeah basically the story is if you wonder what the hell was up with that is that there's this anime and it is on Netflix only.
Rym: but it is an anime produced by Japanese animation studios and such for Netflix.
Scott: but can you watch it anywhere in the world that has Netflix?
Rym: or only if I know I have not watched it it's called neo-yokio which is a real bad name and as far as I can tell it's a bunch of weeb nonsense amped up to 11 all right.
Rym: and the reason it's interesting is that it's Jaden Smith's anime.
Scott: Jaden Smith if you don't know is Will Smith son and he's a really interesting dude.
Scott: yeah because like on the one hand like I guess he has some kind of skill.
Scott: he was in that created cardi kid movie.
Scott: right he has some sort of acting celebrity talent of some kind.
Scott: he has fans of some kind.
Scott: you know he has some popularity.
Scott: yeah as far as I know hasn't done anything evil.
Scott: there's no reason to hate him.
Scott: you know you might not be a fan of him because you know you're not a fan of everyone but whatever but he has been known to say some crazy things like he's definitely a nerdy weeb type person.
Rym: he said some things in the past like he's gonna be a combination of nerdy weeb super fashion and already rich so living this sort of jet-set life and those three combined into this weird amalgam of an internet personality.
Scott: I guess your dad as well.
Scott: yeah it's like all right.
Scott: but yeah I guess Netflix.
Scott: I don't know if Netflix got him to do this show or if he got Netflix to do this.
Rym: yeah I didn't look into the deal but this show he's the I can tell because most of the memes the internet shit I saw about this show was like so ridiculous nonsense that I assumed it was people making fun of the show.
Rym: but it appears that the show is literally like that mm-hmm.
Rym: and what's the plot?
Rym: the plot is ridiculous.
Rym: Jaden Smith plays Kaz Khan a so-called majestic rat who works as a demon exterminator maybe watch this with his and Agatha played by Susan fucking Sarandon.
Scott: well Netflix has money.
Rym: but yeah maybe I should watch this which is interesting because you know what Susan Sarandon was also in recently what Rick and Morty.
Rym: okay and she's doing voice acting and she's really good at it.
Scott: probably her agent is like yeah let's get some voice acting where it gets real easy.
Scott: you get some money all right.
Rym: hangs out with his friends Lexi Gottlieb and his rival arch Angelo Corelli for the title of most eligible bachelor and it's just fucking crazy as far as I can tell.
Rym: okay some like dinky anime cons are already like denying content about this show claiming it's not anime and there's anime register like.
Rym: it's not anime.
Rym: it's Jaden Smith.
Scott: it's anime.
Rym: whether you like it or not mmm that is the matter.
Scott: I do not really care if it's technically anime or not.
Scott: that is a pedantic argument.
Scott: it is technically anime I have no interest in.
Scott: what I do have interested is that it is hilarious that this exists and it is good to know about even if you're not gonna watch it.
Rym: yep I feel like we will review it at some point.
Rym: oh yeah avoid that kind of thing.
Scott: it's just too hilarious.
Scott: yeah good or bad it could be the worst thing ever.
Rym: there's no way.
Scott: there's no way.
Scott: this cannot be one of those things that's actually bad boring bad.
Scott: it's gotta either be so bad it's hilarious and wraps around or it's good or it's wacky.
Scott: it's it's Zazen Jotaro action?
Rym: maybe some Excel saga?
Scott: who knows?
Rym: so yeah this exists and as much as I feel like everyone knows about it I it became readily apparent that a lot of people do not know that this exists or don't know why Toblerone.
Rym: so here you go.
Rym: this is it?
Scott: this is why Toblerone's are on your Twitter.
Rym: so stay tuned.
Scott: one one last thing.
Scott: we all know about crunchyroll.
Scott: yeah I'll know about funnymation.
Scott: we all know about Netflix and Hulu.
Scott: are the places to legally watch the animes in the US online streaming and such right.
Scott: but what some people may not know about is anime strike.
Scott: anime strike we may have talked about on the show.
Scott: it's basically crunchyroll by Amazon.
Scott: I think you have to pay extra money even if you have Amazon Prime to get anime strike.
Rym: oh they got a good show in here.
Scott: but we already did you know judge anime by its cover for the new season.
Scott: it's starting basically right now and next week.
Scott: so we sort of know a little tiny tiny bit about each of the shows that are coming.
Scott: so when I keep seeing news is now that are like here the shows that are streaming I'm like oh I actually know what shows are talking about for one.
Scott: so I guess it's going to be that way from now on if we keep making the show.
Scott: but the show that I most want to see the number one Shiki Inuyashiki which we have done an episode on the manga before on.
Scott: let's go look it up.
Scott: the anime of that show is going to be on anime strike.
Rym: I already pay for crunchyroll in Netflix.
Rym: I am paying for anime strike.
Scott: do not know if and if it will be streaming anywhere else other than anime strike but that is annoying because I don't pay for anime strike right now and that's the show that I want to see above all other shows.
Rym: please stream this show on another service that I do pay for yep because it's funny though I've been watching more anime on Netflix than I have been on crunchyroll lately.
Scott: I've currently am paying for crunchyroll and also Hulu.
Scott: I'm only paying for Hulu because South Park.
Scott: as soon as South Park season ends I'm gonna switch to Netflix to catch up on all these.
Scott: I haven't been on Netflix in years.
Scott: I'm gonna catch up on all the Netflix biz.
Rym: yep meanwhile you're not even caught up on like adventure time which I'm just buying on Amazon.
Scott: at this point I'm waiting for adventure time to be over a hundred percent over no more adventure time ever.
Scott: and then I'm gonna either go back to episode one or where I left off which is somewhere around.
Rym: yeah what was going on when you left off?
Scott: well there was that there's the series with the vampires and Marceline thing.
Scott: you got that far and then there was the.
Scott: yeah there was like a miniseries.
Scott: yeah action yes takes one and then there was some stuff after that.
Scott: I definitely saw but I definitely didn't get to the part they talk about with like islands and water and Finn going over the ocean or whatever.
Scott: I didn't get that far.
Scott: so it's somewhere between the stakes and the ocean part that I stopped.
Rym: there's islands there's elements and elements sets the stage for the end of the show and then there's the season.
Rym: that's on now which is the end of the show.
Scott: okay so what you tell me when the final episode is out and then I'll go figure out where I was or go back to the very beginning?
Rym: yep so yeah anime strike.
Scott: yeah this is happening one hand.
Scott: it would be nice if as a person who is an Amazon customer right you does almost everything Amazon.
Scott: it'd be nice if say crunchyroll Netflix everyone else went away and anime strike was the place to get anime.
Rym: but do you want a monopoly?
Scott: I mean no it's kind of nice this all this competition too but I need to be able to.
Scott: it's annoying that to see all the anime I want to see I got to go to multiple sites.
Scott: I know already I one site to have all the anime that I want to see.
Rym: here's how I go cuz I. there's some Showtime shows I like to watch.
Rym: there's HBO there's all these different services and they're all competing with each other.
Rym: the new Star Trek is on its own thing which means I'm just never gonna see it.
Scott: apparently I'm not gonna see it either because I don't give.
Rym: so what I do now is pretty much I subscribe to a small number of those services and if something is important enough to see and it isn't on one of those I just pirate it.
Rym: and I feel like I'm actually pirating more now than I did a few years ago because of the separation of all these streaming services.
Scott: yeah I mean this is the.
Scott: you know we talked about how shitty cable TV was.
Scott: the shittiness of cable TV you get into the internet now right?
Scott: the shittiness of cable TV was that you paid for this package that got you all the content literally every channel.
Scott: but you're like fuck this.
Scott: why am I paying for all the shit I'm not watching?
Scott: right?
Scott: why am I paying 40 bucks a month for all this shit?
Scott: I'm not why.
Scott: that's why a lot I'm just buying on Amazon right?
Scott: so now they go to streaming and it's like all right.
Scott: well now you're paying five bucks a month to watch just what you want to watch.
Scott: oh but actually you need to get like ten different streaming services in order to watch all the things you want to watch.
Scott: but here's where they're paying.
Scott: and now it's cable.
Scott: again it's like no I need the shows I want to watch with nothing else at the appropriate price.
Rym: I know right I'm otherwise a pirate a monitor premium like I said Adventure Time Steven Universe over the garden wall.
Rym: I just bought them on Amazon not streaming.
Rym: but you know you pay money like 30 or 40 bucks for a season and you just get the entire thing.
Rym: you can watch it anytime forever.
Scott: too much money.
Scott: how many seasons of Adventure Time are there?
Rym: fuck if I know I just buy it.
Rym: cuz if you add up the monthly fees of like a service I guess there isn't a Cartoon Network service so there isn't even an equivalent.
Scott: there's no as far as I know no service offers streaming of every Adventure Time episode yep.
Rym: so I've bought seasons of it and that's been cheaper than a streaming service.
Scott: I can't get it on.
Scott: I'll pick the streaming services.
Scott: I'll keep doing what I'm doing.
Scott: we're just switching between them canceling one signing up for another canceling that one signing up for another.
Scott: yep right but if there's something I want to watch and I can't like it's not on a convenient service or whatever.
Scott: I'm just gonna be our fuck buying a thing specifically.
Scott: that's not worth it.
Scott: it costs so much fucking money.
Scott: yep.
Rym: and the last news.
Rym: I'll just mention it briefly.
Rym: but if you're not going to PAX unplugged you should and you're an anime fan especially if you're listening to this night of GeekNights you should check out anime NYC because it probably is going to be the best.
Scott: we won't be going to this if we pax unplugged.
Rym: it was not coincidentally the same exact weekend yep because as much as I like anime there's a reason GeekNights Tuesday is the easiest show to do and we've done like almost 50 panels at PAX is.
Rym: but anime NYC I'm not promising it's gonna be good but it has the best chance.
Scott: it's good enough that I would go to it and we stopped going.
Rym: I promise that it's good enough that I would go to it knowing what I know now and we have cut literally every anime con out of our schedule at this point mm-hmm and if we re-add one as long as it doesn't continue to overlap with PAX Unplugged.
Rym: I'm mr.
Rym: going to end my NYC.
Scott: well we can find out now how the first one went when we decide about next year.
Scott: yeah some other news is oh you got more news.
Scott: I know some.
Scott: oh so oh this is a news.
Scott: anime NYC.
Scott: I was thinking cuz you started talking about convention I was starting to think about a moment.
Rym: yeah but I think that means it's time for.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: what do you got?
Scott: so this is a video from before I was born in 1979 and it shows some place in Iowa.
Scott: this is only.
Scott: this is on the Iowa Public Television YouTube channel where it is loaded with a wide variety of things a very wide and this is a video of in Iowa in 1979 in color a rolling pin throwing competition.
Scott: that's all you got to know.
Rym: and but this is pretty amazing already mm-hmm oh my god look at all that old camera equipment.
Rym: look at that camcorder mm-hmm.
Rym: oh my god I mean.
Scott: look at the quality of video for 1979 at a rolling pin throwing competition.
Rym: hey yeah that is definitely 1979. look at look at that shirt.
Rym: look at that guy with them overalls.
Rym: look at the way.
Rym: oh my god look at that microphone mm-hmm.
Scott: this is magic yep.
Rym: so my thing of the day.
Rym: a while way back I had a thing of the day that was basically this guy who takes like.
Rym: he's a really good musician and he takes classical music and mashes it up with other classical music on the piano in a very technically proficient manner and this individual has now done something very nerdy that you all will enjoy.
Rym: so if you listen to those mashups that I linked you before as things the day a long time ago and didn't enjoy them because you're a Philistine who doesn't understand classical music it didn't recognize the cleverness of what was going on.
Rym: here's that exact same thing with Nintendo music Pokemon Megaman 2 a bunch of different legends and Zell does in there yep and it starts out good.
Rym: but listen watch and listen to this all the way to the end because it charges its laser and it definitely saves the best for last and it kicks it into high gear right around when Megaman 2 comes in.
Rym: oh yeah Megaman 2 and Star Fox combined and it only goes up from there.
Scott: all right.
Scott: so some meta things that are going on.
Scott: so this weekend is I guess evil Columbus Day weekend.
Scott: fuck Columbus fuck him in the ass.
Scott: yep I don't celebrate that shit but we don't have to go to work.
Scott: so we're probably we're all doing stuff.
Rym: anyway there's gonna be no Tuesday show.
Rym: cuz I realized that's when the hockey game is.
Scott: yes I was about to say that tonight is puck night.
Scott: that is October 4th.
Scott: NHL regular season begins and for the Rangers it begins tomorrow but we're going to a hockey game next Tuesday so there won't be a show.
Scott: yep next weekend after that we are doing a thing at our friend Matt's house.
Scott: we're called temporarily calling review con or whatever.
Rym: yeah this is not so before any of you just man GeekNights you know how we talk about how we're starting a convention.
Rym: this is not that this is a separate event.
Scott: that yeah it's not a convention.
Rym: it may turn into one someday years and years.
Scott: basically what we're gonna do is just gonna go to his house and play board games all fucking day pros only serious business right and play a ton of games.
Scott: that will have a huge stock of tabletop games to review and we're gonna stream so you could tune into that on from mostly prop maybe the night of Friday the 13th in October but also Saturday the 14th is where most of the action is gonna be okay.
Rym: you miss that.
Rym: don't worry because the output of that convention that event will be a shit ton of game reviews like really high quality.
Scott: also right November 4th and 5th in New York is gamer X East - yeah right we went to gamer X East one.
Scott: this is gamer X East - it's coming.
Scott: that same weekend is also the netrunner World Championships Oh and also the New York City Marathon if you care okay.
Scott: and then of course two weeks after that right November 16 17 18 19. well you know that weekend whatever dates are in there.
Scott: yep the week before Thanksgiving is PAX.
Scott: unplug it.
Rym: the inaugural PAX unplug.
Scott: remember Pennsylvania fill a piece of shit Delphi.
Rym: this is a tabletop convention but it has all the accoutrements of a full packs just all focused exclusively on tabletop.
Scott: that's right.
Scott: there won't be no Nintendo booth there unless they're bringing some Mario Party and even then it had to be Mario Party the card game or something and it's not sold out.
Rym: yet you can get badges and I'm telling you right now PAX Unplugged it will fucking explode.
Scott: it will sell out.
Rym: it is going to.
Rym: this one's gonna be a little smaller partly because it's the first one.
Rym: but remember the first PAX East and what PAX East turned into.
Scott: even the first PAX was hella small.
Scott: the Necro Lava Con was even smaller.
Rym: but PAX East the first one was already exploding and then it double exploded.
Rym: so unplugged is gonna be way big.
Scott: and this is the first one since there's no other major competition for tabletop cons in the Northeast.
Scott: right.
Scott: you know the Gen cons and the origins.
Rym: those places are like the Midwest and they're a different kind of tabletop con.
Rym: they're not the packs.
Scott: there is no tabletop con like.
Scott: this is the only one in the Northeast.
Scott: in this major population center is gonna be big and they should have an unplugged West because they don't have anything like this either.
Scott: as far as I know I'm already pushing hard ones.
Rym: I'm already because you know there's PAX dev which is before PAX West in Seattle which is the two-day game industry.
Rym: only black box no everyone signs NDA's you know.
Rym: talk about stuff openly because no one's gonna spill the beans.
Rym: I feel like we need a tabletop like dev unplugged before this one down the road.
Rym: I'm gonna push hard for that because I feel like the tabletop industry is kind of like how yeah you get like high fashion that turns into regular Walmart fashion.
Rym: I feel like the or comics and cartoons drive live-action remakes and stuff.
Rym: I feel like tabletop is where a lot of the real core cutting-edge game design and development happens and then that spills into video games.
Scott: so that's the GeekNights calendar.
Scott: remember to go to all the places on the.
Scott: if you really care about GeekNights so much that you're either watching the stupid stream on YouTube right now we're gonna be a gamer acts even if they don't accept our panels.
Scott: sure we're gonna be right there.
Rym: we're gonna be.
Scott: in fact at least one day we'll go to it.
Rym: we're gonna be at PAX unplugged because this is like.
Rym: this is the convention that was made for us anyway.
Scott: but yeah like I was saying if you're not if you're if you're sad enough that you're watching GeekNights live on YouTube which you can do or listening to it as a podcast like wow you should go to all the places on the internet that GeekNights is like our forum at community dot front row crew dot com our website at front row crew.
Scott: calm.
Scott: both of our YouTube channels Twitter's Facebook's Instagram's every kind of social place that there is.
Scott: we have things and those are all better than the actual product of GeekNights.
Rym: there is a lot of biz on our YouTube channel and we're going to be posting.
Scott: you know I'm basically I'm putting in a lot of effort to post to all the things more frequently.
Rym: oh look GeekNights is live right now on YouTube.
Scott: yeah that's don't watch.
Scott: that definitely have something better to do.
Scott: but if you're really so sad that you don't there it is.
Rym: there are ten people watching right now and there's a lit chat where they're.
Rym: they're talking.
Scott: surely they must have something better to do.
Rym: so yeah in keeping with our spooky theme we're gonna review Scooby-doo.
Scott: so I already learned some things.
Rym: because I'm not an expert on Scooby-doo by any means do not thought.
Rym: if I sound like I know a lot about Scooby-doo it's cuz you read it on Wikipedia today.
Rym: it's not only that it's because I'm looking at the Wikipedia article while I talk to you.
Rym: so when I say something in the next 20 minutes or 30 minutes like ah so when ABC took over from CVS in that today.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: however I knew.
Scott: the only thing I know about Scooby-doo is what I've seen which is a really old Scooby-doo that looks like old Hanna-Barbera cartoons and a pup named Scooby-doo that I saw on Saturday mornings as a kid and that's it.
Scott: so what I know that there are like more recent Scooby movies that are live-action and supposedly a very recent cartoon and there's also some comic books that I've heard that are good and stuff.
Scott: but I haven't seen any of that stuff.
Scott: I've only supposedly be old.
Rym: Scooby-doo is good but we'll see.
Scott: I don't know and I don't plan to watch it cuz even if it's good I got better things to be doing.
Rym: also I'm gonna admit something very openly I never liked Scooby-doo even as a kid.
Rym: Scooby-doo is one of those.
Rym: I watched it.
Rym: I watched a shit ton of it but I didn't particularly like it.
Scott: Scooby-doo is one of those things right.
Scott: it's even weird right cuz?
Scott: you know you think about something like beat ass right like Batman the animated series.
Scott: if that was on I fucking watched it.
Rym: even if I'd seen the episode I was seen it.
Scott: I fucking watched that shit right.
Scott: but if you had come to me and been like you know yo like what's like I would never.
Scott: I'd never considered myself like a fan of it or a Batman fan or whatever.
Scott: but if it was on I watched it like oh my god.
Scott: and Scooby-doo while clearly nowhere near as good as beat ass was much the same way.
Scott: like I never would have considered myself a fan of Scooby-doo.
Scott: I never would have listed it as something I liked or was it or you know?
Scott: anywhere like that wouldn't even come to mind.
Scott: but if it was on and nothing else was on I watched it and this is part of why I'm don't watch TV.
Rym: so I think part of what's interesting to me about Scooby-doo is that when we were kids we sort of grew up as the last TV generation because the internet came just as we were moving into high school in college.
Rym: YouTube came after college oh yeah but we stopped watching TV.
Scott: there might have been two or four YouTube definitely two or three generations after us that watch TV.
Scott: cuz like my younger brother I was gonna get something for you younger and sister is eight years younger.
Scott: they watch TV.
Rym: we grew up doing a generation after.
Scott: that doesn't?
Rym: where Saturday morning cartoons were still a thing mostly true they were a big thing during when we'd like specifically we were childhood.
Rym: we definitely decreased in bigness as my life went on and as a result I would just turn on the TV and watch whatever was on like whatever the best thing was on at that time.
Rym: I would watch it meaning I would often end up on the channel that cartoons and Scooby-doo would be on mm-hmm and I would just watch it.
Rym: yep and as a result I've seen a lot of Scooby-doo and I had this vague idea that Scooby-doo had gone on forever.
Scott: and because I only ever saw because at the time that I was watching TV there was already in crazy reruns well right there was no internet or anything.
Scott: I couldn't get information easily about like the history of Scooby-doo and what channels that had been on or anything.
Scott: that's now just all listed right there in Wikipedia for you to figure out in two seconds.
Scott: yeah so all I knew is like huh there seems to be this one Scooby series.
Scott: that's just Scooby-doo.
Scott: that seemed.
Scott: that seems like it's the original one.
Scott: right that makes sense yeah.
Scott: and this is all the one called Scooby movies that has celebrity guests I guess down knots.
Scott: I guess that one came later.
Rym: that one was only dated for me because I knew who the celebrities were but I can tell by looking at it this still looks old so it must be old.
Scott: yeah then this pup named Scooby-doo which is on Saturday morning and that one looks way newer and is clearly brand new and is clearly garbage.
Scott: well anyway but you know it's like I could just sort of tell but I didn't know anything and there might have been other ones that like if they weren't being broadcast on TV I didn't know about.
Rym: this is what's crazy.
Rym: as a kid I was kind of obsessed with.
Rym: I see these shows like he-man and Scooby-doo and because I sort of started them in meteor as because I didn't know there was never like an origin story or like a continuous plot I'd see an episode I'd see another episode I'd see another episode and I'd wonder like what's their deal?
Rym: I also wondered that every now and then you'd see an episode that was older than anything you've seen before and he'd be like whoa.
Rym: now I'm gonna learn some stuff and you never did.
Scott: no you know the only show as a kid that I met there are only two shows in my youth like mega youth right like elementary and middle school youth that I managed to watch every episode in order and those show well to a certain point at least.
Scott: I stopped watching it after eventually.
Scott: but for years I watched every episode of Fox x-men in order.
Scott: yeah I did that from when it aired with launch actually pissed me off because they fuck up the continuity like it doesn't really dark Phoenix.
Scott: and well yeah and I don't know if anyone remembers this there was a live-action Superman show called Lewis and Clark.
Rym: oh yeah Lois and Clark I didn't like that show.
Scott: that was on ABC and I watched every single episode of that in order as they were aired every single new one until I guess like there was some.
Scott: really it basically jumped a shark at some point.
Rym: it's not watching mask which was my favorite media on earth when I was a child.
Rym: I didn't actually see it all in order.
Scott: Thundercats I couldn't they?
Scott: just it wasn't broadcast properly.
Rym: Voltron Thundercats did have an origin episode.
Scott: oh yeah I never saw until adulthood.
Scott: I saw it as a child but I was not.
Scott: but there were many things I missed.
Scott: like Thundercats it was like suddenly they were on another planet and I didn't see the episodes of how they got there.
Scott: no because they weren't aired.
Scott: or a volt you know what Scooby-doo was like that like it felt like something transformers.
Rym: ha like it felt like something from an ancient time and I really wondered like what's the deal?
Rym: and not enough.
Rym: but I learned something terrifying about Scott right before we heard the show.
Rym: he did not really understand the true terror of scrappy.
Scott: do no see I had only ever my memory which is admittedly not the greatest at least not remembering this sort of thing.
Rym: didn't only remembered scrappy do as a character in pup named Scooby-doo because ridiculous there is more Scooby-doo like a regular Scooby-doo with scrappy in it then without but there was.
Scott: there was definitely sort of this thing where the redone versions of shows you know a different animation that happened in the 90s had additional characters that were not in the original versions right.
Scott: so it sort of made sense in my brain that scrappy do is one of those like oh they concocted this extra character for the.
Rym: yeah that is literally what Pucci was making fun of in The Simpsons.
Scott: exactly.
Rym: they added scrappy do and this is even on the Wikipedia but I knew this already.
Rym: they added scrappy because Scooby-doo was dropping in popularity and scrappy was like this character designed to get kids interested again mm-hmm.
Scott: but anyway yeah I had not recalled scratch seeing scrappy do in old Scooby-doo cartoons.
Scott: yeah but apparently I'm wrong because there it is.
Scott: scrappy do was added in the 70s before I was scrappied is older than me.
Rym: yep all right Scott didn't believe me until I showed him a screenshot of scrappy do?
Scott: it's not that I didn't believe you?
Scott: is that I was just like shocked that it was that you know that my memory was so.
Rym: so the ways the way it actually broke down.
Rym: now I'm looking at Wikipedia because I didn't know this.
Rym: the classic Scooby-doo meaning the actual original one is Scooby-doo.
Rym: where are you with that theme?
Scott: Scooby-doo be do yes that one.
Scott: I have seen that one.
Scott: how many episodes are there?
Scott: uh 41 I definitely haven't seen all of them.
Rym: and then I think I've seen them all and then there's not that many.
Rym: and then there's the Scooby-doo movies which I have seen.
Scott: many of them see.
Rym: what's crazy.
Rym: they're called the new Scooby-doo movies and they're from the early 70s.
Scott: those all have guests on them.
Rym: I'm not the ones I remember the most only remember the one with Don Knots.
Scott: I remember the one.
Scott: I do remember the Don Knots one.
Scott: I also remember the Batman and Robin one which is Adam West and Burt Ward doing the voice acting if I'm not mistaken.
Rym: Oh John Astin was in one.
Rym: I don't know who that is Gomez from the Addams Family.
Scott: oh I there was an Addams Family one I did.
Rym: yeah I don't think I've seen that one but I remember at.
Rym: oh I remember the Dick Van Dyke one I do and the Casey Kasem.
Rym: right he played Robin.
Rym: yeah oh shit it's all coming back.
Scott: I do remember.
Scott: clearly there were at least two of these with the Harlem Globetrotters.
Rym: yep the three Stooges.
Rym: one I remember eating.
Scott: there was a three Stooges.
Scott: I don't think it was the actual three Stooges voice act.
Scott: well as it.
Rym: which three Stooges?
Scott: the original one?
Rym: well which ones?
Scott: the Harry Moe and curly curly.
Rym: what about champ?
Scott: that's the fourth Stu is it?
Rym: yeah who's the fifth Stu?
Scott: there wasn't a fist but you don't get you daughter.
Rym: what about the ones where they had all these other people play?
Rym: a third Stu?
Scott: I'm not that I don't know that we used to listen to pen radio.
Rym: he fucking never shut up about that shit.
Rym: in like every episode he'd be like helmet.
Rym: there's 19 Stooges however many there were and he would go into like crazy detail.
Scott: not someone who knows a lot about three Stu.
Scott: you used to be like.
Rym: we used to talk about this.
Scott: no how do you?
Scott: not I've.
Scott: you know in my life I've probably ever seen like the most basic of three Stooges content.
Rym: there is two just cartoons.
Rym: no okay yes so Scooby Doo meets the Harlem Globetrotters is two episodes the mystery of the Haunted Island and the Loch Ness.
Scott: see how come?
Scott: I can remember that shit but I can't remember.
Rym: Phyllis Diller played herself.
Rym: okay die Casey Elliott.
Rym: okay I'm I don't remember some of these.
Rym: and some of these I really remember.
Rym: but anyway back to Scooby Doo.
Rym: so the other thing that I remember that really bothered me as a is that there was a line between.
Rym: there was like the original episodes all had literally the exact same plot.
Scott: yes to the point that is the main thing I wanted to discuss today is that there are many works of art in the history of the world that are episodic and formulaic.
Scott: right there.
Scott: there are many such things.
Scott: yep exactly of all of them that have ever existed.
Scott: I believe personally that Scooby Doo is the most rigidly formula.
Rym: so what's the formula of?
Scott: and the formula is this right?
Scott: the Scooby Doo gang rolls into a new town in the mystery mobile.
Scott: in the mystery a stranger comes to town.
Scott: of course they're not strangers even though it's a mystery mobile right and they encounter some sort of local troubles.
Scott: they notice it right and somehow get involved in it.
Scott: somehow right it turns out.
Rym: well then they try to catch.
Rym: it's a monster or something.
Scott: somebody trying to catch it one somebody involved in the local troubles decides to dress up as a monster as a way to win out in their local feud.
Rym: oh wait I was gonna way more specific.
Scott: that's creating some sort of legend in the town of the creepy.
Scott: whatever it is the mystery gang attempts to chase this monster all about no and find clues or whatever but they'll first basically they'll split up to chase the thing.
Rym: yes so Scooby and Shaggy will get scared by it while Fred is actually doing an investigation.
Scott: then they have the time then they do the joke with all the doors yep the same joke every time.
Scott: then they're all together again and then somehow they find the person catch them by accident and remove their mask.
Scott: yeah it's the person you obviously thought it was if you're intelligent and not a small child.
Scott: but since this is a show for small children hopefully they would be amazed at the mystery.
Rym: I feel like it was always the second person they introduced.
Scott: it's there's like a person who's like the obviously bad person.
Scott: and then there's the second person who's sort of less notice.
Scott: that's always them.
Rym: yep every time every time I went away with it ever for you fucking kids I don't think they said fucking.
Rym: but so there was a point in the show where it shifted from.
Rym: it is a person in a costume or with a projector which as a kid I never figured out how that worked.
Rym: projectors don't work that way.
Scott: I know there's a lot of explanations of technology in the show that make no sense but it was always just a projector also makes no sense how these costumes that people were wearing were believable enough that they got scared by them.
Rym: well because when they animated it they'd animate the monster as a real fucking monster glowing and flying and then when they take the costume off they animate it looking really shitty and poorly made.
Scott: yet most of the time when I bring up Scooby-Doo it's to talk about the Scooby-Doo effect.
Scott: see it was so poorly and cheaply animated that they would put almost everything in the background.
Scott: because you draw a background once and it's cheap.
Scott: if you got to draw on the cell that means you got to draw again when it moves.
Scott: yeah so you can see something they would do a lot is if there was an object that they were going to interact with in the scene that was going to become.
Rym: it would look really shitty and just be there like one door different.
Scott: only that object would be animated drawn on the cell and the rest of everything will be on the background.
Scott: so you could look at a scene and Scooby-Doo and you see the characters would clearly be animated on a cell with cell paint and then the door that someone was gonna open would be animated with cell paint and everything else is clearly background.
Scott: and so you at the start of a scene things that could be interacted.
Rym: well there's a trapdoor.
Rym: they're about to step on right.
Scott: there's a trapdoor.
Scott: they're about to step on.
Scott: there's the.
Scott: well someone's gonna fall down.
Scott: there's a thing that's gonna move right.
Scott: you could tell the beginning of the scene that that object was going to become animated very soon and that's like it was.
Scott: you know Scooby-Doo.
Scott: if I and I see this often and refer to it often in video games when you're going around a video game area particularly in a 3d game and it's like oh there's an object I can interact with it's Scooby dude.
Scott: you know it has the Scooby-Doo effect.
Scott: it stands out in some way from all the useless background items the chase sequences we were talking about.
Rym: they didn't start doing that till the second season.
Scott: really it feels like there was one in every single episode seven of the second season episodes.
Scott: that's now really okay.
Rym: they got some famous bubblegum pop people.
Rym: I guess I don't know who these people are but there's.
Rym: there's all this stuff about the music.
Rym: I'm just gonna ignore.
Scott: no all the music the original songs.
Scott: that's a memorable kind of okay good song.
Scott: I don't remember any other songs.
Rym: I remember a bunch of them because I was looking through the names of the different series and I specifically remembered a bunch of these but not all of them.
Rym: so like oh those are video games.
Rym: let me get up to the actual television shows.
Rym: here we go.
Rym: so the original show was titled Scooby-Doo comma.
Scott: where are you talked about this already?
Rym: exclamation point.
Rym: no question mark mm-hmm which bothers me now okay so then it was just the Scooby-Doo show for like.
Scott: just edit Wikipedia.
Scott: put the question mark in.
Rym: that's good.
Rym: no that'd be a lie is it?
Rym: and then right after that Scott the show is officially called Scooby-Doo and scrappy doo.
Rym: and then there was all another 99 shorts that were further Scooby-Doo and scrappy doo.
Rym: and then in the 80s the next season was called the new Scooby-Doo and scrappy doo show mm-hmm.
Rym: a pup named Scooby-Doo didn't come until the late 80s.
Scott: yeah no that's good Scooby-Doo scrap.
Scott: a pup named Scooby-Doo late 80s is the only one that was new in my child.
Rym: in fact it looks like they're so when I was conscious was continuous.
Scott: I remember it between 1969 69 in 1984 six really that's got.
Rym: the original show was 69 to 78. whoa all right.
Rym: so in 84 the new Scooby-Doo show ended mm-hmm and then there was this 13 goes to Scooby-Doo and then there's a gap and then sort of like there's this separate next era with a pup named Scooby-Doo right.
Scott: so pup named Scooby-Doo was a show that was in my youth I hate on TV.
Scott: I literally when I was like seven or eight years old it was on I'd bitch about it.
Rym: I usually still watch it because I was watching TV.
Scott: it was a show that I only watched.
Scott: it wasn't it like you know it's not about like x-men and which came a few years later.
Scott: oh well yeah it was Casey Kasem but like I was if x-men was on I was watching it.
Scott: pup named Scooby-Doo was a show that like you'd watch if you didn't even have a video game to play cuz it was so bland.
Scott: but that show also had some other shows that tied in with it.
Scott: the same way when you watch Rocky and Bullwinkle you also get a fractured fairy tale and it don't do right.
Scott: well one of the Scooby-Doo's was always paired with Captain Caveman right I don't know there was a Flintstones or there was a Flintstones remake and a Scooby-Doo remake but Captain Caveman was in there somewhere right and Captain Caveman at least I liked it.
Rym: I don't know if anyone else did but I didn't like it at all but I watched it.
Scott: I like Captain Caveman uh but I don't know if I'd like to caveman and son and the teen angels.
Scott: I don't remember them.
Rym: that's the name of the show captain caveman and the Teen Angels what?
Scott: I don't remember that at Teen Angels part at all anyway really no it was literally always those two things are you sure?
Scott: that's not that particular episode is.
Scott: and the Teen Angels then?
Rym: no that is.
Rym: the show is called Captain Caveman and this I don't remember this at all.
Scott: anyway I remember Captain Caveman and son.
Scott: maybe that was cat.
Scott: it was also a remake of an older captain caveman.
Scott: I've never seen.
Scott: you don't think so I don't.
Rym: well we should have separate episode.
Rym: captain cave who
Scott: knows the point is pup named Scooby-Doo had only basically one redeeming factor right besides being paired in the same slot with other shorts that were better and that is they had this character red herring who was not in the any other Scooby-Doo that I know of.
Scott: and basically red herring was the typical bully character where I had red curly hair ginger kid sort of buff and whatever.
Rym: right and Fred will always blame him right.
Scott: he would bully all the Scooby-Doo kids who were nerds.
Scott: right you know even Fred was busy a nerd even though he doesn't look like one visually right he was.
Scott: he's a lot like that kid on Salute Your Shorts with the red hair or the kid on Doug with the green face and the red hair.
Scott: right.
Rym: he was Roger Klotz.
Scott: yes basically red herring is Roger Klotz or actually vice versa.
Scott: cuz Roger Klotz came later right and red herring would both woods in the early part of the episode when they were in school and still the mystery hadn't been revealed.
Scott: yet red herring would bully them right and then later on in the episode like clockwork because even pup named Scooby-Doo was formulaic.
Scott: okay they would blame red herring saying it was him.
Scott: he's the one who did the man.
Scott: it was never him.
Rym: obviously it was him one time.
Scott: it was him one time.
Rym: so that episode which I do remember Fred was like now it's not him it was.
Scott: they would blame it on him every time and then he would be like it's not me you numb nuts or whatever and like punch them or something right.
Scott: I got that character a red herring and that joke of red herring I still think it's funny.
Scott: the captain came in on.
Scott: nothing else about.
Scott: the show is good.
Rym: the captain caveman intro is literally an origin story where the teen angels.
Scott: fine I've never seen this captain caveman.
Scott: this must be the original one.
Rym: this is the original captain.
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: I thought the captain caveman that I saw which is apparently a remake was actually the original.
Scott: but it's not.
Scott: it was a remake.
Scott: so the captain caveman I saw was much like pup named Scooby-Doo a remake and was captain caveman and son.
Scott: I've never seen captain caveman and the teen angels ever not even once.
Rym: so get back to what I was getting at.
Rym: the line was suddenly the show stopped being people faking monsters for commercial gain and started being actual fucking monsters.
Scott: I've never seen that.
Rym: the.
Rym: that's most of Scooby-Doo.
Scott: I've never seen that.
Scott: I have never seen even one Scooby-Doo with an actual literal monster.
Scott: it was always someone in a mask every time.
Rym: yeah let's see what is.
Scott: I'm not saying they don't exist.
Scott: I'm saying I personally haven't seen one.
Rym: see 1987 to 1988. blah blah blah blah blah yep the Jets it's Flintstones and the Jetsons of rehab Flintstones and Jetsons.
Rym: we do shows on those.
Rym: yep they met they met actual monsters.
Scott: I've never seen one with an actual monster in several along the way.
Rym: they're running monsters man monsters yep it even says actual monsters in this Wikipedia.
Rym: at one point all right but uh yeah I. uh it's weird to me that I've seen so much Scooby-Doo and until I looked at this Wikipedia article I couldn't place where they existed.
Rym: in this continuum I probably have seen none of the newer Scooby-Doo and as a kid a big part of why I didn't like Scooby-Doo is that once I had middle school actually late elementary school I started watching anime and because I was watching anime in elementary school Scooby-Doo just looked like shit and I just didn't like.
Rym: I think I was one of those kids who saw one anime when I was in like fourth grade and suddenly all American cartoons are shit because the only American cartoons I knew about were things like Scooby-Doo.
Rym: so I was comparing 80s anime to 70s American low-budget cartoons.
Scott: right I mean the thing is Scooby-Doo.
Scott: I only watched you know like the older Scooby-Doo's I actually watched later on when I we had cable and when we got Cartoon Network which was rerunning them.
Scott: right.
Scott: I wasn't able to see those and I was younger and even then they looked like crap because that was like you know the mid to late 90s ish area right.
Scott: and I was now compare even compared not forget anime even compared to other crap shows like or not crap shows but just nor you know shows like Ninja Turtles or real ghostbusters or
Rym: ghostbusters textures relatively good
Scott: or Dexter's lab or stuff like that like it looked like crap compared to that.
Scott: yeah so.
Scott: and even compared to other Hanna-Barbera shows like Thunder the Barbarian or Space Ghost or you know any of that yet?
Scott: well I guess Thunder the Barbarian wasn't actually Hanna-Barbera but it was what's it called.
Scott: forget.
Scott: yeah the other company right but the point is is that could even compared to the other old shows it didn't.
Scott: it was bad right visually speak.
Rym: yep so anime really ruined my like continued fandom from elementary school onward of any of this stuff and I still watched it all and I'd really that's just that that was like the TV generation.
Rym: TV would be on and I'd watch it.
Scott: yeah and it's weird.
Scott: how much you know?
Scott: it's not weird it's just there's a lot of.
Rym: is that the kids to our kids today is that gonna be what Minecraft livestreamers are to them like?
Rym: wasn't good but I just watched it.
Rym: cuz that's what you did.
Rym: you sat down and watch whatever was on YouTube.
Scott: well no but I think is that there were the fact because of TV right there were these single identical things that we all consumed just because they were on regardless of what we were actually a fan of.
Rym: like when The Simpsons aired literally everyone in school the next day except the kids in religious households saw it right.
Scott: but it's like because whether you're a fan of Batman or not everyone of our generation knows Batman because you watched a B test if it was on and you can assume literally anyone you interacted with who was in your peer group also watched it.
Scott: yeah people just know it right but there's things like that.
Scott: there's nothing that all the people of generate good enough generations under us younger.
Scott: there's nothing that all everyone knows you can't?
Scott: you know?
Scott: they kids can go to each other and be like oh did you see?
Scott: one kid has seen My Little Pony and the other one doesn't even fucking know there's a My Little Pony show and the other one saw some Minecraft guy.
Scott: the other person doesn't even know that Minecraft guy exists because there's.
Scott: no there's no single identical monoculture like absorbing them all.
Rym: now that's part of drove me so hard into anime fandom so early.
Rym: it was that I saw the anime.
Rym: it was great and no one I talked to at any idea at all and they were dubious and they wouldn't watch it.
Rym: and it was weird to them.
Scott: and this is why you see Hollywood is banking hard on remaking the things that are part of that sort of our era which is that era end of TV monoculture era because after that there's no other monocultures to remake.
Scott: yeah you get past the 90s so they're not.
Scott: when you know when the top when the cycle goes around a decade and Hollywood wants to make remakes for the generations after us what are they gonna remake?
Rym: I mean what would be.
Rym: so there was that 70s show right and then they made that 80s show.
Rym: what the fuck would be the difference between the that 2000 show and that 2010 show.
Scott: right it's like what are they gonna even fucking do?
Scott: so?
Rym: yeah if you really like Scooby-doo that's okay.
Scott: I mean I guess sure it's not a bit like it's a bad thing even to my kid brain.
Rym: it was so formulaic that it bothered me.
Scott: yes you even do a kid brain you can tell but it's a thing because I would watch it.
Rym: if they you know bad at the characters like it's obviously that guy.
Rym: why do I have to sit here for an entire episode just for you to figure out?
Scott: it's that guy the second guy you know what though for as bad as the the plots and the animation and all the problems of Scooby-doo right the characters are actually kind of okay.
Rym: yeah as people he sucked Fred was competent dad.
Scott: they were at least somewhat unique compared to other characters and other shows.
Rym: a little bit I give it that like they all had their deal they're all white.
Rym: yeah because that's style of the time.
Scott: two of them were ladies and one of them was a dog.
Scott: yeah one of those they recognize.
Scott: because in the earliest episodes the guy who looks like he's supposed to be like mr.
Scott: America really isn't?
Scott: he's kind of dumb.
Rym: yeah Scooby was less dumb than Shaggy but more cowardly.
Rym: I think she was actually more cowardly.
Scott: they were both really really cowardly.
Rym: Scooby would occasionally step up.
Rym: I don't think Shaggy ever stepped up.
Scott: well you know what it was.
Scott: I think is that perhaps shit.
Scott: they were both super cowardly.
Scott: but I think perhaps Shaggy was less alert.
Scott: so usually you'd have Scooby in Shaggy's arms yeah and then Shaggy realizes and then also runs yeah but Scooby would occasionally do something that advanced the plot.
Rym: as far as I know Shaggy would just fuck up and run away.
Rym: mmm Scooby would do things accidentally to advance the plot by stumbling upon something although as a kid I never understood that Scooby and Shaggy were definitely getting high all the time.
Scott: oh yes that's why I understand that until I understood what weed was.
Scott: yeah but I think the reason you remember Scooby doing stuff is because they would bribe him with Scooby snacks to do something but they could buy died.
Rym: I feel like you could bribe shaggy with weeds.
Scott: you can't have that on TV.
Rym: yeah I feel like Scooby snacks were just weed.
Scott: yes yes they were.
Scott: there were weed biscuits.
Scott: so we cracked the code give your dog weed biscuit.
Scott: it's not a crack code.
Scott: everyone knows this.
Scott: talk about it until now in this episode.
Rym: all right I think we're done here.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand ok for the logos.
Rym: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda douchette a shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Rym: my steady calm.
Rym: Jeremy minor a genuine bonafide.
Rym: electrified six-car monorail.
Rym: Matthew Smith Nicholas Brandau captain Chinguakasi Rebecca Dunn.
Rym: four to one creations.
Rym: they would have two bases in the middle of a box canyon Shervin Von Hall rare Laval James David White Rochelle Montanona super boy.
Rym: Rym says something funny here.
Rym: sailor Vista Don Schleich Kajar Tavashin Joshua Joestar Sean Jagger Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian Cedroni been Chris mid kit Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas ha and now I leave.