Rym: It's Wednesday, March 22nd, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm discuss and this is the GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about Plutona number.
Rym: Well all of them.
Rym: We read the trade.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I had to make a day trip to Boston yesterday.
Rym: That's why I broke two days ago.
Rym: I've already spoiled that we're recording the show ahead cuz Scott said a Rangers game right now I'm in a Rangers game tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, but as far as the context of the listener You're gonna probably upload this show post to the internet while I'm in the gat.
Rym: that is in fact true.
Rym: But so on Monday this week.
Rym: I had to do a day trip to Boston.
Rym: so I took like the 8 a.m.
Rym: Isella to Boston and I took the 520 p.m.
Rym: Isella home from Boston like that.
Rym: It's pretty easy to do a Boston day trip.
Rym: My coworkers flew, but I feel like that is way more effort than There's a shuttle plane.
Rym: There's a lot of shuttle planes that go between Boston to New York and the way those.
Rym: so the way some of those work is you buy a ticket and you just show up at the airport and You just get on whichever one's next.
Rym: So if you get lucky like you can just get on a plane and go but which airport in New York Did they leave from?
Rym: most of them actually seem to go to Newark, right?
Scott: So the amount of time it takes me to Newark.
Rym: I could be that out of Boston I have a policy and my policy is I will not fly out of Newark.
Scott: I also don't fly out of Newark, but if I did by the time I would get there I'd be could be halfway to Boston.
Rym: Yeah, but the Isella is pretty good.
Rym: So I did that and I basically played a lot of a. I beat the necro dancer because I actually like tried to beat Krypto.
Rym: the necro dancer like tried to finish it in so far as that has a plot the normal single-player Yeah, and there's way more than I thought because I beat the game and then it was like Oh now, you know the deal with the flute.
Rym: now You have to play as the mom and it's way different and upside down castle What I don't even know about a mom or a flute, well, you never saw any cutscenes.
Rym: That means you've never beaten any part of that game.
Scott: I've be.
Rym: you get a cutscene of like my mom disappeared and then every time you beat another level you get more cutscenes.
Scott: I've beaten things in that game.
Scott: in so far as I there were staircases and I went down and that means I'd be level No, yeah, there's four of those and a boss in every like area.
Scott: I've never gotten to a boss.
Scott: What I don't think you've The thing is like it's not like I've tried.
Scott: if you've played less than five percent of that game I put in like almost no effort into playing that game and then stop playing.
Scott: So yeah If you beat the I'm sure if I tried I would get to a boss.
Rym: if you beat all four Bosses by beating all four levels only four bosses.
Rym: All right, then you get to fight the necro dancer Which is a crazy like.
Rym: not what you expect.
Rym: fight.
Scott: Wouldn't it be some sort of?
Scott: you know Dancing Necromancer?
Rym: that is exactly what the necro dancer is.
Scott: Yeah, if you couldn't get nominative determinism dances and then things come back from the dead.
Rym: as he dances Yeah He's literally summoning the undead and dancing around you and you and your dad have to kill him together and it's a puzzle.
Rym: It's really good, but then you become the mom and there's all this stuff.
Rym: So there's a lot more to that game than I realize was the necro dancing.
Scott: I'm not gonna spoil it I'm pretty sure mom was the necro dancer.
Rym: Uh, no, actually no, I'll spoil that your mom is nothing.
Scott: I was dead and is now brought back to life.
Rym: Yeah You do bring your mom back to life with the loot and then your and then you find out that the loot is bad news.
Scott: Maybe I thought you said flute loot.
Rym: Oh, okay, you know the loot the plot.
Rym: I guess you've never seen a cutscene.
Scott: So you have no a loot the instrument not loot.
Rym: No, no, no, though the loot is loot and now I am using the loot as my weapon.
Scott: But it's not.
Scott: it's not a bag with a dollar sign on it No, it is a golden loot.
Rym: It's a thing with strings on is a golden loot that raises the dead I guess but you have to keep playing it or they die again, I guess anyway, the stuff going on.
Rym: but So I get to Boston and I'm there basically to have like one meeting and then one more important meeting.
Rym: So I show up at the place that people are gonna meet me and my meeting or the important important meeting and the people are Supposed to meet me at it are running late.
Rym: So they're like just go in and like, you know stall slash work your magic cuz I'm good at this stuff.
Rym: So I got I'm like, alright fine.
Rym: I'll just go in.
Rym: so I walk over to the address They gave me and I can't find the building.
Rym: Alright, so I'm like, oh Yep, so maybe I'm dumb.
Rym: It's a square.
Scott: What is Google Maps?
Rym: a Google Maps puts a pin in a spot and I go there and a different addresses at that spot.
Rym: Okay, but the number like I'm going to like six and the number there is ten.
Rym: So I go in one direction I see twelve.
Rym: So we'll get to that.
Rym: so I go a little bit.
Rym: in one direction I see twelve and I'm like, aha I'll go the other way and the next building if we go the other way is one One and then twelve and ten and there are no other.
Scott: I mean I've had situations like that in New York on occasion.
Scott: Yeah, that happens in other places much more.
Rym: So so I go into the building at ten and I'm like yo, where's six?
Rym: and I expect the guy to say Oh go blah, haha.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: So the guy says six There's no six and then he calls another guy over like you ever hear of six?
Rym: and the guy's like six There's no.
Scott: say whoever gave you the addresses wrong.
Rym: Yep So I'm like well is such and such company in this building and they're like Let me check takes a surprising amount of time for him to poke at a computer monsters building.
Rym: I was a bit it's a real building like a New York building.
Rym: and then he's like now they ain't in here.
Rym: So I go to one and they're like there is definitely no six.
Scott: well, is there could that company in the building?
Scott: No, okay.
Rym: So I call my.
Rym: well I call my late co-workers who are still late because they were like way out in fucking Because they can't find six evening.
Rym: No, cuz they're way out in Cambridge and they think it's a way shorter drive to downtown Boston than it is.
Rym: So I called them back and they're like six doesn't exist and they're like our uber driver says it does.
Rym: He's taking us right there and I was like, alright, I'll meet you there.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There was no six.
Rym: No, they gave us the wrong meeting and by then that was important meeting and by then it was too late.
Rym: no, luckily they gave us the wrong address and Yeah, so I just went home having done basically nothing.
Scott: So I basically at least get a secret breakfast.
Rym: No, cuz that's way over by Back Bay and I was over.
Scott: but if you're there why you're great At least make it worth the trip.
Rym: I went to a different but pretty good restaurant.
Rym: cuz I'm on a business trip technically so sure I had very well someone else's money and I just basically does that's one steak place.
Rym: Yeah, I fucked around in Boston all day.
Rym: Then I took the train home and I played a whole bunch of knicker dancer.
Rym: That is why I now know what the deal is with the knicker dancer.
Rym: That was my day And that's why there was no show on Monday.
Scott: All right, let's do actual stuff.
Scott: So it's any news.
Scott: Yeah, so Just a tiny news, there's that show free the swimming hot boys show.
Rym: Oh, yeah I watched that she said was good.
Scott: I never watched it because I'm watching a bicycle show Which is slightly less hotness, but slightly more humor, but still hotness.
Scott: Yeah bicycling instead of swimming.
Scott: But anyway, oh and y'all pedal has a new season right now.
Rym: So anyway, so how far are they?
Rym: How many episodes per bike race?
Scott: So far it's really just like lead-up races.
Scott: so there was just a race I just watched.
Scott: that was two episodes.
Scott: Oh see at least initial didn't even take up both episodes.
Rym: Initial D the lead-up would be like a couple episodes.
Scott: Well, cuz really in your pedal It's really there's only one race that matters which is the inter high, right?
Scott: and all these other races are just like sort of setting this the Scene for the big race.
Scott: the big race has only happened once so far.
Scott: It's gonna happen three times I assume because it's high school three years in Japan of high school and the first the first season was a lead-up.
Scott: So the first inter high which took up the entire second season.
Scott: Yeah, and then now we're in the third season.
Scott: So we're leading up to the second inter high which I assume will take up the entire third season.
Scott: All right Anyway but they're making compilation movies for free and you the the swimming show and usually when there's compilation movies for something like there were for your pedal actually.
Scott: Or I'm like, yeah, why do they keep making these things?
Scott: I seen the TV series.
Scott: Why do I want to see the condensed compilation thing?
Scott: Just give me new content instead.
Rym: Yeah, I've never been happy with compilation movies But now it's like.
Scott: this is the first time where I've been like Oh They made compilation movies for the thing that I slightly maybe want to see but don't super want to see.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: That's actually really useful.
Scott: I'm gonna watch those compilation movies for free and not watch free.
Rym: So, I mean, I know freeze good.
Scott: Yeah Please make compilation movies for the ice skating one that I want to see but don't want to watch all the episodes.
Rym: I feel like I should just watch that one straight up.
Scott: It's on the borderline.
Scott: It's definitely definitely Dragon.
Rym: I think I can watch the ice skating show.
Scott: I didn't watch all of Let's made dragon if it weren't for this podcast.
Rym: Yeah, and now I'm still there's a lot of you know in Civ 5 the religions.
Rym: There's like pressure from different religions on cities and the number goes up in danger from different animes.
Rym: There's a lot of pressure from that kimono friends on me.
Rym: right now Numerous angles are pushing kimono friends on me hard.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: yeah the ice skating shows on the borderline of like.
Scott: But if there are compilation movies I'd watch them like as soon as I got home.
Scott: But now so the New York Children's Film Festival is in New York as it is every year And usually we go to the premiere movie, which this year was your name, which Rym saw I saw a long time ago on a plane by chance.
Rym: yeah, cuz the flight I was on was basically it had all these Japanese movies with Theatrical English subtitles, but anyway that movie was like the highest grossing.
Scott: Think.
Scott: it beat spirited away in some category of grossing money.
Rym: It's his best work.
Scott: I think it's Makoto Shinkai the cloud guy.
Scott: Yeah, Hoshinoko.
Scott: It is five centimeters per second.
Rym: Yeah It's it's.
Scott: it's a movie by him, but yeah We're gonna see that.
Scott: it's gonna be in theaters.
Scott: regular like it was good enough I will.
Rym: I will watch it again in a few weeks.
Scott: We're gonna go see that for real.
Scott: We couldn't see it at the premiere of the Children's Film Festival because it sold out.
Scott: the closing movie Of the Children's Film Festival was on CN Which is looks like the word ancient with the T removed from the end and the magic tablet.
Scott: So we couldn't get tickets to that either even though Kenji Kamiyama The director was gonna and the writer also was gonna be at that final screening.
Scott: cuz that sold out.
Scott: Kenji Kamiyama, by the way is the guy who directed goes in the shell standalone complex.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Did he also?
Rym: didn't he actually like, right?
Rym: Even in the East, I don't know.
Rym: he's done a lot of stuff But anyway, pretty sure he wrote that was why it's so as such a bad ending.
Rym: Yeah written by Kenji Kamiyama Okay, so production IG.
Scott: But anyway, he wrote and directed and production IG produced this movie on CN and the magic tablet.
Scott: Rym wasn't in town.
Rym: I I thought until just now that this meant like magic tablet of fantasy.
Scott: I knew nothing about this.
Scott: I thought it also meant a magic tablet as in Ten Commandments tablet Exactly, but that's not the kind of tablet.
Scott: It is at all.
Scott: Me me Emily and Judith went to see this and It's a nice movie.
Scott: It's not like epic or the best.
Scott: the kind of tablet they're talking about is the iPad kind not the Not the other kind.
Scott: And just to give you a quick summary I'm sure Rym will see this at some point and we'll do a real episode on it.
Scott: But what this movie is?
Scott: you got this girl and when she dreams she's dreaming about this sort of Fantasy steampunk ish world where there's a princess and a king and this world is a parallel of this Drama that's going on in the real world.
Scott: Like there are people in the real world and they have character analogues in the magic world and vice-versa.
Scott: and stuff happens in the magic World and then that same thing seem to have a you know analogous happening in the real world, right?
Scott: And it's sort of that weird thing is going on.
Scott: but also It's about self-driving cars.
Scott: well, and it's also about the Tokyo Olympics and it's about the drama of a small-town person versus Tokyo life and Family a small-town first person versus Tokyo life is also the plot of your name degree and family dramas.
Scott: Big, you know the kind of family dramas where you know, it's like, you know, uh, you know mom's dad.
Scott: Mom is dead and grandpa's mad at dad, you know, they don't talk they're estranged kind of thing, you know, that sort of thing.
Scott: Yeah You know the mystery of like.
Scott: I didn't know anything about mom.
Scott: dad never told me anything.
Scott: I don't know what the deal is.
Scott: Let's find out.
Rym: she's from the magic place.
Rym: That's what a style or something.
Scott: So that's that's what this is and it you know, it's not bad.
Scott: It's a good anime movie.
Scott: It's worth watching once.
Scott: I just don't think it's worth watching more than once.
Scott: And I think the main problem with it is it has a lot of scenes that are just sort of like paced wrong.
Scott: It's a two-hour movie.
Scott: It should have definitely been 90 minutes.
Scott: it was and the one that really stood out is like there's a scene where like they're You guys running upstairs and it shows you him running up the stairs and it's like they could have cut the number of flights They showed you In half.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like you can only get away with that if you're oh she making sky crawlers, right?
Scott: But so he's running up the stairs in this action scene and he runs and it's like you're ready for him to be at the Top and he runs up some more stairs.
Scott: It's like they loop that like for like five to ten seconds too long.
Rym: You should just turn that into us that I own me mokushiro, but there's a lot of thing.
Scott: It doesn't fit it, but there's other things like they're driving.
Scott: at one point It's like the driving shot lasts 30 seconds to a minute too long.
Rym: Yeah, your name is pretty long too, but at least it like is Constantly novel and you're constantly wondering what's gonna happen.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of stuff like that.
Scott: So there's a chase scene and the things keep happening in the chase scene.
Scott: It's not just like a static repeat shot, but the chase scene itself could have been half as long and accomplished the same You know effect, right?
Scott: So that's the the main flaw of the movie.
Scott: So if you got time to watch an anime movie go watch that stand in the magic tablet.
Rym: We generally say watch every anime movie.
Rym: there aren't that many.
Scott: there aren't that many that aren't Pokemon the movie 30.
Scott: Yep But don't go in a rush to go see it.
Rym: So cartoon saloon, which you should probably know from the secret of Kells and song of the sea.
Rym: You know Tom Moore's a studio the premiere Irish animation studio that is so far with their two feature films.
Scott: They only hit home run.
Rym: Yeah Literally two feature films two home runs and now we have a trailer for their third feature film Dun-dun-dun wolf walkers.
Scott: Oh, baby, which looks.
Rym: I'm just gonna link to the tray the teaser trailer.
Rym: It was very little other than that probably about werewolves.
Rym: Looks real freaking good.
Scott: I mean, how could it not look?
Scott: I'm only hit home run.
Rym: I mean I've met Tom for like twice and it's like seen him talk.
Scott: Even if you tried to intentionally walk right he'd read they reach out and hit the home run anyway.
Scott: Yeah I mean secret of cows Wrong that?
Rym: and if you read the production history like it is amazing that secretive Kells Was even made.
Rym: and if you're wondering why it kind of ends is sort of.
Rym: I don't want to say it Peters out But it ends in the sort of melancholy and long dinner mom.
Rym: There's a production reason for that.
Scott: like it would have been a very different movie if they had funding but it's thanks to that Success of that secretive Kells that they were able to continue and make the other stuff much similar to the story of Makoto Shinkai Who made anime in his basement.
Scott: that somehow?
Scott: Succeeded and thus was able to eventually make your name.
Rym: and I checked to make sure cuz I'm still amazed Despite the weirdness of that thing.
Scott: We saw at the New York Comic Con.
Scott: I don't even remember the name of that movie He made but meh Ancient in the magic tablet is way better than that Makoto Shinkai movie One with the fantasy world people who play chase distant Ghibli movies through the whispers of darkness or something.
Scott: Yeah, whatever that was.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah wolf walkers just looks real real good And I'm pretty confident that they'll bat a thousand and somehow If any of you follow me on Twitter, you know what my Twitter's like, he hasn't unfollowed me on Twitter.
Rym: So either he doesn't read his Twitter or he's into the Sonic the Hedgehog.
Scott: No, I think he's one of those people who doesn't read his Twitter cuz he think he's following like thousands of people Under 2,000.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You can't follow that.
Scott: How many people am I following?
Rym: I'm following cuz I actually I got a. I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm doing.
Scott: I'm gonna always tell.
Scott: have someone reads Twitter based on the?
Rym: I'll say this definitely if you have more than 2,000 people you are following either You're an insane person who actually uses lists or you're not reading Twitter.
Rym: Yeah, I'm following 357 and I'm actually gonna cut that back a little bit.
Scott: I'm sure a lot of the people I'm following just don't tweet at all is the thing.
Rym: Yep, a few people are tweeting a lot and the problem is I really like what they're tweeting a lot But they treat too much like and you think that I tweet too much.
Rym: These people are pushing I.
Scott: there are a lot of people that I like what they tweet, but they tweet too much.
Scott: So I mute them.
Rym: Yeah, if I feel like I can't unfollow them, of course lately Most of it's been retweets of that meme of an unrelated thing and be like cowboy bebop.
Scott: And then what always happens is I'll mute someone right?
Scott: It's like I'll mute someone and then you'll also follow them and you'll know that you'll at them And I'll see that tweet.
Rym: Yeah, and then it's just like no Sometimes it's good though, because then you get the Conversation you would have otherwise seen unless it turns into one of those like 400 tweet arguments Which is the kind of thing I muted you for.
Rym: yeah Well anyway things of the day.
Rym: So I saw this on my Twitter and I'm not gonna link to a tweet thread, but instead I'll link to this page.
Rym: Well from a choir University in Australia of all places that Showed some of them, but if you didn't know, you know The Ides of March is literally just the middle of March and that's when Caesar was stabbed to death by everybody Kind of instigated by Brutus, you know, you I hope you know a little bit of Roman history.
Scott: I hope I mean if you know anything about Roman history, you know that it to The first thing you know about Roman history.
Rym: Yeah many people the only thing Yep, maybe you know about like wolves and like mythical Rome, but but uh, are you gonna Brute me?
Scott: So, uh, no, you're not cuz I'm gonna Brute you.
Rym: So what most people don't know is that Brutus had One of the more badass coins in history.
Rym: This is like I don't know You know, we had Caesar stabbed to death and participated in said stabbing and he had coined.
Scott: Basically The thing I don't actually know right is like, you know, there's that famous thing where Caesar was like you too Brutus.
Scott: Oh, yeah, right.
Scott: was Brutus actually Caesar's friend and then turned on him?
Scott: or was Brutus just pretending to be Caesar's friend the whole time?
Scott: and was that evil?
Rym: The J?
Rym: because the general narrative was that the people who portrayed Caesar were worried that the power of the Senate was going to be Displaced into a dictatorship and that Caesar was going to become a dynastic King.
Scott: I'm talking about Brutus job.
Scott: Was he actually friends with Julius or?
Rym: I don't know about their personal stuff.
Scott: That's the part that I'm asking about.
Scott: I know the part.
Rym: Yeah, right, but this coin on the front is just a fucking picture of Brutus Which apparently was not something they would do in that era.
Rym: that was seen as very full of hubris.
Rym: Yeah, perhaps also to harken back to again Kings the thing that Brutus was essentially against Yeah, and the back of it.
Rym: It just says Ides of March and it's two fucking knives.
Scott: Yeah, though or a bowl.
Rym: I can't so according to the Twitter where someone was like, okay Let's talk about Brutus's fucking coin.
Rym: That cap is a particular kind of cap that was worn by a slave who was undergoing many a slave who was being freed.
Scott: Essentially two knives freed slaves Ides of March picture of Brutus That's basically a stabbed Rym and then sold geek knights t-shirts or the picture of me stabbing Rym and on the back It's just two knives and it said no more annoying noises Or had picture of some earmuffs.
Rym: So remember this on the Ides of March.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: there's an anime an anime that I have not watched and don't plan to watch called Hidamari sketch and there's a song from Hidamari sketch called sketch switch.
Scott: somebody took that song and Mashed it up with the song black and yellow by Wiz Khalifa and they produced this little video Which is my thing of the day.
Scott: it is on the YouTube.
Rym: Enjoy, what's telling is that I started playing it cuz.
Rym: Scott You know gave me his thing of the day and I think you you pointed out that I clicked like within about three seconds of It starting like like before you even heard anything.
Scott: You just like you open the link like maybe five seconds and you click like there is.
Scott: you know You paused it shortly after.
Scott: you're only at 21 seconds.
Scott: Yeah, I've been 21 seconds on this here from here, but you click like way before that 21 second I'm confident clicks pause.
Rym: the rest of those four minutes, you know are pretty good.
Rym: I'm also confident that these recommended related videos are almost all going to be great.
Scott: What kind of video?
Scott: give me a name of the was in those recommended?
Rym: first M&M.
Rym: All right, bustin I think that's just because I think this is you the sampling of deaf Punk a video platinum level circulation Avicii.
Rym: it looks like another anime mashup of some kind.
Rym: Okay, another anime unwrapping mashup of some kind.
Rym: Okay Hey pops plus animes equals Dang mao die.
Rym: Yeah, there's good stuff in here and Platinum spice which I'm probably not gonna click on but this one is particularly choice.
Rym: This is good stuff in the moment We were at PAX East.
Rym: I'm gonna try to have the panel up pretty soon the new brand new winning panel.
Rym: I think our next con is thank icon which Scott probably will bail out because he sucks.
Scott: What day is it?
Rym: and April?
Rym: Nope, not half a month from now.
Rym: Yeah, I'll be there doing a few panels.
Rym: I assume I haven't really done much preparation But I'll be there.
Rym: if you want to see the stuff.
Rym: I would have run it out of my Boston if we hadn't bailed on anime Boston if I do it as thank icon.
Scott: Yeah, are we actually gonna start doing anime season whatever?
Rym: I feel like we'll just start doing the anime season whatever on YouTube.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna prepare it.
Scott: I feel like we should live Anime Boston time now, which is yeah, I usually do it.
Scott: So I'm gonna prepare one as if it was anime Boston.
Rym: Yep, we'll do it on YouTube because we have at least for the time being bailed on my Boston.
Rym: We're gonna turn our like best anime Boston panel into just a YouTube show.
Scott: that we'll do Because we might need.
Scott: we need some advice about the dates.
Scott: so here's the thing.
Scott: what we do is we would go to the anime chart for each for the Next season and we would just look only at the picture and the text and we would with complete prejudice judge Every one of those things on the chart to prepare people for the next season.
Scott: and we were usually like 90 plus percent.
Rym: Yeah, the first year we did it we put we video that shit and it's on YouTube.
Rym: The only
Scott: thing
Rym: the only thing we were wrong about is we thought Sailor Moon Crystal was gonna be great
Scott: anyway, so We need to know if we do this four times a year once for the fall winter spring summer seasons of anime What date would be best for each season right?
Scott: It's like what is the like?
Scott: What is the day ideally when for example, I guess it's current.
Scott: It's about to be spring, right?
Scott: So we're gonna do spring season.
Scott: spring season of anime hasn't started yet, right?
Scott: Yeah, or is it summer season?
Scott: That's next?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But anyway, I don't think about it.
Rym: I yeah, I get the pressure of.
Rym: hey Everyone's talking about this.
Scott: We want to do this when the chart is at its fullest, right when it's most complete So before the show's done before the shows start airing and we get too much information.
Scott: So like what is the date for the summer season when the chart is fullest, but the shows haven't started yet?
Scott: What is the date for the fall season when the chart is most complete, but the fall shows haven't started airing yet?
Scott: Send us those dates Approximately so we know when to produce this show.
Rym: Yep, the other con that we will be at is Kinetic Con July 7th 8th and 9th in Hartford, Connecticut.
Rym: as you know, we are run.
Rym: We run the entire panels department there.
Scott: It still closes at 9 p.m So we can go to bed.
Scott: I enjoy being at Kinetic Con also.
Rym: It's the only place that a lot of people can run panels that aren't anime or games.
Rym: It's true and like there is content at Kinetic Con that literally will not be at any other Conventions.
Scott: Kinetic Con doesn't restrict itself.
Scott: They don't know they don't pretend they don't say they're an anime con.
Scott: They're like, look, we're just the geek con in Connecticut.
Scott: We do everything.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anime is like less.
Scott: If it's geeky we do it.
Rym: Anime content's been dropping because no one fucking submits it anymore.
Rym: so actually a lot of our content is literary and game related and music related and I think the example I always give is one of the one of one panel that Staffer used to run was literally just I mush with dogs like in Alaska.
Rym: having that guy I don't know hasn't been submitted in a while.
Rym: So I yeah, we'll be at Kinetic Con if you were staffed with us last year Do the thing in the email I sent you.
Rym: And if you want to submit a panel go to the website and submit the panel because I'm literally Scheduling the con right now.
Rym: like it's happening I'm gonna try to have the whole schedule filled out like before the end of April Oh, and I'm playing Zelda like every smart person.
Scott: Oh, yeah, follow Scott's YouTube channel, and I'm streaming it live, but I I don't I've.
Scott: the videos are saved on YouTube, but they're unlisted So I don't I don't know how much effort I'm gonna put.
Scott: it's like finding good bits in them and editing them but maybe I'll find some good bits.
Scott: who knows if I'm actually streaming them on Twitch and YouTube.
Rym: so you can go to whichever one you like and watch me from there if you Record them where your voice is a separate track or in the very least if you have a way to pick your voice out from Like Scott not talking.
Rym: Just go to the places where you're saying shit cuz something must have happened there.
Scott: Yeah, or someone said, you know Oh, I need people to chat at me so I can make the chat the stream more interesting rather than just me sitting there.
Scott: Like, you know ride my horse.
Rym: Yep, though there is There's a whole side of YouTube and Twitch that is not.
Rym: let's plays but long plays and the long plays Like the culture is.
Rym: you don't say shit You just play and these are the videos people go to if they want to.
Rym: just like experience the game pure.
Rym: But not play it for some reason.
Scott: just play it.
Rym: Yeah, like there's a whole I'm getting a switch.
Rym: I think the price.
Rym: I think the switch will be back and stop soon.
Scott: stock soon because I Somebody said the Nintendo store had them in stock today at six.
Scott: Oh, they got in a cab and went over there right away.
Scott: And when they got there gone 603 gone 200 people were in line.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: The thing is if you wanted a switch you should have pre-ordered it.
Scott: I pre-ordered it on Amazon months in advance.
Scott: All I did was go click click click.
Scott: I didn't have to wait in any line.
Rym: No, I didn't order.
Scott: and then on the day the switch was released It just showed up on my fucking doorstep.
Scott: Why didn't you do that?
Scott: if I was gonna buy if I failed to do that for some reason I would just wait until Amazon had them in stock again and do the same.
Scott: So not worth the effort.
Rym: So I did not pre-order because what I said on gig nights was that Nintendo would cross too many lines and Nintendo consoles went from by sight unseen to wait and see.
Rym: so I did what I said, I waited and saw and Nintendo exceeded expectations.
Rym: So now I'm gonna buy one as soon as I can just buy it on Amazon.
Rym: But the price of the people trying to flip them on Amazon Suddenly today dropped by a hundred bucks I mean, but I bought mine from amazon.com and not from someone who is selling it on it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so I'm waiting until it is MSRP Amazon.com.
Rym: Yeah right now the people selling on Amazon are flippers and they're selling it for about 80 to 100 dollars over MSRP.
Rym: But even two days ago, it was like 200 plus dollars over MSRP.
Rym: I feel like the people who tried to flip the switch not gonna come out ahead.
Rym: So Scott as he was want to do because we want to queue up Wednesday episodes in advance He dropped off a bunch of comics at our house and I've read two of them so far.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And I was a little worried for a second when I looked this one up for the show because it said Plutona number one.
Rym: But I immediately realized that that's because trade paperbacks which was what we read.
Rym: Yeah There's just one.
Scott: there's only one volume of Plutona that contains all the issues in one book.
Scott: So you can just buy the one book and you're good.
Scott: Yep You don't need the one book like I. don't link people to this link people to Amazon to buy the trade.
Rym: Yeah buy the trade.
Scott: so this is Jeff Lemire Jeff Lemire and Emmy Lennox.
Scott: Emmy Lennox also did the arts and worked with Jeff on the story.
Scott: So Jeff Lemire obviously is like the favorite not Japanese comic creator of GeekNights.
Rym: Yep, Jeff Lemire.
Rym: It did like.
Scott: he doesn't always hit home run, but Like he started off with the Essex County trilogy, right when we knew Yeah Well stuff and that was like his only work then and it was so good.
Scott: and since then like he's been doing So much stuff like they just you know, he just put his name on fucking everything.
Scott: Yeah Superheroes at the Marvel and at the DC and at the ever, you know, but he pretty much always hits at least a double Maybe a triple.
Rym: Yeah good half the time he rounds home, but not always.
Scott: he did the What's it called the the the kid with the deer horns?
Rym: Oh, yeah, I didn't actually read that.
Scott: have all the volumes I haven't read.
Rym: Yeah, I got a queue of comics building up over here despite you not dropping off a lot of comics lately.
Scott: Yeah, no, I'm reading more comics now.
Rym: Yeah, I started reading the My Little Pony again because actually that comic is still like way good I have every issue of my all my little pony trades.
Rym: I got.
Rym: no I'm not no issues for him But Plutona is a self-contained story by the trade is just a graphic novel.
Rym: It starts in a world that doesn't need a lot of explanation and it ends.
Rym: Well, it ends.
Scott: It's one of those ones that sort of like crosses the blurs the line between like the an indie comic kind of story And a superhero kind of story.
Rym: Yeah, and it edges a little bit into the Oh Superheroes but a deconstruction but it doesn't go like the way some of those go.
Rym: Yeah doesn't embrace that full.
Scott: It's like you're in a world with superheroes, but this you don't really get much of the story of the superheroes at all.
Scott: It's about some high school kids.
Scott: They're are they your middle school kids, maybe of them?
Rym: Yeah, I couldn't tell and I didn't think too hard about it.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: They're kids and Living in a world in which superheroes happen to exist The story is about them and not about superheroing just because superheroes happen to be there.
Rym: Yeah, well, we'll.
Rym: we'll avoid spoilers for the beginning But I think we'll talk a little spoiler toward the end of there's only five issues We got.
Scott: we're gonna.
Scott: this episode will be really short if we don't spoil it.
Rym: Yeah so we'll warn you when we're getting to spoilers because I actually got some things to say that require.
Rym: I Don't want to.
Rym: I don't want to ruin this for you because you should just read it.
Scott: It's good Yeah, and only take it.
Scott: only take you like 15 20 minutes though.
Rym: I did like it.
Rym: I haven't read a lot of other stories like it other than maybe like it.
Rym: Yeah stand by me.
Rym: But stand by me is superficially related in that bunch of kids find a dead body.
Scott: Mm-hmm or stand by me is I definitely the first thing I thought about my me is more.
Rym: Some kids found a dead body other kids try to go find the dead body and the movie ends with them finding the body.
Scott: Yeah, this is the beginning.
Rym: Yeah, they find the body right away and Things are not all as they might appear.
Rym: So did you like did you like it?
Scott: Yeah, it's good.
Scott: I'm not sad that I bought it.
Scott: Yeah, you know, but it's not like.
Scott: I wouldn't give it an Eisner Award probably now.
Rym: It was pretty good Atmospherically and the art actually worked really well in terms of setting up the characters.
Scott: I was like.
Scott: I was real intrigued right of like, you know when there was like unknown stuff and I want I really wanted to see what happened and it kept me hooked.
Scott: Yeah, but then you know, it sort of went, you know It wasn't it didn't really give like satisfying hits of like.
Scott: yeah, and then you know things sort of you know Felt they started going in a direction that not only was unexpected but was also weird and Unsatisfying.
Scott: well, so it was unsettling also, but it's like oh you're going for unsettling.
Scott: I'm down with that.
Scott: Yeah I like that but it wasn't unsettling in the way.
Scott: that's like, ooh, that's unsettling and it's so good.
Rym: It was like, uh, you just kind of unsettling but at the same time it was unsettling in a very real way Because that was too real.
Rym: this deals with actually a lot of different themes and it doesn't really say like This is the good thing.
Rym: This is the bad thing.
Rym: or here's our message.
Rym: it says here's a whole bunch of issues and We're gonna explore them and make you think about them and guess what?
Rym: There aren't just neat easy answers to things.
Scott: I do feel like though Exploring the bunch of issues like felt good right like.
Scott: oh look at all the stuff.
Scott: They're getting in here.
Scott: They're covering so much material, but not much of the material.
Scott: We're like another issue.
Scott: They could have gone deeper on each one, right and it would have been better.
Scott: But they think it's like they only went a little bit beyond shallow on the issues.
Scott: So it's just like Just short yep.
Rym: So I think the main the two themes of this that I can pull drag out though and the name helps a little bit Plutona That basically superheroes are gods and in one sense.
Rym: It's a story about if things like that exists Merely interacting with them as a human fucks you up.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And I think that is a very strong theme.
Rym: That is Repeatedly due to the use of insects and where insects appear in this comic I think that theme is set very well and that the insects are unto the humans like the humans are unto The the superheroes the gods right?
Scott: I mean, that's that's not a new theme as far as superhero books are concerned, right?
Scott: I mean we read Dark Knight Returns where basically Superman is portrayed as very godlike.
Scott: there That's yeah, that's the way Superman should be I think and he's very rarely Portrayed that way properly, you know, but it's like yeah at this fucking Superman out there basically like nothing fucking matters.
Scott: There's a holy shit.
Scott: It's like yeah, you can just bow down to Superman now.
Rym: But then it makes this sort of swerve as you not a super spoiler.
Rym: but you see, you know a lot of flashbacks like it's the kids with the dead body of the superhero and it's cut with flashbacks of what the superhero was doing leading up to her being dead in the woods.
Rym: and You see her being a like 100% mundane person with mundane concerns living a mundane life except when she's doing the superhero stuff, which almost leads to this theme that There don't even need to be gods kids Generally when not when they aren't given enough explanation or context Adults are kind of like gods to them and interacting with adults without context can fuck kids up.
Rym: That is the deepest thread I can pull out of this and it's the only way I can explain the sheer mundanity of Plutona's life as like a waitress because they really focus on that in the flashbacks.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, it's like they keep focusing on like every character is like family a lot Like, you know, it's usually in a story.
Scott: you'll get like, you know There'd be one person like if there's a school of kids you'll get one of their families, right?
Scott: And you'll go deep on that.
Scott: and then the other kids just be like kids and you won't see their family so much Unless you get something that's really long-running like South Park where you you know Literally look at every character, right?
Scott: But usually in most cases like you see is the family and the kids go to school and you see the other kids But you don't see the other kids.
Scott: Families, right because you don't spread the character tree out that far and this one you get all the kids home.
Scott: family story deals Even though it's only five issues like the one kid has you know, the dad messing, you know is like abusive
Rym: Yeah, and the kid of course lashes out and you see the cycle of abuse being perpetrated even though he is actually trying to be A good person, right?
Scott: Yeah, there's the turnabout with the kid with the perfectly normal family Yeah, the kid with a perfectly normal family is the most messed up one.
Scott: It's the quote-unquote normal family right the ID idyllic family Yeah, but then you know, you're looking at those families.
Scott: We also see Plutona's family also, right?
Scott: And it's like oh is the family of kids in school from the kids perspective.
Scott: and here's the family of you know, superhero mom Okay, and then they bump into each other.
Rym: but the fact that the superhero life is so mundane and kind of low-rent Really pushes pulls away the God metaphor and pulls it into the adult versus child metaphor Because otherwise I can't explain why they would focus on that.
Scott: You also have to look at like.
Scott: these kids are basically living in this like woodsy town.
Scott: It's like a suburb kind of place, right and the superheroes living in the city and the kids like looking.
Scott: He's looking out at the city with telescope.
Scott: See a lot of those scenes to watch the superheroes of this telescope from the small town Right and the superheroes only in the small town woods.
Rym: because she got punched so hard that she simultaneously Her daughter and her family the superheroes family their city.
Rym: They're not fucked up by interacting with gods it's Non city folk get fucked up by interacting with the complex cosmopolitan world of the city.
Rym: Yeah Sure without context because yeah actually that works.
Rym: because the whole again that my first theme breaks down two ways.
Rym: because the fact that Plutona's family seems to be totally normal and they know she's a superhero.
Scott: No, she can't hide it from grandma But the kid
Rym: like is watching the news because she knows that mom's in a fight like it's just normal to them and yet it Totally ruins these kids living out in podunk suburb, whatever
Scott: What one town away from the city podunk
Rym: suburb, whatever.
Rym: I think at this point we got a spoil because I Can't say anything else about this.
Rym: So just read it and then come back to this episode I guess.
Rym: but we're gonna spoil everything.
Rym: after this point.
Scott: You can get it digitally too.
Scott: if you don't want to get that pretty sure you can.
Rym: I was spoiler.
Rym: So sure, she wasn't actually dead from the beginning.
Scott: Well, that was kind of obvious right because he's been stun ray.
Scott: Yeah, she had been my stunner Yeah But like he had been she'd been in the woods for a while like if you're a dead body in the woods for even like a day Flies are coming at least right now,
Rym: but to be at beginning it does
Scott: come within minutes.
Rym: Yes There's flies on her in the first panel, but it's like lies all over her.
Scott: She would have been way stanky if she was dead.
Scott: Yeah, it would have not been a good scene.
Rym: But these kids just like hey, but also I forget when it's first mentioned, but they're like, I've got my man My great stunner weapon ha ha ha stuns.
Rym: Yeah, I'll stun.
Scott: you also like they're getting blood from her.
Scott: It's like man, she dead the blood ain't flowing.
Rym: Well, they it's basically Tugger, you know when there's a kid in a comic or a story like this who is made fun of for something weird Usually the the twist is like that kid's actually okay, or that was just like youthful whatever.
Rym: no that kid was kind of messed up and Masturbating two people in school and yet.
Rym: Yeah, he was totally fucked up and that continued.
Rym: Like that kid had problems and was not redeemed.
Rym: He just went crazy.
Rym: Kid was probably would have become a serial killer.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I mean sometimes you know There's a nerdy kid who's made fun of be not because you know bullies are bullies, but because Someone's actually doing something weird.
Scott: That's not socially acceptable and is being socially shunned.
Scott: Yeah, and it's it's showing you that which usually is.
Scott: it's interesting cuz usually in a superhero comic you get the Peter Parker nerd story Which is like no stop picking on that nerd.
Scott: The nerds gonna become spider-man watch out.
Scott: Yeah, we're here.
Scott: It's like kids actually bad and everyone can tell and that's why he's getting picked on.
Scott: At first you think like the bully kid is bad, and they give you that stereotypical story of bully kid is being abused.
Scott: That's why he's bullying, but it's like no.
Scott: He's really only bullying that one kid.
Scott: Yeah, who's actually bad?
Rym: Well, he bullies the girl in green a few times, but then I forget all their names, right?
Scott: But when he's bullying her it it felt to me at least like kids who don't know better like the girl they like.
Scott: No It felt to me at least more like how friends would just sort of talk smack Right.
Scott: when he was when you know to the kid who was actually bad it actually felt like he was bullying him.
Scott: true At least that's just the way I read it.
Scott: You know I could be totally right.
Rym: even then He still also tries to make friends with a kid.
Rym: I mean that he'd like is hanging out with him and like wants to yeah They
Scott: give you that scene right where it's like oh they find something in common Right and they start you know until someone else is there to see and he's like oh no I can't be seen being friends with you in front of anybody.
Scott: yep, but if no one's around okay Let's chat about video games or whatever.
Rym: so I Subjects wise.
Rym: I read that the blonde girl in green again I don't remember any other names already, and I just read this pretty sure she has Romantic feelings toward the other girl and the other girl is romantic feelings toward the bully guy.
Rym: yeah And tugger just wants to be a god yeah, and the younger brother is just kidding like he's actually just a nerdy kid.
Rym: Yeah, but they just get dragged into shit like he's mostly focused on his gameboy.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: He just does good drink.
Rym: yep uh Pretty much as soon as that kid was cutting himself.
Rym: I was pretty sure he was just gonna die.
Scott: Like is he gonna get AIDS or something?
Scott: I was like.
Scott: I was like okay, obviously he's not getting superpowers.
Scott: That's not where this is going right.
Rym: so for a second I was wondering like maybe it'll work cuz that would make this a way different story.
Scott: I thought that there were gonna be some other consequences that weren't right.
Scott: cuz like okay You're doing something.
Scott: so that's that.
Scott: doing that is a Chekhov's gun of some kind.
Scott: right something is gonna happen because you're doing that But it's not gonna be.
Rym: To find it There's a scene in one of the last later flashbacks where Plutona herself is like I could snap wafts neck without effort But I can't.
Rym: I need to be better hit to than him.
Rym: I need to keep the Plutona power under control And there's a few references to the powers.
Rym: let her lose control some superhero nonsense Yep, so I thought I wondered if that was maybe That like foreshadowing something.
Scott: yeah, like maybe she would just explode or something out in the woods.
Scott: Yeah, he's messing with her and the power gets up.
Rym: We don't know where the power comes from but now now he's dead and they clearly didn't go to the police.
Rym: and these kids are All fucked.
Scott: yeah like they saw some fucked up shit.
Rym: and this ends with.
Rym: like the next day the cops show up because the kids dead and they All get implicated because of modern you know cell phones and stuff And they all have to testify in their minors.
Rym: and like it ends on a like you're all gonna learn a hard lesson about life kids Mm-hmm, and it just like that's it.
Rym: It's very unsatisfied.
Scott: I think the best part that was in Plutona wakes up.
Scott: She's just like what the fuck right?
Scott: you expect like the superhero to wake up And you're totally expecting her to just like see these kids and like be like you know.
Scott: they would tell her what happened And she would lecture them right cuz that's what Superman would do right yeah, or Batman would do is they'd be like You know I realize they're in trouble, and it helped them right.
Scott: It's like you see some kids in trouble.
Scott: It's like you save them, and then you wag your finger at them And then you tell them how the world is.
Scott: you know set him on the straight path cuz that's how you do.
Scott: But now this she just wakes up And she's just like what the fuck I get.
Scott: any adult that wakes up in the woods after a hangover.
Scott: It was like what the fuck.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: I gotta get home.
Scott: Oh my god How long have I been here?
Rym: and then she's pissed like what happened.
Rym: my fingers cuz tugger was cutting her right?
Scott: She just goes home.
Scott: She doesn't know these kids are there or know anything that happened.
Rym: meanwhile at the same time an adult It would often do that like what are you kids doing?
Rym: what the fuck I got?
Rym: I got my own real-life adult stuff to do.
Scott: I'm not my kid.
Scott: Yeah, if you're not your kids.
Scott: You're just like you're not hanging out with any strange kids.
Rym: Yeah The same time like they legit needed help and that kid might have survived if she had in any way Tried to help them.
Scott: right well could mean the superhero is her job the way She helps us by fighting villain.
Scott: I guess the villain guy wants like who knows what he wants.
Scott: blow up the city rob all the banks right?
Scott: That's what she's stopping.
Scott: She's not capable of handling.
Scott: You know these everyday or kids social issues That's not what a superhero can do.
Scott: she punches hard And she can't even solve her own social issues with her own family.
Scott: But at the same time she's gonna solve some kids fucked up head.
Rym: She could have just picked him up and taken him to the hospital sure But I don't think she even noticed him.
Scott: no cuz she was just pissed and she just woke up from being KO for days.
Scott: Yep, how's she gonna notice some kid lying there?
Scott: She's like oh shit gotta fly home.
Rym: So yeah it dealt with it.
Rym: we it wove a lot of interesting themes together Didn't fully deliver on any of them or in the very least did not give Concrete stances on any of them.
Rym: hmm it just introduced them Showed you a kind of grim and realistic ending and also kind of left you with this feeling that no there aren't endings There's always the next day, and you have to deal with shit.
Scott: at least it's you know.
Scott: it's unique It's short it's inexpensive You know it's well-written.
Scott: the art is way good, right?
Scott: So it's worth your.
Scott: you know the amount of time.
Scott: It will take you to experience.
Scott: It is just not something.
Scott: That's Legendary must be on every bookshelf next to Watchmen.
Rym: yep, it's something I would read on my commute alongside all the other stuff I read.
Scott: you won't be sad that you read it, and you know put in the time to go for it.
Scott: But if you're not gonna like remember it and recommend it for the ages.
Rym: no, but I'll recommend S6 County to this day sure why not?
Rym: that is some bleak and wonderful stuff.
Scott: I heard underwater welder It might get a movie action.
Scott: Oh, yeah, which is really a weird choice for a movie action.
Scott: It's like what.
Scott: really.
Scott: that's what you're picking for a movie all right.
Scott: Yeah Okay, go for it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our Website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Ellen Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette.
Rym: great job emoji my stady calm William Eisneros Jeremy minor Gosh.
Rym: it disturbs me to see you Gaston looking so down in the dumps.
Rym: Iao nine nine nine nine nine.
Rym: Really, dude all right.
Rym: one two three four five six seven eight nine two oh one three four five six seven eight Comma nine oh one five two one seven six nine eight nine five six six seven lowercase a 234 comma.
Rym: five six seven eight nine.
Rym: Oh you paid five dollars to make me do that.
Rym: sure about horror.
Rym: Rare Laval is pronounced with an O. Rare Laval Roar Laval.
Rym: that O does not give me enough context.
Rym: James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make Rym say Topeka again.
Rym: Brian Fisher sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich Jartavishan Jojo Joestar Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan Perrin an unrequested fission surplus Brian Cedroni blah bear Sreltoi Redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I spent the weekend in Albany.
Rym: and the thing The political thing the thing that I keep telling you like stay tuned the things gonna happen, and it'll be a thing that helps people.
Rym: Yeah, it's happening.
Rym: It's uh We're gonna be filing papers and legal stuff is moving and we got a pretty good idea to make this Literally a reality, and then I'll be able to talk about it publicly.
Rym: so seriously stay tuned It's coming and now I leave you with.