Rym: It's Monday April 17th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about PC cooling.
Scott: Let's do this Alright, so remember when I was like man.
Scott: my computer keeps having these blue screens.
Scott: I'm gonna play I can't?
Scott: I gotta find a replacement motherboard.
Scott: I remember remember that.
Scott: So I replaced that motherboard and it totally worked Until until stop working.
Scott: No, it didn't stop working.
Scott: It's just like the computer.
Scott: still it's like it's weird.
Scott: The computer works perfectly and just blue screens randomly and it's not it.
Scott: the blue screen message Every time is a different.
Scott: one is different.
Scott: So it's like you google all these different ones and you keep getting answers.
Scott: It's like none of these are what I have and you google and it's like I keep getting a bunch of different blue screen messages and that doesn't help you either right, I'd still guess either motherboard or Probably mother.
Scott: is it the second motherboard?
Rym: Well, you gotta use motherboard.
Rym: the blue screen and motherboard itself might have a congenital defect the effect of the womb.
Scott: So the blue screening waxes and wanes, right?
Rym: Well based on what I don't know, huh?
Scott: It just waxes and wanes.
Rym: Anyway, so I don't know what you're from.
Rym: I don't have these problems.
Scott: I just read that's a hardware problem.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: I'm saying I Did.
Rym: I have not had problems like this?
Rym: There must be something wrong with something you did and wrong with some hardware.
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: I did.
Scott: Hardware problem happens to anybody.
Scott: so Yeah, cuz the things that I complain about other people doing is like they fuck up their own shit like oh you installed that malware.
Scott: Oh you installed that shitty program.
Scott: Oh you you you're complaining.
Scott: your phone is broken, but you jail broke it.
Scott: Why are you complaining?
Scott: I don't tell people when they have a hardware problem.
Scott: I don't get on the case Hardware breaks sometimes.
Rym: maybe it's just time to buy a new computer.
Rym: No, even though you wanted to wait.
Scott: No, I don't want to buy a new computer.
Scott: So I'm like, well, I did a RAM test again of like the tenth time and it says your RAM is a-ok.
Scott: So I'm not.
Scott: I didn't even try removing RAM sticks or anything Even though that seems like it's what it should be right.
Scott: and I figure well if the CPUs busted I'm buying a new computer right, so so It's only that computer right?
Scott: Yes, because a thing my new Htbc is so perfect and I think it is never because a thing that could crashed or failed in any way It is the most solid computer since my high energy ionizing radiation could cause single bit errors.
Rym: That would lead to crashes that frequently anyway.
Rym: Well, I mean if there was a high rate it like a high source of radiation like.
Rym: so I thought your apartment.
Scott: So obviously blue screens are mostly caused by driver situations, right?
Scott: So I thought maybe my Nvidia, you know card would be bad.
Scott: Maybe I'll try to use my you know, the built-in card on the motherboard and just take the Nvidia card.
Rym: That's actually a pretty good test.
Scott: But you know, I figure I just updated the Nvidia driver and that didn't have an effect.
Scott: so it's like well I don't really want to not have maybe the video card.
Scott: I don't want to go down to one monitor and have no GPU, right?
Rym: So in fact, I wouldn't be super surprised about something weird like the video card putting stress on the PSU.
Scott: Anyway, I'll do that if I have to write it's not a PSU from.
Rym: so Have you done voltage test?
Scott: you sure if it was a PSU problem the computer would turn off and not blue screen.
Scott: It depends anyway, so I go online, you know, I start researching some of the different blue screen messages Right, and one of them, you know, basically a lot of them were clearly not what was wrong with me?
Scott: Yeah, they were like, oh your RAM is busted.
Scott: I'm like, nope, that's not me.
Scott: They're like, oh you got a malware.
Scott: but one of them was like yeah when Windows 10 was brand new there was some problem with this SATA driver and You know, it got fixed in a way in a later Windows update.
Rym: and I'm like Okay So does your motherboard like a lot of old motherboards have the regular SATA driver and then the other SATA chip to give you The newer motherboard?
Scott: just is all Intel everything okay, so but anyways cuz I had that problem once with an 8-bit motherboard and it was the.
Rym: there was the normal chipset that gave me like for my And then there was this other chipsets.
Scott: obviously my windows 10 is updated so that's not the problem.
Scott: The problem is not an out-of-date driver.
Scott: Yeah, but I was like, huh?
Scott: That's weird though that You know that could cause a blue screen even though it's like storage related.
Scott: you figure when storage fails you just get failing storage.
Scott: So I figured huh?
Scott: Well about you know, there's a harmless process of elimination.
Scott: I got that really old SSD in there.
Scott: I'm just gonna unplug it.
Scott: I'll just unplug the old SSD.
Scott: You know, I only for storage I only use it for swap when I'm for scratch space in Adobe.
Rym: I don't use it for anything else just scratch space or also like Windows swap.
Scott: No only scratch.
Scott: So I don't use it for literally anything.
Scott: So I'm like, I'll just unplug that and see what happens.
Scott: There hasn't been a blue screen since I am play, huh?
Scott: And I'm like really an SSD can cause blue screens like that and I don't know for sure because it hasn't been long enough To you know, I could you know.
Scott: next step is removing the video card.
Rym: That is the problem with that sort of intermittent hardware.
Rym: problem is that unless you have Multiple copies of the same hardware.
Rym: There's really no way to like test it to figure it out.
Scott: So if the blue screen happens again hard drives going back in video cards coming out.
Rym: But if it never happens again, you still don't know for sure if that was it.
Scott: Oh, no, if it never happens again I'll be confident.
Scott: was that I was that SSD and I bought in your motherboard for nothing.
Rym: But eh, whatever the worst case would be if it doesn't happen for a while and then it happens once Happens like I run.
Scott: I read I first I got tried reinstalling Windows and it didn't happen for a long.
Scott: And then it happened and I'm like what the fuck.
Rym: so with the computer.
Rym: Two or three computers ago that I used to do use like resound and GeekNights like in the old days with Gen 2 It would blue screen Occasionally and I figured out there's a bunch of different causes.
Rym: that were they were all.
Rym: basically there are multiple things causing it.
Rym: One of them was the USBs on the case had subtle shorts And when I unplugged them they stopped happening.
Rym: but they then they started happening again less frequently with a different set of error codes and I eventually narrowed that one down to.
Rym: if I ever let the computer hibernate or go to sleep Then I would have blue screens and when I disabled all that stuff and powered it down every day before I went to work and only Powered it up and when I was home never blue screened again Unless I plugged in those USBs.
Scott: No, I'll probably buy a new computer and next to you.
Scott: Yeah Like a 1180 if you can hold everyone else in the 1080s I'd be like, haha 1180 what you could do about it?
Rym: Like if you're gonna buy a computer like we're in this great plateau time to buy one.
Rym: But if you can hold out like another six months or a year, you're gonna get another generational.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's no you know, my computer power wise just fun.
Rym: Yeah, mine was not power wise.
Rym: That's why I got the new one And I so I did a test of a pipeline.
Rym: cuz you know that old advance war show I did a few times.
Rym: people really Liked it.
Rym: people keep watching it.
Rym: There's like tons of views on those old videos.
Scott: There's no other advances content.
Rym: the my old CPU was literally not fast enough to fully run the DS emulators out there.
Rym: So it would like run slow and cause problems.
Rym: So I tested all that on.
Rym: the new computer works like a champ and I turned on the ultra high quality sound processing Including the weird stuff 100%.
Rym: it just maxes out one of my cores and everything's fine.
Rym: So I'm gonna start doing the advanced war show.
Rym: I think Yeah, you got any news On this Monday this tech news day.
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: so You know Apple Apple made some sort of recent more announcement of.
Scott: we're like, yeah We're actually gonna do Mac Pro.
Scott: We know whatever right but nothing is set in stone for that, right?
Scott: They yeah, they could come out with some more garbage or whatever.
Scott: But basically they admitted like that the Mac the trash can Mac Pro from what?
Scott: 2012 or whatever it was sufficient, you know, they basically designed themselves into a hole where they couldn't like.
Scott: upgrade when you know to newer stuff and it's like Dumb asses.
Scott: just get the best possible hardware the same computer that I would buy today install OS X on it overpriced it by Thousand to two thousand dollars and sell it.
Scott: Everyone will buy it.
Rym: There's a little bit of nuance to that like the big complaints about the newer.
Rym: You can ask book pros not being powerful enough.
Rym: We're a little bit complicated because some aspects of them were criminally underpowered but other aspects of them We're not talking about.
Scott: we're talking about Mac Pro the desktop thing the MacBook Pro, whatever.
Rym: Yeah But the people who complained about his performance didn't seem to realize that the storage was all PCIe Which is actually like out of the realm of most computer users experience.
Scott: Whatever the point is, you know, the CPUs the GPUs most of all have always been underpowered and max Yeah, but anyway, you know still eat today and whenever Apple even updates it or price still be overpriced garbage, right?
Scott: They don't know how to make a powerful desktop, right?
Scott: I'd be very surprised if they succeeded at this even though if they just put me in charge of it Windows would just die on the desktop Because I would just be like, oh here's a $2,000 computer.
Scott: it runs OS X and it's godlike.
Scott: Congratulations.
Scott: We now have 100% market share.
Scott: That was easy anyway But yeah, so they're gonna fail and people, you know who must keep OS X for whatever reason they just can't Windows They can't bring themselves to Windows and obviously you can't Linux.
Scott: It's true they've been doing hackintoshes more and more and hackintoshing has become more and more like Successful like it works better than it used to.
Rym: I mean if you're not still it's still.
Scott: I'm not saying it's smooth It's still hacky.
Scott: It's hackintosh, right?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: Oh perfectly good Macintosh, right It's hackintosh.
Scott: But if you want to do it you can do it like if you don't need to play games and you want a powerful computer and you want to run OS X and You don't want to pay a whole bunch for a shitty computer from Apple.
Scott: You can buy regular parts Just figure out which the right parts beforehand and install OS X on a normal desktop computer With an Intel i7 and a 1080 and whatever.
Scott: so What the big news is is that Nvidia put out some new drivers for their new crazy Titan ridiculous video card But also for pretty much all Pascal video cards, which are
Rym: all so the 1050 the 10 series
Scott: Yeah, the 10 series and up right all the new ones the ones that you would buy today Not the old ones that you know There's no reason to buy.
Rym: it also supports all the older geforce and quadra going all the way back to the 8000 series Sure, but anyway, the point is they released Mac drivers for these things.
Scott: It's like wait a minute Wait, you released Mac drivers OS X drivers for a video card that the only way anyone could possibly put one of these video cards into a Mac is either a You've got the old trash can Mac Pro and you find a way to make it fit in there Which
Rym: I'm dubious.
Scott: if that's possible I don't think you can do that too.
Scott: You can get one of these like External things were like you take a video card and you plug it into your macbook pro with like a you know Thunderbolt cable kind of deal or USB C cable.
Rym: Why is that a thing?
Scott: I think it's possible.
Scott: But yeah, whatever Yeah possible.
Rym: I mean a lot of things are possible with computing.
Rym: run J2 the world is possible.
Scott: See you make yourself a hackintosh.
Scott: So now there's an the one part of hackintoshing that was before You know or one of the parts that was slightly hacky is now significantly less hack.
Scott: You have an official legit Nvidia driver that we presume and video is testing on hackintoshes.
Scott: cuz what else the hell could they test?
Rym: So that's it.
Rym: The real story here.
Rym: Isn't that it happened?
Rym: It's why did Nvidia do it?
Rym: for the fuck of it?
Rym: did Nvidia do it because of some agreement?
Scott: Oh because they're gonna make some Monet because there's people who are Mac people who are insisting on being Mac people are not buying Nvidia cards and now it's like hey all you people who insist on Not windowsing.
Scott: Maybe we'll sell some Nvidia cards to you.
Scott: It was worth it for us to make this driver to get those extra sales.
Rym: I don't know if that alone is enough business driver because I've seen Companies leave way more money on the table because it's not worth the effort.
Scott: well, also, I'm pretty sure the Apple computers like have ATI cards in them, right I Don't even know anymore.
Scott: I think I don't think this Nvidia's in the max right now From what I've definitely been in there in the past, but I don't think they are now.
Rym: Everything is talking about hackintoshes.
Scott: when I google for that obviously right just go to app.
Scott: Yeah, oh that I think has and I think that is Nvidia.
Rym: That's from 2012.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh My god this website.
Rym: I don't even care anymore.
Rym: I've already given up but I Wonder if this is part of a longer-term thing where the next max are just going to have modern video cards.
Rym: Or maybe actually if Apple were smart and they didn't want to go your route of put you in charge of everything the smart Route.
Rym: Yeah, but there's that there's a middle path where you make them at the new whatever the new Mac.
Scott: Yeah, no Completely still like trash can.
Rym: Mac Pro has AMD cards in it But you make it still the like closed black box except you have a slot where you can put in a commodity video card The.
Rym: so someone who buys the new Mac could keep replacing the video card and upgrading it.
Rym: but they can't replace anything else without going through the Apple process and that would require probably a Relatively simple deal between Nvidia and Apple.
Rym: I could see that happening though.
Rym: Imagine the new trash can that has a video card slot you slot the video card.
Scott: the MacBook Pros have Intel iris graphics 450.
Rym: Yeah, probably if you want a powerful laptop at this point you just get a surface book Pro with the performance base for service book, whatever.
Rym: There's the surface and the surface book.
Rym: get the one that has the performance base.
Scott: No, if you want a powerful laptop you get the gaming one.
Scott: Oh, yeah You think it actually has a real GP.
Scott: got ones with 1080s in them.
Rym: that weighs almost as much as my desktop.
Scott: It runs.
Rym: not really a laptop so much as a portable computer that has a screen.
Scott: It's still smaller than Like a mini ITX desktop.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: That is in fact true and doesn't require carrying a monitor.
Rym: So in other news, this is this is a good use of technology and I'm really surprised This wasn't more widely deployed sooner and it may have been but I never really noticed it.
Rym: But so cops in Colorado are trying out this technology where the front of the cop car Can shoot a big old dart covered in glue like James Bond.
Rym: Yeah, that sticks to the car in front of them and it's just a GPS beacon.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean if you're sitting in your car and you're driving and you're trying to get away from the cops and you hear Thunk, you know, you'll be like, huh?
Scott: So then the cops stop following you and you go, huh and you get out of your car.
Rym: You've got to stop to get out.
Rym: They don't necessarily have to stop following you but it's not a high-speed pursuit.
Rym: The only way to deal with this thing Pretty quickly, especially if the cops are chasing you your buddy, you know does a little action scene, right?
Scott: He's hanging out the window.
Rym: Well, it's on the back of the car.
Rym: I don't think that's gonna happen.
Rym: Yeah, you get on the trunk, you know crowbar I feel like your best option is to because remember that you got to abandon the car.
Rym: Anyway, it's just gonna force you to abandon it sooner and turn it into a foot chase.
Rym: but cops are actually using this stuff now and technology's actually made it pretty sweet and pretty safe and pretty affordable.
Rym: and supposedly they've been using these things for nine months now and They've had 85% success rate.
Scott: success rate is measured.
Scott: how when when do they use them?
Scott: When do they not use them?
Rym: in situations where they would have had a high-speed pursuit because the suspect attempted to escape?
Rym: so instead they just shoot the dart and then Helicopters and other cops can just sort of corral them or figure out where they dump the car and then as the foot chase Makes it a lot harder to get away because the whole goal of a high-speed pursuit is To still have the car and be out of line of sight of the cops long enough to get away.
Rym: This makes that real hard to do because you can't even if you stop to try to take the thing off the car Like the cops know literally exactly where you are and that you've stopped gonna put an EMP in your car.
Rym: The EMP would also take out the car.
Scott: get old car.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you know car.
Rym: I feel like the James Bond already have has ways to deal with this.
Rym: This is more for James meth addict.
Rym: I Couldn't come up with another name.
Scott: So just yeah, that's pretty much 90% of the time who's running.
Rym: but this is in my idea.
Rym: this is a good and interesting use of technology because there's a problem.
Rym: the problem is Someone doesn't want to get arrested.
Rym: when the police decide they're going to arrest them and there's and the cops have a choice Let the criminal go or chase them with their car.
Rym: And as we know when you have cars chasing each other.
Rym: Blues Brothers is gonna happen at some point and actually a lot of people get killed in high-speed pursuits Usually people unrelated to the high-speed pursuit.
Rym: So even the ACLU weighed in saying that as long as they use them as they're intended.
Rym: This is great.
Rym: It's not illegal.
Rym: They're pretty much fine with it because this is only used when someone is.
Scott: this isn't the kind I mean, you know Long law enforcement in general has misused GPS like they sneak up to your car at night and stick it inside.
Scott: This is a thing that's like funk.
Scott: It's on the back of your car and they're only using it when the cop is behind you and chasing you.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like, you know, there this is.
Rym: You can hide it in your car at night to see what you're doing all they do, but this isn't that.
Rym: yeah This uses.
Scott: this is an okay use.
Scott: It's also very obvious like, you know, like even if you're even if you're just speeding and they you know They drive behind you and use it.
Rym: I love the idea of you know, if we're gonna have cars that humans still drive.
Rym: I am really okay with 100% enforcement of reasonable traffic laws like everyone who ever runs a stop sign immediate ticket immediate never drive again ever.
Scott: I think any driving.
Scott: if we have cars that are have computers driving them Right and they drive effectively perfectly.
Scott: if you don't drive as perfectly as they do You shouldn't be allowed to drive because you're effectively murdering.
Rym: the practical reality of shitty Is that you need a car to live unless you live in like one of four places in the entire country, right?
Scott: So we'll give you a self-driving car.
Rym: Okay, okay.
Scott: Okay The problem you don't even have to give you one self-driving cars just driving around everywhere on their own and you just have one get in.
Rym: but the leap the leap of society between we have the technology and We give that technology to all Americans to make society better.
Rym: I feel like the Gulf between those two is politically insurmountable.
Scott: I'm also okay with the all.
Scott: there's another with another plan right the same opposite plan Which is in places where people have used sidewalks we ban all cars No, and in places where people don't use sidewalks, you know, like the rest of the country We don't have any traffic rules.
Scott: Everyone who drives X everyone who drives will just eventually die and will buy buy natural selection will get rid.
Scott: of all people who want to drive Everything will be great.
Rym: So I have driven cars in and around Istanbul and I've also ridden on motorbikes in Hyderabad in Mumbai.
Scott: That's like almost the worst in the world.
Rym: Also Sao Paulo.
Scott: I've heard a Kyra heard Cairo is possibly the worst.
Rym: Sao Paulo and Brazil like in the downtown.
Rym: It's like New York in the freeways outside of New York.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: Four lanes is actually twelve lanes.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: Emily and I the other night stumbled upon this literally just randomly looking at YouTube shit.
Rym: There is a movie slash documentary from 1988 called computer dreams.
Rym: Okay, what it is is a showcase of the heights of computer animation in 1988.
Scott: so slightly better than Tron, uh Not really.
Scott: no.
Rym: so a lot of the things that we think of as computer animation were mostly practical effects back then.
Rym: This looks like like the the best things in this documentary Look worse than the worst student project you have ever seen in your life from any year since.
Scott: But you said it was 1988 though, right?
Scott: Yeah, okay, but what year did Tron come out?
Scott: 1983 two three something like that.
Scott: I think Tron is definitely before 1982, right?
Rym: I was right.
Scott: Yeah, so this is six years after Tron.
Scott: shouldn't everything look at least as good as Tron?
Scott: So how good should look should look six years better than on.
Rym: how good to try to actually look into.
Rym: which parts of Toronto Are you thinking about that are actually computer generated fully?
Rym: Versus which ones actually use a lot of the light cycles.
Scott: The light cycles are computer generated.
Rym: They don't look that good.
Scott: Tron looks good.
Scott: Yeah, we're looking at GL Tron there.
Rym: That's the photo on IMDb.
Scott: That might be GL Tron and not actual Tron.
Rym: the point is the best part about the documentary.
Scott: There's this documentary.
Scott: that is your thing of the day.
Scott: look better than those screenshots of Tron.
Scott: So it's six years better.
Rym: Uh So it's kind of all over the place because it's a highlight from a lot of different studios.
Scott: I think it's not the height of 88.
Scott: So there's probably some demo scene stuff from 88 that looks better.
Rym: Well demo scene is very different from this stuff.
Scott: Well, you said the height demo scene is the height.
Rym: well so demo scene is a little bit different because that is not so much.
Rym: that is computer graphics as opposed to like models and computer like rendering.
Scott: It's one of those.
Scott: or what it looks like isn't great.
Rym: A lot of demo scene stuff is raster graphics or very specialized draw the pixels.
Rym: I'm just saying as opposed to here is a model of a thing You're not.
Scott: you're not talking about how like how good it looks.
Scott: you think about like the the height is in terms of like the Functionality behind it like whoa, this looks like crap, but it's actually a physics engine from 1988.
Rym: So the technology the output the uses of it.
Rym: the craziest part is this one bit showed the idea of modeling.
Rym: How do you make a computer model of a person to then like animate?
Rym: So they literally sculpted a person and then drew on that physical model basically a mesh of polygons and then used a light pen to trace over the Physical model to input the data into the computer to make the model.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I remember when they did that.
Rym: Yeah, you remember that.
Rym: you remember it to them doing that in 1989.
Scott: I remember those days I've seen that I've seen I've seen that technology in use before.
Rym: This video also gives some pretty heavy vaporwave vibes if you watch it, so Good luck.
Rym: Have fun.
Rym: Watch it.
Rym: Enjoy it.
Rym: And it's pretty.
Rym: it's pretty interesting to see this.
Scott: So in more crime news, there are some people in prison I don't know what for they were at the what the hell the Ohio department Rehabilitation and Corrections Center somewhere in Ohio Marion Correctional Institution Anyway in Marion, Ohio.
Scott: So they were in prison and part of their prisonness was they got computer classes in prison.
Scott: and I was like when I read that I was like, hey, maybe I should like go to prison like no just like just like Rikers Island wanted me to teach people.
Scott: You know, I guess they're gonna close it right but you know, I'll go teach people in prison.
Scott: How do you computer?
Scott: I'll teach him real good.
Rym: I suspect they will not pay you enough money.
Scott: It's a volunteer job.
Scott: I assume.
Scott: but anyway, all right, but they got computer classes in prison totally cool and Apparently these the the supervision at this prison was good enough to keep anyone from escaping Because I guess no one escaped as far as I could tell.
Scott: but they didn't really give a shit what people did in the prison Which seems to be how prison goes.
Scott: Yes, so They took these computer parts and basically took working computers back into some sort of you know place.
Scott: So they're not supposed to have them.
Scott: and not only did they have working computers They plugged them in to the network.
Scott: They put the computers in the ceiling and connected them to the network Yep, and logged in using an employee's login when that employee was not at work.
Scott: This wasn't just the prison network.
Scott: It was like the state's computer network because it was a state prison and it's all the state places are on the same network.
Scott: So I'm assuming they only found out because the state IT guys noticed.
Scott: Huh?
Scott: There's a lot of activity coming from like these two.
Scott: Where the hell are these computers?
Scott: Oh shit, they're in this prison.
Scott: Who's the hell's doing it?
Scott: Oh, it's this guy.
Scott: He's doing it when he's not even on the job.
Scott: When is he easy logging in on like Sunday morning to internet?
Scott: What the hell right.
Scott: and then they found out and it's like whoa, but if we are ever in prison obvious.
Scott: So so way to go prisoners good job.
Scott: This was on FARC.
Scott: So I don't Prison.
Scott: bad job unless it was just drugs.
Scott: in which case good job.
Rym: So, uh, what did you read?
Rym: what they use the computers to do?
Scott: look at porn.
Scott: I assume.
Rym: Oh, yeah You assume that to quote the Ohio Inspector General says visitors found inmate use the computer to steal the identity of another inmate Submit credit card applications on his behalf and commit tax fraud.
Scott: Well, they just.
Scott: you're in prison.
Scott: What good is money?
Scott: What good is a credit card?
Scott: You're in prison.
Scott: Amazon ain't gonna deliver shit one.
Rym: I assume you're gonna get out of prison at some point at least you think you will - you pry no people on the outside.
Scott: You're having your people on the outside buy good shit.
Scott: So when you get out you be like, ah, here's all the good shit about it.
Rym: Maybe or maybe you're sending money to people and then they're getting your.
Rym: you know They're sneaking the contraband in because our prisons let people do whatever they want.
Scott: I see computers in so why not right?
Scott: Yeah That's pretty good.
Scott: I also read that.
Scott: I don't know if they had a. I don't know if they had a printer But apparently they made like security passes and use that get through security checkpoints.
Rym: So I've known a few people have worked at prison over the years and so have you and I did that.
Rym: the one thing I've Learned from talking to anyone who's ever interacted with their prison system.
Rym: Is that it's garbage.
Rym: people in prison are bored and They will eventually figure out how to get around things because they're bored.
Scott: That's right back in the day prisoners used to like, you know study in the library and pass the bar, right?
Scott: I'm sure some of them still do that because they know their public defender can't help them because they got 7,000 cases So they end up doing it themselves, you know, cuz they're not guilty or whatever, right?
Scott: So that you know, that's just one of the things you can do with your prison time man If I was in prison, I would you know, it was some skill.
Scott: I would practice that I'd be become the god of something.
Scott: Nope, no matter at least way and at least one thing possibly more than one thing.
Rym: You're real good at shivs.
Scott: Oh, man Where's that?
Rym: cop?
Rym: prison comics momo Shav is like ain't done yet.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: No, man, you go to the MoMA.
Scott: They'd be like Scott's shivs like masterpieces.
Rym: I Saw an exhibit in a museum once.
Rym: that was a collection of Improvised weapons from US prison.
Scott: Oh, that was the thing of the day a long long time ago.
Rym: No when I was a kid, I saw it in a museum in Detroit.
Scott: Are you sure it wasn't the thing of the day that we're from a long time ago It was it's been the thing of the day I think multiple times.
Scott: that is often a thing on the internet is an extremely early thing of the day like 2005 or 6.
Rym: Anyway, oh look a ton of improvised prison weapons.
Rym: Oh Look at this gun.
Scott: It's a gun.
Rym: That's a pretty good zip gun there.
Scott: Congratulations.
Rym: That looks like a four-barreled shotgun.
Scott: someone made Good job.
Rym: Here's some pretty good shivs.
Rym: Well, this guy's got like a cross guard for his fans like a dueling spoon.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah In the middle of the book the book is still Frank Gerberts dune Dune a not do.
Rym: Yeah, we'll read it.
Scott: It's on Carmack's doom.
Rym: We'll read it at some point.
Rym: It's doing some point.
Rym: after I Began in I'm hanging out with the bird people now.
Rym: I think I'm gonna do that great be.
Rym: second and I got the master sword Finally, yeah, I just I never.
Rym: I only have two stamina wheels and I just went around beating shrines until I got enough heart containers I beat.
Scott: I got I will.
Scott: I've never treated with the dark guy in a clean house before I you know, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I've never treated with the dark God.
Scott: I haven't played in a while gonna play probably me today.
Rym: I was playing last night during that awful hockey game.
Scott: anyway What other metamoments we got?
Rym: our YouTube channels are pretty good.
Rym: You should follow them.
Scott: We're making more video contents lately.
Scott: You should watch.
Scott: you follow us on.
Scott: you know, any social media that you got?
Scott: Twitter Facebook's Instagram.
Scott: Yeah, we have all those things.
Scott: We are on all the places of the Internet.
Rym: so I'm actually trying to post to Instagram more because I made an account and I never really used it and I Noticed that a ton of you are following it even though I never really post anything.
Rym: So I'm gonna start.
Scott: I think I have a GeekNights' Instagram I made I don't know where with the.
Scott: I gotta log into it again, but I met when I made it I was like, aha every time we do a thing like go to a convention or whatever I could post like a photo and then I kept meaning to do it and then not doing it.
Scott: But maybe now that I've said something maybe we'll do it.
Scott: We can post photos of GeekNights things there.
Rym: So, uh, otherwise, yeah, let's just get right into it with computer cooling because we've never really talked about this in depth.
Rym: We've always talked about like the side issues around it or we talked about servers.
Scott: This is one of those topics right where we feel like we did a show on it because we it comes up all the time And we talk about it all the time, but it never got its own show.
Scott: We did do a show on server room cooling which has nothing to do with this.
Rym: Yep, and we did that show in like 2013.
Rym: I want to say it was a long time ago.
Scott: So I'm gonna start way low cuz that's how we got to do in GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah Like the old how computers work series I did back in 2006 you got yourself a computer.
Scott: And how does the computer work?
Scott: is basically this chip which is basically a bunch of wires really tiny.
Rym: No, you're going that low.
Scott: Yeah, it's a basically a flat piece of silicon with electricity running through it like crazy.
Scott: Right now if you take a wire and just put it on a double-a battery, which is not a lot of electricity That wire gets so hot it burns you.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I mean the battery will get hotter than the wire.
Scott: I'm just saying it gets hot.
Scott: That's how electrons work, right?
Scott: They make metal hot.
Scott: what show?
Rym: the electron turns through stuff.
Rym: they get hot, right?
Scott: So when you have a big old power supply on your computer and you're shoving all those watts through this basically extremely thin flat piece of silicon Semiconductor it gets crazy hot right?
Scott: That's just how it does now.
Rym: Why not let it get hot now in the old days with like old crappy computers?
Scott: Sure, a lot of old computers would just be super hot Yeah, and it's like as long as it doesn't get so hot that it breaks.
Scott: Why not right?
Scott: I mean it makes your room warm.
Scott: But it's not really an issue unless it like melts the chip and it stops working Right.
Scott: as long as the computer keeps working It's fine any and computer chips can operate at pretty high temperatures actually like hot enough to burn you.
Scott: But the computer is just fine.
Rym: But in the old days like 486 like these early days of computing They're like the wires inside of all this stuff were actually pretty big and the things weren't doing that much work And they weren't using that much power.
Rym: Like I don't think you realize how slow a 286 is yeah compared to modern computing.
Scott: It's like my modern computer is like a thousands of Maybe even hundreds.
Scott: I made tens of I don't even know how many a lot Yeah, at least thousands anyway, so in the old days you pretty much just like a computer just worked.
Rym: You didn't really think about cooling.
Rym: you definitely never had to do anything about cooling Yeah, you didn't even build your own.
Scott: often often the computer would have you know, even Things that aren't actual like full PCs But just electronics will have heat sinks for any parts that heat up right and a heat sink is a really basic device.
Scott: It's a piece of metal shaped in an interesting way.
Scott: So basically all you're trying to do with a heat sink is increased surface area.
Scott: right you've got this chip that's flat and It gets hot and the heat comes out the top.
Scott: So if you put a piece of metal on top that conducts heat Right that piece of metal will heat up and then that piece of metal has wings or you know fins on it of some Kind or spikes or some something to increase the surface area.
Scott: It's all about surface area and That will just conduct the heat into the air more efficiently.
Scott: So it cools down faster.
Scott: You know like if you take a heat sink and you just put it on like your forehead like your forehead will feel cool because The heat coming out of your head is being conducted, right?
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: you know We make hats for people in the winter to stay warm.
Scott: that insulate We can make heat sink has to cool down in the summer and I just I guess it's not stylish.
Scott: Well, the reason would also be really heavy wearing metal on your head.
Rym: The main reason you need to increase all the surface area is because it turns out if you don't know this that air like the air You breathe it's actually a really good insulator.
Rym: Yeah, the only reason the air.
Scott: That's why winter coats are warm because they're all poofy and the air is insulating.
Scott: The only reason the layers keep you warm cuz every layer has area between.
Rym: Without a fan like with that heat sink is because the air actually moves around.
Rym: because the convection says the air gets hot It'll start cycling around and moving out of the way.
Rym: because there's a lot of reasons not getting into the physics.
Rym: But because air is not a good Conductor of heat you need to have the biggest surface area possible to spread that heat out exposed to as much air as possible.
Scott: So the heat sink was like the first step of cooling computers that they didn't break from all the heat They made right.
Rym: and then the old days you pretty much just had a heat sink on your CPU, right?
Scott: So the second step was we had to introduce fans right because the air just from convection alone wasn't moving around enough.
Scott: now You're like, well, wait a minute.
Scott: Why do I need a fan?
Scott: Can't I just like not put my computer in a box.
Scott: right if we didn't put our computers in boxes?
Scott: It's like yeah, you actually probably wouldn't need as much fans.
Scott: You could just make sure that like your room has good circulation or you've got an air conditioner on or something You know, but like you would need a lot less fan if you didn't put your computer in a box.
Rym: So air that's moved on its own by the heat action alone Doesn't move that much.
Scott: No, but when you've got a lot more air in the room, right?
Scott: It's not as much of a problem.
Scott: However, the thing is when you put your computer in a box, you know You're trapping that hot air in there to some extent even if you got holes and stuff, right?
Scott: So the reason we put the computer in a box, even though it causes a slight heat problem Is because you're gonna expose your expensive computer to someone stepping on it someone spilling something on it someone kicking it.
Rym: So forget all those practical concerns.
Rym: only two real reasons.
Scott: one boxes are cool.
Rym: electronics attract us.
Rym: So if electronics are exposed to the open air, they will be covered in dust.
Rym: Why do you think you need to dust your TV all the time?
Scott: Yeah, so that's why even though it's bad for heat.
Rym: We put the computer in a box But - if you just have all the components out in the air and you don't have some sort of active Directed movement of air over those heat sinks.
Rym: You're not actually gonna get that much cool.
Scott: It'll still be better than in the box.
Scott: Well, it's an improvement over in the box is what I'm saying.
Rym: Yeah, assuming you don't have any fans, but by putting it in the box you can direct air through.
Scott: You can direct air through it even without the box, right?
Rym: Yeah with unless you direct the air pretty like if you don't have channels or some way to really direct the air You're not gonna get that much better.
Rym: fans are pretty directed and the first of the big difference between old computers and new computers is that as Computers have gotten more complicated more parts of the computer generate a lot of heat that needs to be distributed.
Scott: Yes That's.
Rym: that's why motherboards today have a whole bunch of passive heat sinks and heat pipes all the fuck over them.
Scott: Yeah, so computers got faster and they got hotter and we figured well, we can't really make them faster without making them hotter very easily.
Scott: Let's just make them faster and solve the heat problem separately, right?
Scott: so fans.
Scott: So there's a lot of argument going on the internet like about how you should do fans, right?
Scott: Like what kind of fans you should get?
Scott: how many?
Scott: which direction do you aim them all this stuff?
Scott: So I'm gonna tell you what you should do.
Scott: number one You got to make the heat sure the heat sink on the CPU the hottest thing.
Scott: as a fan on it It's gonna come with one.
Rym: So right again now this really comes down to you can?
Rym: there are passive heat sinks for CPUs.
Rym: the drawbacks of these are one it better not be a super high-performing Chip or it's gonna slow itself down because it's gonna get too hot adding.
Scott: having that you got the increased surface area Thanks to this awesome heat sink.
Scott: If you start blowing the air onto it.
Scott: That's just like whoa super cooling right there.
Scott: It's so good, right?
Scott: If you want to see this in action, look at passive heat sinks on modern computers or go Go on YouTube find videos of like CPU fans taken with like thermal like infrared camera type things and it's like Oh, I see how the fan works.
Rym: Ooh, you can also see videos of like blowing smoke into computers to see how the smoke travels through all the fans but the passive heat sinks on modern CPUs are Enormous because they have to be enormous if there's no fan in it actively moving air through it.
Rym: Yep, because all the air moving through really does is expose it to more air of a lower average temperature, right?
Scott: You know think about this right?
Scott: Imagine you're in your room, right and it's summer.
Scott: It's hot summer.
Scott: It's so hot that I'm even sweating a little bit and I'm like mmm.
Scott: Maybe I will turn on the air conditioner.
Scott: Maybe right?
Scott: That's how hot.
Scott: it is crazy hot.
Scott: So Do you want a fan to be blowing on you or do you want a fan to be aimed blowing away from you?
Rym: All right, so that is actually a difficult question depending on a lot of very specific circumstances, but we're gonna skip all that.
Rym: Yeah, so in general you just want air to be moving over or through Whatever the surface is that you're using to distribute that heat.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So, you know you got you're the CPU.
Scott: your heatsink is your skins, right?
Scott: You just got to have air moving across.
Scott: Yep, right, you know if you'd aim your fan go out the window to try to get the hot air out of your room.
Scott: You know that means the cold the new fresh air is gonna be like sucked into your room through like all the not airtight parts of Your room right like underneath your front door and stuff.
Rym: Yep So you basically need a fan on the CPU directing air from the water area of your case Into and then out of that Heating.
Scott: so it's the same thing with a computer.
Scott: we think about the box.
Scott: Your computer is in your case as a room and the CPU is the person in the room Right in the outside is cold and the inside is hot.
Scott: You got to have some fans definitely the top fan aiming up blowing the hot air out.
Scott: cuz hot air rises Right, you got to get the hot air out of the box.
Scott: You also got to bring the cool air that's in the room outside the box into the box you have the in intake fans and Outtake fans because when you get that cool air from your room blowing right on to the CPU the CPU goes.
Scott: Now a lot of the same way you go.
Rym: Just have the power supply would have its own fan drawing air from inside the case And skicking out the back and we'll have matters.
Rym: usually didn't have any other case fans?
Scott: No, usually not.
Rym: if they did they maybe had an intake fan in the front someone.
Scott: I don't think my apple 2gs has any fans whatsoever.
Rym: My 486 had one intake fan on the front and the PSU was the exhaust fan on the back and it was roughly a static Pressure case.
Scott: I think the 486 only had PSU fans.
Scott: I don't think had any other fan.
Rym: I definitely had an intake fan.
Rym: cuz I would I would take it apart and dust the hell out of it Dog hair, right?
Scott: So that's the other problem, right?
Scott: We talked about dust before right?
Scott: But once you get these fans going on dust becomes a big issue.
Rym: now It's less dust than if you just have it out in the open But you're still taking air from the room and pushing it into a closed box.
Scott: So all the dust in your room gets sucked in by this fan.
Scott: So on all your fans that suck air in you need to put filters Right to keep the dust out and then you had to clean those filters once in a while.
Scott: and I can tell you I have filters On my computer on all my intake fans and my computer is so dust-free.
Scott: when I open it It looks like it looks almost new.
Rym: I have some old.
Rym: most people did not put filters on their computer intakes unless they were nerds who made custom computers Only recently have a lot of like in the last five or six years of most cases.
Scott: Yeah, all modern cases will come with filters.
Rym: But I've noticed pre-built computers pretty much never do and a lot of pre-built computers still use negative pressure.
Rym: So everything we're talking about what nerds will say is do you have a positive pressure case or a negative pressure case, right?
Scott: So positive pressure means that you got more air being sucked into the box.
Scott: then you have pushing out.
Scott: So your fans that spit air out are not pushing out as many Cubic feet per second of air as the fans that push air in.
Scott: so now the air pressure inside The box is higher than the air pressure outside the box Which means dust can't like, you know get sucked in through like the crevices in the side of the case Cuz.
Scott: air is getting, you know pushed out of those holes, right?
Scott: So nothing's gonna come in there now.
Rym: in my experience people used to argue and I've I've argued on both sides of this based on experience over the years if they're in the absence of any filters.
Rym: A lot of people argue that positive pressure still reduces internal dust as opposed to negative pressure.
Rym: Some people will argue the opposite and I have found over the course of my entire life that actually that is so highly situational.
Rym: That's very difficult to make a broad judgment, right?
Scott: Now really negative pressure would be.
Scott: you got so many so many fans in your computer spitting air out That the air just gets sucked in from the outside.
Scott: the pressure inside your computer is so low And now all this cool air is getting just like pulled into the computer on its own and you think oh both of those sound Kind of good, which one do I want?
Scott: and the answer is you want positive be only want a little bit positive, right?
Scott: You don't want to be like super positive Because that's that causes problems.
Scott: all the fans that are trying to suck air in and out fighting against each other Right, like if you had two fans both trying to pull air out.
Scott: It's like they're pulling against each other, right?
Scott: There's like, you know, the air sort of connects them like a rope, you know physics.
Scott: So, you know, you don't have too much positive or too much negative, but you want slightly positive so that you don't get dust You know pushing its way into the holes.
Rym: So let's talk practical.
Rym: the reality is in the older days You really had to think a lot about how you're gonna route your air and how you gonna where you gonna put all your stupid ribbon Gables and all this nonsense, but now you
Scott: buy a case that had like a whole bunch of fan holes and no fans Like.
Scott: well, do I put fans on all these holes and which direction do I point them?
Rym: And nowadays pretty much buy a modern computer case from one of the modern companies that sells to nerds and everything is already set up.
Rym: Yep The fans will all be pointing in the right direction and just do what the case says.
Scott: almost everything these days.
Scott: a standard mid tower case At least right.
Scott: if you buy not standard mid tower case, it's gonna be weird But a standard mid tower case right.
Rym: your PSU is gonna have an intake and an outtake fan on its own and your PSU is Gonna be in the back bottom of the case, which is the opposite of how computers used to be used to be in the top Back.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, and it's gonna just deal with itself.
Scott: No problem Right, the GPU is gonna have fans built into it that are appropriate to itself.
Scott: Just let it do its thing.
Rym: We'll talk a little bit about the three kinds of GPU fans.
Scott: Yeah, your CPU will have a Cooler that comes with it and if it doesn't buy a very standard one There's no reason to get one of those ginormous stupid ones unless You're overclocking which you shouldn't do well
Rym: or so the the high-end Normal i7 chip today the normal i7 the highest one does
Scott: no longer comes with the heatsink.
Rym: Yep So you have to buy an aftermarket heatsink.
Rym: That's correct and the chip will just perform better if you cool it more up to a certain point.
Rym: Bigger heatsink.
Scott: Yeah, that's not a matter of overclocking.
Scott: That's just how it is.
Rym: Well, arguably it's overclocking because it has the spec.
Scott: It's not about a semantic argument.
Scott: The point is you're not.
Scott: when I say overclocking I mean going be trying to push the chip beyond its spec, right?
Scott: It says it's gonna go this fast and you try to make it go even faster than advertised.
Scott: Right that auto scaling with temperature thing is advertised.
Scott: Therefore.
Rym: It's not overclocking what I'm running out right now Let's see.
Rym: So right now my 4 gigahertz CPU is running at.
Rym: that's my RAM Maximum speed 4 gigahertz current speed.
Rym: It's - clocked down to under a gigahertz cuz I ain't doing much right anyway.
Scott: So, you know get if it comes with a heatsink just use that.
Scott: if not get a real standard one.
Scott: Get like one with five stars a new egg But nothing ridiculous.
Scott: that like messes you up right.
Scott: and then your case if standard mid-tower case is what we're talking about here Is probably gonna have to intake fans in the front Outtake fan on the top and an exhaust fan on the top All right, and the
Rym: CPU
Scott: all right and an exhaust fan on the back aiming out Yep And that's gonna be even right for fans to in To out the CPU fan.
Scott: the GPU has its own fans and the PSU has own fan.
Scott: Now the PS now is enough to cool a modern computer well enough to function.
Rym: I've seen two common designs on the PSU though.
Rym: Some of them will put the PSU in.
Rym: So the PSU is itself static pressure meaning it doesn't affect the pressure right.
Scott: a lot of cases these days have it in like a Separate compartment where it doesn't affect the rest.
Rym: like my PSU sucks in from the bottom outside and out the back.
Scott: That's a good way.
Rym: It's its own loop, but other ones.
Scott: make sure the filter on the bond will act as an Exhaust fan.
Rym: so if this PSU is drawing air from the inside of the case it counts as an exhaust fan.
Rym: You got to take that into account.
Scott: Yeah, you know, but then you're pulling hot computer air into your PSU.
Scott: So make sure you got a real good PSU that can tolerate that hot air.
Rym: Yep Now in the old days used to worry about things especially though with like old and like the AMD chips You would want to worry about like the idea of impinging air flow.
Rym: So you could often make an old case cooler by having the top fan Coming in instead of going out because you'll have better heat exchange there and then have an exhaust fan in the bottom.
Rym: None of that nonsense matters anymore.
Rym: Just do what the cases do And buy a reputable case.
Scott: So another thing that's happened recently is back.
Scott: water cooling is not new.
Scott: I've been seeing water cooling since the 90s.
Rym: It used to be only for overclockers and nerds for whom the water cooling is itself And it was always a custom thing.
Scott: like you would buy hoses you would buy a pump, right?
Scott: You'd like, you know You would mod your case to attach the pump and get power to it.
Scott: You'd like fill it with like you get.
Scott: you wouldn't use water.
Scott: you do some like sort of cooling liquid and like you People would mess up and get their computers wet and shit, right?
Scott: But more recently this has become a thing that you can do very easily and perhaps even should.
Scott: right.
Scott: if you are building a Computer and you are building something that is top of the line like, you know an a-plus computer like you want horsepower You can buy these cool liquid coolers that come with the case and fit in it perfectly.
Scott: Require, no difficult setup like the liquids already in there, right?
Scott: The hoses are already attached.
Scott: You don't got to worry about anything.
Scott: This is basically a radiator and a heatsink part and you just put the radiator in the case where it belongs.
Rym: It just fits in there perfectly and then and the manufacturer will tell you based on the case what direction the fan should point.
Scott: Everything is just automatic.
Scott: and then you take instead of putting a heatsink on your CPU You just take the thing on the other end of the hoses and put that on your CPU.
Scott: and there you go.
Scott: You've got this now radiator thing which it comes with fans.
Rym: It's just like all pre-packaged totally easy and the fact that it's liquid cooling doesn't really matter because all this is The.
Rym: it's not a heat pipe But it's doing the same kind of thing.
Rym: All it's doing is taking the heat from the CPU and instead of having the heatsink be right there It's sending it to a heatsink that's far away.
Scott: a big heatsink on the front of the case.
Scott: Yeah, we're too big-ass fans on it.
Rym: A little heatsink on your CPU CPUs heatsink right at the edge of the case instead of like in the middle of all.
Rym: your not.
Scott: And you got these intake fans pulling the cold air from outside the case right onto that heatsink and that's like Crazy cool in that CP.
Rym: now ideally if you really wanted to make this like super optimal the right way to do that would be to have the heatsink with You know be entirely outside of the case just in its own loop.
Rym: The only reason we don't do that is silly is because that's a pain in the ass for a lot of reasons.
Scott: So basically if you want to go crazy, you can you know have like a refrigerator where the compressor Send the liquid out into a compressor and like cool it off, right?
Rym: So but the generally the way these things work.
Rym: if you do unless you're doing something crazy You only need one of these and you're really only needed for the CPU.
Rym: Yeah, because it'll draw air cold air from your room into the case warming it up by cooling the CPU But then that air in the case will be blown out through your normal cooling loop with the fans.
Scott: The best part about this right is something we didn't talk about yet.
Scott: Is that it's way quiet, right?
Scott: It's like you're already gonna have.
Scott: if you have a fan on your CPU That's probably gonna be among your loudest fans except for maybe your GPU fan Which we'll get to.
Scott: and if you're basically use liquid cooling you eliminate that sound a hundred percent, right?
Scott: Even if you get the quietest fan in the world, it's not as quiet as no fan.
Scott: So fan.
Scott: you're gonna have those two intake fans on the front.
Scott: Anyway, whether you got using liquid or not So you just eliminated a whole fan.
Scott: you were saving so much noise.
Rym: the only other where the fans on the heatsink With the liquid cooling because they're not right next to CPU can be way bigger.
Rym: and the two things that influence how loud a fan Are the faster it is louder it is.
Rym: Mm-hmm the bigger it is the quieter It is because it can move slower.
Rym: and by moving slower because as bigger fins move the same amount of air.
Scott: Fans are measured in like cubic feet per second Like how much how much feet cubic feet of air can the fan push?
Scott: you've got a bigger fan.
Scott: It spins.
Scott: one time it pushes more air than a little fan spinning like 10. so it can be quiet, right?
Scott: So spinning faster is louder.
Scott: bigger fans spin less make less noise.
Scott: also Fancy or more expensive fan up with better bearings are quieter.
Rym: So there's a reason you buy the $40 fans for your.
Scott: if you really the $12 if you really care about quietness You just spend a lot of money and get the highest rated fancy fans like the Noctua's or whatever they are.
Scott: Yeah, and those are.
Scott: I think I put two of those in my htbc because that's a computer.
Scott: you want to be quiet And it already had sort of like sad cooling because in a weird htbc case.
Scott: So I wanted to make sure I had really good the best cooling I could get considering limitations.
Scott: Yep, so I put two of the fancy Noctua fans in there and like I never hear them ever now It's very important.
Scott: I think they cost me like 20 or 30 bucks.
Rym: talk about that.
Rym: They were not.
Scott: they were not the cheapest fans.
Scott: $5 fans like.
Rym: there are two very different use cases there for the htbc use case.
Rym: one is plays games Generates heat because it's fast and has a video card use case.
Rym: two is You're not playing games on it.
Rym: If you're not playing games on it.
Rym: Don't need a video card.
Rym: It doesn't need to be super fast.
Rym: You can go with a completely passive solution.
Rym: That'll be literally silence.
Rym: Yeah, I mean look like an app but inside your tiny case you love this giant ass block of aluminum crap.
Rym: Just stick it out of your CPU.
Rym: What do you care, but it won't make any noise?
Rym: So there are still reasons to have passive cooling in modern computers.
Rym: It really depends on how much heat you're generating.
Rym: more heat is generated by either having video cards or having fast chips doing stuff All right, so we talked about GPU fans a little bit.
Scott: But you know when you go to buy a GPU You're gonna see different kinds of fans on them.
Scott: a lot of them these days.
Scott: the high-end ones will have like three fans on there.
Scott: Well, some of them will have two fans and some of them will have like this weird blowy fan That's totally sideways and different.
Rym: So the weird blowy fan or the turbine or whatever.
Rym: Mm-hmm You pretty much don't want that.
Rym: Usually those will be called like the founders edition or the reference edition?
Scott: Well, no that has nothing to do with the fan.
Rym: Usually though so the reference editions always have that weird turbine fan.
Scott: The reference edition is just means that like we're gonna charge you more for this and like this is the original Nvidia design Something.
Rym: but as best I can tell the only reason they have that weird turbine fan is Because of a convention where the reference editions always have that.
Rym: I think it's like three articles about this.
Scott: I've never seen any connection between the fan style and the found.
Rym: every reference edition has the turbine.
Rym: Anyway, so and the reason for that is nonsense The turbine fans are one just louder and two.
Rym: they count as an exhaust fan.
Rym: They pull air in from your case.
Rym: Just like that PSU.
Rym: I was talking about and blow it out the back, right?
Rym: And they suck.
Scott: I actually intentionally got the turbine fan on the 1070 in my HTPC.
Scott: Cuz the HTPC is way narrow and there's no if I got the regular.
Scott: Oh, yeah Cuz the right, okay I got the regular two or three fans where the hell they blowing just down.
Scott: Cuz it's a. it's a weird case where the video card is like sideways And those fans be blowing at the ground and then the hot air would rise right back into them.
Scott: Yep And so I got the blowy fan to make sure it blows out the back.
Rym: now the regular fan the ones you're thinking of where There's like two or three big like case looking fans on it that those are a lot quieter Usually.
Scott: yeah, you got three fans on there.
Rym: They don't need to spin very fast But they work a lot like an old CPU cooler did in that they're just blowing air inside your case to cool it down.
Rym: So you gotta make sure the case is still getting the hot air out of the.
Scott: yeah usually you're gonna have you know cool air coming right across the bottom of the case in the front and out the back and That's gonna go right past that GPU and take that hot air that those plans blow right out the back.
Rym: So I would generally recommend Get the fan that had the the GPU that has two or three normal looking fans on it and not the turbine unless you have A good reason to.
Rym: the third way to go is passive which is just for like.
Rym: like.
Rym: if you're doing passive cooling Why do you even have a video card?
Scott: You can probably get away with using your like Intel like a core whatever You know you can get like you know like 1050s and stuff or like you know weaker video cards that can still do stuff that some of them only have like one fan.
Scott: You know this you'd be surprised.
Scott: like the kind of video card you can get that's got one fan or no fans.
Scott: It is pretty significantly powerful faster even than the integrated graphics.
Rym: But the other kind is.
Rym: you do the same thing just like we talked about with liquid cooling the CPU Where there's no fans on the GPU and instead it again Just has a two pipes or two tubes and a separate fin thing to be the heat sink.
Scott: So sometimes you can buy a video card that already has this yep Or you can buy a video card and somehow take the fans off and attach one of these which is doable.
Rym: But as I wouldn't recommend that right in general You don't need to liquid cool your GPU if you only have one GPU.
Rym: my My straight-up recommendation if you have a fast computer liquid cool the CPU And then the only things generating heat in the case directly are the GPU and all those heat sinks All of your motherboard for all those chips and your RAM.
Scott: Let's think about once you you know every when you cool that CPU with the liquid cooling you're helping out the GPU, right?
Scott: There's less heat in the case now, right?
Scott: You're just helping everybody, right?
Scott: So it's like oh the GPU.
Scott: you might have been struggling if the CPU is poorly cooled.
Scott: heating up this case.
Rym: Yes, the G is pumping hot air directly into your video card.
Scott: But now I brought I brought down the case temperature with my superior cooling in another area.
Scott: So now the cooling of the GPU is now doing even better.
Rym: It's everyone works together now Irrespective of whether or not SLI and multiple video cards is a good idea.
Rym: if you're doing that.
Rym: that is the use case for the liquid cooled GPU.
Scott: Yeah, and for no other reason.
Scott: when you put two video cards next to each other You want two video cards pumping air through each other?
Scott: One of them is gonna be blowing its hot air onto the back of the other one.
Scott: Yeah, right You want a liquid cool the one that would be blowing on its friend and let the friend blow on the bottom of the case Or whatever.
Scott: right and then that way you protect the bottom card from the card that's next to it now.
Scott: That being said I have seen setups at like conventions and packs or whatever where like Ati's got like a booth or something and they got like four GPUs in the same box and they all had fans and they all Work just fine.
Scott: It could totally work.
Scott: Yeah, it's just probably, you know, not for the best.
Rym: So the other cooling that you might hear occasionally a lot of people don't really understand.
Rym: with these hours.
Rym: You'll see you'll hear about my heat pipe or you'll see like pipes all over your motherboard Which wasn't a thing a long time ago.
Rym: It's happening more and more.
Rym: the problem is the chips that do stuff like it, you know in the old days.
Rym: Yeah, it's actually it's gotten so much more complicated than that, but it also doesn't matter like it's a chipset now.
Rym: It used to worry about that a lot because like certain North bridges wouldn't be compatible with certain things But nowadays none of that matters.
Rym: you don't worry about it.
Scott: Well, you do have to choose the right chipset, but you don't care which chips are in the set.
Scott: All you got to know is that oh, I got the Z 270.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, I got an Intel H whatever it is.
Scott: I know I know what chipset I have.
Scott: That's all you got to know.
Scott: You don't got to know what chips are in the chipset.
Rym: But all those different parts of the motherboard and the RAM Actually generate a lot of heat these days because a lot's going on in there.
Scott: They don't generate so much heat that they need a fan of their own.
Rym: But they need heat sink.
Scott: the motherboards thin at the mother But the motherboard includes those right.
Scott: they're gonna just have heat sinks on them.
Scott: Yeah already built into the motherboard You don't even think about it It's just there.
Rym: but if you see all those pipes all those are doing is they're doing what the liquid cool Would do but they're passive.
Rym: instead of having a pump Literally pumping liquid through the heat sink, you know Through all these channels inside of it and through all these channels on the puck on top of the CPU They're passive.
Rym: They basically will have a liquid evaporating and moving to one end of the pipe and it'll transfer the heat from the hot side to the cold side right.
Scott: you got a Whole bunch of chips in a set and some of those chips are gonna be hotter than others depending on what's going on with The computer.
Scott: and so it's like oh you got this heat sink on this one chip But it's not doing much because that chips not hot But meanwhile this other chip is crazy hot right now and it's heat sink is like, you know It's adding it's gonna be adequate But why not link it together with these other heat sinks and that way they can all sort of share the load.
Scott: It also means long as they don't all get crazy hot at once Each one of them is now being cooled better than it otherwise would be and now your computer lasts longer.
Rym: It's also important because you'll often have an area of the motherboard that's further away from stuff.
Rym: We have more room to put a big heat sink But the area that's actually hot.
Rym: you can't put a bunch of heat sinks and crap there because proximity matters.
Rym: computers are so performant These days that the distance between components actually does matter.
Rym: That's why they design them the way they do You know pump all that heat from the hot area to a further away less valuable real estate on the motherboard And that's you can have the heat sink some fancy motherboards.
Rym: So because basically if you're doing a super high performance computer and you've got the you know The second GPU with liquid cooling and the CPU with liquid cooling at that point You're better off having both of those use the same cooling loop and that's when the complicated crap happens.
Scott: Yeah that you had to do effort to make that happen.
Scott: That's not something you can just buy easily because if
Rym: you're going that road some motherboards will actually have on the motherboard two little headers And you plug those into your cooling loop and the same thing that's cool in the CPU in the GPU Will also cool all the things on the motherboard.
Rym: There's channels built into the motherboard.
Rym: That is crazy nonsense.
Rym: You probably don't need anything like that.
Scott: It's like there's all this stuff and you think do I need that?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no that's just for people who like make this their hobby.
Scott: It's not for normal people.
Rym: Yep, but don't be afraid of liquid cooling.
Rym: I highly recommend if you have a modern fast computer and You're the CPU you buy doesn't come with a heatsink.
Rym: buy the liquid cooling one.
Scott: If you can't make sure you get a case and the cooling thing that go together Yeah All the same manufacturer from the same company.
Scott: if you try to buy like one liquid coolie thing and put it in a different case You're gonna have a bad time, right?
Scott: Yeah, these things are not.
Scott: there's not like a standard for these so much as there is for other things.
Scott: So you want to make sure you get a nice, you know a set pair and everything will go very easily for you.
Rym: And otherwise, I mean as long as you buy a nice case Cables got small you don't have to worry about ribbon cables like literally Redirecting air and causing hot spots.
Scott: modern cases like show you where you're supposed to route the cables.
Scott: But even if you just do a big mess, it's not they're not.
Scott: I guess it's not a big ribbon cable.
Scott: It's not blocking anything.
Scott: It's really not going to affect your airflow that much Yep, and nowadays all the PS use I have like they let you they're modular.
Scott: Yeah, they let you.
Rym: Don't plug them in.
Scott: you don't have a big mess of cables in there hurting you.
Rym: Actually cut a bunch of cables off of a PSU a long time ago And I sort of like wrapped him up and got him out of the way.
Rym: and I used to cut ribbon cables for my hard Drives, you know take a razor and cut along all the lines and they could bundle them.
Scott: So they'd be out of the way Yeah, but weren't they flat for a reason?
Rym: Yeah, they were it was it was they did.
Rym: Sometimes it worked sometimes it did.
Scott: there were definitely some ribbon cables that I got I remember like towards the latter days of IDE.
Scott: I would buy you buy a hard drive to come with a ribbon cable that was already bundled like yeah, and I'm like, alright Whatever it worked and in terms of hard drives and everything like they do generate heat.
Scott: They usually every everything generates heat but like SSDs even magnetic drives They don't need to be cooled, right?
Rym: Well modern cases will place them in in in areas where they will get enough cooling As long as you do what the case said to do.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: you don't have to put fans on them or anything.
Scott: It's like, you know back in the day that used to be.
Scott: I think I actually did have at one point This super long ago.
Scott: This is the Pentium three, right?
Scott: No had which at the time was crazy a sea gate 7200 rpm drive.
Scott: Oh Right, so that was so many rpms then oh my god, I think it was four gigabytes this drive.
Scott: it was insane And you know that was.
Scott: that was too fast.
Scott: this needed its own cooling right.
Scott: you couldn't just put this drive in with the other Drive, this is gonna be like set on fire.
Scott: I wanted this drive to last a long time.
Scott: It was expensive and high quality.
Scott: So, you know top of the line magnetic hard drive here.
Scott: So I bought a thing that was a giant heatsink.
Scott: You put the hard drive in there and had fans two little fans on the front and then you put the hard drive into a five And a quarter slot instead of a three and a half slot and now that hard drive is gonna be so cool.
Rym: Most cases will just have the hard drives in a place where the intake fans Like that air will just kind of wash over room and that'll be enough.
Scott: Yeah, but I Probably didn't need that thing back in the day, but I had it.
Rym: Yeah well also back then like cases sucked and there were a lot of hot spots and like that was a that's still a big.
Scott: I Don't think I needed to put my three and a half inch hard drive in the five and a quarter slot with its own Enormous heatsink with its own two tiny fans.
Rym: It's hard to say like I'd like.
Scott: we know a lot.
Scott: I couldn't say I could have saved that money when I was younger.
Scott: maybe used it on something better like food.
Rym: So, uh, it's actually like.
Rym: it's interesting how it got more complicated But at the same time like just in the last four or five years, I'd say in terms of actually building computers It's way easier.
Rym: I think the worst time was about six to ten years ago Where you started to have advanced cooling needs, but there weren't a lot of good off-the-shelf Solutions.
Scott: the need the needs and the problem are more difficult than ever.
Scott: There's more heat than ever but the products you can buy just solve the problem for you.
Scott: Yeah, and you don't need to think about it or work hard at it You didn't.
Rym: you know like you used to is you only need to work hard if you're already doing weird stuff and you're already Edging into set like hobbyist nonsense, right?
Scott: If you're not a hobbyist like the off-the-shelf stuff just by the default and it's gonna work great and it's totally awesome.
Rym: but seriously Positive pressure and have intake filters if your computer doesn't.
Rym: not too positive.
Scott: Oh just slightly positive.
Rym: if your computer does not have intake filters You should dust the hell out of your computer with an air And get filters on there.
Scott: and if you don't have filters You can just stretch some pantyhose over the front of those intake fan.
Rym: Yeah, that works.
Scott: It works crazy.
Scott: Well, and it's so cheap.
Rym: Yeah, it's like nothing like that changed my life.
Rym: I did that to my computer two times ago, and then I never had to dust it again.
Rym: It was just amazing.
Rym: Yeah, just every month.
Rym: I would literally I didn't even clean the pantyhose.
Rym: I would just replace it.
Scott: I mean, yeah, I have filters.
Scott: the filters on my computers are Magnated on so are mine.
Scott: They're just like this you turn your computer off you peel them off you go outside You shake them and yep, I just whack them on the balcony all the dust falls off.
Scott: You can also take a can of compressed air and spray them and then just slap them back on there.
Scott: done Do it like once every few months.
Rym: Yep, and in terms of just you know, I'll mention it.
Rym: laptops They cool themselves.
Scott: don't mess with the laptop cooling.
Scott: Yeah, but if you see a laptop is blowing a lot and is making a lot of noise.
Scott: I don't buy that laptop.
Scott: That's a crappy one.
Scott: That's bad cooling design.
Rym: Well, I mean it like.
Rym: so might like.
Rym: I have a Lenovo x230 which is still a great laptop like even today like it'll place.
Rym: If six, okay, which is still kind of amazing me that'll totally pull that off.
Rym: but if I start playing Civ six and that's this fan that usually isn't spinning and suddenly it spins.
Rym: you hear this like An air hot enough to be uncomfortable is coming out of the side of this tiny laptop.
Scott: Mm-hmm That's not good.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean it's gonna die.
Rym: I think it'll be fine.
Scott: It's good day.
Rym: It's uh, it'll be fine It's gonna die.
Rym: that laptop is so old.
Rym: Like I'm shocked.
Rym: It still works.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duschett.
Rym: great job emoji my state e.com William I suppose Jeremy minor smash the world shell for the revolution of the world.
Rym: zankoku not ten.
Rym: She know yoni Shona?
Rym: no, she Shinwani nare the terrible secret of space.
Rym: four to one.
Rym: creations, you know with the plan for us and stuff I don't know man, but Sherwin von Horrell rarely.
Rym: Val James David Wright Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make room safe food bar.
Rym: Sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Shleich judge office in Georgia, Georgia, sir Tyler Eller Shawn Yeager Sam Carter Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan Perrin.
Rym: That's why you're the judge and I'm the law-talking guy.
Rym: Brian Sidroni the space-time vector of an african-european swallow carrying kiwis redacted.
Rym: Chris midkiff Chris Knox and go Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn and I leave you with this welcome to cautionary tales of swords.
Scott: I'm trip Fisk, you know swords are dangerous.
Scott: They'll cut your fucking throat wide open.
Scott: That's what this show is all about Warning people about the dangers of owning swords.
Rym: First story is about a dad who really fucked up.
Scott: It's called honey.
Scott: I killed our son.