Rym: It's Tuesday March 28th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: That's good, and this is GeekNights tonight America a party game where close counts involving Friedman Freese.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So you know After several Nintendo things ago I agreed and I said very openly on GeekNights that Nintendo had moved at least for now from a buy site Unseen company to a wait and see company.
Rym: So when the switch was announced and we could pre-order it.
Rym: I Chose not to pre-order it.
Rym: to wait and see I saw.
Scott: well, this is all the game in my life I have played and beaten every single player Zelda game except Majora's Mask, do you?
Rym: I guess you're not counting the CDI games either.
Scott: No, but I'm counting all the real made developed by Nintendo even Capcom Single-player official mainline Zelda game.
Scott: so the ones on the GV the GV the GVA the DS but not CDI or NES SNES N64 no game of cube We and and now the Wii U one is the same as the the switch one.
Scott: So switch one.
Rym: But I true my word I waited and saw and everyone else is playing Zelda cooking food Taving horses and no other games and having a real good time.
Scott: Actually, you should buy the snippy clip game so I don't have to buy it.
Rym: Uh, yeah I almost want to get one to switch because I feel like it would get brought out of parties.
Rym: But I've seen real mixed reviews.
Scott: I watched Gabe and Tyco play one to switch and I said wow, that would be fun for like 10 minutes.
Scott: It's not worth 50 fucking dollars.
Rym: You know what it would be fun for 10 minutes or 10 dollars But not 50 minutes or 50 dollars.
Rym: Nope So I feel like it would have the same scenario that the Wario were on the We had.
Scott: I will however, there is a blaster master game out for it and that blaster master game I heard is co-op.
Scott: So yeah, we should do that.
Rym: I'd be into that.
Rym: I've been buying my games on Amazon.
Scott: We could like what we could like stream it for like an hour after each podcast or whatever.
Rym: That's actually a pretty good idea.
Scott: I'll bring my pro con.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, so of course I realized that.
Rym: yeah What have I done?
Rym: I've made a terrible mistake.
Rym: And of course the Wii U was the Wii U. the switch was sold out everywhere.
Rym: So I had one on release day because I just waited a little while and then it was back in stock on Amazon And I just bought it with next day delivery and was immediately playing Zelda.
Scott: There's no reason to wait in line or go anywhere Right, and we're not shilling for Amazon.
Scott: Amazon doesn't pay us anything Except for the affiliate program, which anyone can do.
Scott: it's not like.
Scott: they came to us with that.
Scott: I went to you know, I just signed up.
Scott: It's just the thing And we make like no money on that.
Rym: Anyway, well partly cuz.
Rym: yeah, I don't have like.
Rym: I Haven't made links whenever I linked to this stuff.
Rym: Like I don't make the link.
Scott: Yeah, we get like if you buy the book club book from the link on our website We get like what 50 cents.
Rym: so it sold out again.
Scott: That's a shame.
Rym: But of course I just have it and a lot of people were complaining to me when I said hey It's just on sale and I just bought it.
Rym: They were like bullshit.
Rym: No, it isn't.
Rym: It only showed up as in stock to people who have Amazon Prime.
Scott: take that.
Rym: Yeah, that's what happens.
Scott: That's what happened.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, it's pretty great and I've only beaten like nine shrines The world of that game super dangerous.
Rym: I really like the way that cooking is portrayed.
Scott: Where do you see a line now?
Rym: I already I've run into a lot of situations.
Rym: I'm like that looks like some kind of moblin.
Rym: ask dude I can probably take it.
Rym: Whoa one hit insta-death.
Scott: Yeah that whoa Anything that looks like a moblin or a lizard I can take anything.
Scott: But no, I can actually if you encountered any things with lasers coming out of there.
Rym: Yeah, I encountered a few of those.
Scott: Yeah, I actually beat a few of those most my most recent play.
Scott: I smashed some of those Yep, with with great care though.
Scott: I had to be.
Scott: it wasn't like I was so strong that I could just take them Right.
Scott: It's like I had to be tricky.
Rym: I beat a camp cuz.
Rym: I'm pretty weak-ass in the game.
Rym: Like the enhanced lizard spear is a pretty fucking great weapon.
Scott: Yeah, that's basically a stick with a nail in it.
Rym: But uh, I saw a bunch of dudes who are war would could one shot me with that and they were down like on a beach.
Rym: So I stood up on a hill and spent five minutes just rolling bombs down at him till I eventually killed.
Rym: everybody Picked up all their sweet-ass weapons.
Rym: Mmm I also encountered apparently Team Rocket exists those ninja type dudes.
Scott: Yeah, I still know what their deal is.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what their deal is, but I'm pretty sure wherever they live is where the bananas are.
Scott: Yeah, I want to find them and kill them.
Scott: Yeah, cuz those guys all bombs down the hill at their village.
Rym: Yeah that village if I find once I find out where you live you guys are done.
Rym: But yeah, this game's real good.
Rym: You should get a switch and play this game.
Rym: If you don't have it isn't a $400 game Yeah, but I there's gonna be a few other games on the switch.
Rym: and Also, the switch is a pretty good console so far.
Rym: So no review yet, but I bought a switch and Scott bought a switch.
Rym: This is the first time Ever that Scott and I both owned a non portable console You know because we lived in the same place.
Scott: We just get one.
Scott: we didn't need to reason to game of cubes Yeah, but it was always me buying those wheeze in a game again.
Scott: It was it was Yeah Cuz.
Scott: I remember back when you should buy me a computer.
Rym: back when the n64 came out.
Rym: I remember thinking to myself This is kind of a bullshit console And I'm just gonna throw myself a hundred percent into PC gaming for the rest of my life.
Rym: And I didn't resume buying Nintendo stuff until the DS.
Rym: No, GBA GBA DS.
Rym: Those are the two things but no mainline console.
Rym: now until the switch.
Rym: I By the time we split our domiciles, I no longer needed a GameCube Because the GameCube at this point exists solely to play Rampart which we could do on MAME if we really want to I guess or WarioWare.
Scott: there's a lot of games to play in Game of Cube f-zero.
Rym: Oh, yeah that f-zero That is lit.
Rym: That is the best f-zero has ever been.
Scott: I have many GameCube games In my little binder that are not available on any other thing easily.
Rym: Yeah, if I had a rank NES consoles or NES Nintendo consoles, I think it would be SNES NES GameCube switch.
Scott: Yeah, the real Smash Brothers.
Rym: Yeah So I'm one yani gaming news.
Scott: Yeah, so this big deal going on.
Scott: is the Starcraft Remastered?
Scott: right?
Scott: so Blizzard has been doing this trying to milk their old games for money for which we've we said in a panel And we did a PAX prime and like why you no do this 2010?
Rym: Literally they should do this.
Rym: We like basically everything we've said people should do in that panel.
Rym: as of this like 90% of that panel has come to pass.
Scott: So on the one hand it seems good and the other hand it seems a bad, right?
Scott: So in the good part is like hey old Starcraft is gonna be zero fucking dollars.
Scott: They were charging money for real Starcraft up until now and now they're gonna give you real Starcraft for nothing.
Scott: Not bad, which is good for anyone who doesn't already have real Starcraft, but I fucking paid money for real Starcraft.
Scott: at some point I forget yeah, god damn it.
Scott: You assholes.
Scott: I could have waited.
Scott: I didn't need to pay for that Even though I suck at.
Scott: RTS is big time.
Scott: I actually really like single-player Starcraft.
Scott: Starcraft 2 yeah, and the plot and such.
Scott: it's like Starcraft 2.
Scott: I played on like mega easy mode Went through the campaigns which are fun and saw the plots and things.
Scott: I think it might be one expansion still I didn't do.
Scott: I might do that at some point Probably post Zelda world because it usually only takes like a day or two to do the whole campaign or whatever right?
Scott: But it's worth it.
Scott: But anyway, so here's what they're doing.
Scott: old Starcraft is free.
Scott: They're gonna patch old Starcraft for free.
Scott: You don't have to put in this patch if you don't want to because if you're some Starcraft purist.
Scott: but what all the patch does is basically Allow you to connect to people using the new Starcraft.
Scott: That's how compatible the new one is gonna be.
Scott: Right?
Scott: it doesn't change the mechanics in any way Right?
Scott: they're just allowing you to play on the internet against people using the new Starcraft.
Scott: the new Starcraft is really the exact same goddamn Game just looking fancy so you can you play the old one for free or the new look fancy.
Scott: looking one for not freeze The new rush 20 guys right?
Scott: so the new.
Scott: imagine if like you could play counter-strike against someone But you were using like modern textures.
Scott: the other person had blocky old CS 1.0 people And you could just play against each other because it's still the same game.
Scott: This is like.
Scott: it's annoying though because does that mean you're not gonna get like the user interface improvements of Starcraft 2 To go along with the graphical improvements.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I really wish you could get those graphic user interface improvements.
Scott: the other question is if you're playing online Serious competition is it unfair that you have those user interface improvements, and it's different?
Scott: You know?
Scott: is that really?
Scott: are they gonna disable those and you play it competitively so that even though you have fancy graphics You're still limited to like the way you had to control Starcraft?
Rym: You could you have the same questions about doom like all that There's like controlling the stupid worker.
Scott: guys in Starcraft 1 sucks way more than in Starcraft 2.
Scott: Yeah, they come out of the base and just automatically start working, and you don't like keep clicking on right.
Scott: You know I hope that.
Scott: are they gonna change that kind of stuff.
Scott: It doesn't seem like they are.
Rym: well I feel like if they did the kinds of people who still care about the original Starcraft Probably actually care about the clicking.
Scott: they care about that a lot.
Scott: Yeah, that's why it's important anyway And also for you know for competition to be fair.
Scott: even though I prefer not the clicking be I prefer the new way better As someone who sucks.
Scott: obviously for it to be a fair competition You can't have different control schemes for different people.
Scott: It's got to be the same for everybody right whether it's new way or old way It's got to be the same forever.
Rym: Yep, listen seems to be pretty good in general about being ultra customizable for the people who care about that kind of.
Scott: Yes, so the new one is gonna be non free But I might buy it anyway because I actually never completely beat Starcraft 1 single-player.
Scott: I only got most of the way through the Zerg.
Rym: I definitely did not beat Starcraft 1 single-player ever.
Scott: I beat the tech I was playing on easy mode.
Scott: right cuz I suck.
Scott: But yeah, I played Terran and then I played most of Zerg and not any protoss parts.
Scott: so But the new one is gonna remaster like the story parts, so it'd probably be more enjoyable to see what's going on there.
Scott: but also It's gonna give you like 4k resolution Widescreen aspect ratio because remember the original one is designed for 4.3 right and all new graphics.
Scott: So it should be way nicer to look at and easier to see what the hell's going on.
Scott: Maybe they'll even like redo voices or something.
Rym: Yeah, because I know that problem.
Rym: what if you never used to replaying doom with the like upper-res?
Rym: You know ports of doom over the years.
Rym: So if you play an old doom like it took me a minute to see anything in that muddy mess.
Scott: Yeah, so if you never played any Starcraft ever Right and you it's something you should play you can either a get the old one for free and play it and learn about Starcraft B. if you got money and you want a better experience pay for the newer one and See if you're a competitive Starcraft player.
Scott: You probably don't give a shit about what someone who plays on easy has to say.
Scott: So whatever but You know, it's a good end of bad, right?
Scott: I'm salty that I paid for Starcraft where if I had just waited until now it could have got it for free.
Scott: But on the other hand, maybe I'll go back and do some more Starcraft and just like finish all the single-player parts Completely after I'm done with all these other games.
Rym: So as you guys know, I play a lot of overwatch.
Rym: It's kind of my main game.
Rym: In fact, it only got sidetracked recently because of Zelda.
Rym: But I kind of got this urge just out of nowhere.
Rym: My body was like, you know, you haven't done in a while You haven't played Counter-Strike in a while and Scott and I were talking today that yeah, like even though we don't really play Counter-Strike anymore I haven't played Counter-Strike in long.
Rym: We probably played more Counter-Strike over the course of our lives than many other games We have ever played.
Rym: quite possibly we played a lot of Counter-Strike for many years before we.
Scott: yeah It's like you just play a little Counter-Strike a little Counter-Strike over the years and years and years little.
Rym: I would play like four Hours a day in RIT.
Scott: There were peak times.
Scott: we played shit tons of Counter-Strike.
Scott: But you know, I've been playing Counter-Strike You know on and off and on and off and on and off sometimes intensely every single day Sometimes not at all for years, but since beta 7?
Rym: We played before the p90 existed.
Scott: No, the p90 was there.
Rym: They edited it In the year 2000.
Scott: the p90 was there the first time I installed Counter-Strike.
Scott: But I was playing Counter-Strike at a time where I had to download it separately and mod Half-Life 1 to play it.
Rym: Yeah, we only got Steam and there was no Steam.
Scott: Steam did not exist.
Scott: There was only WAN.
Rym: When Steam existed it existed solely to give updates to Counter-Strike.
Scott: WAN is the World Opponent Network and that is what there was before.
Scott: there was Steam anyway.
Scott: It's an ancient history.
Rym: So I go and I start playing.
Rym: and the first thing I notice because I just jump into a random game like, you know Easy, whatever.
Scott: You're playing Counter-Strike Source or Counter-Strike Global Offensive?
Rym: Go Global Offensive.
Rym: I'm not playing the old shit.
Rym: Plus.
Rym: Source is the worst.
Rym: If you're gonna play if you want to play old Counter-Strike You wanna play original Counter-Strike or go?
Scott: No Source?
Rym: Yeah, Source is like the middle child that no one wants.
Scott: Is there anyone who plays Source?
Scott: Or is it like a dead game?
Rym: Last I checked it was still surprisingly high in the list of games People are playing on Steam.
Scott: But is it the least loved Counter-Strike or more people playing Source than 1.0?
Rym: It was the least loved Years ago when I checked I do not know offhand right now I also heard like people still play Left 4 Dead.
Scott: I wonder how popular that is compared to old Counter-Strike.
Rym: Wow, I can't imagine what it would be like.
Scott: Because it can't be more popular than CSGO.
Scott: So it has to be.
Scott: but is it more popular than old Counter-Strike?
Rym: I can't imagine like what it would be like to interact with the people who are still playing Left 4 Dead in Left 4 Dead Like.
Rym: are they just perfect at the game?
Rym: Like what what could?
Rym: Anyway, so Already, I've played so much Overwatch and I haven't really played any FPS's but Overwatch that when I start playing Counter-Strike Stuff felt weird in this very specific way.
Scott: You mean it felt like oh right the overwatch is wrong.
Scott: Yeah, this is what right feels like.
Rym: The guns, so the guns Felt really tiny and my hand on the mouse felt like I was.
Rym: it felt like I was using up I don't know a spoon to try to do open-heart surgery Like everything just felt really tiny and fiddly and actually looked and started comparing screenshots.
Rym: Everything Overwatch is enormous Yeah and the gun on your screen Takes up a huge amount of screen.
Rym: real estate actually and the things that happen are huge.
Rym: and in Counter-Strike It's this tiny little gun and it goes puh-puh-puh-puh-puh.
Rym: Yep, so What's weird is that I kind of in some ways was better at Counter-Strike that I've been in a long time Really?
Scott: You think it was the opposite, right?
Scott: Yeah, but after you go around clubbing people It's kind of hard to do some, you know pointy knife fight, but at the same time Some of my like old Hesitancy and carefulness.
Rym: I was a lot more reckless which meant it sounds like me two-thirds of the time and in a disaster Yeah, at the M5 But one-third of the time me and a p90 took out the entire enemy team.
Rym: So just by running in gah.
Rym: But the other thing was that the game sounded way Way different.
Rym: So I but I wasn't using headphones.
Rym: I said my speakers.
Rym: I just assumed that because I have like changed computers and changed physicals A lot of stuff has changed that it was just the speakers.
Rym: but then I switched to headphones and it still sounded weird and the gun sounded way different.
Rym: and then I found this thread on Reddit titled from six months ago Why valve changed?
Scott: the gun sounds what the fuck the gun sounds where I think from what I heard were Recorded from the original gun they were.
Scott: I got like a fire new ones.
Scott: I went to a firing range with microphones and recorded the original guns.
Scott: and that's what those guns sound like.
Scott: So why the hell would they change them?
Rym: So they sound Way weaker and more muted.
Rym: Uh-huh, but they're not as blown out.
Rym: So those old gun sounds they're kind of they're a little bit clips Like they blew out the microphones early.
Scott: because I'm like, I'm like listen Even though it was the year 299 or whatever, right?
Scott: If you take a microphone to a gun range and make a you know, 64-bit 44, whatever kill her 40 kilohertz WAV file.
Scott: You're not gonna really do any better today.
Scott: We get the same exact WAV file technology.
Scott: We had then.
Scott: well Well, so I really sound like you can do a better job now because of logical reasons audio middleware.
Rym: But does it can do a better job of layering the sounds in the game?
Scott: I mean like yeah, that's true, but a WAV files away file.
Rym: There's no reason to change the original Because the way there's a huge like.
Rym: Guns are way louder.
Rym: If you've never fired a gun guns are super loud Firing range.
Scott: you wear big head earmuffs cuz bang.
Scott: It's loud.
Scott: It's explosions.
Rym: Like I don't care how Metal really hard.
Rym: Imagine the loudest gun you can think of.
Rym: I promise you it is way louder in real life than you have any idea.
Rym: Even if you have like a silencer on it, it is even silence.
Scott: guns are still loud.
Scott: They're just not nearly as loud as guns that aren't silence.
Rym: Most microphones will not actually capture that full range from silence to the gun in a realistic way.
Scott: Yeah, I guess at the time that they made those or even now because you there wasn't like super professionals, right?
Scott: These are some guys making a mod of Half-Life 1 for no money But also for human perception reasons.
Rym: a blown-out gun sound Does actually sound more like what a gun would sound like to a human because it kind of blows out your perception of audio.
Rym: Cuz our ears are not that good.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: So they kind of sounded.
Rym: they were bad and wrong But they were right in the way that a human would experience them if they were actually present when a gun went off Mm-hmm, but the the two reasons that appear to be stated as to why they made the.
Scott: can you still I mean Did you still have a pro like if something?
Scott: if you heard a gunfire in the distance and counter-strike I could tell you which Gun, they're sure you still can.
Rym: in fact you can way easier You didn't.
Scott: you didn't have to relearn be like those sounds it's still set clearly like oh that's an aug.
Scott: they got there.
Rym: I got picked it up again pretty quick.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Oh, that's clearly the sound of the AK.
Scott: The only problem was the M the sound of one a cake laughs.
Rym: the m4 fooled me and I thought it was the weaker Whatever gun instead.
Rym: Yeah, then I was like, oh wait.
Rym: No, that's an m4.
Rym: Oh shit thing.
Scott: I never buy.
Rym: Yeah, but So the rationale one which in retrospect I agree with and I think it's a good change.
Rym: The gun sounds as they were both with the blown-out effects and their relative volume and how they were layered.
Rym: however I don't know what audio middleware they use in counter-strike if they even use any.
Rym: But all that combined meant that if you play counter-strike for more than like 20 minutes you get some actual like serious ear fatigue And then counter-strike has always been that way.
Rym: That's just something you dealt with.
Scott: I never had that problem.
Rym: You probably didn't didn't really think about it.
Rym: ear fatigue It's not like it's gonna give you a headache or anything But what'll happen is you start to get lazy and start to miss a lot of other audio cues.
Rym: It might also make you irritable.
Rym: There's a lot of things that can happen with your counter-strike.
Rym: makes you irritable but Basically the play experience if you play for long periods of time It's actually way better now because you don't get that ear fatigue.
Rym: So two hours later you're still experiencing audio and reacting to cues at about the same level You already first started as opposed to the previous days where ear fatigue would mean you might just miss Sounds like someone sneaking up on someone or someone defusing the bomb.
Rym: So it actually makes counter-strike a lot more playable and a lot more pleasant to play in the long run And it also makes the game more fair in that everyone has a better chance to hear Necessary audio cues
Scott: as apparently
Rym: the pros are doing shit like having some people firing guns simultaneously when someone else starts defusing.
Scott: Well, that's oh that's good strategy Yeah, but that's also kind of like ultra fiddly and also you gotta be pretty close to them in the first place to hear the Defusing right?
Scott: You can't hear the defusing all the way across the map.
Rym: You can hear it not across the map No, but you can hear it like around the corner.
Scott: Yeah close.
Rym: so The other reason that has been stated here is that the old blown-out sounds might have sounded really cool when you're playing the game.
Rym: They sounded like ass on a television or a stream as a spectator.
Scott: Why?
Rym: Because they're blown-out terrible audio.
Rym: So the same ear fatigue and stuff will happen for the spectator.
Scott: Did I at least give people the option to use the old sound?
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Can I go in the folder and put the old wave files in there?
Scott: It would say I'm cheating because I modified the files.
Rym: if I do that I assume so and also it would just make you worse at the game.
Rym: probably yeah, but Basically, if you take counter-strike and put it on TV The old sounds sound way bad partly because the speakers people use that the headphones people use when they're just like watching a stream tend to be way less quality than what they use when they play a game and There's a lot of other factors.
Scott: you can read this thread and see more details on it But all I want to do now is just mention that it's the year 2017.
Scott: Yeah, and we're talking about Starcraft encounter stray.
Scott: Yeah 17 year old game and an old and even older game than that.
Scott: Yep Fascinating whose games are like almost 20 years old, basically Yeah, you know what else we're still talking about and they're still the games of talk.
Rym: go to any average Wednesday GeekNights.
Rym: We'll bring up Evangelion occasionally.
Scott: These are still the games of note.
Scott: Even Jillian's even older.
Rym: Yep So they changed another sound too and this one pissed the counter-strike community off.
Scott: What noise could they change the chain?
Rym: the knives of the chicken guns now make a unique and subtle sound?
Scott: in the last few bullets of their clip The clips emptying so it is a hollow space in it.
Rym: So there's a low ammo noise.
Rym: you can.
Rym: if you were paying attention You can listen and hear when someone is running out of ammo with a particular gun.
Scott: Is that true in real life as well?
Scott: Sometimes if someone has an AK and they just start shooting it like crazy and the clip gets to like 80% Empty will the noise sound different?
Rym: So by default, I don't think that is something a human could figure out.
Scott: What do you mean.
Scott: take an AK and just let You.
Rym: I don't think you could perceive that difference even if it existed in the real world.
Rym: That's my guess.
Rym: but I know that in World War two and the Vietnam War a lot of clips would make a noise.
Rym: Well, that clips magazines gun people.
Rym: don't fucking bother me about that shit.
Rym: They would make a pinging sound when you ran out of ammo.
Rym: Hmm, which was good because it would remind you that you're out of ammo and it was bad because it told everyone around you You're out of ammo.
Rym: Mmm, but basically they change this like a typewriter to get it.
Scott: to get it to get it.
Rym: Some of the grognards who play counter-strike.
Rym: We're super mad about it because it removes the skill of counting how many bullets everyone's used and blabber blabber blabber.
Scott: This is why Starcraft ain't changing shit.
Scott: It's the same deal.
Rym: But meanwhile the wider Professional community that isn't like super grognardy about it seems to have agreed that actually it's a minor change That's probably pretty good and that people are overreacting this.
Scott: This is the two extremes right the Starcraft Which is you know run and played by the purists and the counter-strike not afraid to change shit.
Scott: Yeah, we're on like the third version of counter-strike.
Scott: There's still only now the first Starcraft and the new one is compatible with the old one.
Rym: Overwatch changes things all the time as well, but a big difference between how Blizzard does this stuff.
Scott: Well, how ever watch is not 20 years old.
Scott: You don't have.
Scott: you don't have purists, right?
Scott: You can.
Scott: it's a brand new thing so you can keep changing it all you want Yep, and set the standard right kind of like how hockey rules change all the time.
Rym: baseball rules don't change that often Right, they probably should.
Scott: They're changing more.
Rym: But yeah, I think it's I think baseball too late for baseball but valve Basically just made the change and then you know The butter.
Rym: people got butter and the pro people like there's all this like internal nonsense community drama around this really really minor change.
Rym: But blizzard every time they're gonna make a change they always put the changes on this public test region so you can always play on the current version or The coming version.
Rym: that's getting feedback.
Rym: So the community as a result feels like they have input even though Blizzard appears to mostly ignore those people because they're wrong.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: No one does that for card games and they really should because every card game on earth when they come up with new cards.
Scott: It's like just have a test thing.
Rym: Yeah have the test and have that.
Scott: have the crazy, you know, the evil players who like to make the evil decks.
Scott: You know play there and figure out the evil cards first and then never release the evil cards to everyone else.
Rym: Yep, it's like a honeypot for shitheads like a really shitty card and then let people base their beta decks around it.
Rym: so this is all fascinating and you should read both these articles because they go to a lot more depth than I have any time to get into on the show because It's time for things of the day.
Rym: You got for me.
Scott: What's the name of this thing?
Scott: It has a name in Dutch.
Scott: I'm not gonna I can't pronounce it headwinds.
Scott: I know the actual name of it is like something Dutch.
Rym: Hagen win fight Fiest.
Scott: yeah, just okay.
Rym: It might send if you might say I guess like fighting.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is what I can win fights in.
Scott: this is a competition.
Rym: Hagen van fights in.
Scott: this is a Dutch competition.
Scott: Someone's gonna make fun of me for how I said that hanging in some fights in in the competition people are bicycling Into a headwind so the wind is blowing at their face and they're biking forward.
Scott: It is a very very very very strong headwind.
Scott: they wait for a day with this particular weather in order to do it and Then everyone on a shitty ass bike.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: with one gear.
Scott: No, they say everyone has the same shitty kind of shitty ass bike with one gear.
Rym: this guy in the video I've got up looks like he's probably crying.
Scott: you have to bike like X kilometers into the headwind.
Scott: It's not stopping and whoever has the best time.
Scott: It's just time trial is the winner.
Rym: I Feel really bad when I'm biking into like that little bit of wind.
Scott: you get coming around the curve on the east side bike path Don't know if I open my balcony, and I see that there's a wind and I see like trees moving I Don't get on my bike, and I go take the subway.
Rym: This guy just he looks like he's crying while he's right Is like a previous winner and he was not the winner this time trying to defend his title.
Scott: Yeah, this video is actually kind of old.
Scott: When's it from like 20?
Rym: It is from December 11th 2014.
Scott: Yeah, so this is an old, but I mean they still do this, right?
Scott: I'm sure you can maybe if you search around find a video from a newer one, but this video is good enough.
Rym: Yeah, this is pretty good.
Rym: So because I was talking about counter-strike.
Rym: Here's an article from a blog I follow that it's an interesting blog it has.
Rym: if you're into this kind of thing you can follow the blog.
Rym: But my thing of the day is you know the p90 the gun that's in counter-strike They get it's the best gun in goes in ghost in the shell.
Scott: effectively It's the best gun in Goldeneye and counter-strike.
Rym: It is the fabric national p90 and the fabric national 5-7 pistol.
Rym: These are two weapons that people who don't know shit about guns But think they know shit about guns because they played counter-strike or other games.
Rym: We'll talk about all the time.
Scott: Well, the p90 is just used in so many movies and things because even though it's a real gun in the real world That's also widely used like.
Rym: it is a ultra modern gun.
Scott: It's the submachine gun.
Scott: It shoots a lot of bullets really really well and it loads with like this Rectangular magazine on the top that put.
Rym: the bullets are sideways right.
Rym: they twist down a loading ramp into the gun, right?
Scott: It looks like super futuristic But it's totally just a real gun that you can buy.
Scott: and if you're like some special forces person you probably have some.
Rym: it was Originally designed for rear echelon troops.
Rym: So basically people in the military who are behind the front lines in a war who need to be able to defend themselves But don't need to be fighting on the front lines of a war and they don't need like an assault rifle or like a regular Old rifle like an m16.
Scott: Yeah, you don't need something that can like shoot across the battlefield.
Scott: You need something goes like you're in town and if some crazy bad guys in town You have to do some you know urban type warfare.
Rym: So like if you kind of like you do in counter-strike where you're in a little high-capacity Uh, you know, I think these things hold like 50 bullets a whole lot.
Rym: Yeah, and if you don't need like an m4 carbine or anything bigger like a full-on rifle or whatever It's gonna fucking kill someone.
Scott: is the point.
Scott: it's a gun.
Scott: It's gonna kill them just the same.
Rym: So as crazy as this gun is this article actually has a bunch of images of the prototypes When they were designing this gun because it is a crazy gun.
Rym: and if you think it's crazy these prototypes you just way crazy.
Rym: I mean if you just look at this one looks like it's something from Robocop.
Scott: I mean you just look at the actual gun and you know that it's like.
Scott: it's so crazy to begin with right?
Scott: So the prototypes is you know, everything about this gun is great.
Rym: this article is just really interesting if you don't know anything about this thing and When some nerd who thinks they know about guns because they played counter-strike tries to talk to you about the FNP 90 You can talk even more about the FNP 90.
Rym: You'll know one more thing than they know.
Scott: So are these prototypes like the p80 the p70 the piece?
Rym: No These are just prototypes.
Rym: as they were designing they had a set of Not to get too much into how the fan by the way is the company that makes it.
Rym: I'll break national.
Rym: Yeah, when a gun is being designed usually the military like a military or a police Organization will say here are our requirements We want it to have at least this much capacity Use this kind around have these kinds of performance characteristics and then gun manufacturers will design guns that meet or exceed those requirements And then they'll have trials.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: So these are some of the designs that did not make it to the final rounds of that early prototyping And This one has like a pistol built into it like a pistol grip and it looks like a pistol But then the gun shoots out the bottom.
Scott: guns are bad.
Scott: Don't kill people.
Rym: Yeah, but guns are also really fascinating.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It's like it's like fighter jets.
Rym: everything about fighter jets is Absolutely amazing except the fact that we use them to murder.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: We just use them to get places.
Scott: Yeah, you know how fast I could get like I had to go to Europe how fast I could be there if I could take like a b2.
Rym: What's that fighter?
Scott: Yes, we saw if anything would get you.
Rym: what's that fighter jet we saw in the in the museum?
Rym: That was notable for that.
Rym: It could fly faster than his own bullets and one of them shot itself down in a test, right?
Scott: But the point is, you know, you can get where you're going real fast.
Scott: Just you'll need to refuel like three times.
Rym: You know when I was a kid I did a star base program at International Guard base and one of the things we learned was doing navigation for like jets and stuff and like route planning and we literally had to plan like attack runs for f-16s, which meant like Refueling and how far could you go?
Scott: and like we're not far at all because you're going so fast.
Scott: They go real fast but the burn rate fuel tank is not large and you're burning all the fuel in like one.
Rym: go the fuel.
Scott: the fuel burn rate was Like a full order of magnitude more than a normal play Really old arcade games where you're like in a jet and there's like fuel and the fuel keeps running out and you're like god damn it.
Rym: It's kind of like that.
Rym: It's realistic.
Rym: It's always been like that.
Scott: It's still like that.
Rym: Yeah, so yeah in the meta moment, the book club book is Frank Herbert's Dune Dune, which we've just never read all the way through and probably make fun of us for it and fuck you.
Rym: It's.
Scott: that's how important nerd book of all time previous booklet book was good or bad Rebecca which you should read cuz it's short important movie not nerd book of all time.
Rym: Otherwise, we have no conventions until we have like zinc icon and then I think ConnectiCon and then Pax Prime and then Pax unplugged and then I am almost definitely going to be at Pax Australia this year Bringing the panels back.
Rym: Scott can come if he wants but because anyway You don't have to decide until way later because you'll get the badge.
Rym: either way I can go by myself and I'm not paying to fly so mmm.
Rym: But right now round-trip tickets to Sydney and coach are like 700 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, but we're going to Melbourne not Sydney.
Rym: Yeah, same price basically.
Rym: Okay, plus you can fly between Melbourne and Sydney.
Rym: It's like a dollar.
Rym: It's like less than an hour flight and it's like 30 bucks.
Rym: cuz I've done it.
Rym: Yeah, you just fly like tiger air or something.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Another thing that's kind of important is We've been getting just recently like over the last month or two Multiple requests from people for various reasons.
Scott: multiple meaning a handful with three Oh, which is still planning.
Rym: Yeah, three people which you know is significant.
Rym: significant considering we're not a popular thing and also just consider is a large percentage of our audience considering the percentage of people for whom This is a necessity.
Rym: Asking for closed captions on our panel videos, which upon doing research it would cost about $20,000 for me to pay a company to sub to do real closed captions that are accurate on Just our panel videos and nothing else.
Rym: Mm-hmm to do all our videos would be like $300,000 probably.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I can I cannot pay for that out of my pocket.
Scott: There's also no reason to do that because in the relatively midterm Robots and computers be able to do it for us.
Rym: I hope so.
Rym: so basically enough I'm gonna link to a forum thread where we're talking about this because If you didn't know you there's a whole interface built into YouTube, it's actually a really good interface.
Scott: I tried it.
Scott: I subtitled like I closed captioned 10 seconds of our video of one of our videos.
Scott: I closed and it was very is very easy to do.
Rym: It's just time-consuming.
Scott: It's just very time-consuming.
Rym: Yeah, one of our listeners on quality took the time to Completely closed caption all of the designing game rules panel your hero.
Rym: It took him a whole weekend and in this forum thread He noticed some really interesting things about how me and Scott talk.
Scott: Those were not new information to me, but they may be new information to anyone else who isn't paying attention.
Rym: Yep, they are spot-on about how the two of us interact.
Rym: Another listener and I don't know who cuz they didn't claim credit did my five nights at Freddy's video.
Rym: Someone else did another video.
Rym: There's a spreadsheet I made.
Rym: So if anyone wants to contribute closed captions to our videos Go to this thread and make sure you're not wasting your effort if someone else has already claimed a video to work on it.
Scott: I'm also really curious how we have fans who are hearing impaired because we're doing a podcast.
Scott: if you want to start subtitling the thousands of episodes of GeekNights Good luck.
Scott: or transcribing.
Rym: Yeah transcribing them.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But also I know no one listening needs the closed caption.
Rym: I did add a patreon goal.
Rym: if I hit that goal I'm gonna take all the patreon money that comes in and just as fast as I can pay a company to do our videos in Order of how often they are watched.
Scott: You're just gonna use all the patreon money for that all the L basically.
Rym: if so Basically if people hit that goal I think I can do two a month with that in with that new income coming in like I won't.
Rym: I won't take the previous money Except I took some of the previous money and I paid a company 300 bucks to do a professional Closed captioning of our old mastering game mechanics panel.
Rym: and those subtitles are also fantastic.
Rym: Like they did a fucking I cannot believe that they got the word Provost without asking me what the hell we were talking about.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: They missed two words in the whole thing.
Rym: They missed the concept of king making which is a kind of really like weird inside baseball term, I guess and tantamount.
Scott: They don't know the word tantamount.
Rym: well I said it real fast today in a context that I Could see how someone who does not know about games might think I was talking about a game mechanic of some kind.
Scott: Maybe because we talk real fast Was it really worth it for the person to put it cuz like.
Scott: I saw how much effort it was to do five seconds.
Scott: If you paid me $300, I would not have continued to the end.
Scott: And the per.
Scott: and if it's a company the company's taken some of that 300. so the person doing it is making less than the 300.
Rym: the other reason I bring all this up is that for about I assume only one person did the whole thing and they didn't Have a team for a but they got the whole thing done in three business days.
Scott: Yeah, that's a that's a one-person job.
Rym: if I Got some quotes - I am looking at getting translated subtitles as well.
Scott: See that would be super worth it.
Scott: So I Caption that's uptight.
Rym: I would start with Spanish.
Rym: Yeah, that's a good idea And I think I I'm not sure what I would do next.
Rym: if why?
Rym: you know if this all panned out, but probably German.
Rym: But so many German speakers also speak English, but I feel like I could probably do better.
Rym: But it's like.
Scott: shouldn't we do Chinese and other Chinese?
Rym: I guess we could.
Rym: You know, yeah the most spoken languages there are or Japanese partly because actually there is a burgeoning like Andy tabletop scene over there.
Rym: I feel like there is a dearth of game design lectures about tabletop in Japanese.
Scott: Arabic Also good choice.
Rym: Arabic could actually be a really good choice.
Rym: good choice, but Spanish first We'll see.
Rym: I'm still getting quotes and looking at all this.
Rym: stay tuned This.
Rym: this might be a good direction to put patreon money for this foreseeable future Because I feel like that's just a nice public good like it's the exact kind of thing That I couldn't afford to do on my own but I would do if I could have money to just do it.
Scott: I feel like even so like that's that's a better use of patreon money than other things.
Scott: but Shouldn't we be spending it to subtitle things that people should actually be watching.
Scott: Well, not us.
Rym: Yeah, if you're Why are we doing gig nights when we could literally be in Somalia right now helping people?
Scott: We couldn't we would just die in Somalia.
Scott: It's a horrible.
Rym: Why don't we try?
Rym: Why are you even?
Rym: why are we?
Rym: Donating all our income you go first hundred percent of our income you go first so worthy causes not going there.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you know I could be doing a lot of work doing research on the surface of the Sun.
Scott: Why don't I go?
Rym: Yeah, so anyway, we're at packs PAX East.
Rym: they all blur together.
Rym: at this point There's just so many packs and we weren't enforcing and paneling we were playing games and our good friends Chris and Anthony They uh, they bring the games.
Rym: They said something to me and it was a combination of words that did not at first make sense.
Rym: They said hey, I got a Friedman Freese trivia game if you want to play it.
Scott: So that's apparently not entirely true, but it sort of is true, right?
Scott: So here's the thing.
Scott: Rym does not like trivia games in general and I understand why.
Scott: here's the real.
Rym: so it's complicated.
Rym: I Really like trivia games and also really hate trivia games.
Rym: I was a varsity quiz ball, right?
Scott: Here's the problem with trivia games, right?
Scott: Is there games of?
Scott: they're not games of skill.
Scott: They're not games of decision-making They're not even games of luck.
Scott: It's just you either of a lot of them most of them especially trivial pursuit the worst of all are just binary.
Scott: you I get asked a question and you either know the answer and Succeed or you don't write.
Scott: someone either asks you like, uh-huh.
Scott: What's the first boss of Zelda 1?
Scott: and you know like Aquinas, right?
Scott: Somebody asks you, you know, what year did Louis Armstrong releases first album?
Scott: And what was it named?
Rym: Yeah, it's like the Rangers games.
Rym: They'll have the trivia.
Rym: That's like how many goals did so-and-so score in this important game?
Rym: And it's multiple choice.
Rym: You're like, yeah, I got this and then it's like a 3 b 4 c 5 d 6.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like you either know it or you don't.
Scott: it's binary and it's not fun or exciting or you know And you barely you don't even really learn anything value.
Rym: Well, I guess it's.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's fun and exciting if the domain of the trivia overlaps heavily with the domain of knowledge of all the players.
Rym: Correct.
Rym: That is the only situation where those games are fun.
Scott: Yeah, but even if we go to nerd trivia, right?
Scott: so I've been to nerd trivia is very few times because I don't like them but Also, I don't drink.
Scott: So I was at a non drinky one.
Scott: Yeah, it was a nerd NYC thing Remember, I
Rym: remember that and one of the questions was like fist of the North Star something exactly
Scott: That was in my domain and I was like, yeah I know what else knew what the hell you know fist of the North Star was.
Rym: you were the only table that got that one.
Scott: But then they were asking questions about like Star Trek or whatever other garbage.
Scott: and I'm like I don't think I remember what games of Thrones and I'm like, I don't.
Rym: one of the questions specifically was Name all of the ajas in the Wheel of Time and that was before we'd read that fucking Book.
Rym: and in fact, unless you've read a lot of the books you wouldn't know the answer, right?
Scott: I'm like, I'm just like.
Scott: It's not a fun game, right?
Scott: So This trivia game unlike garbage like Trivial Pursuit right fixes those problems.
Scott: now It's not the only trivia game to fix those problems, right jackbox fixes many of those problems by a using multiple choice and be bringing in humor even when you have no clue.
Scott: the humor can make It valuable.
Scott: There's also games like wits and wagers where you're sort of guessing like over-under kind of things on numbers.
Scott: Yeah, so and then you know that way it's not just pure Do you know it or do you not?
Scott: and it's fun for everybody.
Rym: some games really focus the domain.
Rym: So if you are in that domain like Starcraft trivia and you play with all your Starcraft obsessed friends are like Simpsons trivia
Scott: exactly, so here's a game called fauna and fauna is a game by Friedman Freese who Makes all his games begin with F and usually have two words like fresh fish and power grade.
Rym: We'll go shop.
Rym: Yeah power.
Scott: It is actually called something else.
Scott: Show his games come in green boxes, right?
Scott: Anyway, the game called fauna is an animal trivia game and we didn't play fauna.
Scott: Well, we played as a game called America a party game something something counts.
Scott: So everyone Everyone's sitting at the table knows about America because we're all We did not.
Scott: we're mostly American right and even the people who are not American, you know They were living in America for a significant period of time.
Scott: and new American things, right?
Scott: So This game is the exact or close to or exactly the same mechanics as fauna But as American trivia with a map of the United States and is made by someone else.
Rym: So the conceit is pretty simple that the the the execution is basically flawless.
Scott: Yeah so the conceit is the only problem it has that other trivia games also have is that you will eventually go through all of the trivia cards and then The game is done for you.
Rym: it is physically designed so that one the person who Chooses, you know, which of the two categories to use which is a great mechanic to have in any trivia game Because it allows you to direct the domain which adds a little bit of strategy.
Rym: unlike trivial pursuit where you roll dice to determine The domain the person who asks the question is not prevented from also trying to answer because of the physical design of how those cards Work, that's true.
Rym: They can't see the answer.
Rym: That's a baby's first mistake.
Rym: If you make a trivia game, yep, and to the the physical thing you put them in has two sides and every trivia card has Two sides.
Rym: So if you when you finish a card you put it facing the same direction in the other side It guarantees you will cycle through every single question Exactly once and then hit the end.
Rym: so you will never get the situation that a lot of trivia games will get into Where you play it again and a question you saw three games ago pops up again.
Rym: But there are questions you have not seen right?
Scott: you keep the cards in the bog.
Scott: You can do it in trivial pursuit also if you keep the cards nicely in the.
Rym: yeah But this game has a like.
Rym: that is part of the rules.
Rym: I keep that shit.
Scott: you own a copy and you're the only one who ever plays it.
Scott: you will eventually See a card you saw the first time you played.
Scott: you could even like put a slip of paper there to remember where that spot Is yep, and then you'll be like, oh we've played this whole game and then you can sell it to someone else.
Rym: I'm pretty confident.
Rym: by the time I got to the beginning again because there's a lot of questions I'd have forgotten the answers to a lot of them.
Scott: That's also true cuz.
Scott: there's a lot of questions in this box.
Rym: But the conceit is that once the question is asked and you pick from one of two topics The question will be about a thing like Pez or something something American the Olympics a sport and they'll actually be three questions.
Rym: The answer to one of them will be a year Mm-hmm.
Rym: the answer to one of them will be a number and the answer to one of them will be a state.
Scott: Mm-hmm In the United States like Connecticut Oklahoma five Guessing cubes.
Rym: It's a cube game Yep And on your turn you choose one of those questions and you put your cube on What you think.
Scott: the answer to that question is now you don't have to even be exactly right.
Scott: For example, if you think that you know the Mets won the World Series in 1986, which they did There isn't a spot.
Rym: just that's the thing.
Rym: I would not know.
Scott: there isn't a spot just for 1986.
Scott: There's a spot that's like 1985 through 1990.
Rym: they're all ranges.
Scott: They're all ranges.
Scott: So you just put your cube there 1985 through 1990. right now the next person has to put their cube out.
Scott: you take turns so they're like damn it.
Scott: I knew it was 1986, but I can't go there.
Scott: They can just put their cube next to yours and still get points because they're one away.
Rym: So even they could go answer a different question, right?
Scott: They might be like, well, they got a lot of points for picking 1986 But I know that, you know, the state the Mets play in is New York and they'll put their cube on New York.
Scott: It's like aha.
Scott: I got points for that and now people go.
Scott: I know it's New York also, but they can't put their cube on New York.
Scott: So they put their cube on adjacent states like New Jersey.
Rym: So you get I think three points if you are correct Yep, and you get nothing.
Scott: It's seven points if you get a bunch of points.
Rym: if you're correct Yeah, and you get a smaller number of points if you are Next to the correct answer.
Scott: if you're more than one space away from the correct answer Then you get no points and you lose your cube.
Rym: yep, and you only get.
Rym: and if you lose too many cubes you either recent you bump back out to I think three like you Reset or if you're at three or more you get one cube from your lost pile back every round.
Scott: now Here's another benefit of this game Usually in a game of trivia when no one knows the answer because something ridiculous like what year did something's crazy happen?
Scott: Like what year was Pez invented?
Scott: it was like I don't fucking know right?
Rym: one person's like 1976. is someone else like 1908?
Scott: it could have been 18 something.
Scott: You don't even know they had sugar then right?
Scott: It's like Right.
Scott: So everyone starts guessing but you can vote and you can say you know what.
Scott: I think Nobody got the answer exactly, right?
Rym: And you can also say I don't think anyone's even gonna be near the answer.
Scott: And if you say that and it turns out to be true you get points if everyone else is actually wrong.
Scott: so you can just bet on people being wrong when no one knows the answer which gives a Strategy and fun element to questions that are bullshit.
Scott: So they're not just complete wastes like they are in trivial pursuit.
Rym: the scope of the questions is great.
Rym: So like the number part see it's a scale and it starts like you can bet like zero one, two, three But then the scale gets bigger and bigger.
Rym: So when the top half the gradations are a hundred thousand a million ten million a hundred million a billion Right.
Scott: So if you think it's between a hundred million and a billion you just vote on the hundred million spot and you're good to Go, you'll be exactly right.
Rym: if you're right the years go to like to the year The game was made and they started 1492, right?
Scott: Yeah, the the billion spot the spots at the very end actually count for like up to infinity or to negative infinity.
Scott: So like if you think it was sometime before 14, whatever you just vote on 14 Whatever and that goes all the way back to.
Scott: you know The creation of the universe.
Rym: now in terms of play the way this ends up shaken down Is that one?
Rym: a lot of people will act like they know the answer and then on the turn they'll be like, ah I don't actually know.
Rym: Yeah, and two You get context from other players Which is where a lot of the magic happens.
Rym: because even if you don't really know Like so one of the questions that we were all we were all super fucking dumb about this.
Rym: We were super stupid, but it was where did you?
Rym: where did jaws take place?
Rym: Like where was that book slash movie set?
Scott: We were so sure it was like Jersey.
Scott: Yeah I'm like It was not a southern tropical beach, right?
Scott: Because you've seen the movie but it was.
Scott: it was still a beach in the summer right clearly Atlantic waters.
Scott: It wasn't beautiful Pacific water.
Scott: Yeah, so we're all like God Jersey.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's warm enough.
Scott: You're going to the beach.
Scott: It felt like Jersey, you know.
Rym: So half of us kind of knew or at least thought we knew and we're very confident like put our guys right down there.
Rym: other People saw like oh both of them are guessing like the Jersey area and they seem really confident.
Scott: So I'm gonna go to like Pennsylvania, which is right or Delaware, right?
Scott: Right next to be adjacent, right?
Scott: It's a next to Jersey.
Scott: They were just trying to get points but putting their cubes next to the right answer.
Rym: But in another one like what it was I think the question was literally what stays the Pez Museum in world?
Rym: Right.
Rym: So someone hazards a guess and then other people are like, yeah, that feels right.
Scott: and guess near Well, I there is actually in Connecticut where I lived a Pez visitor center and a Pez factory, I think and You can see it's like billboards for it.
Scott: And there was an incident in high school where a kid brought went there and he brought a shit ton of Pez to high school.
Scott: I'm just handing out sacks of Pez to everybody.
Scott: It was crazy.
Scott: So I vote.
Scott: I voted Connecticut with confidence.
Scott: I was like, yeah Pez Museum in Connecticut and apparently that's crazy wrong.
Scott: There's only a Pez visitor center and factory in Connecticut and the Pez Museum is somewhere else.
Rym: So basically what this means is that Even if there is a huge disparity in knowledge because some of the questions like around the Supreme Court of the Olympics it ranged from Someone who like literally knows everything about the Olympics to someone who literally has no idea about any
Scott: doesn't know what the Olympics is
Rym: Yep, and they can both play this trivia game together and have a good time,
Scott: right?
Scott: Cuz you.
Scott: if you don't know the trivia you can use you can play a game of cube placing strategy instead.
Scott: You know figuring out who do you think is right and just putting your cube next to theirs because you can't put out you Can't put out all three cubes at once.
Scott: You got to put one cube at a time and take turns.
Rym: Yep, you go around.
Rym: So if you know a lot about the Supreme Court and you know the answer to two of them Then you're thinking now is which one of these questions will no one else know?
Rym: So I'll get a second go to put my answer on the second correct one.
Scott: The other thing is that any cubes you put out that don't score any points you lose those cubes.
Scott: You've only got five cubes because one of your cubes is a scoring cube on the scoring track And then you only get one cube back from the graveyard per turn.
Scott: So you do want to take at least one risk per turn because you're gonna get that cube back.
Scott: But if you take two risks per turn you're sort of limiting your ability.
Scott: So like there were times you're like I could guess and get a point But I used up all my cubes because you're always gonna have at least three cubes no matter what.
Rym: Yep, I've noticed people who went bankrupt early and were basically stuck on three cubes.
Rym: for us the game almost never.
Rym: I don't think they ever won this game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it means they also put out a bunch of wrong cubes.
Scott: Yeah, but usually they put out a bunch of wrong cubes like way early and so it's like it's simultaneously this trivia game But it's also a like a real board game of like place cubes for optimal point scoring Right, and you're sort of balancing these two things.
Scott: So you got interesting stuff going on two different ways.
Scott: Yep So this game saw a lot of table actually played it like two or three times at a pack.
Scott: So it was worth packs time.
Rym: Yep, I played it.
Rym: I want to say three times.
Rym: I think three times it packs And I would have played it again, but we ran out of packs.
Scott: It's also great because it's super accessible to people who aren't super hard gaming types.
Rym: Yeah, they might miss out on that cube point placing strategy, but everyone else is gonna get into it like real hard, right?
Scott: But then but the trivia part is like anyone can get into and since if you're like us living in the u.s You're gonna know stuff right.
Scott: the other original version which is animal trivia It might be harder for a lot of people.
Rym: some of our friends would know a lot about that and some of our friends would.
Scott: Right, but everyone is gonna you know, because we're Americans there's gonna be cards, you know and cards you don't.
Scott: but no You're gonna have some connection to the game if you live in or are from this place, but this mechanic Is I mean the only you could make other you should.
Scott: someone should make many many trivia games using the same mechanic.
Rym: Dude, if I could I would just.
Rym: I would just license it and make a series of game.
Rym: The problem is it first state per city I'd make.
Scott: one problem is like if we did like video game trivia, right?
Rym: We're gonna put for the man.
Scott: if we did nerd trivia Like what's the map gonna be?
Scott: we could do a number and a year for nerd trivia, but what's our math gonna be?
Rym: Yeah, you might and if you just have three number things or like that It would be it would lose a lot of its magic, right?
Scott: You need to have some sort of map.
Scott: Money would be taking a game like you could do Lord of the Rings trivia and have a man Map of Middle Earth, but it's enough.
Scott: how much how much?
Scott: Lord of the Rings trivia.
Scott: Can you make?
Scott: Can you make enough to fill a box?
Rym: I don't know confidently if you include the silver fucking rillion, right?
Scott: And there's not enough locations in Middle Earth.
Scott: So you'd have to be really fine-grained with the locations and only so many of them are plot points.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you would need like, you know a really complex universe To get as complex as the real universe.
Rym: Market this to local color types.
Rym: So there'd be a New York City one.
Rym: It's a map of New York City.
Scott: you could do in New York City one broken up into neighborhoods.
Scott: Yeah, absolutely.
Scott: You could make a New York City.
Rym: every state every city.
Rym: That's got some history basically every single city in like.
Rym: the thing
Scott: is it might get boring because if you do like New York State like you're only gonna have so many topics and that are interesting and if you start doing ones that cover the boring areas It's like alright a bunch of worthless cars But
Rym: as we found actually the boring ones for America Ended up being real interesting because even if like it was like Pez like other than you no one had any.
Scott: We didn't do a lot of this.
Scott: But if you actually you're supposed to read the cards in completely out loud at when you're answering After you're revealing the answer they just teach you stuff and then you'll learn things.
Scott: Yeah, we did.
Scott: We just read the answer like oh is this day?
Scott: We didn't read the text underneath because we were running low on packs time.
Scott: Yeah But if you do read the text underneath you will get fascinating and interesting information and educate yourself.
Rym: So yeah, if you avoid trivia games, you know trivial pursuit doesn't explain its answers.
Scott: It says here's the answer.
Rym: Also, we did not really encounter questions that were just broken or wrong.
Rym: We don't.
Scott: common problem is on the questions about the states.
Rym: It does split it up.
Scott: It tells you in advance whether it's the east half of the US or the west half.
Scott: We're using the Mississippi River as the dividing line.
Rym: I think at least three times.
Scott: I think a I rally would have rather had those hints not be there Yep, and be at least one card only one card.
Scott: We saw it was actually wrong it.
Scott: the hint was West and the answer was Easter rice verse.
Rym: I forget But at the same time I feel like that might be oh So that might be good for people who don't know a lot about American geography.
Rym: But there are two sides to the board.
Rym: the front side names all the states with their Two letter acronym or initialisms.
Rym: the bag does not have that.
Scott: only play with the bank side only.
Scott: side only blank side only.
Rym: But this game only no babies super fun.
Scott: Like we really enjoyed playing this at Pat This is a game that I would like to actually get and bring to like Thanksgiving with family.
Rym: Yeah, just like.
Scott: bring this because it's like because it's a real game.
Scott: They're like I would enjoy playing but also a game that everyone else would enjoy playing who's not gamers?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette.
Rym: great job emoji my steady calm.
Rym: William Isen Rose, Jeremy minor.
Rym: Every guy here loved to be you gets and even when taking your lumps.
Rym: I 0 9 9 9 9 0 1 1 8 9 9 9 8 8 1 9 9 9 9 1 1 9 7 2 5 dot dot dot 3.
Rym: Shervin von Horl Rar Rar Laval is pronounced with an O. James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make her him say cabbages.
Rym: Brian Fisher sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich.
Rym: It's our topics.
Rym: and Joshua Joe star Tyler Ehlers Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin.
Rym: Give us hell.
Rym: Quimby Brian's Adroni Blair Bicicil toy Redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Yep, try to get the rims rants going again.
Rym: I've been kind of busy between that political slash Public good thing that I'm working on that I keep talking about that.
Rym: I can't talk about more closely yet because there's still legal work to be done.
Rym: But the rims rants should be about once a week After this week once I get things rolling again, and I got no cons until zenk icon, but now I leave you with something Back beat the word is on the street that the fire in your heart is out.
Rym: I'm sure you've heard it all before but you never really had a doubt.
Rym: Anybody feels the way I do about you now And all the roads we have to walk a winding and all the lights that lead us there are blinding.
Scott: There are many things that I would like to say to you, but I don't know how because maybe You're gonna be the one that saves me.
Rym: Ah You're my wonder.