Rym: It's Monday October 2nd 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I am Scott and this is spooky GeekNights.
Rym: It's tonight.
Rym: We're talking about terrors of technology.
Scott: All right, so yesterday was October the first You go apple picking.
Scott: Yeah, so Originally, it was like hey, let's go apple picking.
Scott: then it's like wait a minute Let me search for the best place to go apple picking cuz usually when we live upstate It's like oh we go to the nearby apple pick.
Rym: Yeah, like just drive north and you hit apple field, right?
Scott: So you just go to the one nearby and they're all mostly all have everything you want because everything you want is cider and Cider doughnuts.
Scott: I had a doughnut and apples.
Scott: those are the three things you want and every single one of the places has those three things and some of them have a Maze and maybe you want the maze or maybe not and you get a pumpkin.
Scott: All right, whatever.
Rym: Yep, sometimes you buy some maze because we're in the city.
Scott: I had like pick one out like which place is the best apple?
Rym: or you know what?
Rym: that's actually a tricky proposition because remember They all have delicious Apple.
Rym: that time when we were we took the taconic home from upstate back to New York instead of Going the normal way on the throughway and then we saw that farmer's stand.
Rym: We're like, oh shit We stopped and bought some stuff and then we passed like ten more farmer stands that were all way better than the one that we Stopped to had delicious apples.
Rym: Yeah, but the other ones had more.
Rym: it looked fancier.
Scott: Yeah, the farmers invested more in the construction of their stand.
Rym: Anyway made the mistake of going to the first one.
Scott: So I discovered though the Warwick Apple Fest.
Scott: so Warwick is a town I've been looking at because it's near some lake houses, which I've been investigating.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm like, oh well, there's a giant Apple Fest.
Scott: It's like the biggest Apple Fest ever every year.
Scott: Let's go check it out.
Scott: So I'm just gonna quickly talk about what happened there.
Scott: So the Apple Fest itself is pretty much the way you phrase that.
Rym: let's talk about what happened there.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so The Warwick Apple Fest is like 99% white people.
Scott: That's okay And you know what for it is upstate New York for an Apple Fest.
Scott: There are surprisingly few apples at the Apple Fest.
Scott: there were deaf.
Scott: You could definitely get a pie there or a cider or whatever, but not a lot of apples at the Apple Fest.
Scott: It's mostly craft fair local businesses people taking advantage of the fact the Apple Fest is happening.
Scott: So they're throwing a tag sale on their front lawn because their houses in like a great position.
Scott: You know the church is in such a great position.
Scott: So the church leaders are out selling apple butter on the street.
Rym: make sense, you know.
Scott: So the thing is when you think about those townie fairs, they usually kind of small.
Scott: This was like them, you know, it didn't have any different stuff than other townie fairs But it was substantial and crowded.
Scott: for one of those townie fairs Like whoa, you needed to park in the high school and take a shuttle bus.
Scott: Wow It was hard to walk down the street.
Scott: It sounds like the Awaka festival back in Leroy and it took like Set more than two hours to see all the stuff and there was some good stuff.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: There's an old lady who was way Awesome.
Scott: She was from New Jersey and what she does is she collects t-shirts and sweatshirts All right, and when she gets enough of them that are all sort of go together.
Scott: She sews them together into a quilt and I needed a new couch blanket and she happened to have one that had like 12 New York Rangers together from our failed Stanley Cup finals in 2014-15. ish.
Scott: So I'm like, oh whatever.
Scott: It's better than the shitty blanket.
Scott: I got now.
Scott: It's actually way warm.
Scott: So, you know anyway, so that was good, but then it's like well We wanted to go up.
Scott: We wanted actual apples, right and we couldn't really get any at the Apple Festival Oddly enough.
Rym: Well, yeah, I see mostly pictures.
Rym: only the only pictures there are pictures of the pie contest.
Scott: Yeah, there's a pie contest eating and also baking But we didn't hang around for that anyway.
Scott: So I had previously researched right just in case I thought of this like what if we can't get apples at the Apple Fest?
Scott: So I researched the best nearby Apple pickin which was a place called massacre orchards.
Scott: like a person who wears a mask or a person who makes a mask?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: So you go to massacre orchards and if I found out hmm Maybe massacre orchards isn't so good because apparently it was the only one that lets you drive right up to the tree.
Rym: Oh, and I'm like, oh that's that's that's a bad sign.
Scott: So I'm thinking that's a place for lazy people to go apple picking.
Scott: not a because normally you park walk out get apples and walk Back, yeah half the fun is just like walking around outside in the apple orchard.
Scott: But actually while that is true that massacre orchards was an apple orchard for lazy people It was actually the most happen in apple orchard.
Rym: Oh, look they publish their ripening schedule.
Scott: Yeah, they just let you like dry cuz.
Scott: they just let you drive the fuck right up to the tree, right?
Scott: Yeah, but actually not only that they just let you have free range.
Scott: Like it's a public park.
Scott: They don't give a shit Right.
Scott: So people basically People who knew better about massacre orchards were literally just driving up their like SUVs or pickup trucks Opening up the back and having picnics all day in the apple orchard.
Scott: And you can eat an apple in the apple orchard and they don't give a shit, right?
Scott: You just can't.
Scott: if you leave though, they search your car for apples And you got to pay.
Scott: so it's $30 a bag when you leave with apples, right?
Scott: But also they had you know, the country store area, right?
Scott: So in the country store area They had the cider donuts which were great, but not like the best ever, right?
Scott: They also had Pizza which I didn't eat because I didn't know about it, but it looked.
Scott: it didn't look like New York Pizza.
Scott: It was like a fluffy square kind of pizza, but whether you want to even call it pizza It still looked like a legendary pizza if you were buying them like crazy, right?
Scott: And cider.
Scott: so I waited in line cuz you know I went to the into the country store area where you can buy pick up something go to the register and It was so crowded at this place That like that country store didn't have apple cider.
Scott: You had to go up wait in this line to get apple cider and that was the same line to also get pizza and donuts And ice cream and pie by the slice with ice cream on it.
Scott: And while I was waiting in line the power went out At the little state so I couldn't.
Scott: I was like waiting in this huge line just to get cider and then only I found out As we were leaving That when you pay for the app, oh, yeah, you can just get cider with the exit.
Scott: You can get cider at the exit.
Scott: they didn't tell me that in advance Scott.
Rym: that's in like their main fact.
Scott: Yeah on the website.
Scott: There was nowhere at the orchard to figure that out But anyway, so I made a mistake.
Rym: so you went to a place without going to the website.
Scott: I went to the website just say what is best app orchard anyway, even talk about the pizza.
Scott: Yeah, so if you want to go to the most happen an apple orchard.
Scott: Oh, I forgot the most important part The Apple Festival which is in the same town as its orchard.
Scott: by the way The orchard had no presence at the festival other than advertising in the guidebook.
Scott: The Apple Festival is 99% of white people the apple orchard 90-plus percent not a white people.
Rym: Oh What is up with that?
Scott: What can you explain the not white people who are all happy to know that you should just go to the apple orchard and have?
Scott: A picnic.
Rym: I don't know the Fed.
Rym: It's a white.
Rym: sounds like it's got a lot of that sort of country.
Rym: kitsch Feel.
Scott: yeah, I don't know.
Scott: It was definitely, you know, it was a festival.
Scott: It was fine.
Scott: The festival doesn't?
Scott: it's not a thing that I think you need to repeat.
Rym: Yeah, but on one hand I love apple picking but on the other hand Because I have an oral allergy to pollen and apple skins a lot of the joys of apple picking are lost on me.
Rym: Cuz I can't just eat apples like I used to when I was young.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but I can cook them and bake them.
Rym: But if I get even one bag of apples, he just cleaned the apple.
Scott: cuz the pollen just clean the pot So it impregnates the skin.
Rym: I have to peel.
Rym: I can peel them And then I can eat them.
Rym: just fine or I can make the skin is so delicious.
Rym: that's the problem.
Rym: Whatever occasionally I'll eat apples But usually I got to go to a place where I know there aren't birch trees and easel crumbed and then ate apple.
Rym: Uh, well, so if I eat an apple, it won't kill me and it's not like an allergy Like I'll get puffed up.
Rym: basically my throat will swell up and make it hard to swallow for like four hours.
Rym: Hmm, that's it.
Rym: But it doesn't get worse than that No matter how many apples.
Scott: I have you a problem because you'd eat an apple and then you'd go to the country store.
Scott: Yeah pizza and a pie and a cider donut Yeah, that'd be trouble.
Scott: but yeah if you are looking at I don't know if that's the ideal apple picking experience for everyone.
Scott: But if you want to go to it like spend all day in an apple orchard just having a good time You know partying you can't grill out there, but you can do pretty much anything else and Such and such and have you know, like a party apple orchard.
Scott: I recommend this one.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So in some news, I don't really want to dwell on the mass shooting because they happen all the time in America.
Scott: What is there new to say?
Scott: I shoot people.
Rym: I think the last new thing to say was after Sandy Hook When we realized that even children being killed in mass was not enough for the government to do anything.
Scott: People want to shoot people.
Scott: They don't care if someone else shot someone.
Scott: good.
Scott: Yep They're probably secretly at home being like, oh it's good.
Scott: Someone shot those kids.
Scott: Yeah, because they're evil That's how they are.
Rym: Or it's all a false flag.
Rym: They're they're all crisis actors.
Scott: No, I don't think they actually someone actually believes that but I think I have so because of our belief.
Rym: I know a lot about people who may just like it when people get shot.
Scott: I know a lot about people who literally believe they just fantasize about shooting people and if someone else shoots people they like it.
Rym: but yeah that happens and I don't know what you can do other than if you got into the habit of calling your senators and reps because of health care.
Rym: Not a bad time to start doing the same thing over this cuz it's working a little bit, uh-huh Yeah, right.
Rym: No, there's some really you don't read like 538 or anything.
Rym: There's some evidence that it's having an effect?
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: I believe when I see it.
Rym: Okay, you're just choosing not to look at it.
Rym: But anyway in other news.
Rym: so hacking has been in the news a lot lately because there's been a bunch of hacks and also a lot of people are stupid and use guessable passwords or use the same password everywhere or Log into their email on a public computer and don't log out or very
Scott: large important organizations.
Rym: I really shitty IT Yep, but you can do a good bit wide extent.
Rym: protect yourself from many of those things by having basic security practices.
Scott: But this you could learn if you listen to geek then yeah, which comes down to people.
Scott: only listen to hear GeekNights.
Scott: They don't listen to it.
Rym: So they won't Use unique passwords.
Rym: don't give anyone your password ever.
Rym: That two-factor that alone will cover like 90% of the problems.
Rym: you're likely to run into that.
Scott: me I do it.
Rym: one of the biggest Vulnerabilities today is the fact that most companies want to make money.
Rym: Obviously, they don't care that much about support.
Rym: They don't care that much about really anything.
Rym: Unless those things get in the way of making money.
Rym: So they actually want to care a lot about the support Experience because they want people to be happy and keep giving them money.
Rym: Mm-hmm a big part of that is that they try to reduce barriers to getting support Like if you need help from I don't know your cable company because your cable stopped working.
Rym: They want to make it real easy for you to get that help so that you won't just cancel the service.
Scott: But
Rym: to make it easy it turns out that because most people are kind of stupid They don't like to do things like put a password into the website where they have to go complain about their cable service not working or They don't want to have to like prove who they are on the phone before someone resets their password or unlocks their account.
Rym: The end result of this is that most of the vulnerabilities out there that are trivial to exploit do not require much technology knowledge.
Rym: they simply require Trying to open a support ticket of some kind with a company and eventually that company will probably just give you access To someone else's account.
Scott: you didn't read this article.
Scott: Did you
Rym: so this article that I'm about to link to
Scott: see if you read this
Rym: goes to a much more specific example of using exploits in that kind of technology like for example the way you auto register an account on a domain and how you can get companies to give you credentials to things that you shouldn't have access to through basically purely automated systems that Rely on basic things like oh they have an email address at organization comm.
Rym: that must be good never mind the fact that Certain other magic number organization at organization address calm will actually send a message through somewhere That is publicly accessible.
Scott: right.
Scott: so think about this right, so let's say Craigslist has a slack.
Scott: Yeah well the Craigslist slack will let you have an account if you have an email address at Craigslist.
Scott: because who can get an email address at Craigslist unless you work for Craigslist?
Scott: Craigslist has a system of generating anonymous email addresses for people to help them do transactions anonymously.
Scott: Those email addresses are at Craigslist.
Scott: So if you get a email support ticket at like Time Warner who knows where right?
Scott: Your name?
Scott: but their support system might generate this email address that autumn forwards to you to help you be anonymous.
Scott: Or you know just for your support ticket it creates a brand new email address That sends emails to you and that email address is at Time Warner.
Scott: And now you can use this support ticket email address to log in to like the Time Warner slack is.
Scott: who would have an email Address at Time Warner except time Warner employee?
Scott: well that people with help desk tickets will have.
Rym: and this is you know Social engineering is what we usually talk about.
Scott: no this engineering this is an actual vulnerability.
Scott: by by.
Scott: Not any individual product will write would have this problem.
Scott: It's a. it's the fact that one organization with one domain you thinking False assumptions about the don't security of the domain set up multiple products that combine together Cause a problem in one of the other.
Rym: the reduction of friction.
Rym: people they want.
Rym: Everyone out there wants it to be very easy for you to if you're authorized to use something Click on a thing and it just works, you know single sign on and all these different methods, but the Prove who you are purely by the domain of your email address is shockingly common and this is a very Specific set of detailed examples of how these exploits can be used.
Scott: Yeah You set up one thing and it's based on the assumption that yeah Of course everyone who has at front row crew dot-com email addresses is someone we know and trust.
Scott: Yeah, and you set up another thing where I just create automatically crazy email addresses for people.
Scott: It's like oh they both make sense on their own and then when they're both installed on the same domain together It's like oopsie.
Scott: I didn't realize that wasn't thinking about that.
Rym: Yep, and There's no good way around this because the reality is almost any company That's small ish or even medium-sized and they want to reduce friction for things like making accounts or proving identity.
Rym: This is the kind of shit they're gonna do because the alternative is to set up complicated single sign-on mechanisms that require actual authentication of the person on the other side of the connection and not just some trivially spoof credential that they might have.
Rym: and There's not much you can do about it except if you start a small company.
Rym: don't do this.
Rym: But I wanted to give a very specific Example of how these things work because when people usually say hacking as Scott and I often complain about Most hacking comes down to your password was easily guessed and/or is the same across.
Scott: all is an example of a hacking.
Scott: That is you know, it's this is this is real hacking, right?
Scott: You want to see a real example of real hacking?
Scott: This is it?
Scott: It's now it is.
Scott: it's not someone the Pharisee cracking codes with a black screen with green text.
Scott: It's just something stupid like this.
Rym: but at the same time this is Social engineering adjacent because it's only because it has to do with a help desk.
Rym: Not just that it's the same kind of workflow.
Rym: So where a lot of this comes from is that a support desk?
Rym: will usually especially in a middle-sized company have processes for how credentials get figured out and identity gets proven and a lot of the implementations of this kind of logic.
Rym: the prover you are with your email address was in response to Automating those workflows so that no one has to call a person on the phone because the person is easily socially engineered.
Rym: But because the workflows primarily mirror the thing that the person on the phone was doing anyway They're just as vulnerable but in a different way.
Rym: Hmm So yeah, you got some news.
Scott: I don't have any news, but I do have a geek bite of this Apple watch I bought.
Scott: so I bought the new Apple watch because they added the 3g the LTE feature right which suddenly made the Apple watch Sound way good and the pebble watch with iPhone at least was declining in quality.
Rym: Meanwhile pebble on Android is great.
Rym: I don't know what I'll do when this thing breaks because I love the hell out of it.
Rym: But I bought a new one and can't get an Apple watch.
Scott: So the Apple watch let's just go over quickly.
Scott: number one They got some problems.
Scott: they have still have not fixed for the actual LTE.
Scott: the reason I bought it still doesn't work.
Scott: Verizon I can't.
Scott: I mean a lot of other people have gotten it to work But I still can't make it work and I contacted Verizon and they said yeah, we know it's a problem.
Scott: We have to fix it with Apple and you'll hear from us when it's fixed.
Scott: I tried it yesterday.
Scott: It didn't work still and I haven't heard from them.
Scott: So Okay, at least I'm not paying $10 a month.
Scott: So, you know, that's okay.
Scott: I'm not paying for the broken part, which is fine.
Scott: But yeah, I guess a lot of the things I had to say about Apple watch are things that are probably true of the first Apple watch.
Scott: so I'm like, I'm not sure about the differences between one two and three because I only had three.
Rym: Yep I never had one and two and the only thing I can confirm is what cuz you had the problem.
Rym: is you also because you Have an Apple device.
Rym: Smart watches that aren't an Apple watch are often crippled in many ways.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the first thing is that The ability to easily change.
Scott: it's like it's annoying that you have to buy an Apple watch band, right?
Scott: You can't just buy a standard watch band.
Rym: But like even my pebble uses right.
Scott: but standard watch bands actually are slightly annoying to remove and put back on What they have.
Scott: that little because you need a little tool.
Rym: I need a little bar standard watch bands have.
Rym: I have one extra one sitting on my desk right here.
Rym: Modern watch bands use this little bar.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's a little bar with a little button I need.
Rym: you need to push the button and it comes off.
Scott: You need a tool to get in there and push the belt out.
Rym: Look that sticks out.
Rym: There's a little button.
Scott: I cannot.
Scott: I've always needed a tool to get it in there.
Rym: push the never had one that looked like that.
Scott: Yeah, it's the one.
Scott: it's the kind I have on my time watch.
Scott: I cannot get it out without a tool I could.
Scott: it's so small and pointy.
Rym: Uh, I can look I can just take it off my pebble or look at that.
Scott: Oh, what happened?
Scott: Anyway, how?
Rym: how did you have trouble with this?
Scott: I've never been able to get one out without a tool.
Scott: they even make a tool the out.
Scott: if you go to the watch shop They'll use a tool.
Rym: No, I just did it right here.
Rym: I'll do it again.
Scott: Put it back.
Scott: How did you have trouble with this?
Scott: I could never get one of those on or off without a tool.
Scott: anyway It's back on.
Scott: Oh Jesus.
Scott: Congratulations.
Rym: Oh, look, I'll take the bottom.
Rym: Oh, it's off.
Scott: The point is is that Apple overcharges hella for these proprietary watch bands like 50 bucks each.
Scott: It's bullshit, right?
Scott: If you go nothing wrong, I know exactly how it works.
Scott: I cannot physically get in there to push the button cuz it's so tiny.
Rym: Okay, that's crazy to me.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I don't have any fingernails either because I bet them all off.
Rym: I'll use my smallest fingernail the one that I busted off.
Rym: Oh, look how it's off.
Scott: Anyway, okay The point is if you go ahead and you go on Amazon you can actually buy Apple watch bands made by other people that aren't Apple for like almost nothing.
Scott: and Actually, it's kind of nice.
Scott: just be changing watch bands like we.
Rym: you mean like I've done.
Scott: for as long as I've worn watches I've never been able to easily change a watch band.
Rym: There's no tool that's needed for this.
Scott: I've always needed a tool.
Rym: Are you?
Rym: I don't think you had the same kind of bar with the button.
Scott: It is.
Scott: It's the same exact kind.
Scott: I I guarantee it.
Rym: this fascinates me Scott.
Rym: Okay, no end.
Scott: The point is you like.
Scott: it's easier to change the app even even if I had a fingernail.
Rym: This be like imagine we had a mutual.
Scott: we get off of this and talk more about Apple watch.
Rym: Imagine if we had a mutual friend like scojo or something and we just learned like he can't take seatbelts off without help Like you just can't do it without a tool.
Rym: There's a little bit.
Scott: if a seatbelt was microscopic Just pop it off and on.
Rym: I literally changed my watch band every time I go running.
Scott: Anyway, I am most people did not change the watch band so easily.
Rym: I'm confident that anyone I hand this watch to without prompting can change the watch band in less than 10.
Scott: Anyway, let's talk about the other parts of the Apple watch.
Rym: besides changing watch band I feel like this is the most important part for you.
Scott: So it has a heart rate monitor That I'm not sure how good it is because I know nothing about heart rates or if my heart what a heart rate should Be.
Rym: so the new pebble and I didn't get was supposed to have that and it doesn't so.
Scott: and it works by basically shining a green Light into your arm and detecting how much light is reflected.
Scott: black because blood Absorbs green light.
Rym: what's what?
Rym: the useful thing about them is don't worry about the instantaneous rate because they're not that accurate.
Rym: Obviously you opt for trending especially feel if you have like Strava Pro Gives you what does it give you?
Scott: it gives you what?
Scott: Walking average resting rate.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: So if those trend upward over a long period of time go to a doctor I don't know I don't.
Rym: if they turn down over a long period of time like a way long period of time also go to a doctor.
Scott: the Battery people are acting like the battery lasts like one day.
Scott: I had the battery last like today.
Rym: That's probably cuz your LTE isn't working.
Scott: It's probably a thing.
Scott: But also here's the thing that's it is bad.
Scott: So I was have the Strava app which works.
Scott: I push play on the watch it starts.
Scott: recording is great.
Scott: Yep, it seems like when I do that and I push start on my watch It doesn't just tell my phone to start Strava ing.
Scott: it actually just the watch does the Strava ing and kills the fucking battery.
Rym: well Cuz the idea is that people who do that want to just cape the watch and know which.
Scott: that would be fine.
Scott: if I Was out there with watch only.
Scott: I would hope that it would say oh my phone isn't nearby.
Scott: I guess I'll have to do the Strava myself with my own GPS and my own LTE.
Scott: But if the phone is nearby, it should say oh the phone is here.
Scott: Let me just tell the watch to do the Strava and save my fucking battery.
Scott: That's what my watch does.
Scott: that is not what the Apple watch does.
Scott: if you push play on the watch It uses the watch and kills the battery.
Scott: So I'm only can push play on the watch in instances where I don't have the phone with me.
Scott: Yeah, that's annoying.
Scott: One good thing is the pebble even on iPhone.
Scott: Let me control music just fine, right?
Scott: And the same thing with Apple watch.
Scott: it lets me control the music on the phone just fine, right?
Scott: It can also play its own music, which I haven't done ever.
Scott: I don't know why you'd want to.
Scott: I guess you've got the wireless headphone.
Scott: you would but I don't have those.
Scott: But there are additional features.
Scott: right the the pebble can only do forward back play pause stop.
Scott: Yeah, the Apple watch when I'm listening to a podcast can do go forward 15 second back for back Right, which is I've used that a ton like Oh podcast advertisement starting 15 second Right without having to get my phone out and then push the button.
Scott: So that's really nice.
Scott: There's I remember the milk app that doesn't really work so well, uh-huh.
Scott: It doesn't synchronize but that's remember the milk's fault.
Scott: One thing that's crazy.
Scott: Good.
Scott: Is that the Apple pay is on the watch?
Scott: Yeah, I went to Dwayne Reed and I just sort of waved my arm and then they gave me stuff.
Rym: Well same thing with the all the passes like when we went the Rangers game.
Rym: Emily's had it on her watch and just boop and got in.
Scott: all the Apple passbook stuff is on the watch.
Scott: So he's like, okay, just walking fast to our garden.
Scott: Like look at my watch.
Scott: Let me in.
Scott: Okay That's like pebble watch.
Scott: Definitely can't do that.
Scott: Not even close.
Scott: But yeah, it does.
Scott: a bunch of you know at the expense of some battery life and some money.
Scott: if you have an iPhone It does a lot fancier better stuff.
Scott: Not everything works perfectly.
Scott: Some of the things are not, you know the greatest but overall it's better than pebble.
Scott: if you have iPhone It just costs a lot of money.
Scott: So if you want those betterness things then and you have money then do it.
Scott: I assume the LTE will be fine once it fucking works.
Rym: Yeah But it doesn't right now because the rally is that having a smartwatch if you go like if you do stuff is a Really useful addition to your life.
Rym: notifications are way more reliable And also which again is only a problem for you with a pebble in the iPhone because they're Lockstep on the pebble with and they're just more reliable.
Scott: I always see them every time.
Scott: but also Better than pebble you can reply to them Most of them anyway, and you can reply to them in very very useful ways, right?
Scott: So if I reply to a text I can like draw on the screen to write words and then push send No way pebble doesn't even have a touchscreen right.
Scott: I can talk which I think pebble can do.
Scott: you can talk at the watch And then it'll turn into text and reply which I can do.
Scott: that But do like any notification like a tweet or a hangout or yeah That's something
Rym: I really want to have because with Google Glass it did that really well And that was one feature of Google Glass I used quite a bit was Responding to things and just talking and it would type the message and I could just send it
Scott: and the custom watch faces And you know I can start.
Scott: you know I usually like if I go do laundry.
Scott: I got to bring my phone to just set a timer so that when I know when the laundry is done I'll just do that on the watch.
Scott: now watch has timer.
Rym: Oh, you mean like my watch does the pebble watch?
Scott: you had to get like an app to be a timer.
Rym: There was always a built-in timer.
Scott: I never used it.
Scott: I guess it worked great.
Scott: actually Didn't integrate with my phone, so I think if I set the timer I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I said a button BAM got a timer.
Scott: I haven't actually tested it.
Scott: I wonder if I set the timer on the Apple watch.
Scott: will the phone ring when it's done?
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I haven't tried it yet, but there is a. there's a nicer timer than pebble watch.
Rym: Yep, but I feel like if you want a smartwatch also It does Siri shit, but I don't use Siri regardless if if you get an iWatch or a non iWatch I feel like if you if you feel like you want a smartwatch at all.
Scott: pretty much now's the time to buy because I don't Think I don't know anything that they seem to have plateaued in their power batteries.
Rym: Processing power and material science together will limit any Significant advancement in the usability of smartwatches for years to come.
Scott: Do not buy official watch bands from Apple.
Scott: They make you buy one.
Scott: you can't get all Apple watch.
Rym: I thought they were supposed to have like logic or something in them, but they don't know.
Scott: it's just a just a band.
Scott: It has little plastic clips at the end of the slide into the watch.
Scott: Yeah I thought they had logic in them which is why they were 50 bucks plus.
Scott: But no So you have to get one because your Apple watch must come with one.
Scott: so pick the Apple watch that comes with the one You like and then buy a whole bunch of them on Amazon.
Scott: Yeah, also I got the.
Scott: I've had a tiny wrist.
Scott: I got these smaller Apple watch.
Scott: I didn't get the bigger one and these watch bands fit way better.
Scott: I'm actually using the third smallest hole and not and not the smallest hole.
Rym: Yeah, I got.
Rym: I use like some Barton.
Rym: I think Burton Barton.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: I buy because I buy this man.
Scott: I just went on Amazon and got whatever.
Rym: I'm in the third smallest hole here.
Rym: when usually I'm always on an extra smallest hole That I've cut myself.
Rym: Yeah, so that's progress.
Rym: Mm-hmm What are our wrists just getting smaller?
Rym: or are we finally being accommodated as a demographic with tiny wrists?
Scott: I just bought the smaller watch the.
Rym: but anyway Things of the day.
Rym: what do you got?
Scott: So there's a. there's in New York City.
Scott: if you're in Queens at least Western Queens and you want to go to Brooklyn These.
Scott: you got to take a bridge because there's some water and there's also a highway and there aren't that many bridges.
Scott: Actually trains the stuff in the way.
Scott: you can't get there without a bridge in Western Queens.
Scott: There's some poisonous water Western Brooklyn and you want to get to.
Scott: nor, you know go north in the clouds.
Scott: There's two bridges.
Scott: There's the bridge we use 90% of the time which is the Pulaski bridge because it's the one that's closest to the water.
Scott: They finally have an awesome.
Scott: It had a shitty bike path that was mixed with pedestrians But now they take away the lane away from the cars and there's an awesome bike But it's so great.
Scott: You can just fly over on your bike.
Scott: We it's the greatest right?
Scott: It's also the closest We can walk there from here.
Scott: It's so close.
Rym: Yep, and it's probably the most used by non carp It's right near Hebrew.
Rym: No, you won't go there, but I think we're gonna cook tonight.
Scott: But I also have left over blue apron.
Rym: But the problem with the Pulaski is that if you're driving it connects busy non freeway roads together.
Rym: It's like normal roads connected.
Scott: Anyway, there's another bridge over to the to the east a little bit called the cuz you go cuz you go.
Scott: let's go something something I can't pronounce.
Scott: I'm sorry bridge cuz co.
Scott: Anyway, Polish, I assume they what they did with this bridge is They replaced some of it with an awesome bridge of modernness that has that new design where there's like a triangle of cables.
Scott: You know the design I'm talking about.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: You see those bridges all over the world.
Scott: It's like the new bridge style.
Scott: It's like they'll trend in bridge design these days, right?
Scott: You don't have a step.
Scott: one comes.
Scott: distance is basically one tower with a bunch of cables instead of two towers, right?
Scott: Anyway And then they have gonna get rid of the old one and then replace the old one with a new one and now have double Bridge.
Rym: because that's the trouble with New York.
Rym: You can't just tear down a bridge and then build a new one because millions of people use that bridge every and they're even gonna have You know bike and pedestrian on there - yeah once that the other one's done.
Scott: So which is gonna be great.
Rym: I biked over there a bunch to watch the construction because there were some big crazy crane things going on over time.
Scott: People have been driving on the new one for a while.
Scott: Oh, yeah for a long time We're gonna blow up the old one and then there's like well actually we're not gonna blow up the old one We're just gonna take it apart carefully.
Scott: It's like I. they get ten minute hauling and delaying and whatever.
Scott: finally yesterday at 8 in the morning, New York time they Energetically felled the old one meaning they blew it up.
Scott: meaning they blew it up Basically, they blew it up in such a way that it would sort of fall apart and then just fall straight down.
Scott: They did a good job.
Scott: It worked.
Scott: I was in bed at 8 a.m But I knew that it was gonna happen at 8 a.m.
Rym: Yep, I thought I'd go watch it and then I didn't because I know I'm getting.
Scott: I'm going over there at 8 a.m on Sunday, but I did Listen, and I didn't even open my window because my window is actually really good at blocking sound.
Scott: No, but I'm like if it's really loud, I'll be able to hear it through the window at 8 a.m.
Scott: I definitely heard like some sort of exploding noise in the distance, even though my windows are closed.
Rym: comment here I felt my apartment shake a mile away in Sunnyside.
Rym: They don't mess around.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: second comment This is a shitty old bridge everyone hated.
Rym: We're happy to see a cow.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: Also that bridge if you like go look at that bridge because you can see it in the video.
Scott: You can see the old one next to the new one.
Scott: Also, this video starts out muted.
Scott: make sure you unmute it before you play it.
Rym: Yeah, because it's it's it's worth it, especially cuz we watch the video.
Scott: You'll see There's many videos of this.
Scott: DJ hammers even made a video of it.
Scott: But this is the best video of this Energetic felling that I have seen.
Rym: but if you think the kuzco bridge looks shitty from a distance I've run under that thing a lot.
Rym: It looks like it's a deathtrap.
Rym: Like it looks almost as bad as the frogs now.
Scott: Yeah, people talk about infrastructure right and how we don't maintain it.
Scott: Well, look, we did it at least in this one tiny spot.
Rym: Hurray and it took a long time to get to this point.
Scott: Yeah, we this is how hard.
Scott: we shouldn't be this hard, but we at least we did something.
Rym: So Scott if you take a polarizer a linear polarizing filter like in sunglasses Mm-hmm, and you hold it up it blocks what percentage of the light?
Scott: Depends on isn't it like dependent rotation and where the lights coming from?
Scott: All right, like if there's glare coming off a window onto your.
Rym: it depends on the phase of the light.
Rym: So let's put it another way.
Rym: if you have one that's oriented say vertically and you put another one that's oriented 90 degrees So it's perpendicular to that one.
Rym: What happens?
Scott: you get zero light.
Rym: That's why if you put on good sunglasses You probably can't read your cell phone screen if you hold it sideways because LCDs are polarized often.
Scott: Oh, well, I think I don't have that problem with my phone But I do have the problem with my monitors.
Scott: if I look at my monitors with sunglasses I can't see anything with my with my cell phone.
Rym: if I turn it 90 degrees I literally cannot see anything.
Rym: because all of my glasses I have them with a vertical polarization, but I digress.
Rym: What happens if you put a third filter in between the two at a 45 degree angle?
Scott: Mmm, it's probably gonna let some light through because the some light gets to the first one and the second one probably messes with the light.
Scott: So the second one messes with it in such a way that some of it will not be at the wrong angle Anymore that the first one put it in so it'll get through the third one.
Rym: But you realize how crazy that sounds.
Rym: you have a thing that you put up and if you put another one in 90 degree angles It blocks 100% of the light.
Rym: but then if you put another filter and the filter cannot add light It can only block light in between those two light gets through again.
Scott: Okay, imagine like a hockey puck.
Scott: right and the hockey puck is horizontal, right?
Scott: Okay, so we set up, you know a slit That's a horizontal slit.
Rym: So let's horizontal hockey pucks through.
Scott: it gets horizontal hockey bucks.
Rym: All vertical ones get blocked, right?
Scott: So the sort of.
Scott: after that the horizontal one goes through and then we have another one that blocks horizontal ones Let's vertical ones and now nothing gets through.
Scott: Yeah, but now imagine if the middle one sort of sends some of the hockey puck.
Scott: No, that's No, some of them will end up vertical.
Rym: No the analogy there would be.
Rym: in the middle of those two you put one that has a. It's the shape of a hockey puck and an angle.
Rym: only angle pucks can get through it.
Scott: No, it knocks him around It's not.
Rym: what do you mean knocks him around?
Rym: Yeah, no.
Rym: so This video because this is something that I've in theory I've known since I took high school physics But I never really.
Scott: also light is not.
Scott: light isn't a wave and a particle so it's all fucked up.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I'm just gonna say when I was a kid and I was in AP physics class We had a similar problem and the teacher was like So why is light this way?
Rym: and I was like because it's both a wave and a particle as light is fucked up.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: He said he said yes, that's true.
Scott: And also that's a stupid answer because that doesn't tell me shit It tells you the light is fucked the fuck up and never does the things that physical things do.
Rym: this video for the first time expresses in sufficient detail while simultaneously avoiding going too deep Why this happens and why it's crazy.
Scott: I have to watch it.
Rym: This video is really good.
Scott: It's minute learn more about particles.
Rym: And yeah, but but it taught it also gets into like.
Rym: it shows you like.
Rym: hey This is what happens.
Rym: So here's something for you Scott.
Rym: What happens if you put like ten filters in between the first one in the last one?
Rym: Depends which ones and well, they're angled and how pretty much all the fucking light will get through now.
Rym: What?
Rym: Yeah And they point out how fucking impossible that is and how basically how does it get?
Scott: Okay So what if I took a vertical one and then a horizontal ones and I know light gets no light gets through.
Scott: then I add Filters after can suddenly light reappear.
Rym: Watch this video.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: The video is like 17 minutes long.
Rym: This is not trivial.
Scott: to explain That'd be like, ah, I can't get through this wall But if you add more walls behind this wall now I can walk through them up.
Rym: the the root of it is is Bell's theorem and it gets into something fascinating where the numbers don't even add up the way you'd expect them to and the conclusion one can make is that there could not be a Variable.
Rym: we don't know about.
Rym: that determines whether or not the filter will block a light particle.
Rym: It cannot there cannot be an answer.
Rym: it must be probabilistic and it does a really good job of explaining Why and also why that question even matters?
Rym: Like of all the minute physics videos because they I love these videos like this is a great channel.
Scott: But a minute physics, I thought you said metaphysics But this one I don't know.
Rym: this one really.
Rym: it helped me with something that's bothered me for most of my adult life.
Scott: Most of his adult life he's laying in bed before bed each night.
Rym: It's like Polarization, you know what?
Rym: so here's what would happen every time I was wearing my Sunglasses out somewhere and I picked up my phone to take a picture and I remembered.
Rym: Oh, I can't see and I did some of this.
Rym: Then I would think about this and it would bother me again.
Rym: Uh-huh So yeah, this is a really good video.
Rym: In the meta moment the book club book is not the first not the second not the sixth But the fifth season.
Rym: I'm gonna finish it hopefully before the next Thursday show.
Rym: How much did you read first chapter?
Scott: Great, it's not that long.
Scott: I finished the whole thing.
Scott: I'll probably read it a long while ago I got some flight.
Scott: I started reading the second one but I held off because I play Metroid video games and also because I don't want to Accidentally mess up my brain because it picks up exactly where the first one ends.
Scott: So I don't want to mess up my brain and mess up the pot.
Rym: We made that mistake with wheel of time because I we both way over in that first book And that colored my perceptions for good or ill.
Rym: yep, but yeah, I got a bunch of flights coming up this coming weekend So I will probably have it done by Thursday.
Rym: Hmm next Thursday, not this Thursday.
Scott: other things actually.
Scott: this weekend None of us will be there or have anything to remotely to do with it.
Scott: But the New York Comic Con is this weekend?
Rym: Yep, I actually met a lot of people who are desperate to get tickets and they're all just buying them from bootleggers Apparently new comic-con or scalpers really newer comic-con is even worse than ever before.
Scott: They're having pre-event lotteries.
Scott: you go online and there's a digital lottery that chooses whether you're gonna get like some exclusive You know swag or go to a panel or something based on these lotteries.
Scott: that happened before the convention even starts.
Scott: I guess Lottery like that because you have to buy tickets from you know, their special, you know, make an account thing.
Scott: So now they're using those accounts to do these other sorts of lottery.
Rym: if Pax's still had the problem where every panel had people waiting three hours plus to get into it and they all filled all the time That would always make sense.
Rym: Just do a lottery right there.
Rym: So no one has to wait for three hours.
Scott: I'm not into it.
Rym: What are you gonna do?
Rym: What's what's the alternative?
Scott: wait for three hours?
Rym: Why why?
Rym: why is that a good answer?
Scott: What's wrong with it?
Rym: So three hours for the panel.
Rym: have everyone show up who wants to go.
Rym: just do a lottery right there.
Scott: Be like you for me the person who shows up and waits the longest the person who wants to see it the most badly All right.
Rym: Well, so what about?
Scott: there's no one for being dumb and waiting wanting to go to that panel so bad.
Rym: What about the situation where there isn't a place to put a line for that long?
Rym: What about the situation when there are three one-hour panels each of which has a three hour line?
Rym: waiting for it in the same place?
Rym: The moral is don't wait in line for stuff at conventions and don't collect stupid swag.
Rym: Oh, yeah well, the real moral is the New York Comic Con is a soul-sucking nightmare that I Despite having free tickets to for years after I stopped going until eventually they stopped offering me the free tickets.
Rym: I didn't even though I could just take the subway right there Literally had no inclination.
Scott: The next invention we are going to is the week before Thanksgiving.
Scott: It is PAX Unplugged unplugged We will be is gonna be so lit.
Rym: Yeah, it weird.
Rym: There's this is all.
Rym: this is our fuck.
Scott: The only thing bad about it is is in stupid, Pennsylvania, but that's a Cancelled out by the fact that is easy to get to.
Rym: it's cancelled out by the fact that it's way Cheaper and easier to take a train to than Boston.
Rym: the hotel cost like a third of what the hotel in Boston would cost And it won't be freezing cold yet like Boston is.
Rym: and we'll see if it has bag checks.
Rym: actually don't know I don't know.
Scott: But anyway, I don't imagine they'll be big enough for bag checks.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Yeah, but it's gonna be Lid for a lot of reasons.
Scott: We'll talk about it a lot more as it gets close The exact same weekend as PAX Unplugged is a convention We would be doing if it wasn't PAX Unplugged.
Scott: and that's anime NYC the first ever anime NYC.
Scott: It looks like we know people who are gonna be there and are working on it.
Scott: so if any anime con you are an anime person and not a Gaming con person and you really want to see an amaze and not tabletop games go to anime NYC.
Rym: it I like.
Rym: it is a who's who of people who know what like.
Rym: they're like the kinds of people Who we are friends with who we'd sit around and talk about.
Rym: man, you know, it's bullshit about the way bad cons are run.
Rym: Yeah, let's run it like packs.
Rym: Well, it's all those people.
Rym: Mm-hmm I can't promise it'll be great.
Scott: But it's the first one and I trust the people.
Rym: Yeah No Anime con that's all I can go has ever had as much of a chance as being the packs of anime cons as this one.
Scott: Any other meta things.
Scott: make sure you come and find us on the internet and all the places that we exist on.
Rym: Scott's YouTube channel has the first episode of our judge anime by its cover series that we're going to continue doing.
Rym: it channels social media networks things Twitter's and our forum our own website front recruit calm a show that I used to appear on a lot a long time ago And I haven't because I've been busy.
Rym: I made a guest appearance on the most recent Friday night party line Which is surprised that still exists.
Rym: third not only they go in strong, but they're on episode 134.
Scott: I'm surprised that still exists.
Rym: Yeah, it was super fun.
Rym: I forgot how much fun it is to be on a podcast where one I don't have to plan shit.
Rym: someone else sends me a list of the topics and If I don't have anything to say I can just sit there and be quiet and someone else has got to say something Speaking of things.
Scott: I've I didn't realize that atomic trivia war 9000 still exists.
Rym: Yeah, it's also pretty late.
Rym: I was on it a while.
Scott: God I was on it some months ago.
Scott: I completely forgot about it until just now.
Scott: it was I think wasn't.
Scott: you were out of town or something.
Scott: Yeah, I was on it and I basically was like, oh that still exists.
Scott: Okay, I'll be on it Okay, and then they I wanted extra hard trivia and they made extra hard trivia.
Scott: But then when it was like actual Zelda trivia, I just toward it toward it When it was trivia, I actually knew it.
Scott: just I was like, oh, okay.
Rym: What is the thing that dodongo dislike it?
Scott: Mmm, is it?
Scott: is it fake smoke?
Scott: Smoke you put in the little electric train.
Scott: So, yeah, uh, what do I bet you'd like to have more of?
Rym: Well, the real answer in my heart is heart containers cookies, but I'll accept more bombs.
Rym: All I gotta say is as a kid I remember when I first met the guy who said I bet you'd like to have more bombs Because I've been so that points like yes, I do bet like.
Rym: up until that point I thought four was like fucking or eight or however is all however many you could get and I would like like.
Rym: I couldn't even imagine the possibility that I could expand that inventory slot like I could.
Rym: my heart.
Scott: Yeah, oh one last thing Murder ball, which is pretty much going way downhill.
Scott: Yeah, not only is it going downhill.
Scott: in general the New York football Giants are oh and four, you know what that means.
Scott: When they they were so close to winning like they lost to two of those games.
Scott: I'm basically last-second field goals, right?
Scott: The game that they just lost.
Scott: I watched like only the very last second of it and I was actually like hoping they would lose.
Scott: Yeah, it was so much better that way.
Scott: But that doesn't matter.
Scott: We're done with murder ball.
Scott: Goodbye murder ball.
Rym: It's time.
Scott: It's time.
Scott: It is I think three days two or three days Until hockey hockey is here.
Rym: Yep I got.
Rym: I gotta see if the Red Wings can recover from their reckoning and If the Rangers can at least make it into the playoffs and put a good show.
Scott: I think Rangers hockey starts in three days and yeah hockey starts in two day.
Scott: So you're probably listening to this on October 3rd, most likely even though we're recording it.
Scott: the night of October 2nd.
Scott: Hockey is probably tomorrow.
Rym: Yep, baby.
Rym: God the first article when I type Rangers hockey is Rangers in danger of underachieving.
Rym: Yeah, it's possible.
Rym: me VC something Kevin a something.
Scott: Yeah, it's entirely possible.
Rym: Yep thing is as old as Lundquist is we got still does those saves?
Scott: Yeah, we got some old people who are now a year older, you know, we got some new people who are untested Yeah, one of whom appears to be a piece of shit.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: Oh, yeah the that guy fuck.
Scott: Yeah, right, but can't be worse than Giants.
Scott: No, no Hockey causes less brain damage than murder ball much less Yeah, in fact, they could eliminate the hitting from hockey and people probably wouldn't give a shit.
Scott: No, let's compare.
Scott: I went to see some roller hockey to take photos of it like a week ago And there's basically no hitting in that roller hockey and it was fucking lit.
Scott: It was oh my god There's no spectators.
Rym: You should come to some NWHL games with us this year.
Scott: Well, they're paying the ass to get out there.
Rym: They're in Jersey.
Rym: Now.
Rym: We stick the path over it.
Scott: I don't have to be asked to get to.
Rym: it's pretty easy.
Scott: I have to go through hell literally to get there.
Rym: Yeah, but then you get some pretty good hockey.
Scott: Bring it to the the.
Scott: I was able to bicycle and pay zero money to see the roller hockey.
Rym: We could bicycle.
Rym: we go up over the GWV.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, that'd be a fun ride.
Rym: No So, yeah, uh, we decided for good or ill.
Rym: I'm just gonna warn you guys cuz this is the first show we've done in October that Regardless of what our topic is for the for this entire month We're gonna force ourselves to try to make it spooky themed Spooky podcast.
Scott: all of October and also as you know, the Halloween is the anniversary of GeekNights.
Scott: The first non beta.
Scott: GeekNights was technically a Halloween episode.
Scott: So we released in 2005 and it is now 2017.
Scott: So this is I guess 12 years cuz.
Scott: 17 minus 5 is 12.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The full story is on November 1st We released the first episode of GeekNights to the public not just to the beta listeners and then the next day I list I've re-listened to the beta episode.
Rym: we've recorded the previous day on the 31st and I decided it was above the line Of quality.
Rym: so I uploaded it and retroactively posted it Mm-hmm, and that is why the first episode of GeekNights was the second one published and that'll be a trivia question someday Somewhere.
Scott: No, it won't be.
Scott: But all right the spooky technology.
Scott: what the hell is spooky about technology.
Scott: This is all you.
Scott: I had the idea, but I don't have.
Scott: I didn't have any actual content, but you wanted to go with it.
Rym: Anyway, I got a bunch of ways that could take this.
Rym: So one time I saw a ghost.
Rym: I was in my office at IBM a long long time ago and There was a problem with the DHCP network on a network that I was ostensibly responsible for.
Rym: Some of the devices on the network could not get IP addresses But some of them could?
Scott: was it out of IP addresses?
Scott: Did it?
Scott: was it like the block was 255 and there was more than that many devices.
Rym: So there was nothing like that.
Rym: like I didn't stop giving out new addresses like I got some logs from the DHCP server Which I administered which so that was easy.
Rym: Yeah, and it had plenty of space and everything was fine.
Rym: then Okay, and there's no like network tickets.
Rym: so I starts to investigate.
Rym: so I go down to the lab and I start going to individual machines and just Trying to do like a release renew or an if config just to see what's going on.
Scott: That sounds good.
Rym: I start with.
Rym: I got all these Linux boxes.
Rym: I deployed all these like Linux thin clients and then it goes came out of the computer and said So what that meant was because I made these machines.
Rym: there was a back door so I could basically go to one and do a thing and enter my credentials and just get a Console and I could just like start fucking around with the network stuff.
Rym: So I started like checking out the DHCP servers working fine.
Rym: So I do a packet capture just in case and everything looks fine.
Rym: Like I see the ad like the DHCP is all happening.
Rym: So the problem is still occurring.
Rym: so then I go to Another one of my thin clients somewhere else on the same like physical network and I do the DHCP renew and it fails.
Scott: It just times out It was too far away from the DHCP server.
Scott: It didn't reach in time.
Rym: So man, I Start going I look behind the computer and I see the wires and I see that there's a wire plugged into the back and there And there's a link light.
Rym: but the link light looks weird.
Rym: so I unplug it and the light turns off and I hear a click.
Rym: I plug it back in and After like four seconds, there's a click and the light turns back on.
Rym: So then I follow the cable and it goes to an adapter to a big fucking token ring connector That's plugged into the wall.
Rym: It was token ring.
Scott: So Spooky token ring.
Rym: the DHCP is not working and it was working before it seems to be on token ring.
Rym: Yeah, okay Token rings a loaded.
Scott: I know the token ring is a lower level of OSI stack and you can do that.
Rym: But I feel like you shouldn't guys go here some terror stories.
Rym: We can talk a lot about mouse multi access units.
Rym: That's the equivalent matter.
Scott: Is that on the same level as token ring?
Rym: That's that is the equivalent of a hub or a switch for token ring, okay, they're really complicated.
Rym: they have relays in them.
Rym: That's the click Literally relays to add the device to the ring or remove the device from the ring physically.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I want to do a packet capture on the actual token ring network to see what's going on.
Rym: There's no way to do that.
Scott: You got to use your trap after you zap it with your pro time.
Rym: So I go to my boss and I say what can I do?
Rym: and he he looks at me.
Rym: He gets this rye smile and he says follow me.
Scott: No, you know the boss knew what to do.
Rym: So he takes me into a part of the data center I've never been but the containment unit and in this room is an EPA guy Dick.
Rym: he hands me a device that looks like a fucking Ghostbusters trap.
Scott: Is it a fluke?
Scott: Is it made by the fluke company?
Rym: No, we had flukes.
Rym: and he says this is the only known device To do packet capture on the token ring network.
Rym: and I say what is it?
Rym: And he says this is a portable computer from before you existed from before 1982.
Rym: I don't know how old they actually are.
Rym: But so he opens it and sure enough this big fucking metal box is actually a computer like this keyboard comes out of it It's got an orange phosphor screen.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and we boot it and it has some packet capture software on it.
Scott: Okay, and it has token ring connectors and this guy is boss actually knew That that's what that was and knew how to use it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Okay, so I take it out there worked.
Rym: so I take it out there and I start doing packet capture a fucking token ring network.
Rym: and I'm looking at the packets and sure enough some of the DHCP requests are working fine and some of them the DHCP server is sending the address back and the machine just isn't acting like it didn't get it At the low level.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I don't understand even with the packet capture I don't understand needs a new token ring card.
Rym: and then I noticed something.
Rym: Some of the packets on the network Were 802.3 frames.
Rym: Some of the packets on the network were ethernet two frames Mm-hmm.
Rym: the old devices were using ethernet.
Rym: to the new devices like the DHCP server we're using 802.3 and The old devices were incapable of handling both formats.
Rym: And if you need to know the details of what the difference is between those two.
Rym: fuck you that is so not Interesting and I don't want to talk about it.
Scott: But did with the packet capture machine.
Scott: How did that one do?
Rym: I guess you didn't give a fuck?
Rym: Oh, I guess you're was like, here's the packets.
Rym: Okay and I was looking at the bytes and it was decos decoding the headers.
Rym: and that's when I noticed because I forget.
Rym: but there's like a length field in Ethernet.
Rym: no in 802.3 But there's a type field at the same byte location and ethernet - I don't fucking remember.
Rym: This was a long goddamn time ago to do that again, but I really want to see that capturing computer.
Rym: I'll try.
Rym: I might have taken a picture of it.
Rym: I'll try it.
Rym: I'll try to find that.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: But yeah, I think you had a phone with a camera.
Rym: then Uh, I had a phone with a camera that I was not allowed to bring anywhere because you couldn't have phones in the facility.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Also, you know, I taken a picture with that camera.
Rym: I could not have gotten the picture off my phone.
Rym: Mm-hmm, cuz I didn't have the weird cable.
Rym: So you don't have a picture of it, but I might have taken a picture with my fucking actual camera.
Rym: okay, cuz I took pictures of stuff cuz Working at IBM.
Rym: that was like a crazy world of ancient technology.
Scott: So the ghost maybe we can just search for token ring packet capture and find a picture of it.
Rym: So yeah, that was what I was one Avenue I had to take with this show of tell IT troubleshooting stories like they're ghost stories.
Scott: Yeah, you added no ghost in this whatsoever.
Scott: only I did and it was only bad jokes.
Rym: It was it was more just the scare the the investigation of and then I opened the door and there was a missing cable.
Scott: I don't have any scary Technology stories really.
Scott: here's my scary technology story, right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Here's there.
Scott: Yeah, it's real scary, right?
Scott: So when I was in kindergarten, there was Apple - oh Baby that.
Scott: and I said when I saw that Apple - I said, you know what?
Scott: I've never seen that before but every minute you let me touch that and go touch that.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, and I was so excited to do computer.
Scott: I was like, oh baby computer, right.
Scott: and then for my whole life all the way even even when I had a computer in high School and even in college the internet was so fast.
Scott: Oh my god I just wanted a computer any second I could computer even when it was like news.
Scott: I got to use some shitty old Solaris machine in the CS lab at alright.
Scott: I was so excited to just use a different kind of computer.
Scott: It was novel.
Scott: I could learn something about it.
Scott: Oh, man, and then after actually having a job where I have to sit a computer for eight hours a day every day I Don't want to sit a computer no more and life is lame and Everything is gone.
Scott: And that's the scariest thing of all.
Rym: All right I think it was.
Rym: it might not have been this exact one, but it was kind.
Rym: it was a compact 386 of some kind.
Scott: Okay, so it's not that old.
Scott: No, I'm just.
Scott: I've seen those.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You could even run Windows on that 20 megahertz on a 386.
Rym: That seems right.
Rym: had a floppy drive.
Rym: Yeah supports Windows 31.
Rym: We did.
Rym: the windows was not on this thing.
Scott: No, you could play doom on that easily.
Scott: Easy doom easy doom.
Rym: I think the ISA bus had the token ring card in it.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Oh I say yeah, I say bitches PCI came way.
Scott: Everyone now has like your computer has like a PCI Express maybe more than one of them for the.
Scott: that's x16 for your video card And you might have an X and it has some regular PCI Express's.
Scott: back in the day We had ISA and PCI and then they added PCI.
Scott: It was like, holy shit.
Rym: and then AGP and then AGP had a bunch of different flavors and also AGP had three different mutually incompatible voltage standards.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you could.
Rym: you could fuck up a computer bad if you messed up with AGP.
Rym: Mm-hmm ISA card.
Rym: so when I had my old kid, here's a. here's a horror story for the young kids today.
Rym: Computers used to not have any way to connect them to networks.
Scott: So yeah motherboards today have like Ethernet cards built in and some of them even have Wi-Fi built in.
Scott: Used to be.
Scott: you had to buy an Ethernet card.
Scott: Yeah or buy a modem.
Scott: I had a u.s.
Scott: Good I love modem good.
Rym: You had an RS-232 and maybe a parallel port you could plug shit into.
Rym: yeah, and So when I got when we had a modem a 33-6 modem and before that we had a 2400 baud modem We had a 14-4 modem, but then I got a 56 came up.
Rym: Oh, I never had a 56 K.
Scott: 14-4 to 56 K. I basically was always one step ahead like everyone else had a 386 and I got a 46 of the 14-4 modem and then everyone else had a Pentium 2 and I got a Pentium 3 with a TNT 2 and a 56 K modem and I was like I was always one step ahead.
Rym: See we had the 2400 baud modem that I used.
Scott: of course The thing is was I really one step ahead or was I actually just buying a computer one year after everyone else?
Scott: Yeah, everyone else had Pentium twos.
Scott: Well, I had a 100 megahertz And then a year later, I'm like, alright enough of that.
Rym: But so the reason I didn't upgrade to a 56 K from a 33-6 is because Cable modems like early as beta cable modems got rolled out to my whole neighborhood.
Scott: Yeah, we I don't think we could have got.
Rym: I had a cable modem.
Scott: way There are people in town who had them but we did not have one.
Rym: So when he got a cable modem, we needed to plug an Ethernet into the computer and didn't fucking have that.
Rym: So we only had one PCI card in the one PCI slot in the computer.
Rym: So we got an ISA network card.
Rym: Oh I had a PCI network card But we also already had because I upgraded because I was really into music production even way back then.
Rym: So my parents like as a huge gift got me an all 32 sound card Which was also ISA.
Scott: In that Pentium 3 I got a Sound Blaster Live.
Rym: Yeah, Sound Blaster Live I bought for RIT Mm-hmm, and that actually was kind of in retrospect the Sound Blaster Live was kind of a piece of shit.
Rym: Yeah But the Sound Blaster 16 I had before that was way better, but it was fully backward compatible with the old Sound Blaster stuff Yes, which mattered to no one unless they did.
Rym: MIDI pretty much mattered when I had DOS.
Rym: Yeah Yeah that too.
Scott: It mattered when I ran Linux in 1999.
Rym: but the horror story is when I got broadband if I was downloading a file or Visited a website While I was playing music through Winamp because of the nature of the ISA bus the music would stutter as packets came in over the network card.
Rym: So I had to do some shenanigans to upgrade to get around that problem and none of you will ever experience that nightmare.
Rym: Wow, the show's almost gone.
Rym: in an hour we could just stop.
Scott: I don't have like.
Scott: I mean I had the idea to do a show with spooky technology stories But I don't actually have spooky technology stories.
Rym: I have a bunch that are only spooky in the sense of problems that couldn't be reproduced that were agonizingly difficult.
Scott: I'm sure there might have been one of those and I may have discussed them on the episode of E-ignites around the time they happened.
Scott: if they happened within the past 12 years or I've just completely forgotten them because my memory is and I don't remember any of that worthless nonsense.
Rym: Yep, whatever are the other way we could have gone with?
Rym: the show is talking about.
Rym: we thought about talking about technology That scares us.
Scott: like the problem is not a lot scares me nuclear technology like nuclear weapons.
Scott: Yeah, don't just don't go near it and don't use it on me.
Rym: Yeah What about all the stuff in the show Black Mirror like the technology that might fuck up society and/or us?
Scott: I mean, I haven't watched that show but I've read enough sci-fi things and I'm not really scared of them.
Rym: Yeah, but they are scary even if not to us personally.
Scott: Yeah, I mean There's people out there who are scared of like, you know cute bunnies, even though they're not scary.
Scott: That does that mean that cute bunnies are scary?
Rym: Yeah, all the people who aren't afraid of bunnies and Monty Python and the Holy Grail we saw it happen to them.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I Think we need to stop.
Scott: Yeah, I think so.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the spooky patreon patrons for this episode of youth nights are I Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette a shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Rym: My steady calm.
Rym: Jeremy minor a genuine bona fide electrified six-car monorail.
Rym: Matthew Smith Nicholas Brandau captain jingu Akasi Rebecca Dunn 421 creations.
Rym: they would have two bases in the middle of a box can.
Rym: Shervin von Horl rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy.
Rym: Rym says something funny here.
Rym: sailor Vista Don Schleich Kajar, Tava shin Joe Shiro Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perry drew open lander Brian Sidroni in Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn and Now I leave you In your bed I
Scott: Hate.