Rym: It's Tuesday August 15th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights side.
Rym: We're talking about Namco museum on the Nintendo switch.
Rym: Let's do this This past weekend.
Rym: We spent probably our last summer beach day because Pax is coming real soon, and it's also cold and rainy.
Rym: Yeah, it's like there was.
Rym: basically we had this window of one day where we could go to the beach in a while.
Rym: Just because weekends have been busy And it's actually been not the best beach weather We stayed on that beach as long as we possibly could.
Scott: we got back to that ferry as it was pulling.
Rym: Yeah, you guys like roll it.
Rym: cuz we rolled up ahead to throw away all our stuff in the dumpster.
Scott: I would have made it sooner, but someone was slow.
Scott: Yeah, but that happens We could have left early.
Rym: Yeah, we could have but we were on the beach.
Rym: If no one wanted to leave the beach you couldn't wait for the next ferry - yeah We are already like we packed up already unbeached.
Rym: If you're gonna let's stay for the second ferry.
Rym: cuz that's two more hours.
Rym: You've got a commit to staying at the beach that two extra hours.
Rym: Otherwise.
Rym: There's no point plus.
Scott: Oh, I need to go home.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I got stuff to do for packs.
Scott: I still haven't even done laundry.
Rym: I did a big loader yesterday.
Scott: cuz the way to clean my kitchen and living room, but the bedroom is a problem.
Rym: I can do laundry pretty well while I play Civ 6. and so my first news Civ 6 if you weren't paying attention got a big update.
Scott: Oh, some people are playing that game still.
Rym: yeah, so I played it again and It's hard though.
Rym: So I didn't fully read the release notes because I didn't realize there was a patch.
Rym: I just started playing Civ 6 kind of out of nowhere because the Civ 5 games that I'm playing with the patrons are going pretty well.
Rym: The Civ 5 game I'm playing with our friends is not going well.
Rym: You are all monsters.
Scott: Yeah, get them.
Rym: the entire world is ganged up on me.
Scott: All right, listen to Scott.
Rym: finally Jesus Christ all of the world Jesus versus tiny Peaceful enlightened Portugal Just wants evil Rym going down.
Scott: It's only the real world would unite against evil the same way that that great world of civilization has united against evil.
Rym: Portugal Rym to go never at once violated a treaty in good faith.
Rym: did not invade Germany on.
Scott: We're like victory-seeking.
Rym: I attack our hungry.
Rym: The true danger the menace on the eastern horizon Western horizon the menace of Ethiopia and Lisa.
Scott: good job people.
Scott: now Nobody turned your back on the rest of the United World, right?
Scott: You need to remain united until the threat of Rym to go has been 100% completely Just like the threat of scotch a goal was annihilated.
Rym: Only hope grasp my mummified heart and understand the true danger.
Rym: If you don't unite with me now in my great ordeal to destroy Ethiopia y'all are fucked.
Scott: You can get Ethiopia after Rym is dead.
Rym: No, if you know if you wait too long It's it's a lost cause because Ethiopia is equal.
Rym: if not actually if Ethiopia fully uses her continent Ethiopia is undefeatable.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: that's fine.
Scott: Cuz at Rym doesn't win as long as Rym doesn't win.
Scott: It's okay.
Rym: I just want to point out that you got rolled by the AI and Lisa like right away.
Scott: I don't know how to play sieve too many stuff in sieve.
Scott: They got to simplify an abstract.
Rym: But it's easy to forget how long ago Because I started upload I over to the first video of like turn hundred when James was still in the game in England How thoroughly I rolled him.
Rym: and I would just point out as much as you might say I'm evil.
Rym: No one could blame me for invading England.
Rym: You would have done it.
Rym: Anyone would have done it.
Scott: I don't invade I just build.
Scott: I just build stuff.
Rym: Scott if your neighbor had three nice cities One composite Archer and the great library and nothing else not even walls.
Rym: What would you do?
Scott: I keep.
Scott: I just like happily peacefully building my shit.
Rym: Why not just have?
Scott: it was a no war version of sieve where everyone just could only build settlers and workers And buildings and you couldn't build any military units.
Scott: That would be the best game.
Rym: That's just playing Sim City next to other people.
Rym: I know Yeah But so I started playing Civ 6 just like for a few hours not a warlike person.
Scott: I am NOT evil like Rym to go.
Rym: I'm not evil.
Rym: I'm simply Appropriately bellicose to the time and circumstance of my civilization is back.
Scott: Is it portrait Rym?
Rym: Yeah, I think it.
Rym: Rym to go is better.
Rym: But I started playing Civ 6 and it just felt better.
Rym: like I. all I could think to myself was wow I remember being pretty harsh on this UX and UI but it's actually feeling pretty good.
Rym: Maybe I was?
Rym: no they actually changed it and I just didn't notice.
Rym: this patch that came out recently Actually made a lot of subtle changes that combined just make the game feel so much better.
Rym: The notifications are way more apt so you don't miss stuff.
Rym: The game just feels like really right that kind of thing.
Scott: Yeah Like the game just tells you it's like I want to play it.
Scott: But the problem is I want to play all the games and I only have time for so many games Time for other stuff.
Scott: I want to do this not games.
Scott: and then it's like how can I invest in a game that takes like Half a day to play.
Rym: Yeah, but it was so fun.
Rym: Like I got into that city.
Scott: so fun.
Scott: But it's like there are also other things that are so fun.
Rym: How do I choose if I didn't have a job?
Rym: I probably pay place if a lot more.
Scott: Yeah, if I didn't have a job I could do all the things I want to do and the job takes 40.
Scott: I probably get a majority of my waking hours every week are spent at job.
Scott: So doing this one stupid thing I just want to sit when I could be doing many great things.
Rym: I want to sit on a beach with a surface book Just playing save and every now and then saving my game and going swimming.
Rym: But yeah, so you can read the change notes.
Rym: But they made a ton of changes and most of them are actually really minor balance changes to individual saves and they added new saves like Aqueducts are 30% cheaper and sewers are 50% cheaper.
Rym: districts as a whole or 10% cheaper Like they just made the game.
Scott: cheaper is good because you can do more stuff.
Rym: It's more cuz it felt it always felt like it took too long to build takes too long to build everything But they calm that down like military units would take like a couple turns and anything.
Scott: I didn't like building military.
Scott: I like building buildings and they take for a fucking ever.
Rym: They also fixed a lot of stuff with the AI.
Rym: So if you're gonna win the game Even if the AI is like by its rules super friendly because you've been super friendly to it It'll get increasingly aggressive if you're actually on track to win, which is probably good.
Rym: I feel like our eyes our human eye friends and that's if game should not have done this.
Rym: and again If you guys you're all evil and I hope you burn in hell once Ethiopia destroys you after you invade me.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: that's fine But like the combat preview just like works way better.
Rym: So like, you know A unit that you gave a long set of orders to like ten turns of moving.
Rym: if you hover over it It'll show you what it's gonna do.
Rym: all these little things added up to where the game is just way more pleasant to play.
Scott: Well, these are all things that you know are a symptom of games, you know getting released before they're super super super polished.
Rym: Yeah in the old days These are the things that you had doing like the last six months of.
Rym: you know.
Scott: Other people are releasing their games and calling it early access and some people aren't.
Scott: but when sim six is released It was basically, you know, what was the difference?
Scott: because they didn't call it early access.
Scott: It counts as released.
Scott: It's like it's just names for the same thing.
Scott: Yep, you know, whatever.
Rym: But yeah.
Rym: so if you Mables mean nothing.
Rym: if you haven't played civ6 in a while right about now is a good time to just poke at it because you might find it a lot more pleasant or Wait a little bit longer and maybe it'll be even cheaper.
Scott: a nice bundle occlude everything.
Rym: I just buy Civ games when they come out.
Scott: I can yeah, I bought every sieve when it came out since sieve three.
Rym: Yeah, I pirated sieve - because back then I didn't really understand Siva - I'm sim - I bought but I didn't get it.
Scott: as soon as it was released It was like I went to copy us a
Rym: friend of my parents like this like this other dad literally just like gave us a CD That I'd save on it and he was just like hey install this on your computer It's pretty good
Scott: a CD with the real book and everything.
Rym: Yeah, I never.
Rym: I never had the book.
Rym: I just look like xcom.
Rym: I just learned the game from trial and error.
Rym: I never saw an instruction book.
Scott: I saw.
Scott: the only way time I saw the xcom instruction book is the PDF on Steam.
Rym: Oh, yeah I never saw it as a kid and I never heard the sound.
Scott: yeah pro tip if you got games on Steam They do have instruction manuals.
Scott: They're on Steam.
Scott: you go to the Steam page and on the right side There's all these links that have tons of info including like soundtracks PDFs, etc, etc.
Scott: And it's it's not.
Scott: it's somewhat not super obvious, but they're all there.
Scott: You should check them out especially for old games.
Scott: in related news There are civilization board games off and on but there is a well There's a lot of games that are like they're effectively sieve the board game like through the ages Yeah, and then there's a lot of games that are actually branded Civilization.
Scott: there's a few of those full disclosure.
Rym: I have never liked any of these games.
Rym: I've never enjoyed them.
Rym: I like through the ages, but no I'm gonna use the word that Luke crane I think it might be is one of his most hated words on earth, but they're too fiddly.
Rym: They don't buy.
Scott: actual sieve isn't too fiddly which even though it's way more for actual save is way more fiddly.
Rym: But most of the fiddling is semi-automated or fully automated by the game.
Scott: You still have to think about it.
Scott: Yeah in this you have to think about a lot less cuz.
Scott: this you know.
Rym: yeah But I don't want to play a card that says and I quote move even to each of your caravans up to four spaces.
Rym: They can move into spaces matching this slots terrain or lower.
Rym: Your caravans can move into barbarian spaces.
Rym: if you move over a caravan in barbarian space defeat that barbarian without gaining a trade token.
Scott: Right.
Scott: so this?
Rym: I do not want to parse all that text.
Scott: That's because this particular civilization game is Published by fantasy flight, and this is a kind of crap.
Scott: Oh game.
Scott: They make it's.
Scott: you could tell it's a Literally pictures of art from the game Fantasy flight game.
Rym: right away you see this on a table, and you're like that's fantasy flight.
Rym: Yeah, or someone's ripping off fantasy flights is no they're publishing it So you can skip this one.
Rym: probably look at all these pieces to prove It's good, but this game on my prediction is the game has a lot of complexity that does not translate into a lot of strategic Thinking.
Rym: no and there will be numerous rules parsing issues.
Rym: Oh, yeah No, yeah, it appears to be multiplayer like four sieves.
Rym: I just can't.
Rym: if you want to play a game play eclipse No, or dope.
Rym: if you want to play a game that gives the feels of sieve play tempest.
Scott: mmm temp actually actually abstracts Eclipse.
Rym: yeah, you keep every turn.
Rym: What do you want to do?
Rym: walk around?
Rym: Sit and think make some babies fight with somebody.
Rym: build a city like that's your options.
Scott: Make babies every turn.
Rym: make babies every turn is not the worst strategy sometimes.
Rym: That's my real-life strategy.
Rym: Oh yeah, people are.
Rym: people are talking about how this is basically a port of sieve six and Not feeling this at all the more I look at it
Scott: You know just because it had people get in this trap where because something has an intellectual property license that is associated with some sort Of goodness well that like they had that they suddenly now you're paying attention with.
Scott: if that board game didn't have a sieve license It wouldn't even be on your radar.
Scott: You wouldn't know it existed You never talked about it.
Scott: that just because it has this license and intellectual property trademark on it suddenly It becomes news on GeekNights.
Scott: right you have to escape this idea.
Scott: right stop paying attention to things Just because there's some license attached to it.
Rym: well I mean remember the.
Scott: It's like some crapo dice game, and they put a picture Luke Skywalker on it and suddenly whoa Everybody remember those adventure time games.
Rym: because on the done that what the DS.
Scott: Yeah, that's a perfect is.
Rym: those games were Garbage weren't?
Rym: the more I think about him.
Rym: like they're they're bad.
Rym: They're worse than some of the games in the Namco Museum We're about to talk about like.
Rym: they're the worst and even worse.
Scott: those games It's like a platform or someone made in a weekend like the first level of those games seems like okay.
Rym: This is like this could become a decent game if I keep playing it and then everything after the first level is just increasingly garbage.
Rym: So yeah, I would skip this game unless the reviews are somehow really good from people like us.
Rym: If we come back and say this game is good.
Scott: I guarantee it's good It's got a lot to prove.
Rym: yeah, if we don't come back and if we never talk about this game again never buy this game.
Rym: So uh how about that dota bot?
Scott: yeah, so the dota international?
Scott: What seven I think was the seventh one I don't know a team liquid one, which I guess yay.
Scott: They're cool.
Rym: Whatever I hear their name enough to where I recognize them.
Scott: Yeah, there's a guy who's on team liquid.
Scott: I watch play Hearthstone all the time this Finnish dude and He the thing is he doesn't seem to compete in eSports very much But he has like a team liquid chair, and he's on the team, and he makes.
Scott: he sells.
Scott: You know he makes money and whatnot, but he doesn't do any eSports, so I'm like how does that work?
Scott: Imagine if I was only the New York Rangers, but I didn't like he.
Scott: I just sat around at home and made hockey streams All day, but I wasn't actually in the NHL or any league not even a minor league Somehow like get it.
Scott: I got a jersey.
Scott: people buy it.
Scott: I'm it's so weird right.
Scott: I don't know how that works But anyway One of the things that they do you know they don't just have the tournament there They have other events there.
Scott: and one of the things they had was they had this AI bot set up and the bot Was very limited right.
Scott: it played only one hero and all it did was solo mid.
Scott: and they were like if you can beat this bot Then you can you know you get a prize or whatever.
Scott: and there were some pro players who basically got destroyed by this bot Because they played it at its own game.
Scott: They went into the middle And they did the things that it had been trained to beat which you know go to the middle and fight.
Scott: But people quickly figured out after a little bit of practice like oh this bot is really honed in on doing this one thing It can't really do anything else.
Scott: if you do this You'll confuse the hell out of it, and then you can sort of just win and get the prize.
Rym: So everyone collected the prize on yeah, but before anyone says yeah, the MOBAs are so complicated.
Rym: This is why bots will never be good at it.
Rym: I want to remind you that it wasn't that long ago when there is that AI that could beat people at poker But it can only beat people at like two-player limit poker.
Rym: and people were like yeah, Texas Hold'em No limit is so different, and then the bots were like yeah, no fuck you humans They'll never be good at poker again.
Rym: ever like that happens so quick.
Rym: Same thing's gonna happen here because the problem with MOBAs is that bots are almost like wait isn't there still online poker for real money?
Scott: Still a thing.
Rym: yeah, I'm pretty sure a eyes are just going to ruin that space real quick.
Scott: But why can't I shouldn't I just do that right as soon as I get home get the best poker AI and just Hook it up to the online poker?
Scott: I don't know like a hundred bucks in there and then come home to like a million bucks.
Rym: I don't know all the details, but it's this team at CMU is the article I remember.
Scott: give me why are they using their code to make free money with online folks?
Rym: I assume they are because.
Rym: otherwise why would you make a poker AI?
Scott: Give me I can run it on a computer - why don't I deserve free tell you what guys.
Rym: I'll pay for the Amazon server to run It.
Scott: I'll pay for whatever.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: I'll give the initial bidding money and the run the server.
Rym: I'll just take my portion of the free money I think is if I were them I'd run the bar for a while And I would sell the bot to everybody at the same time.
Scott: yeah, but and everyone's running the bot yeah, and then what?
Scott: well It should run the bot against itself and see what.
Rym: how it does I Guess theoretically.
Rym: theoretically if there were any come down to luck of which has the best car in a game that had perfect Perfect AI that was optimal and perfect.
Rym: and let's skip all the like game theory ramifications of that and the the impossibilities of you Know deterministic world yeah, it would just be random at that point.
Scott: hmm Then I could just put money in a slot machine.
Rym: Yeah, yeah slot machine.
Scott: What have we made?
Scott: a slot machine that paid out fairly?
Rym: What do you mean fairly?
Scott: Well because like a slot machine is programmed in such a way to pay out such that no matter how much even if you get Lucky, you're not gonna make more money than you put in over time.
Scott: No, we can make a slot machine that pays out even money over time Instead of always my house winning over time.
Rym: Why would I ever have that slot machine?
Scott: It'll be fun.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I guess we could.
Rym: just I could have one in my house mmm, but I probably just rig it cuz.
Rym: But yeah.
Rym: so with MOBAs the skill that is primarily being tested in MOBAs is not the Overall strategy of what your team is gonna.
Scott: There's a lot of different skills on it Yeah, but a multi it's a multidisciplinary game.
Rym: well as we saw this bot is really good at like the close-in tactic.
Rym: So have a widely different strategy, and it just flails.
Rym: doesn't know what to do.
Scott: It hasn't been trained yet, though eventually it'll be trained to do everything.
Scott: yeah To buy items at the item shop.
Scott: I don't think it knows how to you know.
Rym: change the parts of dough of MOBAs that are the hardest for humans to deal with.
Rym: Are the things that bots can do trivial?
Scott: That's the things.
Rym: perfect.
Rym: last hitting no matter what Frame perfect input on any attack.
Rym: if you're gonna gank and you use a power and you get frame perfect the last Pixel of your range get someone.
Rym: that's the shit that humans mostly only do by luck or extreme skill that bots can do Trivial and the bot will do it every single shot.
Scott: Yeah, every time non-stop right and so like a speed run where it's like.
Scott: Oh here comes a frame perfect part It's like.
Scott: no every single frame is frame perfect.
Scott: the whole game also.
Rym: I set of body game is 40.
Scott: what the game is 40 minutes long 60 FPS with 60 times 40 24,000 I think.
Scott: great perfect inputs six 2,400. every single one of those frames will be frame perfect.
Rym: now.
Rym: But there's the the skill of humans communicating with you.
Rym: They're on a team to coordinate.
Rym: the bots can communicate faster than humans can communicate if they're allowed to communicate.
Rym: Well humans can talk to each other.
Rym: let the bots talk over a microphone.
Rym: They'll come up with the language.
Scott: the bots don't communicate with each other through a communication channel.
Scott: They'll be able to communicate to each other with their movements in the game.
Rym: Yep so It'll be real interesting to see when we get to the point.
Scott: Why did that Bob buy that item sell that item and then buy a different item?
Scott: oh it was signaling to the other bot.
Rym: Yeah I wonder what'll happen to MOBAs as a sport if there are perfect Ai's that are better than all humans no matter what.
Rym: because you can say those by AI's don't exist in the real tournament space.
Rym: We're only watching the humans compete, but I feel like the bot competitions would be more interesting to watch.
Scott: yeah I want to see race.
Scott: car races where there's no drivers is who can make the best car AI.
Rym: and also There's a there's precedence in the battle of engineering only and not athleticism.
Rym: We know a possible endgame because chess is facing this problem right now, right?
Rym: So you can't just have a eyes and the chess tournaments because humans cannot beat a eyes just it's over right in chess.
Rym: So what happened now is that it's humans only in the tournaments.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: the humans study what the bots are doing Because that is the height of chess.
Scott: yes It's easy to study what a bot does in a fucking turn-based game.
Scott: You can't study what a bot does in a real-time game.
Scott: I mean you can study.
Scott: you can study some of its broader strategies like oh see how it does this.
Scott: But you can't be framed perfect for.
Rym: but the end result of this is that chess matches are increasingly ending in draws Because the attractors in chess are more often draws than defeats.
Rym: So it's easier to draw a game out forever.
Rym: Rather than wait like you can't win because the against an AI because it'll always beat you you might be able to force a draw.
Rym: So against a human you're almost better off always going for the draw unless the other person fucks up and the meta of chess is getting real fucked up before someone gets bad.
Scott: at my math a 40-minute game that is 60 FPS would be a hundred and forty four thousand frames.
Rym: All right 144 thousand frame perfect inputs.
Rym: Yep beat that beat that soloing mid.
Rym: So in some other news we've talked about this off and on.
Rym: knit hog was not the best.
Scott: Why are we even talking about this?
Scott: Well, because now it's just Rym's obsessed with it.
Rym: Well, cuz now it's.
Rym: I really like the original lid hog for a lot of reasons They don't - is actually out now and I thought to myself I should buy it.
Scott: No play it.
Scott: so I when we first saw screenshots of the game was hideous and ugly.
Scott: when we saw an action It was nothing like knit hog one and it was even more hideous and more ugly.
Scott: Yeah, every indicator is that.
Scott: yes, it's hideous and ugly But also nothing like knit hog one and a bad game and not a good game.
Scott: The only way it seems to have improved over knit hog one is the netcode is better.
Scott: So at the same time cream still wants to buy.
Scott: remember what more do you need to know?
Scott: So remember there's good games you could be buying.
Rym: So remember Mario Kart or like Mario Tennis when it came out on the DS or the 3ds or whatever.
Rym: Every single no one reviewed the parts of the game that I cared about.
Rym: like No, I read a bunch of reviews of Mario Tennis and to this day I think we're literally the only people who pointed out that the last incarnation of Mario Tennis was a fundamentally different game.
Rym: Like core mechanics were changed that made it not like timing didn't matter at all.
Rym: Like there's all these things that changed that no one reviewed it talked about and I have not found anyone who reviewed knit hog.
Scott: You don't need to talk about the details of a game when all you need to tell people is don't buy this don't play it.
Scott: The details of a game are only we're talking about if the game is worth playing and worth thinking about.
Rym: So I have not yet read a review that mechanically talked about the impact of The changes to the game on whether or not it's good like no one Significant or important and a game that you shouldn't buy right?
Rym: What's bad about it out - Okay, so first of all there than the fact that it's ugly as shit, right?
Scott: So knit hog one was all about like, you know, you got all you have is a sword, right?
Scott: And you can throw it and you can you know up down stabby stabby, right?
Scott: It was all this sort of like, you know clever movements and such and such right?
Scott: Like the core of what a fighting game is.
Scott: Whereas knit hog - there's all these different weapons and it's sort of like a smashy-smashy game and it's not Subtle and elegant in the way.
Rym: need how but why?
Rym: what exactly about the mechanics?
Scott: I I want I haven't played it and I'm not gonna play it to find out cuz it's not worth it.
Rym: But that's the thing.
Rym: no one who refused these kinds of games talks about that stuff in detail because they're smart enough to Spend their time when they're playing a shitty game.
Scott: They don't think about it that hard.
Scott: It's not worth investing the short time in your life into something bad to figure out it.
Rym: But it might be good.
Rym: and my point is no it's not.
Scott: I guarantee it's not.
Rym: I mean it might not be.
Scott: the problem is it's definitely not.
Rym: literally no one who's reviewed This game has talked about it in that detail.
Rym: good But it might be you don't know.
Rym: you're just sort of assuming a lot of things.
Rym: I think you're primarily you wanna bet on it.
Rym: I think you're primarily prejudice against this game because I hate the art and I hate the anime.
Scott: if knit hug - is a good game Right, then I will pay for it.
Rym: But if you pay are you buying it out - I'll buy a pal I'll buy with a page around money for one.
Rym: I'm not finding with my money.
Scott: Oh, oh, that was gonna be.
Scott: look at what Rym's wasting your money on fucking nidhag - he won't let me waste it.
Scott: I'd like a trip to some tropical island.
Scott: You buy.
Scott: if you buy nidhag - which you shouldn't do and it's actually good I will then pay for it.
Scott: So it doesn't cost you anything, but if you buy nidhag - and it sucks as I said, it sucks Yeah, you then also give me the price of nidhag - in my head and you stand you also.
Scott: so basically you had to pay Double what it cost.
Scott: thing is once to me and one to the creators.
Rym: I do worry that it sucks, but I have no mechanical verification of that and all the people who say it sucks.
Rym: Well, what a lot of people say it's great, but the people who say it sounds great.
Rym: I've reviews are pretty good.
Rym: This rock-paper-shotgun review is the only Negative review from a legit outpost I can find and it's not even that negative.
Scott: What a review of you read.
Rym: I read a whole bunch today because I wanted to talk about this tonight.
Rym: I was just skimming through.
Scott: Why do you want to talk about this baggie?
Rym: Cuz you Also, I'd say that it's still a lot better than that civ6 board game.
Scott: Well, that's not saying much.
Rym: and also like people don't review games Mechanically anymore mostly good game to review mechanically something worth thinking about.
Rym: Well, I think we're gonna review investing time.
Rym: We're gonna talk about pac-man verse again in a little bit cuz it's back.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So this is probably the biggest other news that we got.
Rym: so for honor.
Scott: I know I knew that there was a game called for honor.
Scott: I knew nothing else about it.
Rym: It's a game that looks moderately fun But the gist at first I mean I have not actually played it.
Scott: Is it an FPS or a third person?
Rym: This stuff how do you not like talk to an old person to read the Internet?
Scott: What kind of game is it?
Rym: So usually you really don't know.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: So imagine that you didn't know either before a few days ago.
Rym: No, I knew because I've seen a whole bunch of memes about this game and people talk about this game.
Rym: I saw a lot of people on Twitter.
Scott: I've never heard.
Scott: I only knew.
Scott: I knew there was a game called for honor.
Scott: I knew nothing else about it until this news in which now I know that a thing happened to the for honor tournament But I still don't know what kind of game so imagine like Combat kind of like Dark Souls, but not that crazy.
Rym: a third-person walk around hit things game, but no no, but it's a fighting game.
Rym: It's like 2v2 or 4v4 with an objective.
Rym: It's a 2v2 So like a knight and an assassin in a FPS looking world like a castle or something Versus an assassin and a samurai and you have this big duel for honor With your weapons and it looks moderately fun.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's a game that is not above my line of play right now because of all the reasons we talked about before.
Scott: Yeah, I don't need to play that.
Rym: I kind of want to play it though.
Rym: It looks fun But if I'm gonna play anything I'd play that pub G before I play for honor.
Rym: So the deal is there's been.
Rym: um, so I learned some updates about some issues with this game.
Rym: But basically for honor has a long-standing Exploit where you can do what they call it unlock tech and I don't know enough about the game to go into details.
Rym: But basically you can do a thing to make it difficult or impossible For opponents to parry a certain kind of attack.
Rym: you might do so.
Scott: you can basically have an attack.
Scott: that guaranteed to hit that guaranteed Unperiable.
Rym: they could dodge it to do other things, but they can't parry it.
Rym: Mm-hmm And someone legit just use this Saw constantly to win a tournament.
Rym: good knowingly and constantly good job anyone cuz the rule that's part of the game.
Scott: Why didn't the other people do this?
Rym: because they're stupid, okay That's the only explanation I can find is that the all maybe they weren't good enough.
Scott: Maybe it's hard to do or something.
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't seem like it's that hard to do and also to their credit.
Rym: I'm quoting the article He got the trophy for honors creative director said and this is a quote.
Rym: This is what he said while he awarded the trophy.
Rym: Good job, buddy.
Rym: Soon you may have to change your play style Mm-hmm implying that the exploit will soon be patched out of the game.
Rym: He got his 10 grand.
Scott: Yeah, they probably.
Scott: you know the terms of the agreement and the tournament entry probably couldn't.
Scott: they couldn't deny him because it wasn't against the Rules.
Rym: so man machine on Twitter pointed something out real interesting because I don't know enough about the meta of this game.
Scott: I don't even know what kind of game it was.
Rym: There's way more to this story.
Rym: Apparently the meta right now is Heavily defensive play and is boring.
Scott: if someone can be super on you can't parry my attack.
Scott: I guess my only way to do is to be super defensive and block or dodge everything.
Rym: a smash tournament.
Rym: That's based on Lives remaining as opposed to kills.
Rym: the Rym strategies is pretty effective depending on the stage, right?
Rym: Don't fight anyone hide forever.
Rym: Fuck you all.
Rym: But basically this defensive strategy much like the trap in hockey sucks to watch sucks to play against sucks to play.
Rym: Yeah, so a lot of people in this is boring.
Rym: a lot of people Seeing a fight coming up soon A champion of defense are apparently very defensive of this glitch because this glitch is Actually a really effective way to break that fucking defensive meta.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the community is really split on whether or not Exploiting this is truly exploitative.
Scott: It sounds like what you should do is not play this garbage game and play something else.
Scott: the same thing You should do with Nidhogg do but at the same time Ubisoft, which I've never most garbage game publisher Not the most garbage.
Scott: who's more garbage.
Rym: Uh Who's most garbage?
Rym: who is the most garbage?
Scott: Even EA is better than Ubisoft.
Rym: but the the other component of all this the bit.
Rym: one of the big debates is that Many big eSports like almost everything in modern MOBAs were built around what were originally Basically exploits of a poorly designed game Dota, I mean last hitting.
Rym: no one sane on earth would argue that last hitting is a good mechanic But it became an effective mechanic to optimize play in a game and then like Later game design sort of built around it.
Rym: So is this one of those things?
Rym: Is this an exploit?
Rym: and the answer is Ubisoft gets to decide because they're the ones who run this scene.
Scott: I guess people are playing it and they have a tournament that is big enough to make the news.
Scott: So but props to the Ubisoft will be money.
Rym: This is one of the first time.
Scott: I don't give them any props.
Rym: This is one of the first times in modern eSports where I think the use of an exploit was handled correctly and frankly I'm disappointed and all the other people in this tournament who did not do anything about it in the context of the game.
Rym: Why did they?
Rym: they knew he'd do it?
Rym: What do they think was gonna happen?
Rym: It'd be like if I went to a Mario Kart DS tournament and I was like, I ain't gonna snake I have honor and everyone else is just like.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: So our friend Luca Crane?
Scott: Who not Luca Crane?
Scott: I just Luke Crane who has made the burning wheel and many other excellent games and his official job.
Scott: I think they actually changed his job title to be correct.
Scott: He is head of games at Kickstarter.
Scott: That is his job.
Scott: He is in charge of all kick-started games.
Rym: Luke Crane is literally responsible for the front row crew and GeekNights Discovering a world outside of Dungeons & Dragons like games in role-playing.
Scott: Well, I think we knew that world was there But we basically looked down on it and paid no attention to it.
Scott: cuz every nerd who's like I'm gonna make my own system All that guy and he was the one who wasn't that guy.
Rym: Yep, and then we spread birdie wheel far but anyway He was at some convention.
Scott: I think in Europe somewhere.
Scott: Where was this?
Scott: I Can't tell I don't know.
Scott: It's called a maze.
Scott: was the convention or conference He was at and it was.
Scott: it was a video gaming conference of some kind and he's given a panel there as you know Head of games at Kickstarter and that's Vincent Baker.
Scott: Oh, hey, that's me and he's talking about this game He made called inheritance, which is so full disclosure.
Rym: I kick-started like the nice version.
Scott: I mean, oh, yeah We don't need to tell you the story about this game because when you watch this video You're gonna hear the full story about this game, but I will say this I but it is a story.
Scott: it is a story in which we are tangentially related.
Rym: So this cuz we this Incident that is on the screen right now on the stream Where I'm standing there with my hand over my chest and Vincent Baker is lying on the ground.
Rym: this was like a one of the later play tests of inheritance at a burning con.
Rym: right, yeah, was that a burning con?
Rym: and This events this game this larp that I played that physical instance was literally like one of the top three best Gaming experiences I've ever had in my life.
Scott: I played I'm not extremely extremely early version in 2000-whatever at UberCon that was using the burning wheel system.
Scott: It wasn't a larp yet And that was one of the still one of the best RPG things there was like I got like.
Rym: I cannot express you like.
Rym: Try the entirety.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't until mere months ago that we had this game in our hands.
Scott: That's how long this game was made.
Rym: the entirety of my time playing tribes 2 is Equal to or possibly lesser than the 4 hours.
Rym: I played this game this one time.
Rym: Yeah, probably and a bunch of our like holy shit.
Scott: after all that waiting of 10 plus years We now have a copy of this game To this day.
Rym: Vincent Baker is salty about what I did to him.
Scott: Well according to Luke in this panel is still salty Yeah And all I say is that what could I do?
Rym: Luke handed me the knife and basically said do what would do what thou wilt and What I will.
Scott: a knife only does one thing stab.
Scott: well two things stabby and cutty.
Rym: and frankly you know the real villain here is our friend cat.
Rym: because Not to so cats character.
Rym: basically in joke heading character Said I could marry her daughter Which is the thing I actually wanted other than all the other things I wanted.
Rym: but that was the thing I really wanted.
Rym: and she Was like I'll only let you marry her if you bring me Vincent Baker's fucking head.
Rym: And I was like sure.
Rym: and then Luke was like oh, we got to play this out.
Rym: Oh, we got to play this out and Vince is like really.
Rym: and we had this final encounter.
Rym: and holy crap That was a moment.
Rym: this video is great though looks a pretty good lecturer as well.
Rym: You should go check out his other videos.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah watch this so learn a story.
Rym: I was doing research for some of our new panels and So remember way back I talked about I did this thing of the day long long time ago, but there's this video.
Rym: That's every way to die in shadow gate.
Scott: So there's a don't do every way to die in deja vu.
Rym: uh yeah, I've seen that video Okay, but I never actually played Uninvited.
Rym: what the hell's uninvited you holy shit uninvited.
Scott: is that another shadow gate or deja vu type game?
Scott: yes But I have never heard of.
Scott: uh what the fuck what the fuck system is it on any s?
Rym: really you can play it on the Thought.
Scott: there were only two games.
Rym: no so this was a hidden third game.
Scott: this whole time my whole life I didn't know.
Scott: are you sure this isn't like some alternate matrix kind of glitch thing we're like?
Rym: well I did not expect you to not know about this game.
Scott: You just created this game out of nowhere to fool me.
Scott: So all I'll say you think it always existed when it didn't.
Rym: so this game is probably way more Complex and interesting than shadow gate.
Scott: Let's deja vu is more interesting.
Rym: Yeah, but more importantly the deaths in This game there aren't as many as shadow gate.
Rym: Holy holy fuck are they like beyond the pale of horrible.
Scott: I think this game was just invented.
Rym: so this is a video that is a ton of the deaths in uninvited and the next video in this person's channel is the rest of the deaths and This is worth a watch because these deaths are Haunting and terrifying.
Scott: oh yeah to research this game that you just made up.
Scott: So the plot I think I just entered a different world here where they were three games.
Rym: in this plot of this game is that you and your Fiance or sister some girl like crash your car you go somewhere that you weren't invited.
Rym: Yeah, you you crash your car and your sister disappears.
Rym: So you go into a house that you're not invited into and there's a Transylvanians in there.
Scott: uh of the transvestite variety it appeared.
Rym: No, that would be a whole different game.
Rym: No, I want to play a dating game.
Rym: I want to play the dating game of that Holy shit Movie.
Rym: you don't need a game a dating game of the rocky horror picture show characters.
Rym: I can't believe that doesn't exist.
Scott: Don't make it.
Rym: I should I should license it.
Rym: Holy shit would that make money?
Rym: I would just hide the money expensive license.
Rym: I the people who made dream daddy that exact creative team should just make the rocky horror picture show dating game.
Rym: I would invest all the money I have.
Rym: that would make so much money.
Rym: If you think the death screen and the death music and shadow gate is haunting The red skull of death in this game and the sound that happens when you die America's mortal enemy.
Rym: This is good biz.
Rym: In the matter moment the booklet book is the fifth season which we're gonna do soon.
Scott: So I got some extra info in the fifth season.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, so the last year the Hugo Award was for the best novel was given to the fifth season And this year the Hugo Award was given to a different novel I forget the name of by the same author of the fifth season.
Scott: two years in a row daddy five seasons same person Same award two books.
Scott: How can you ignore these books?
Scott: You can't.
Scott: that's why we're gonna read it.
Scott: But club book fifth season NK jemisin get with it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Also we are going to be in a few weeks at Pat.
Rym: well I'm gonna be a PAX dev with Emily and then the two of us plus Scott and our crew will be at PAX West.
Rym: We just know all packs not you.
Scott: so goddamn soon.
Rym: Not three not five, but four days of paxing in the heart of Seattle.
Rym: Oh, thanks.
Rym: Wes is my favorite kind of love.
Rym: you mag fat, but you're number two.
Rym: Number two is still a pretty good honor there.
Scott: It's a waffle.
Scott: I'm gonna get a crack and my flight is like lady.
Scott: I just like afternoon on Tuesday.
Scott: So I got all this time.
Rym: I might go to biscuit bitch for breakfast before I fly home.
Scott: It's gonna be yeah.
Rym: But we're doing on Sunday a panel not on quitting.
Rym: I like the high level of like what is quitting but this is like rage.
Rym: quit specifically those fuckers Mm-hmm, and it's on Sunday.
Scott: I'm just can't think of a new panel idea.
Scott: He's got a redo.
Rym: All right We got.
Rym: actually we were talking about this.
Rym: So the 2018 heat nights panels will require more research But I think I'm doing these same panels, so I'm making new ones.
Rym: We've only been doing it for a year.
Rym: We basically every year we pick a set of panels quitting panels like three years old at least.
Rym: Well between.
Rym: so I actually changed it all.
Rym: if you looked at the slides yet.
Rym: It's not the same pen Oh, but you barely.
Rym: uh It's like 60% plus different same idea.
Scott: It's not a new idea.
Scott: Yeah, it has got to make sense.
Scott: 100% new.
Rym: No, you don't.
Rym: plus.
Scott: it also has a completely different moral Like some DJ who can't come up with the new melodies you just remixing.
Rym: I like to mix.
Rym: that's you two mixes one song remixed A hundred times as you right now.
Scott: I'm gonna make new music.
Rym: What panel did you give me that I could have submitted to PAX West?
Scott: I didn't think we were gonna redo.
Scott: I thought you were gay.
Rym: What do you think?
Rym: I told you.
Rym: Hey, here's my ideas.
Rym: and you said, okay You didn't say anything that I'm making new ones now.
Scott: I'm tired of shit.
Scott: You make any new ones lazy man, I did.
Rym: I made this one.
Rym: it's not new I think it is.
Scott: it's a remix.
Rym: It's actually pretty new.
Scott: It's not new.
Rym: Also how many times you think we've done this panel?
Rym: because you're busy.
Scott: You're busy inventing entire video games and never existed like uninvited New panel.
Rym: careful.
Rym: If you play on invaded you'll get fully taken into the hell dimension.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: So yeah, Namco Museum came out on the switch.
Scott: Well Namco Museum has been on man.
Rym: The museum is a franchise with many iterations that are all like there's like a mix match of different Namco games.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty sure it goes back to like PlayStation.
Scott: I think is the maybe the first time.
Rym: we are only talking about the release that just happened recently on the switch Right, which confusingly is literally just called Namco Museum.
Scott: If you go back in time to the arcades right all the best arcade games.
Scott: There are some made by Nintendo like a Donkey Konga.
Scott: Yeah, there is some made by Atari like a pole position or a centipede.
Rym: There's the Bimanis by Konami's.
Scott: Well, that's way newer, but I'm talking about classic arcade games, right?
Scott: Most of the best classic arcade games are made by Namco Pac-man Dig-dug Ms.
Scott: Pac-man Galaga.
Scott: it's like pretty much all if I'm gonna make an arcade in my house out of old real arcade machines.
Scott: a Lot of them are gonna be Namco machines.
Scott: Maybe even more than 50%.
Rym: so who made Rampart?
Scott: actually don't know also Namco.
Scott: Anyway, so they always release these collection things of like hey If you want to play these old Namco arcade games on your modern console, no, no Atari Really?
Rym: It was on the Atari platform.
Rym: All right captain news to me.
Rym: Anyway, why did you think why?
Rym: why did you make that up?
Rym: Why were you wrong?
Scott: Cuz it's on the name code.
Scott: is it collection with the cinestar and whatever?
Rym: anyway anyway.
Scott: so Like I was saying they release these discs that collect a whole bunch of Namco arcade games together Right into a single software package.
Scott: that even in the year 2017 you can buy a game from 1982 and not feel bad because you would never pay this amount of money to get just dig dug, right
Rym: I mean I might depend but I've
Scott: probably put more money in quarters into dig dug machines Than it would cost to buy this collection.
Rym: more importantly These games are sort of official like they're real official legit ports and like really what it is.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's just meme.
Scott: Oh, yeah where the user interface?
Rym: Well, because the options are the same like you and the options on dig dug.
Rym: You can be like turn our peg man You can.
Rym: there's a fix for the kill screen that you can turn on and off and you can like pick what arcade mode you Want to put.
Scott: pretty sure that this is just an emulator with ROMs that you buy to run on your console.
Scott: That only plays a small set of ROMs that are included and that's it, but they're so polished.
Rym: They just work perfectly And they link up to like internet servers.
Rym: So if you get a high score like it just ranks you with all your friends.
Scott: Yeah, and no one's hacked the scores yet.
Rym: and more importantly this damn cool museum is special because it includes one of the best Multiplayer GameCube games on earth.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Not only does this one most of the time They just include a bunch of old arcade games, right?
Scott: But this one includes a non arcade game.
Scott: that is a game that up until now if you wanted to play this game, you would need to buy a GameCube a GBA of some kind the game and Three game of cube controllers to go with your GBA and a link cable.
Scott: if you can find one.
Scott: I have a whole bunch where you can't have them.
Scott: It is included.
Rym: No, there is no other way to play.
Rym: No, there's one other way to play it.
Rym: What is the other way ten years ago?
Rym: Namco Museum came out Namco Museum came out on the DS.
Rym: Really Pac-man.
Rym: Galica's Xevious Super Xevious Galaxian Mappy Land Tower of Druaga dig dug - oh And a remake of Pac-man verse.
Scott: All right, but yeah Pac-man versus you have the arcade these days and they got this bullshit there Which we think we've talked about called Pac-man battle royale.
Rym: It is awful.
Scott: Pac-man battle royale is a pile of shit.
Rym: The alternate rules that packs used for the omega-thon finale were way better than the actual rules of that game.
Scott: But that game is still a pile of shit even at the and even under those circumstances.
Scott: so the way that game works Pac-man battle royale is Eating pills doesn't fucking matter.
Scott: All that matters is you live longer than your other Pac-man.
Scott: There's four Pac-mans and you got to eat your friends or push them into ghosts.
Scott: and that's the whole thing.
Scott: and it's stupid.
Scott: Pac-man verse is legit.
Scott: The way Pac-man verse works is one player is Pac-man and the other players are ghosts.
Rym: So you don't understand back then.
Rym: this is why the GameCube link take cable was so utterly Revolutionary because the person who's Pac-man on their gay on their Gameboy?
Rym: Gameboy Advance Literally just sees normal Pac-man.
Rym: They're just playing back.
Scott: They're playing Pac-man.
Scott: They see the full the full map.
Scott: All they're doing is playing Pac-man except they're playing against ghosts that are much more dangerous Because they're controlled by humans and not by the default Pac-man AI.
Rym: The ghosts are all on the TV.
Scott: the ghosts are looking at the TV and but the thing with when you're a ghost All you can see is this very limited radius around your ghost.
Scott: You can't see the whole map.
Scott: So you're not always sure where Pac-man is and if you kill Pac-man you become Pac-man.
Rym: Yep, we won't get into like the super details the way this works.
Rym: on the switch everyone has a switch or You only need to one switch.
Scott: one screen run switches the Pac-man and the other switch is all the Pac-man ghosts, right?
Rym: So we're not gonna get into depth about Pac-man first.
Rym: All I want to say is that it is like that is.
Scott: the reason to pay for this game alone is to get Pac-man verse because it's the best way to get Pac-man verse cuz no other ways to get it are gonna be too difficult.
Rym: I cannot express to you how much we're going to play Pac-man verse at PAX West.
Scott: You also need to know that even if you just have a switch Only one of your friends needs to pay the money to buy this game Everyone else.
Scott: that's.
Scott: in the e-shop There is a free download that I recommend you get no matter what if you have a switch at all.
Scott: That will let you give you basically the client to be a ghost, right?
Scott: So that way you can just join in on a Pac-man verse for free if one person owns it.
Rym: It also has a mode.
Rym: if you only have one switch It just only.
Rym: basically it's only ghosts and the.
Rym: no one can be Pac-man and it's obviously not the full experience But it's not that bad.
Scott: That's better than no Pac-man verse.
Rym: Yeah, but I'll dig up the.
Rym: I'm sure we reviewed this at some point a long time.
Scott: Yes, we did super long ago like two thousand five or six like.
Scott: I cannot express to you how great Pac-man versus versus the best Multiplayer Pac-man and is maybe one of the best local multiplayer games period.
Scott: yeah It's not that I mean, it's not the best period but this is it's way up there.
Rym: So damn cute Museum is Just.
Rym: you know that and all these other games and it's worth buying just because of Pac-man first buy it.
Scott: Even if you don't care about any other the games on this list It is worth buying one copy of this in your friend group just for the Pac-man verse.
Rym: I feel like we should spend like a couple minutes for viewing each of the games.
Scott: But it also comes with all these old classic arcade games and we'll review them all beginning with the best one dig dug.
Rym: How about we go in chronological order?
Rym: Cuz that's the list I have here.
Scott: What's older than dig dug dig dig as old as me Pac-man.
Scott: Pac-man is old and dig.
Scott: I guess it is 1980.
Scott: It's the original Pac-man.
Scott: It's not as good as miss Pac-man.
Scott: It's not as good as Pac-man.
Rym: see yeah, that's a lot of people disagree.
Rym: I'd like I've gotten some vitriol over this before.
Rym: I think miss Pac-man is better than Pac-man.
Scott: sure Pac-man is almost the worst Pac-man.
Scott: I think Pac-man jr.
Scott: Is worse.
Rym: Pac-man jr.
Rym: Is not good.
Scott: I mean Counting actual Pac-man game.
Scott: Okay, not like some 3d garbo Pac-man.
Scott: That's not doesn't?
Scott: I'm talking about 2d Pac-man's.
Scott: where there's a there's a maze.
Rym: CEDX is real fucking good.
Scott: Pac-man.
Scott: CEDX 2 is not.
Scott: it's not not it's not.
Scott: no it's weird.
Rym: Yeah, Pac-man CEDX is weird, but it's a good way.
Scott: X plus is the best Pac-man Single-player yep, but miss Pac-man is the best like pure old pack your old one Yeah, but this is regular Pac-man, which you know.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: how fun is regular Pac-man?
Scott: pretty fun It's okay, it's but it's like hey if you have this you can play regular Pac-man on your switch if you're in a Pac-man mood.
Scott: Yeah, and I wish they would put Pac-man.
Scott: you can turn off plus on.
Scott: you can turn off the screen by the game again.
Rym: You can turn off the kill screen.
Rym: Just keep going past the last level.
Rym: hmm Galaga is also older than Dig Dug.
Scott: Oh, it's Galaga.
Scott: I love Galaga.
Rym: the thing is I love Galaga But I actually like Galaga 88 way more.
Scott: well Galaga 88 is a better game.
Scott: Yeah for if you have modern sensibilities, but Galaga is like.
Scott: so Galaga is actually the sequel to Galaxian.
Scott: Galaxian is really a bad game.
Scott: Yeah It's like this Galaxian.
Scott: you have this grid of bad guys that are sort of meh and Occasionally they come flying down at you, and it's really kind of static and you shoot like pew pew right.
Scott: Galaga is really dynamic Like you know guys are swooping down and swirling and flying and you can get captured.
Scott: There's a lot of there's actually significant complexity like do you let yourself get captured and then get the double-shit?
Scott: but now you're more vulnerable and interesting.
Scott: different kinds of bad guys come in and you get the bonus round and the Positioning and it's like in the bag.
Scott: I shoot a ton of fucking missiles at you all over the place.
Scott: It's like Galaga is serious serious business.
Scott: Galaga 88 is a really fancy Galaga.
Scott: It's not like.
Rym: it's also Galaga 88 technically came out according to Wikipedia in 87.
Scott: Yeah, probably I think there's also a Galaga 90 for the Cerbographic 16.
Rym: yeah, but anyway, so that's the two Galaga's their Galaga.
Scott: Yeah, Dig Dug my boy Dig Dug is Dig Dug.
Scott: It's the best game on.
Rym: so when I got when I got this thing I didn't I just played Dig Dug and I've been playing Dig Dug a bunch recently the third time I played Dig Dug ever since I bought this thing.
Scott: This is the best portable Dig Dug because I don't think before now, right?
Scott: It's like there's.
Scott: you've been able to get Dig Dug on like lots of portable consoles, right?
Scott: But I don't think there has been a pure emu.
Scott: there might have been on a PSP or a Vita or something But I don't know because I don't pay attention to those things.
Scott: There has never been a pure, you know Emulated perfect Dig Dug legally released on a portable console I think before now that I'm aware of.
Rym: but Dig Dug is one of our favorite old arcade games up there with Rampart.
Rym: We just love the hell out of it and we're both pretty good at it.
Rym: We're not like world-class Obviously not but we're pretty good.
Scott: So the better than a normal person.
Rym: I literally played it three times and on the third time I got the 37th highest score on like the leaderboards and as of today, I've only dropped to 42nd.
Scott: I saw I checked the leaderboard on my switch yesterday.
Scott: It said you were 50th.
Scott: I guess I dropped a little further But anyway, I'm like I'm a hundred something.
Rym: I can't beat the score I got the third time I played it.
Rym: I played it a lot more than three times since then.
Scott: the problem is I've learned how to get high scores and Dig Dug like Drop two rocks get the vegetable try to kill guys with rocks But so but the real pro mode is kiting three enemies simultaneously.
Scott: I can do that as long as I'm not stuck on the bottom left corner of the screen where I usually am because that's where Meanwhile I was playing with.
Rym: Judith was hanging out and we're just playing Dig Dug and we realized something really horrifying about this game.
Rym: It's the way you kill these monsters is really awful.
Scott: You harpoon them and then you inflate you.
Rym: It's like inflation girl.
Scott: It's awful, but they're basically inflatable monsters.
Scott: They're in they're not like but like that's every lady real slow and watch with these the sprites.
Rym: They just like explode out of their stomach like really horribly.
Scott: Yeah, it's like this the North Star.
Rym: Yeah, basically.
Rym: But uh Dig Dug is super great.
Rym: I love the hell out of it.
Rym: and If you've never played Dig Dug and you buy this for Pac-man first Dig Dug.
Rym: Dig Dug and Galaga 88 are probably the two best games other than Pac-man verse.
Rym: on this thing.
Scott: Yeah, we have she.
Scott: we've done an old GeekNights just about Dig Dug.
Scott: So you can go find that.
Rym: you can go find that if you want, uh Tower of Deraga is horrible and you just don't play It.
Rym: well, okay.
Scott: So Tower of Deraga is one of these games that like steals quarters from children.
Scott: Yes, that is true But the thing with the game is that it's like it's so close to being good.
Scott: It's just like it's oldness ruins it if someone would just update Tower of Deraga a little bit.
Scott: It could be great and the way it.
Scott: basically it's a game.
Scott: whether the maze million levels as it has a million levels.
Scott: There's a maze and it.
Scott: the maze is one screen, but it's kind of long.
Scott: So you have to scroll left and right to see the whole thing And you're a dude with a sword and you basically hold the sword Controls.
Scott: you hold the sword button to make the sword come out and you walk into a bad guy to kill it and you let Go the sword button to put the sword away and have the shield out and have the shield out right.
Scott: and and the first level It's like this green slimes and okay.
Scott: so you walk around and you stab I think five green slimes and that makes a treasure chest appear and in that treasure chest is The pickaxe which you used to bust open a wall.
Scott: You need this thing.
Scott: if you don't get this in level one, you are so boned.
Scott: You can't get it after level one.
Scott: Like then you have to get a key and then go in the exit door.
Scott: If you grab the key, you can't walk past the exit door anymore.
Scott: So I hope the mate you don't mess up and like kill the wrong slimes in the wrong order or anything.
Rym: This is one of those old games where like if you don't get a certain item at a certain point You'll get to the end of the game.
Rym: You just can't win.
Rym: You gotta go all the way back.
Scott: in level two You have to kill I think two black slimes to get the most important item, which is the walk faster item.
Scott: in level three I think you can get an item that gives you like an extra life.
Scott: It's not as important but it's like so on and so forth and the instructions actually tell you how to get the item to appear In each level.
Scott: Yeah, you can be really game with a fact, but really the it's in the game.
Scott: It gives you the manual but the really the pickaxe and if you don't get the pickaxe and the walk faster You're done.
Scott: because the main problem with this game is That there's this fucking timer in every level like gauntlet and you have to get.
Scott: if you don't get to the exit before the timer Horrible bad guys appear that are super that chase you down if I can kill you and there's not much you can do about them And it just eats your fucking quarters If someone just made this game more elegant and remove
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: and things.
Scott: sometimes you can get boned by the maze.
Scott: like the maze is just arranged in a bad way So it takes super long to get to the exit.
Scott: It's just basically just it.
Rym: this game is why it's like one of those old games from an era like those Like those sort of earth or whatever games.
Scott: Someone just polished Tower of Druaga to make it not evil and not some arcade quarter muncher.
Scott: It could actually be kind of fun But no such thing is the case.
Rym: is this good.
Rym: This just got replaced by roguelikes.
Scott: Yeah, I think just play a roguelike instead is right.
Rym: sky kid Which I never played before is way more fun than I expected.
Rym: actually like sky kid a lot.
Scott: sky kids Okay, but it's so it's a.
Rym: it's kind of hard.
Rym: They still write to left shmup, which is annoying.
Rym: Yeah, I want to go left to right based on World War one like a style combat.
Rym: the way you got a fly You got a cool thing is you've got to take off and land and you can do a little loopy loopy loop and shoot while You're looping.
Rym: Yeah, so like the dog fighting is actually like kind of complex Like you can't turn around and shoot backwards though and a lot of guys come from behind.
Rym: Well, you can do a loop and shoot while you're looping.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: So yeah, there's a high skill component like there's cool stuff going on, but it's got.
Scott: this mechanic component means hardest boss.
Rym: Independent of that there'll be a target and you just get a picture of it and it'll appear at some point during each map and At some point during each map before the target.
Rym: There'll be a bomb.
Scott: you have to pick up that bomb which means you have to go down near the ground where this dangerous because trees will just kill you.
Rym: and The only way to launch the bomb is you'd start a loop and you'll like launch the bomb while you do the loop meaning while You're carrying the bomb.
Rym: You're slow and heavy and can't do the loop anymore.
Rym: and It's got.
Rym: basically it's got a lot of the feels of like an old chop lifter game Mmm, and I liked chop lifter a lot.
Scott: chop lifters a lot more dynamic though.
Rym: Yeah, this is simpler, but I had a lot of fun with it.
Rym: and also the that art of the Eagle.
Rym: I love that Eagles face cuz he's just so like why?
Rym: Sure, that's like a Waluigi face.
Scott: It's an oak.
Scott: It's not the worst game on here But you know, it's not like you're gonna play that much of it.
Scott: It's an old cruddy arcade game.
Scott: So rolling thunder rolling thunder - or just those like boring rolling thunder and rolling thunder - are boring elevator action.
Scott: Crappy versions of elevator elevator action without the elevator.
Scott: right elevator action is actually a good game.
Scott: elevator action - is an incredible game.
Rym: They remind me of all those bad Sega port rolling thunder.
Scott: rolling Thunder is elevator action but fucked up so that it's really annoying and unfun to play Because the bad guys just like you'll go into a door to hide and the bad guys just mill outside the door And you can't possibly exit because the bad guys don't move.
Scott: Oh, and what are you gonna do?
Scott: get out and take a damage and then you get killed.
Rym: The kinds of arcade games as a kid I'd like play once and never play again cuz I hated them.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know, you're better off playing like sunset riders and playing this.
Rym: So tank force is actually reasonably fun as well.
Scott: Force is a good game.
Rym: It reminds me a little bit of that battle mode in advance.
Rym: It's combat, but the controls are actually good, but the battle mode in advance wars DS as well.
Scott: It doesn't really cheat you It's just.
Scott: it's just fair.
Scott: hard.
Rym: protect your base kill the bad guys and the two players.
Rym: seems like it's also pretty true player Is it?
Scott: that's the one thing about this game?
Scott: Is that because the way the map is it's not like the game.
Scott: get the game gets easier with two player.
Scott: with one player It's kind of annoyingly hard because the bad guys are coming in from all these sides and you're just one tank.
Scott: What can you do?
Scott: Yeah But if you have two players Playing co-op the way this is meant to be played this game gets real good or real fast and is that it's real fun?
Rym: I really like it.
Scott: Yeah, imagine it combat, but instead of shooting each other You're protecting one area of the map and a million bad guys come in from all sides and there's two of you.
Scott: But the controls are really good and you can get a lot of upgrades to get better shots and stuff and the environment is destructible, yep, so Splatterhouse is kind of notable because that was I think I'm pretty sure that game came out.
Rym: I'm Sega guys.
Scott: Splatterhouse I remember being a Genesis game.
Scott: I don't remember it being.
Scott: I think it might have been mad.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Do you not understand if you're younger than us?
Rym: how?
Scott: Controversial Splatterhouse was right because this is a game that actually showed like when you would chainsaw Like ghostly bad guys and they would get guts everywhere.
Rym: It wasn't quite a giant fetus hanging from a womb at the end of the game Like it was a horror game that showed horror imagery.
Scott: You're basically Jason.
Scott: You had a Jason mask.
Rym: Yep The mask of power even though it's basically a Jojo's mask, even though you're a good guy and not a horrible guys.
Rym: Well, no, you're a good guy who gets possessed by the mask of horror.
Rym: That's some ancient like Aztec thing.
Rym: But you go.
Scott: you go into this mansion of evil to save your girlfriend who got captured by horror.
Rym: Yeah, it has a bad ending.
Rym: You can't save her.
Rym: It's bad news.
Scott: Yeah, everything in the mansion is hard and you go through basically horrifyingly Murdering and chopping up all these other evil things.
Rym: It's actually more fun than I expected.
Scott: No, Splatterhouse was actually a legit good game.
Scott: It's a lot like I don't know how many people know this game.
Scott: Oh, is it what the hell's the name of it?
Scott: Is it Astya next?
Rym: Oh, yeah Really?
Scott: Is that what is called?
Scott: Let me look it up.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Yes, Astia X as G and X is a game for the NES where you're this giant dude and give a Greek guy and you have.
Scott: you're really kind of slow and your attacks are really slow and you're really big and your side scrolling and there's all these bad guys that are really fast all over the place and you had to beat them all.
Scott: and Splatter house is really really similar to that only better cuz unlike double dragon.
Rym: You can't move up and down It's just left and right.
Rym: But even though you only have sort of punching kick and jump There's a lot of combinations and items and things that make it skill based.
Scott: It's really actually quite similar.
Scott: you people love your fucking Dark Souls garbage, which I don't like.
Scott: This is like 2d Dark Souls and insert of the combat way.
Scott: There's no exploring and that kind of stuff, but it's like in terms of the action aspect.
Scott: It's like oh for this bad guy You need to back up a little bit and then get in on him and for this bad guy You got a crouch and whack him a bunch.
Scott: There's yet to figure out a different way to approach all the different enemies.
Scott: combat wise because you don't get a lot of health Get killed real fast.
Rym: Yeah, but it's a piece of history But it's more fun than most of the other like I'd play it again before I would ever play tower of drive.
Scott: Yes, bladder house is actually a decent game like no one, you know.
Scott: That's the thing is that if you look at history when of people of controversial, you know video games like Mortal Kombat and stuff The only games that had these Controversies around there.
Scott: There are plenty of other horrible violent games But like custard's revenge wasn't in the news because no one could buy it and it wasn't actually a good game.
Scott: the games like splatter house immortal combat became controversial because a bunch of people were buying them because they were a fucking good Sad nap.
Rym: go museum.
Scott: Like if you want to switch there weren't any other games talk about.
Rym: no, that's it.
Rym: That's all there.
Scott: I feel like you missed one.
Rym: Pac-man Galaga dig dug top dragga sky kid rolling thunder.
Rym: Galaga 88 splatter house rolling thunder to tank force.
Rym: pac-man verse.
Rym: Alright, there's nothing else on there.
Scott: Okay, but yeah It's I don't know if you're like.
Scott: I wouldn't pay full price for this right now on your switch unless you unless you're a fan Of one of these games.
Scott: right unless you really want to play one of these because you can get the.
Scott: let someone else buy pet Buy it and play pac-man verse for free with them.
Scott: But if you're the kind of person like me who's gonna try to you know, register some dig dug high scores when you're bored.
Scott: You know, I basically bought this and Magical drop and those are like my quick play switch games.
Scott: I don't think I'm gonna buy any more quick play switch games unless something really great comes out on there.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and there's a tiny feature that's really useful.
Rym: You can rotate the screen to any orientation.
Scott: Oh, yeah, cuz a lot of these games there are vertical arcade games like.
Rym: so Doug I play dig-dug holding a controller and I set it on the table like your switch sideways like a cocktail cabinet.
Scott: It actually lets you rotate it 90 degrees in any direction.
Scott: So there's four different orientations Even though the two are which is just example of if you play.
Rym: if you poke around you'll see in the options There's so much polish to this.
Scott: Mm-hmm that it's an emulator.
Scott: It gives you all the features that you need For these games and not any other of the features that are in emulators, but honestly, it's worth paying full price for it Right now just because of pac-man first.
Rym: pretend you're buying pac-man first.
Rym: Yeah, cuz that game is worth.
Scott: how much did we pay for pac-man first?
Scott: on the GameCube?
Scott: fuck.
Rym: if I remember that was like Including 14 years ago the cost of link cables and everything else.
Rym: It was 2000 and then I gotta have friends So I gotta buy three hookers to come over and I gotta buy a house and I gotta buy food electricity.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon page runs for this episode of geek.
Rym: knows it was name as fast as possible this time Ellen Joyce, how do we nickel a man?
Rym: did you shed roundabout MP3 my city.
Rym: calm William?
Rym: Life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet Earth genuine, but if I'd like to ride six car monorail Nicholas brand out captain Chinguacos see Rebecca done for two.
Rym: and creations.
Rym: Even if we were to pull out today and if they would come take our base.
Rym: Sure, but horrible.
Rym: James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Rym: Sailor kimquat sailor Vista Matthew Smith down.
Rym: She likes our television.
Rym: Joe shows your star Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton wall driven from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent drew open letter.
Rym: Brian Sidroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Pax is coming up.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: for.
Rym: you know, the utenna.
Rym: I keep saying it's coming but believe me it's coming as well as another Anime related project that we're working on for YouTube.
Rym: Also, I'm gonna start doing the same thing.
Rym: We're doing for our tabletop reviews with our old anime reviews.
Rym: I'm slowly working on putting that together.
Rym: and Yeah, otherwise the convention that we're talking about we're putting some serious effort behind making that actually legit happen.
Rym: We've been crazy busy lately for a bunch of reasons.
Rym: that all come down shortly after PAX and now I leave you with.