Rym: It's Thursday, March 16th, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm not wearing a grandpa sweater And this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We ain't afraid of no sleep, and we ain't afraid of no bed busted Literally talking about beds, but not sleep only beds.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah, we're.
Rym: uh we're back from PAX.
Rym: This was the worst weather that has ever occurred out of PAX in the history of PAX as far as I can tell.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: It was dangerously cold coupled with the fact that Boston
Scott: It was woman cold
Rym: being the city of cowards Not only forces packs to have ridiculous security where they check Everyone's bag coming in and out of the convention center and the convention center holds at one time like 40,000 people.
Rym: But they also have metal detectors.
Rym: So the lines take forever and people were trapped outside of the dangerous cold.
Rym: And it was a giant shit show.
Scott: it wasn't just witches tit cold It was like it was witches.
Scott: lesbian orgy cold.
Scott: well, which is lesbian orgy sounds great sure But it's also really cold which is don't heat up when they get it on.
Rym: you're thinking of the wrong kind of witch.
Scott: Imagine getting it on with like a block of ice.
Rym: Maybe the Ice King is a better example.
Scott: Well, that's what a witch is only the Ice King's a dude.
Rym: But on top of all that like I put it this way it was so cold like I ski right It was cold enough to where that's the kind of weather where I say it's too cold to ski, and I don't go skiing.
Scott: It's always too cold to ski.
Rym: No You're just a baby.
Rym: But this is kind of why I like cuz.
Rym: you know we dish anime Boston this year And the reason was actually straight up cuz I know isn't it like next week or the week after or something in April sometime?
Rym: I don't even know cuz I didn't you know do anything.
Scott: It's too soon is the point.
Rym: but The actual reason we skipped anime Boston this year is because the security getting an anime Boston is even more of a shit show Because I guess anime Boston doesn't have as much clout.
Rym: so like the city does way worse security for them than they do for even packs And there's way less places.
Rym: so the lines are even worse than anime Boston, but I don't know if I can ever go back to anime Boston cuz even PAX East is trying my patience like The fact that I can mostly skip the line is the only reason I go to PAX East anymore.
Rym: as much as I love packs It's a real annoying.
Rym: I really hope packs leaves Boston when their contract is up with Boston because this shit is real bad And I think PAX East is going to be For the foreseeable future the only Boston convention we will ever go to.
Scott: yeah when there's conventions in the Javits There's no fucking security.
Scott: you can just walk right into the auto show PAX Prime packs, Australia.
Rym: You just walk in and wander around and while San Antonio has their you know security Multiple times.
Rym: I went into that line which took two seconds and the dude Literally looked at my bag that was not open looked up at me and just gave me the head nod of yeah Just go in.
Scott: that's called being white.
Rym: Yeah, that's the separate problem.
Rym: But I do think that pack San Antonio is mostly just checking for people who are carrying guns in because there's weird guns Stuff in Texas.
Scott: yeah, you can carry a gun outside the convention center all you want.
Scott: You just can't bring it in the building because it's Texas And that's how they do.
Scott: so they have to check everyone to make sure you're not trying to sneak one in there because it's totally Cool to just walk around with one right outside.
Rym: well totally cool by the law But not totally cool by like modern human standards no, but all that aside uh My laundry room has been unavailable for about a week in this building.
Scott: You haven't done laundry in a week.
Rym: uh no which luckily our laundry was like a hundred percent ahead.
Scott: Why don't you just bring your laundry to some nice Greek lady like I do who do it for you?
Rym: Because we I mean the lottery in the building is nice.
Rym: It's not like yours.
Rym: that takes forever.
Scott: I was like real good whatever, but you know why has it been unavailable?
Rym: so the last time this happened It was because an unnamed young lady who I would guess was in her early 20s Started a fire in the dryer.
Rym: because you know how do you start a fire in the dryer?
Rym: what lots of ways?
Scott: What did you put in there like?
Scott: Matches.
Rym: so the primary way dryer fires start and I know a lot about dryer fires cuz my dad was a fireman.
Scott: So it's not empty the lint you take the lint don't throw it in one you don't empty the lint.
Rym: and there's a surprising number Of adults.
Scott: lint is way flammable.
Rym: Yeah, don't know you have to do that like you would be surprised How many people literally don't know.
Rym: lint traps exist own houses and have completely clogged lint traps?
Scott: I empty the lint before and after every time I use the dryer.
Rym: I'm like obsessed with the lint trap stuff.
Scott: Also lint is awesome.
Rym: We yeah Actually, I got a new shirt and something happened to me.
Rym: That is not happening to me many years.
Rym: at the end of the day I had a whole bunch of belly button lint.
Scott: I have belly button every day.
Rym: I do not get belly button lint.
Rym: I guess the shirt just like you have an Audi belly button.
Rym: I got a pretty deep belly button.
Rym: It's just no lint.
Rym: in there There's a couple is like a speck of lint.
Scott: I guess That was it.
Scott: I have like too many layers.
Scott: I can't get to the lint hold on.
Rym: wow We haven't done a show in a while because of the snowstorm and everything and I suddenly here's my here's my lint for today.
Rym: I'd say there's decent amount of lint back there.
Scott: It's a little guy.
Rym: so anyway, the other thing that'll cause the fires is the motor burns out because you have a shitty ass dryer and While your lint trap is clean There's lint inside your dryer and all these places you have no idea about.
Scott: especially you have a crappy Top-loading dry and there's a spark somewhere inside the dryer that catches the lint on fire.
Rym: Something like that.
Rym: or a wire will heat up and start a smolder of some lint.
Rym: and then you know when the dryer kicks in And air comes pretty much all lint related.
Rym: Yeah The lint if you have external lint exhaust and air exhaust lint gets in there and actually, you know You know that ours blows out the building, you know that accordion style like two people use.
Rym: Yeah ain't supposed to use that shit that she has been deprecated.
Rym: You're supposed to use straight steel Tubing like pipes.
Scott: No.
Rym: All right, and if you have turk corners, you should have a Steel or a pipe corner not one of those elastic foldy things.
Rym: if you have the elastic floaty thing fully things You should clean them or replace them like every year.
Scott: All right, if I see any of those around in anyone's house I'll let them know like that's bad news.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's probably a lot of lint in there.
Rym: I've also seen people because I was remember we were trying to buy houses and Beacon who are literally just venting that lint like Into their walls are at it because they don't realize you're
Scott: supposed to vent it out of your house like
Rym: Yeah, like people who have a you know, the the grease hood that usually those just go back into the kitchen through the grease filter But sometimes they go out of the house.
Rym: I've seen houses where they look like they're going out of the house, but they actually just go into the attic.
Scott: Yeah Even in my mom's house, which is way old Right if you're in the backyard and the dryers on you can see there's this thing on the back of the house And is definitely air coming out because you can tell when you're outside if the dryers on or not.
Rym: But the other cause of dryer fires are people who either put clothing That cannot be put in a dryer in a dryer that has flammable shit in it.
Scott: What kind of clothing is this?
Rym: some kinds of sports stuff some kinds of high-fashion stuff?
Rym: cosplay stuff often Anything that has certain kinds of vine?
Scott: I mean that's got to be something kind of really weird that you put.
Scott: I mean I imagine like vinyl would just melt in there if it's too hot.
Rym: So it might melt depending on how hot the dryer is.
Rym: it might melt.
Scott: But how could it start a fire?
Rym: but that is older.
Rym: it doesn't have to necessarily start a fire fire.
Rym: Most fire fires actually just cause a lot of smoke damage.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It could be.
Scott: it could be something that's like that goes in there Right and heats up a whole bunch and it like traps the heat in such a way So that the cotton touching it then starts on fire.
Rym: All sorts of mechanisms right.
Scott: like the dryer itself doesn't get hot enough.
Scott: You know it doesn't spit out hot enough air to burn cotton.
Scott: otherwise obviously every dryer would start a fire ever.
Scott: But maybe you could put like for example a pizza stone in there.
Rym: Yeah don't put a pizza stone in there.
Scott: and then or a piece of a pizza stone and the piece of a pizza stone keep getting Hotter and hotter and hotter as it absorbs heat and eventually some cottons touching it would ignite.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm just guessing that might not be possible.
Rym: People will leave say a cell phone with a big-ass battery in their dryer in their pocket and do wash it.
Rym: So it's nice and wet.
Scott: and why is your cell phone not on your body at all times?
Rym: But the other off thing that'll happen is if certain kinds of clothes if you clean them with certain kinds of solvents like fancy clothes And there's some of that solvent left that will smolder or ignite in the hot dryer.
Rym: Lots of ways you can cause a. you can put such a heavy load that it burns out the motor and causes a smoke problem.
Scott: Flammable is in flammable.
Rym: Yeah, I watched that episode recently.
Rym: Okay, go to their old Simpsons Last night.
Rym: We just watched the gabbo episode.
Scott: He's also flow.
Rym: so the first time this happened, uh We're in the apartment and we're asleep and I start I wake up and I have that danger sense.
Rym: You know, sometimes you like danger sense like something's wrong.
Rym: Rabbits are thumping like something's wrong and I said that rabbit warning system And I smell like a little bit of smoke.
Rym: and you know, dad a fireman I mean there's smoke there's fine.
Rym: I jump out of bed I'm like, ah fuck and I turn on the light and there is like this burning smell and a little bit of smoke.
Rym: And it's coming in from the outside of the building as I figured out by doing some air test Trying to figure out if I wasn't in your apartment.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Nothing fire extinguisher.
Scott: I go downstairs.
Rym: I walk down because you know don't get in the elevator duh, so I go down the stairs.
Rym: I get to the second floor.
Rym: the smoke smoke fire alarm wasn't going off.
Rym: No I get to the first floor and it doesn't get a lot.
Rym: it gets a little stronger.
Scott: a con 911.
Rym: No, cuz I'm I know what I'm doing.
Rym: I get to the ground floor and it smells like smoke and the doorman is standing there looking at this girl And she's just like I just got to go into the laundry room to check on something and he's like there was a fire in There because somebody put something they shouldn't have in the dryer.
Rym: and she was like, it wasn't me I didn't put anything weird in there.
Rym: I just need to check something.
Rym: and he's like what dryer did you use?
Rym: and she's like I Just need to check something.
Rym: I just needed it was definite.
Rym: It was her clothes.
Rym: She put something in there that caused the smoke problem.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: The same thing happened again while we were at PAX.
Rym: I assume it was another 20-something.
Rym: It doesn't know how to do laundry.
Rym: I might be wrong.
Rym: I kind of hope it's the same person.
Scott: Okay, that's never happened in my laundry or even RIT's laundry.
Rym: I have an RIT's laundry's all the time.
Scott: Didn't have one.
Scott: I was there ever.
Scott: the laundry.
Rym: the laundry room in colony was shut down multiple times for people fucking up shit in there.
Scott: I never had that problem.
Rym: Someone pulled once.
Rym: some of it was vandalism.
Rym: someone filled a bunch of the washers with crayons one time.
Rym: That's bad.
Rym: Yeah, someone put a bunch of bricks in the dryer and turned it on.
Rym: I remember that one.
Scott: Don't do that.
Rym: But yeah, so I currently can't do laundry unless I go to a semi-public laundromat and hopefully they will done.
Scott: You just bring your clothes to a nice lady who will clean them.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I could.
Rym: that's so decadent weird though And I feel like a better use of my money would be getting a cleaning lady.
Scott: It's not that much more expensive.
Scott: It cost me like 20 bucks Which is like what it costs to run all those laundry machines.
Rym: to do a load of laundry for us cost like a dollar 50 cost me 250 and the dryer costs like a dollar 250. the washer takes 23 minutes.
Rym: The dryer takes 40 minutes.
Scott: They take 40 minutes each.
Rym: Yeah 40 minute washer.
Rym: what the hell kind of washer do you have?
Scott: and whatever kind of washer they got in the building.
Scott: Top loader no side load.
Scott: All right.
Rym: It's making sure cuz top loaders are bullshit.
Scott: It's the ripoff guy.
Rym: That was a tangent.
Rym: you got any news.
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: they announced that they're gonna I guess this is reboot the matrix Movies, so there was only one matrix movie.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there's one of them.
Scott: There's one matrix movie and I guess reboot doesn't mean remakes.
Rym: They're not gonna retell the same story Which I guess is good because a big part of the matrix was that most of us went into it.
Rym: I have no idea what it was about.
Scott: They're gonna tell new stories in the matrix universe.
Rym: So animatrix, that's fine I guess.
Scott: I guess yeah like animatrix only live-action movies and more of them because they got no new ideas.
Rym: My my concern.
Rym: there's two ways.
Rym: This could go.
Rym: it could go the Star Wars like rogue one way where they're all pretty good stories.
Rym: It could also go the like World-building for nerds way because I don't want to learn more about that world.
Scott: Well, there was already that matrix MMO where you could learn everything you need to know about that work.
Rym: Yeah Shame that that was canceled alongside those second two movies.
Scott: They were planning on making yeah, you know, so Matrix is like is like it's the thing about this.
Scott: right is like they're doing this constantly everywhere with everything these days.
Rym: But I don't feel like that's a these days thing old man.
Rym: I feel like that's just like it's the same burn rate.
Rym: We talked about this before we went live.
Scott: Anyway, the point is the matrix one is Still so good, and I love it.
Rym: So Is on a very short list of movies that if I'm like at a relative's house or there's a TV somewhere and that Movie is on unless something stops me.
Rym: I'll just wherever it stops.
Rym: I'll just watch it to the end, right?
Rym: It's not episode four.
Rym: if that's on no matter even if it's at the end of the movie beginning the movie I'm just gonna watch it.
Rym: That's just gonna happen, right?
Scott: So You know making more stuff in that universe is sort of like mmm, you know matters for some reason, right?
Scott: Just like making more Star Wars matters.
Scott: No, so Let's see what happens.
Rym: Well, yeah The thing is Star Wars had a lot of mystique in the sense that when we were kids Star Wars was all already out And they're like there was no chance as far as we could tell of them ever making more and the toys weren't being made.
Rym: So like Star Wars stuff was like this thing from a bygone age.
Scott: All right, well think about this right?
Scott: what year did Episode one the bad Star Wars movie come out?
Rym: bad Star Wars.
Rym: I was in high school.
Scott: Yeah, it was like 98 or 99 right when did Return of the Jedi Come out.
Rym: Oh, that was what?
Rym: 85.
Scott: no, I think it's like 81, right?
Scott: Like the year before you're born 83 83. so we were one year old.
Rym: Yeah, we were.
Rym: we were both.
Rym: we hit.
Rym: so 83 to 99 is how many years some number of years 16 years right between.
Rym: I'm saying there was a lot more Cultural baggage.
Scott: I'm just saying there were 16 years between Return of the Jedi and Phantom Menace, right?
Scott: No the matrix one Came out in what year.
Rym: also in high school I think I could drive so pretty much of effectively same time as Phantom Menace.
Scott: and How many years ago was that?
Scott: Yep?
Rym: 16 or 17 1999 16 or 17 years between.
Rym: But the matrix did not have extensive toy lines that were mystical to kids.
Rym: The the matrix did not have like.
Rym: you see it and your dad you're like your parents show it to you like hey Here's something you ain't ever seen.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well cuz now we've seen it.
Rym: Yeah, there's very different situations like.
Scott: But I mean the matrix is not Star Wars, but it's still so good.
Rym: I'm just not excited about the matrix reboot.
Scott: who said anything about being excited.
Rym: I'm barely even interested in it.
Rym: Cuz I don't feel like There are long interesting long-form stories to tell in that world unless you get into world building Which is literally the last thing I care about.
Rym: in the matrix Animatrix was only good because it was shorts that took the concept of Virtual reality world and like the fact that there's the stuff going on and told really short stories within that.
Rym: But the key I think was that they were short and did not address the world itself.
Scott: Just make some badass action movies with some hacking and some you know Keep the shit in the matrix or shits cool Don't none of this outside the major but the outside of the matrix was inside the matrix - done done.
Rym: It's almost like they're just making it up as they went along.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, so this is a moderately contentious news That was around and a lot of people were reporting on this from a lot of different angles.
Scott: You really think this is a much bigger news than I think it is.
Scott: This is like a tiny news.
Rym: It was there So a lot of people who were reporting on it were reporting on it from a particular angle to try to prove various points.
Rym: But the gist of this because this is a minor drama that has happened Perennially because of the internet and the fact that the Americans with Disabilities Act and the extensions to it Don't necessarily fully account for the way that the modern internet progressed.
Rym: I mean, I think the last extension to it was the 1990 ish.
Rym: Anyway, I don't know the.
Rym: uh, so basically the story was that Berkeley Started a university University University of California, Berkeley.
Rym: Yes State University started putting all the things that you know.
Rym: They video lectures and they have one set of lectures and videos.
Rym: That's for students.
Rym: Like you're in a class you can go to a thing like watch a video lecture but they took like 5,000 of their lectures that they just happen a video of and said skirt and audio to like.
Rym: some of them were just basically like Audio recordings and just put it all on YouTube and iTunes and other places for free saying hey Here's a bunch of educational content and it cost us nothing to just give it to everybody.
Scott: Well, it cost Google something cuz.
Scott: then what's hosting?
Rym: it cost them nothing, right?
Rym: Just put it out there for people to use.
Rym: I believe most of it was licensed Creative Commons.
Rym: Sure Basically Because of title two of the Americans with Disabilities Act and a lawsuit They were ordered to make all of that free content.
Rym: not for students because they already comply with the ADA.
Rym: for students if a student Needs an accommodation to access course required materials.
Rym: They make that accommodation obviously, but they were not making those accommodations for this free public stuff.
Rym: they just put out and Upon examining it they decided that there was no way they could in any reasonable timely or cost-effective fashion Make even general accommodations for all this content.
Rym: They took it all down instead.
Rym: Now they have pledged that they do want to re-release it conforming to these standards.
Rym: So subtitles closed captions those sorts of things aren't those the same thing, but it?
Rym: well, they're not actually the same thing.
Rym: They're actually very different in subtle ways.
Rym: That could be a whole topic of a show if you want to get into that.
Rym: I waited to learn a lot about that in RIT Anime Club because we we presented subtitled screenings.
Rym: We did not present closed captioning anyway.
Rym: They do want to put it all back online But that's going to be at substantial cost and it'll take a long time to do so effectively.
Rym: all that stuff is offline and the debate is whether or not that Action and everything that happened here serves the intended purpose and spirit of the ADA because on one hand The ADA has to be somewhat strict because otherwise Everyone who has a profit motive will push the line and do the minimum possible to comply with it.
Rym: but on the other hand You basically forced a lot of free educational material that a large number of people could use that wouldn't exist Otherwise off the internet for an indefinite period because it wasn't as compliant as it could be.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: The twist to this is that because it was licensed mostly Creative Commons bunch of nerds Downloaded it all and are making it publicly available on another website because due to technicalities They do not have to be compliant with the ADA.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So this is all a very interesting story and not being disabled and also not having Sort of like a policy expertise here.
Rym: I'm not gonna weigh in with a very strong opinion because I have a very complex opinion and this is just a very interesting story.
Rym: I'm curious to see how this all shakes down because there's a fight like for example GeekNights if we had to make our lectures Closed captioned and someone wouldn't just do it for free Probably wouldn't put any of our lectures online because I couldn't afford to make that happen
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: but at the same time we are not a state-run institution nor are we a large for-profit institution.
Rym: nor you know We're a small fry and this is all just very interesting and you can read these articles to find out more about it.
Rym: Okay, you don't have any opinion on this.
Scott: I just feel like you know, I like the ADA a lot But I feel like your solution should not be.
Scott: you know This doesn't make you know, you're not.
Scott: this Solution doesn't solve the problem, right?
Scott: It doesn't make anything more accessible by removing if there's a Pizza place in town and the pizza place has stairs to get up to it, right?
Scott: It's like you can force this pizza guy to put in a ramp if he can afford it But if he can't and you force him to close all you did was make things worse for everyone.
Scott: You didn't make the world a better place.
Scott: You need a different solution, right?
Scott: You know find a way to get money for the pizza guy to build a ramp.
Scott: Don't find a way to just shut him down if he can't build one.
Rym: Yep Well, I think it specifically comes down to taking but also don't not do anything.
Rym: It is let a pizza guy operate with a staircase But in the case of taking existing media and making it.
Rym: making it online as opposed to not making it online.
Rym: You're sort of forced to not make it online if you are I guess held to the standards of the ADA because you're that kind of organization Which means you're most likely not going to make it online because you were gonna make it.
Rym: You're only putting online because it cost you nothing to do so.
Scott: I mean, this is the another thing is, you know In general, I see a lot of people putting stuff online and then putting it online in such a way that it gets taken down.
Scott: It's like dudes just anonymously bit torrent that shit and then there's no one can take credit for it.
Scott: And I think a lot of people don't do that Specifically because they want to take credit like fansub.
Scott: people want to take credit So they won't just put some anonymous fansub on the internet.
Scott: You know people make like some.
Scott: there's.
Scott: Nintendo has gone around hitting a lot of people who made like remakes of Nintendo games.
Scott: There's that like 3d chrono trigger remake.
Scott: They got shut down.
Scott: Remember that it's like dudes.
Scott: If you just didn't put your shit on a website that was identifiable and track trackable to you and just put builds up on bit Tor anonymously, there would be no one to send a takedown notice to and the whole internet could enjoy whatever awesome thing that you're making.
Scott: It's simply your greed of wanting to take credit that is preventing this beautiful sharing of artwork.
Scott: If I was Berkeley and I realized I mean they didn't realize it to begin with Right, I would just be like, oh, okay.
Scott: Take it off my website.
Scott: put it on bit torrent myself So I will.
Scott: I will do that.
Scott: who did that?
Scott: I don't know that one.
Rym: It's a four terabyte archive Sure, but to most people they only know how to use YouTube to see anything.
Rym: So putting it on bit torrent basically means no one will see it.
Scott: You can ask me if some something is something people want now.
Rym: people don't know why it.
Scott: torrent is so easy.
Rym: There's so many people want to watch like their TV shows their cartoons and rather than using a bit torrent To see them legit.
Rym: They watch those like mono audio.
Rym: That's distorted Thing.
Scott: I've been complaining about pretty much my whole life is people would rather do hard work and get shitty results and learn something.
Scott: It's so easy.
Scott: You literally click a link with a magnet next to it and the file downloads.
Scott: then you double click the file and it opens in VLC it does.
Scott: how is it really that I mean, yes, it's easier to go on YouTube.
Scott: where you go to a website click.
Rym: So I think it's like it's like two less steps.
Rym: downloading is not their problem.
Rym: they don't know how to find the stuff.
Rym: You can't just go to pirate Bay.
Rym: Pirate Bay is getting pretty bad.
Scott: Pirate Bay has never failed for me.
Rym: I can think of a lot of things pirate Bay will not have Or any torrent site that's legit.
Scott: you type in the thing you want you see a link to that thing.
Scott: You click it you click the thing with the magnet next to it.
Scott: It downloads.
Rym: A lot of things are not available.
Scott: They're just saying oh, those are things you shouldn't be watching because everything that I watch is on there.
Rym: Okay, mr.
Rym: Only watches Korean dramas, I don't watch any Korean drama only Korean music videos.
Rym: Those are on YouTube for legally This library site quote until library launches to the public in April.
Rym: The videos are only accessible to technical users via the command line.
Rym: Okay They have a command line for this.
Rym: Here's a guide to access library UC Berkeley.
Rym: What do we have is if I click on this in a browser?
Rym: Yeah, the browser does not handle LBRY colon but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so You guys know that I'm variously for whatever reason.
Rym: I know a lot about nuclear weapons.
Rym: So many people have been messaging me or emailing me evil.
Rym: That's why I'm tweeting at me to tell me this exists.
Rym: Yes, I know it exists and it is now my thing of the day.
Rym: basically, uh a whole bunch of videos of Atmospheric tests of nuclear weapons like the named ones like hardtack and The ones in the islands, yep, but mostly the ones that are on the a tolls, but also some that were in the desert.
Rym: Videos of these have been declassified and they're all being scanned in and ultra high quality and just put on YouTube.
Scott: Well, I mean, I've already seen a whole bunch of these.
Scott: so I guess there's more that we didn't see.
Rym: there are hundreds There are 216 tests and there are.
Rym: I think they didn't destroy the world and they're between Thousand films of these.
Scott: Oh, cuz they're felt multiple films of each one.
Rym: Yeah, different angles close and far and also there's I mean what's to be classified?
Scott: It's a big mushroom cloud.
Scott: Well, so depending what can you learn from watching it?
Rym: You can learn a lot because remember atmospheric testing is banned and most nuclear testing is banned.
Rym: actually good.
Rym: The only way nuclear weapons can be developed is mostly by trial and error because the engineering problems are Immense.
Scott: these videos contain like zoom in details of the bombs like insides before they like.
Rym: now it's just a lot of stuff gets classified because While the individual data in general related nuclear weapons, the individual data are not particularly useful to making a nuclear weapon.
Rym: Correlating pieces of information from disparate sources has let people figure some shit out.
Rym: There probably should not have been figured out by those people.
Scott: I do not think that watching videos of mushroom clouds will teach you how to make So some.
Rym: in the early days videos like this could be used to estimate yields thus estimating nuclear Capabilities.
Rym: but in the modern era these videos are not particularly useful for that purpose So they wouldn't be wouldn't declassify them if they were useful.
Rym: Yeah, the point is they've been declassified now because in the modern era they are probably not as useful or it is now Cost effective to make them public.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: So these videos are fascinating because many of them are Views of nuclear weapons that you never could have seen before.
Rym: some of them are slow motion Video extremely slow motion of the frame by frame of the actual reaction and the plasma ball itself Mm-hmm add some scary shit.
Rym: and these things are kind of amazing though.
Rym: A lot of the videos are just black Forever and then a white thing appears in the distance and then black again because There's a lot of videos for different purposes.
Rym: if you're a nuclear enthusiast These are all fascinating.
Rym: and the cool thing is if you watch a video, they're all classified.
Rym: It's like the one on this page I'm looking at.
Rym: is the nutmeg.
Rym: I guess launch or the nutmeg Detonation from operation heart attack one.
Rym: you go to Wikipedia and read exactly what the deal was with that.
Scott: individual tests Like did they just like put these bombs down run the fuck away and then set them off?
Scott: or did they drop them from planes?
Scott: Or did they shoot them for summer?
Rym: all different kinds all different guys all different kinds.
Scott: I want to watch some of the submarine ones.
Rym: There's a famous video of a submarine launch.
Rym: That is okay you to watch.
Scott: they didn't The bomb part.
Scott: I want to see how the submarine shoots it.
Rym: Uh, those exist.
Rym: I'll send you some links.
Rym: Those are cool.
Scott: But though these are these are the surface and then open up a hole on top.
Scott: or can it shoot it from when it's on From under the water.
Scott: Yeah, so just a missile just comes out from under the water basically.
Scott: Yeah, that's scary shit.
Rym: Yeah it is.
Rym: But yeah, these are videos of the explosions primarily.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So what you think of the day?
Scott: So here is a video of Sam and Davis jr.
Scott: One of the coolest people to ever live.
Scott: Yeah, and he's in a commercial selling you something.
Scott: the thing he is selling you is Manischewitz wine, but not just any manischewitz wine not the shit you get on Passover.
Scott: He's selling you Almanetta Manischewitz one like almond.
Scott: It is almond flavored manischewitz wine.
Scott: I don't know if they still make it.
Scott: It might.
Rym: that sounds Horrifying.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not gonna drink the shit.
Scott: I don't have to find out.
Scott: But Sam Davis jr.
Scott: Says you should drink it.
Scott: Maybe you should.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: I'm looking at a wine website.
Rym: Blah blah blah Cream almanada, I guess you can get it.
Rym: Okay, this website's bad.
Rym: I give up.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I don't want to taste this.
Scott: Sammy says otherwise know what?
Rym: so everywhere I click on seems to say email us and we'll tell you Look, I don't think you can get it.
Rym: Yeah, all the all the Google I'm finding actually comes back to that.
Scott: Sammy Definitely existed at one point when Sam Davis jr.
Scott: Was young when Jewish wine was big with Gentiles - When you couldn't get a lot of other wine shortly after prohibition.
Rym: Many oh my god, this just the more I look at this the more terrified I am of it.
Scott: I'm sure you can get some other almond wine and to see how I like amaretto, but that's a cordial.
Scott: It's not wine.
Rym: Yeah, it's a cordial.
Scott: This is grapes plus almonds in the same.
Rym: that does not feel good at best.
Rym: at best That'll be the same as making like an oatmeal.
Scott: I mean, it's.
Scott: I don't sure I don't drink wine But imagining having almonds on my left hand and grapes in my right hand and shove it in both of my face at the same Time and that's not the worst.
Rym: Yeah Yeah Hmm.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I could mix a little bit of amaretto with like a super sweet wine.
Rym: We could try it and see what that tastes like.
Scott: I could just take my grape juice and Put some home and eat some almonds.
Scott: You need some drink drink some grape juice while the almond Want an almond extract of some kind.
Rym: I could give you a tincture of almond drops and get almond butter.
Rym: I I don't think almond butter is gonna do it.
Rym: I don't think you want to mix Butter with your beverage unless you're making a sitting bull.
Rym: I mean just like almond butter, which is a cocktail that if anyone actually orders that in a bar.
Rym: My hat is off to you.
Rym: Look at what a sitting bull is and you'll enjoy it.
Scott: You're gonna get a Harvey while banger In the meta moment.
Rym: we were just at PAX East.
Rym: I will try to get the video up of our panel as soon as I have a chance.
Rym: I've been busy with a lot of other stuff and I'll be out of town this weekend So hopefully sometime by next week.
Rym: I will get that going.
Rym: our next con is ConnectiCon.
Rym: maybe ConnectiCon and like July and zinc icon, I guess I'll be at that.
Rym: you won't be at probably and Pax prime and I'll probably be at PAX Australia this year.
Rym: That's probably gonna happen guys.
Rym: Well, so, uh people keep bugging me.
Rym: you keep that every year.
Rym: you guys like.
Rym: Oh my god, you come back to PAX OS.
Rym: Pretty likely I'm coming back this year.
Rym: You come with me.
Scott: Maybe we'll see.
Rym: You can decide way later.
Rym: cuz if I'm going I'm putting the panels in anyway.
Scott: I'm playing a lot of Zelda right now cuz you know, I don't play some Zelda.
Scott: So I I set up this thing.
Scott: It's actually pretty good.
Scott: I highly recommend it.
Scott: It's been working terrifically called restream.io.
Scott: They they have a website.
Scott: you make an account and then you stream to them with RTMP and they stream to YouTube and Twitch And maybe even other places at the same time.
Scott: so you can watch me play Zelda either on YouTube or twitch.
Scott: Whoa Two different channels whichever one you like better.
Scott: You can use that and watch me play Zelda.
Scott: And if you it's better if people chat to me because then I have things to say and it won't just be me sitting there Quietly, you're not gonna be like welcome to my live stream up gamers.
Scott: No, that's not how I do.
Scott: But if you talk to me, I'll talk to you.
Scott: So, you know, otherwise, I'm just sitting there collecting, you know, spirit orbs and it's not exciting.
Rym: Well, it's like if I did.
Rym: people keep asking me do a live stream of sieve.
Rym: I don't think you understand what a live stream of me playing sieve is like.
Rym: it's literally me staring at the screen Suddenly moving a bunch of stuff around and then going into like menus full of numbers and staring at them for like a minute.
Scott: Yeah, this is it's.
Scott: it's weird, right?
Scott: I'm trying to figure out this sort of like chicken and egg problem of streaming.
Scott: It's like the people have exciting streams.
Scott: They can do it because they have a. they're popular already They have this big old chat full of people.
Scott: and because they have a big old chat full of people they can like really get Some action going right when you play lighter games and you have banter going like all the time.
Scott: But like if I if there's not even I don't need thousands of people I just need like, you know 20 people and like at least one or two of them.
Scott: So at any given moment at least one or two are paying attention or saying something and then I can keep you know The talking going while the streaming is happening.
Scott: It won't just be me video of me being quiet while the game is playing.
Rym: The other option is to do like my advanced war streams where you know enough about the game where you are Constantly talking about the game in detail.
Scott: Yeah, I can do that.
Scott: But the problem is is like I run out of materials like I did Faxanadu and I talked a whole bunch of the beginning of Faxanadu.
Scott: then I ran out of material and then it got quiet.
Scott: I don't think I ever ran out of material on my old advanced war stream Zelda 1 I did a pretty good job because there was always something to say the whole time.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, I say everything I know about the game and then it's just me playing the rest of it.
Rym: I should bring those advanced war streams back anyway, I Haven't done that.
Rym: When did I?
Rym: let's do that?
Rym: That's what.
Scott: that's some content for you while Rym is away.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Yeah, February 2015.
Rym: Whoa, a lot of people watch that one Like way more than I thought I'm gonna be doing a lot of switch streaming.
Scott: in general I got it all like set up.
Scott: So it's not a lot of effort for me to just keep doing it.
Scott: So once I finish Zelda, I'll probably move on to some others these comments.
Rym: who the hell was watching my advanced wars?
Scott: I'm sure though.
Scott: There's not a lot of advanced wars content.
Scott: It's people like advanced.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, these comments are all like But worth nitpicking.
Rym: you didn't move your bomber south of the AAS on that base.
Rym: You kept attacking on this one turn.
Rym: Dude.
Rym: okay, I'm not gonna argue with you, but maybe that was a better move I am confident.
Rym: I made the correct decision in the street.
Scott: You didn't even know what you did.
Rym: I am real fucking good at advanced war.
Scott: How do you remember?
Scott: Maybe that guy's the one who can beat you.
Rym: It's lands end.
Rym: I know that map like inside and out.
Rym: Anyway, that's the one that's shaped like Italy.
Scott: Let's talk about beds.
Rym: So, uh, yeah beds.
Rym: I've been using the same mattress for Years.
Scott: doesn't it like get worn out?
Scott: and me?
Rym: it's a super.
Rym: it's like a double pillow top.
Rym: It's like oh, it's more than a foot thick.
Scott: I don't like them pillow top.
Rym: and it's on top of a box spring because it's an old-style bed.
Rym: Oh, well, and then it's got member.
Rym: I bought the slats to replace the slats that broke because they were like a hundred years old.
Rym: because it's an ancient bed.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: So, uh, I'm thinking about getting a new mattress because I bed technology has changed a lot and the box spring is Obsolete.
Scott: matches are tough, right?
Scott: Cuz you know how they rip you off right and it's like you have this.
Scott: this weird thing that goes on.
Scott: We're number one.
Scott: you go to the mattress store, especially sleepies.
Scott: Don't go there.
Rym: Yeah, they're super regulated and like the mattress The industry is kind of fucked up.
Scott: It's like they try to rip you off and charge you a fortune for this mattress.
Scott: It's not worth the fortune, right?
Scott: But then on the other hand on the other hand a more expensive mattress is clearly superior.
Rym: Yep, so it's like and you gotta try it out.
Rym: You can't just buy one online cuz?
Rym: you don't know right?
Scott: How do I Cuz?
Scott: it's something like a mattress and this is this a line that mattress salesman will tell you.
Scott: but it's also true.
Scott: You sleep on this thing Hopefully eight hours a day, right?
Scott: Every goddamn day you use your mattress probably as much as if not more than you use your computer.
Scott: It is one of the most important things.
Scott: you own it also slowly Your vital juices and oils I'm saying of all the things you own you use that thing a lot.
Rym: So getting a good one is Well case in point remember that show we did where Scott and I back and we didn't have a lot of money.
Rym: Bought our fancy chairs, right?
Scott: Exactly, right in this chair no matter how Or you are.
Scott: a good mattress is a good investment and that's you know.
Scott: It's like a thing mattress salesman that are sleazy will tell you but it's also a true thing.
Scott: But not true thing they tell you is like woo woo.
Scott: We're like this mattress will heal your energies.
Scott: and but right it cost five hundred dollars more.
Scott: get this one.
Scott: Yeah, fuck you Right.
Rym: the ancient Germans lay on the floor on beds of leaves Covered with skins or in a kind of shallow chest filled with leaves and moss.
Rym: Sure I'm not in the Wikipedia page for bad.
Rym: I don't know what else I'm gonna look at here.
Scott: We're not ancient though We're modern so we don't do that.
Rym: But yeah, so, uh I'm a rock in the queen-size bed.
Rym: I remember in RIT because you had a like a tiny bed.
Rym: Was that a single or a twin?
Rym: Like that's how you had.
Rym: you basically slept on a cot at RIT I mean, I just I arrived at college.
Rym: They would go into our bedroom because one of the computers in there and they would always Always no matter what comment on the fact that I had this gigantic bed and Scott had a car in college.
Scott: You know the fact that we're in college.
Scott: It was unusual for you to have a gigantic bed in
Rym: our apartment was like people would look at our window and bother us sometimes Just because if you walked around colony and looked in people's windows I think we were the only apartment in the entire place that had real furniture Maybe like we had an actual couch.
Rym: we had like a wine cabinet, right?
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't unusual for you to have a tiny bed in college.
Scott: It was unusual for you to have a large one.
Rym: Yeah great eyes.
Scott: as soon as he moved into colony we Went over to the furniture store and I bought the cheapest bed they had because it was a college bed.
Rym: But it's still like my whole life.
Rym: as soon as I had a bedroom by myself I have always used a queen bed.
Rym: queen bed has always been the minimum size of a bed for one.
Rym: Mmm, I cannot I have.
Rym: I do not like sleeping on twin beds and a single that did Might as well be a coffin Because I like to I like to.
Rym: I form the starfish if I'm in a bed.
Scott: Well, there's a full-size bed, which is like it's weird Like you hardly ever see a full-size bed because but I had one.
Scott: this is a weird size I guess bigger than twin and smaller than Queen but it's it's big enough for one person sleeping there.
Rym: My parents when I was a kid had a king-size bed in the bedroom like big-ass bed But partly because you know adults but - we had dogs and the dogs want to sleep on the bed.
Scott: Have you got dogs?
Scott: You need the king-size?
Rym: Yeah, a queen-size bed plus any number of dogs not gonna work.
Rym: I'm gonna be tiny tiny dog.
Rym: Yeah, we never had tiny dogs.
Rym: We had real dogs.
Scott: The thing is, you know people make a big deal about bed size and it's like.
Scott: clearly king-size is superior But if you're just one person as long as the bed is big enough to contain your body within its edges It's got to contain your body and your expected sprawl, right?
Rym: You know as long as it has got to be queen-size unless you sleep like a dead vampire.
Scott: No, I mean full-size is Big enough to hold an average adult person, right?
Scott: But maybe you're like fucking Andre the Giant and the king-size isn't even big enough.
Rym: Well get a king-size sleep on it sideways.
Scott: I'm just saying, you know, it depends on your body.
Scott: You just need a bed big enough for your body.
Scott: What if you're a tiny person?
Scott: You don't even need a full-size.
Scott: You could fit in a twin size like right in the middle.
Rym: No problem I'm pretty.
Rym: there was a. I feel like there was a time where the double queen was in fashion.
Rym: Hey, I'm looking at bed sizes now.
Rym: So small single or cot are all the same.
Rym: Yeah, so that's that's even baby.
Rym: There's single twin or bunk.
Rym: They're all the same.
Rym: There's an extra long twin.
Scott: I've never seen an extra long twin.
Rym: All right, there's a Olympic queen Expanded super California.
Rym: What the fuck are all here?
Scott: Here's a chart Like an aspect ratio chart.
Scott: Yeah So California King is slightly longer and slightly less wider than a regular.
Scott: can?
Rym: it seems like the stupidest possible?
Scott: Unless you're really tall, I guess a king is actually not any longer than Queen.
Scott: It's just a little bit wider.
Rym: Yeah, that's the Queen though.
Rym: I always thought of you know twin full Seven feet tall the king isn't long enough.
Scott: I guess you need the California King.
Scott: I guess that extra few inches, but even that might not be long.
Rym: That's why cuz.
Rym: in McMansions there was a time because I remember talking to real estate agents where they always talk about how this bedroom will fit a double queen.
Rym: cuz Double queen seemed to be the thing whatever And there'd be two queen beds.
Scott: the point is as you can see on this chart This is a full-size bed is a reasonably sized bed.
Scott: You just don't see them too often.
Rym: Yeah, cuz but twin is way too small.
Scott: Well, I mean if you're an adult Yeah, if you're a child and you fit on one is not a problem.
Rym: even as a child middle school high school I had a queen-size bed.
Scott: Anyway, so Enough of that bed sizes, right?
Scott: The point I'm gonna make is that a harder mattress is bullshit and you'll die you want.
Rym: Ideally, you want a pillow top slab.
Rym: just sink into it.
Scott: pillow tops are for babies and princesses who worried about peas and shit.
Rym: I'm real worried about peas.
Rym: now It's like my mouse right if there is.
Rym: if there is so much as a speck of sand under my mouse pad I know I don't feel it.
Scott: I'll feel it.
Scott: but Bed now.
Scott: the bed should be like a slab of granite with a sheet on it.
Scott: So it's not.
Rym: why don't you sleep on the Floor?
Rym: then why don't you get a futon?
Rym: Why even have a bed?
Rym: So the Japanese futon the problem.
Scott: sleeping on the floor that shit is cold.
Rym: It's not cold.
Rym: If you're living a nice place.
Scott: No, it's cool.
Rym: Our floor is not cool.
Rym: fine Then get.
Rym: why don't you actually get like an elevated futon of some kind?
Scott: because it's not hard and it's not the right.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Scott: I'm just gonna get it.
Scott: You just gotta get an extra firm mattress actual mattress But also extra firms.
Scott: you lay on it and it moves a tiny bit.
Scott: So it fits the shape of your body because your body isn't flat right.
Scott: it fits the shape of your body moving.
Rym: That's called being soft.
Scott: It fits the shape of your body, but then Every part where it touches your body has no give.
Scott: it's like, you know, it's like.
Scott: it's like if someone but that's not.
Rym: That's like memory foam.
Scott: No memory foam squishes too much right a firm mattress.
Rym: How can it squish too much?
Rym: once you sink into it?
Rym: Everything has equal pressure.
Scott: then you're all sunken in like Like an adult.
Rym: I hate that shit.
Scott: no sleep my side I.
Rym: so I actually I think part of our disagreement is that I'm pretty skinny and my bony em stick way out.
Rym: a big big chunks of my body can be described as Antlers encased in skin.
Scott: I have that.
Rym: Yeah, but if I sleep on my side for one my arm Will fall asleep.
Scott: that happens to me a lot.
Scott: Yeah, no matter what not no matter what.
Rym: but unless I twist a month or so and Also, I crush my balls.
Scott: I don't have that problem.
Rym: unless I put a spacer pillow between the knees I could just push my balls out front.
Rym: Yeah, I can push them out front, but that shit ain't comfortable.
Scott: I don't really have problems.
Rym: I do like the hip splay, but then that's not comfortable.
Scott: I don't really have a problem with that.
Scott: I actually do sleep on my back Just like way back.
Scott: are they like growing out of your taint instead of out of the front?
Rym: they actually have a pretty sizable Roaming range.
Scott: let's say How close are they?
Scott: are they much closer to your asshole?
Rym: I think no, I think they ever.
Rym: they have quite a range.
Rym: I think it's just that my thighs are actually really thick Really big sure like I cannot.
Rym: if I close my legs together I will crush them right now.
Scott: so another important aspect of a bed Not just the mattress which is the most important part of the bed because it's the part that's actually functional right.
Scott: the other parts are Just like decorations that hold the mattress up off the ground unless you have.
Rym: so There's the difference between.
Rym: like there's a modern beds often are much lower to the ground.
Scott: Then older beds where I don't understand why you want a high up bed.
Scott: It's like what you want to climb into that shit.
Scott: just keep it down low So it's easy to get into.
Scott: and if higher up is warmer you want.
Scott: by your own definition higher up is warmer.
Scott: It's barely warmer.
Scott: Yeah, it's not warm enough to make a difference.
Scott: Your thermometer would not change.
Rym: also being up high is kind of nice.
Scott: No, if you're in a bunk bed you want That is at a height at which if you sit down on it It is a chair levels.
Scott: That way it can also be used as a chair.
Rym: Never sit on the side of your bed.
Rym: I like to jump up into my bed.
Scott: You can sit on the side of your bed and put your slippers on Or sit on the side of it and then swing your legs into it.
Rym: also higher a bed means storage underneath.
Scott: I mean every bed should have a little storage underneath unless it's one of those ultra modern beds.
Rym: That's basically like way low to the ground making a bed.
Scott: That's literally on the ground.
Scott: It's just sacrificing storage space.
Rym: also super high up bed means the rabbits can't jump into it.
Scott: Well, that's the end.
Scott: cause trouble different problem.
Rym: That is a very specific problem to our household.
Rym: So yeah, Scott if you're in a bunk bed you want the upper bunk in the lower bunk.
Scott: I don't really care.
Rym: You really Wow, really?
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why people care so much I mean when you're a kid the up one is so fun Right because I say you fall out of it like I did at RIT.
Scott: Well, the point is the top part is so fun like we right until you roll out of bed.
Scott: But the bottom part is like ah so luxurious Right, and especially the bunk beds we had when I was a kid.
Scott: the bottom part was full and the top part was twin.
Scott: So it was like the bottom part was way better.
Rym: But I do like the super soft pillow top Because I don't I just I enjoy the very calm soft comfy like sink into it very decadent feeling.
Rym: I'm very.
Rym: that's very much my time.
Scott: I like the hard time anyway.
Scott: other bad aspects sheets Thread count ain't no joke.
Rym: It's also mostly counterfeit lies.
Scott: It's also true.
Scott: See at the one hand you go into the store and it's like man thread count a billion and you're like what let me see.
Scott: And it's actually thread count like a hundred and like this.
Scott: shit is like fucking sandpaper.
Scott: fuck that shit, right?
Scott: It is lying to you, you know.
Scott: But if you do actually get the high thread count biz like silk or like whoa It feels so good.
Scott: You lay down into it like whoa.
Rym: But I find that the sheets themselves don't matter as much as what kinds of blankets you put over them because if you have A blanket that is a little more airy It'll make even crappy sheets feel way better.
Rym: Well, let's just do coal.
Rym: see.
Scott: the sheets are about the texture of the material touching your skin.
Scott: That's what the sheets are about.
Scott: the blankets just go on top of the sheets And keep you warm as long as they got.
Rym: so usually the blanket is the base layer for base warmth And then that comforters are actually keeping you warm.
Scott: However, I Like the sheet is the part that touches your skin.
Scott: So the textures of the other parts don't matter.
Scott: only their insulation properties matter.
Rym: But if they're if they're insulating but also have a little bit more air give like the whole air is insulating.
Scott: That's what the air is for.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: So it's like technical fabrics.
Rym: You could have things that will insulate it.
Rym: Do you know by unidirectional blankets?
Rym: Yeah, actually that might be pretty good tactical blank tactical blankets.
Rym: but I Don't like comforters and I would never own one because my.
Scott: what are you doing?
Scott: What do you wear in the?
Rym: What I'm getting to is my entire life I have only ever ever lived in places with the exception of colony Manor at RIT Where the HVAC systems were such that there were not drafts and the house was always Pretty much everywhere a very nice temperature to where a comforter was literally never ever ever needed ever.
Scott: So you just heat your whole house with fire and then not use blankets.
Rym: No, I'd use blankets.
Rym: I would not use comforters.
Rym: I would always have a sheet and then a reasonable medium or thin blanket Depending if it's summer or winter and never have a comforter Because the comforter would always be way too hot because the house is always like 76 degrees.
Rym: So This apartment.
Rym: we're in New York, right?
Rym: The other thing about no control over your heat your apartments always like a million degrees.
Scott: The other thing about do you have a comforter?
Rym: Yeah, you use it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm using it right now While your apartment's way too hot for that.
Scott: That's the thing about a comforter.
Scott: is that even in the summer you get under the comforter and it feels great.
Scott: It feels great.
Rym: No matter what too hot.
Rym: You'll sweat.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: it's temperature regulating magic of the comforter, right?
Scott: Is that like?
Rym: what kind of cover do you have?
Rym: This temperature regulating comforters are just too much.
Scott: No, you get under it and you always feel great.
Scott: It doesn't matter what the temperature is outside.
Rym: I'm gonna get under your comforter.
Rym: It'll be too hot.
Scott: There's no such thing as too hot.
Rym: There you you were just implying that keeping my house at 76 degrees was too hot.
Scott: No, I said is a waste of energy when you just get under the blanket.
Scott: Let's see.
Rym: However, it was not much of a waste of energy because I've also always lived in super fucking insulated houses.
Scott: Anyway, modern like it's the most ridiculous thing I've ever heard.
Scott: you put a blanket people even in fact.
Rym: Actually now they live in your days in New York.
Rym: The problem is stuff stays too warm because a lot of people have control over the heat.
Scott: even in the days when people had Fireplaces in their bedrooms they still had blank.
Rym: because fireplace in the bedroom means you live in a drafty ass piece of shit pre-world War.
Scott: one house fireplace in the bedroom is way warm.
Rym: Yes one till you burn your house down to.
Rym: fireplaces are way too warm.
Rym: I lived in a house for a while when I was in Poughkeepsie that was heated primarily by Fireplaces, let me tell you it was way too.
Rym: I slept naked on the top of my bed because that that thing had two settings.
Rym: no the Sun and Nothing.
Scott: no such thing is too warm It's cold.
Rym: You gotta get warm, but I actually prefer these days to have just a sheet and no blanket.
Rym: pretty much ever even in hotels In the summer, yeah, even in the winter cuz that's just so airy and the hotel.
Rym: you want to turn off that AC?
Scott: Yeah, I mean in the summer yeah just a sheet.
Rym: I Feel like we should skip pillows cuz that could be a whole show in and of itself.
Rym: Pillows could be a whole show.
Scott: I switched to the Z pillow.
Scott: It's been working out.
Rym: Yeah, I bought the highest rated.
Scott: See memory foam is bullshit.
Scott: I don't like no memory foam.
Rym: I got you should try my pillow.
Rym: It's the highest rated pillow on Amazon.
Scott: No mine is the highest rate pill on Amazon.
Rym: is that your mind is eyes memory phone?
Scott: It's silicone type stuff.
Scott: It's pillow shaped not like a weird blob.
Rym: I want the hump and then bigger hump.
Rym: now I need neck support cuz I sleep on my back.
Scott: the Z pillow has neck support.
Scott: the way it works Is that it is.
Scott: even though it is normal pillow shape the middle area is has more bigger holes in it and is less dense.
Scott: So it squishes more than the part Normal pillow.
Rym: that's bullshit.
Scott: It is shaped like a normal pillow But when you put your head on it The middle part goes in more than the edge part.
Rym: you find the pillow that I bought some bullshit.
Rym: memory foam memory foams garbage Foam is great except while you're so people who say they have memory foam have some bootleg crab That smells like the inside of a factory from China.
Scott: You know, you scrolled a lot way down this page for the highest rated pillow.
Scott: It shouldn't?
Rym: it's sorted by irrelevance not high.
Scott: It may be the first one.
Rym: average customer review.
Rym: Let's see.
Scott: Is it the first one that black thing?
Rym: It's that weird blousey.
Scott: It's not that weird black thing.
Rym: I'm guess No, it's not looking for it.
Rym: I bought this pillow like three years ago.
Rym: So, uh-huh.
Scott: What if Z pillows where it's at?
Rym: Only on the top?
Scott: that's bullshit.
Rym: Also doesn't need cold pillow.
Rym: It looks more like this.
Rym: Yeah This pillow.
Rym: the selling point was that the core is like a heat sink almost So it always feels cool no matter what.
Scott: that is what the Z pillows all about has the holes in it and those holes make it always nice and cold and You get your pillowcase on.
Rym: there is you know, it's not this pillow, but it kind of looks like this pillow.
Scott: It's weird, right?
Scott: You can never be too warm.
Scott: But for some reason I'm all about the cold pillow and when one part of the pillow warms up I move my head to a different part of the pillow.
Scott: That's warm.
Scott: I mean, it's cold and I got.
Rym: I got these sleep.
Rym: Oh, it's lost of stars since I bought it.
Scott: Yeah, it's some garbage.
Rym: Oh, I bought it in 2014.
Rym: All right, that's some bull three years ago.
Rym: So look at this.
Rym: See it's nice shape.
Scott: Yeah, it's a piece of shit.
Rym: It's this is the best fucking pillow and I have lent this pillow to friends who stay over because all my other normal pillows I actually have bird feathers in them because they're like fancy down pillows.
Rym: down pillows are real comfortable But uh, if you're allergic to chickens, that's bad news.
Scott: the only problem I have with feather pillows is that when the feather bottom parts poke out and stab you a Well-designed down pillow will not have that problem.
Scott: pillows on my couch have that problem.
Rym: Yep This pillow is the best pillow.
Rym: It's so garbage.
Rym: It's so cool on your skin garbage.
Rym: Wonder why it got low rate?
Rym: because you used to have five stars because people wise up and got the Z pillow.
Rym: I think I got the Queen.
Scott: one realized memory foam is bullshit.
Rym: All right, let's see.
Rym: Let me look at these reviews.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: what people say is I have a blah blah blah.
Rym: I want to see the one star reviews.
Scott: They're always gonna say something stupid.
Rym: a few things went terribly wrong with this pillow.
Rym: Oh the pillow I got was not the one it's okay.
Rym: So this guy got ripped off and got a bootleg pillow.
Rym: This pillow sucks.
Rym: no support at all.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Scott: It's like it must have a giant head.
Rym: It was hard to sleep on.
Scott: okay, dude, maybe you had it upside down.
Rym: they smell horrible.
Rym: No, you got a bootleg.
Rym: I'm not happy with this pillow.
Rym: I got it help cooling my head at night.
Rym: Bad smell.
Rym: No bad smell.
Rym: No, it was so hard.
Rym: This pill is not hard at all.
Rym: I Think these people are all day.
Rym: This is like so when we were in on the ski trip right sound like a game developer reading their own steam reviews.
Rym: Yeah When we were in on the ski trip, right?
Rym: I was looking at reviews because there aren't that many restaurants out in the boonies and there's this Mexican place and Most of the reviews were like this food is garbage.
Rym: It'll make you sick.
Rym: Fuck this place.
Rym: Like.
Rym: the reviews were real bad.
Rym: The place had like three stars total, maybe two and a half.
Rym: There was one review and all it said was two words all lowercase run away.
Scott: But best review ever.
Scott: it still gave it three stars.
Scott: Well three stars run away.
Scott: I Never seen my run away be one star.
Rym: I really want to know what the story is there to where it still got the extra star Two star bonus for runaway.
Rym: But I'm thinking about buying a new bed because that mattress is accumulated 16 to 20 years of my.
Scott: yeah, that's about the lifetime for a mattress.
Rym: Yeah, actually I've been told by people are trying to sell me mattresses that every five years you buy a new one.
Scott: That's people trying to sell you mattresses.
Rym: See how I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna Google right now also often.
Rym: I type how often and the first Google representations.
Rym: Should you poop?
Rym: Should you shower?
Rym: Should you wash your hair?
Rym: Should you change your sheets?
Scott: Okay I don't change my shoes enough.
Rym: I do not change mine enough either, but I'm trying to change it more often.
Rym: your Mattress that's actually one of the recommendations here.
Rym: five to seven years according to the National Sleep Foundation.
Scott: The National Sleep Foundation is an organization that is trying to sell more mattresses.
Scott: My mattress is already like eight years old.
Rym: I'm not buying a new one for consumer reports, which is also kind of a scam and not as much consumer reports.
Scott: Hey, you're mostly legit ten years.
Scott: All right, so I plan to buy a new mattress in three years.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with the mattress.
Scott: I am mine is just so old that I bought it when I moved to New York.
Rym: Oh, no, and it's probably gained ten pounds from the oily secretions of my body over the last.
Scott: Oh, that's something else.
Scott: A lot of people don't have these but I highly recommend the mattress pad.
Rym: Mattress pads.
Rym: I have felt like are obsolete and black.
Rym: So the mattress pad is pads always.
Rym: you know what I used to use them for.
Rym: if you have a shitty mattress It makes the mattress more comfortable.
Scott: No, so you're looking for that pillow top action, right?
Scott: I mattress pad I have does not provide any pillowy top.
Scott: It is merely sort of like a mattress protector.
Scott: in a way you put it over the mattress Then you put your sheets on and that way your oily secretions go into the mattress pad Which you can replace and your mattress is still beautiful to new always
Rym: But I feel like that's what
Scott: it's for
Rym: and make the mattress worse In terms of airiness because I actually part of what
Scott: I'm mine Do not affect.
Scott: the one I have is does not affect the feel of the mattress in any way.
Scott: All right, it is simply a Absorbing oiliness protector to keep the mattress itself You know relatively clean because it's easy to clean and take a mattress pad and throw it in the washing machine.
Scott: It's not easy to throw a mattress in the washing machine and the sheet is not enough to protect the mattress from your body.
Rym: Yeah, definitely not the sheets themselves.
Scott: You'll see that you need that extra layer.
Scott: So My mattress pad is all like yellow from skin oils.
Rym: Yeah, my mattress is all.
Scott: yeah It's supposed to be.
Scott: I should probably actually replace the mattress pad because even after washing it it's still yellow with skin oils.
Rym: But yeah, I'm thinking about dishes.
Rym: So actually if anyone wants an antique like Fancy rosewood bed.
Scott: I mean a bed the bed part is a bed, right?
Scott: It doesn't even fucking matter It's just if I get a modern bed.
Scott: All the bed does is hold the mattress off the.
Rym: if I get a modern mattress I want to get a modern bed frame because this is a classic old-style bed frame meaning It's two pieces of wood on the side a headboard a footboard and you put slats.
Scott: What do you think a modern bed is?
Scott: It's some sort of square structure that you know has slats and elevates a mattress off the ground.
Rym: Often modern ones don't have slats.
Rym: They just have a pad like a plate like a pad or rails to put the thing on.
Scott: It's all the same.
Rym: It's some sort of platform that is Have built-in storage and stuff in a way that I don't want to just like slide shit under the bed Sure, but that those aren't related to the bed part.
Rym: So if anybody I don't want to put a modern mattress on this Current bed frame because it's an ancient as bed frame doesn't matter.
Scott: It'll the mattress is the part you sleep on.
Scott: It'll feel the same no matter what frame is elevated.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of the modern mattresses I want this one because it has the slats.
Rym: I'd have to have a box spring or something under the mattress.
Rym: I just have a modern.
Scott: my IKEA bed had came with slats and I just put a big flat piece of wood over the slats And then put the mattress on top of that.
Rym: And it's what kind of matches do you have?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: no box spring though?
Rym: No, I do feel like box springs are obsolete.
Scott: You need a box spring depending on the kind of frame I don't know.
Rym: or if you got an old Usually use the box spring.
Scott: if the kind of frame you have is the kind is just like a metal rectangle with wheels under it And then you put the box spring on that and the box spring basically is the platform that the magic can go on.
Rym: here We go types of frames platform frame which is used without box frames.
Rym: That's the modern ones.
Rym: That's the one I'm looking at getting.
Rym: captain has drawers beneath the frame.
Scott: I guess that's what I had when I was a kid.
Rym: Oh water beds.
Rym: water beds were real big in the 80s water beds.
Scott: There's a kid I knew who had one.
Scott: it was really cool and fun, but I don't
Rym: know
Scott: if it's a good idea to actually Sleep on one every night the
Rym: ones that
Scott: was like this thing where you see one or you're laying one And it's so cool and so awesome, and then if you actually do it every day, and that's like your main bed I think it's bad.
Rym: They're not actually that comfortable if they have baffles to prevent them from sloshing.
Rym: Then you lose a lot of the aspects of it being a water bed.
Rym: But if you don't have those baffles every time you move it'll make waves also.
Scott: What if it lock leaks?
Rym: Yeah, that happens.
Rym: Also.
Rym: They're so heavy that they will break your floor.
Rym: true and there's.
Rym: they're probably full of bacteria and nasty as water in there.
Rym: well I mean sealed system, so it doesn't matter a lot of leases in New York.
Rym: ban water beds.
Scott: Yes, cuz you'll flood your fucking neighbors if it's not happens.
Rym: Don't go also.
Rym: They're too heavy.
Scott: That's also bad.
Rym: Yeah, everything on water beds is bad.
Rym: I feel like they were a trend in the 80s, then they just died.
Rym: yep So the modern version painted 1971 Popular in the 80s and 90s and now they're basically dead.
Scott: I feel like you can make a water bed like a new design out of something like you know more modern Material that doesn't just have one big blob of water But has lots of little.
Rym: that's what a lot of the ones in the 90s did.
Scott: they had various baffles or like some pone in Some water chamber, oh, but it's like you could just use air instead.
Scott: air is fine.
Rym: Oh, they also had to be heated.
Rym: you had to heat that crap.
Scott: That's not good.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, there are a lot.
Rym: Okay, there's a whole article on water beds.
Rym: another a bad news bear.
Scott: yeah air mattress is fine You don't need a water.
Rym: Only good thing for air mat for water beds is when you were a kid in the 80s and 90s You'd have regular trips to the mall with your family's lived in the burbs and think you did Rookstone would have it.
Rym: You'd you go into the department store because you always went into the department store because there's something your family always had to buy In there.
Rym: and what I would do me and my brother is we run off from her parents.
Rym: every time There's a bed on display.
Rym: We'd run at it and jump on it to see if it was a water bed Because maybe one in ten was totally a water bed back then also.
Scott: There's also those beds that like Like the motor to recline and change whatever Used to see those on TV commercials.
Rym: you still see those on TV commercials if you watch TV.
Rym: those are for old people or injured.
Rym: Yeah, I don't like technology beds because I feel like like a bed with a massage or a heater inside.
Rym: I feel like those are all just cheap crap that are gonna break or aren't actually that pleasant?
Scott: Yeah There hasn't been one yet.
Scott: if there was one that was so good it would become the new standard for beds everywhere.
Rym: unless I were Bedridden or old I would never want a bed that does that reclining nonsense.
Rym: I would just get our recliner.
Scott: and about a nice nice vibrating bed.
Scott: you put a quarter in a ticket ticket ticket ticket ticket.
Rym: Yeah, last time I ran into one of those was in a real bad motel.
Rym: I think we've exhausted our bed talk.
Scott: Oh, no we hadn't.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Ellen Joyce, Rebecca Dunn Nicholas, Brenda.
Rym: I didn't think Amanda Duchette.
Rym: Great job.
Rym: Emoji my stady calm William I said Rose Jeremy minor cookie cat.
Rym: He left his family behind cookie cat.
Rym: I nine nine nine nine.
Rym: Christian coons one two three comma four five six comma seven eight nine comma one Oh one two comma three four five comma six seven eight kind of nine.
Rym: Oh one comma two three four comma five six seven kind of eight nine.
Rym: Oh Sherman one whole rare.
Rym: Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy.
Rym: I paid five five bucks to make Rym say Topeka Brian Fisher sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich chart option.
Rym: Jojo Joestar Tyler Eller Shawn Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin employee of the month isn't all ham and plaques.
Rym: Brian Cedroni Blab bear steel toys Redacted.
Rym: Chris mid give.
Rym: Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We're back for bad and you know that thing.
Rym: I keep talking about the political thing that I said.
Rym: hold your horses and wait.
Rym: I'm going to a meeting this weekend to make that move forward in a substantial way.
Rym: It's a working weekend So stay tuned.
Rym: things are happening.
Rym: And now I leave you with something that I doubt many of you remember.
Rym: I'm not sure but it could be.
Rym: well, there's only one way to find out.
Rym: It doesn't look good.
Rym: What's the matter?
Rym: Every time we use the key it seems to get weaker and the doors a little harder to open.
Scott: How many doors can you open before it stops working?
Rym: Oh Look Hamish Book said the puppies came from a place with snow and strange lights.
Scott: Do you suppose?
Rym: Let's just see what's going on.