Rym: It's Thursday September 14th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about souvenirs and such.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You can always tell when we didn't have a good idea for what to do the show on.
Scott: Yeah I got like tons of like Open-e bits and I got a few things of the day.
Scott: I got actually have a lot of news, but it's news.
Scott: I got a save for Monday Tuesday Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have any Thursday appropriate news.
Rym: I'm gonna get more Thursday appropriate news or at least a lot of geek bites.
Rym: cuz I'm watching a lot of stuff That you're not watching.
Scott: So there's a lot of stuff.
Scott: You're not watching.
Rym: Yeah You should watch a little bit academia though because I want to I'm gonna sue.
Scott: I'm paying for Hulu right now.
Scott: Cuz South Park started yesterday.
Scott: I'm gonna watch it as soon as I get home today.
Rym: crushed Velvet is the material you're looking for.
Scott: I will go buy some.
Scott: Thank you.
Scott: I'll buy that.
Rym: wait Let's get some crushed velvet underwear some crushed velvet gig night.
Scott: That's all you.
Scott: I'm just getting crushed velvet tablecloths.
Rym: I'd like to drink myself in velour.
Rym: anyway in the news, uh I hope you voted and you're probably thinking wait didn't?
Scott: I guess if you live in New York State?
Rym: We had our primary and Emily and I went in.
Rym: so the saddest thing.
Rym: we went to vote in the primary and one no one's there dot.
Rym: there were ten poll workers there and they were all So Excited that someone showed up.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah that we were there.
Rym: Well, I had a tab playing in the background and So happy that we were there voting.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the two choices we had where we had to vote in the mayoral primary for the Democrats Which that's actually you're voting for mayor.
Scott: Basically, that's yeah, that's the mayoral election.
Rym: I don't care if you want to say you're an independent because the Democrats are more centrist than you'd like.
Rym: like that.
Rym: I can understand that.
Rym: but if you live in a place like New York The Democratic primaries are the elections for literally everything because Republicans they win in shit Some districts.
Scott: but yeah where you live you that was pretty much that was the vote.
Scott: the people you voted for are the winners.
Scott: Yeah, and you might think oh, well, you know, it's just it's already decided but it's like no It's not looking like some of the percentages.
Scott: It's not like, you know, one person is a hundred percent and everyone else has one.
Scott: It's like you'll see like Oh de Blasio had like 70 or 80.
Rym: Imagine that like 11 people voted in that to have primary.
Rym: No.
Scott: No, it gets down to two digits past the decimal point.
Scott: the
Rym: biggest danger is like in the Democratic primaries in New York, you'll see like one normal liberal I'm not a crackpot liberal and then a bunch of fake liberals are actually really conservative or religious or weird And you can't risk one of them win in a primary cuz no one voted.
Scott: no, that's that happens.
Scott: It's simple fell there.
Rym: So on the other side we had a public advocate.
Rym: I think was the other thing we could vote for which shit?
Rym: Yeah so there were two people running and I looked up their platforms and their platforms are pretty much identical.
Rym: other than The only way to distinguish these two candidates.
Rym: is that the incumbent who I voted for?
Rym: Black woman and the person running against her is a white dude.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I voted for her.
Scott: cuz duh She hasn't done a bet.
Scott: I mean if you look at her platform is great.
Scott: if you look at like If you go to any sort of online community of New York City people who are either talking about local or state-level politics Basically everyone no matter what side they're on Bashes everybody who's currently in a elected position.
Scott: Oh, it's exactly the same wasn't?
Scott: you?
Scott: go to a mess game and those are your players That you picked.
Scott: and during the offseason you were like, yeah trade for that guy And now that they're on the field your bum.
Scott: Yeah, I got the field your bum, right?
Scott: So that's what you see.
Scott: You never see a single positive thing said about anyone.
Scott: So if you go look up, you know Letitia online and you'll see like people talking.
Scott: everyone's like, ah, she's done such a crappy job She's worthless.
Scott: But then it's like if you actually look at what anyone does it's like they're pretty much doing what they said.
Scott: They would All my representatives.
Scott: It's like I was like.
Scott: it's like even if I thought about running.
Scott: It's like well, I can't even run for anything cuz I'm not better than any of the people.
Scott: Yeah But they're all doing what I would do on.
Rym: the other difference was that the incumbent who I voted for has a little more like her.
Rym: policies were more focused on social justice and The white dude his like the top of his policy list.
Rym: we're all about small business Mm-hmm, and I feel like social justice is way more important right now for obvious reasons.
Scott: Yeah, the important thing is small businesses in New York are having real problems.
Rym: really Yeah, but it's really good.
Rym: my message is that if you didn't vote in the primary, whatever But at least vote in the 2017 election not because it matters because you're probably gonna only have one person.
Scott: Like it's like they're all I may say have no choices.
Scott: The only choice I have is I go in and it's like choose five judges and there's six judges and One of the judges is like not is a total crackpot.
Scott: Obviously not a real judge.
Rym: Yeah, it's like.
Rym: it's like It's choose the five judges you already have.
Rym: it's like, okay, just whack-a-mole and pick the crackpot.
Rym: It's almost like a capture for government.
Scott: This is why you got to go next year when you vote for governor because not only do you vote for governor the most important Action, right?
Scott: You can also maybe kick out your awful state senator if you have an awful one like Like well the next district over does I have the best one and the next district over has the worst pretty much.
Rym: if you don't Live in the limits of actual New York City or state representatives are probably garbage, right?
Scott: But also That's when the questions come out.
Rym: Oh, yeah the questions that people don't read and vote randomly on the ones.
Scott: Remember we were in Beacon and we voted yes MTA money and everyone else voted no MTA money.
Scott: And now everyone's complaining that.
Scott: and as old as GeekNights that we were living in Beacon at the time As old as GeekNights, we voted.
Scott: Yes, MTA money back then in last decade and now this decade everyone's like MTA sucks.
Scott: It's like I seem to remember voting.
Scott: Yes, MTA money in 2008 or something.
Rym: We could certainly fully fund the schools with a simple $1 per year tax and Homer's like taxes.
Rym: So Yeah, in other news Scott forwarded this article to me and the headline really speaks for itself.
Rym: What was that headline?
Scott: Uranus opens and closes every day to let out planets.
Rym: I feel like every copywriter in the entirety of Journalism was trying to craft the same headline for this story.
Scott: I mean it really.
Scott: I'm sure this is gonna tell you some story.
Scott: I don't haven't read it and I don't really care about like how.
Scott: storms on Uranus or there's like a maybe a hole in the surface.
Scott: There's a storm in Uranus right now and this stuff inside of the planet that comes out for some reason You know and I saw pictures and it showed like it looked like, you know, Jupiter has a giant-ass storm on it.
Scott: giant-ass storm yeah, I Do was like a picture of like a day in the life of Uranus and in one part of it The storm was there and another part the storm was gone and it was opening and closing.
Scott: somehow It's like.
Scott: you don't need to really know much more than that.
Scott: You're never going there not in your lifetime.
Rym: So there's an episode of Rick and Morty and that shows great like.
Rym: you haven't watched it I know but it's actually pretty great.
Scott: There was some drama with that show.
Rym: today a new drama.
Scott: No involving the No, the animators like making a union and the show running guy being upset.
Rym: So the animator union thing has been an ongoing issue not just with that show.
Rym: Yeah, well that that's a good time to good news for Tuesday the Korean TV stations are on strike - yeah.
Rym: But anyway in that episode there's this like gaseous entity that That gets named fart.
Rym: And really that's the thing.
Scott: but it stands for.
Rym: it's an acronym for something but you don't care No, so basically it can read minds and it.
Rym: but I don't want to get into the weeds of this episode But it turns out it's evil and it'll destroy all life in the universe if it gets its way from its home like dimension.
Scott: so hold it in.
Rym: so Morty murders it and then he goes back on the spaceship with Rick and Rick wasn't there.
Rym: like Rick doesn't know that this thing was actually evil.
Rym: and then Rick's like, I know you're sad You miss your friend fart, but I got good news.
Rym: I actually found out where his kind come from and There's a portal and there's thousands of them behind this portal and we're gonna get him.
Rym: We're gonna bring him into our universe and he's like, no, you'll kill us.
Rym: Oh, okay, and then Rick just farts and just laughs and that's the end of the episode.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So yeah Uranus, uh, Always love a good Uranus joke.
Rym: Yeah just killing time before we get to the main bits and Things of the day.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: This is a time-lapse, right?
Scott: But this time-lapse is 30 days.
Scott: I've made time lapses before of like Hurricane Sandy out my window and stuff.
Scott: I recorded audio time lapses of board games at packs.
Rym: It's like if anyone wants that I have a branch recording of like a couple hours of the hurricane Whoever.
Scott: this was made a 30-day long time-lapse, which like I'm just like, whoa How did you get you powered your camera for 30 days your 30 days of storage?
Scott: but I guess if you're only taking like what a photo every hour or so, there's plenty of time between shots to like You know change batteries or swap SD cards or who knows what you're doing.
Scott: Right, we kept it, you know.
Scott: still you got to remember and keep it going for 30 days and line everything up.
Scott: make it Perfect.
Scott: It's not easy.
Scott: It's a lot of work.
Scott: But this person was on a Container whistle.
Rym: Oh, those are a good kind of whistle.
Scott: I think it starts that it starts the time-lapse like leaving the Suez Canal And then it goes really really far and you can basically see the whole world, you know the whole Atlantic Ocean.
Scott: I guess it's one of the better time lapses I've seen ever like it could be like top ten time lapses in history of time lapses.
Scott: This is real good.
Scott: It's only gonna take you how long to watch?
Rym: Ten minutes.
Scott: I think I think that's a good use of your ten minutes compared to whatever bullshit You were gonna do like listen to GeekNights.
Scott: It's just top this podcast right now.
Rym: It's definitely worth ten minutes of your time.
Rym: So this is just a tiny thing, but I bumped into it the other day, which is really cute.
Rym: It's a really short animation and it's just princess peach princess a peach pulling up a vegetable and Killing some dude with it.
Rym: and that's it.
Rym: and it's just really cute.
Rym: and I like stuff like this.
Rym: Okay, that's all I got.
Scott: Is it by an animator?
Rym: We know it's not by one of the like four channels that we keep inexplicably going to.
Scott: you mean like Piece of sheep.
Scott: He's a rice pirate.
Rym: Yeah No, this is Mark Hendry.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, maybe Mark Hendry's worth subscribing to.
Scott: let's check it out.
Rym: Yeah, this is like 20 seconds long and the whole rest of the video is just like Storyboards and concept and animatic and how-to and like everything.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's just really cute.
Scott: Okay, so I yeah in the moment the booklet book is the fifth season I am halfway done with this book and I just read chapter where crazy shit happened.
Scott: I didn't think was gonna happen soon at the end of the book.
Rym: I'm like, yeah I'm into it what I've read so far and I'm gonna power through it over the coming weeks so we can do a show On it, you know I can say about it.
Scott: It's doing one of those things that fantasy Novels tend to do where you have one chapter about one set of characters another chapter about another set of characters You start to go a little back and forth, right?
Scott: What these are people up to see what those people are up to right and usually when you have a situation like that It's a prince of nothing.
Rym: Yeah, I end up caring a whole lot about some of them.
Rym: Yeah, and not a whole lot about Like Oh kill moments again.
Rym: I just want to yeah, it's like good stuff.
Rym: another kill moments chapter.
Rym: Then at the end when you stop seeing the horse breaking you're like wait, what's kill moments up to now?
Rym: Well, I want to kill moments chapter.
Scott: No, I just want I just want horse breaking every chapter Interesting that kill moments.
Rym: His name is kill moments considering the name of the king.
Scott: Anyway, the point is that in this book fifth season that you should definitely read it is our book club selection.
Scott: they have gotten to a point where I now equally care about Every single different thing they're focusing on.
Scott: there is actually a moment.
Scott: There is hot shit going on in all of the different Lines of story and I'm can't wait for the snatch car crash to happen.
Rym: I just still can't get over.
Rym: I Love the planet and that kind of stuff.
Rym: because now that I've seen that theme because there's the game player of games planet There's the dune planet.
Rym: I'm starting to notice other planets.
Rym: I think the prince of nothing planet might have like literal hell inside of it Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I feel like that's gonna be a thing with me.
Rym: now I might have to add planet with with a deal right next to weird magic system and precursor technology.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't have a terrible secret of space, it's terrible secret of the planet you are on.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So otherwise this weekend unless something horrible happens We're gonna actually do something that we should talked about a long time ago because as you know For every year at anime Boston, we would do a panel called judge anime by its cover.
Rym: One of the up two of them are on YouTube.
Rym: I think a cold guy uploaded one or two.
Rym: Well, he uploaded one I uploaded two and we only stopped doing it because we skipped anime Boston.
Rym: and now that there's like seven goddamn packs is to go to We've been cutting back on our non packs conventions Mm-hmm, and I don't know if we'll return to anime Boston regularly in the future Who knows.
Scott: but the point is we're gonna do four times a year.
Scott: I need to.
Scott: I guess we're gonna do the fall season in September and I forgot when I'm supposed to do this winter spring and summer ones.
Scott: Someone will remind me.
Scott: we're gonna take the anime chart for what animes are coming out.
Scott: So in about 30 days is gonna be new animes.
Rym: The original one got like 13,000 views and we
Scott: are going to go through each show looking only at the title the name of the studio a short description and a screenshot a promotional image and judge what that anime is gonna be about whether it's gonna be worth watching where there's gonna be good.
Scott: and then Four months from now when the anime season ends, you can tell us how right or wrong we were.
Scott: We've been very right in the past I gotta say in order.
Scott: it'll be even more impressive if we actually make these predictions every single season And we can see what our actual track record is.
Scott: What's gonna help is that we can even make another set of videos at like the end of the post-mortem.
Scott: we can do yeah at the end of a season we could be like how we did last season and then Is the new season.
Scott: but so also you farted as the worst part?
Scott: Usually your fart you always like oh here comes a deadly fart and I'll smell nothing What.
Scott: but no it smells like someone like diarrhea in the corner on the day.
Rym: The thing is It's definitely a fart as opposed to the seventh guest it actually I'm pretty sure this is the seventh.
Scott: This is not going away.
Rym: I'm a space traveler.
Rym: What can I say?
Scott: We found the guilty party?
Rym: But in the video we uploaded in 2013 we were Right on literally every show except we said that Sailor Moon crystal was gonna be good.
Rym: They say that we did.
Rym: we were like.
Rym: this will probably be good and we gave a bunch of reasons why mm-hmm.
Rym: We were also Super super like doubly crazily right about eccentric family.
Rym: What we said that show is gonna be was like 100% what that had no idea what we said then.
Scott: But I know what we see now, which is that show is super great.
Rym: Well, I vaguely remember cuz I was looking at these videos recently to kind of guide how we do this now that we're gonna Do it as a YouTube show.
Rym: when we pulled the slide of her eccentric family You like clapped a little bit.
Rym: you were like that shows gonna be our show.
Scott: Anyway Lastly, I just want to remind everybody if you go to the internet which is I'm sure is a place that you go often.
Scott: you can find us in many many places such as Twitter a Facebook our own website our own website for our crew calm.
Scott: iTunes Instagram where I posted like two photos.
Rym: Google+ I post something by.
Rym: actually I forgot to post it the Tuesday show Doing that by hand.
Scott: cuz I'm not doing that automatically.
Rym: there's no API that I know of And I don't think so.
Rym: Yeah, there were.
Rym: cuz the only reason g-plus wasn't automated is there was never a fucking API for it that I know.
Rym: right And don't tell me this than that.
Scott: different YouTube channels.
Scott: Well, it's like so I You can find us on the internet.
Scott: You should go on the internet and find us especially in our forum Which is more active than it has been.
Scott: and when I told people to go there quite a few people listen to me and went there and if you're one of those people who went there and joined you should like just make a habit of going there once a Day and reading the threads that interest you and maybe saying something once in a while.
Scott: Yeah They seen I got saying this has gotten people to sign up to our forum and it reminded me cuz not a lot of people Are posting regularly.
Rym: so like I'm like, I want to say 2006 through about 2009 the GeekNights forum was Crazy rocket like the traffic there was.
Scott: kind of.
Rym: it's never been dead But it's less rocking than it was but it's more rocket in the last year than it has been in the year before.
Scott: I think since we changed the software has helped a bit.
Scott: Yeah, cuz vanilla was starting to fall on his face pretty bad Yeah, and well cuz you know and we were paying for it then I saved a lot of money not paying for that anymore Yeah, and it works way better.
Rym: what we're using now, like I have almost no complaints about this forum software.
Scott: well there I have a lot of complaints, but uh I fixed them.
Rym: I've also I got to admit I've come around a little bit on Docker.
Rym: No, I've come around a little bit more Now that I've used it for some other projects.
Scott: I still can't figure it the fuck out So I.
Rym: so the problem is most people who make like Docker containers Suck at computers.
Rym: so Docker containers feel like they suck if someone knows like generic computer and they make a Docker container.
Rym: the Configuration of how you like make that Docker thing work Works the way you'd expect.
Rym: the problem is most of the people are putting stuff in.
Rym: Docker are people who don't know shit about system Administration?
Rym: that is my opinion.
Rym: But this is a Thursday show so most you have no idea what we're talking about.
Scott: still a mess.
Scott: Yeah souvenirs.
Scott: Well sort of right.
Scott: so uh I mean, I guess we can talk about the concept of souvenirs first.
Scott: right is like you're traveling somewhere and They're selling a bunch of useless crap like I love New York t-shirts and You buy one why?
Rym: So as a kid like when I like when I first when I did travel anywhere other than cedar point because our annual vacation We always went to see your point a bunch of times.
Rym: That was like.
Rym: that was a big part of my life as you can tell if you listen to GeekNights.
Rym: So when we went somewhere other than cedar point there was like this culture of you got to get souvenirs And it was just a thing and I didn't really think about it.
Rym: every in every game in Disney World I have to get a souvenir.
Scott: yet we would go to a gift shop and you'd go.
Scott: every time there was a gift shop at a place you at you'd buy something and A lot of the times.
Scott: it was because at least in those days the 90s 80s Those gift shops are selling things that you couldn't get.
Scott: there was no internet.
Scott: Yeah, it's a buy stuff on.
Scott: there was no Amazon.
Rym: You
Scott: would see things in the gift shop that you would not see in any store in your town or any mall or any place That you could buy things at
Rym: that board license plate with Mickey Mouse
Scott: on it Alright, so you'd be like, whoa That is a thing and the only way I can get that thing is to buy it here in this one place.
Scott: Therefore I will buy it.
Scott: The other reason I think to buy a souvenir that legitimate reason is As some sort of memory thing, right?
Scott: It's like you buy this, you know from this place and then when you know someday in your house You notice it because you'd have it lying around and then now you're able to remember that trip you went on Whereas otherwise you might have forgotten it.
Scott: Yep an additional memory aid.
Rym: There's one other component to this is that most of the souvenirs I acquired over the years We're when I was a kid traveling with family and other family members would like push to get souvenirs, which usually men I mean a kid I just like buying stuff.
Rym: Yeah as a kid any time I had the discretion to make a purchase of any kind it was use it or lose this.
Rym: I was gonna use it, but I usually wanted like a toy as opposed to just a tchotchke.
Scott: Well, sometimes, you know you get you go to like a science museum gift shop.
Scott: This toys there.
Scott: Yeah You know, sometimes you can get a useful thing and not just a useless thing like this.
Scott: people collect spoons.
Rym: So yeah, so my grandma collected the fuck out of spoons.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: She has a little tiny spoon.
Scott: Yes, the tiny collecting spoon that goes a wooden thing on the wall.
Rym: They also did the pin thing after they went to Australia a bunch where they had a hat and they'd put all their pins in The Hat and they they really tried to get me into both of those.
Rym: so they get us a spoon.
Rym: Like at my birthday, I get like a real present and a spoon.
Rym: but Before we get into actual souvenirs I found that as I've traveled more because in the last like six years I've traveled all over the world a bunch and also I moved to New York, or I don't get a lot of room I'd try to bring as little.
Rym: like I always try to come home with less than I flew out with Like I try to bring as little home as possible.
Rym: So I Transitioned from like.
Rym: the first time I was in London I was like who and I got some stuff and the first time I went to Hong Kong goes like oh shit I got to get something.
Rym: But I really rapidly shifted from buying a traditional souvenir to buying something Consumable like a food or something that we'd bring.
Rym: I'd bring home and we'd eat it immediately and then it's gone.
Scott: Well for the memory purposes, we don't have internet.
Scott: So it's like there's some sort of digital record of my trip now.
Scott: So I don't really need to bring home like some tchotchke to remind myself.
Scott: Well, that's it.
Rym: I make a point whenever I travel.
Scott: I got videos and photos that went up immediately.
Rym: Even if I travel somewhere stupid I make sure that I take a few pictures with my phone no matter what because that Locks it into a bunch of digital timelines forever.
Scott: The other thing is that being someone who lives in New York City and works across the street from garbage souvenir shops Right that so I love New York t-shirts and other crap and someone who's been to places like The beach that sells horrible schlocky souvenir crap.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: I can.
Scott: now I now look at souvenirs as Schlocky worthless crap.
Scott: So even if I go somewhere like say I don't know if I went to like Vienna Which is where I've never been but and they had like souvenirs.
Scott: My eyes would still see them as worthless garbage crap.
Rym: Well, if they're that kind of souvenir like model statue of the Eiffel Tower, they don't have Eiffel Tower at Vienna.
Rym: Well, that's I'm on the Wikipedia page for the word souvenir.
Rym: That's the first image.
Scott: Yeah It's like you don't need a little metal Eiffel Tower.
Scott: What are you gonna do with that?
Rym: Yeah, that's worthless.
Scott: Why did you even make those who buys those and what do they do with them?
Scott: So they put them in their house for a little bit and they throw them out.
Scott: They did go in a I don't know.
Rym: my favorite souvenirs in my entire life are actually minor injuries.
Scott: Partly cuz when I try that time, are you gonna take this episode?
Rym: When I travel I tend to do sports like I run a lot.
Scott: Yeah, don't do any with Rym mountain bike.
Rym: Yeah Yeah yet again.
Rym: So last weekend I was in Salt Lake City mountain biking.
Rym: and what happened?
Rym: someone on the trip like busted their hand.
Rym: real bad It's.
Scott: if we go on vacation if we're gonna do any sort of activities Don't go mountain biking with Rym's going alone and the rest of us are going a different way.
Rym: if I go alone Nobody gets hurt.
Rym: It's only if I go with other people they get hurt.
Scott: At that time you almost found out your glasses fell whatever.
Rym: Yeah, but I survived and actually so there's a tiny crack like on the edge of the frames of those glasses and That little crack like I can't.
Rym: you can't really see it, but I can feel it from my front my finger over it.
Rym: This might sound weird.
Rym: That is a souvenir to me because every time I put on those glasses I feel that little crack and I remember when I was out in the Outback on this pillar and I almost lost my only pair Of glasses.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: Every time I look at the messed up scar on my chin.
Scott: That's not a souvenir.
Scott: That's like fuck.
Scott: I wish my chin was the way it was before.
Scott: like whatever like whatever I noticed like I was already a fucked Up chin from falling on my face previously and I fell in the same place of my same face two times.
Rym: I got a couple scars on my knee.
Scott: My right chin is way bigger than my left chin and every time I feel them There's like some.
Scott: I'm not getting plastic surgery to fix it fuck.
Rym: I got some spots on my left knee where hair doesn't grow because I've had like pretty big bike accidents over the years and Every one of those little divots that doesn't have hair.
Rym: I have a specific memory of a great time I had mountain biking.
Rym: great except actually the worst of those injuries was not mountain biking.
Rym: I was just like biking on a sidewalk just way too fast.
Scott: I mean I was just biking on a street.
Scott: Yeah into a tram track with a tram You were
Rym: just biking on a street But it was the street filled with deadly traps to be fair Cuz as we learned after that trip the tram tracks claim a lot of bikers like on a monthly basis
Scott: only Avoided all other obstacles, but there was one I did not foresee it came.
Rym: So it came before when I first started traveling globally.
Rym: My favorite souvenir was actually to bring back a tiny amount of local money.
Rym: But now that I'm quite a bunch of bit of local monies from many places But now so now I have in my junk drawer I probably have like three pounds of coins from all over the world that Know why you can't exchange coins in the US.
Rym: no one will take them.
Scott: the bank will you know?
Rym: No, they'll take bills only.
Scott: All right, what if they add up to enough money?
Rym: They still don't want the coins really for most countries.
Rym: They don't want the coins You get.
Scott: I mean you're in New York.
Scott: You'd wait for someone from the country where the money's from.
Scott: Yeah, change it with them.
Rym: But the worst part is with the bills.
Rym: I'll bring them on my next trip, even though I think to India.
Rym: that's technically illegal, but whatever really yeah Don't get if you take.
Rym: so if you take rupees out of India In the airport that are like you cannot have Indian money when you come into the country.
Rym: really You're also not allowed to have unapproved maps.
Rym: What if a map?
Rym: Shows the wrong borders in Kashmir?
Rym: that map is technically illegal and you can be Arrested.
Scott: or does Google Maps correct itself.
Scott: No, when you enter in technically you're smart.
Rym: Don't get me started on this.
Scott: Okay, I guess I'm not bringing my phone to India while I'm planning to go to India.
Rym: The other thing you cannot bring is satellite phones.
Scott: It's not high on my list of places to go.
Rym: satellite phones are like way illegal in most of Asia.
Rym: Why?
Rym: because it lets you communicate without going through the state-controlled systems.
Rym: Okay, so sad phones are a big no-no Mmm, you're just a sad phone.
Scott: I've seen one.
Rym: The the weirdest thing about them is that there's Just enough of a delay like when you're talking to where it makes conversations like really awkward and hard to follow.
Rym: But it's not so long that you actually like pause and back off and wait for it.
Rym: So it's just really hard to talk on them.
Rym: Mmm, but I digress.
Rym: So now I just have this pie.
Rym: I probably have like five or six hundred dollars worth of currency from all over the world.
Rym: I can't do anything with it.
Rym: Anyway, I got now I got a pile of like 25-pound notes.
Scott: Why don't we make a website?
Scott: and the way the website works is people send in their money and we have a shittier Exchange rate but we let people descend in bulk all kinds of crazy currencies And then we'll just add it all together from all the different people that send us their money and we'll sort it out.
Rym: Why don't I just make it and I'll make a loot box?
Rym: if you saw I'll make a pet here on patreon For GeekNights.
Rym: if you're at that tier, I'll mail out a loot envelope and it's just random money from around the world.
Scott: Oh you get rid of your money that way.
Scott: I was gonna say we should make a tier on patreon Which is don't give us real money.
Scott: Send us all your random foreign monies.
Scott: We'll give you all Worthless stuff cuz and then we'll take we'll collect a bunch of foreign monies from all these people So and then sort them out and then we'll be able to exchange them.
Rym: there is there is a coin from a country I travel to a lot not gonna name names cuz I don't want any of you to Take advantage of this cuz I'm not gonna take advantage of it other than one time when I did.
Rym: It is detected as a quarter by pretty much any vending machine in America.
Rym: Hmm, and it is worth Way less than a quarter.
Rym: Oh, really way less.
Rym: I discovered this by accident But why don't we?
Rym: I did fill a laundry machine downstairs with this currency once.
Scott: let if we if we go to this country again Let us get some rolls from the bank.
Scott: Yeah, we could do that and then buy dollar, you know, $1 bottled water at conventions for much less.
Scott: That's pretty much the only time I ever use a vending machine.
Rym: So do you have any souvenirs?
Rym: because I don't have that many actually.
Rym: So with the caveat of I'm excluding gifts because I've gotten gifts from people who are from countries But I treat that as like a very separate kind of thing.
Scott: So I mean when we would travel places, you know, we go to the gift shop and you'd buy something, right?
Scott: But when I was very little but I guess I don't remember how we got into the habit of doing this But for some reason we would always buy a snow globe just like oh, I don't know why we did.
Scott: You know, it's I don't know but it's like I don't know when it started But I just remember it continuing like we got it.
Scott: suddenly we had four snow globes.
Scott: I just like every time he went somewhere new he bought another fucking snow actually did the same thing with music boxes.
Rym: Okay, so that that's just the thing that happens.
Scott: I guess they probably they're probably all like they're mad dusty and I think they don't have any water in them.
Scott: But I think somewhere in my house, there's probably like a box with like 50 to 100 snow globes in it and the old ones are like the kind that's made of white plastic and inside and it's weird to think of like Just how many different snow globes there are back in those days.
Scott: like who designed and made all of those different globes Right, and then it's like then they had a different kind.
Scott: eventually It stopped making the white kind.
Scott: it started being the black kind that were a little bigger and had sparkles inside instead of the white Snow and they were a little less fancy because the inside of it wasn't like this little plastic sculpture that was painted.
Scott: Not I mean, I'm saying using very the word sculpture very liberally But they started just being like a sheet of plastic with an image printed on it inside.
Rym: Yeah, that in general you've noticed that there's like with a lot of these kinds of shots keys Like there was an era in the 90s.
Rym: I feel like that was when like the production values of all that shit went up.
Scott: and then in the 2000s the production values went way down and it was the early 90s was an 80s was up.
Scott: and then well I mean you can even go to the museum's I've seen like, you know the world the world's fair souvenirs from you know Way back right and they were really high quality friggin souvenirs.
Scott: I'm like, dude, I buy that.
Scott: Why doesn't someone like just make those again?
Rym: But you want to be you want to.
Rym: why don't you make the quality of souvenirs Funko pop equivalent of snow globes?
Scott: But I mean like that's our company.
Scott: Physical quality of souvenirs has only been going down over time.
Scott: It has never gone up right.
Rym: apparently the Colombian 25 peso coin also works as a quarter.
Scott: Is it worth less than a quarter Scott?
Rym: Make a guess is 25 pesos worth less than 25 cents.
Scott: I don't know how much Colombian money's worth.
Rym: Just make it.
Rym: There's a Fermi guess you can make there.
Rym: I Don't have any Colombian.
Scott: There are countries that have money that's worth more than US dollar.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that is true.
Scott: Columbia sells a lot of drugs.
Scott: It's not what they're known for.
Rym: So you refuse to make one currency stereotype and you make a very different stereotype.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: That was why it was funny.
Rym: So that so I was hoping when I went to the snow globes page on Wikipedia that I'd learned something really interesting.
Rym: Now this is literally the most boring topic on earth.
Scott: no, it's really boring.
Scott: However, it was interesting to find out at one point I don't know if it's still true But at one point in time there was like an interest in snow globes and like particular rare ones that were no longer made.
Scott: We're worth a bunch of money and we happen to have two of them.
Scott: I think I still have them.
Scott: So there's one.
Scott: It was I remember like seeing a news story like Bronx Zoo snow globe.
Scott: They don't make it anymore.
Scott: It's worth something and I'm like I have that is a white plastic snow globe with two polar bears in it.
Scott: And it said Bronx Zoo and I still have it I think has no water in it, but it is mad dusty.
Scott: But we still have it.
Scott: and then as a place in Connecticut that you I don't know it was worth traveling to you can read all about online called Gillette Castle, which Keep in mind is a castle in North America.
Scott: It's not old Right, it's not a real castle, you know like a European castle.
Scott: that's actually from the medieval times But it is structurally a castle.
Scott: and when we went there we bought a snow globe and then I saw a thing like oh They don't make that snow globe from Gillette Castle anymore.
Scott: It's in high demand from collectors and I have one of those really old snow globes used bone chips to make the snow.
Scott: I was not aware of that.
Scott: I thought it was.
Scott: I thought it was plastic bits because the ones I the oldest ones I have are the white plastic kind.
Scott: So I figure if there's white plastics Clear plastic for the top that the bits would be white plastic.
Scott: I'll shoot up.
Rym: How old is plastic And how old are snow globes?
Scott: So plastic is When the old telephones are made with bakelite.
Scott: that was sort of plastic.
Rym: So it's probably the first like mass-market plastic.
Scott: I don't know if it counts as plastic right but bakelite is from like the 50s 60s ish, right?
Scott: It's not it's not.
Scott: Plastic wasn't really used a lot until like 80s 90s 70s, you know.
Scott: snow globes appeared in the Tracks in the 70s were made of plastic early 19th century.
Rym: France seems to be when snow globes became a thing.
Scott: Oh, so they were like metal and glass.
Rym: they were like glass bone chips bone chips.
Scott: Uh-huh Alrighty.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I thought I don't have.
Scott: we didn't collect that kind.
Scott: We collected el cheapo kind not el fancy ceramic with the glass ball on top that lights up kind.
Scott: we didn't do that.
Scott: We did cheapo $2 plastic ones.
Scott: So I guess that I have but they're still good because you look at them and you remember it's like oh, yeah I remember we went to that Gillette Castle and that Bronx Zoo and that wherever right.
Rym: so most of the souvenirs I've gotten over my life are buried in boxes at my mom's house.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: mine, too Yeah,
Rym: but the the only two that I can well the only three I can think of that have real Significance that I think about regularly are one When I went to Disney World for the first time on a band trip Was also the first time I flew in a plane that I was not sitting in the front of.
Rym: It was the first time I went on a commercial flight as opposed to just riding in someone's Cessna Mm-hmm, and I was in Disney World.
Rym: everyone's buying all these garbage Tchotchke like things and I remember the only souvenir I bought was this really tasteful Black and white like Mickey statue like old steamboat Mickey.
Rym: Mm-hmm I just I remember I did it.
Scott: I did a similar thing in Disney World and you actually Reminded me of like one of the few souvenirs that is actually in my apartment and not in a box somewhere Right is when I went to Disney World.
Scott: I wanted to get a fancy souvenir too, right?
Scott: So what I got is I got this basically this pad of paper And it's basically this base and then a little notepad on it and the notepad has like a metal flap that holds the top down Like you'd put it on a fancy executive desk.
Scott: that kind of deal Obviously, it's not gold or anything.
Scott: It's just like gold colored metal And then on top of the metal gold cover that holds the pad flat.
Scott: It was like, you know, like Disney World Mickey with his magic hat whatever.
Scott: and it's you know, it's like Disney World, right?
Scott: So it's like if you were an executive at Disney World You would put that on your desk and I bought.
Scott: I was like, oh that's real fancy I want that.
Scott: and it was so fancy that throughout my entire childhood I never wrote on that pad ever.
Scott: Yeah And it's now in one of the drawers in my apartment and I saw it like the other day like oh there and you just Reminded me of it.
Scott: So the second one is I when I went back to this I guess we had similar things at Disney World by one by one Really fancy souvenir.
Scott: No, don't we did.
Scott: I didn't buy stupid Mickey ears.
Scott: I didn't buy you know.
Rym: So the second one that I have a memory is of is pretty recent But Emily and I went back to Disney World for Ken marks wedding Mm-hmm, and I was the first time experiencing Disney as an adult and there was.
Rym: there was a good time all I had all around but Every night because you know, there's not much to do at night.
Rym: Yeah, but instead of seeing the fireworks in Disney the secret was because we're staying in shades of green is to go to the Polynesian because there's a nice like outdoor bar with good food and You can see over the water and you can see all the fireworks from there and they pipe the music from the fireworks Into the bar.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's just like it's a really nice place.
Rym: so we went there every night and had a drink and some food hung out and Because it's the Polynesian they have ridiculous tiki drinks.
Rym: so I ordered the ridiculous tiki drink and I got it in the ridiculous souvenir tiki mug and I still have that giant ridiculous tiki mug and anytime I drink a weird tiki drink I will put it in that ridiculous tiki mug and that encapsulates The entirety of my Disney experience.
Scott: between that and the black and white Mickey Mouse You actually reminded me of another kind of souvenir which is the kind that you get for free when you do a thing Especially you go to a sporting event.
Rym: I still have it.
Rym: I still have that ticket.
Rym: It's in my jewelry box.
Rym: I used to keep it in my wallet.
Scott: Oh the ticket.
Scott: Yeah, I still have the ticket also.
Scott: So I don't know where it is, but I do know I have it.
Rym: ass sweat Seeping into my wallet was slowly eroding the quality of that ticket.
Rym: tickets now somewhere secure But that ticket to this day.
Rym: It was the greatest hockey game I've ever seen in my life.
Scott: I wasn't even thinking of ticket stubs.
Rym: I was thinking I kept that fucking ticket.
Scott: That's a souvenir I'm thinking of like things you get like for example, you know and again a quality decreasing over time, right?
Scott: If you go to a baseball game today The best you're gonna get is shitty bobblehead night, which isn't even gonna be as good as the bobbleheads They sell.
Scott: it's like a lower tier of bobblehead tinier and crappier and it has Advertisements on it right in back in like late 80s early 90s.
Scott: and we went to like Shea Stadium.
Scott: We went I remember specifically we went on beach towel day.
Scott: We got full-size Beach towels the kind you would pay money for.
Scott: Fofre just handed him out of the door.
Scott: No the gate, right?
Scott: We all had one.
Scott: so when we go to the beach every single person had this met Snoopy MetLife Beach.
Scott: We all had them and we still have them because it was such a high-quality beach towel.
Scott: It's lasted 20 something years plus maybe even 30 years, right?
Scott: That's how good the stuff was.
Scott: now you'll get we go to like the playoff hockey which caused way more than a regular season baseball game And you give you this tiny worthless towel and a light stick that lasts five minutes.
Scott: They throw the light stick out you rub your head with the towel and you put it in the closet.
Rym: It's like come on and the only other souvenir I have.
Rym: that I think is kind of important even though I technically I guess smuggled an antiquity.
Rym: So, you know, I as you all know I used to spend a lot of time in Turkey as particularly Istanbul And I worry that I'll never be able to visit that city again, or at least not in the immediate term by any stretch.
Rym: but a problem and I definitely contribute a little bit to this.
Rym: but in countries like Turkey certain antiquities are protected but many of the more important ones are in extreme states of neglect or Are otherwise not controlled.
Rym: so in Istanbul if you're ever there the famed Theodosian walls are still there.
Rym: They've been restored to varying degrees of historical accuracy in some sections But the bulk of them are there in there.
Rym: like.
Rym: the core is the same original core from like 400 AD And those walls are probably the most important famous walls in all of history.
Rym: The Great Wall is probably the only thing even close to it in comparison.
Rym: But this thing actually fought off.
Rym: like these walls were literally impenetrable until gunpowder.
Rym: But if you're in Istanbul and you go over where these walls are on the edge of the old city You can just climb up on top of them.
Rym: Like there are people who have like made houses inside of them in some parts.
Rym: I was threatened by some people with weapons who were living in there who didn't want me poking around.
Rym: But I had a whole adventure Walking through the literal Theodosian walls like climbing up in these towers and it was just there like there's no one guarding.
Rym: There's nothing.
Rym: So as I was leaving, I wasn't gonna like chip a piece out of these things.
Rym: for obvious reasons Let me damage this ancient object further than I already have by walking around inside of them.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but Some was some chips of the old part of the wall it like falling all over the ground.
Rym: so I picked up this one tiny chip and I took it home with me and Obviously if everyone did this, this would be a problem and I'm saying you all shouldn't do it.
Rym: I got mine.
Scott: Well
Rym: But I have this tiny piece of the actual Theodosian walls and it's just sitting like I keep it with me and It's very profound Whenever I touch it to think about all that history and also to think about all the time I spent living in that city and the fact that I can't go back to that city right now.
Rym: It's not safely.
Scott: you can not safely those planes that go there.
Scott: It is not say you go to the airport and give money.
Rym: It is not safe.
Scott: don't let you in it is not.
Rym: I would I would be feel safer.
Rym: I Can list a lot of places that you would consider pretty dodgy that I would be more comfortable visiting than Istanbul right now.
Rym: It is not safe for an American to travel to Istanbul without taking Precautions.
Rym: that would make the trip not fun.
Rym: So, yeah, I have that piece and I will probably have.
Rym: I will probably carry that souvenir along with that Hockey game to my grave the only time I went anywhere where there could have been antiquities.
Scott: stealing is on to Israel.
Scott: I didn't steal any antiquities because I'm not evil person But I'm trying to remember what I did buy.
Scott: that I don't.
Scott: I didn't buy a lot because they didn't have a lot of money And actually I spent.
Scott: I think I remember.
Scott: I spent all my money or like I had money and then I lost my remaining monies.
Scott: Do I remember?
Scott: But basically cuz like even that was when I started to realize souvenirs are crap Especially with like, you know, like you could people are coming.
Scott: I was 18 and like you could tell like these people coming up to you on the street They could tell you're a terrorist, right?
Scott: Yeah, and they're like, hey, come on buy my drag about my drag And I'm like, I can tell it's direct now.
Scott: I'm 18.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'm not even a New Yorker.
Scott: You haven't lived in New York yet, but I already know.
Rym: Oh, I do have.
Rym: well so I used to go to India a lot and I had a lot of free time just wandering around in Mumbai and Because you know the exchange rate and everything like there's the people trying to scam tourists all the time and sell them tapestries and carpets Usually carpets.
Scott: All right, I'll take a carpet.
Scott: These guys are trying to sell me like worthless junk.
Rym: Yeah, they're trying to sell you a carpet and it's a scare.
Rym: They're good They're gonna like.
Rym: you'll get it carpets in the end But you'll get one way more carpets than you expected for way more money than you expected.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Why can't I just get the one carpet?
Rym: Yeah, good luck There's a whole.
Rym: there's like.
Rym: I could.
Rym: I could do a whole show Explaining in detail how the carpet and tapestry scams work.
Scott: I just like one carpet.
Scott: No one carpet.
Scott: They're Fascinating one carpet.
Scott: I'm only by one one and in fact when I much one no when I touch one No, when I travel to these places you try to hand me another one.
Scott: Nope not touching it.
Scott: I have watched other people Succumb to these scams and it's kind of funny how I mean I see people get scammed by the CD guys on the street.
Rym: Yeah, but these get like the scams is particularly in like India and Turkey and like the places in that general like places that are like that.
Rym: they're surprisingly elaborate how these scams go, but I Want to make it want to make a game about that?
Rym: We pick a board game about that.
Scott: You could you owe a bunch of carpets.
Scott: You got to get rid of them all Marrakesh - yeah You already won all the carpets now Zelda.
Rym: so one time I was I was on my like.
Rym: I had a whole day to kill.
Rym: I had one meeting in the morning and I had nothing to do.
Rym: I was flying on that night.
Rym: so my cab driver like I asked him to my driver asked him to drive me back to my hotel and He starts on one of the scams.
Rym: because one of the things they'll do is say hey if you got some time How about I can draw?
Rym: let me take you to me I gotta want to get some coffee and then let's stop by my brother's shop and let's go have some tea there.
Rym: if Any cab driver ever asks you to have tea with them they're going to scam you.
Rym: they're not gonna rob you.
Rym: they're gonna scam you.
Rym: mm-hmm.
Rym: the ones who are gonna rob you will be a beautiful woman who comes up to you at a bar and Asks you to join her at a better bar.
Rym: that they're going to rob you.
Rym: Yes, possibly kill you.
Rym: Correct, but So I know it's a scam like I'm pretty much like.
Scott: I don't understand about that.
Scott: It's like why are you asking someone to go to another bar?
Scott: It's like just walk up to someone stab them and take their money.
Scott: Why you got to do this elaborate nonsense?
Rym: because the bar they take you to is in on it.
Scott: So if they stabbed you in this bar wouldn't go down.
Scott: Yes, so What if you happen to accidentally walk into a bar that's in on it?
Rym: Let's do a show out.
Rym: Well, then you're fucked.
Scott: Did they stab you right away?
Rym: Let's do a show on scams.
Scott: I don't know a lot about scams.
Rym: I know a lot about scams.
Rym: I'm not evil.
Rym: I'll do a patreon on scams.
Rym: I know a lot about tourist scams in other countries Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway, so the cab driver like basically Begins the scam and I'm bored to get a lot of time to kill.
Rym: So I basically Decided I was willing to spend about a hundred bucks because that's about how much it was gonna take Probably for that kind of scam to experience the full scan.
Scott: how many carpets he got?
Scott: How come you don't give me a carpet?
Rym: I bought this Chachki, that's a bunch of wooden nesting peacocks and it's on the piano in there.
Rym: Okay, and that's because I had to but you had to buy something out of the end because otherwise the people who run the elaborate Scam, they'll actually get in trouble with the scam bosses.
Rym: Like it'll fuck them up pretty bad So but basically I went through the whole thing.
Rym: So I haggle with these people for like an hour over tea About the carpets and I what about that one?
Rym: What about that one?
Rym: And then I don't want a carpet in the end.
Rym: So at least buy something.
Rym: so I start looking around and I see this one Chachki.
Rym: and then there's the sword.
Scott: How do you end up running a Chachki store that you have to scam people to buy stuff in?
Scott: Why not just run a legit store that sells growthful stuff.
Rym: So here's the thing the those kinds of scams.
Rym: It's not like they steal $4,000 from a tourist.
Rym: It's more like they sell the tourists a carpet a set of carpets for $4,000.
Rym: that if you bought equivalent carpets in the US would have been about two thousand dollars.
Rym: Hmm, so they make a profit of like two thousand dollars But it cost it.
Rym: you're buying it in the country where it cost two hundred dollars to make those carpets.
Rym: So there is a huge upside and they pretty much only go after.
Rym: wealthy looking people basically look for white people from countries where The people who are tourists from those countries don't know shit about scams and are very easy to scan and you steal enough from them To be valuable to you, but you don't scam them for so much money That they're gonna realize they even got scammed.
Scott: I think when we were in Israel, they were selling these backgammon sets.
Rym: everywhere In Turkey was the same thing with a backgammon set.
Scott: I could tell by looking at him that they were basically Mass-produced backgammon in Mexico.
Rym: It was these like stone carved chest sets, right?
Scott: These backgammon sets came in two sizes small and big and I you could tell that Even though they looked like they were handcrafted some kind of art.
Scott: They were actually mass-produced.
Scott: They just looked they were just mass-produced things that looked like they were handcrafted with patterns and design.
Rym: So these Mexican chest sets are handcrafted but in factories, right?
Scott: I mean it this wasn't like some actual artisan thing, right?
Scott: This was some, you know, just some nonsense, right?
Scott: So, you know people who you know people bought quite a few of those and I was like no I got one.
Scott: I'm good.
Scott: I like backgammon a lot, but that's not.
Scott: I don't need that Yeah, but basically so that and I don't want to carry that around for the rest of this trip.
Rym: that souvenir I have is like the memory of fully interacting with one of those things and It was just really fascinating to see like the four or five different people who?
Rym: Rotated in through the shop as part of the elaborate thing to get me to buy all these carpets that I didn't buy.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And actually bringing that home was probably illegal because it's made out of wood.
Scott: So customs didn't notice the wood.
Rym: customs doesn't notice shit, let's smuggle.
Rym: I mean what what I would want that when I was in Hong Kong the first time I brought back a shit ton of tea Mm-hmm to bring back tea.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: probably you can usually bring back tea.
Rym: I mean I could see not bringing back leaves and trees, but already had a checked bag full of like a giant sack of vegetable matter.
Scott: Dead though.
Scott: Yeah, but It's not like it's a tomato Scott.
Rym: another thing someone might have hidden in a suitcase.
Rym: That is a large sack of vegetable matter.
Scott: I'm pretty.
Scott: even if they inspected it.
Scott: I'm sure they would go.
Scott: Oh, it's tea.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and close it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's plenty of teas from Hong Kong available in the u.s.
Scott: It's not any legal thing to import.
Rym: there is a difference there.
Scott: That's where you know where you're bringing enough to open up a tea Shop.
Scott: yeah, you're not like a business getting around some Tara for something.
Rym: so really but it's partly that sometimes like especially when I travel Europe I would forget to declare all the things I had and There's an allowance, but it's okay as long as you declare it.
Rym: But I wouldn't remember like that I'd bought a bunch of wine because I was there for two weeks.
Rym: like on day two I bought a bunch of wine.
Scott: the only thing that I would really buy and try to like import is go to you know Asia and buy electronic goods that are unavailable or more expensive here Like yes, I'll buy that camera that cost twice as much in America.
Scott: Yes Buy that video game that is not available when I was waiting for the mind.
Rym: You know my weird cell phone is the Xperia when I was waiting for this to come out in the u.s.. I was in Hong Kong and you saw one.
Rym: I saw the Asian.
Rym: yes, I'll buy that very tiny laptop which was Great because actually the Asian variant of this phone is way better than the American version because it has a fingerprint sensor.
Rym: Yeah, but and it would have worked on LTE in the u.s.
Rym: Mostly, but it wouldn't work that well in Europe.
Rym: and the bands?
Rym: I it was.
Rym: it was worth it to wait for the u.s One phone has all bands.
Rym: Yeah, does it every band.
Scott: I thought the iPhone has effectively every band you're gonna need.
Rym: I want to check on that.
Rym: I mean, I will look it up because there are some bands that are not so easy to get but I digress.
Scott: Then did the new it like since like I forget at what point but at some point eventually Like at least the Verizon iPhone that I have which is unlocked because Verizon deals Effectively.
Scott: you can just put a SIM card in it as long as you can get the SIM card activated, which is the hard part.
Rym: Anthony's in here in the shed.
Rym: bone chips.
Rym: He's he's still talking about bone chips.
Rym: Oh, you're like own storm bone chips in harmony Thinking about those bone chips in hearthstone.
Scott: There's a new card.
Scott: That's really powerful called bone mare.
Scott: It's a skeleton horse.
Rym: I Still I gotta I gotta play skeleton with a bindle when it comes out.
Rym: Yeah sure Did you actually go up at PAX and see that game?
Scott: I did.
Scott: you're like his giant skeleton walking across the land.
Rym: Yeah, telling stories.
Rym: Yeah All right, I think we killed an hour.
Scott: good.
Scott: I'll go home.
Scott: Yeah I spent enough time here today.
Rym: All right, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette roundabout on mp3 mystady.com.
Rym: William Isen rose Jeremy minor a genuine bona fide electrified six-car monorail.
Rym: Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando Captain jingo ocassie Rebecca Dunn for two one creations.
Rym: Even if we were to pull out today and if they would come take our base Shervin but horrible rare.
Rym: Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy sailor moon moon sailor vista Don Schleich jar tavish and Joshua Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open Lander Brian Sidroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Rym: as some of you know, I did start a new job this week after a week in Salt Lake City.
Rym: Shouldn't we can pack?
Rym: so I've been busy but bit by bit the GeekNights stuff is spinning back up as things calm down And I slot into my sort of normal new life.
Rym: But anyway, now I leave you with.
Media: she came into the shop and said I want to know what the problem is.
Media: I Said you don't want to know what the problem is.
Media: And she said I want to know what the problem is so I can get the problem fixed.
Media: I Said you don't want to know what the solution to the problem is and you don't want to know what your problem is.
Media: She says how do you know that?
Media: I'm not gonna like it.
Media: I said, I know you're not gonna like it.
Media: So she said just tell me what it is and I'll tell you if I like it.
Media: and I said maybe Maybe I'll tell you.
Media: she said why won't you tell me?
Media: I said the problems your ass.
Media: She said what I said the problems your ass.