Rym: It's Thursday, May 25th, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm scared and this is GeekNights tonight in another episode of.
Rym: I can't believe we didn't talk about this before Talking about amusement parks.
Scott: I'm pretty sure we tell you to show me the episode.
Rym: find it Let's do this.
Rym: So tonight I don't care about hockey in a visceral level anymore because no team I care about is in contention for the cup.
Scott: So on Pittsburgh to lose.
Rym: I do want Pittsburgh to lose.
Rym: tonight's an important game because say the Senators in Pittsburgh It's gonna be a game seven.
Rym: One of them is gonna go on to fight the Preds.
Rym: The other one's gonna go home.
Rym: That's right and Really don't want a Pennsylvania team to ever win the Stanley Cup again if we can avoid it.
Rym: same with New Jersey Same with all but one New York team.
Scott: But if the Sabres wanted to be funny, I guess no, whatever they could win out.
Rym: But I think I'm rooting for the Preds and I'm hoping to see predators senators and Because neither one of them is my team NHL is not hoping for that.
Scott: They're really their ratings will be.
Rym: but if it comes to that I'm hoping it goes into game seven and I'm hoping game seven has like 20 over times because Overtime hockey is one of the most stressful things in the world to watch if you care about the outcome of the game.
Rym: And it's one of the best things in the world to watch if you don't give a shit.
Rym: As long as you care about hockey in general at least I guess No, even if you don't care even if you don't even know what's going on Overtime game seven hockey is exciting.
Rym: Even if you literally don't know what's happening.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: So, uh, I got some news here.
Rym: You got some news.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Rym: We can talk about whatever cuz it's the lounge.
Scott: Yeah, it's your mom And a sad news, so, you know way back in the college days, you know when we were in the a nine clubs Right, we listened to lots of j-pops and j-rocks and whatnot because that was the style of the times You know and especially like in the summer We would tend to play that music more often because it wasn't really the greatest winter music Even though winter was most of what we experienced in college because I'm in Rochester.
Rym: Well, that was also, you know in that era like I became a weeb when I was in fourth grade.
Rym: So I was already like I came to RIT already like mostly listening to like j-pop.
Scott: Yeah, so I don't know how many people realize but there's a person named Ayumi Hamasaki.
Scott: He's basically sort of like The Madonna of Japan.
Rym: Yeah, like I remember as a kid I found for I found Megumi Hashibara because she did a lot of anime music and then at RIT I discovered Ayumi Hamasaki and she rapidly game one of my favorite music performers on earth, right?
Scott: Stuff is on Spotify and there's lots of like eurobeat remixes of her albums and stuff and she has like tons of hits and I Think it's you know, it's one of those names like every Japanese person will know who that is.
Scott: I almost everyone, right?
Scott: Yeah, I guess someone who was just born wouldn't know Right.
Scott: This is like a super famous person who hasn't really done anything recently, right?
Rym: Or at least if she did I didn't pay attention like I didn't know.
Scott: But like every like, you know, maybe like once or twice a year every year Like I'm remembered that she exists usually in the summer You know and I go back in and I find something like a euro mix album or something.
Rym: I'm like, oh, yeah Kind of like how with Megumi Hashibara I remembered she existed because I was at Zenk icon and I did a panel on anime openers and We had a song that she sang on it.
Rym: So I was like, oh right she exists.
Scott: But anyway, uh, but I like didn't know what she was up to recently until this news appeared in the news feeds.
Scott: Right because this news appeared it linked out to all the other news's of what has happened to her, right?
Scott: So the last I had heard from her was years ago.
Scott: She married like some guy from like California or something like some non-celebrity person.
Scott: It's like, oh, that's nice.
Scott: So I kind of like it when like celebrity people like meet and marry non-celebrity people, you know Cuz it seems more like a. you know I hope that they have like a genuine thing going on.
Scott: you tend to see lots of like mega celebrity people like Get married with each other and have like these Weddings that at least appear they might be legit, but they you know Appear that like they're just for show right there and then they you know divorce and get remarried like 20 times.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, that's because it's you know, they're not like really, you know in a real relationship To like keep your circles in that same public sphere.
Rym: So you sort of limit your dating pool to people who are like that.
Scott: But anyway, but I heard you know One of the news's I saw is that that is no longer a thing which is kind of sad.
Scott: But the really sad news is that even though like she is a pop star and a singer She appears to be losing her hearing and she's not that old right now.
Rym: Apparently that itself is not news know what?
Scott: so what happened was is a long time ago actually, she had already been losing hearing in one ear right there was like an infection I think.
Scott: and But she was on tour and rather than like, you know, take a break and you know get some medical attention She's like, nope show must go on and ruined her ear and now the other ear is being ruined and it's like, you know we've had, you know, Beethoven was deaf too, right, but it's like You know I can't think of like someone who was a pop star like a huge such a huge one that then lost their hearing.
Rym: Well, it's just.
Rym: it's extra sad in general whenever you see someone who is very good at a thing and a physical Disability comes along and prevents them from doing the thing that they love Like a hockey player gets the you know, one too many concussions and has to retire early.
Rym: Mm-hmm any of those situations are always sad.
Scott: Yeah, so that's a thing.
Rym: Yep in a lighter news.
Rym: So, you know that we go to PAX South and PAX South is a really good.
Rym: packs Like.
Rym: if you have to pick one packs and you can't afford to go to like PAX West PAX South is way Cheaper and nicer than
Scott: even if you live far away from PAX South at least if you live in the United States PAX South, even if you live in New York PAX South will probably be cheaper than PAX East.
Scott: You know if you live in like Massachusetts PAX South is probably shockingly cheap.
Rym: food cost nothing there.
Scott: Flights and hotel will probably cost less than the parking in Boston.
Scott: Yep Okay, and so you're gonna and then the ticket.
Scott: you're gonna be able to get it very easily.
Rym: Just buy it on the website at face value.
Rym: It's like hotels like a hundred and twenty bucks a night.
Scott: Right, you're only gonna be disappointed in like and you know PAX South If you're one of those people who just wants to be in the expo hall playing triple-a games.
Scott: in which case Please stop going to pack.
Rym: So from my perspective the expo hall at PAX South is kind of better than the one in paxies.
Scott: Yeah, it's less crowded.
Rym: Let's go the weird like lower tier games of people who can't afford to be at a bigger packs Which is usually the more interesting games.
Scott: And also there is some trip place that remember the last PAX South Frickin.
Scott: Nintendo was there with the stretch and shit, right?
Scott: You know.
Rym: and peck south was until PAX Unplugged got announced the most tabletop in packs.
Rym: For a lot of reasons it ended.
Rym: so it's great.
Rym: But I think we talked about this.
Rym: but when we went to San Antonio for the for PAX South We got trapped there for extra days because of a blizzard back in the north.
Rym: So we saw the fuck out of the Alamo.
Scott: Yeah There is nothing.
Scott: there is no tourist thing to do in San Antonio that we have not dude.
Scott: So there's no reason for me to stay there any longer than this.
Rym: We've said that we literally we went to the Alamo and spent hours there because there's nothing else to do.
Rym: So we read every piece of text Everywhere in the entire facility.
Rym: we sat in every little park all around it.
Rym: So Apparently said the Alamo made it on this list as The worst tourist trap in Texas.
Scott: who made this list under what I don't even know or care?
Scott: Is this just some BuzzFeed list or is it like a real list?
Scott: Wso ctv.com I guess some local TV network?
Rym: yeah, but that that's not news because the reality is the Alamo might be in terms of Expectation versus reality the second worst tourist trap in all of America.
Scott: I mean the Alamo is not it's it.
Scott: I mean I my expectations were low but I can understand how people's expectations can be high because it's mythos.
Rym: You've seen that Davy Crockett, right?
Scott: of the Alamo.
Scott: the legend of the Alamo is Larger than the reality which is it?
Rym: just sort of this building and it's not In some ruins and it's like there's just strip malls next to it.
Scott: now, it's half gift shop.
Scott: Yep You'll probably have more fun if you're a tourist like with a family doing like the Ripley's believe it or not garbage across the street yep, uh.
Rym: So I think the only tourist trap in all of America that has a bigger disparity between the average person's Expectation and the reality of it is Mount Rushmore.
Scott: Fuck Mount Rushmore.
Scott: What's wrong with Mount Rushmore?
Rym: You ever been to it?
Scott: No, why?
Rym: if the thing with around much Mount Rushmore people treat it like it's something you should go see right?
Scott: is that never been?
Rym: There I know better.
Scott: is it's which?
Scott: it's in South Dakota, right?
Rym: It's it's in the middle of nowhere, right?
Scott: Is it nothing you're gonna?
Scott: you're gonna go to this place in the middle of fucking.
Scott: no meaning that it is your desk.
Scott: There's nothing else.
Scott: there Is a bunch of faces on a rock.
Rym: there's nothing to do there and the faces aren't even that great.
Scott: There's nothing around it.
Scott: It's just.
Rym: but think about this.
Rym: if Mount Rushmore We're like at some exit on your way to a real place.
Scott: Yeah, it's a five-minute.
Scott: Check it out worth.
Rym: It's going like oh look at that then keep going.
Rym: But the fact that you would have to make your entire trip around going to it.
Scott: At least the Alamo there's like you can walk around.
Scott: so it's like a museum a tiny crappy one But a museum.
Scott: there's something in there.
Scott: Mount Rushmore is like is a bunch of rocks of four president's heads that someone made by dynamite.
Scott: And here they are.
Scott: but you look at them for a few minutes and then you're good.
Rym: San Antonio is weird because I've been going there every year.
Rym: now like I'm gonna keep going to that packs.
Rym: I love it, but a Lot of people especially families seem to go to San Antonio as a tourist destination.
Scott: Well, I mean if you live nearby, right if it's.
Scott: if it's you know, there's a lot of land.
Rym: No, these are these people are?
Rym: it's not like they live nearby and they come in and like go out like day trip.
Rym: These are people like come and stay for days in hotels and go around the city.
Rym: It's a two-day town And that's if you go like out of your way to like the museum's right.
Scott: So the best part about this article the other thing you had to understand though Is that and we're sure definitely gonna talk about this in the main part of the show.
Scott: Is that you know?
Scott: He who travels alone travels fastest.
Scott: Yeah, it's like so we're and we're too fast people.
Scott: So even together we're really we're pretty fast.
Scott: Yeah, we're faster than a lot of one people's traveling.
Scott: Right, so but when you're with a family traveling with the children, yeah, that's hella slow.
Rym: So like a two-day town grandma doesn't want to go see the thing and mom's picky about it.
Scott: at the rest You know the mother tie Alamo.
Scott: that takes you and me one hour to see everything is gonna take a family all fucking day but San Antonio is.
Rym: so the best part about this is not necessarily that you know article.
Rym: It's the FARC thread associated with it of people talking about Texas San Antonio and Tourism because basically everyone there is the exact same opinion We do.
Rym: the river walks nice and there's this Tower of America's thing I guess you can go on top of and this comment here.
Rym: Yes Let's climb to the top of this building so we can see all the highways and Walmart parking lots.
Scott: That's what we saw.
Rym: Yep The only interesting thing we saw up there at all other than the awesome mysterious industrial facility far away Yep out in the desert couldn't even tell what it was.
Rym: There's some sort of factory looking thing.
Rym: We spent like 10 minutes like trying to figure out what it was and that was cool.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: It's just San Antonio.
Rym: People go to this place as a tourist destination Mm-hmm, and I really just don't get it.
Rym: and you can enjoy this FARC thread of people comparing even people who come to New York.
Scott: What do they do?
Scott: They go look at the Statue of Liberty?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: What's the difference between the Statue of Liberty and Mount Rushmore?
Scott: it was made by French people and Statue of Liberty is next to like 4,000 other things you can do of a similar caliber, right but those tourists they don't go to Ellis Island, right?
Scott: You know, they're doing stupid shit.
Rym: They don't even go to Governor's Island.
Scott: Like they don't know the Governor's Island exists.
Rym: Yeah, like if you're a tourist coming in here, it's like they just go whoa tall buildings and they buy stuff They go to stores and some of the coolest things you can do in New York are just like ride the East River ferry.
Rym: It cost like a dollar.
Rym: Well, I guess it cost 275.
Scott: Well, I mean if you're a tourist you can ride the circle line.
Scott: the circle line is actually not bad.
Scott: Yeah, that's like it's a one one of the few things you can do as a tourist.
Scott: That's not bad Yep, but like you can live in New York and I can just go ride the circle line tomorrow.
Scott: That's a good time.
Rym: Ah someone pointed out you can see the Alamo from top there Which you can and that really puts in the stark contrast that the Alamo is not a thing anymore.
Rym: Also the the last stand of the Alamo was a bunch of jerks who were basically fighting to preserve slavery.
Rym: so Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah In some other news, I got a little bit of a geek bite.
Rym: So I know I'm late to the party on this but I on my flight back from Hong Kong I watched a bunch of episodes of Westworld.
Scott: Oh The you'll Brenner TV show doesn't have you a Brenner in it.
Rym: No Well, yeah, you think of it as a year-old Brenner TV show, but it's Michael Crichton.
Rym: Really?
Rym: You're just obsessed with your Brenner, which I can understand why An attractive man.
Rym: But Westworld I actually watched a bunch of it.
Rym: now Emily and I are watching it together to watch it all the way to the End season one is done.
Rym: It's only ten episodes.
Rym: So it's pretty short to watch.
Rym: It's real good and The best way I describe it is if you like say Jurassic Park or that episode of The Simpsons Where they go to itchy and scratchy land.
Rym: Both of those things are actually more referencing or based on Westworld than based on anything else.
Rym: You might think they're based on who I mean.
Scott: who didn't know that?
Rym: Most people think that itchy and scotchy episode is based solely on Jurassic Park and have no idea that Michael Crichton also made Westworld.
Rym: Okay, people don't know this stuff I've discovered.
Rym: but Westworld like the TV Westworld is Jurassic Park with robots instead of dinosaurs Except it gets a lot more into like cyberpunk Ghost in the Shell nonsense.
Rym: Mm-hmm and the new TV series.
Rym: it takes the premise of Westworld and Kind of minimizes the action thriller like cowboy robot shooting each other And it really focused.
Rym: It's just Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: It's Ghost in the Shell nonsense and it's really really really good in so far as I've seen the first third of it.
Scott: So I'm gonna watch.
Scott: it's ten episodes.
Scott: You only seen three.
Scott: Yeah, but you're on a flight from Hong Kong.
Rym: That's enough time to watch like 30 because I also So that flight to Hong Kong from Hong Kong.
Rym: I slept for half of it.
Rym: Okay, and the other half I mostly went around collecting bits to upgrade the Hylian clothing all the way to the max and Went around collecting thing.
Rym: I basically got my hundred ancient arrows turned out.
Rym: I only needed like 10 to be gannin.
Rym: So yeah I was not just watching Westworld and in fact I was watching the fourth episode and then the flight was about to land.
Rym: so I didn't see the end of that episode.
Rym: But it's real good.
Rym: And if you're into Existential Turing test like what does it mean to be conscious?
Rym: Cyberpunk nonsense.
Rym: It's real good, but it is real violence and real disturbing.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: I mean the original Westworld movie was disturbing.
Rym: Yeah, but in a more Because of the tech this the special effects capabilities of the day.
Rym: it's a little more over the top.
Scott: So it's each of the killer disturbing.
Rym: This one is more.
Rym: you know each of the killer like.
Rym: the main part of its violence was that the camera wouldn't cut away And you'd see like three more seconds of that knife cutting across before it would snap back.
Rym: Westworld is very hyper realistic violence.
Scott: I heard something about someone was like gonna like remaster.
Scott: each of the killer like HD.
Rym: each of the killers, you know I don't know if I really want to see that because You see the killer like.
Rym: I like that movie.
Rym: what I made in the in the sense My only.
Scott: really the only thing good about that movie is that if you it's one of those movies where you can You know watch it when it's super late at night and like you're really really tired It's got that sort of Nighttime mood sort of the same sort of same mood as Space Ghost has when you watch it at like, you know 2 a.m It's like
Rym: it's.
Rym: also it's much like apocalypse zero.
Rym: It's one of those media experiences where it may not necessarily be good and I may have been disturbed by it But I remember it and it was an experience that I'm glad I had even if I don't necessarily want to replicate that experience.
Rym: West world has moments that approach that level of violence, but unlike each of the killer they are coupled with actual Emotions and characters and plots you care about as opposed to something that makes no sense.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: I mean the hypnotist like each of the killer really Really does not end the way you probably all think it does Because all those people that Oda kind of walked out before the end They didn't get to see that muscle hypo hypnotism moment Which is I think that might be in my top five of scenes and movies I've ever seen
Scott: right?
Rym: Because I did not know how to react to what was happening on screen at that moment in that movie.
Scott: That doesn't make it top five Makes it I think is in my top five though top five of things.
Scott: I didn't know how to react to.
Scott: sure.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, it made me sit up and go.
Rym: Wait.
Rym: What's this movie about again?
Rym: A bit of the ultra violence, but yeah Westworld is super good so far as I've seen and it's only ten episodes.
Rym: So you might as well just watch it and it's real easy to see it whether or not you pay for it.
Rym: Just saying Got any other news.
Rym: Is that it?
Rym: We're good.
Rym: then I guess it's time for Things of the day says, you know Another thing I've watched the scout doesn't watch is it's always sunny in Philadelphia Which kind of scratches that the itch that Seinfeld would scratch?
Rym: except Seinfeld does not Largely live up to modern comedic sensibilities.
Rym: Seinfeld was more revolutionary for its time But I wouldn't necessarily recommend people go back and watch it.
Rym: It's always sunny.
Rym: It's just it kind of scratches that itch now and I really like it.
Rym: I'm not gonna review it right now.
Rym: My thing of the day is a super cut of all the intros to all the episodes of.
Rym: it's always sunny in Philadelphia because the open the intros to these episodes have a very particular theme and style and way they come together and shotgunning all of them in this 11-minute video is Pretty entertaining even if you don't actually know what the show is about.
Rym: So what do you got for me?
Scott: Alright, so here's an old old old issue of.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's the village voice But it could be just voice but it's from like October 1986 and the article is favorite dinosaurs of The Mets as in the New York Mets who play baseball and I'm not sure if the author Charlie Rubin spelled exactly the same as my last name related to me Actually went and Interviewed the Mets to get these answers or if this is a complete work of fiction, but it does not matter.
Rym: Nope, the mythos is all that matters.
Scott: He answered it in the character of the various players.
Scott: So it's as if they answered the question.
Rym: Mookie Wilson.
Rym: when I'm in a slum I comfort myself by saying if I believe in dinosaurs then somewhere they must be real They must be believing in me.
Rym: It must be something I could.
Scott: it was cut off in my and if they believe in me then I can believe in me.
Scott: Then I bust out.
Scott: Yep, right, so it's like.
Scott: is basically he asked, you know each met real or fiction?
Scott: I'm not sure if you know if you actually asked them, but these have to be fictional because they're Rafael Santana.
Rym: I know two things the best ball players in the world come from San Pedro de Macau Ris in the Dominican Republic and the best petrosaurus come from terrace or terrace.
Rym: those come from Kansas.
Rym: Kansas is the San Pedro de Macau Ris of flying shit.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: There's an excellent article from olden days and I think you know, it makes you think and realize like, you know Every day or consuming, you know so much internets, right?
Scott: I read so much internets every day But I'm only reading things that are like brand new that day like instantly even if something's five minutes old.
Scott: It's too old not reading it right, but there was already so much content created in the past.
Scott: Most of it you could ignore, you know, like you don't need to read a newspaper article from like, you know About some local townie happening in the 80s or whatever right, but you know a lot of things like this.
Scott: You know, I've been in magazines and you know Newspapers and all sorts of other print medias, you know things that like aren't even like like saved likely like programs to various Events and things, you know, they're school newspapers.
Scott: You know some things some kid made somewhere.
Scott: Well, you know what.
Scott: so there's a ton of great content out there That's really inaccessible or is hidden in libraries and unless someone takes a photo of it and puts it on internet You're not gonna see it.
Rym: So when I was in middle school I was there because they were busting me over to the high school to take mostly high school classes.
Rym: I didn't have enough Actual classes in the middle school to take so the school put me in this sort of like work program where I worked For the school's library.
Rym: So for an hour and a half a day I just sit in the library and I guess shelve books but there wasn't enough work to do.
Rym: so what I did is I would they had an archive a physical archive of Every issue of popular science and popular mechanics.
Rym: I read all of them.
Scott: every single one covered cover.
Rym: I'm not covered a couple.
Rym: Well, I'm based.
Rym: I take each one out what every day I just take a pile of them and I flipped through each one like look at every page and see if there's anything interesting and I'd Would get.
Rym: I'd get through like 30 of them a day.
Rym: And that's what I did in middle school.
Scott: That's a lot of time.
Rym: What else was it gonna do?
Rym: They wouldn't let me play.
Rym: my gameboy Wasn't allowed to do that.
Rym: Uh Modern like there's no smartphone.
Rym: It's not like I could sit and look at the internet.
Rym: What was I gonna do?
Rym: I looked at the physical internet.
Rym: So in the moment, the book club book is Frank Herbert's Dune and because I beat Gannon, I'm gonna read it soon.
Rym: Just be Gannon.
Rym: You guys just go kill Gannon right now.
Scott: I have even gone to Goron land.
Rym: Oh, you can.
Rym: you could kill Gannon right now.
Rym: In fact without going to Goron land.
Rym: It might be more fun.
Rym: Probably Goron land is way easy and boring You really I'm really really sad that I did Goron land last cuz it's the weakest of the four Mmm, like the plot is boring The characters are boring the.
Rym: the shrine is either the shrine the beast is easy and the quest to get to the beast is also Really easy.
Scott: I didn't do any of the house buying stuff or yeah the dragon scale getting I got.
Rym: I did to the dragon scales I didn't care anymore.
Scott: I only got one.
Scott: I gave the other two.
Rym: I was trying to farm the dragons to upgrade my champion shirt cuz that's the only way to see actual hit points of enemies.
Rym: But I just wore my like Zora suit.
Rym: It didn't matter.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So yeah, otherwise, you should check out my youtube channel and Scott's youtube channel.
Rym: This episode of GeekNights is live streaming right now on YouTube And if you follow my youtube channel most episodes of GeekNights just live stream and there are 11 people watching it right now And they're actually.
Rym: they're having a great big old chat in there right now.
Scott: They should not do that.
Scott: I'm sure there's something better to do.
Rym: Well, they're literally like just like chatting There's like.
Scott: I mean look, you know while I haven't seen it and I can't personally recommend it Wouldn't you be better off going to watch that Westworld the room was just talking about than watching GeekNights?
Scott: You are better off what it.
Scott: wouldn't that be a better use of your time?
Rym: Even watching the old you you'll Brenner Westworld is definitely a better use of time than watching GeekNights though I don't let anyone spoil Westworld for you Like if you don't know what the deal is with Westworld don't go look it up like the old Westworld Robots.
Rym: watch this robot people, you know, it's funny cuz this wasn't planned cuz robot cowboy.
Rym: We didn't know what we were doing the show on until like just when we started recording.
Rym: but we're doing the show on amusement parks and it just so happens that half of our Topics ended up being about amusement parks there heads that we had to have done a show to use in parks.
Scott: I couldn't find one.
Scott: No way.
Scott: This is like one of rims top five favorite things to talk.
Rym: Yeah, it's like what I was gonna talk about on NTP heuristics the fixed protocol.
Scott: I Will be not done a show in all of rims favorite things already.
Scott: I mean I sir you could search yourself, but I'm sure we did shows on all of Scott's favorite things.
Scott: learning Yeah, but I this I mean did we even do a show on the fixed protocol?
Scott: Don't worry about it.
Rym: We could do a show on the fixed protocol.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: You're better off watching Westworld than listen to me.
Rym: Talk about the fixed protocol.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: So I have a complicated Relationship with amusement parks because on one hand I Grew up in a place where I could go to Cedar Point Which is literally the best roller coaster park in the world bar none.
Rym: Like there is not even a question It's not the best amusement park by any stretch, but it is definitely the best roller coaster park.
Rym: But growing up like near that and like literally going to Cedar Point multiple times a summer every summer It was a big part of my childhood and roller coasters actually were a big hobby of mine like learning about them and like learning About how I knew how to see your point and amusement parks get run.
Rym: But at the same time I'm gonna see you playing a rollercoaster tycoon.
Rym: I did a lot just not recently.
Rym: But well, the problem with roller coaster tycoon is that it's not accurate at all much like playing striking Uh The same rib bone twice and yet making tudes entirely distinct sounds.
Scott: Why don't you?
Scott: Make roller coaster like simulator.
Scott: that's accurate like the farm simulator and such.
Rym: Ah, you know what?
Rym: I wonder if that exists anyway, I will look that up.
Rym: but amusement parks outside of Cedar Point Always feel weirdly Sad and cheap to me.
Scott: Well, I think it's just that when I was young, you know Cuz like kid brain.
Scott: Yeah, it's just kid brain, right?
Scott: It's like even like when you're in San Antonio, right?
Scott: We saw those like believe it or not sitting haunted houses and shit across the street from the Alamo.
Scott: And when I was a kid I went to those things and when I passed by them say in Niagara Falls or New Hampshire or any other kind of touristy Place like George I'd be like, ooh, I want to go in there.
Scott: That looks cool.
Rym: Not only does exist It's called no limits.
Rym: It has a sequel It also works with VR and it's like ultra physics engine.
Rym: It looks like sure.
Scott: But now when I see those my adult eyeballs like oh wow, those look really sad and run down and crappy.
Scott: Yep, I do think though some aspect of that rundown this?
Scott: I'm not 100% sure on this.
Scott: I'd need like video or phone was less rundown when you were younger fertile.
Scott: Yeah Is that?
Scott: I think like my memory is like in the 90s it seemed like there was like some economic Explosion where there was tons of money.
Rym: well case in point malls, right animatronics.
Scott: You would go to malls and like the Disney Store would be like some crazy Experience full of animatronics shit and they'd be like a VR thing and that'd be like a you know NASCAR simulator thing.
Scott: and there'd be a laser tag in the mall.
Rym: and then the mall in my house had a water park Inside of it.
Rym: Yeah, and there were water slides that wound their way around the mall that had glass walls.
Scott: You could see people going by things like battle tech pods, right?
Scott: But now as time went on, you know, those things weren't upgraded.
Scott: They were run down shuttered, you know destroyed sold Disappear owed.
Rym: Yeah, it's got dirty and janky.
Scott: They were not maintained.
Scott: so it's
Rym: interesting because you know I by going to the same amusement park year after year after year and By not only was I a nerd about amusement like Cedar Point and roller coasters But my family was too like the coffee table book in our living room for a long time was this gigantic hardcover like in-depth history of Cedar Point Like that stuff.
Rym: so like.
Rym: I knew a lot about the history and the park was way more rundown when I was younger and then it got an infusion of money and was like way cleaned up and got way better and Then I got kind of crappy to run down again.
Rym: and then they like super rebrand and got rid of all the Berenstain Bears dust and replaced it with like Ultra commercialized Snoopy nonsense.
Scott: I like Snoopy.
Scott: I like Snoopy a lot better than Berenstain Bears Yeah, but the Berenstain Bears thing was like this barely commercialized like science center And I thought Berenstain Bears is religious.
Scott: or is that just something I'm remembering incorrectly?
Rym: I feel like it was adjacent to that, but I don't think it was directly that I remember just being Inoffensive and lame and really like gender-rolly.
Scott: I was not a fan of Berenstain Bears when other kids were reading it in like first grade.
Rym: Yeah, well because by first grade you're already a little too old for the Berenstain Bears not some of the kids in my class.
Rym: I remember in my elementary school in fifth grade They gave the four smart kids in class my side of the mountain to read and they gave all the other kids in class the biography of Michael Jordan.
Scott: I've read a biography of Michael Jordan.
Scott: Yeah for fun because they figured that the the rest of the class When I read a biography of Michael Jordan, he was still playing Yeah But uh, he hadn't even played baseball yet at the time.
Rym: so amusement park.
Rym: So it's weird too because amusement parks are like fake by design.
Rym: but at least for like nerds like us it's almost more interesting to Embrace the fakeness to me and like really try to look around the corners Look at the things you're not supposed to look at and like check out the back end and like see what's going on in that Parking lot.
Scott: I was always doing that but yeah You know that you could still write the.
Scott: the front sides of things were, you know, pristine mostly, right?
Scott: So like The amusement park I went to most when we were young was the one that they would take us to on trips whether you know in the Geographically, you know situated right which is called Riverside.
Scott: I had this raccoon mascot and then what happened is the years went on.
Scott: Eventually Riverside got bought by Six Flags and it's now Six Flags New England.
Scott: and when Six Flags New England bought it.
Scott: they started Adding and replacing and adding and replacing, right?
Scott: So there's like still like.
Scott: if I go there I can still point out like ah That's from Riverside that you know, there's like this this area in the middle It can is still Riverside.
Scott: basically, even though it's not hasn't been called that in forever And everything else that's like out, you know, it's all brand new stuff.
Scott: So that's where I went the most.
Scott: but like also you'd be there like summer camp and you could like.
Scott: I think I went to Dorney Wants and Hershey Lake Compounce.
Scott: Yeah the the ambulance I went there was.
Rym: I just learned from Wikipedia that Lake Compounce is the oldest Continuously operating amusement park in North America.
Scott: Yeah, Lake Compounce actually originally was sort of like this just like Lake with like bungalows.
Rym: Well, so it's contemporary to Cedar Point.
Rym: Cedar Point started the same way in the 1800s as like a lake resort on Lake Erie.
Scott: Yeah, just like a resort like rich people would go there and hang out and have a good time and then eventually You know slowly they added rides to it at some point, right?
Scott: Yeah Became a natural place to put that sort of thing and then that became the bigger attraction than the original.
Scott: It's like if you owned a roller skating rink and you put in a pac-man machine and suddenly everyone's playing pac-man and no one's roller skating.
Scott: Eventually you get rid of the roller skating and just fill it up.
Rym: As a kid, I used to go to roller rinks a lot.
Rym: There were a bunch of them in my town.
Scott: There's only one in our town and it I think some years it like burned down multiple times And now it's actually gone.
Scott: now for reals.
Rym: I think they used to run these all-night parties where you'd go there all night and just like Rollerblade and hang out in the arcade mostly.
Scott: Yeah, we went you know, there were many birthday parties there.
Rym: Yeah but yeah, like all these old amusement parks like eventually started like adding rides bit by bit and becoming like real places and Disney is probably the first like modern amusement park.
Scott: I want to say well Disney's a theme park, right?
Scott: It's not really well true.
Rym: There's a theme other than just there are amusement, right?
Scott: There's like.
Scott: there's like.
Scott: it's like a few different tiers, right?
Scott: The first tier is the portable one that like comes to your town Arnie's the carny one, right as a kid We'd whenever the carny's were in town.
Rym: I always wanted to go over there.
Rym: My parents are like, no, they're in a store.
Scott: Oh, they were in a story like last week.
Rym: Yeah Like yeah, that's a kid brain.
Rym: There's rides.
Rym: I want to ride them.
Rym: I don't give a fuck about how safe they are.
Scott: And those rides are safe.
Scott: Yeah, the tiny ones.
Rym: Yeah They're not that safe.
Scott: Yeah, you're good.
Rym: I saw someone get seriously injured on one when I was a kid Sure, and I was on one that broke down and other people got hurt.
Rym: I was actually okay.
Rym: But I I saw one the chain that like drove the spinner snapped and flew out into the crowd.
Rym: It didn't hit anyone but it hit a tree and like embedded inside of it Yeah, nice like that would have killed whoever it hit.
Scott: I'll be on YouTube today.
Rym: Yeah, the funny thing is if you're on that ride, it would have been safer.
Rym: Yeah, I rode one once We were in luck.
Rym: We went to like a Michigan State Fair and they the carnies set up these rides and there's this one ride that was manually controlled Like it wasn't just like hit a button to start hit him on the stop.
Rym: the guy was like moving this throttle constantly and like looking at gauges and My parents started talking to the car and he was like, yeah this thing's actually illegal in most of the country because it's super fucking dangerous and like.
Rym: I could really hurt people if I mess up and It's fun so fast.
Rym: I couldn't breathe Nice.
Rym: Yeah like literally start spinning and my brother and I like faster faster and the guys like like he gives us his thumb up and then He's basically it's a spinner and then around it are Sub-spinners and the cars are on the end of those sub spinners.
Rym: So if the sub spinner was spinning in the same direction as the main spinner, you literally could not breathe And I never wrote that thing.
Scott: So the next tier up is sort of like the established in one place amusement park, but not a big one, right?
Scott: So in Connecticut, there's like quasi is the one we went to.
Scott: there's also one in New Hampshire That was like.
Scott: it was sort of like an old timey town.
Scott: I forget what it was called, but it had like.
Scott: It had a like one of those houses where you sit in it in the room turns around you and a train ride.
Scott: You know, it's just like it didn't even have a one roller coaster, you know, but it's like an established place with some rides.
Scott: But you know, it doesn't It's not really large.
Rym: Yeah, and then there's the full-on theme parks The ones like people follow the world or at least all over the region will go to.
Scott: well There's even stuff in between that though, right?
Scott: It's like, you know the six flat, you know like six flags kind of places are in between the small places in the Few roller coasters and like a bunch of like basic thrill rides.
Scott: Right and this even with though even with the six flags level of thing There's all.
Scott: there's almost sort of like two levels of that, right?
Scott: There's some six flags that are like tiny and there's some that are like the mega.
Scott: No, we're the.
Scott: we're this crazy six flags and we're sort of like yeah, we're just a six flags We're like one of the crappy ones.
Rym: So as a kid, it was weird because I would like like my family like, you know We're talking about fast like we're fast movers when it comes to travel Like we see the whole Alamo and like we've seen everything.
Rym: we were like that at amusement parks anywhere We went.
Rym: we'd like study the map in advance and like we're gonna ride this ride first and we're gonna like You're gonna eat in line and not waste time be there when the park opens you leave after the park closes Like we were puff puff puff go go go 100% Even when I was a little kid
Scott: Yeah, I mean the difference was is like, you know, I think Probably me one who was willing to ride more rides than anyone else in the family.
Scott: You know see my whole family was like down with the roller coaster, yeah Yeah, and it wasn't like we were gonna like split up in some crazy crowded place when we were all children's.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So it's like we just sort of you know, we weren't slow, you know We're definitely faster than some others, but we were not the fastest right.
Scott: and you know, depending on the place, you know you know how long lines or whatever, but I never felt like We missed out on like there was never a time where there's something I wanted to go on that we didn't go on.
Rym: no No, it's like dinner point was just so big and it's so many coasters that you regularly would not ride Like you could not ride every ride there in one day.
Rym: Yeah, there's literally no way.
Scott: the other the other good times though We're like when we went with like summer camp or something You just sort of like be on your own or with a couple camp friends.
Rym: those are those early forays into Independence.
Scott: or you'd go with school and you just be like with a couple of your school friends and then you just run around Everything.
Rym: that was so my high school.
Rym: the physics classes would always do like physics day.
Rym: We're like y'all go to Cedar Point and you have to do some experiments and the rides.
Scott: We didn't do any of that.
Scott: We just said we're going to be used in parking.
Scott: There was no.
Scott: there was no Justification other than school trip.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: So when I took the day I turned 16 was in January.
Rym: so like I got a car and I could drive that was crazy.
Rym: and that summer When I was 16, I had this revelation like I was in school one day.
Rym: It was like near early June like school's gonna be out soon and I just suddenly realized wait a minute I could just drive my car to Cedar Point.
Rym: I could just go there.
Rym: Who's gonna stop me?
Rym: I can do whatever the hell I want.
Rym: I have a car.
Rym: So the next day me and a bunch of furniture skip school and she went to Cedar Point.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and that was great Being.
Rym: that was like being alone in amusement parks as a kid without your slow parents slowing you down Was one of the like the highlights of my childhood, but now I haven't been to one in a long time.
Rym: But I'm feeling that itch like real strong Man, I mean like.
Rym: I'm not feeling the amusement park.
Rym: itch like I don't want to go see shows in an amusement park.
Rym: I don't even want to go to the arcade in an amusement park.
Rym: I just want to ride a roller coaster.
Rym: I'm feeling the roller coaster itch Independent of any theme parking.
Scott: that is true, right?
Scott: Cuz it like in those days right in the 90s or whatever, right?
Scott: We didn't have no YouTube.
Scott: So like the show at an amusement park was like like whoa, holy crap.
Scott: now It's like you can see those things on the internet and they're not that exciting.
Scott: The arcades of the amusement park it used to be.
Scott: you'd go there and they'd like some games there.
Scott: It's like holy shit.
Scott: Even it with the time we were in college like early 2000s you go to reason parking at DDR and it's like oh my god Did your machine?
Rym: Yes, the Cedar Point was the first place I ever saw a physical DDR.
Scott: It was always.
Scott: it was always upsetting that the Arcades adding amusement parks cost like four times as much as the ones in your town.
Scott: But they always had like for some reason new the newest bestest fanciest games there.
Rym: I don't know if it's still there.
Rym: Cedar Point at least when I was a kid had a bunch of modern arcades, but they had one Giant arcade like, you know, it's other than fun spot, which is just mostly an arcade.
Scott: Yeah, the place that I went with the second biggest arcade was actually of all places Sesame Place in Pennsylvania, I don't know if it's still there.
Scott: I mean it's Sesame Place is still there But I don't know at least I think it is but I don't know if the arcade is still there.
Scott: The arcade at Sesame Place was like two stories tall as I remember it right and in one part They had all these custom Sesame Place computers.
Scott: Whoa, they were like Apple twos with simpler keyboard kind of things going on.
Scott: I can't remember.
Scott: maybe you search your Sesame Place computer.
Scott: You'll see one.
Rym: I think it's gone.
Scott: Anyway, and it had these like Sesame Street games on them and you could choose from among the games.
Scott: They're all like kid games, right?
Scott: Because it's Sesame Place, but those games were not available Like anywhere else ever.
Scott: it was like the only place.
Scott: you could play those ABC games at those computers at Sesame Place.
Scott: But that wasn't the whole arcade.
Scott: the rest of the arcade was a two-story big-ass room regular old arcade And I played like Simpsons arcade game there.
Rym: The biggest one was obviously not retro on purpose to like make money from being retro.
Rym: It was just they put all the old shitty games and like this one giant arcade.
Rym: But that giant arcade was nothing but like a retro arcade museum effectively and the games in there were only a quarter.
Rym: Well a token they didn't take quarters and the arcade games and the normal arcades cost normal money Like put a dollar in there to play your Simpsons or whatever.
Scott: Sesame Place still exists.
Rym: Let's see if this Sesame Place arcade still exists Because it looks like a lot of the games that were in the retro arcade at Cedar Point are not there anymore based on some tentative interneting.
Rym: But as an adult if I want to play retro arcade games, I could just go to magfest.
Rym: So if I go back to Cedar Point, which I'm really thinking about doing this summer I think I'm just going to ride roller coasters and literally do nothing else in that park And I think part of why I got amusement park out of my system like independent of a roller coaster was that I was just Recently in Disney for the first time as an adult and I think I amusement parked out in the course of that trip.
Rym: I'm just killing time while you look up your thing.
Rym: Have you looked it up yet?
Rym: Do I have to keep killing time?
Scott: I don't know if they still have an arcade there.
Scott: It's not clear from their website.
Scott: No, I want to find a picture of those old computers though.
Scott: So how cool would it be to get one of those computers?
Rym: Yeah, so in terms of that's the kind of thing you bring to magfest.
Scott: Oh, yeah, right?
Rym: Yeah We got to get on that.
Rym: see if we can find someone who will like bring it to magfest.
Scott: I found a picture of it.
Rym: So in terms of amusement parks like as a kid What?
Rym: what were your favorite rides?
Rym: and has that changed as an adult as a channel?
Scott: I haven't ridden rides in a long time.
Rym: I think the last ride we rode was both of us Remember when I had Lyme disease and Wildwood and we both paid the like $14 to ride that one roller coaster.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I don't really have a like a favorite kind of right.
Rym: maybe what kinds of rod like throw up forget roller coasters.
Rym: How about just throw rides?
Scott: I mean, yeah, so I'm saying it's like this.
Scott: It's pretty much as good ride or bad ride, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like if there's a roller coaster that's all shaky.
Scott: It makes you sick.
Scott: It's no good, but it is a roller coaster.
Scott: That's like whoo, then it's good.
Rym: You know, it's like mmm, but when you don't care like inversions or like partial inversions or hanging or I mean You know this good inversions and bad inversions.
Scott: now hanging ones that are good and bad and you know It's like there's definitely there's no particular category.
Scott: That's like better or worse, right one.
Rym: Yes, cuz I because I you know, I was a nerd about this I think about it in turn like they're sort of legit industry categories for all those different kinds of thrill rides.
Rym: So I can categorize them much more easily.
Rym: But that technology definitely changed like when I was a kid.
Rym: there was this inversion ride.
Rym: There was just a wheel like a ferris wheel that started sideways and then it would slowly rise to be vertical.
Rym: So you're just going upside down upside down upside down upside down and it would make some people real sick.
Scott: Yeah That's a good ride.
Rym: But that was like that era similar to the roundup Yeah, but in that era that was like the height of like full inversion thrill ride.
Rym: But I remember just as I was getting ready to go to college like a few years before that when I was in high school Cedar Point.
Rym: they kept the witch's wheel.
Rym: that was like a retro ride and they added this other ride called chaos.
Rym: It moved in so many axes that you could like it was.
Rym: it was insane how disorienting that ride was and you could see like this moment where Thrill ride like design and technology started to.
Rym: I guess use data or get more advanced or maybe material science Like allowed them to do crazier things.
Rym: But uh You know I kind of only liked thrill rides as a kid because you couldn't.
Rym: you literally could not just ride roller coasters all day Or you might get sick or get a headache and the lines were long.
Rym: So thrill rides were just like Many not roller coasters.
Rym: you'd ride between roller coasters Like.
Rym: I would never ride a thrill ride unless I was on my way to ride a real roller coaster.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: and in terms of roller coasters I pretty much primarily like the mega coasters like the out-and-back like Super giant hills super fast.
Rym: big drop like that was my favorite bar none like the Magnum or the millennium 4 And I was just happy to be riding a ride right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you're going whoo pretty much matter what ride it is You know It's better than not riding a ride.
Rym: wait in line has ever been a ride that like messed you up or you didn't go.
Scott: Woo, like it was bad news when I was super small Super small, right?
Scott: So again sesame place There was it.
Scott: there's a water ride there.
Scott: it's actually called the counts car wash and the count is my guy.
Scott: Yeah, I know the counter guy other than you know, Cookie Monster, right?
Scott: And the counts car wash is basically sort of like.
Scott: I'm sure you could find pictures of it.
Rym: It's basically like, you know tubes you crawl around in like, you know mesh net - oh They had one of those on the roof of the ball pit building when I was a kid.
Scott: yeah, you know and it sprays water on you all the time, right.
Scott: but You know the second time I went to sesame place, you know I had this memory of the first time I went there.
Scott: and the memory I had of the first time I went there Was not, you know when I looked at it I saw like you're just being sprayed with water everywhere, right?
Scott: It wasn't like any big deal, but my memory was that it was basically Cylinders and tubes and you know pieces that were 100% filled with water.
Scott: And like.
Scott: I had this fake memory obviously fake memory of like, you know, basically being trapped in these tubes Yeah, completely submerged.
Rym: I had all these memories.
Scott: Like I was like I was inside a clear but filled in submarine trying to swim out.
Scott: I had all I was not, you know, I had a severe negative memory associated with the counts car wash.
Scott: Now when I look at it, it's like whatever it's.
Rym: I had all these weird fake memory.
Scott: I guess I went on it when I was too young.
Rym: It created a false thing cuz there was like the giant tube thing.
Rym: It wasn't water.
Rym: It was just like on the roof of this building versus John.
Rym: as far as I remembered as a kid It was a structure so large and so complex that I was pretty sure there were kids who just lived inside of it And like had never found their way out.
Rym: and when I saw it as a teenager I went up there and looked at it.
Rym: I was taller than it.
Rym: and yet I remember it towering above me to the point that I never thought I'd see the top of it.
Rym: Perspective of how high your eyeline is actually changes those situations a lot.
Rym: But the only ride that ever messed me up I think was so see your point added.
Rym: because they started doing like the different kinds of coasters and They made a new kind of coaster one year called the Mantis.
Rym: It was a standing coaster.
Rym: you stand on a platform and there's a fuck up harness that comes over your shoulders.
Rym: But you stand and they're like vertically and the ride goes and there's a little platform that kind of comes up Like almost like a bicycle seat.
Rym: you're not supposed to sit on it But it like is there to keep you from falling down out of the roller coaster.
Rym: so the first so I. I waited in line for like three hours to ride the thing cuz it was a new ride never was Lined up for it and I finally get on it and I go and the bicycle seat thing Stayed a little too high and crushed my balls and I spent the entire ride desperately trying to not get my balls Completely crushed at the bottom of every hill and it was a nightmare.
Rym: It's very telling that they since got rid of that roller coaster and they rebuilt it to be a different format of coaster is no Standing coaster.
Scott: so I can't find a picture of the counts carwash.
Scott: it's apparently been replaced with the counts splash castle.
Scott: and Looking at a picture of the splash castle like wow, that thing is actually fucking awesome looking.
Rym: Oh, yeah They read they renamed it the Rougarou and it's flawless.
Rym: instead of floor that literally tries to crush rims balls.
Rym: Okay, so a good job.
Rym: I think that was the only bad roller coaster I ever rode other than oh Well, I when I was a kiddo there was a quasi.
Scott: there was like a. we rode like this tiny tiny roller coaster where there's only two people in the car like a little cat and mouse dealing and It's one of those ones, you know goes up and then it sort of makes all like these sharp turns like you're going perfectly straight Like there isn't any elevation changing and it'll make like a 90-degree turn a 90-degree turn and return.
Scott: It's just like uh, uh, uh, and it's a wooden and crappy.
Scott: and click click click click click and it's really uncomfortable.
Scott: Then it'll go down a little bit and it's like yeah, and it's just sort of someone like beating the shit out of you Right, like shaking your body around in random directions.
Rym: That's what it was like for me with the old cuz.
Rym: I like old wooden coasters for like history and aesthetics.
Rym: But actually riding one of those things is just a guaranteed migraine headache.
Scott: for the rest I mean, they're good wooden ones and bad wooden ones.
Rym: Most of the ones you think of as good wooden ones are technically steel Possibly if they're smooth if the track if the tracks are round steel tubes It doesn't matter if the whole thing is made out of wood.
Rym: That is a steel coast.
Scott: No, the tracks are.
Rym: there's still lots of metal.
Scott: Yeah, the rails right.
Scott: so I get a Busch Gardens.
Scott: There's one where it's like this Uh, it's it's wooden and there's two roller coaster to sort of go at the same time a red one and a blue one.
Rym: There's one of those in Cedar Point called Gemini, but it's a steel coaster, right?
Scott: But it's like a lion tiger deal or something because Busch Gardens has you know animal theme.
Scott: Yeah, right But it's like it's.
Scott: definitely they're on rails But it was you know at the time I went on it.
Scott: It was like it was modern and smooth and kind of nice to ride.
Scott: It wasn't like, you know What's the?
Scott: what's the one that was at Riverside?
Scott: It was like Thunderbolt or something and that thing was shaky as fuck.
Scott: It was like, you know, it was a normal looking roller coaster.
Scott: You go up you go down a hill you make a turn you come back you go down another hill, right?
Scott: But the whole time it was like someone was shaking you like the vibration machine.
Rym: Yeah, so the mean streak was the longest fastest wood style roller coaster in the world when they built it.
Rym: so it was the super super long ride and It was pretty fun and it was like a but it was a wooden coaster.
Rym: after a few years Wooden coasters tended to grade in quality rapidly and it got so shaky that it like I would literally get a splitting headache If I wrote it, I'd still ride it almost every year.
Rym: Anyway, I don't know why I just felt like I had to but I would not ride a traditional wooden coaster again unless there was some particular historic reason to.
Rym: So Do you think you'll go to roll out to a amusement park again at some point?
Scott: I'm sure sometime before I die.
Rym: Hopefully you want to go with me to Cedar Point this summer.
Scott: No, I would like to go but the problem is it's just not worth it Considering how much of a pain in the ass it is to go there.
Rym: That's why my plan is to fly there.
Rym: do like two or three days of like get all the roller coaster out of my system And then go back to my normal life.
Rym: It's still too much of a pain in the ass to go there Kinda like how I just did for Disney went to Disney and all the Disney out of my system and now I can wait a Decade.
Rym: I'll go back to Disney when like the new Star Wars land is fully fully fully complete.
Scott: So whatever roller coaster it is that we rode at Busch Gardens.
Scott: That was wooden.
Scott: He's not on their website anymore.
Scott: I don't understand that right.
Scott: people tearing that like you run an amusement park, right?
Scott: People are gonna like.
Scott: they're always trying to get like the biggest craziest ride or whatever but like, oh, why?
Scott: Are you like, you know?
Rym: Smashing rides it's a point used to not like.
Rym: there was a point where they stopped tearing down roller coasters because they figured why not?
Rym: Just keep adding them and always have the world record of having the most roller coasters But then they started destroying ones that didn't get ridden anymore that maintenance cost more than like the value.
Scott: I'm saying it's like you only care that people come to the park.
Scott: You don't really care how much they ride when they come there.
Scott: You just wanted to come and stay right?
Scott: So they're gonna come pretty much no matter what rides you fucking have.
Scott: No, cuz I really.
Scott: are you really gonna get like more if you pay zillions of dollars for another roller coaster?
Scott: Is that really gonna bring in enough people to like pay for it and make you more money?
Scott: So what with the rides you got already?
Rym: I think so Disney doesn't need to like.
Rym: I don't think Disney could probably get away with never fucking changing anything forever because it's such A cultural icon, but they change things constantly Yeah, but they also keep a lot of old stuff there Not as much what Nate.
Rym: what's something new in the Magic Kingdom?
Rym: in the last decade I haven't been there.
Rym: So I don't know but I can tell you old stuff they got rid of Yeah, but most of the old stuff especially the ride rides are just still there and they're mostly the same.
Rym: but so like Cedar Point because it was like if a place has repeat traffic as opposed to occasional traffic like Regionally the people who go there every year.
Rym: they always have to have a piece of news to advertise to remind people Hey, there's new shit here.
Rym: Come back.
Rym: So like there would be ads on TV like as a kid right around like April Like May as they get toward the end of the school year ads would be on primetime TV Advertising the new roller coaster.
Scott: Yeah, we had those all kinds of ads like that advertising the new roller coaster.
Rym: People would come to the park who wouldn't otherwise go and line up for four hours to ride.
Scott: But you could have just had an advertisement.
Scott: just say hey, we got a crazy amusement park.
Scott: Holy shit, you don't need you know advertising the specific roller coaster.
Scott: How much did that really help?
Rym: I guess it depends on.
Rym: are you getting a lot?
Rym: is your business?
Scott: What if you had spent the money building the roller coaster?
Scott: I just more advertising instead, right?
Scott: Or just you already bought the advertising.
Scott: don't build the roller coaster.
Scott: You're gonna get the same number of visitors advertising the roller coaster You've already got.
Rym: I feel like what you're.
Rym: that philosophy you're talking about is how most amusement parks are run.
Rym: Hmm because they don't change that often I feel like the ones that do something different.
Rym: have some other business model around like Get like to having a region where you're trying to make sure that you have regulars who come every year forever like get people hooked.
Scott: I can understand.
Scott: if you know Disney has regulars like.
Scott: I understand having the biggest or the most or Changing significantly can help you.
Scott: if you're pulling international traffic, right?
Scott: It goes like or long-distance traffic Disney World.
Scott: you go to Disney World.
Scott: All right, and it's like, okay, you got this family.
Scott: They come good, right?
Scott: We need that.
Scott: we want them to go to Disney World on vacation more years, right every year if possible if they're from far away.
Scott: But are they gonna come back to Disney World if it's the same exact thing as last year?
Scott: if they're not Disney nuts?
Scott: probably not and that's why you would update because you're whole you got to pull someone from far away and give them a reason to Make it worth coming because there's something crazy new.
Scott: but if it's just hey, you're in town come here and have a good time.
Scott: Well, you're gonna have a good time with the rides.
Scott: They already got.
Scott: it doesn't need to be a new ride every time.
Rym: I wouldn't go back like most amusement parks.
Rym: I've ever visited in my life.
Rym: I wrote every ride.
Rym: There's literally no reason for me to ever go back to them.
Rym: ever Disney.
Rym: there's only a reason for me to go back When you know, they do a full refresh and there's new Star Wars shit to see.
Scott: I feel like there's still a reason to go.
Scott: You know, the ride is fun.
Scott: more than a few times, especially if you haven't written It's like new again.
Rym: Yeah I think that I guess it's partly I just got room.
Rym: I see your point like The crappiest roller coasters there are better than some of the best roller coasters at most places.
Rym: So I just like like.
Rym: I went to Canada Wonderland once and I wrote every coaster and they're all bullshit.
Rym: I was like, well never coming back here Even though those roller coasters were fine by like a six flag standard.
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: I was a. I was an amusement park hobbyist Primarily around roller coasters as a kid and the only reason I didn't keep that up as a hobby Is that it's not a very active hobby.
Rym: It's not like I can build roller coasters Can't?
Scott: you'll build them in the backyard all time.
Rym: Yeah, I live in New York where I can build it my living room.
Scott: I guess you don't have to live in New York.
Rym: Yeah, I do Though something that's kind of I've always been even as a kid like I remember being really Disgusted like like actually disgusted by most of the other people who were at the amusement parks.
Rym: that weren't me and my friends Mmm, because as a kid, I remember a lot of the people in the park weren't there to ride roller coasters and Were incapable of moving quickly and we're often in my way on scooters
Scott: when someone is Touristing or and going to amusement park.
Scott: that is like when they are at their worst.
Rym: Yeah, like they're already slow cuz you're all slow.
Rym: Most people are slow, right?
Rym: But now they're like they're going slow on purpose, but they're going slow.
Scott: relative People are waiting in lines in the heat bothered by kids.
Scott: You know Way too much of that terrible food Carrying around a bunch of heavy crab that they don't need right, you know.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's the kind of things people are doing when they're, you know, touristy amusement park.
Scott: And if you're just you know Trying to efficiently ride rides those vast majority people are gonna be in your way Yep, and I remember people getting particularly testy in lines.
Scott: It's it's hot out Yeah, and none of them would talk like standing around doing nothing.
Rym: I remember standing in a line to ride a new roller coaster to Cedar Point with a bunch of high school friends.
Rym: We were in line for a little over three hours Which we didn't care cuz we can go anytime we want a couple hour drive But no one in the line was talking.
Rym: They were just standing there in the heat being surly and we were talking and being loud and we're the only people.
Rym: so it was hundreds and hundreds of thousands of people silent and also being loud and I remember this one mother was just like staring at us and staring at us and then eventually she just yells shut up and everyone got silent and Then we just kept being loud again.
Rym: cuz what's she gonna do?
Rym: and that story doesn't go anywhere.
Rym: It's not like she could get through the turnstile to get to us.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: It's not like there's a rule against talking.
Rym: Mmm It really.
Rym: it really hits stark though like it really bothered me recently when we were at Disney World because I feel like a full third of the people there were Had lived such sedentary lives that they could not Walk the distances required to even experience Epcot.
Rym: and we're using mobility scooters even then even though in their normal lives, they are mobile and walk.
Rym: I Think literally one in three people in that park were in mobility scooters.
Scott: a lot of people don't walk Yeah in their daily lives.
Scott: They sit in a house.
Scott: They take a car to go anywhere.
Rym: Parking lot for the closest parking spot.
Rym: minimize walking, right?
Scott: People don't walk very much at all If they live a suburban lifestyle and suburban kind of people.
Scott: the kind of people go to use and park Yeah, and amusement park requires lots of walking, you know if you want to get from here to there.
Scott: Yeah, even if there's monorails and little cars and tram cars and things like that.
Scott: You still got to walk a whole bunch.
Scott: There's nothing you can do about it.
Rym: Oh I'm probably going to see your point.
Rym: this summer chase wants to go so it might be like me Emily chase.
Scott: Sure, you don't want to go.
Scott: It's too much of a pain in the ass One weekend.
Rym: take one day off.
Scott: We're in a weird-ass place.
Scott: It was a convenient place to go to Right near a major city where you could fly there direct or it was cheap.
Rym: And but it's it's a couple hours from Detroit.
Scott: You can fly there So you gotta fly Detroit and then you got to get two hours away from Detroit.
Scott: Yeah, how do you do that?
Scott: It's not like a train Rent a car renting a car.
Rym: Okay, great Renting cars outside of New York like in New York, like it's a hundred plus dollars a day to rent a car.
Rym: But like outside of New York, I've rented cars for like eight dollars a day.
Scott: I'm just saying it's not a convenient trip where it's just nice and easy right place to Sandusky, Ohio $87.
Scott: I'm just saying we could.
Rym: it's a what what.
Rym: what are you gonna do in a weekend?
Scott: Enjoy, New York a much better place.
Rym: I'm in New York every day.
Rym: I enjoy it.
Scott: every weekend has a reason for that.
Rym: so I can go enjoy a different place Pretty easily.
Rym: two cheap flights.
Scott: I'm good.
Rym: Stay in the hotel breakers a fancy old hotel No ride.
Rym: some of the best roller coasters in the world.
Scott: I'm good.
Rym: Yeah, you say you're good.
Rym: I remember we were both and when we were in Wildwood We paid that $14 each which felt like way too much money was to ride that roller coaster once and it's a tiny crappy roller coaster.
Rym: We were both pretty cynical and down on it and then while we rode it we were both hands in the air.
Scott: Whoo Yeah, roller coaster is fun But it's not so.
Scott: it's not so fun and so amazing that I'm gonna fly somewhere and my weekend just
Rym: I'm willing to pay one weekend and a few hundred dollars to spare to ride like 50 roller coasters
Scott: that are
Rym: all at least four times better than that roller coaster
Scott: and think I'm good.
Rym: It's a density of experience is what I want.
Scott: So you go to Disney and you're like cramming Weekend and a few hundred dollars I can do better.
Scott: Just go to the beach.
Rym: Well, I can go to Sandy Hook anytime.
Rym: I want those I go to a lot of I could go to like a tropical beach.
Rym: You want to go to a tropical beach?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, let's go that we could go to.
Scott: it's real easy to go.
Rym: It'll be about the same level of hassle.
Scott: No, because we can get a plane directly to the tropical beach with no car renting at the other end Hotel immediately touching that Beach.
Rym: the hotel that I stay out of Cedar Point is in Cedar Point.
Rym: I'm just saying it's like going to Disney.
Rym: you stay like in.
Scott: it'll be a beautiful private beach belonging to the hotel.
Scott: The water will be.
Rym: no actually dinner point has beaches on Lake Erie.
Rym: Yeah, it's not tropical No, but it well, it's it's warm in a few tropical because that Beach is mad shallow and mad polluted.
Rym: I Think we're done here.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays Night's is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce, how do you mean nickel Amanda to shed and Thomas?
Rym: Han my city calm Willie vice rose Jeremy minor.
Rym: These aren't the droids you're looking for.
Rym: a genuine bonafide electrified six-car monorail Rebecca Dunn the terrible secret of space 421 creations.
Rym: No, you sure?
Rym: Yeah, Shervin von Horrell rarely.
Rym: Val James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona Superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make Rym say pickle Sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don slight cuz you're our top vision.
Rym: Joe Shiro Joe stars Shawn Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin USA.
Rym: Okay, Brian Cedroni someone who finally delivered their master's thesis.
Rym: Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer who fucking declared war on me In that sieve game.
Rym: and I'm gonna tell you son.
Rym: Hell is coming for you and Thomas on.
Rym: So yeah in the in the big sieve game, I'm playing for a while.
Rym: Literally the entire world is declared war on me including Egypt with its tiny army.
Rym: Ah I'm coming I'm coming.
Rym: I got artillery.
Rym: None of you fools have artillery.
Rym: I'm coming and now I leave you with a Show Ah.