Rym: It's Tuesday June 6 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym mouse got and this is GeekNights tonight talking about game controllers and game pads input devices for games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So as you guys know GeekNights was delayed a little bit, but Many of you probably Wario day.
Scott: Yeah, and then you were sick.
Scott: Yeah, I was so and then you went away.
Rym: Yep, so my grandfather died, which you may have seen if I posted in the forum.
Scott: my grandparents left.
Rym: That was my last mate like direct grandparent.
Scott: I'm also down to one.
Rym: Yep, and So we thought he lived to be 88 Found out he wasn't 80.
Scott: He was 87.
Rym: He was he was actually 87. and the other thing is I'll take it turns out no one in the family knew his middle name and Like everyone knew everyone knew him is eight like Jim James H, right?
Rym: There was a substantial debate.
Scott: isn't there a birth certificate?
Rym: So this is what happened at the funeral someone like there's middle name and someone else was like no
Scott: no, that's
Rym: not his middle name and there was a debate and no one actually knew what his middle name was and The birth certificate just said H
Scott: Mysteries and I guess this is a bad joke because he had Alzheimer's but you guys you couldn't ask him either Even when he was
Rym: alive, right?
Rym: Yeah But no condolences.
Rym: like.
Rym: the reason I'd probably seem pretty upbeat about all this is that the dude lived like an amazing Like pretty awesome life.
Scott: I'm not crying for anyone who dies 87 of an illness.
Rym: Yeah, especially is normal especially when he was happy like I Went to see him last year.
Rym: actually when does Arizona and despite the pretty advanced Alzheimer's like he was living with my mom in the Desert.
Rym: he was going out into the desert Working every day like clearing brush and taking care of the horses and
Scott: he
Rym: basically knew he had Alzheimer's And had lived such a full life that he was content with it and basically just living every day waiting to eventually Pass out in his sleep and he died peacefully in his sleep.
Rym: And that was the end of that.
Scott: I'll take it.
Rym: Yeah so, uh, it's it's funny, I guess it's fun to go to a funeral where everyone's sort of upbeat and just Remembering because it's not like this death with a shock and I'm kind of lucky that no one's really died early anywhere in my family.
Rym: That's affected me directly.
Rym: So all my funerals have mostly been quiet remembrances, but no more grandparents.
Rym: Mm-hmm Meaning, uh, let's get morbid.
Rym: It's gonna be parents time someday.
Rym: That's the next round.
Rym: But independent of that right after I found out I immediately got a stomach flu So I almost couldn't even go to the funeral.
Rym: grandpa's ghost.
Rym: Yeah, it was grandpa's ghost.
Scott: He's like which one of my grandchildren did.
Scott: I hate the most That annoying ass Rym.
Scott: I remember now Let me go haunt that asshole.
Rym: He he did believe in ghosts.
Rym: he also Saw a guy get shot and helped cover it up when he was young because the relatives on that side of the family were fucking mafia bootleggers Mm-hmm.
Rym: He lived an interesting life.
Scott: I'm only believing half of this cuz it's coming out of your mouth.
Rym: Uh, you want to talk to my mom.
Rym: She'll corroborate a lot of these stories Apple.
Scott: Don't fall far from the tree.
Rym: My mom though does also believe in ghosts.
Rym: So watch out.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I think most of my family believes in ghosts.
Scott: Mm-hmm You did too.
Rym: Yeah when I was a kid, of course, I did.
Scott: you believed in ghosts as recently as college?
Rym: I don't believe in ghosts and possibly more nonsense then but I did not believe in ghosts.
Scott: You definitely believed in ghosts.
Scott: you in fact told.
Scott: you in fact told ghosts as if it was true to a room full of people Multiple occasions.
Rym: dude, when you tell a ghost story, you gotta act like it's true.
Scott: It was a not.
Scott: This was not a Halloween ghost story situation.
Scott: This was I really believe in ghosts.
Rym: We were walking around the cemetery in downtown Rochester.
Scott: No, cuz that's you're just hanging out in the apartment and you were like no I totally lived in a haunted house when I was young.
Rym: I'll tell though you all tell all the stories on the patreon.
Scott: then there were there bees and my brother or something.
Rym: No, that was.
Rym: that was not the house that as a kid I thought was haunted.
Rym: the bees of my brother was just literally bees attacked him in his bedroom in New Baltimore.
Rym: Anyway, we had separate bedrooms, right?
Rym: We got separate bedroom plan.
Scott: is you believed one of the houses you lived in?
Rym: One?
Scott: I want you believe that when you were old.
Rym: I watched on solve mysteries.
Rym: If you watch that show as a kid, you'll believe in ghosts.
Scott: You'll think that the Mafia is literally coming to kill you Even aliens because Everywhere I did believe in aliens because of those shows.
Rym: Oh my god, maybe high school times This will be my thing of the day on Thursday, but I'll tell you now.
Rym: So I found a wiki and you know what it is every unsolved mystery whether or not they were solved.
Rym: since In detail and I went read some of them and this is like I like.
Rym: this is all legit.
Rym: Some of them the answers were real crazy and fucked up, too.
Scott: How do you know that's true?
Scott: and not just someone named Rym was writing.
Rym: all because the ones that have answers are all like.
Rym: This person was arrested in 2011 and it was tried take trace back to the crime and then like bunch of newspapers What about America's most wanted?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I only did the unsolved mysteries one.
Rym: But uh, yeah, so we're back.
Rym: We're doing GeekNights.
Rym: We're alive.
Rym: Someone just said one time.
Rym: I saw a ghost.
Rym: You Got any news is that Chris?
Rym: it was not Chris.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah, so the elves team You know the center of all gaming in the universe.
Scott: They've had this thing called greenlight for a while.
Scott: Now if you're not aware the way greenlight works is you you're making a game, but you're not a real publisher.
Scott: You're just some people making a game some Indies or even smaller than Indy one person chopped or whatever.
Scott: Maybe you're a big deal.
Scott: Maybe you're like kick-starting a game who knows but the point is you're making a game and you're not like Activision or some big-ass company.
Scott: they can get your game just on steam, you know guaranteed.
Scott: So, how do you get your game on steam if steam just let all the games on there?
Scott: It would just be a madhouse.
Rym: It's already a thousand games that literally are just malware.
Scott: It's already a madhouse as it is right and it's too much work for them to manually check every single goddamn submission.
Scott: You know cuz that basically be like you could.
Scott: basically their competitors could put them out of business by pumping in submissions To force them to pay to review them all.
Rym: that's what uber was literally like.
Rym: they were doing stuff like that to lift Yep but anyway.
Scott: so the what they did is they have steam greenlight and the way it worked is you would put your game up on greenlight for Nothing, and then you needed to get actual steam users to steam accounts, which are relatively difficult to fake, right?
Scott: And Have them vote for your game.
Scott: And once you got enough votes steam would be like, ah This game has some sort of community support behind it that is large enough to meet our threshold.
Scott: Therefore we're going to evaluate it and see if this is good enough for real steam and that's how you would get your games on Steam.
Rym: Yep, cuz you could you might say why don't they just like manually curate everything?
Rym: That is way too much work.
Rym: At least one automation pass.
Scott: Yeah, I think I think you also had to pay like a hundred dollar fee or something.
Scott: Yeah, maybe but whatever the point is it was an okay system, but it had some problems right.
Scott: So they now have a new system.
Scott: greenlight I think is as of today maybe is done and they have a new.
Scott: what system called steam direct and Steam direct seems to me at least a much better system.
Scott: Even if some people don't like it.
Scott: I think that oh well too bad, right as it's you know, I come thinking about it from Valves perspective and also the gamers Perspective.
Scott: I think the new system is better based on the words that have been used to describe.
Rym: I think I agree, but I withhold my final judgment until I read a lot more details I mean from the indie developer perspective.
Scott: I think it may be bad Yeah, but I can't do anything about that and I don't really care about you.
Rym: The indie developer situation is rough as it is like it's a hustle even without you're competing with so many people, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, whatever.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: So the way the new system works is you put your game in there and you pay a hundred dollars and fill out some forms.
Scott: Right, if you've never put a game on Steam before Right, they're gonna check you out to make sure you're legit for 30 days, right?
Scott: They got.
Scott: they're gonna take 30 days to make sure that you aren't just some bullshit person trying to put up some garbage.
Scott: Oh on Steam, right if they say, okay, this person's not garbage.
Scott: Oh then Alright, you paid the hundred bucks your games on Steam.
Scott: Congratulations, right if you've submitted games before you just got to pay the hundred bucks and whatever.
Scott: right.
Scott: also Once you know, they find out that you are legit any games you submit and pay $100 for they're gonna review them by hand To make sure they're not malware to make sure they are what they say they are and aren't like, you know Happy ABCs after you go through the main menu is Yeah, they make sure it's actually what you say.
Rym: it is which the game is actually just a pirated movie that plays.
Scott: I think that could be problematic.
Scott: For example the game that had fraud fractions to in it, right?
Scott: You know, it's like what if my game is like hidden inside another game is like are they gonna really play the whole goddamn thing?
Scott: To make there's no way they will.
Scott: you Think they're gonna need some sort of tools to like scan all the files in the game to find like all the data That's you know, all the images and sound.
Rym: They're gonna do a like minimal effort there.
Scott: Yeah But I mean at least they're checking is not malware and that actually runs doesn't crash cuz it's not malware.
Rym: is there been a lot Important?
Scott: there been a lot of problems, you know buy a game on Steam and it just crashes right away Like this bullshit and it caught and then it cost steam.
Scott: You know money in the.
Scott: they have their auto refund thing now, which takes care of that.
Scott: But if anyone has to go to customer service, that's a problem, right?
Scott: It cost them money.
Scott: So anyway, once your game Brings in a thousand dollars in sales.
Scott: They give you your hundred dollars back.
Scott: So it's like if your game doesn't really sell it's like well, why did you put?
Scott: why did you bother us with this hundred?
Scott: You know putting your game on Steam tiny ass game, you know All your game did was sell less than a thousand dollars worth, right?
Scott: We're keeping your hundred bucks as a fee Penalty to punish you for wasting our time, but putting this, you know unpopular thing on here.
Scott: But once your game gets over a thousand they give you the hundred dollars back.
Scott: So even if you know a long time goes by and your game eventually gets popular like gets discovered or something You'll get hundred dollars back.
Scott: So it's like you can you know, whatever?
Scott: and I think there's a good system.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there's always.
Scott: you don't like the system.
Scott: you don't need to have your game on Steam.
Scott: Yeah, it'll be hard to sell because you won't get the marketing of being like on the Steam.
Scott: You know page where people can buy it easily.
Scott: But you know people like just distribute stuff on your own.
Scott: you make a website You have a buy button on the website.
Scott: Yeah, I'll give you money directly.
Scott: steam will not take a cut But you get a hundred percent of the money.
Rym: and Scott that's hard to do in a pain in the ass.
Rym: Yeah, maybe that's why people pay steam a hundred bucks.
Scott: Yeah, also It's actually not that much of a pain in the ass.
Scott: It's a way easy to do.
Rym: Well, you see you say that but this is like an out-of-the-box thing.
Rym: you and I are both ITCs professionals who do that.
Scott: if you can make a video game you can make a website.
Scott: if you can't make a video game if you don't have the skills to make a website and Somehow you make a video game I can see that I can't imagine that your video game is good enough to be worth playing.
Scott: I could see that happen as a piece of software.
Scott: It would have.
Scott: it's probably garbage.
Scott: If you're incapable of making a setting up a website now I guess I'm assuming that you're gonna pay services that manage all that.
Rym: for you Cuz it'll be like trying to run for a mile by your arm.
Scott: I did one for much less than the hundred dollar cost of the steam.
Scott: You can set up without having to code anything a website that will sell digital goods.
Rym: I mean ever.
Rym: there's always been a complicated Discourse around steam because valve basically stopped being a game company and is just a platform.
Rym: I don't think they'll ever make games again.
Scott: Make dota.
Rym: Yeah, what do they made sense?
Scott: They're still making dota.
Scott: It's a not any.
Scott: it's a non ending game.
Scott: Yeah, well, they'll make counter-strike.
Rym: I'm pretty confident There will never be a half-life.
Rym: 3.
Scott: Yeah, probably but they keep patching the games They got and they're doing a bunch of VR shit - yep.
Scott: Actually, there's a bunch of big New things coming - well the VR but the VR people left, but I think they're still doing stuff.
Rym: There's a bunch of stuff coming to counter-strike that basically adds the kinds of features that overwatch started with which is interesting Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think they're feeling a little bit of hurt from overwatch in the competitive circuit, but those games aren't alike at all.
Scott: They're not.
Rym: but I see more and more people in like the competitive overwatch set just like the randos who?
Rym: Mentioned say things like they used to play counter-strike, but they got bored with it.
Scott: Well, you playing the goddamn thing for 17 years.
Rym: Yeah I haven't played how to strike.
Scott: the same I made.
Scott: saying you're bored of counter-strike after 17 goddamn years is like saying counter-strike is the greatest game Which is close to true.
Rym: I mean how long a run to tribes to head before you literally couldn't play it anymore like games.
Rym: Yeah, eight months games don't last long someone.
Rym: I saw an article the other day.
Rym: They pointed out that the fact that overwatch and it's year one anniversary is more popular than when the launch is already pretty crazy.
Rym: Yeah, absolutely.
Rym: I mean hearthstone fucking is like four or three four years old that So, uh, I mean in some other news that battle tech game that I still got to go.
Rym: See if I actually backed or not.
Scott: I kick-started it and the beta is now out and they let me have the beta and I haven't played it yet But I installed it.
Scott: so I'm gonna stream it once I get home from this podcast and eat dinner.
Rym: So you should in a few hours go look at Scott's YouTube channel Which I'll link to instead of listening to this as an mp3.
Scott: You can't see that but you can go to my youtube and see it already uploaded like as a you know video.
Scott: You just won't see it live.
Rym: and if you go to the GeekNights website www.frontrowcrew.com or just type GeekNights into Google.
Rym: I swear it'll get you there.
Rym: You'll see a link to it because apparently no one ever does that or sees our website.
Rym: I don't know That seems to be able to.
Rym: our fan bases seem to be weirdly Separated trying to bring them all together and then I guess they'll fight or something.
Rym: But I'm excited about this game, but I don't know yet.
Rym: Like I don't know if it'll be great.
Rym: It might be terrible.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: what I've seen right is so I met these people at you know packs and such.
Rym: Oh, they said the right words.
Scott: They said all the right words and then I saw the game in person.
Scott: It was at PAX Prime.
Scott: I saw the game running in an alpha and I was like, wow That looks like they actually fucking made a game and they weren't bullshit.
Scott: and that looks like fucking battle tech to me.
Rym: Yeah, look at that.
Scott: Ooh a missile fired a laser shot a heat save you see PPC.
Scott: a mech moved around on some hexes and then shot another Mac and he went.
Rym: boom I Haven't seen yet.
Rym: is a Mac that only has front armor two gauss rifles and targeting computer with its back against the mountain never moving?
Scott: You know what?
Scott: You're gonna see tonight.
Scott: We'll see what they have.
Scott: How much is in the beta?
Scott: It's still beta.
Rym: So some other news, uh, if you didn't notice PAX West slash prime.
Scott: Yeah, the real packs a one true pack like I.
Rym: we joke about this a lot.
Rym: PAX West is the best possible packs experience from all perspectives.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's just it's way more or goddamn days.
Rym: It's way more chill than East.
Rym: There's infinite food in hotels like all around it.
Rym: in downtown Seattle The weather has been nice almost like 90% of the time we've gone.
Rym: ish 90%.
Rym: it's usually pretty sunny.
Scott: It's been worse in recent years.
Scott: when the earlier years we went it was way good.
Rym: Yeah, it was good last year.
Scott: I remember like the first and second year we went.
Scott: it was like isn't Seattle supposed to be the place?
Rym: Everyone's like this is freakish weather.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Seen it rain though recently.
Rym: Yeah past couple labor days, but if you pay attention Around this time a year as in like this week next week The following week is when PAX West badges go on say PAX West ticket sales are imminent.
Scott: It could even be goddamn tomorrow.
Scott: It could be as we're doing this podcast.
Scott: It's gonna be within a week.
Scott: I would bet real money.
Scott: It would be within my seven days.
Rym: My advice to you is starting around 10 Starting around tomorrow.
Scott: this second as soon as you hear this right you should go and you Wednesday.
Rym: I'll say this Wednesday 10 a.m.
Rym: Is like alert times.
Rym: Yeah, Thursday 10 a.m.
Rym: Is high alert.
Rym: Friday and every single weekday onward is maximum alert.
Rym: Mm-hmm because This shit sells out in like seconds.
Scott: Yeah, so the way to get tickets That's always worked for me every year including last year is on Twitter.
Scott: You can follow the official packs Twitter account.
Rym: Don't ever coup anymore.
Rym: He's not gonna tweet about it He's not you know, the official packs Twitter account.
Scott: you follow it.
Scott: Okay, big deal.
Scott: You're following it on Twitter.
Scott: You can't read Twitter every single second, right?
Scott: But you know if you'd even if you'd like me and check Twitter every 10 minutes, you might miss it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So you got it one time.
Rym: Scott saw it literally two minutes before me and it was sold out.
Rym: You have to buy in that two-minute gap between when Scott clicked and I clicked.
Scott: so what you can do is in Twitter There's an option so that you can get notifications whenever an account tweets.
Scott: So now if official packs Twitter account ever tweets anything your phone will go ding within Seconds.
Scott: right no matter what it's guaranteed to work, right?
Scott: And if you see now this might be annoying because they do tweet things other than tickets are going on sale.
Scott: But and you'll get a mini heart attack like when last week when they tweeted our website is down.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep Yep, but all I thought was what and I like frantically look at my watch to see what the notification was.
Scott: Their website was just down but you know They've got it back up.
Scott: So but it's okay because they do not tweet much.
Scott: most of their tweets are at replies to people tweeting at them with customer service stuff and you will not be notified of those.
Scott: you will only be notified of their tweets to the world which are few in number.
Scott: and as soon as you see that on your Phone or the first internet connected device you have click that link and you'll get tickets if you're fast enough Which is if you do if you touch it when you get the notification You will be fast enough.
Rym: now other packs is like especially PAX East.
Rym: the hotel is way more important than the badge Mm-hmm, but it West.
Rym: while it is slightly annoying to not get one of the like five great hotels Even the faraway hotels are actually surprisingly close to packs like one.
Scott: but the one year we had the faraway hotel was like It really said it was Blair.
Rym: Well, the problem was that that hotel was not only far away But it was far away in the wrong direction for every restaurant.
Rym: We like to eat at And it was far away.
Rym: Like it was like the worst possible waypoint for where tabletop was that year.
Scott: Yes, the northern western hotels are good.
Rym: the south eastern Yeah, that's the best possible hotel is the Sheraton.
Rym: But my advice to you is to not go for it because it's probably already sold out.
Scott: It's also too much money.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it.
Scott: none of them are super cheap, but it's more money.
Rym: but if you go for the Sheraton You'll likely fail and by the time you look at like the Olivette or something.
Rym: It'll be sold out.
Scott: It's a good option.
Scott: There's plenty of good options.
Rym: So be warned be prepared.
Rym: even though we've been a speaker at every single packs with free badges since 2008.
Rym: I'm so paranoid that I buy badges every year because I will not.
Rym: I will and I know.
Scott: I know I can sell them.
Rym: Yeah, I would give them away to a friend.
Rym: I think I'm just gonna buy one this year plus if you have a bunch of friends if you all agree to buy the maximum number Usually only a few of you will get in and you can help your friends go to pass.
Scott: Are you telling me I should buy the maximum instead of one maybe two?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It's always a pain in the ass to sell past and I've bought too many.
Scott: I've had to sell them and it's annoying.
Rym: so there's another secret that you can do But this is this is the money or game dev option.
Rym: I go to PAX dev every year and I've only gotten a free badge.
Rym: by speaking once I kept going because I really like PAX dev.
Rym: and What many people don't know if you buy a badge to pack stuff which ain't cheap it's like 300 plus dollars Ching you have the automatic right to buy a four-day badge to PAX West even if it is sold out.
Rym: You can just buy a badge.
Rym: So actually I could just buy my dev badge now and buy one West badge now.
Rym: I could do this literally today.
Scott: I also get the hotel room.
Rym: I don't know I've never tried that because that's what we need.
Scott: get the hotel room.
Rym: I will try.
Rym: I will see if I can get the hotel room when I booked my PAX dev Tonight and I will let you all know if that works Because that would actually save me a lot of headache if I could get the hotel now.
Rym: so, uh You might have noticed and this is my main news that There's another PAX website PAX unplugged and we're going to it.
Rym: it's gonna be awesome and we've talked about it, but there's yet another PAX website and Most people only stumbled onto this by accident.
Scott: It was in the new gaming news, you don't read gaming news.
Rym: So I saw it in some gaming news But now I found there's a much better article that explains what's going on here on polygon.
Rym: But there's a powered by Pax running on the same infrastructure as although like PAX website stuff because all the paxes have the same back end It's not as sophisticated as you think it is, but it does exist.
Rym: There is a pax or at least a convention that is powered by all the infrastructure of pax in Guangzhou in China in November of this year November 10th, that's like right after pax Australia, I think This is not a normal pax in that as far as I can tell like Dave and Taika are not gonna be there.
Rym: I don't know if it's gonna be in English or in Chinese.
Rym: I assume it'll be in Chinese.
Rym: the fascinating thing about this is that this is a great way I think for them to monetize The infrastructure of running a pax because there is big money in running gaming conventions But - it allows them to do that without diluting the pax brand.
Rym: because if you had more like legit paxes There's only so much gave in taiko.
Rym: There's only so much like US games industry or Australian games industry.
Rym: It would get watered down in a hurry But in most of the world there are very few or no gamer focused gaming conventions.
Rym: Most of them are industry focused or Competitive gaming audience focused But they're not People who play games.
Rym: focus.
Rym: pax and magfest are unique and that they're the rare ones that are like that and the rest of the world Those don't exist.
Rym: So I'm really interested to see how this goes.
Rym: pretty sure those exist.
Rym: games come But there are not that many.
Rym: compared to like comic cons and other kinds of things a lot of the things that people talk about as gaming cons are more industry focused and Less like random Joe gamer on the street focused.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I'm gonna like do an article here.
Rym: You can read about more of the details.
Rym: Kind of want to go just to see what the deal is cuz I'll be in Singapore around that time.
Rym: Anyway need a visa.
Rym: I can get a visa to Guangzhou.
Rym: Guangzhou was pretty easy to get a visa to.
Scott: I know I'm just saying you got to do it.
Rym: It's like getting a visa to I don't know a Shenzhen those areas.
Scott: It's not as easy as getting one to Australia where you click a button and pay 20 bucks.
Rym: Yeah, cuz that's not actually a visa.
Rym: That's an electronic.
Rym: Yeah, I got a passport.
Scott: it has the same function regardless of what name is applied to it, right but I There is a small chance.
Rym: I might just buy a badge and go to this for a day Just to see go for it cuz I like.
Rym: I'm literally gonna be in the area.
Scott: Anyway, it doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't count as a pecs.
Rym: No, it does not because it is powered by packs.
Rym: This is extra interesting too because penny arcade Needs a made like long-term Monetization plan to continue to do the things that it does because frankly gaming conventions make a lot of money But they're also especially packs is?
Rym: there's also a little bit of an industry fueled gravy train and much like the heyday of the anime Industry can't say that might last forever.
Rym: or my Peter out Gotta have backup plans.
Scott: I'm curious what services they actually provide.
Scott: I'm also curious how much they charge Yeah, and I'm curious like how much if it's not called packs it was just powered by packs.
Scott: I'm curious how much that brand helps in the non english-speaking world Where it doesn't seem to have as much value really, but I do get It is really popular in a surprising.
Scott: if these conventions fail while they fail, right?
Scott: Yeah, and if they succeed if I'm if I run.
Scott: was it called GZ play?
Scott: Yeah, if I'm the people running GZ play I'm sure I have some sort of contract with packs that lasts more than one year.
Scott: But if my convention is successful and I learn from packs what I need to learn I'm not renewing that contract and giving them any more money.
Scott: I'm just gonna keep running this GZ play on my own in my experience.
Rym: However, I Find that almost no one is capable of doing that.
Rym: You know of having seen someone I mean look at the conventions that read runs that aren't packs.
Rym: I Mean, I'm just saying that's just saying they're part of.
Scott: that is not because of you know, they're incapable, but they're Managerial decisions that you know might be overridden.
Rym: Well that that is the magic of packs that makes them so unique and why I'm curious how this will go down is that?
Rym: packs and magfest is like one of the few that's like this is so hyper focused on the experience of the average attendee as Company would care about when they run.
Scott: Okay milk more money.
Scott: I know let's sell VIP badges.
Scott: Yeah, make us more money.
Rym: Yeah What do we have?
Rym: a complex bidding process where badges are very expensive and slowly get cheaper to get maximum money out of these?
Scott: Rubes, what if we have some expensive exclusive swag that we give out to people who spend more money?
Rym: What if you have to pay individual money for every game you want to play?
Rym: What if panelists have to pay to get a projector in their panel room?
Rym: And for those of you who only go to PAX is literally all of those things happen routinely at other gaming cons But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So there was a story that no one believed in the 1830s when some pirates Well, some convicts were on their way to the prison camps in Australia Hijacked the ship they were on Mutiny and sailed off for adventure.
Rym: and when they eventually got caught again and were on trial for piracy in London Yeah one they were the last human beings on earth hung by the British crown for piracy Mm-hmm, and two they told a crazy story of getting attacked by samurai.
Rym: and No one believed that.
Scott: but it was true.
Rym: some evidence was uncovered.
Rym: Recently like really recently didn't have cannons headed.
Scott: samurai messed them up.
Rym: Uh So it's really funny the story.
Rym: So basically their story was pretty dumb.
Rym: What year was this?
Rym: 1830?
Scott: You could definitely mess samurai up with cannons in 1830.
Rym: Yeah, so I like these coastal towns in Japan often had like one or two cannons.
Scott: Yeah But they were like basically that orders from couldn't have been as good as the ones on the boat.
Rym: No, no, no that one.
Rym: usually they were stolen from boats or like Foreigners they'd murdered.
Rym: Yeah So the I guess this town had like one raggedy-ass cannonball and they shot it at the barbarian ship And they hit it and they hit it.
Rym: good job.
Rym: And they actually knocked the telescope out of one of the guys hands and hurt him.
Rym: And this like pitted ass lead ball was like on the ship and they kept it as a souvenir.
Scott: There's all this nonsense, but basically I just like went through the hall and landed on the floor.
Scott: I don't even
Rym: went to the hall because the Japanese in that era was
Scott: landed on the deck like
Rym: it landed on the deck like bonk And apparently the samurai were extra fucking pissed off about the fact that when they fired their cannon the pirate ship There's a quote in here, but do but
Scott: do but do.
Rym: No, it didn't even bother.
Rym: It's just very slowly and leisurely raised a sail and just kind of slowly Got out of the water.
Rym: It was no big deal.
Rym: The pirates basically showed up.
Scott: Thanks to the free cannonball.
Rym: Yeah, and we're like, we'll leave soon.
Rym: We just let us like hang out here and like repaint our ship so we can like get away from the British.
Rym: and the samurai Were like, yeah, we have pointy swords.
Scott: We don't get to use them often enough.
Scott: We also really want to fire this cannon.
Scott: That's how I would be if I was that samurai.
Rym: so basically this French scholar like translated.
Rym: they found all these accounts from samurai in the 1830s of An encounter with barbarians and They translated it and they put one in like two and two together and they figured it out that this.
Rym: and then they like they Went and like found the records from London.
Rym: They are really confident that these are the exact pirates that they ran into and the Japanese even drew pictures of what the pirates looked Like.
Rym: oh, they're reasonably accurate.
Rym: The crowd the samurai chronicles are pretty funny.
Rym: one sailor Bared his chest to the disguised samurai to reveal a tattoo of quote the upper body of a beautiful woman.
Rym: Another produced a big glass of what appeared to be an alcoholic beverage and indicated that we should drink.
Rym: We declined by waving our hands upon which they pass the glass around themselves.
Rym: So this is just a fascinating story such excellent gentleman and I don't know.
Rym: it shows that There's a lot of history that we actually have evidence of and just no one bothered doing the research you're putting it together.
Scott: Well, cuz it's not like this isn't world affecting history?
Scott: whether this happened or not doesn't have any you know.
Scott: Remember
Rym: while I read that the same thing happened with the Battle of Midway the turning point of World War two in the Pacific where apparently no one in America ever bothered to actually like Translate and read Japanese accounts of the battle because those Japanese accounts actually proved a whole bunch of stuff about the battle that we were Wrong about.
Scott: but winners write the history.
Rym: Yeah, but we wrote the history dumb and wrong and we win though.
Scott: Yeah It doesn't mean you winners write the history, right?
Scott: You just write it.
Rym: Yep, but a lot of the things we were wrong about like we way overestimated Japanese capabilities during that battle and Japanese primary sources gave a very different picture Mm-hmm.
Rym: So anyway, this is just a funny story that I think you should read.
Rym: All I could think the whole time was Harris and impact.
Scott: Yeah pretty much.
Rym: So I got a thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, so this has been.
Scott: this has been like all over the Internet's and the main the real news of.
Scott: a lot of people have Probably seen this but also a lot of people are nerds who listen to this the kind of nerds who are so sad they'd sit In our chat.
Rym: you call it sports ball and you make fun of it when other people talk about it, right?
Scott: So the New York Metropolitan's?
Scott: they not to do it so good.
Scott: They back to their old ways.
Scott: They were in the World Series just two years ago and they didn't win it Now.
Scott: the back to being el garbage Mets as usual and at a recent technical New York tour for that is bums.
Scott: Yeah, so about a week ago ish if you know They were sucking particularly badly.
Scott: I think it maybe it'd been like Wednesday or Tuesday last week.
Scott: Particular suckage was going on at Citi Field and Some of the fans is nothing better to do because there was nothing to see on the field.
Scott: They were heckling the mascot.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Met heckle heckle.
Rym: No, you never see mr.
Rym: Matt It's a man in a mess.
Scott: It's a beautiful person.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of different people who are in.
Scott: Oh, yeah, we don't even know who's in there.
Rym: It is a person.
Rym: Sir name is mr.
Rym: So I'm assuming that their character is canonically male.
Scott: Yeah, there is a mrs.
Scott: Met.
Rym: there is.
Rym: I've never seen mrs Matt.
Scott: it looks like mr.
Scott: Matt with ponytail cuz.
Rym: I guess there's not a lot of sexual dimorphism in baseballs.
Rym: No, because his head is just a baseball with a mess hat.
Scott: Yep Any has four fingers, yeah, mrs.
Scott: Matt has boobs and a ponytail.
Rym: They felt the need to like super gender that literal baseball, yeah anyway.
Scott: So they were heckling mr.
Scott: Matt big time and On his way back into the underground of the field from possibly doing like a t-shirt toss or something like that They were giving him a good old heckle while videoing him with their little phone camera.
Scott: And mr.
Scott: Matt, whoever was in there that day wasn't having wasn't having none of it and gave him the finger Which is really funny because a that's a New York thing to do.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Matt should be giving people the finger and be.
Scott: mr Matt only has four fingers.
Rym: So he was just pointing up.
Scott: I guess sure so but I mean he also did you know the old.
Scott: So that so they have told us that that mr Has been relieved of their duties and will no longer be in the costume, but they could just be lying.
Scott: Yeah, it don't matter I hope they are lying.
Scott: I would you know would promote that mr.
Scott: Matt.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I would give that mr.
Rym: Matt a bonus Yeah, and or properly demonstrating to New Yorkers what happens when you heckle mr.
Rym: Matt.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: But anyway, here's the video of mr.
Scott: Matt giving someone the second or third finger.
Rym: You Know it's funny.
Rym: living here long enough Like this isn't some like?
Scott: I just want people to know.
Scott: like the first time I saw this I thought it was like a fan-made thing and not a real thing, you know, cuz like if a car like this is a real thing That's the actual mr Matt.
Rym: like if I'm biking or walking in a car honks at me and I'm not like I'm not jaywalking or anything Like I flip them off as instinct.
Rym: I literally don't even think it just have it's just out the fingers.
Scott: It's subconsciously controlled.
Rym: Yeah, like it's such a such an instinct and it doesn't even feel like anything.
Rym: It's no emotion to it It's just like a hello.
Rym: No wave gentle wave.
Rym: Not only thing today but in the meta moment.
Rym: the booklet book is Frank Herbert's Dune.
Rym: I began in a while ago.
Rym: I'm gonna read it soon.
Rym: I guess you're gonna read it.
Rym: You're gonna read it.
Scott: I guess I'll start reading it.
Rym: I also start reading it but We're so excited about this in some other more interesting.
Scott: I didn't like it the last time.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't finish.
Rym: you might have noticed that I keep uploading all these.
Scott: you do 90 something.
Rym: I got about 109 more of these to upload as I make them but I'm taking literally every tabletop review We've ever done in the middle of a GeekNights episode and splitting them out into their own Separate dedicated YouTube videos.
Rym: that are just the review.
Rym: not all that crap We talked about before the review some of these that we had to have a show.
Rym: we did like five board game reviews.
Rym: So I cut each one out into its own thing and there's a playlist you can click on and just watch all the reviews with none of the crap.
Rym: Mmm, uh, I think this is a decent thing to do and I planted this more GeekNights things in the future.
Rym: I got a nice pipeline going on, but I don't know like and subscribe.
Scott: I'm doing lots of video action in terms of like.
Scott: I can now stream from my phone Immediately with the YouTube app because I have a thousand subscribers.
Scott: Yep I did it during your brother's wedding a live stream your toast because it was a good toast great And then I'm using that feature whenever I feel like it And I'm streaming more stuff from my house mostly video games because that's easier to do.
Scott: But I have the technology and equipment to stream pretty much anything in my apartment whatsoever Not just video game, but anything happening in real life.
Scott: so Give me ideas and whatnot.
Scott: I've done some cooking.
Scott: I've done some Gundam model building.
Scott: We'll see what else happens.
Scott: Of course It's summer So I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna see if I can do the phone streaming while biking and see what happens.
Rym: that could be interesting.
Scott: I don't know if it's gonna work with the internet quality Changing as I bike around.
Rym: Yeah Cuz it was.
Rym: the internet quality was pretty dodgy in that wedding venue too and the stream did not come out.
Rym: super great quality wise.
Scott: So I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna attempt it though.
Scott: Maybe the next warmer weekend.
Scott: Maybe even this a weekend.
Scott: Ah, look for there's gonna be some exciting things happening in the city this weekend.
Rym: I mean like so Brooklyn pride is that weekend and Emily and I were running in the 5k race in Prospect Park during it.
Scott: I was maybe gonna bike down there.
Rym: You should bike down and that but Phil is running in the race with us, too.
Scott: Well, Phil's gonna finish the race probably in half the time.
Scott: It takes you to finish it.
Rym: So it'll be interesting though because while Phil is super athletic He does not run long distances all the time.
Scott: Like I do but it's only 5k is it's not long distance.
Rym: It's considered long distance running now, but uh while I'd normally train Like like six or seven five K's in a marathon Yeah, marathons like 26 miles.
Rym: I don't run marathons because that's super bad for you.
Rym: I run half marathons regularly, but I'm also old and like 35 is younger than you.
Scott: Yeah, 35 ain't 31 guys It's 39 ain't 29.
Rym: Yep, but I'm 35 and I think my peak like the best times I ever got running these races was like 28 through 31 and then it's gonna be.
Rym: I'm lucky to even like make those half hour to run five K's.
Scott: What?
Rym: No, I've got 20 minutes.
Rym: Okay, no my dad I usually place in the top three of my age group and as I get into older age groups I feel like I'll do better and better.
Rym: I think I'm aging better than a lot of the people I see But me the last time I remember Emily got screwed because she was the oldest.
Rym: she was the oldest person in her age group and she was like one place away from like placing like in the top and The times for the people in the age group one step above here were way slower.
Rym: She would in first place in that age group.
Rym: So the next year she was in that age group and all these super freakin fast people were in that age group And she would have been first place in the younger age group.
Rym: So who runs the race?
Scott: Yep There's always like 20. that's how it is the net writer tournament.
Rym: I won when the good people didn't show up Yep, and then the super good people they're all like 19 to 22 years old and they beat me by like five minutes.
Rym: They started the front.
Rym: they they beat.
Rym: they finished the thing in like 18 minutes 17 minutes.
Scott: So you catch them?
Rym: So the last try real hard.
Rym: the last time I said the best time I ever got I did it because I ran real hard and I ran over the finish line and Immediately just vomited in some bushes.
Scott: Well, I'm pretty sure the prison who finished in 18 minutes also vomited in.
Rym: They're just younger and fitter than me I think is the problem.
Scott: I'll run the race.
Scott: I'm a bike.
Scott: I'll finish in 18 minutes.
Scott: In fact, I'll give you a 10-minute handicap.
Rym: You give me a 10-minute handicap.
Scott: I might be able to do okay 5k on a closed course on my bike trying to go fast.
Scott: No, I could probably go close to 20 miles an hour.
Rym: Yeah, it's Prospect Park too.
Rym: So it's like easy.
Scott: Yeah, 20 miles an hour.
Scott: How long will it take to go?
Scott: five K's not long Five minutes.
Rym: I couldn't find a show where we specifically talked about this.
Rym: I think we've talked.
Rym: I think we might have talked once about like first party and why you should always get first party stuff But like I couldn't find shows on like just game controllers.
Scott: Seems weird, but I know well, it's such a broad topic.
Scott: I don't even know what you think we're gonna talk about.
Rym: I search like gamepad and everything.
Scott: Why don't we are?
Scott: here's how we should live.
Scott: there's many ways we could limit this right?
Scott: Let's talk about specific Game controllers ones that exist and review them in the if you the pre-analog era The super NES controller.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: historically is to this day I think the best console or console game or generic game pad the world has ever seen.
Rym: but again pre analog.
Rym: Maybe anyway name a better pre analog controller.
Scott: Oh pre analog.
Rym: Yeah Cuz the NES controller doesn't have enough buttons.
Scott: Yeah, no, it's too small.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Anyway, but yeah.
Scott: So let's just start at the beginning right with the arcade.
Scott: right people don't know.
Scott: Right arcade sticks are not all the same.
Scott: in Japan They have a square gate and in the US they have the sort of gate That's like the gate is the thing that controls the range of motion of the stick.
Rym: All right, if you go get before that there wasn't even standards.
Rym: and like what is a control?
Rym: like the idea of a stick with?
Rym: Directions wasn't like people.
Scott: Yeah asteroids has buttons only it doesn't have a stick.
Scott: Yeah Some games have a ball.
Rym: There was like no standard like you'd see crazy buttons all over the place on different arcade games Took a long time.
Rym: like it really wasn't until home consoles that controllers standardized Because you needed one controller to run multiple games.
Scott: There weren't even game pads until the NES slash Famicom.
Scott: before then it was like joysticks or you know Things with a bunch of buttons on them.
Rym: Yeah, look at like a little tiny joy stick.
Scott: Some things had a big joystick.
Scott: you gripped it your whole hand.
Rym: Look at Atari game controllers you had With a button on it.
Rym: the Intellivision was a number pad and a flat disc.
Rym: you could like shove down.
Rym: That actually had like like.
Rym: it was almost like a. I don't ever seen anything like it.
Scott: Yeah No, I think maybe the NES max was somewhat similar to the disc.
Rym: Yeah, maybe.
Scott: but anyway all of those things that came before the NES gamepad were except for arcade normal Arcade stick and buttons was good because arcade stick and buttons The controls is still good today.
Rym: but you made a game.
Rym: the controls were literally part of the game.
Rym: as soon as you had a console you had to have one Controller or a set of controllers for all possible games.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: So the really the Famicom controller for the NES the original one a B select start up down left Right.
Scott: the pad was the invention of the d-pad, which is still necessary today.
Rym: Yeah, and It is terrific controller, but all third-party ones garbage in my yeah, I remember as a kid it was a very like specific differentiator of It's sad to say this but like socio-economic class in that.
Scott: and this applies also to other third-party controllers for all systems.
Rym: up until today even middle-class kids in my neighborhood all had like just first-party standard controllers.
Rym: the Yuppie kids all had the weird like Nintendo controllers.
Rym: I know.
Scott: I noticed that even kids who had you know were affluent they would still only have enough You know main game pads for themselves, right?
Scott: No, and they would just buy.
Scott: they get the cheapo madcads garbage controllers, you know for anyone who might be visiting.
Scott: But they never use those.
Rym: most of those kids in my experience They always had the special controllers that turbo buttons and nonsense on them.
Rym: to cheat.
Rym: some people did that They'd make me use the first-party regular old controller that didn't have the turbos.
Scott: there were First party controllers that had nonsense.
Scott: is the NES advantage.
Rym: Yeah, which all the yuppie kids had which sucks, by the way It's it's garbage.
Scott: I there's the NES max which I had which not so great, but it was okay.
Scott: It wasn't as bad as it is now.
Scott: You don't want it.
Scott: All right, but it's a thing.
Scott: I think there was also one that was just the same exact thing as the regular controller But just had two turbos added to it, but that might have been third party or first party.
Rym: I remember yup But yeah, but actually in that era all the other consoles that were contemporary the controllers are pretty garbage.
Scott: Yeah, no any all the other consoles that tried to compete with the NES even the ones that copied game pads from them Like I think there were game pads for.
Scott: like Commodore 64, maybe Turbografx-16 had a gamepad and it was a gamepad.
Scott: It wasn't awful, but it wasn't even as good as the NES one that came before it.
Scott: Yeah, it was worse than it.
Scott: It's like what you do now.
Rym: I don't know how you all feel about this.
Rym: The Sega Genesis controller would have been Marginally acceptable if it weren't for the fact that it was contemporary to the SNES controller.
Rym: the god of controllers.
Scott: Yeah, the Genesis controller the first one, right?
Scott: Had three buttons ABC.
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: Start button good.
Scott: The main problem with the original Genesis controller.
Scott: Is this too big?
Scott: Yeah, it was a monster and there's people today are like so many people not just with controllers with phones and stuff.
Scott: They're like, oh my god, my hands are too big.
Scott: My hands are too small.
Scott: I can't grip.
Scott: Oh, it's - you know It's like.
Scott: no these things are made one size fits all.
Scott: they're pretty much one size fits all.
Scott: if you have a problem It's not a problem with the size of your - barring of course accessibility concerns - unless you are not Andre the Giant You are not Shaquille O'Neal, right?
Scott: You are not Tom Thumb.
Scott: Your hand is the right size for pretty much any normal controller.
Rym: In my experience most people who don't have like a disability or a reason why they can't use a normal controller Their problems stem from the fact that they held the controllers wrong.
Rym: Yep, they use them wrong.
Rym: They gripped him in like crazy death grips.
Rym: I just I saw.
Scott: I saw people.
Rym: I saw kids would hold their NES controllers like from the bottom only.
Scott: like recently I've seen people who are not proficient with controller, right?
Scott: They'd have their left.
Scott: You know left thumb on the left analog and right thumb on the buttons and then to use the right analog They were bringing over the left thumb to the right analog and back.
Rym: That's like watching a top touch type is always going for left shift because they don't really know that the right ones there.
Scott: I know that.
Scott: that's.
Scott: the one thing I do wrong when typing is I never push right shift.
Scott: I think my right shift button that might have zero actuations.
Scott: I Type it.
Scott: Otherwise, I type correctly except for that.
Rym: Anyway, I don't use right shift often, but I do use it.
Scott: Yeah, I guess we should talk about keyboard at some point, but I think just talk about handheld controllers only controllers.
Rym: Okay, that constrains this cuz.
Rym: otherwise we're talking about yolks and all sorts of shit wheels.
Scott: Yeah, you forced to see what game pads only then right?
Scott: So we did talk about joysticks.
Rym: a little bit though as a kid I remember to like a lot of my friends like Kind of how like you'd have kids who would play games to win and kids who like didn't seem to understand the point of games.
Rym: It would just like play him forever.
Scott: play just play it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Play just play it.
Rym: A lot of my friends who played games just play him.
Rym: Like I'd watch them hold controllers in such a wrong way that it Viscerally bothered me as a kid and people wouldn't have the muscle memory and have to look at the controller.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep No this day.
Rym: I know despite the fact that X has been in literally every possible position It could be.
Rym: I know where it is.
Rym: I know where it should be.
Scott: The only time I get messed up is PlayStation controller with triangles squares circle.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I never played PlayStation games.
Rym: The only PlayStation ever owned was an RIT and that was just to play DDR.
Rym: Yeah, we never played any game but DDR in that thing.
Scott: Yep I didn't play.
Scott: I just haven't played enough PlayStation to get it burned into my brain and I don't really think I'm gonna know which Wasn't a problem until we were ever wanted to play Soul Calibur 2 or 3 at anyone else's house.
Scott: Yeah or at the main time it hurt me is playing games that were rhythm II such as that bust a move or bust a Dancing.
Scott: they've driven a lot of trouble with a ribbon and the Naruto game because the nose Naruto Smash Brothers game on ps2 I think and it would pop up shit on the screen and you'd have to be like Circle circle X triangle.
Scott: you have to type in a move or something.
Rym: Patrick points out.
Rym: I knew people who played Atari 26 controllers upside down.
Rym: That's actually a pro move Mmm, that controller hold it.
Scott: It doesn't matter which way you hold it.
Rym: Yeah The classic position of cupping it in one hand holding in the other super inferior pro mode was you put it on a table Sideways and you just like hold on to that thing like this.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: But game pads were different cuz they're designed to be held in your hands, I think the n64 controller was revolutionary but I also hated it and that was like that spawned this era of these gigantic ass controllers that were like Fitted for your whole hand to like just fit in there to ensure that no one would hold it the wrong way.
Scott: Well, the n64 controller basically had two modes right is?
Scott: they were like.
Scott: we need these analog sticks cuz PlayStation 1 already has them.
Scott: But we don't like their sort of dual shock idea going on right we're making the controller for Mario 64 But we're pretty much we don't know.
Scott: Mario 64 was like the first 3d platforming game.
Scott: that was not garbo right or even the first one period.
Scott: so They didn't know like they're like, okay This is the analog stick you need for this.
Scott: But they didn't know that the 3d games are gonna catch on or people are gonna make them or you know anything.
Scott: So the mate, you know.
Scott: So they still put the d-pad and flat buttons on the outside of the controller for regular game mode.
Scott: Right thinking that most games would still be like that not realizing that.
Scott: Oh I guess 99% of the games on this system are just gonna use the analog stick in the middle and that whole left side of the controller Isn't gonna get used too much.
Scott: Yeah, and then instead of putting a second analog stick They had see up see down see left and see right which is basically another d-pad Over there on the right side, which is okay, but not as good as another analog stick
Rym: I think
Scott: is what you really needed for the free look right goal.
Scott: That's the main thing that killed.
Scott: that hurts golden eye and the other is that you didn't have the second analog stick.
Scott: You know, you had to look with those 4c buttons and that was no bueno.
Rym: now I do think that all of the controllers that have like the weird shape that like fits your hand completely I think the GameCube was actually the best one.
Scott: Oh, that's not that the GameCube controller just looks weird.
Rym: Yeah So scap of it.
Rym: when I saw the first images of it like I did not trust it and with like the weird yellow nipple.
Scott: and It just looks weird because the shape of the plastic.
Scott: but really it's pretty normal except for the layout of the buttons on the right.
Scott: But the layout of the buttons on the right is actually really it while it hurts a lot of games.
Scott: Or you sort of want the buttons lined up nicely.
Scott: It's really great for games like say, you know, Zelda type games.
Scott: You get this big ol a button you're hitting 90% of the time and everything else Right, so that was the.
Scott: that was the thinking that went into.
Scott: that was like look you got the four buttons and they're all equally Sized and sort of equally positioned with the bottom two a little bit easier and the top right one a little bit harder to reach.
Scott: But the GameCube controller is like look you're hitting this one button way more than the other ones And you got this little one off to the side you're hitting second most and these X and Y ones you're hitting much more rarely.
Scott: Let's put those off to the to the back but still within reach.
Rym: Thing was the game that it fit.
Rym: the best for me was Soul Calibur because of the.
Rym: you know They had like vertical attack horizontal attack and the way those controls map to the GameCube just felt super intuitive Because the Y button was directly on top.
Rym: Yeah, be like vertical.
Scott: Anyway, the PlayStation controller originally didn't have the two analog sticks, right.
Scott: originally it was just you know the four arrows on the left and the four buttons on the right with the But and the shoulder buttons.
Scott: it added this the extra shoulders the l2 and r2 Which is above and beyond what the Super Nintendo had with the other just L and R. So that was okay, I guess you mean we still have it today.
Scott: We have those buttons right as analog things.
Scott: So that's that's cool.
Scott: but the thing I hate about PlayStation controllers so much even to this day is that the Buttons on the left the d-pad are sort of separated by this plastic thing.
Scott: Look the thing is underneath.
Scott: It's still one contiguous d-pad.
Rym: Wasn't that just to get around the patent or whatever?
Scott: I don't know what it was But it makes it really uncomfortable to use and really annoying.
Scott: also those arrows are sort of mushy Right compared to d-pads which are more, you know digital like go.
Rym: I haven't touched in any answer as any.
Rym: as gamepad like go find it Just touch one and like move that d-pad or you haven't touched.
Scott: Yeah, like you might not have PlayStation buttons in general are kind of mushy.
Scott: So that bothers me.
Scott: I like buttons to go like, you know, where you can definitely feel like click click.
Scott: This is pressed and this is unpressed.
Rym: not sort of like Because I gotta build a Nintendo finger.
Rym: Sometimes you need a Nintendo finger in there.
Scott: Yeah, so It was.
Scott: they did have the analog on and off thing going on.
Scott: They also had invented This is the one thing Nintendo didn't invent is pushing the analog stick in to as a button press.
Rym: I'm still Real real ambivalent about that because on one hand it's super useful.
Rym: Well, it's some context, right?
Scott: So the good parts about that is that you're moving analog stick and in order to press the button We say you got left on my analog stick, right?
Scott: If you want to push a button with that left thumb You have to remove it from the stick and now it's reset automatically to its neutral position Which is like maybe I wanted that left stick in a non neutral position while also pressing a button on the left side with the thumb Can't do it.
Scott: So you assign that function to pushing the stick inwards and the stick goes in and clicks.
Scott: and that's you know, okay good You did it.
Scott: also it adds an extra button to the controller without having to take up any extra space Which is also great for games that need more buttons.
Rym: So in breath of the wild I Hit that fucking button.
Scott: Mm-hmm so often.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I'm just.
Scott: naturally when I'm playing a game I'm working that stick hard and I've put some force on the stick and
Rym: as soon as the line L comes and I start working it And
Scott: I'm pushing that stick in just cuz I'm pushing the stick hard and it gets act activated Accidentally and that is bad.
Scott: So I prefer I would prefer that those functions not be there.
Scott: I prefer a stick be a stick and a button.
Rym: Here's the other problem.
Rym: I found and they're what you can do though Use.
Scott: you could put an actual physical button on top of the stick like a flight stick has the missile button on time But nobody does that on a tiny little analog stick.
Rym: So The real problem with that isn't that it's an option that you could use.
Rym: It's that there was an era and there's a lot of games that still do this.
Rym: But I remember all those like later ps2 and ps3 games that all our friends played at RIT that we didn't really care about.
Rym: But we'd like watch them play like Devil May Cry or whatever.
Rym: There was all these games that would because the controller had X button or N buttons a number of buttons not X button.
Rym: They would map something to every single button and that was how they designed their like fighting mechanics.
Rym: almost They'd be like we have this many buttons.
Rym: every fucking one of them is being used And I feel like that.
Scott: you don't have to do that.
Scott: You can just use some of the buttons and leave the other ones is doing nothing or just double up.
Scott: be like this is jump.
Scott: This is also jump.
Scott: This one's also jump like Sonic the Hedgehog.
Scott: You had a sage is in control with ABC.
Scott: What's the difference in a B and C?
Scott: nothing?
Scott: Help they all did the same goddamn thing pitch whichever one's more comfortable for you because the controller is enormous.
Scott: Good luck Right.
Scott: Actually, there was a six button controller for Sega Genesis.
Scott: That was actually, you know, it wasn't as good as the one I've got.
Rym: actually it wasn't as it plugs into the Atari 2600, right?
Scott: It wasn't as good as Super Nintendo controller because didn't have L&R but it did have the same number of buttons, you know six Plus a d-pad and a start.
Scott: the one problem the good thing about the six button controller in addition having six buttons is That it was smaller.
Scott: So you could actually hit all the buttons.
Scott: Also for something like Street Fighter the rows of three and three.
Scott: so important so good That's like.
Scott: that's why Street Fighter 2 Championship Edition on the Genesis While the software was a little bit not as good as Street Fighter 2 turbo on the SNES had those six buttons.
Scott: six button controller Playing Street Fighter with the SNES controller.
Scott: I mean people did it but using L&R for one of the punches and one of the kicks is not as good as using, you know the Final two buttons on the Genesis controller.
Rym: There's a reason.
Rym: I have that expensive Fight stick.
Rym: Yeah, even though I suck it all non Soulcalibur 2 non Bushido blade fighting.
Scott: I also use it for main arcade games.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and pac-man.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So after PlayStation the PlayStation 2 I'm not sure like what changes they made in the DualShock 2 because that's the arrow I think they only made like subtle changes that like weren't a big deal?
Scott: I don't really remember because I wasn't a PlayStation type person.
Rym: Yeah in the Xbox I was also like I hated those controllers.
Scott: Well, the first X the first Xbox controller was basically a PlayStation controller only way big like a Genesis controller Right.
Scott: It was enormous.
Scott: And in fact, they later on released like a special edition of it.
Scott: That was a normal size.
Rym: I mean penny arcade made it so many strips making fun of that giant ass controller on the Xbox.
Scott: Yeah Oh, I shouldn't forget to mention Dreamcast controller Has control the weird one from the weird console, right?
Scott: So Dreamcast controller looks enormous and weird But actually it's really comfortable and really useful and just perfectly feels really intuitive.
Scott: It only feels weird if you look at it while like you look down you're like, oh, right The only problem it really has is it doesn't have the right analog stick, right, you know But it's.
Scott: and the other problem has is the.
Scott: I think the cord comes out the bottom.
Rym: Yeah, that was always weird.
Scott: Yeah, I don't like cord coming out.
Scott: the bottom cord must come out the top.
Scott: But anyway it all the thing it had is the VMU thingy.
Scott: Right and the VMU thingy was like a little memory card.
Scott: You putting it in the controller was great much better than putting a memory card for save games into the console back in the days.
Scott: And we still need memory cards and we didn't just have storage.
Scott: But it also had a little screen on it and you could also take it out and play little games on it Which was in some ways better than the GBA link cable.
Scott: But since it was way weak, it was nowhere near as good as the GBA link cable Yeah, and it couldn't do funk.
Scott: You couldn't have a crystal chronicles in the Dreamcast.
Scott: But I would have loved in the day for that VMU idea to have been as good, you know Like what if the GameCube the official controller was the GBA and there were no GameCube controller do right something like that?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So I think right now in terms of consoles the best controller money can buy is the Nintendo pro controller.
Rym: It feels so tight.
Scott: Yeah, I've had it look sticks.
Scott: I pay it's 70 bucks, which is fucking bullshit.
Rym: It's worth it though, but I have it for the switch and like it's pretty great.
Rym: It's like the analog sticks like you don't realize to use them.
Rym: They're way more sensitive and they feel like they're like they have more play.
Rym: like they're just.
Scott: it's just.
Scott: it's just a perfect normal Controller as it has a good head.
Scott: It has two analog sticks.
Scott: It has four face buttons.
Scott: It's got l1 l2 r1 r2 and that's it.
Rym: built-in battery.
Scott: It just charges on the console USB-c cable does wireless has perfect high, you know fancy rumblin.
Scott: Oh, we didn't talk about rumblin.
Rym: I feel like we should do a separate show on rumblin a whole show and I think we do a whole show on rumblin.
Scott: But yeah, the current Xbox is a big deal.
Scott: It is a big deal.
Scott: But you know, the current Xbox controllers are perfectly serviceable.
Scott: So are the current PlayStation ones except for my personal dislike of the separated arrow.
Rym: So outside of consoles until recently I would say that the regular old like Xbox 360 controller Is the best controller to use on a PC?
Scott: It's still a terrific controller.
Scott: It has a d-pad though is so weak on it.
Scott: It's like a circle with a raised plus on it and it is not very good.
Scott: You'll often be hitting the wrong arrow when you try to use it.
Rym: Well, the other problem it has is that the official dongle to plug it into a PC Like they just stop making it you many years ago.
Scott: I've heard that the third-party ones work just fine Yeah, but like it was just weird that they stopped making the official way you can and I think that I think the Xbox one Controller, I think we'll just connect and so will I think the PlayStation controller?
Rym: I think so.
Scott: I think they just connect to PCs like with Bluetooth or something.
Rym: What about the Nintendo Pro controller?
Rym: cuz I haven't tried to connect it to my PC.
Scott: I don't think it connects to a PC cuz they would.
Rym: I think it is I think the best controller for the PC.
Scott: I think someone tried to do it with Linux or something.
Rym: I gotta look into the state of that because they would be would dethrone the Xbox controller.
Rym: Maybe because the only attempt to make a better controller by anyone serious on the PC to play games with was the steam controller.
Rym: Frankly I think they kind of failed.
Rym: I don't think it's that good a controller.
Rym: No, it's got a lot of flaws It has.
Scott: it has some things going for it that make it good like those inside buttons are brilliant.
Scott: Yeah, they're pretty good league.
Rym: Those things are amazing.
Scott: It works really well with PC.
Scott: right because I'll made for PC You know, the buttons are nice.
Scott: the two touch pads with the tactile miss I'm sure this gate and like the fact that it just work as a mouse.
Scott: It's like it's really good Sometimes when you want to use those things, but those times are so rare and nobody's making games.
Scott: That's the thing is Nintendo made games of the analog stick Like.
Scott: I talked about how they made the a64 controller and then in Mario 64 that goes with it.
Scott: Right, the steam controller has these tactile discs and the valve didn't make a game to go with that.
Scott: So it's like they don't have a. you know, it's sort of the way that John Carmack would like makes game engines But without John Romero, he doesn't make a game to go with the engine.
Scott: you get something like rage Which no one wants to play.
Scott: Yep, right?
Scott: You have to make a controller with a game together and then you will that those two things feed into each other And then you design the controller properly.
Rym: also the steam controller Like if we want.
Rym: if I want to just like oh, hey Let's play a game and I get a like pair a bunch of controllers on my HD PC.
Rym: I often find that the steam controller Sometimes because it's kind of too smart for its own good It just works brilliantly and other times it just doesn't play nice with the game or doesn't play nice with.
Rym: like the fact That I also have three Xbox controllers and I ended up not using it in the living room at all anymore.
Rym: I bought another Xbox controller instead.
Scott: I mostly use my steam controller on my desktop piece.
Scott: That's what I do for those times.
Scott: You really need a controller on your desk here Even though you wouldn't use a controller when you're sitting at a desk.
Scott: It's in here solely for that purpose and then I use Xbox controllers on the HD PC.
Rym: That is exactly what I do as well.
Rym: I would not recommend buying the steam controller unless you already have it or like you get it cheap.
Scott: Yeah What are the controllers out there.
Scott: Oh So also on peep on top PC before you had the steam controller and before you were able to use console controllers on your PC You had to buy like PC game pads and they were a drive his game pad, right?
Scott: So they were very poorly supported for many many years because basically people making PC games didn't make games that required a game pad.
Scott: because like which one there I remember like someone bought Super Street Fighter 2 turbo for PC for DOS and it came with a six button PC game pad.
Scott: They had a game connector.
Rym: Like if you had a game controller or a flight stick or anything at all You usually plugged him directly into your sound card.
Scott: So in the reasons that are way beyond the scope of this episode in the commander keen days There was the gravis game pad, which was for but for face buttons and a digital pad that you could also.
Rym: it was so garbage.
Scott: It was not.
Scott: it was not good but it was the only game pad you can get on PC and playing commander keen with that was better than playing it with the keyboard and keyboard.
Scott: Yeah So they did make a gravis game pad pro that I got.
Scott: that in addition to the four face buttons.
Scott: All.
Scott: it was basically a Super Nintendo Sort of controller right and it's sort of a PlayStation controller.
Scott: Also, it didn't really have the analog sticks but it had the d-pad on the left four buttons on the right l1 l2 r1 r2.
Scott: and You know, there weren't really games made for that but you could you know any game that was.
Rym: you know Games use that primarily in that era Emulators.
Rym: Yeah, any SSM you later?
Scott: That's exactly what I used it for.
Scott: is I would you know in those days when I had emulators on my old wind This is Windows 98 times.
Scott: I'd plug in that gravis gamepad Pro, which is not even USB.
Scott: I don't think it might have been USB or might have been still been game controller.
Scott: I actually had a game a car a PCI card that you plugged game controllers into with it, you know Yeah had a game port.
Rym: So because we've got we've got a long enough I think but I'm good.
Rym: Something that I think because we talked about Steam greenlight dying and like any games and all that it is Inexcusable in the year 2017 to release a game that doesn't just support controllers and just work.
Rym: Yep, like joy to key if you need if your game requires people to do nonsense like that you fucked up.
Scott: Yeah the steam controller you don't need joy to keep.
Scott: you have a steam controller because they have this thing where it turns into a And you'll get proof for if it's a popular game and a profile will exist for it and you can sort of download the profile Yeah, and it'll just suddenly work which is really nice.
Scott: And that's another time that I'll use the steam controller which is why it's kind of worth having.
Scott: if you play a lot of steam games sitting at your debt, you know, but It's still not.
Scott: it shouldn't be that way You're.
Scott: if you have a game that you just made your game should support controllers properly.
Scott: right whether it's PC or not.
Rym: Yep, like it's it's sort of a minimum requirement of releasing a game in the modern era.
Rym: I'm even if you don't.
Scott: if I was steam.
Scott: here's the thing.
Scott: if I was steam with this new system I'll just require it.
Scott: I'd reject any game that didn't support controller the appropriate controls appropriate to the game.
Scott: Now you might say if doesn't need gamepad support true, right?
Rym: You might say but my I wouldn't accept platformer.
Scott: I'd be like game pads or no one steam.
Rym: So you might say your game doesn't need it, but Having that Configurability is very important for accessibility because a lot of times crazy Accessibility devices will show up as a game controller or a keyboard of some kind And you need a way to be able to map it and use it.
Rym: if your game doesn't support that you lose Accessibility and you piss me off.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we were.
Scott: I tried to.
Scott: you know, the topic is so broad I wanted to only talk about the actual controllers.
Scott: Yeah, but you do need to remember right?
Scott: You know part of controls is in the software as well of each and every individual game.
Scott: You can have the best controller right and a really crappy game has bad controls, right?
Scott: It's like the end.
Scott: think about NES games.
Scott: You got something like Mario 3 and you got something like I don't know.
Rym: playing Mario 3 in an emulator with a gravis gamepad Was almost impossible right but but not right that's true.
Scott: but also just think about having an actual NES with Mario 3 and An actual NES with a really bad game with bad controls like man.
Scott: Yeah sure, right.
Scott: It's like you have the same controller the same hardware Except the game is different and now the same controller is now garbage with that bad game.
Rym: Should we do another show on controls?
Scott: I think we I don't know but it's like You have to be able to separate like when is the controller at fault and when is the software at fault for being bad?
Scott: Sometimes hard to tell if a whole bunch of software gets it wrong and you can't find any software doing it, right?
Rym: So anyway, get that Nintendo Pro controller working on a PC.
Rym: Whoever's working on that.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order My think is when giving basis set as fast as possible without stopping our Nicholas Brando Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas on my stage calm William Eisner's Jeremy minor.
Rym: I like big butts and I cannot lie.
Rym: you other brothers can't deny a genuine.
Rym: but if I'd like to five six car monorail Cuz you are top of shit.
Rym: No, you sure?
Rym: Yeah Matthew Smith Chris Reimer show sure Joe star Rebecca Dunn ran from New Zealand Finn Daniel Redman Shervin van Horrell Don Schleich Rochelle, Monta Nona, mr.
Rym: Black Chris Knox Chris midkiff rare Laval the terrible secrets base.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make Rym say pickle Clinton Walton sailor Vista Ryan Perrin Brian Cedroni for two one creations Thomas, hon just Sam Cordery Shawn Klein James David white and Sean Yeager.
Rym: and Now I leave you with something weird.
Media: It is a good day in Pokemon world.
Media: I think I should catch a Pokemon.
Media: Oh look a Bidoof.
Media: There's a Bidoof and there's a Bidoof over there behind the bush.
Media: I I think I'm gonna catch him Pokeball.
Media: no, he's angry.
Media: He's Someone signed in.
Media: Oh, look.
Media: He's he's angry.
Media: He's gonna.
Media: he's gonna attack me.
Media: Oh, no, he's got a knife.
Media: He's got a knife.
Media: He's he's throwing the knife at me.
Media: He missed but oh, he's got a gun.
Media: He's firing his gun.
Media: This is the most angry Bidoof has ever been.
Media: he's.
Media: oh, where'd he go?
Media: He's disappeared.
Media: He's.
Media: um, I don't know where he is.
Media: Oh He's in the sky.
Media: He's on that cloud.
Media: No.
Media: No, he's throwing ninjas at me.
Media: The ninjas are everywhere.
Media: Oh No, oh I'm on fire now.
Media: This is not good.
Media: I'm I'm gonna go home and there's oh no the Bidoof.
Media: He's burnt down my house.
Media: I had a wife and children now.
Media: They're all dead.
Media: Oh Mr.
Media: Bidoof why why would you do this to me?
Media: All I wanted was to catch you with a pokeball No.