Rym: It's Tuesday July 18th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight reviewing board games.
Rym: the way that we do it dog Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, so we wanted to actually review a board game.
Rym: We've been playing recently, but we haven't played it enough and this show instead will be about Why.
Rym: that makes it hard to review a lot of board games like we used to in the I don't know like five years ago.
Scott: It's all you.
Scott: yeah, it's your idea you're carrying it.
Rym: Hey, it was my crab people and I admitted it was a crab people, but that's what I got for tonight.
Rym: I got nothing But we'll probably be able to play that game enough to the next Tuesday show be able to talk about it Or maybe I'll just blow through night in the woods and then we can do a full show on that.
Scott: You can also play.
Scott: I'm gonna start playing chef II on the switch.
Scott: Oh, yeah play that we could do a show.
Rym: I'll play that.
Rym: I'll play the hell out of that cuz.
Rym: uh, I can't get past much in tumble seeds.
Scott: They just made tumble seed easier, yeah, maybe I should.
Rym: I get that update.
Rym: I actually went back into breath of the wild and went and did a whole.
Scott: I'm gonna do that also.
Rym: I went and got a whole bunch of shrines that were like the weird hard-to-find ones.
Scott: I'm gonna be doing that soon because the DLC updated and I paid for that.
Rym: Yeah, my money's worth You know, I didn't get the DLC and the more I look at what it is I don't think I care.
Scott: but I also get other DLCs that are coming later.
Scott: I'd say it was a pack.
Scott: This is this isn't all I'm getting.
Scott: I'm getting like a whole other dungeon later.
Rym: Yeah, I will see.
Rym: I'm gonna wait and see if the dungeon is great because breath of the way I'm gonna pay more for that dungeon.
Rym: Yeah, breath of the wild was already like this really like perfect gaming experience and because I've sort of played it Through so hard that the incremental returns on playing it more actually pretty minimal even if there's more content.
Scott: I'm just tempted because I was tempted because all the Zelda games right you play them you beat them and then they're so done.
Rym: It's like well, but no breath of the wild.
Rym: to your point.
Rym: Yeah cuz like I booted up the other day cuz I was like waiting for something to finish like I was doing a render and I was just like, huh?
Rym: I wonder what's over there?
Rym: I don't have any like.
Rym: there's not a lot of waypoints or things in that area of the map.
Rym: I wonder if there's something there and I just went to this part of the map.
Scott: It's like, you know, even a game.
Scott: That's so enormous.
Scott: You still I'm still have covered a great amount of it.
Rym: Yeah That's the last area I explored.
Rym: I explored the fuck out of that area So the tempt ate.
Scott: my favorite area The temptation of a Zelda that keeps going is like the temptation of the netrunner where they adding more car.
Rym: Well, it's also because you're so powerful by the end of breath of the wild if you did all this stuff.
Rym: They're walking around like this god-man with weapons of the ancients just like silver line out, whatever.
Rym: He won't even touch me.
Rym: Let's go, bro Mm-hmm.
Rym: I didn't even upgrade most of my stuff all the way like it didn't?
Scott: I think I got the ancient armor But I got to do a lot of upgrading it by getting Lionel part.
Rym: I decided that wasn't worth it.
Rym: I pretty much only ever wore the Zora like the full Zora.
Scott: I think the thing is I just really want to be able to walk up to ancients get and have them shoot lasers and like Nothing even happens like oh you hit me with laser big whoop.
Scott: Wha you're dead.
Scott: That's what I really I just want to do.
Scott: That's so bad.
Rym: Yep so, uh, yeah, if you didn't notice it's kind of actually important news because it is it is the most chill packs and it is Real packs.
Rym: but PAX South.
Rym: in San Antonio is January 12th through 14th, which Unfortunately is one week after mag fest.
Scott: So you go to.
Scott: you go to New Year's party Yeah.
Scott: And then the next weekend you go to mag fest and the next weekend you go to PAX South and you pay someone to do Your laundry in between because you know that time for that.
Scott: Yeah I'm gonna be gone for a while in January between all the weekend before.
Scott: that is is xmas, right?
Scott: so it's like you have four consecutive weekends from the end of December to the middle of January of Boom-boom-boom-boom.
Scott: And if you don't do that, you ain't living.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So PAX South remember it.
Scott: Why be a nerd alive on this world?
Scott: If that is not what you do
Rym: if PAX Prime is too hard to get into and too far away and too expensive and PAX East there's no hotels because the so hotels are probably sold out for the next 20 years already And you can't just fly to Sydney every year like I do.
Rym: PAX South is like super great and I know we say this a lot but a lot of you don't seem to really understand How great it is.
Scott: it is cheaper to go to PAX South in San Antonio Even if you live if you have to drive and use a hotel at PAX East Because you're just like you're within driving distance of it, but you have to pay for parking in hotel.
Scott: It would be cheaper to fly to San Antonio because the hotel there is so cheap and the packs ticket is so much cheaper.
Scott: and
Rym: packs badges went on sale because my alert went off because I forgot to turn it off after when
Scott: I didn't get the alert because I turned it off and also In the bathroom when I had
Rym: and my blood got up because you know my brain still says oh shit packs.
Rym: So I went straight for the hotel and I got the good hotel.
Rym: I won't say the name of the good hotel because I don't want it to ever become the hotel that sells out.
Scott: It's not the cheapest hotel.
Scott: So don't it won't sell true?
Rym: Uh, yeah, none of that.
Rym: I think the con hotel like the closest one is sold out.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but nothing else is no and Three day badges are still available.
Scott: Yep, three day.
Rym: You can buy a single badge That covers three days at PAX South.
Rym: Mm-hmm That might seem crazy if you've been to other paxes But that is how it is and it is a full pax and it focuses heavily tabletop and even the people.
Scott: who?
Scott: Go to PAX for your swag and your industry.
Scott: shit, right?
Scott: It's like yeah It's not nearly as big as East or West not even close in that regard if that's what you're going to PAX for.
Scott: however At the last PAX South that was the first place that they had like Nintendo Switches and all those and it's like it's still There and it's crowded.
Scott: not like they have none of it They don't.
Scott: it's just not crazy like just walk up to one of these booths wait like five minutes and see what's going on And even the eSports like it packs out last time.
Scott: There was a hearthstone tournament right there.
Scott: So I'm like, oh, I'm not doing anything Right now.
Scott: I walk over and sit down and like every single famous hearthstone person Which is there and I'm sure the same was true over in the games for the eSports of other.
Scott: You know things like even though it's PAX out.
Scott: It's it's still a pax.
Scott: It still brings out big guns.
Scott: It's just not a big hoo-ha because it's in San Antonio.
Rym: yep, and Most paxes other than West are mostly locals who attend.
Rym: so PAX out.
Rym: There's mostly people who live literally like within driving distance in Texas.
Scott: Yeah, that most of the people there are from Texas, Oklahoma and nearby places.
Scott: There were not as many people from far away, but look it's cheap if it's from far away.
Scott: You can go Low prices.
Scott: so we will find inventions.
Scott: go.
Scott: I mean if you can't afford PAX out, you can't afford a convention.
Scott: That's you can't.
Scott: that's outside your town.
Rym: Yeah But at that point you gotta look for those local cons like the Zenkaik on the Connecticut.
Scott: the one that makes you are the one That you can like drive to and from with your car to back to your house every day and pay for no hotel.
Scott: That is the cheapest car.
Rym: Actually, I think that's part of why the hotels don't sell out.
Rym: at PAX out is a lot of people just come for the day Sure?
Rym: or They drive in because they live near San Antonio and they just drive in every day.
Rym: Sure Cuz I notice a lot of people drive out like the hotels are pretty dead at night FX out the parking lot has activity and is full.
Rym: So there's another packs that finally we can announce about.
Rym: at least we're doing at least one panel at PAX West.
Rym: I believe it is our 42nd pax panel.
Rym: That really but I think at this point pax is eclipse Literally every other con we've ever performed at even Otakon where we used to do like five plus a year.
Scott: So unlike pax out, which doesn't sell out pax west.
Scott: I think it's sold out.
Rym: Yeah I don't think so.
Rym: Anyway, I'll check.
Scott: you might be able to buy a Monday But the point is I I've been going to soon be in possession once they mail it.
Rym: Oh Monday is low.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: There are a few Monday badges.
Scott: I have four full sets, but Emily's buying one set Yeah, and some internet person is probably buying another full set, but I still now that our panel is confirmed.
Scott: Yes I have.
Scott: I do not need these two other full sets of pax west badges.
Scott: Friday, Saturday, Sunday Monday.
Scott: if you want to go to pax west and the only thing keeping you from going is that you could not get badges in The crazy run up to buying them You can buy them from me for face value because I don't need them and I do need my money back that I only spent as insurance.
Rym: we buy badges as Insurance because if our panel is rejected we need to go to pax or you will die If I couldn't get one then.
Rym: well, so there's another secret I don't.
Rym: we bring this up occasionally if you care a lot about game design or in the game industry or especially if you're a student at a University if you buy a badge to pax dev which is expensive But there's a huge discount if you're a current college student.
Scott: Mm-hmm You have to be studying.
Scott: games are gonna be studying like medicine.
Rym: You can be studying studying.
Scott: Can you be studying medicine?
Rym: I think they check you out like they might email you and be like, hey But I'm pretty sure if you're just going to university they'll let you in.
Rym: All right, but You have the right even though pax west is sold out to just buy one set of full badges for pax to go with your pax dev to go with your pax dev because no one flies to Seattle just for pax.
Scott: that's not cheap though because if you don't live nearby You're also gonna have to pay for extra hotel nights to use your pax dev bed and such and such.
Scott: so that's not a cheap Option, but it is a way that you can spend money to avoid hassle and pegs.
Rym: Yeah, wealthy is real good and it's been getting better year by year.
Scott: I really enjoy it But I would if I had a ton more vacation days.
Rym: I don't go and the only caveat is Do not go if you expect to play games because it is a serious convention.
Rym: We're literally like it's all workshops and like serious panels and business stuff.
Scott: It's if I actually can finish making a game and published a game.
Scott: then I would go to pax dev.
Rym: yep, I go partly because I've actually learned if I was really close to doing so and Actually, I've learned a lot too about things we need to do for the convention.
Rym: We're starting that Pre-shit talks and I can talk about it a lot yet, but stay tuned.
Rym: The GeekNights convention is coming.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's basically first come first serve.
Rym: event by friend.
Rym: if you hear our voices saying this right now, that's good enough.
Scott: That's pretty close.
Rym: Not that many people listen to GeekNights now But we will be at pax west doing a panel on Sunday at 6 30 p.m And keep in mind It's not the last day.
Scott: Monday's the last day.
Rym: Yeah in a theater We've never performed in before the hippogriff theater Hi in the Hyatt because it begins with an H. I think it's the one we saw the Tetris guy in that one year or the One next to it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Those are both pretty big too.
Scott: Yeah, they're hard the horizontal kind.
Rym: So the panel is called the rage of the quitter.
Scott: now you might say It's a redo of the quitting panel.
Rym: we did before you might say that but actually kind of rewriting that panel because we ran that panel a bunch of times and We both figured out a lot of stuff.
Rym: and I actually I think we have a very different panel to give.
Rym: and well We're still gonna talk about 10-cent beer night because that is one of the most wonderful things that's ever happened in baseball.
Rym: But this panel is gonna happen and we're gonna be a fax is gonna be awesome.
Rym: see my scene.
Rym: we talked about tumble seed and The game is hard.
Scott: We did a whole episode in tumble seed games real hard.
Scott: Well, it's not.
Scott: see the thing is tumble seed.
Scott: I think actually has the right level of difficult.
Scott: I've said this before but I say it again It has the right level of difficulty for a roguelike type game.
Scott: the problem of tumble seed is that The difficulty curve is too steep right away.
Scott: The beginning of level one is there's holes There's monsters that chase you.
Scott: it's like there's holes and bad guys right a fucking way.
Scott: It's like no no, no.
Scott: You can bring that on.
Scott: you can.
Scott: even.
Scott: the game could actually probably get to a difficulty level towards the end.
Scott: That is harder than its current difficulty level towards the end and it would be fine.
Scott: You have to start even in the easy mode.
Scott: now the game starts and the board looks like Swiss cheese.
Scott: It's like you should start with one hole then one bad guy then maybe two holes, right Mario Mario starts with a flat splays no holes to fall in and one fucking goomba.
Scott: right.
Scott: you start at the absolute rock bottom where a baby would have to be the only one who could mess this up and Then you curve up nicely and then if you curve nicely you can get to the fucking Mount Everest Heights.
Scott: Right as long as your curve is nice You know you could.
Scott: actually you could have a game that curves up nicely and because goes into fucking outer space or the difficulty Is ludicrous like doom nightmare mode difficulty right and that would be fine.
Scott: You cannot have a game that starts at like hurt me plenty Even if it only goes up to ultra violence.
Scott: you started to hurt me plenty.
Scott: people are gonna be like oh Cuz they didn't build the skills to deal with.
Scott: even that medium hurt me plenty level.
Rym: having played it a bunch of Morrison We did that show.
Rym: I almost think too that really Even if it started with the Swiss cheese if there weren't enemies for like 10 minutes 10 minutes is too long I mean like just like a screen or two.
Rym: even even 10 minutes like the Swiss cheese alone gives me trouble I but I really okay.
Scott: You just really you just really suck.
Rym: I am actually like we're like ice.
Rym: cold beer is a real hard game But I am way worse at it than you might expect.
Scott: okay, you must be really bad cuz.
Scott: I got Anyway, the new my friend Chris was way the netrunner Chris.
Scott: He's way in a tumble seat.
Scott: He was streaming it Whoa, he went away and came back and now it's been updated.
Scott: So he streamed again.
Scott: So what they done is Instead of just the adventure mode, which is still there There's now four other mountains one for each of the four parts of the big mountain So you can just play forest and then you can play jungle and then you can play Right and you can sort of.
Scott: it gives you this opportunity to build up your skills and do these little quest You know what.
Scott: and it also gives you these auras.
Scott: remember in the old one The auras are just like partially hurting you.
Scott: Yeah Now you can choose when you basically by playing the small mountains you unlock these auras So you can start with one of these auras.
Scott: that's positive only and something like the first aura is like oh You know don't lose your spikes when you fall and or we don't lose your spikes and you get hit or don't lose hearts.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: all that is because I was thinking about the game as I played it more.
Rym: The model for how to map the difficulty of a game like this is actually Crypt of the NecroDancer.
Rym: Crypt of the NecroDancer is like a case study in Introducing increasingly difficult and complex things in a way that will give the character the person playing all the tools They need to get better.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the games that equal that are Mario Super Metroid and I think Mega Man.
Rym: I'd say though because of the way this game works at the stages and the levels.
Rym: in the roguelike aspect NecroDancer is a closer fit Because Mega Man and Mario and all those games have one thing that's very different you the games are not random.
Scott: Yeah, even net hack did a better job at curving up than the first tumble seed.
Rym: Yeah, you can get through like one or two rooms As we said in the review.
Rym: I appreciate the fact that the game is just fuck you in your face.
Rym: That's kind of what ice-cold beer is and this was made by people who were ridiculous fans of that game.
Scott: Yes, but if I spend that money to buy this game and I can only play it for a minute before I want to return it That's a problem not for me.
Rym: You sure.
Rym: But yeah, this article talks about how the game will likely never recruit its costs and they talk it's sort of post-mortem.
Rym: It's a fascinating read it.
Rym: I'm not gonna paraphrase the whole thing.
Rym: You just read it, but a sort of tangential point that I think you should bear in mind is that Most games do not recoup their costs.
Rym: No Don't think that the fact that this game is hard is the only reason it did.
Scott: Well, I think.
Scott: I think also the costs of making tumble seed were higher than you would think because a they put in a lot Of platforms even the switch.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Also look how fucking polished it is as a piece of software, right?
Scott: Even though according to the visuals the sound the they can even get the rumble, right?
Scott: It's like they polished the fuck out of this game and that cost them like months and months of development time Of course, which is why it's so great based on specific it.
Rym: like Interactions I've had in the industry about games have succeeded or failed where I learn things about like the actual back-end process The games that tend to make the most money are the ones that spent way more time and money on the polishing aspects.
Scott: Like there's nothing unpolished about tumble seed.
Scott: It just has a difficulty curve.
Rym: They polished a knife and then they pushed it into my abdomen.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's We're announced as someone gonna yell at us from is pronouncing it again these.
Rym: I'm so bad at German pronunciation.
Scott: I cannot pronounce it, but it's why it's the game of the year.
Scott: You've probably seen his logo on various board game boxes.
Scott: It's a red pawn with a little yellow flag sword fighting.
Scott: very good and they yeah, they award this award.
Scott: We said this so many times in the show, but whatever every year they give this award out to the best board game.
Scott: There's one that's the spiel.
Scott: this are the default one.
Scott: This one is the kinner spiel.
Scott: That's like the one for the kids game and then there's like a another one for a strategy game, right?
Scott: so the regulars feel this are you know, the the sort of criteria for winning?
Scott: it is sort of like.
Scott: You know not what you would expect But it doesn't matter.
Scott: the games that win it are usually terrific and the game that won it this year is king domino Or is it king kingdom?
Scott: I know kingdom, you know, you know what it's.
Rym: it's kingdom up.
Scott: Yes It's a game that combines The theme of kingdoms with the play of dominoes.
Scott: King domino king domino Whatever you want to call it.
Rym: It's dominoes and kingdoms.
Scott: Okay, I'd be seeing it.
Scott: I really want to play it.
Scott: Yeah, I really don't want to keep it in my house.
Rym: I see spend money on kingdoms dominoes all together.
Scott: I love kingdoms and I like dominoes.
Scott: So full also.
Scott: I got green.
Scott: look there's a green piece I played from here.
Rym: I played a lot of dominoes as a kid.
Scott: like straight dominoes itself is not great.
Scott: No, dominoes is not a good game No, but dominoes is a good game to play with some Hispanic guys on a folding table out in Queens.
Rym: But that's a lot like playing backgammon with a bunch of like old Turkish guys in Turkey exactly playing for the game.
Rym: You're playing as an excuse to sit out in the evening under the Sun sipping some tea and bullshitting for four.
Scott: I'm playing as practice for my retirement year.
Scott: Yeah, cuz that's one day I'm gonna be that old guy and some punk kid is gonna want to practice for his retirement And it's gonna come play backgammon and dominoes with me circle of life.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I have no idea what the mechanics are.
Scott: Yeah I think you play tiles that are domino like a forest test a touch of forest and then you put ponds on them Like I don't know.
Rym: There's definitely some card counting I think.
Rym: as it looks I see a a board that tells you how many of each type exists.
Scott: I'm sure it's a great game.
Rym: We'll play it probably very soon Because I'm actually gonna get rid of a bunch of board games me too.
Scott: if anyone wants a bunch of board games.
Rym: Hey, well keep stay tuned.
Rym: We're gonna make a post in the forum sometime this week because we're gonna.
Rym: We both want to get rid of a lot of games and I want them to go to good homes.
Rym: I don't even need to make money.
Rym: I just want to give them to someone who will play them.
Rym: Yep, or give them to a library of a convention looking at you cold guy If you'll pay shipping, I need to remove a lot of stuff from my house.
Scott: Anyone who wants to help remove it.
Scott: like if someone comes to my house and wants nerdy shit Like I'm gonna choose which shit is available to you and you can take whatever of it you want.
Rym: Or should we do the paint that patreon thing that we're talking?
Scott: Oh, we just send our shit to people.
Rym: if people make a tear and if you're at that tear every month We'll mail you something at least as valuable or nerdy as a board game.
Rym: Until we run out of stuff No We'll get rid of.
Scott: the problem is what if I have like I want to get like.
Scott: one of the things I'm trying to get rid Of is all.
Rym: my initial team on the valley says give me your games.
Scott: I have volumes of initial D. I've got like 20 plus of them.
Scott: What if I said one person find one and one person find that's even funnier and one person find the right way to do it.
Scott: That's the right way to do it.
Scott: I feel like I all got to go to the same phone all of dr Slump, but we want to keep that.
Rym: I just want to read it before I give it away.
Rym: That's exact.
Scott: so I'm doing a full metal alchemist.
Scott: I haven't not given that away even read all I'm gonna.
Scott: I have every full metal alchemist manga volume.
Scott: I'm gonna read them all and then sell get rid of them somehow I don't know.
Rym: I feel like my brain does that.
Rym: I lost Interest in full metal alchemists like the part of my brain that was into.
Rym: it just said what was live-action?
Scott: now I don't even it came like it came back the other day.
Scott: I saw tweets about full metal alchemists.
Scott: I'm like what the fuck.
Scott: and it's like oh, there's live-action like what the fuck.
Scott: But the manga is different from the the other one, you know, yeah There's two anime and that stupid movie.
Rym: none of them seem to link up.
Rym: they're all just like it's the El Hazzard.
Scott: That's why I'm just gonna read the whole manga.
Scott: cuz look that because the thing is the models don't even care.
Scott: The person who made the manga is real good.
Scott: They also made silver spoon.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah, it's a good the manga.
Scott: I think might be the best version of it.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is I just finished eccentric family and yeah also.
Scott: Yeah, Oh Chikoku, but there wasn't as much Chikoku as you promised.
Scott: big episode and then there's a callback there is but that you promised more Chikoku than there was.
Rym: I guess I guess that I was just so much Chikoku like crammed in also.
Scott: That's my kind of Chikoku.
Scott: Yeah, it is the best cut the industrialization of hell.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's some good biz.
Rym: So in some other news we talked about this way back that Blizzard Is trying to do for real eSports like teammate like the new.
Scott: I wonder if it's because some Blizzard employees sat at a panel where we said that someone should do this.
Rym: Yeah, it might have been.
Scott: could we take credit for this?
Scott: I don't know But we did do a panel where we said a lot of these ideas and there were definitely Blizzard People in the audience at this panel and those are people who are smart.
Scott: That's all I can say like how they haven't spoken to me since I actually have no idea.
Scott: It's
Rym: kind of like how back at RIT we all of us made that we had this long-running joke about mosh mosh revolution and then like a few days later Mosh mosh revolution appeared in mega Tokyo and we're pretty sure that Ken Hashimoto the blur
Scott: You mean can quote the blur.
Scott: quote Hashimoto?
Rym: Yeah, Ken the blur Hashimoto.
Rym: Yes, pretty sure.
Scott: where is and what is Ken the blur Hashimoto doing?
Scott: Oh 2017?
Rym: Someone told me recently, but I forgot it all like some stuff happened with him.
Rym: I guess I don't know.
Rym: Maybe for all I know he's listening to this.
Rym: I would be very very sad the blur if you were listening to this.
Rym: email us.
Rym: I want to get you on the show.
Scott: Also, how do you feel about being called the blur?
Rym: I Feel like that was a badge of honor at least at one point I didn't think of as an insult.
Rym: that was just a descriptive nickname because he was the blur.
Scott: The thing is as the problem happens a lot is you have a nickname for someone that's not insulting But it's just describing of their personality and and you know personage, right?
Scott: Yeah, but you don't use it.
Scott: You don't call them that to their face.
Scott: So it feels like you shouldn't like Because you haven't done that.
Scott: it feels like you're insulting them.
Scott: plus, you know There are certain kinds of nicknames that are phrased in such a way that you could call someone that like if someone's nickname is stumps You could like yo stumps.
Scott: Yeah, but you can't be like yo.
Rym: the blur You know.
Rym: definite articles just don't work.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't work.
Scott: But anyway, I give isn't?
Scott: it was blurry.
Scott: I could be like a blurry.
Scott: what's going on?
Rym: That is not the news.
Rym: the news is that it's really it's.
Rym: it's really.
Rym: take it off for real because The owners of some of the teams are now known right?
Scott: So to become an owner you have to buy a team license from Blizzard or whatever for millions of dollars.
Scott: Yep, and then you now own a team.
Scott: Congratulations.
Rym: Jeff Wilpon who owns the New York Mets Now owns the New York team, which means we will never win anything and we will buy season tickets anyway.
Rym: Well, what'd you say?
Rym: We're gonna be.
Rym: we're gonna those two old dudes like 80 years from now.
Scott: Well now think about the Mets exit have only existed since 1962. there are people at least some who have had season tickets to the New York Mets since 1962 and they were probably 30-something years old then and now they're 80 years old.
Rym: I mean, I knew some people tangentially as a kid whose family had passed down like Red Wings.
Rym: season tickets forever, right?
Scott: So now this is art.
Scott: does every you know?
Scott: sports are a thing that you know.
Scott: They feel like they're so long like they've always been there.
Scott: It's like no.
Scott: the NBA is super new.
Scott: the Super Bowl is about as new as the Mets.
Scott: Right is not.
Scott: it's like MLS is actually a big deal and that's really new right?
Rym: Well, I mean look at.
Rym: so I tweeted the other day.
Rym: I was looking at magic and like the tiny percentage of magic I have played compared to all the magic that has happened in the many many many many years since I stopped playing It's like 20 years of magic.
Scott: Yeah, that's in a few sets a year Okay.
Scott: Anyway, but the point is we will buy season tickets to the New York overwatch, whatever they are.
Scott: Well, where they're?
Scott: fucking jerseys?
Rym: Yeah, I'll get a jersey.
Rym: Yeah a hundred percent.
Scott: I don't even play the goddamn game and I'm gonna go there and go woo in the Boston team.
Rym: They're the Boston team.
Rym: Robert Kraft who owns the New York New England Patriots bought that team.
Scott: Yeah, so 30 years from now our kids look like whoa, we inherited The kids we won't have yeah are gonna inherit tickets to all our friends kids This team with the great legacy the New York, whatever overwatch player.
Scott: They won four Reinhardt cups.
Scott: Yeah, the only the only thing is that I don't I really want it to be a thing that lasts a long time But I don't have confidence in any video game even counter-strike lasting as long as a game like baseball or hockey or Right.
Scott: Yeah So we're gonna go see this overwatch team and cheer for them and whatever.
Scott: And but then like 15 years now overwatch will be dead.
Rym: and this is the big debate.
Scott: What's gonna happen?
Rym: What will?
Rym: what is going to be the dominant model of eSports in the future?
Rym: Will it be a heterogeneous environment?
Rym: Will there be leagues that are multi or teams that are multi sport or that evolve over time?
Rym: Whether be leagues just based on individual games or it'll be leagues based on genres like the fighting game league and they play it like Multiple fighting games.
Scott: I wonder if like for example Street Fighter is already on Street Fighter 5 Evo just happened.
Scott: Yeah Someone I didn't want to win one, but that's whatever the.
Scott: Can they keep Street Fighter going forever by making Street Fighter 6 Street Fighter 7 Street Fighter 8?
Scott: Can they keep that going for literally eternity or super as long as baseball?
Rym: I mean today is like hockey version 9.
Scott: They've had Street Fighter going since you know, the 80s 90s, right?
Scott: So it's already been quite a while, but they got a long way to catch up to baseball levels.
Scott: Can they keep it going?
Scott: and if they can where they just get out like that if they can do it with Street Fighter Which I guess is the one that's furthest along.
Scott: I think it is the furthest along right then That means you can keep it going with counter-strike.
Scott: You can keep it going with League of Legends Going with overwatch by making overwatch 2, overwatch 3, overwatch 4, CS go, CS stop, CS run, CS walk.
Scott: Yeah, whatever you got to make right?
Rym: So this is news.
Rym: The other news I got is that apparently this seems to be like a recent thing.
Rym: It appears that the MLB May be in a trademark dispute with the Overwatch League about how similar their baseball man is to Tracer.
Scott: But the NBA Jerry West logo is more similar to the MLB logo.
Scott: It uses the same fucking colors.
Scott: Why would you try they just suing the Overwatch League because it's the same shape?
Rym: I think I am NOT a lawyer.
Rym: This is just my personal opinion that this is a sign that traditional sports are afraid of eSports.
Scott: I think that's just something that eSports people want to tell themselves.
Rym: I feel like if eSports were not on this like Significant money tide that's coming in MLB would have not even looked at this twice.
Scott: Mmm, cuz I like you definitely don't sue anyone who doesn't have any fucking money, right?
Scott: And this you're a patent troll.
Scott: Yeah You sue people who have money.
Scott: so that means that overwatch has enough money to be worth suing.
Scott: well Activision Blizzard Yeah, they have enough money to be worth doing.
Rym: I own a bunch of their stock.
Rym: Sure But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so we were just talking about the evolution of sports, right?
Rym: This is an article I'm not going to summarize all.
Rym: you should read it yourself But it shows a lot of examples and talks in depth about how dramatically Goalkeeping in hockey has changed just in recent years because of a few very specific and seemingly minor changes to the way Goal-tender equipment functions.
Scott: Yeah, people always talk about like I'm a goaltender said these giant pads.
Scott: They keep getting bigger and that was true.
Scott: But there have been recent some rules changes that have been made making them smaller in size, right?
Scott: But so the fact that they rotate around the leg the size matters much less than these other things That lay people do who just seek.
Scott: because a layperson looks at the giant pads looks at the old small pads It's like uh-huh that ruined goal tending.
Scott: That's why But a layperson doesn't see this.
Scott: But if you read this article and watch these videos, then you will see what lay people don't see.
Rym: you layperson you yep, and it's very important because like we said, you know overwatch to overwatch 3 or a street fighter with the with the with the eSports leagues regular sports keep changing the rules.
Rym: hockey like so many versions and this version of hockey today is more different than hockey of the old time days.
Rym: then Baseball like like all these sports change faster than video games do.
Rym: if you actually think about it it's just people think of sports as being very continuous and think of the tradition as being very static.
Rym: and Unless you're a superfan, you don't notice all these actually really big changes that occur.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So we got.
Scott: so everyone knows Bowling is kind of lame.
Rym: Yeah I took a bowling class and I got up to like 170 180 average after 10 weeks and I'm right back down to my 170 80 average.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway yeah, the bowling is the thing that people do in small-town America because there's nothing better to do and things you do a birthday parties or work parties because it's generic and Appropriate for all ages and accessible even if you suck at it.
Rym: We used to go to the bowling alley right near RIT a couple a couple times because there was a DDR machine there.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: We thought the DDR we didn't play.
Rym: they had like a max one machine there and all the other places had like fifth mix.
Scott: so but anyway It's all.
Scott: if you know anything about bowling you'll know that like they wax the bowling lanes otherwise, the ball wouldn't really roll too well and just some bare wood.
Scott: right.
Scott: it's waxed up and Because it's not just rolling.
Rym: It's also sliding Yep.
Scott: So the thing is bowling lanes based on the machine that waxes them or if they're waxed by hand, which I don't think anyone does They have a different pattern of wax.
Scott: and that pattern of wax that is on the bowling alley Significantly influences the ball movement which to a normal person doesn't matter.
Scott: But if you're a pro who's got a bowl of strike almost every time or at least a spare that small You know way in which the wax moves the ball around is the difference between a spare and a nine and that's enormous.
Scott: You know, it's there's doing a strike and a nine right because the ball is just an inch to the right or an inch to The left because that wax.
Rym: well think of it.
Scott: if the wax were perfectly uniform Pretty much any confident bowler could do a 300 If the wax was a hundred percent the same on every bowling alley ever and it was always perfect every time.
Scott: all you had to do is practice this thing and practice it so much that you could Perfectly repeat it every single time like line your foot up with the markers stand at the exact same distance Do the exact same moves
Rym: like the bowling in Breath of the Wild with the
Scott: snow and it's like a human can achieve that if they?
Scott: Put enough effort into it.
Scott: It's called pitching in baseball, right?
Scott: They throw the ball in almost the exact same spot at a ludicrous speed by and they get there and they do it by Practicing and doing it over and over again, right?
Scott: So the fact that wax is different is what makes bowling at all challenging Which is actually kind of interesting because what sports do we have where the in?
Scott: not your equipment not yourself But the environment.
Scott: hockey the ice the ice and hockey makes a difference.
Scott: the field and baseball actually makes a significant difference.
Rym: The fields are different to like in different places like they're shaped differently in different football.
Scott: You have grass and turf and the crowd influences a little and every any spectator.
Scott: sport the crowd influences except for the annoying country Club ones like bowling golf tennis where you're supposed to be quiet.
Scott: right tennis.
Scott: You got the clay composite grass situation, right?
Scott: But In bowling, I think it might be matter like the most directly and obviously Partly cuz.
Rym: there's not much else that could matter right?
Rym: There's not that much like I'm not saying the I 70 or 80 like I'm not a good bowler.
Scott: the pins do not matter in bowling is yeah There's only so many factors that matter you the ball in the lane and the wax in the lane and that's it.
Scott: So If you we always knew that this is a thing the wax but I didn't actually know the details of the wax.
Scott: How does it matter?
Scott: How is it apply all this stuff?
Scott: So Here's a great video explaining everything that a normal non bowling person needs to know about bowling wax.
Scott: It's really interesting.
Scott: if you care about even if you just care about games And sports even if you don't care about bowling itself, it's still interesting.
Scott: Yeah, it's worth your time to watch this.
Rym: It's in the in the moment.
Rym: The book club book is Frank Herbert's doing.
Scott: I have finished reading this book as have I so Tomorrow we're gonna work.
Scott: Well tomorrow you're listening to this probably on Wednesday.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: Yeah, it's we're releasing this Tuesday night.
Scott: There's nine people listening to it right now, I guess most people will listen to this Wednesday, which means that Thursday we're gonna record an episode about dune and announce the next book club and Probably listen to that on Friday because it's a book club episode.
Rym: We're gonna assume anyone who listens to it read the book.
Scott: Yep, that's how we're
Rym: gonna talk about it
Scott: And I'm sure since this is one of the most famous nerd books of
Rym: are gonna be real mad about our opinion
Scott: Because we also have a board game that is related to this and I haven't played the RTS So I can't really say anything about that.
Scott: Yeah, even though that was one of the first real RTS games ever We're gonna have a lot to say about this.
Scott: So you should listen.
Rym: I think it tells the exact same story as Hyperion but much more simply.
Scott: Oh, it's similar to Hyperion.
Rym: Yeah Well very specific things are similar and what how much?
Scott: well how much of Hyperion was inspired from dude?
Rym: I think I'll significant.
Rym: I think the core premise was inspired maybe of Humanities path and evolution and also that shut thou shall not disfigure the soul.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That is stuff That's heavily cribbed in Prince of Nothing.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but All I want to say is that a lot of you over the years who have given me flag for not having really read dune Have implied that this book is way more complex than it was.
Scott: Well, I think also just because something is some epic ultra-famous nerd book it gets like this huge Reputation that it has to like uphold right and the reputation comes after you write it not before.
Scott: so it's like who can you blame?
Scott: On this right?
Scott: It's just like you know.
Scott: When so many nerds prop something up you start to look at the nerds and not at the thing.
Rym: true true But just the characters were the opposite of inscrutable.
Rym: Oh What's the Baron?
Rym: our Conan won?
Rym: he wants little boys to rape and he's a bad guy.
Scott: He wants Monet and power.
Rym: He wants to keep his line going because of his own stupid reasons.
Scott: He's also not actually that smart and he's won spies cuz everyone wants fun.
Scott: Yeah, he's hoarding it and he's bad.
Rym: That's that's the extent of the complexity of that character.
Rym: and the bad guy Favorite my favorite.
Rym: He's my favorite in the game.
Rym: I think I want to always play the Harkonnen in the game.
Rym: My favorite character is actually Kynes Keens.
Rym: Well, yeah, Leah Keens the ecologist.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think he's my favorite character other than maybe Stilgar Still guys.
Scott: All right, my favorite guys.
Rym: really Jessica a lot.
Scott: I thought your favorite guy would be Bard guy.
Scott: Oh, yeah Gurney.
Rym: Yeah, Gurney's a super great dude.
Rym: Yeah, Gurney is like he's a multi-class fighter Bard And he's pretty high level too.
Rym: Anyway, we will talk about dune in depth on the next show.
Rym: and the other important meta thing other than things We've already talked about is that a big part of why I had the idea to do the show we're about to do.
Rym: the topic is that I have listened to a Lot of the board game reviews that GeekNights has done over the years some of them from as far back as 2006 2007 well And some of them more recently and I noticed a lot about the way we review board games And we've gone through like Almost five sort of distinct eras of what we focus on and how we review the game.
Scott: Well, unlike some, you know journalistic outlets that actually care about reviewing with some sort of integrity or whatever.
Scott: Well, they Yeah, they Pretending to have object.
Scott: Yeah They tend to have a format or a process for reviewing like a checklist of things your review has to do Right and some of them even have scores and categories and shit and we don't do anything.
Scott: We just talk about something for 20 to 30 minutes.
Scott: Yep, and So our formats have you know, like, you know, we might not forget to talk about an aspect of something or whatever.
Scott: You know It just happens.
Rym: but the thing was interesting.
Rym: is that much like with anime and everything else when we started GeekNights We were fresh out of university.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and we had consumed a lot of media a lot of games A lot of stuff in our entire lives up to that point.
Rym: So we had a backlog of things we could review that we had immense experience with.
Rym: So like when we started reviewing board games like we reviewed Puerto Rico on GeekNights We had already played it more than a hundred times.
Rym: Mm-hmm when we reviewed Carcassonne or settlers we had played them to the point that we had solved them.
Scott: So all those early that's true is that we were reviewing.
Scott: we were reviewing a game, right?
Scott: We were basically.
Scott: the first episode of GeekNights was in 2005.
Scott: It had at least five years of material to work with.
Scott: now, even if we take a break for a vacation, it's like, okay great We've got an extra two weeks of material to work of things.
Scott: We haven't talked about yet.
Scott: Once we drained that five-year pool of material, right?
Scott: It's like now it's just a trickle.
Rym: but the trouble was that are the.
Rym: When we gave reviews that were good like in my opinion having listen to a bunch of them done some pretty mediocre reviews occasionally.
Scott: Yeah in a thousand something episodes most of them are crap in fact by all of them.
Scott: Some are slightly less crap, but they all crap.
Rym: But our best reviews were when we'd played a game so much that we had a deep Intuitive understanding of all the mechanics of the game.
Rym: Yep So I noticed that our reviews did follow a pretty specific format.
Rym: We talked about the premise then we talked about the rules themselves and whether or not they were well written or consistent The learning experience the initial play experience.
Rym: and then we talked about the end game.
Rym: Like how long will it take to get to the end game?
Rym: What is the end game?
Rym: Is there an end game?
Rym: When will the game be done?
Rym: Mm-hmm and that our.
Scott: what's the most you can get out of this game?
Scott: yep, and you really invest your soul into it.
Rym: and the games that we Liked the most and continue to still like where the games that we invested our souls into we're not just that were the games that after 20 or more plays We had not we had still not plumbed the depths.
Rym: Mm-hmm and the rules to those games were Relatively elegant or simple or airtight.
Rym: Yeah games that were Complex or we hadn't solved that were only not solved because there are a billion different kinds of cards We lost interest in pretty quick.
Rym: But games like like Hans the Teutonic is a good example of a much more recent game that had all those aspects that we liked so much in the games that we lauded in the 15 years of doing GeekNights.
Scott: Danica isn't really a new game.
Scott: It's just new to us.
Rym: Well, I mean it's the time I'm just gonna be like three years ago.
Rym: Maybe four is the most recent game we've reviewed where I can say confidently that we know you just reviewed race to the galaxy a game We've played a time.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it's the most recent game that was published that we've reviewed Fully.
Rym: hmm in my opinion like with that level of deepness.
Scott: After that, I think the other thing is a lot of the games you review games You've played more recently like we did one potion explosion, right?
Rym: Well, we only.
Rym: so that's that's the other thing.
Scott: It's like we played that game a few times, but there's nothing more to get out of it.
Scott: So we did like even though our review might not have been the greatest review you could do I think it was not like what?
Scott: Yeah, what else could we possibly say?
Scott: There's no reason to play that game any more than we have.
Rym: so I want to say our reviews there.
Scott: So the first reviews were doing you can do a better review of a better game because you can play a better game more And a better game usually has more to say about it.
Rym: But it shows how we evolved in terms of understanding games because they aren't.
Rym: for years We only reviewed games that we had played ad nauseam Or games that we played once and hate it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And usually we'd say yeah, we played this once we hate it Like we did that to innovation.
Rym: We're like, ah, yeah, I'm sure.
Scott: yeah, I'm sure even though I don't like innovation I don't want to play it.
Scott: I'm sure if we played it a bunch more Begrudgingly that we could find a lot more to say about it and do a better.
Rym: Identically to Twilight struggle it there they're in the same class.
Scott: if we played a bunch of Twilight struggle we could definitely do a much better review of it
Rym: and But at the same time
Scott: I have no desire to do so still
Rym: served its purpose because even games We don't like we tend to do a good job of describing who the game would be for like.
Rym: If you like this you'll like this game if you're like for us.
Rym: Yep But then we entered this era where we were doing GeekNights like much more fervently, but we tapped that cue Like.
Rym: so we started buying new games to play them to review and what I noticed there I didn't do that was buying games to play them.
Rym: Yeah But we also like would make a point of like tub Reviewing them as we played them to figure them out so that we'd be capable of doing review.
Rym: But back then we still had a lot of free time so we could sort of do that.
Rym: So we'd say we play the games like at least ten times before we'd review them, but we wouldn't play them a hundred times now.
Rym: There was a the air after.
Rym: that is where we got really the most interesting because we finally learned enough about games and we started Doing this around like 2009.
Rym: I want to say okay where We seem to read the rules of a game play it half-assedly once Pretty much be 90% sure of our review and maybe play it one more time just to make sure we're not wrong.
Rym: Mm-hmm and We were incapable of doing that for a long time And I think we just learned a lot about games.
Rym: and once you play enough games like potion explosion You can see what's going on in that game real quick There's.
Rym: we could literally not say more about the game by playing it more But it.
Rym: but had we reviewed potion explosion say back in 2006 I think we would had to play it like ten more times to realize the things we realized about it.
Rym: Yeah, and nowadays, uh We just struggle to get together a group of people outside of conventions who are willing to play super serious games super seriously Repeatedly.
Scott: and the thing is our problem isn't that we lack friends?
Scott: is that everyone is actually doing other things in life.
Rym: for reals We're like we're.
Rym: we're shockingly busy.
Scott: Well, I just like I'd rather go biking then go and play a board game.
Rym: Yeah, well partly cuz it's summer.
Rym: Yes, we got some plans though.
Rym: There's there's some tentative plans of doing a writer's retreat at some point whereas I a small group of dangerous people are gonna get together and play like 15 games and review the fuck out of without stop and play tons of games.
Rym: That'll be review con.
Scott: Yeah game publishers.
Scott: Usually I don't ask for free review copies of games and especially when people people have called us mostly with books They want us to talk to the authors on the GeekNights and stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I always turn them the fuck down.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: actually I don't say no, but I'm like is like look you can send us all the free shit you want.
Scott: There is no guarantee that we'll review it.
Scott: There's no guarantee we'll review it positively.
Scott: if we do review it I promise you basically nothing.
Scott: but feel free to send me free stuff if you want.
Scott: And that basically is the same thing as no don't send me free stuff, right?
Rym: Well, actually the publisher offered to send us pen Dante too because we didn't actually own it.
Rym: Sure, but I didn't.
Scott: You are a board game publisher We are we're.
Scott: if we do this legit, right don't send it to us until we say we're doing this But we're.
Scott: if we do this legit, then I promise you that if you send us a game And we will play it there at least sometimes and we will review it 100% honestly if you're ready to deal with that
Rym: like to the rule that we offer to people to pay us money to do
Scott: and We will even send you the game fucking back because I don't want to keep it in my house.
Scott: Yeah, if we don't like it.
Scott: Yeah, you know what if I do like the game and I want to keep it I'll even give you the money to buy the game from you.
Scott: Yeah, right if I would have bought it otherwise Right, well, you know now I'm not gonna I'm not gonna buy before I try is what I'm saying for another board game in my very Small apartment.
Scott: So so no one out there.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: So nowadays it with our current knowledge of games and you know Like we've literally we've done this a few times.
Rym: We've put some reviews up on GeekNights where we literally just read the rules.
Rym: That was all we did.
Scott: Sometimes it's all you need.
Scott: Yeah, so some people get real mad about that, right?
Scott: There was a thread on the board games reddit actually recently that was like so mad at like reviewers Like not playing the game enough and stuff like that.
Scott: and it's like look, you know, you know on this.
Scott: on the one hand It's true.
Scott: You shouldn't judge a book by its cover.
Scott: This is why we do the judge anime by its cover panel, right and we say this at that panel The rule book is the whole book.
Scott: That's what listen, you know Judging anything by its cover.
Scott: It's true You shouldn't judge things by their cover because you will not always be right.
Scott: you will often be.
Scott: you know Oh, this looks like crap.
Scott: And then if you actually had played it you would have realized.
Scott: Oh, no, it was great.
Scott: You look at some food.
Scott: that food looks ugly.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: It tastes delicious.
Scott: It was what's that green slime?
Scott: It's guac.
Scott: You just did.
Scott: you just judged it by how it looked.
Scott: what's wrong with you?
Scott: Yeah But at the same time the fact is if you judge things by their cover You will be right.
Scott: like 90 plus percent of the time.
Scott: romance novels look like romance novels.
Scott: trashy sci-fi books look like Travis.
Scott: I've had books right pulp fight and fantasy novels look like pulp fantasy novels almost all the time.
Scott: You can judge things by how they look almost all the time.
Scott: so if you judge something based on one playthrough or a reading of the rules and it's a game and Depending on how much your understanding of games is and we're gonna just you know Be I guess arrogant and say we have an amazing understanding of games.
Scott: We're great.
Scott: Yeah, if you we can we are skilled talented and knowledgeable enough to judge things in areas where we are experts with less Experience.
Rym: with the same point.
Rym: I looked we we reviewed eccentric family on judge anime by its cover.
Rym: You know we said mm-hmm exactly 100% correct.
Rym: All right show is exactly what we said.
Rym: It would be terrific.
Rym: So today When we review games, I've we definitely Review games from the perspective of people like us.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, that's how everyone reviews things.
Rym: They review it from the perspective of people like them Yep And the but a lot of people try to pretend they don't which is kind of.
Scott: I will sometimes Remember to say things like if you're this kind of person though, you might like this like there's a lot of games I know that are like all theme and no substance.
Scott: and if I look if you really love that Like, you know this fucking theme you'll probably love this shit.
Scott: But I don't like.
Scott: if you're some, you know, I'll be like, oh if you're a grognard, you'll love this Twilight struggle, but I don't.
Rym: But I've also noticed that the specific factors we look for in a tabletop game are actually pretty simple.
Rym: are the rules Well written is like are they unambiguous?
Rym: Like that is number one.
Scott: I need to go to board game geek for a fact.
Rym: But if there if the rules to a game are ambiguous like usually we don't even review it.
Rym: We just like cut it out of our brains and never look at it again.
Scott: Yeah, like there's unplayable garbage.
Rym: It's like I picked up.
Scott: that's like trying to play a game on Steam and it crashes.
Rym: It's like yep Literally picked up games at PAX like I'll grab random games sometimes just start reading the rules to see if we'll play it at The table like between things and I put them back when I couldn't resolve a rule question on my own reading.
Rym: Mm-hmm Number two is there's two sort of kinds of games.
Rym: We look at German style like Euro tabletop games.
Rym: So that's mostly what we review.
Rym: Are they primarily?
Rym: Optimization or machine driven or are they primarily?
Rym: exploratory meaning?
Rym: are there dense mechanics that you're expected to explore and play repeatedly to understand?
Rym: or are there Mechanics that you can logically figure out and build complex machines in your head with mm-hmm?
Scott: He takers in your phrase is exploratory, right?
Scott: You have a few pieces to work with placing tiles catastrophes Monuments, right and you have to explore different ways to use those pieces as you play it multiple times.
Scott: Right, and that's how the game works.
Scott: But if you look at a game like say Puerto Rico, it's like well There's nothing to explore.
Scott: You can see all the buildings right there.
Scott: Yeah, you just had to figure out or Agricola or any of these types of games, right?
Scott: It's like alright Here's all the pieces.
Scott: They're spelled out in English What?
Scott: how to build an optimal machine given the fact that you're competing for machine parts with other people and such and such and Such and all these cards and stuff, you know?
Scott: And in and then when do you start cranking that machine to spin out victory points?
Scott: and how hard can you crank it?
Rym: If a game is exploratory We expect it to be elegant meaning The fewest number of rules to achieve the most complexity with those rules.
Rym: So if a game is super complex, but it has a billion unique cards to make it complex.
Rym: F that noise That's an that's inelegant complexity.
Scott: That's that's like.
Scott: that's like a lot of PC games.
Rym: Oh my god I wish I could quote it.
Rym: There was a talk at PAX dev last year actually on this topic That was super great.
Scott: Like if you look at a lot of 5x games or 4x games on the PC or like, you know Europe universalis is the greatest.
Scott: That is a deep and complex game sure But it's like it's just tons and tons of numbers and graphs and so much Shit, it's like you cannot put all of that information into a human brain unless you're you know, especially powered.
Scott: Yeah, right much more smarter than I am Smarter that you'll say you won't say stupid things like more smarter.
Rym: but any sort of game that has that sort of exploratory bent to it if The mechanics are too complicated in light of how complicated the actual strategies are That is that is our main criteria I think like above all others and I think secondary to that is the fun economy because even if the game is dumb and broken and everything if it's short and we had a Moderate amount of fun in that very short time.
Rym: Well also rated very highly even if it fails all these other categories.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's a lot of games like that because especially, you know, just the social situations that we're in.
Scott: You know you get a game like say red seven like not a masterpiece by any means but it's like oh But it's fun enough for five minutes that it takes to play and it's like a calm.
Scott: played again I could play the red seven right the fuck now.
Rym: So a game that has reasonable like a game that has high depth low complexity to achieve that depth Short time play like time span to play but a good experience in that time That's like the perfectly designed game our like basic rubric, right?
Scott: It's all.
Scott: it's all about.
Scott: you know in.
Scott: you know How much you have to invest to play the game versus what you get out of it, right?
Scott: So you only have to invest a little bit.
Scott: You don't need to get that much out for it to be good and worth your time.
Scott: if you have to invest a lot To get you know, not so much, you know, that's not so great.
Scott: You know eat like.
Scott: so I think what happens?
Scott: I think there are a lot of games out there where you still have a positive experience playing them, right?
Scott: So if you you invest like an hour of time and a bunch of work studying rules and you get fun out of it It's like positive experience.
Scott: It's a good time and I think other people would be like, wow This is a really good time and they'll rate it really highly.
Scott: where I'll be like, no, it wasn't worth the trouble Even though it's good, right?
Scott: We'll rate that game badly.
Scott: Whereas other people won't.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We also there's the if a game is reactive or not meaning if there's multiple players How interactive is the game and how much do you have to react to what other players are doing?
Rym: Like how much do other players affect the state of the game?
Scott: We're definitely you know, that's just our personal taste I think is we don't tend to like games that are straight races as much.
Scott: Yep, right.
Rym: They're good filler games Like.
Rym: I actually liked that America game where we were just like writing.
Scott: that's not a race This computer competing for the spots in turn order.
Rym: No, no, no, no, not that not the trivia game the one with like you're right the numbers on the map.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's just a race.
Rym: That's just a solitaire race.
Scott: Oh, yeah, we didn't talk about that game on the show.
Rym: Oh, no, we didn't but I think we did.
Scott: Yeah, you know a race, you know You're not supposed to touch the other racers when you're doing 100 meter - right?
Scott: There's a lot of board games and other video games Competitive games in general that are just races where it's like everyone's playing solitaire and at the end who does the best solitaire?
Rym: Right that has a time and place.
Rym: like if you have if you want a game that holds a large number of players That is the optimal way to do it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and there's that there's a time and a place for that.
Scott: Candyland Is that never everyone's playing Candyland at the same time and whoever gets to the end first wins.
Scott: So the game is literally a race.
Rym: if a game is a race We sort of review it from the perspective of.
Rym: is the puzzle I am working on myself fun Mm-hmm, and is the socialization that occurs around that mechanic fun?
Scott: And also how many times is solving the puzzle gonna be fun, right?
Scott: Or if I've played it once if I is that ball I need I don't need to play it again because I've already figured out Rolling America, that's the name of that one.
Rym: I've already figured Chris and Pat both simultaneously.
Rym: We're like rolling America, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: have I already figured out the fastest way to run this race?
Scott: Well, then I never need to run it again.
Rym: But if a game is interaction with other people Right as the Judonica and Tigger's new phrases are good examples there in that pretty much every most games most multiplayer game but if it's highly interactive I've noticed we Heavily dislike games that are also highly political Mm-hmm, like.
Scott: well, every game is technically political it is but you can do based on the rules.
Scott: The influence of the politics can be higher or lower.
Rym: Well, like Hansa, Judonica and Puerto Rico are both good examples of games that are like.
Rym: the actions You're going to take are deeply dependent upon the game state created by the decisions.
Rym: Everyone else is made.
Scott: But you know Hansa is highly political, right?
Scott: It's like I can choose to attack Rym by messing with him But I think it's actually way less political.
Rym: but you can't.
Scott: There's a limit to your power and how much you can mess.
Scott: you would need to have unity gang up on someone to ruin them And most you can't really afford to gang up on someone and sacrifice your own biz Whereas something like I'm not gonna say diplomacy something else like the scythe game, which is basically diplomacy.
Scott: Yeah, right That's just basically a hundred percent political.
Scott: It's really the vote who wins.
Rym: You said I we like games that are highly interactive But have minimal Political.
Scott: there is still political interaction But your ability to the influence the influence of the political interaction on the victory condition is lesser Right than it could be because the rules are restrictive.
Rym: Yeah, so the more the more the politics turns into risk the less we're interested in it.
Rym: Mm-hmm in terms of the machine games like, you know the straight-up crank the machine like Sulkin like that kind of game.
Rym: you literally crank the berserk in here.
Scott: Literally crank it.
Rym: Yeah, I do like Salkin.
Scott: I only played it half a time.
Rym: I played it three times now and I actually like it more.
Scott: Yeah I'm definitely something up.
Rym: We should play this out.
Scott: I feel it.
Rym: Let's play it.
Rym: I don't want to buy it, but I'm sure it'll be there.
Scott: I definitely have room to keep it.
Rym: No, but I crystal skulls them or Kayla's any kind of game where there's sort of a machine of any kind that you can make.
Rym: I noticed we tend to prefer the games where there are a. There are multiple paths to victory and some nuance to how you Optimize between them because I've noticed a lot of the games we don't like that We never reviewed on GeekNights because we're playing once in a packs and we're just not excited about them tend to be machine games.
Rym: A lot of them have trained themes.
Rym: I've noticed.
Rym: Mm-hmm where There are like three ways to go and they're basically all mutually exclusive.
Rym: Yeah, this I go after the gold points or the potion points or the hat points.
Rym: But if you do one hat and three potions, there's literally no way you can win.
Scott: Yeah, it's like we've.
Scott: we've built three efficient.
Scott: There's a bunch of pieces here to build machines with right and it's basically three machines.
Scott: If you tried to build any one of the three machines, they're all pretty much equally efficient.
Scott: But if you try to build a combination of more than one machine The efficiency is gone and you're not gonna get enough points if someone else just concentrates on one machine.
Scott: Yeah, that's the first problem.
Scott: Another problem is some games.
Scott: They have multiple machines or ways to build the machine But one of them is vastly more efficient than the others and off usually there's not enough parts to go around.
Scott: So one person gets the efficient machine and everyone else gets a subpar machine and they've already been there already.
Scott: the winner as soon As they held that one.
Scott: I made the first baby in a curricula.
Scott: Well, you're not guaranteed to win but that's like you're far along Much further along than the other players.
Scott: Yeah What are the other?
Scott: but you know a good machine building game has many different and interesting ways to build the machine in different combinations that can all work.
Scott: and Also, they offer ways.
Scott: for example Maybe I realize in some games like maybe in race to the gals about I think that's where I was going.
Scott: Galaxy, maybe I realize huh?
Scott: Rims got an efficient machine going.
Scott: my machine is much less efficient But now you know what rooms gonna do it because my machine is less efficient.
Scott: Maybe I can crank it harder Starting earlier and get as many victory points.
Scott: at the moment the game ends.
Scott: So I'll just start going.
Scott: consume consume consume consume because I can't do what he's doing.
Rym: Yeah, and there's another way to go.
Rym: you see that I'm doing a strategy where I'll be producing semi regularly So you can assume that that'll happen.
Rym: never produce and build around using the fruits of production.
Scott: Yep, so you find some other way.
Scott: There's always some other way to win and the gate.
Scott: we don't like games that you know.
Scott: It's the thing we think I've complained about and a lot of reviews like this game ends before it ends.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of games have that problem.
Rym: It's super common look at gate like look at when we play Puerto Rico or Tigris new Freighties or honestly The game is up in the air until like the second to last turn pretty close to the end.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, Hanza in particular ends up often being shockingly close.
Rym: Yeah, it's where you know, even though Hanza has problems It's not my favorite game.
Rym: I use it as an example because what it is Shockingly elegant in what it has accomplished in terms of barely political player interaction Especially among skilled players because there is a cost to playing highly public.
Scott: if you play that game politically you tear yourself down Deeply and usually the way to accomplish this when you make a game is to do is to is it goes hand in hand with?
Scott: Another thing I complain about which is games often have like big pieces like in Puerto Rico.
Rym: you big Park steampunk has.
Rym: well steampunk has physically big pieces for no good reason, right?
Scott: And it has things you'll never build but it's like, you know There's always like the big guy like in magic the gathering you have like the big creature Right the legend that takes black and green.
Scott: Yeah There'll be something, you know, just something big right and usually a good game.
Scott: you can play the big thing close to the end and Use it a few times and then the game ends.
Scott: and that is a good thing because it means you can actually be behind most of the game and invest in building the big thing as an alternative to just playing efficiently throughout the game and that Big thing will come out and actually do some work before the game ends Thus allowing you to possibly catch up to the people who were playing the smaller or other medium-sized strategies, right?
Scott: Yeah, whereas a lot of games I've noticed you can't even play the big thing Unless it's a miracle.
Scott: and even if you do play the big thing like that will be the last turn of the game and you'll Maybe use it once if you're lucky.
Scott: and that's you know, what was it?
Scott: Oh my good I just will not have put that thing in the game.
Rym: Oh my goods doesn't have that have the rule where at the end of the game you crank your machine twice.
Scott: Yeah, and oh my goods.
Scott: It's like at the very end of the game.
Scott: Everyone gets to crank their machine one extra time.
Scott: So it really gives you that incentive like oh you can build something really big at the end of the game.
Scott: I made a bunch of windows And actually use them and not just have the game end on you.
Rym: Yep, cuz I remember Kayla.
Scott: That's the thing that we really like.
Rym: like Kayla's feel that arguably the first worker placement game Which we were obsessed with because back when it came out the first worker placement game arguably it is Really?
Rym: worker placement game.
Scott: before there had to be name one there had to be.
Scott: that can't be the first worker placement game.
Scott: There's no way.
Rym: What was the first worker placement game?
Rym: Kayla's really.
Rym: Maybe there's an old game called bus that might have predated it really but bus is from 1999.
Scott: Kayla's really the first I did.
Rym: we've talked Whoa Valley of the Mammoths, that's the one.
Rym: I forgot about that.
Rym: So I never.
Scott: I never heard of that.
Rym: That's all this from 91.
Scott: I never seen that in my life.
Rym: I don't know if I've.
Rym: I Don't know if I've seen this game or not.
Rym: I've never.
Scott: I've never seen that.
Rym: I think my brain is conflating but my brain wants pictures with tempest.
Scott: Yeah, they're not but my brain wants to play it.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely looks like.
Rym: I want to play that.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I want to play tempest again - it's been a while.
Scott: I'll play tempest and Vinci.
Rym: Yeah But yeah, so that game had the problem where there are a bunch of big things that you pretty much never be able to build You're not gonna get that much stone ever.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So unless you get the miracle play.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So Otherwise, I think the main thing that we've reviewed pretty heavily is you sort of get a sense of One whether or not they actually play tested their fucking game.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and two whether or not they play tested with a wide audience.
Rym: because a lot of new tabletop games partly because the industry sort of been democratized and a lot of people like The barrier to entry to tabletop is pretty low these days.
Scott: There was a thread on working geek reddit about that.
Scott: was some guy was like with no evidence whatsoever By the way was claiming that listen you guys keep complaining about Kickstarter exclusive shit.
Scott: But you have to include exclusive shit on your Kickstarter or people won't buy your Kickstarter.
Scott: they'll just wait for the regular edition because it's the same damn thing and it's like You don't have any evidence of that.
Scott: Show me the sales figures.
Scott: Yeah right but in that thread.
Scott: The thing that's relevant is so many people in that thread so much of the people in the board game hobby in the community are really really interested and like fancy pieces and And the construction of the games and extra minis.
Rym: We basically don't care about that at all and we give no I give me the.
Rym: you know what I say about that.
Rym: Usually if the pieces are particularly amazing We'll say the game's really well constructed.
Scott: Yeah, but like I give no shits about that whatsoever Give me the cardboard shits.
Scott: Give me the you know, the plain old dice.
Scott: I don't give it's I care about.
Rym: You know what I'll complain about.
Rym: I rarely like paper money because it's a pain in the ass.
Scott: Sure, right and some you know We talked.
Scott: we do talk about construction a little bit.
Scott: only if all their board game reviewers talk about construction.
Scott: a lot Your factor for them and a lot of people buy and enjoy board games Based on the construction and we give almost that factors into our view like almost not at all.
Scott: So yeah, there's a lot of shitty games out there site that are really ridiculously on you know Undeservingly popular because of their construction getting them a huge amount of sales.
Rym: Well, it's like all those anime because they talk about the liner notes and the quality of the truck.
Scott: that right I also think what happens is that a game with quality construction gets big sales from that part of the community.
Scott: and Because now the game is popular and everywhere.
Scott: It's spilled, you know, it's yeah, it spills over into That terrible Ghostbusters game.
Rym: cuz it's a.
Scott: I don't think that many people bought it.
Rym: So it's a lot of people bought it like a lot how many?
Rym: but well they all bought it on the Kickstarter.
Scott: No one bought it after that guys to this day.
Rym: I've never seen someone play it at a con Ever.
Scott: no, because it's not that many of us.
Rym: they bought it for the pieces Which aren't even that paintable as far as I can tell.
Scott: we give no shits about peace.
Rym: Yeah, so basically it'll be a. it'll be like it'll be a negative if the pieces in like hinder the gameplay in some way.
Rym: Oh, yeah We'll actually talk a lot more about graphic design than the physical construction because a lot of games have graphic design.
Rym: That is very poor.
Scott: sentinels a multiverse.
Scott: Your art is the worst.
Scott: I don't know I can't.
Scott: I mean, it's not though.
Scott: Literally the word is not great.
Scott: It's awful.
Scott: Why can't people just admit it and come out with it?
Scott: I'm like the only one who notices like.
Scott: I feel like I'm like it's one of those situations.
Scott: Yeah, like it's like a. they live Where I'm like.
Scott: people think this art is good.
Scott: It's like Overall.
Scott: I know that I can't draw for shit but like if I practiced drawing For like a month I could do better Sentinels.
Rym: is that the graphic design of like?
Rym: the you like the UX like the way the cards are actually laid out just is not.
Scott: It's not a good game, right?
Scott: And it's not good.
Rym: the character art It's not.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: just.
Rym: not so much that it's bad is that it's way like it goes off model like anytime I see it Like everyone looks like they're drawn differently.
Scott: Listen, Rob Liefeld draws better than whoever draws.
Rym: I'm not saying I'm talking about the graphic design of like.
Rym: was that game we played where you have the nobles like the Vienna Hotel or something?
Rym: That was okay.
Rym: Yeah, but the design of the cards made it off Hotel to read.
Scott: I didn't have a problem with what they were.
Scott: so I have a problem with like old glory to Rome old printing.
Rym: Well, that's that so old glory to Rome Physically hurts my brain to look at.
Scott: that's what I'm saying.
Rym: But a lot of games just have Poorly done like subtle parts of their graphic design like the sewer card in the new glory to Rome.
Scott: Yeah, that's I mean, but that doesn't it.
Scott: that just hurts your eye But it doesn't make it impossible to play in any way.
Rym: Yeah, but then there's also a lot of games that poorly distinguish aspects of the board that are interactive or relevant to the game.
Scott: Is that country bordering that country?
Scott: How many games do you have to ask that question?
Rym: Yeah Why did you use a cursive script to describe the names of those people that I need to look up constantly in this game?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So that's a problem.
Scott: But otherwise, why did you use that font?
Scott: That's not legible.
Rym: Yeah, where'd you even get that fun?
Rym: You went out of your way to find the worst possible.
Scott: Is that a one or a seven?
Rym: And What else?
Rym: what else we care about that?
Rym: because that's pretty much it the play testing things probably in the end one of the most critical ones because You can sort of tell right away if a game wasn't play.
Rym: tested that thoroughly.
Scott: You can definitely tell right away when the game says right on the front this we didn't notice this at all But because that game was honest, it was good.
Scott: We should make a game.
Scott: I wonder if we can get sued if we made a game that saying we play tested this way too goddamn much We play tested that fuck out of this game And that's the name of the game.
Rym: is we play tested the fuck out of this and think but they make the games So utterly simple that that's why it's perfect because there's barely a game there.
Rym: No, it's cops And it's just.
Rym: it's just white cards with the numbers printed on them, yes Really?
Rym: That would be a really nice font though.
Scott: We can make them like the best goddamn cards, right?
Scott: We'd have the red the red deck and the blue deck for the players and then the gold deck would be the points that you Bit up.
Scott: they'd be nice and big and we like me old lead to make it nice and even instead of going to 13 We'll go to 15.
Rym: Yeah, I Don't know we'd have to play.
Rym: test that.
Scott: Yeah, we play.
Scott: test the fuck out of it.
Rym: so yeah, that's how we review games and I cut.
Rym: that's why part of our that idea of having our own private review con Really tickles my fancy because that could push our geek nudge reviews into yet a new era of reviewing Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean it would get us episodes for at least half a year.
Rym: Oh, yeah Plus obviously, you know We do is.
Rym: we'd also like just record the audio of the entire time.
Rym: We're playing the game live stream the entire time.
Scott: We're playing the game.
Rym: I could be fun.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so we'll see that might be the the other con that we run the tiny one.
Rym: That's just us.
Scott: Anyway, that's it's not a con.
Rym: It's it could be a con.
Rym: It's our writers.
Rym: retreat.
Scott: I'm hungry.
Rym: Leave the writers retreat.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon page runs.
Rym: with this episode of GeekNights are Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas on my stady comm Willie maestro's Jeremy minor.
Rym: Life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth.
Rym: a genuine bonafide like about six car monorail Nicholas Brando chappin Captain Chinguakasi Rebecca done the terrible secret of space for to one creations.
Rym: That's because they're fighting each other.
Rym: sure who done horrible?
Rym: rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy.
Rym: I made paid five bucks to make room say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich.
Rym: It's our top vision Joe sure Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Renford New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew up and Lander Brian Cedroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn and a bunch of other people actually a lot of people who do not want to get credited.
Rym: So like I said So a bunch of rimbly reviews are coming down the pipe a bunch of talk about heuristics and the rims rants.
Rym: I got a whole ton of board game videos that I'm gonna upload and Stuff's coming now that we're done with ConnectiCon.
Rym: so stay tuned for Ggx which we're working on actively and there's a tiny chance.
Rym: There'll be a pre beta event in 2018 And then the real event will start in 2019.
Rym: But anyway now I leave you with Looking pretty good home star.
Scott: come up here right now.
Scott: What's the tofu, please?
Scott: Hang on Doing Something chop-chop.
Scott: Everyone's gonna be here in that Marzipan.
Rym: I hate to tell you this, but I don't think anyone's covered your party.
Rym: I think they're all going to strong bad marshmallow.
Scott: He scheduled something on the same day as the luau.
Scott: Oh Man you guys this part is gonna be crazy.
Scott: go nuts.
Scott: Check it out.
Scott: I got the marshmallows.
Scott: I got all the latest releases from the artists of today.
Scott: Carefully filled out everybody's name tag.
Scott: Oh Crap, I forgot the wood.
Scott: Come on guys.
Scott: I know where we can horse up.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: I'm drinking so much melanin.
Scott: I think I'm serious problem.
Rym: You're gonna have a problem.
Rym: If you don't monitor this tofu.
Scott: I have to tune my ukulele.
Rym: Okay Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo!
Scott: Oh strong dad how long have you been standing there?
Rym: Oh about 20 minutes.
Scott: Okay That's weird.