Scott:
Rym: It's Thursday August 17th 2017 I'm Rym.
Rym: that was good, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about cars that thing we don't like anymore.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so I come home today and I'm looking at some YouTube stats while I'm just setting stuff up and a whole bunch of our videos got flagged as not monetizable because they're not advertiser friendly mm-hmm, which Basically as far as I can read that only applies to extreme vulgarity like racism like the Sexy stuff, but and I thought oh crap the automatic filter or whatever.
Rym: maybe we're swear too much.
Rym: But then I went and looked at what videos were flagged mm-hmm And it's like the most random selection of like the most inoffensive possible.
Rym: like one of them is me playing overwatch Silently for like 20 minutes.
Scott: Yeah, you can't advertise on something.
Scott: That's as blizzards content in it.
Rym: Oh, no, you can.
Rym: you totally can because all my other overwatch videos weren't flagged.
Rym: just that one.
Scott: Oh, that's an AI It's doing.
Rym: it's not a good job, so and then another one was like one of our live stream shows.
Scott: I was like oh how much are you making that much YouTube money on that video?
Rym: you actually my YouTube money at this point?
Rym: Covers the Libsyn costs completely.
Scott: all right.
Scott: well then dispute it.
Scott: then Your 30 cents more YouTube money from that video.
Rym: oh one of them one of them was a video that has one view.
Rym: That I guess.
Rym: I guess it was one of those live streams that failed and I guess I made it unlisted But it was monetized by default, and I guess nope that video is really offensive.
Scott: It's probably that no one wants to buy ads on a one-second video.
Rym: Oh see I thought that I thought maybe it's something like that.
Rym: But I looked at the list of things that will flag a video like this And that's not the kind of thing that flags it mm-hmm.
Rym: It's specifically things that advertisers would be uncomfortable with not things that are not likely to be watched.
Scott: Maybe they you know that the YouTube code that does this is not so great.
Rym: Yeah exactly so it's interesting.
Rym: So I disputed a couple because it's just.
Rym: it's not like the copyright thing where I have to like Write a legally binding document and sign it.
Rym: you click a button, and it's like okay.
Rym: So we'll see I'm gonna poke around with that.
Rym: I don't make care about any YouTube money, so I Ignore that it's paying for the lips in though, so I'm gonna let it keep paying for the lips in also I assume anyone smart as ad block.
Rym: It doesn't see ads.
Scott: so I have YouTube red.
Scott: I don't see ads.
Scott: yeah, even if I use the YouTube app on my iPad which you know has no ad blocker in it.
Rym: Yeah, I currently do not actually pay for YouTube red because I don't watch.
Rym: like when I watch YouTube lately It's pretty much just like videos of cockatoos doing things or DuckTales.
Scott: I watch mostly YouTube and also Not only does it remove all ads from YouTube you also get Google Play music for free.
Scott: So I switched to.
Scott: I stopped paying for em.
Scott: I was playing for Amazon music.
Rym: now I'm not but I pay for the Amazon music.
Scott: I use it a lot with the Sonos I stopped playing the Amazon music And I started paying for the Google music instead and now it's I'm saving money because the Google YouTube red is cheaper than Amazon music.
Rym: What I watch the most of these days is actually Netflix.
Rym: like I've been using my Netflix a lot It's good stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I'm wet.
Scott: It's South Park season real soon, so it's gonna be Hulu time.
Rym: Yeah, but uh so Little Witch Academia season 2 is out now.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna watch it at some point.
Rym: It's uh Real good.
Rym: I know I've watched enough to where it doesn't know that I but now I know for sure.
Scott: Oh, it is this.
Scott: gold is real valuable.
Scott: this steak is delicious.
Rym: It might look like gold.
Rym: what is water is real wet might be a gilded turd.
Rym: there might be poop in there.
Scott: Water so wet.
Rym: Oh, man I mean everyone on earth said they're ready player.
Rym: one was gonna be the best book I'd ever read and then I Flipped through it and I learned that horrible truth.
Scott: I read the whole book.
Rym: I did not.
Rym: so why did?
Rym: why did you read it?
Scott: I was way back in the day.
Scott: It was like beacon day.
Rym: So anyway, there we got a bunch of random news because it's Thursday.
Rym: it's like, you know the lounge on GeekNights.
Rym: talk about anything we want and This is Scott linked us to me earlier and it's just sort of an interesting idea.
Rym: I don't really want to talk about the details of this so much but the idea well I think the deal is this was a startup and they did.
Scott: their price was $50 a month and the price went down to $50 a month is way too much.
Scott: price went down to $10 a month and that's Like crazy for what they give you.
Rym: Yeah But the idea is to pay like 10 bucks a month and then you can just go to the movie theater as Much as you want.
Scott: It's like as much as you want.
Scott: It's once a day once it.
Scott: Yeah, well, which is them as much as you want?
Scott: who goes to the movies more than once in one day?
Rym: Uh, you know who?
Rym: I can see a situation where I would do that if I were homeless Sure, I would pet.
Rym: I would might pay the $10 a month to basically be rents.
Scott: The problem is if you're homeless you want to be in a city because where there's more help for homeless people.
Scott: But if you're in a city movie theaters more expensive.
Rym: But if I only got to pay 10 bucks a month Then I'd sleep in the movie theater all day just shuffling between Pick the longest movie and sit in the back and every time the movie and just move to another movie.
Scott: Yeah, so that's exactly the problem with this service is it lets you go to like the big-time cinema chains And I think it was like AMC regal those places, right?
Scott: But I don't go to those movies ever like once a year for Star Wars.
Rym: I mean I go to them like I don't know maybe every other month.
Rym: Yeah, I usually want to go to like what we'd see at the Angelica or like and this isn't gonna let me go there.
Scott: just the other.
Scott: like a week ago, I went to go see Lawrence of Arabia and 70 millimeter at the Museum of the Moving Image and It's like first of all surprised that that many people were there to see something that's four hours long.
Scott: Second of all, obviously this service would not have gotten me a ticket to that.
Scott: Yeah, and so it's completely worthless to me Because that's the only kind of thing I'm interested in going to the theater.
Scott: for if something's playing in a regal or you know Major, you know cinema chain then it's gonna be streaming on a major service within like a few months.
Scott: So you know and I'm not I don't go.
Scott: I go to those kinds of movies once or twice a year.
Scott: and Even though it's even more important Can I sign up for this service in the month?
Scott: I'm gonna go to the theater, right?
Rym: So if it's ten bucks is already like less than a movie ticket to see Star Wars is $15.
Scott: I can sign up for this in December see Star Wars then cancel before January and get $5 off my Star Wars ticket.
Rym: Yeah The problem with this business model is it says here that movie pass.
Rym: the people will do it.
Rym: quote Will pay theaters the full price of each ticket used by subscribers.
Scott: Yeah, they're using some VCS money to pay the difference.
Scott: Yeah So does any more selling or selling your data to make money to make up the difference?
Rym: does any VC want to invest in?
Rym: Because I promise we will.
Scott: I promise I will not buy a tropical island and live on it with your money.
Scott: and So fast, I promise to actually incorporate a business and do something that may or may not be profit.
Rym: But like most of the time I want to go to a theater I want to go to like Nighthawk or something like the place that serves food and drink.
Scott: Yes, I think this gets you regular movies again.
Rym: It also It excludes 3d and IMAX.
Scott: Yeah, I can't imagine this giving you the fancy 3d IMAX.
Scott: choose your seat reclining kind of movie theater.
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna give you a regular old seat and regular old 2d theater.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: I'm basically completely uninterested in going to a movie theater unless either it has predetermined assigned seating or You know like I have to I want to pick my seat but well in advance So I can just show up right when the movie starts There's no lines not gonna get there early and sit there forever or it has to be a theater that serves like booze and food.
Scott: Yeah, and this also isn't gonna help you out with any food or anything, which at movie theaters is expensive.
Scott: So that's not a place you want to go often.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So I feel like this kind of service is actually already the kind of person there are people who are like so into movies.
Scott: They're just constantly fucking going there for them.
Scott: This is amazing and for anyone else like it's your.
Scott: even this Ridiculous discount where a month going to the movie 30 times in a month once a day for the price less than the price of Going once is still bad.
Rym: I mean ten bucks.
Rym: It costs less than some streaming services.
Scott: How many people go to the movies once a month?
Rym: when I was a kid?
Rym: We went to the movies like every other week.
Rym: I mean I did not but remember back then maybe once I mean, what was my option?
Rym: my 240p TV?
Rym: Or go to the theater, it's not like HD existed yet in homes when I was a kid.
Scott: Okay, maybe in high school.
Scott: We went the most often and that was like maybe once every other month.
Rym: so In some other news you might know if you live in North America an eclipse is coming real soon.
Scott: It's kind of eclipse the solar or the lunar kind solar.
Scott: This might be the pretty sure we're not gonna see another lunar one for a long-ass time.
Rym: But the solar one is interesting cuz I don't think I've ever been in a place Where to a total solar eclipse was like nearby.
Scott: I don't ever and my memory is worthless.
Scott: But I do remember seeing an eclipse a solar eclipse at my house in Connecticut.
Scott: this was Maybe just a bunch of bullshit.
Rym: the path of totality Goes like right across the middle of the u.s.
Rym: Like a lot of people in America like the u.s.
Rym: Specifically can see a complete and total solar eclipse.
Rym: It's only gonna be about 50 60 percent where we are Which is fine because solar eclipse is a really weird and eerie because it's just like gets dark and animals freak out.
Rym: But the news is not that.
Rym: the news is one.
Rym: if you want to look at it, and you don't already have special glasses It's too late.
Rym: Amazon is literally sold out Like completely and - you just make a box of the hole in it.
Rym: No, that's a shitty way to look at an eclipse who says uh me there's way better way.
Scott: Have you ever used the box of the hole in it?
Rym: Have you ever used real solar eclipse glasses?
Scott: the box of the hole in it is pretty cool solar eclipse.
Scott: It seems lame, but actually it's pretty sweet.
Scott: the glass is one.
Rym: You can see it in color instead of just a shadow and two.
Scott: you look directly color white yellow.
Rym: no, it actually it'll shift depending to look like orange or red and These glasses you can just look directly at the Sun.
Scott: but well you could just get a welding glass and hold in front of your face or similar, but The problem is because the eclipse is coming through the u.s.
Rym: There's a lot of bootleg glasses out there.
Rym: so my warning to all of you is one don't look at the Sun.
Rym: and that advice does not matter if Whether or not there is an eclipse because the Sun will fuck up your eyes.
Rym: And if there's an eclipse it fucks them up just as fast.
Rym: But it doesn't hurt.
Rym: so you won't realize it.
Rym: you could look straight at the Sun to think wow that's cool You're gonna blind yourself.
Rym:  if you look through your eclipse glasses Anything other than the Sun and you can see anything your eclipse glasses are fake.
Rym: There's a lot of bootlegs out there.
Rym: Yep eclipse.
Rym: uh the other reason I bring this up is literally the other day I'm sitting at work, and I said something something eclipse.
Rym: No one knew an eclipse was coming like no one.
Scott: I've just seen news about the eclipse for like six months.
Scott: every day for like a few weeks now There's news about the eclipse in some feed somewhere.
Rym: Yeah I Realized there's a ton of people who just do not like.
Scott: compared to the last time there was an eclipse people are way high on This eclipse.
Rym: I mean imagine the person in like Tennessee because looks like he's gonna right through, Tennessee Who's just like sitting in their yard drinking a beer.
Rym: they don't know.
Rym: and then the Sun just goes out.
Scott: How about the caveman back in the day?
Scott: The Sun would just go out.
Rym: Oh dogs found religion.
Rym: call the cops.
Scott: So don't look at the Sun.
Scott: why do you need to be told not to look at?
Rym: yeah I feel like 2017 told me that there's a.
Scott: it's like don't poop your pants unless you're a small Small.
Scott: look directly at the Sun unless you're a small child who doesn't know better.
Scott: You know you don't need to be told not to look at the Sun and by the way if you have children Do not let them be outside alone during the Eclipse because they will look at the Sun.
Scott: look at the Sun.
Rym: But like seriously if you have kids Don't let them be outside alone during the Eclipse.
Rym: like I'm serious They will look at the Sun and fuck up their eyes also.
Rym: Maybe your dog will - oh no animals get freaked out by it.
Rym: They don't look at the Sun.
Rym: They usually run away.
Scott: You never know can't hurt to keep them indoors.
Rym: So you got any news yourself.
Scott: do I have a news?
Rym: that is I pulled it up already.
Rym: It's this thing.
Scott: Oh, yeah, right, so You know when you're looking for a job, and you're not looking in Europe or something where they have reasonable mandatory vacation plans Mandated by the government of like 40 some days or some shit right in the u.s.
Scott: You get almost no vacation days.
Scott: if you're you're pretty much less than every other Civilized country.
Rym: if you're lucky like a like the best you're gonna get in a normal company in the u.s.
Rym: Is 20 days plus Holidays plus unlimited sick days.
Rym: That's like the best deal.
Rym: You're gonna get.
Rym: it's like a good deal And if you work there for 10 years or 20 years us like you'll get 20 you'll get 25 days.
Scott: Anyway, so a lot did you always read a story about like oh this place actually people everyone telecommutes everyone works from home.
Scott: They actually have unlimited vacation.
Scott: they actually you know.
Scott: and the thing is first of all unlimited vacation is bullshit.
Scott: because what happens with the limited vacation in reality is People end up like not afraid to use it.
Scott: and also some people are competitive like I gotta outwork the other people.
Scott: I know you end up.
Scott: It's like you think I'll have a limited vacation.
Scott: That means I could just like go to tropical island for a month.
Scott: No one does.
Scott: All right, so unlimited vacations bullshit.
Rym: I would say it's only bullshit.
Rym: because of poor management a well-run company people would use that vacation and the company would still make money.
Scott: It's never.
Scott: apparently the evidence is that when you have unlimited vacation policies people just don't use them.
Scott: Yeah They'll use like less days than if you gave them a set number of days.
Rym: and then there's probably another class of person who literally just Never comes to the office again.
Scott: Yeah, that's me and then you get fired anyway.
Scott: So, you know and you can never act when you're looking for a job you can never actually find any of these places.
Scott: I think they just made up places for our articles.
Scott: They're never hiring anyone.
Scott: These companies have like five employees.
Scott: But anyway, here's a story that I assume is about a made-up company and isn't real.
Rym: but here as supposedly this Mandatory vacation is not that there are places to do that.
Rym: I've worked with people who worked in places like that.
Scott: Well, how come they're not hiring?
Scott: Let me work there.
Rym: So it's a lot of Wall Street companies and the rationale some.
Rym: sometimes it's a compliance thing.
Rym: If a trader like you think about a truck driver truck driver gets tired because they work too hard They fall asleep at the wheel they can cause serious damage.
Rym: So there's laws.
Rym: you can only drive so much in a day and in a week and all that stuff For certain kinds of trading jobs same deal.
Rym: You can't get overwork.
Rym: You've got to take certain amount of vacation a year and you're not like.
Rym: some of these places will literally like you have to leave Your blackberry at work and they lock your account out.
Rym: You can't check working map, right?
Scott: So here's what this place does supposedly right.
Scott: whatever company this is is the way they did.
Scott: the mandatory vacation as they said It wasn't even like you must take this many days.
Scott: It was every X the week.
Scott: I think it was seven or eight weeks.
Scott: You must take a week off like that.
Scott: It's you only work for that number of weeks and then they schedule in advance like this week.
Scott: You're not working this week.
Scott: You're not working and then and so you're forced to not work those weeks.
Scott: But wait, what if that person just like, you know, like you said goes to tries to check their work email?
Scott: They got something even better than turning off your blackberry or leaving it at work.
Scott: Yeah, right if you check a work email or do anything like that You don't get paid for that vacation week And you just don't get it.
Scott: So you're like afraid to do and to even call into work or go to the office or anything because that's gonna cost you Presumably a lot of money hundreds or even thousand dollars and who knows how much you get paid, right?
Scott: 150 second, you know your salary divided by 52.
Scott: It's still a lot of freaking money for pretty much anyone, right?
Scott: It's just because percentage based right?
Scott: It's a week of work no matter how much money you make so you don't want to lose that.
Scott: so this is pretty great and Company wherever you are hiring me.
Scott: I have skills.
Scott: well I mean if anyone knows any companies that are actual companies that are actually like this that are hiring and aren't just made up companies to write articles about because I have not once in My entire life actually seen like a job post at any company with any sort of remote working or you know mandatory Vacation or any of these things.
Scott: or you know work whenever you work the number of hours You need to work whatever however many that is.
Scott: I've never actually seen a real place that does that.
Scott: I've only seen articles talking about this bullshit.
Scott: If anyone knows a real place that does that point me at it So tangentially.
Rym: I've worked at many places that have the the similar but related concept of unlimited sick days.
Scott: I have I have don't.
Scott: I don't have unlimited sick days But I have.
Scott: the sick days unlike the vacation days don't reset every year.
Scott: So I have like a zillion sick days.
Scott: That's cool.
Rym: If I got way sick unlimited if you're an employer is better because one no one's gonna come into the office and get everybody sick.
Rym: mm-hmm and two People aren't just going to use all the sick days you give them every year as vacation days because they don't get it on vacation.
Rym: So people will take real vacations because they won't be afraid of wasting their days.
Rym: I'm sick, and they'll stay home when they have the flu.
Rym: I cannot.
Rym: it is it was it's night and day the places I work that did that and the places I work that didn't.
Rym: and how often the entire office would get sick mm-hmm.
Rym: So there's some other news.
Rym: You know Millennials are killing everything and I'm gonna go to in depth in this But there's a really funny set of sentences all the every time.
Scott: you know you mean that's always like.
Scott: that's like a meme these days.
Scott: Oh my god Millennials are killing whatever, but you know what?
Scott: anything I've seen Anything.
Scott: I've seen either a parody or a real article saying Millennials are killing X. now X is always something I want to die perfectly.
Scott: I've never seen someone write like oh Millennials are killing something that Scott wants to stick around.
Scott: Like Millennials are killing all the pretty fishies or yeah Killing all the delicious fruits.
Scott: I've never seen any article fake or real saying that it's always Millennials are killing X. and whether it's a parody article or a real article.
Scott: It's always like yeah kill X fuck X yeah.
Scott: so Applebee's if you're not aware kill Applebee's fuck him if you don't live in the u.s We ate there a lot in college days, but the garbage yeah.
Scott: But you know why we ate there a lot cuz one.
Scott: that's where people went.
Scott: We didn't have money And there was nowhere else to go.
Rym: when we went that Applebee's had a policy where they would sell all their Appetizers half-off after like 10 o'clock at night I mean this like weeknight, and we were po.
Rym: so we would go there and as a group probably order like 17 or 18 appetizers and no actual food.
Rym: But Applebee's is not a restaurant so much as a microwave.
Rym: They just have bags of food that they microwave and bring to you like it.
Rym: Don't look into how Applebee's works.
Rym: You'll feel real bad.
Scott: I mean all those restaurants pretty much work the same way.
Scott: the food is largely to a great extent pre-prepared.
Scott: difference between.
Scott: There's not any real chefs back there.
Scott: It's you know it's based on.
Scott: usually there's centralized Chefing warehouses that pre make the food and ship it to the restaurants already ready right and the people at the restaurants are basically not Any more skilled than say fast-food workers who just assemble the food following instructions.
Scott: It's a little more complicated than putting together McDonald's burger, but not much.
Rym: Yeah, it's less complicated than like a blue apron.
Rym: Yeah, that's why they're the only difference between like Applebee's TGI Fridays, Ruby Tuesday.
Scott: They're all the same restaurant.
Scott: as far as I'm concerned there the branding is different.
Rym: the demographic they go after is different.
Scott: They're owned by different.
Scott: some of them are owned by different companies.
Scott: some of them are owned by the same company But they're all basically the same food with different menus different styles But the same damn thing.
Rym: so Applebee's is like shutting a hundred and like a ton of stores and consolidation.
Rym: Apparently the same company owns I hop and I have to not doing well either.
Scott: I hop has never been doing well.
Scott: He was like you know when I was young and like I the best Menu is fistfights like when I was a kid.
Scott: I really wanted to go to.
Rym: I have.
Scott: I was like I'm.
Scott: I got pancakes.
Scott: I'm gonna win.
Rym: the one came by RIT and we were like oh shit hard.
Scott: It was hard to find I hop because they were always going out of business and not doing well even when I was very young.
Scott: Yeah, I'd go to diners and shit instead.
Rym: well I remember we wouldn't go to I hops cuz.
Rym: people were like yeah, they'll be fistfights cuz.
Rym: yeah There's fistfights, and I hops.
Rym: I don't know why I know why but Actually, I got another news.
Rym: That's related to why there are fistfights that I hops mm-hmm, but so Applebee's rather than just Taking it like a noble warrior and dying of their wound in glory they have a plan to stay alive and It's kind of amazing because they basically decided that our friend scojo his dad.
Rym: That is the exact kind of person that they can milk money from forever.
Scott: Yeah, that's the kind of person who will eat at Applebee's.
Scott: the person who doesn't who doesn't taste food is very picky You know only wants to eat meat and potatoes and nothing.
Rym: I have a quote.
Rym: This is literally the whitey white people the strategy of who Applebee's is going to go after.
Scott: but isn't that that's already the strategy?
Scott: That's the strategy of all these restaurant.
Rym: Oh, no, but how it like how they're doing it.
Rym: This is amazing in my perspective.
Rym: There's a quote for the article from Applebee's.
Rym: I think this pursuit the pursuit being trying to go after Millennials who have a more sophisticated dining mindset Led to decisions.
Rym: that quote created confusion among core guests.
Rym: Yeah, why do you write to your way from what I'll call its middle America roots?
Rym: So basically they added a rugel into the menu and middle class American white people were like what the fuck is that?
Rym: and they got confused.
Scott: Mm-hmm, so quote regular the best of all lettuces moving forward.
Rym: Yeah, it's spicy.
Rym: It's got like some.
Rym: it's good stuff the best.
Rym: Oh, I don't make a pure real salad though.
Rym: You sprinkle that it was.
Rym: no No, you got to buy a mix, but you know, it's still the best lettuce quote moving forward They said that Applebee's will focus on routine traditionalist who Actually enjoy casual dining chains.
Rym: Yeah and have favorite menu items.
Scott: I mean, that's Applebee's will.
Rym: just they even know this.
Rym: they say the words Actually, enjoy.
Rym: I mean, they're like, let's find people who actually eat this shit and like market that exclusive.
Scott: They already been doing their whole existence.
Rym: No They were trying to expand into people who have taste buds and they realize that that will scare away their non taste bud demographic.
Scott: I mean you just make a new rest.
Scott: if you want to get people who actually have taste buds You have to make a new restaurant with the new brands.
Scott: You don't know that it's Applebee's.
Rym: take Applebee's Shit food, but call it like artisanal beef burger.
Scott: I mean and for a grown Was not a separate business.
Scott: imagine if so wouldn't eat their shake shacks.
Scott: not that good I'm not saying.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Scott: but people who have you know People eat there right.
Scott: people who refuse to eat at McDonald's go to Shake Shack, right?
Scott: If you were McDonald's you could just use your McDonald's money and open up shake shacks.
Scott: It's assuming like or you make up a new.
Scott: make up a new thing, right?
Scott: Imagine if Chipotle wasn't actually its own thing if Chipotle had just been a thing that Taco Bell came up with and it was owned By Taco Bell.
Rym: Ah, but there's a big difference.
Scott: instead of opening up Taco Bell's they started opening up You know fancier thing that sector that the so-called fast casual like Chipotle is basically in that category.
Rym: They're doing better not because of branding or anything But because I guess young people with taste buds just want better food and that kind of food while it's not great is Actually prepared.
Rym: Yeah, like.
Rym: it's not just a bag.
Rym: You can see it.
Scott: You can see prepared Yeah, and it's prepared very simply.
Rym: but I feel like what's killing.
Scott: if Applebee's wanted to get money from different people They could just use their money instead of opening up an Applebee's.
Scott: open up make up a new brand Right and no, but there have arugula there.
Rym: their value prop is the super master's food.
Rym: And I think the real problem, I mean Olive Garden owns Capitol Grill and Capitol girls great and Olive Gardens garbage Yeah, but at the same time Capitol Grill Has a much different value proposition and demographic.
Scott: Yeah, you need a different.
Scott: we can't take the existing Applebee's brand.
Rym: No But your argument is just.
Scott: it's too hard to try to please you.
Rym: just make a video game studio just make games because there's more Margins that like you know, I'm saying look Applebee's Applebee's.
Rym: just take all their money and put it in an index fund.
Scott: You can't take your existing Applebee's brand Which is always made food for one kind of person and suddenly sort of shift it to aim at a different person.
Scott: All right, so now they I guess someone's stupid they're trying to do that and now they're just going back.
Scott: yep It's not.
Scott: what's the big deal?
Rym: I feel like it.
Rym: the the thrust is that Because of internet and people and like things like Yelp people act like like.
Rym: even I like me and everyone I know if there's a New restaurant in town.
Rym: I go check out its reviews and like see what's up with it and see if it's real food.
Rym: I don't go back to places that have bad food.
Scott: Why would you go to a place of bad food?
Rym: a routine traditionalist who actually enjoy eating a casual restaurants people who are dying.
Rym: So another minor news that is interesting and kind of an end of an era.
Rym: Chuck E. Cheese's isn't doing well either.
Scott: No, why would it be so?
Scott: if you're not familiar?
Rym: Chuck E. Cheese's much like major magics in the u.s.
Rym: if that even still exists is a chain of places where Families can take their children to lose them and then get into fistfights with other families while eating terrible pizza.
Rym: Mm-hmm that's basically the service they provide and The showcase of all these kinds of restaurant quote-unquote arcade restaurants.
Rym: the ball pit was the Animatronics on stage.
Rym: That's what five nights at Freddy's was making fun of.
Rym: Chuck E. Cheese's is trying to rebrand so they're getting rid of a lot of the old animatronics.
Rym: They're retiring them and what they're doing?
Scott: don't give a shit about this.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but what they're doing is even worse.
Rym: Chuck E. Cheese's plans to modernize several restaurants by toning down its wacky colorful design Removing animatronics and Adding dance floors where humans dressed as the eponymous rodent will come out and dance with children.
Rym: All right I don't really think that children ever wanted to go to a Chuck E.
Scott: Cheese's to dance.
Scott: No, that was a kid.
Scott: is there to play games because there aren't arcades anymore.
Rym: So when I was a kid, I wanted to go to a Chuck E.
Scott: Cheese's only have crane games now.
Rym: Yeah, uh and fistfights even.
Scott: we went to Dave and Busters, right?
Scott: So this I went to a Dave and Busters recently like within the month it had like one almost playable game.
Scott: I Went to that Dave and Busters in the Palisades when it was brand new and when I was one of the only Dave and Busters That existed.
Scott: and when I went to it in those days, right?
Scott: It had fancy pool tables.
Scott: It had you know, the shuffleboard table shuffleboard.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's good stuff, right?
Scott: It had laser tag that was relatively high quality.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't Cuzar but it was relatively high quality laser tag.
Scott: It was you know, it wasn't the greatest but he was.
Scott: it was there.
Scott: And it had all these legit arcade games like, you know time crisis DDR and like all the street fighters back me all the legit arcade games that you expect now, right and when you were standing at any arcade game there's a little switch.
Scott: you could flick and you flick the switch weight service would come to the arcade machine and ask you what you Wanted to drink or eat and then bring it to you.
Scott: So you could eat or drink and they even had a cup holders on the machines and everything.
Rym: I feel like within ten years something like that could be remade in some capacity.
Scott: so target people like in between that time which was in I guess the late 90s and now the 2017 that Dave and Busters is still there the same exact location.
Scott: There's no laser tag there.
Scott: They still had the shuffleboard tables and the pool tables.
Scott: Yeah however The there were basically no real arcade games to speak of.
Scott: the only real arcade games They had were a pump.
Scott: pump it up.
Scott: no Yeah, what.
Scott: and just one of them.
Scott: and if you looked at the pricing to play this pump, right?
Scott: Pretty much every game was ridiculously overpriced because you had to basically get a card Put money on the card and I did math on my phone to figure out like how much these games actually cost to play.
Scott: They had one air hockey.
Scott: That was a good air hockey, right?
Scott: It was basically like two dollars to play this air hockey two dollars plus man.
Rym: I remember when I was a kid.
Rym: Arcade games were a quarter.
Rym: a new arcade game was 75 like Mortal Kombat was 75 cents.
Scott: when it first came to play There was one Ms.
Scott: Pac-man Galaga And a game that moved cost a dollar.
Scott: it cost over a dollar to play one round of Ms.
Scott: Pac-man slash Galaga.
Scott: Right, they didn't have it.
Scott: There was not a single fighting game there.
Scott: There was the Mario Kart arcade game.
Rym: cost like multiple dollars to play once also to be honest when I finally played that Mario Kart Arcade game.
Rym: it's not good.
Scott: It's actually if you look at it It kind of is good.
Scott: the problem is in order to like it's made.
Scott: it's actually a Japanese arcade machine, which is weird.
Rym: Oh, it could be almost good if you played it with people.
Scott: Yeah It's meant for you to play it like Constantly like go to the game center after school every day and keep playing like the initial D game that I would do.
Scott: that It's actually a real Japanese arcade machine.
Scott: Not the kind of thing you could you want in a Dave and Buster's that cost like multiple dollars to play even just one race.
Scott: Every single other machine in the place was basically gambling for children.
Scott: but actually I think it's weird.
Scott: right how it's like if we have gambling in a casino and Where you put down a dollar on the craps table and you could win real money or lose your dollar most likely.
Scott: Right, that is perfectly.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Oh, I do not know legally exactly why those are different.
Scott: It's only for adults that this is allowed right and children cannot do this.
Rym: only people who are Looking Wildwood little kids can like get yes and win a TV right.
Scott: yet you go and here in the Dave and Buster's They have what's basically a gambling machine, right?
Scott: Ski-ball is gambling or you know, there's some skill involved but not really right and you put your money in and you gamble and like.
Scott: there's like a Real good examples.
Scott: They had like a dealer no-deal machine, right?
Scott: And it's like you put in real money and the only thing that can come out is tickets, right?
Scott: Even if you lose no tickets come out.
Scott: if you win tickets come out, but your money is gone No matter what it's gambling with a hundred percent chance of losing Right, at least at the casino.
Scott: You have a non zero percent chance of losing even though it's you know, really high.
Rym: So I remember coming to a terrible realization It's a hundred percent chance of losing your money and all you're gonna get is maybe some worthless plastic garbage Tickets Would go to the arcade and like I get tickets in the course of playing even some real games.
Rym: I really care about them.
Rym: But then I realize plastic frog and some candy on my way realized one day there is one like bullshitty crane type game And I figured out how to always get the maximum payout.
Scott: cranes go.
Scott: actual cranes though are gambling We know because they're all rigged, but this wasn't actually a crane.
Rym: It was like a roll of quarter and lands on a strip.
Scott: We were good at.
Scott: that's the one we used also because I was the only game Where you could that had the highest ticket.
Rym: to coin radio me and a bunch of kids.
Rym: we figured out the exact angle.
Scott: We got a hot glue gun and we glue Oh use the glue tape to tape it in the exact right.
Scott: we filled the two sides with hot glue because you could get 200 tickets for one token.
Scott: we get that guy.
Rym: remember we unplugged.
Rym: remember those like hologram games Like the cowboy game or the time crappy Sega ones.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, we unplugged that machine to plug the glue gun in.
Rym: Glue gun did.
Rym: and then we and then the kids start like putting quarters in and like getting the max pay out a machine run Out of tickets.
Rym: Oh, yeah It ran out of tickets and the guy had to come over and put more tickets in and then you emptied it again.
Rym: We had emptied it like three or four times and then the guy was like, yeah This machine's coming out of service.
Rym: and then the next day the machine was gone forever.
Rym: But while the kids were doing this, I didn't put any money in the machine.
Rym: I calculated that you were basically getting like Four cents per quarter worth of actual money.
Scott: So even with you it's like 200 tickets, you know gets you this prize.
Scott: What's the most valuable prize here?
Scott: There's always the TV.
Scott: the TV is this many tickets.
Scott: to get that TV You'd have to put this many tokens in that machine Even if you got the jackpot every time.
Scott: so I'm glad I was just buying that TV for this much money.
Scott: You could buy a TV for less than that.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they had a game.
Rym: I remember they had a Sega Game Gear.
Rym: We had a game gear but my dream in life was to get a Saturday to game gear.
Rym: It had a link cable thing that I was never able to use.
Scott: only one game used maybe uh What used it there was?
Scott: uh, so that Advance Wars like game crystal warriors for the original game boy game boy The only games I ever remember using the link cable for on October.
Rym: Holy shit Was that a good game with the link cable?
Scott: is that the?
Scott: there was an f1 racing game?
Scott: Yeah, it was pretty good and Pokemon F1 racing game was like the game that they launched with the four-way game boy.
Scott: Like that was the game that was meant to go with it.
Scott: That was like the Crystal Chronicles of that thing that game boy.
Scott: only three games.
Scott: I remember ever using it.
Scott: Maybe there was another one.
Rym: I don't remember that game gear would have cost and the best-case scenario like $600 to win.
Rym: so yeah, but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So, uh You know, we always enjoy a good ol good ol fight or a good ol sporting event when someone gets some comeuppance.
Scott: alright, so I found this video I came across today is Various sporting events.
Scott: most of them fights cuz you know But some of them also football and other basketball and whatnot.
Rym: where the first one is so good.
Scott: No, the soccer one is the best one Where you have one athlete?
Scott: Taunting the other athletes and what what?
Scott: oh, I'm so great.
Scott: Oh, right, dude You know, you know the game is on but they're spending time in the game to say show me your moves Or I'm better than you.
Scott: Look I can do some bullshit.
Scott: There's a lot of good.
Scott: But anyway, oh that I saw that.
Scott: oh, yeah, that's piece of shit.
Scott: DJ X anyway, uh So here are many is a compilation here.
Scott: Not just one one of these would be enough to be thing of the day but there's a whole compilation right of Instances you may have seen.
Scott: I saw I seen some of these before Yeah where one player taunts another player and that or perhaps someone in the crowd taught somebody and then Come up ins.
Rym: This is a good thing.
Scott: So it's very satisfying.
Scott: you get how many minutes have come up and see almost four Whoa, and for a YouTube compilation, that's a long one.
Scott: The soccer one's the best one.
Rym: So I found this essay a while ago and I kept forgetting about it, but it's really really fascinating and it is titled Alternative endings in Danish and Russian silent film.
Scott: was this like a silent movie that had different endings?
Rym: Oh, no, no, no, no, I'm gonna read or different times.
Scott: They screened it.
Scott: They showed different endings.
Rym: So I'm gonna read the entire first paragraph of the introduction because that's the only way that it describes it.
Rym: Well, this is really this paper is so fascinating.
Rym: I'm just very.
Rym: I'm just gonna read this.
Rym: Toward the beginning of the last century film companies began producing and exporting Alternative endings for different national markets drawing on stereotypes to create a film narrative that would satisfy the Edge is the first thing or an audience.
Scott: It's the first thing I said where the different countries got different.
Scott: Yeah, so like who?
Rym: the Russian people are sad, let's have sad endings.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: at the center of this study are two countries Denmark and Russia who were to exchange specially adapted endings in the 1910s until the Russian Revolution of 1917 was severely restricted to Restrict trade and everything I messed up.
Rym: in both cases The endings consist of a final scene in which the fate of the characters is altered.
Rym: This meant that Danish actors would often come to a tragic or fatal end on the Russian screen When they had a happy resolution in other markets such as the UK US Denmark Sweden.
Rym: Meanwhile Russian film companies would retain the inevitable end for the domestic audience But produce alternative happy endings for Western spectators of the same film.
Scott: Would the Russians?
Rym: Russian movies ended in fatal tragedy, but they'd have a happy ending for like the US or Denmark.
Scott: So there's this stereotype, I guess that must have existed saying that Russian people wanted to see.
Rym: People made this for themselves, too.
Rym: It wasn't just like dumb Americans don't understand the world and make different endings.
Rym: Russia made different endings for itself as well.
Scott: the thing is Was there perhaps a chicken egg cause and effect situation?
Scott: We're actually showing Russian said so you want to know the deal.
Rym: read this essay.
Rym: This is a fully researched paper that explains Literally every aspect of this.
Rym: it is really really really fascinating.
Scott: So the Russians and other people made the Russians more sad by showing them tragedies Read your essay and made everyone else stupid by showing them happy and I haven't even finished it yet.
Rym: I only read like the first 10 or 11 pages.
Rym: But this is super gets.
Scott: if some of these movies are still available in some form Do they conclude both endings on the the DVD or?
Scott: Yeah, though there's a clue like clue the movie.
Rym: I think there's a couple of old Buster Keaton movies that I'm gonna watch soon because I learned about them and they're interesting.
Rym: But I digress.
Scott: I've seen quite a few of them.
Scott: I don't know if I've seen them all.
Rym: Yeah So anyway in the meta moment, uh Our forum the GeekNights community.
Rym: we upgraded it a while ago.
Rym: So if you were an old-time listener GeekNights, you stop going to our awesome forum.
Rym: That entire thing is archived in stasis in perpetuity.
Scott: Hundreds of thousands of all of the public components of the old forum right are visible on the internet.
Scott: not perfectly But all the content is there for you to go and look at.
Scott: we're gonna keep it there frozen in time Like cats in America, right?
Scott: But our new form if you have a login for the old form You can still log in if you want to see like your direct messages to other people and stuff like that.
Scott: I guess they're still in there somewhere.
Scott: But you cannot make any new content on the old forum.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: We did this a while ago.
Scott: The new forum is new and it's rockin.
Scott: we finally got people to go to it.
Scott: So because we mentioned it so we're gonna keep mentioning it to hopefully keep more people going to it.
Rym: So if you if you're listening to these words That probably means that you'd have a lot in common with other people who listen to these words and our forum is kind of known at least for the people who've gone to it for being now if not an ivory tower then at least
Scott: a
Rym: Slightly less poop filled tower.
Rym: that's slightly above the poop line of the Internet.
Scott: So you want to go to our website for a crew calm and at the top of the website is a link like community Or forum or whatever.
Scott: it click on that shit and then sign up.
Scott: the thing you need to know is that when you sign up?
Scott: There's gonna be a box and that box is gonna say why are you joining and a lot of people fill in that box?
Scott: someone filled in that box today and They wrote something that was so obvious that that was the person who knew who they were.
Scott: So I said But somebody else filled it out and they were just like.
Scott: I want to have discussions with like-minded people And now that seems like a sentence that is clearly answering the question as do I fellow children?
Scott: And it is an answer in that box that you're pretty sure like a bot wouldn't write that right.
Scott: However If that sentence didn't tell me anything to prove that this was a person who listens to GeekNights and knows who we are Right, you need to write something in that box so that I know that you if you any guy deleted your application And you didn't get into the forum.
Scott: try again and write something in that box.
Scott: That's better this time, right?
Scott: something that lets me know that you are Someone who was actually in our community and not just a random internet person or bot.
Scott: now if you're not sure You could even write for example, if you wrote something like Rym is a doodoo head It's like oh, this is a person who knows what GeekNights is All right, the box not gonna figure out to put the word Rym in there, right?
Scott: If someone wrote something like, you know, I want to insult Scott a whole bunch.
Scott: It's like oh, I know this is a person who knows what the deal is.
Scott: I'll approve that right?
Scott: So what I'm gonna link to?
Scott: but if you say I want to talk about video games, it's like well I don't know.
Scott: you could just be.
Scott: so who knows who you are?
Rym: If you're not sure if you want to deal with this forum What I'm actually gonna link to is the rules of our forum and you can just go to this site one.
Rym: We updated them recently.
Rym: So I kind of want people who haven't read them in a long time to read them but to.
Rym: These rules will tell you exactly what kind of community we have and as much as I love both packs and penny arcade their forums are Something.
Scott: well, I mean there's definitely worse forums than.
Rym: oh, yeah, there are worse forums, but I wouldn't go to those forums either.
Rym: Our forum is a place that I would hang out at and I do hang out at.
Scott: and the other thing about our forum Is that all the content in it is actually public on the internet?
Scott: So unless private messages and shit, which I guess they're in there somewhere.
Scott: I don't use those.
Scott: But so if you don't want to make an account you can just read and lurk Without having to do any account making or anything all you want.
Rym: But if you make the account, it'll keep track of like how far you're read into the like 400 post fruit thread.
Scott: Yeah, it's useful to make an account even if you don't post anything because then it's easier to like.
Scott: You know mark things as read and see when there's new posts and that sort of thing.
Scott: So and like you can like things even if you don't post.
Rym: Yep Also very soon We're gonna be at PAX West Emily and I'll be in Seattle for like eight days and Scott will join us Shortly after we get there and you're like there two or three days after.
Scott: yeah PAX West the mothership the real pack will be there.
Rym: We'll be home.
Rym: It's real soon and we're only doing one panel on Sunday September 3rd 6 30 p.m.
Rym: In the Hippogriff theater.
Scott: Our panel is competing with like all these big-time events like, you know So, I don't know how many people are gonna come to it.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: I mean one year we did like literally the last panel and no one no one came a peck south.
Rym: a ton people came.
Scott: Yeah, but no but it PAX West.
Scott: our attendance has been Dwindling yeah, but East and South we're still getting good attendance.
Rym: Oh, man West as far as I can see panel attendance across the board has dwindled.
Scott: There's so much more panels and they're spread out among different buildings.
Rym: So the secret is the first letter of the name of a panel room at where it is every year.
Scott: I'm like afraid that like we're actually gonna get denied for panels at West because it's getting so bigger.
Rym: It's big time because there was a time when we would do like three or four panels at a pack.
Scott: It's getting bigger time or you know It's a bigger deal at PAX West than it is the other paxes, but you know what?
Scott: I saw a panel on the schedule.
Scott: I went through guidebook and added all the stuff I might want to see and there was some real good stuff in there.
Rym: Oh, yeah Well that chicken panel I went to with the last packs.
Scott: There was a panel about like Like the data science of.
Scott: I'm going to that one if I can anyway.
Scott: but there was one that was like let's rate the top ten NES games of all time and it's like Like alright if that's on the schedule, then I'm not worried about us getting on the schedule.
Rym: So I double-checked.
Rym: this will be our 42nd panel at a pax
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: that's a lot of panels
Scott: and that's only the ones at paxes Yeah, and other conventions
Rym: if you add up other conventions were over 400 so over Yeah, a lot of panels over the years, but because the name of the panel groom is hippogriff It starts with H. It's in the Hyatt.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So go over to the Hyatt to see our panel.
Rym: That's where we saw Tetris guys.
Rym: somebody.
Scott: it's not in the Tetris guy room It's in the room further back than that.
Scott: Yes, the smaller one.
Scott: Obviously.
Rym: I didn't look at the map.
Rym: Is it smaller?
Rym: I thought they were the same size, but it's more squarish.
Scott: Is the other ones wider?
Rym: I can never tell.
Rym: I don't
Scott: know what the capacity
Rym: I mean in the old
Scott: days You
Rym: know, you can tell that panels have changed at paxes like they don't really fill that often unless there's swag or big celebrities because in the old days like our game mechanics and mechanism design panel filled this giant fucking room and There's so many more panels now.
Rym: packs actually did a good job of like spreading the crowd out.
Rym: You can usually see a panel you want to see.
Rym: unlike the old days You have to line up like three hours to see anything.
Scott: Anyway, so the last thing we got time as the book club books.
Rym: Oh, you have an updated the site yet a book club still doing.
Scott: I actually thought about doing it and then I got busy and Didn't do it.
Scott: So the book club selection for the next book club episode which will probably happen after pack sometime in September or something is the fifth season by NK Jemisin.
Scott: Summer not March not fall.
Rym: stupid smart, right.
Scott: this book, right?
Scott: I have learned won the hugo award two years ago and The next book in the same series as this book by the same author when the hugo award This year and the third and I think final book in this three book series Just came out and this is like nobody I don't think anyone's ever won the hugo award twice in a row.
Scott: old friend same book in the same series.
Rym: old friends and people have been coming out of the woodwork in the Ignite community because we mentioned this book.
Rym: is the book club to Talk about in the forum.
Scott: I chose this book is the book club because it's such a big frickin deal And this book was just optioned.
Scott: They're gonna make a TV series on TNT.
Scott: Yeah, so this is like this.
Scott: This is like the hottest of the hotness of sci-fi fantasy type, you know literature Novels right now.
Rym: I feel like this is gonna tide us over cuz now that the Last Prince I mean, I don't.
Scott: I've only read like half a chapter and and then I stopped to redo it and I'm gonna go back to It.
Rym: price just start over because I forget I gotta finish the the the false son after the because I finished the appendix in the friends of nothing But I didn't finish.
Scott: I read the whole finish all the appendix.
Rym: I read every entry in the appendix.
Scott: But anyway, uh the point is I Can I cannot imagine this being not a miraculous incredible amazing book?
Scott: No, probably gonna end up just going one two three with all three of these books and also if they're all as great as I Presume they are I'll probably just read every work of nk.
Rym: That's probably good because the no god is gonna be.
Scott: it's gonna be a while before that but it's gonna be a while before I Need to read any other books.
Scott: So this yeah those books alone will be able to carry me over probably all through the winter and maybe into next year.
Rym: Yep Though I didn't remember that Scott backer actually read his two non fantasy books.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: they're good.
Rym: Actually, they're just really Really?
Scott: I got better things to do.
Rym: Well, so disciple of the dog Is about a private detective?
Rym: Well, yeah He's just and the only.
Rym: the only gimmick is he has perfect memory and no one else on earth does no magic.
Rym: Just he has literally perfect memory.
Rym: That's it, but I don't know no one else.
Scott: I don't even remember what's on the previous page in the book.
Rym: And the other one neuropath is basically all the same shit that happens in The Prince of Nothing like that kind of stuff But in a world where there is no magic and there aren't gods.
Rym: So the answer is just well, you're fucked.
Rym: No free.
Scott: Well, mm-hmm.
Scott: So I have cars.
Scott: Oh, and I was.
Scott: this is your idea I didn't have.
Scott: well Are you sure we haven't done an episode about show such a fundamental aspect of life in modern society?
Rym: We did a show a long goddamn time ago where we still when we used to do our how to not suck at series Called how to not suck at driving and I listened to a little bit of it.
Rym: We seem to just talk about the technique of driving and how to not be a shitty driver.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the thing with cars that before cars it sucked to get anywhere like to go somewhere was an Oregon Trail situation.
Rym: Well, does that for you?
Rym: or if you were rich and you lived in like London you just sit in a tiny box and people Carry it on sticks.
Scott: Yeah, or Eventually, we invented trains but even those or and boats But even those would take a long ass time to get anywhere.
Scott: the car was such a tremendous invention.
Scott: You could finally fucking go someplace alone without a whole bunch of people in a schedule on a train or a boat.
Scott: Just on your own.
Scott: you can go really far really fast.
Scott: You could actually get to like the.
Scott: you know, fucking California for New York Right and like a reasonable amount of time like a few days.
Rym: Now, of course the problem an entire year-long journey in America Gas prices being cheap coupled with mass-produced cars meant we could just start building houses in places that were previously non-viable And people were just commute into the city.
Scott: and even after we invented planes which let us go really far really fast like California in a few hours Cars were still much better for going shorter distances really fast.
Scott: So I Loved driving driving as an activity either For transportation or racing or recreation.
Scott: I still think driving is mad fun.
Rym: I love playing racing games and driving cars is fun, but ever since I moved to commute in New York I hate cars.
Rym: I think I would either love a future where driving a car is illegal.
Scott: Not only While I still enjoy the heck out of driving as an activity to do right even if I'm not even going anywhere Just driving a car.
Scott: operating a vehicle is fun.
Scott: Yeah As much as I enjoy that I get this twinge you're like, oh right the hassle and cost of having a car even if I live in a place where I need the car is Worse is not worth.
Scott: that hassle to the enjoyment doesn't make up for it.
Scott: And also Today we have different technologies available for transportation.
Scott: Right besides car better car different car, right?
Scott: We host.
Rym: those options don't exist unless you live in New York.
Scott: I'm just saying there are.
Scott: there are other options that exist if we would You know in state car called the bus.
Rym: Yeah, what a car that only goes on one lane called a train.
Scott: There are things we have if we would say that are better than car Even though they just haven't been set up.
Scott: So car is like is a forced choice in most places.
Scott: but Cars now like back then they helped the world.
Scott: they helped, you know for all the damage They did in terms of murdering people and pollution and whatnot.
Scott: They advanced society by just you know, finally making transportation possible.
Scott: But now we're at a point at which the harm they are doing in their current form is Greater than the benefit they are giving.
Scott: Yeah, so we really need to do something about car.
Rym: So at least for my personal experience though, it's interest.
Rym: I think uber as much as uber is horrible.
Rym: I'm not talking about their business model or anything But that sort of like really changed a lot of people's relationship with cars I think because the conventional wisdom has been forever.
Rym: if you live in America, you must own a car Full stop.
Scott: The only exception was I mean I bought one as soon as I could, you know could buy one.
Scott: It's like as I had to have one.
Scott: the only Necessity was if you live like food water car house if you both lived and worked in New York City Maybe Yonkers.
Scott: Yeah when I moved here.
Scott: I was like, yeah I'm not gonna need the car but ended up driving it here and bringing it here and then after like You know like six months or something I was like, wow, I've had this car here and I keep moving it back and forth across the street.
Scott: Yeah, and I'm not using this car ever.
Scott: I used it once.
Rym: I remember I drove to comp con when I was on the Otakon staff.
Rym: I borrowed your car and I just drove there.
Scott: Yeah There were occasional times when I needed the car But most of the time I was just moving it back and forth across the street doing nothing.
Scott: And so I got rid of it.
Scott: and I have a friend actually who Lee has the car.
Scott: he lives in New York.
Scott: He leaves the car at his parents house in Connecticut and we're like Why the fuck do you still have that car use it like once in a blue moon?
Scott: The parents like take care of the car for him and he's just like what the fuck.
Rym: seriously Really, but at the same time rid of that shit the convenience because there's times when a car be useful Like for example if I wanna go skiing There's like the best way to go skiing like you just got to drive.
Rym: you realize rent a car but renting cars Success because the car rental industry acts like it's still the 90s to this day Like renting cars sucks.
Rym: if I want to say I want to rent a car for the weekend in New York, right?
Rym: Sure.
Rym: There's a car.
Rym: There's a million car rental places that I can walk to from our apartment.
Scott: They all give you a car.
Rym: They all close early and they're not open on Sundays.
Rym: if I weren't in a car for a weekend I probably have to rent it in the morning before I go to work and park it somewhere and then go get it when I'm Gonna go to my thing and then I have to drive home on Sunday and then I have to park it somewhere and then pay Because I can't actually drop it off or give it back to them until Monday
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and also it costs a ton of money.
Rym: renting a car in New York City Costs like eight times more than renting it even a little bit outside of New York.
Scott: So there were for a while these services like zipcar which I guess still exists.
Scott: it did barely.
Scott: I canceled my zipcar cuz it's garbage now Yeah, but it used to be a big deal for a few years.
Scott: You're like we were making use of it and it was totally zipcar used to be literally.
Rym: Oh we need a car.
Rym: I literally was opening up my phone and then pick a car nearby walk over to it.
Rym: We just open and we just drive it.
Rym: We used them all the time.
Rym: They were great.
Scott: and but now all of those services for I don't know what reason.
Rym: I know exactly why I've failed and I know 100% why uber Uber is killed zip.
Rym: I think uber killed zip car.
Scott: So are you gonna use an uber to go to the grocery store get groceries and then go back?
Scott: So what happened was as far as this is just my opinion or you get one uber to go to the grocery store another uber You to go home.
Rym: Yeah, that's what you do.
Rym: That's cheaper than a zipcars.
Rym: The problem was zipcars model was if you need a car for like a few hours use it.
Rym: But as far as I can tell hardly anyone in the city's used it for that because no one needed that.
Scott: No I only I need the car for that's like when I had the car.
Scott: the times I used it were like driving up to Albany.
Scott: Go to my parents house go on a weekend trip go you know like these sorts of things the things that are too long to use a subway or a Car.
Scott: what amaze I don't want to have to park.
Rym: zip car would have made their money.
Rym: We have people in New York like using a car every like every week or so for like an hour.
Rym: But everyone as far as I can tell when I tried to reserve cars They would reserve them for entire weekends or entire weeks and use it just like a normal rental car.
Rym: Because and I can't stress this enough.
Rym: This is this is like a defining characteristic of Millennials.
Rym: I think I don't want to interact with a human.
Rym: I don't want to go to a physical place.
Rym: I want to go to a website click a thing and then have the service automatically appear Mm-hmm.
Rym: So zip car was great.
Rym: I'd go to a website.
Scott: I was talking to someone today.
Scott: It was like making an eye doctor appointment, right?
Scott: They were so afraid.
Scott: They didn't want to talk on the phone to anybody.
Rym: Remember Austin, right?
Scott: They were able to make an eye doctor appointment with a new patient.
Scott: Right entirely by going on the internet I you know, then they received a phone call from the eye doctor to confirm the appointment.
Scott: I do all my doctor stuff.
Scott: I don't go to the eye doctor.
Rym: I don't call.
Scott: my doctors are perfect.
Rym: I go to a website and I schedule like my dental appointment and it just works automatically.
Rym: I get a calendar invite Otherwise, I'll forget.
Scott: I'm my dentist.
Scott: I made one appointment the first one over the phone and then ever since then you make the appointment for the next appointment on Your way out.
Scott: Yeah, so and then they text me when the thing is.
Rym: and such remembered RIT What Papa John's wasn't good, but when we could order it online We started ordering there almost exclusively just because no one wanted to call on the phone.
Scott: The main thing with ordering things like food, especially on the other side doesn't understand you.
Scott: Yeah, you don't have to worry about hearing and the the fuzziness of human language.
Scott: It's like if the order is written down in text, it's like ah, it's exactly right, you know, yep
Rym: But anyway, I hate talking to rental car people when I rent cars at airports like I hate every second of it, but Zip car was great and then people like me only use it on the weekends, which they probably lost money on that proposition.
Rym: so they kept.
Rym: they raised the prices to the point that it was cheaper to rent a regular car.
Rym: and Remember the one time we drove one out to Pennsylvania and then the time the car broke down like we got a flat tire They had to like get someone to fix it for me because that's how their business model worked.
Scott: and they're giving everyone free gas Yeah, and free easy pass.
Scott: I feel like they shouldn't know if it wasn't for easy pass.
Rym: the easy pass pass through to your credit Card.
Scott: Okay, but the free gas I feel like because back then If I get a real rent a car, right?
Scott: It's like I have to fill it with my own gas money.
Scott: I don't know why they like easy pack.
Scott: I was I was totally happy to zip car included free gas Oh, you know why they did was very simple shouldn't they have?
Rym: You know made you pay for your own fucking gas because they wanted people to leave them generally full and people would just fill it Up if they just used another credit card and they theoretically baked it into the prize.
Rym: but anyway So they lost.
Rym: all the people.
Rym: all the people who use the service pretty much just used it like I did which wasn't good for Them and anyone who would use it.
Rym: the way that would actually make the money switch to like uber Because uber is cheaper to get a car to drive you to the place car to drive you home then zip car to ran a car for hours in a set amount of time and if you're bringing the car back late to its parking spot you Get in trouble and lose money and all that nonsense.
Rym: So now there's really just no solution.
Rym: people who are Willing to give up on all moral character use uber and I just don't use cars unless I'm absolutely forced to.
Scott: I mean Even regardless of the economic model of the car owning renting Uber in taxi Whatever right.
Scott: using a car hurts the world.
Scott: You're poisoning the air You're burning fuel.
Rym: lying probably hurts your words.
Scott: You're putting your life at risk.
Scott: cars are super dangerous to be in.
Rym: we're going to packs.
Rym: It's really way worse for the environment than driving anywhere.
Scott: I'm just saying I get to wait in terms of saying if you care about the earth flying all these care about.
Scott: I mean this.
Scott: You know this I'm only doing it occasionally, right?
Scott: Yeah, but that all the people are driving a car fucking every day You're comparing like a short car ride to like Okay, so you're gonna make that argument.
Rym: my counterpoint is without.
Scott: the one flight to packs doesn't pollute the earth more than a person driving their car every day all year without Radically like forcing people to move massive imminent domain everywhere.
Rym: There's no other way to get around in an efficient manner.
Rym: I'm just saying and I think Self-driving cars kind of solve that because if we get to the point to where we ban non self-driving cars Then cars form a grid of information sharing and basically function like mass transit.
Rym: So I feel like the window of humans individually.
Scott: Inefficiency of cars.
Scott: and like you take this big old car that could carry four people uses a ton of space.
Scott: You're just one person right, but the car is gonna move itself.
Scott: So it's a whole bunch of energy wasted because it's a giant car.
Scott: some people might know one has those tiny cars.
Scott: No one has those.
Scott: Yeah, right motorcycles.
Scott: It's like you're good.
Scott: You're good.
Rym: Yeah, you're just gonna die, but you're good, right?
Scott: But you know, so and it's it's super inefficient.
Scott: Like you could have carpooled right the self-driving car It's like a car sitting there not moving for a lot of the time.
Scott: right with self-driving cars You're gonna have the minimum number of needed cars.
Scott: when will?
Scott: they'll drive all the trips necessary and no other X plus.
Rym: you could like get rid of traffic lights eventually.
Rym: Cars are just like automatic and efficient and they're just a grid and they just work.
Scott: But anyway, there's also the danger of cars right.
Scott: flying is ridiculously safe.
Scott: Yeah, people are super afraid to fly and when they get in a car, they're not afraid at all.
Scott: So I gotta get in a car.
Scott: I'm like, oh my god, I'm gonna die.
Scott: Yep I didn't used to be that way, but now it's just like I really thought of that problems.
Scott: that is wise.
Rym: I wasn't sure how this show would go cuz we had no plan.
Rym: I was worried we'd you.
Rym: cuz I figured we just get into like anecdotes like cars.
Rym: we owned and things but with Car getting into a car.
Rym: One of the biggest problems I have is that you and I are both Extremely picky about driving technique and safety.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I don't fucking trust like almost anyone I know to drive a car that I'm in let alone like cab.
Scott: I mean, you know Rym doesn't crash.
Scott: He said that one time he rear-ended people in the big pile up.
Rym: Oh, yeah I got.
Rym: I was in a Massive pile up of the back of my car was smashed in the front of my car was never crashed ever But you backed into a fucking car.
Scott: That was not.
Scott: that's not like a crash.
Scott: That was a crash.
Rym: You crashed.
Scott: your car is not like.
Rym: you crashed your car to another car that wasn't even moving.
Scott: Extremely tiny parking lot Extremely tiny rationalize.
Scott: I pulled into a spot, right?
Scott: I read I ran in I put some quarters in a laundry machine and ran out was in there for less than a minute.
Scott: All right I got in my car and I tried.
Scott: I started backing out when I pulled when I parked.
Rym: we didn't look.
Scott: When I parked there were no other cars in the lot.
Scott: you drove a vehicle in there for one minute.
Rym: you engaged a Multi-toned vehicle to move without looking at what might be in its path.
Scott: I slightly buzzed.
Scott: I was going the speed limit.
Scott: a new car had appeared in like the one minute I was in the laundromat.
Rym: I was going the speed limit on a freeway in tight traffic and I came up over the crest of a hill and there was an accident and cars were stopped and I hit the car in front of me.
Rym: point behind me hit me and the car Behind him hit.
Scott: the point is and Rym drives a car.
Scott: He hits the brake way late.
Scott: So you're very uncomfortable to be in the car, even though it's safe.
Rym: Actually, what I do is something.
Scott: I hit the brakes if I see a red light way far away.
Scott: I hit the brakes so far in advance.
Scott: I accelerate so lightly I grab it's like a. it's a nice very slow curve up to speed and it's curved slowly down.
Scott: So there's.
Scott: no you know, the car doesn't move back and forth.
Scott: It's so smooth.
Scott: when I Drive I refuse to accelerate or decelerate rapidly if necessary.
Scott: So the real problem is that driving unless it's necessary driving in Rym though speeds up real fast and then stops real fast.
Scott: Yeah, you know what driving it is while it is.
Rym: It is very uncomfortable though In the city, that's kind of the only way to drive until you get down to the freeway and freeway.
Rym: just cruise control Just whatever just chill.
Rym: but on the freeway when you say that I'm breaking late.
Rym: what I really do is I am hyper averse to an accident like.
Rym: I Do not want to crash my car and I'm like crazy Psychotically focused on not crashing my car.
Rym: Mm-hmm so say I'm on the freeway and I got cruise control on and I'm just chillin and In the lane ahead of me like weaving way ahead.
Rym: I see brake lights.
Rym: I immediately do a quick hard brake to shed a significant amount of speed so that whatever is coming I have shed speed early because the longer you wait the less safe chance you have to shed speed.
Rym: So on the freeway if there's even the hint of trouble ahead I do a short sharp brake to shed a bunch of speed Then assess the situation and then decide if I'm gonna engine brake or hold course or whatever I'm gonna do.
Rym: but I do recognize that that sharp reaction is Uncomfortable for everyone who's in the car except me.
Scott: Yes, don't do that.
Scott: That's bad driving.
Rym: Anyway cars suck and I hope that no human is allowed to drive cars on any public street.
Rym: at some point in my life People seen that.
Scott: so the self-driving car right.
Scott: people seem to have this idea Like if the cars aren't perfectly safe if they ever hit anyone then we can't use them yet.
Rym: So you humans already drive like shit, right?
Rym: I would trust current self-driving cars over most of you.
Scott: That is totally totally stupid.
Scott: Here's how it works, right?
Scott: Let's say a human driving a car has a 10% chair every every 10 trips.
Scott: They're gonna have accident.
Scott: Obviously that's way high.
Scott: but you know, I'm just using made-up numbers, right?
Rym: Look at all the dents in cars parked in New York, right?
Scott: but the point is let's say a person driving a car has a 1 in 10 chance of an accident, right.
Scott: if if the self-driving car has a 0.9 in 10 chance of an accident if it's even a fraction Safer than a person it's still flawed.
Scott: if it's at if it's even a fraction safer than a human Multiplied by all the trips made in cars and all the miles driven that adds up to less people dying Yep.
Rym: Now you can't even point.
Scott: Oh, oh one percent safer than a person.
Scott: It doesn't have to be a hundred percent.
Scott: See if it's one.
Scott: if it's a fraction of a percent safer than a person driving Added up over all the trips and all the cars all over the world Many many many many lives will be saved and the fact is they're not a fraction of a percent safer than a person.
Scott: They're drastic even in their current shitty state.
Rym: So they are in some degrees.
Rym: but on the other hand there's certain kinds of situations still that they don't handle at all.
Rym: Yes that a human would but well even so.
Scott: but even they are still in their current shitty form as shitty as it is drastically safer than a human.
Scott: because like in those states They don't know.
Scott: you're not.
Rym: when we say human.
Rym: We're not saying like someone who's a good driver.
Rym: We're saying the average driver.
Rym: Yes even in Weird situations where the driving test consists of did you knock down less than 50% of the cones you're good to go, right?
Scott: Even in those situations those self-driving cars are likely to just sit there doing nothing.
Scott: They're not like gonna drive around like crazy hitting people, right?
Rym: So well, so there is a counter danger self-driving cars Probably because of shitty Internet of Things security.
Rym: probably really easy to hack.
Rym: Different scenario, but I think that actually might be a big danger.
Rym: Yes, but because if you're gonna assassinate someone, yeah, the car doors won't open and the car just drives off a cliff.
Scott: yes, that is true, but Given those numbers.
Scott: I think it's amoral to allow people to drive and to not immediately say you're starting right now All cars must be self-driving counterpoint.
Scott: It would be more killing people by not doing that.
Rym: you would kill people if you made that mandate without buying everyone a self-driving car Because the people who'd be hurt most by that are poor people who need to drive to get to their job because of the shitty Way our society set up.
Scott: you just make it so that all new cars You don't you can't just take say everyone has to throw out your car now, right?
Scott: It's a waste of resources, right?
Scott: you say starting now or starting like next year All new cars must be self-driving.
Rym: all new cars would cost more.
Rym: poor people couldn't afford them But they could afford shitty used cars.
Scott: you force them, you know, if that's cars that people are forced to make No, you know you do.
Rym: you subsidize it so that people get free car.
Scott: do whatever it is You got to do.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: We're talking about cars not time economics here, right?
Rym: Ah, but economics is.
Rym: the point is you are just as intrinsic.
Scott: You cannot put a dollar value on the lives of the people who will not be killed by cars.
Scott: Therefore whatever the price Oh You can most definitely put a dollar value ever.
Scott: the price is you pay it to make sure that all new cars are self-driving right Because it's even if it's a billion dollars and it saves one life.
Rym: pay it and on that note we killed plenty of time.
Rym: So this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce I do me a nickel.
Rym: Amanda Duchette roundabout at mp3 my stadium.com.
Rym: William Isemeros Jeremy minor.
Rym: life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth.
Rym: a genuine modified like five six car monorail.
Rym: Nicholas Brandau captain.
Rym: Jean Guacas.
Rym: see Rebecca Dunn for two one creations in rear to pull out today.
Rym: And if they would come take our base Shervin about horrible James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy sailor Topeka sailor Vista Matthew Smith, Don Schleich jar tovish and Joshua Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian Sidroni Finn Chrisman give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Scott: Say the blue gum buzz the to play the big zoo.
Scott: big zoo Said we saw the two can be the big zoo big zoo He'll go they me.
Scott: yeah No We will be News Big zoo Oh.