Rym: It's Tuesday September 12th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about exit the game the secret lab.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah, we're back from basically a two-week hiatus because we had PAX West which basically is a full week and then I went straight from PAX to New York and then immediately back to Utah to go mountain biking.
Rym: and Now we're back.
Rym: I'm back in my normal life And we played a lot of games at PAX that we had not played before.
Scott: We played like every game people brought plus games that were at PAX that were new plus everything.
Rym: Yep I think offhand the games that stick out the most which we're not gonna talk about on this show.
Rym: We got to save it.
Rym: Black Friday, like really was better than I could have possibly expected.
Scott: Maybe the best stock market game I've played were you buying and selling stocks and out.
Scott: their prices are down.
Scott: Prices are going up and down.
Rym: downforce was fun, but a little disappointing like it.
Rym: There's not as much to it as camel up.
Scott: Yeah downforce is like it.
Scott: It's a good game that I like.
Scott: I just wonder how many plays it has.
Scott: it's one of those games that it's like.
Scott: good should buy but eventually You're not gonna use all those score sheets before you don't want to play down.
Rym: Oh, it's anymore and it's an unlike formula.
Rym: Did?
Rym: it doesn't seem like it could expand as easily?
Scott: I think it could expand.
Rym: you'd have to add mechanics However maps right?
Rym: Yes, but it expands just by a new map.
Rym: Like I have the Singapore map totally different game.
Scott: Yes, it could expand it which would make it, you know extend it quite a bit.
Scott: The problem is it should have had that expansion in the original box already.
Rym: Yeah, because we played on the most advanced mode that was in that box.
Rym: It was not enough.
Rym: Mm-hmm sticking sticking Whatever.
Scott: that game was nice trick-taking game that we never finished because of the seventh guest but it was super backwards that game.
Scott: It's the backwards trick-taking game.
Rym: Yeah, you don't have to follow suit and literally everything's Trump except the suit that was led.
Rym: So yeah It's like hearts, but you don't have to follow suit and everything's the Queen.
Rym: Yep so yeah, but we'll talk about all those games in due course on various shows as we come up.
Rym: and Yeah, we're back from PAX.
Rym: I didn't die mountain biking.
Rym: I actually only got a minor injury this year.
Rym: Oh only a minor injury.
Rym: so I realized something at doing this mountain biking again because basically there were two other people who were like pro at it and Some other people who said they'd mountain bike before.
Rym: but I've realized that when most people say mountain biking What they imagine is something that is not mountain biking.
Rym: They imagine riding a mountain bike in the woods.
Rym: They imagine riding a hybrid bike in the woods.
Rym: They imagine riding a mountain bike on a trail.
Rym: some of them seem to just imagine riding a mountain bike.
Scott: Mountain biking is not usually televised that often right?
Scott: So people think like, you know Like well like biking on a mountain on a road is not mountain biking.
Scott: That's road biking.
Scott: You don't even use a mountain bike for that.
Scott: Yep, you know the tour de France and the Tour de France.
Scott: They go up mountains in the Alps that are way bigger than any mountain.
Scott: You're going to mountain bike on and they're not using a mountain bike.
Rym: Yep This is a good time but one person who was with us was like yeah mountain bike once or twice and then we get on the lift and he's like Why are we on a ski lift?
Rym: and we're like, you're fucked dude.
Scott: You have not mountain bike before apparently.
Rym: So and then even in the forum, I was like yo does anyone mountain bike?
Rym: I don't think I know anyone who mountain bikes.
Scott: It's not really that common.
Rym: It's only common I think in places where like it is common Like if you live in a ski town in the summer people mountain bike because there's nothing else to do there.
Scott: Yeah, lots of people have mountain bikes, but they're not.
Scott: you know, actual mountain biking is not a common.
Rym: But someone in the forum was like, well, why don't you do cyclocross cyclocross?
Scott: It's not even remotely close to mountain bike and also does not look fun.
Rym: I don't like Bicycle racing.
Rym: that is primarily dependent upon your pure physical ability.
Rym: So I actually do like for racing.
Scott: So here's the thing.
Scott: I actually do think cyclocross looks fun.
Scott: However, I'm not interested in racing I just want to.
Scott: I just want a bike on a fun obstacle course without any, you know conditions of trying to win or anything.
Scott: Yep, right That no one's doing cyclocross without the racing part.
Scott: So that makes me not interested in Vikings.
Rym: the opposite.
Rym: Most people are just doing it for the thrill of like, what's the puzzle?
Rym: How do I get down this trail?
Rym: They're not racing like.
Rym: there are people who race but it's flipped.
Rym: They're the minority.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but I've determined that I'm actually real good at mountain biking.
Scott: Uh-huh Let's let's find a professional mountain biker and see what they have to say.
Rym: Two of the people we were I was racing with we started kind of racing because they were pros like.
Scott: therefore They get paid to mountain bike.
Scott: That's their job.
Rym: They compete.
Rym: one of them is an instructor like and Yeah, they're like.
Rym: I'm good at it apparently But I don't think I could teach it because the last instruction I got was like a kid and I just kind of do it.
Rym: I don't think about it that much.
Scott: The only problem is Are you doing like the you know, dangerous deadly jumps like I see with GoPros on YouTube?
Rym: I don't like jumping but even skiing I don't do jumps so much.
Rym: I mostly focus on technical track.
Scott: That's a pro people are doing.
Scott: there's different kinds of even mountain riding on some really crazy narrow thing real fast narrow thing fast.
Rym: It's real easy.
Rym: That's called single track.
Rym: That's what I did Like that's.
Rym: I did that so much as you move a little bit to the side you die.
Rym: Yeah I did that so much as a kid that that's second nature like I. actually I am more comfortable doing that.
Rym: Then I am like going fast downhill on a road bike.
Rym: Yeah, like yeah Well, you remember even you were on a nice road bike.
Rym: we're going downhill.
Rym: you were breaking right?
Rym: Cuz it's scary to go that fast on a bike.
Scott: I always break.
Scott: I break more than everybody.
Scott: during that I did the century and I realized like oh Everyone gets away from me on the downhill.
Scott: Oh, I'm breaking way more than everybody.
Scott: Yeah That makes a lot of sense.
Scott: You know, it's like I didn't think I was slower than that guy.
Scott: I guess he's just less afraid to go fast down the hill than I am.
Rym: So I am less afraid of going fast downhill and a mountain bike than I am on a road bike.
Scott: I mean, I just don't want it.
Scott: There's a certain speed at which you know, I just don't want to go faster than that period.
Rym: Yep also mountain biking you'll be going real fast and then it's like car racing where you Break real hard to get around a corner and then accelerate again.
Scott: No I break way way way in advance and go around the corner nice and slow and then go fast again and with nice smooth Acceleration though.
Rym: Yeah, the one thing though.
Scott: I do not like accelerating or decelerating rapidly no matter what I will break a mile in fucking advance.
Rym: Accelerated and decelerating is what I enjoy the most.
Rym: That's what I do.
Scott: That's why I don't go in your community.
Rym: So how was that century?
Scott: Basically, you wake up at the crackety crack crack at a crack crack acid on.
Scott: Yeah, you go to Central Park So it's already putting some miles on.
Scott: I almost got worried because I was.
Scott: I'm like I want to.
Scott: I don't want to go The long way over the Queen's borough.
Scott: I'm gonna go over Randall's Island to get to the start The top of Central Park right and I'm like, all right, let's go there the the Randall's Island way and It's dark and I'm on Randall's Island and there's people on Randall's Island at 5 a.m I guess
Rym: we're doing
Scott: what?
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Scott: there were cars there and shit.
Rym: Maybe I might be.
Rym: you know, what?
Rym: actually it's probably kid baseball stuff.
Scott: No, they were going to like, you know, the I think.
Scott: so what?
Scott: at least one person who's driving to the nut house I don't know if not has a derogatory term unrelatedly.
Rym: Apparently there was a con.
Rym: this was a FARC story.
Rym: I was gonna use my thing today, but I didn't.
Rym: on Randall's Island.
Rym: There's concerts, right?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So you can't bring liquor into those concerts.
Rym: so this dude buried bottles of vodka on the island two weeks before a concert and Dug him up at the concert documented everything and they interviewed his friend and his friend said and I quote the man is a legend.
Scott: I am against the drinking of poison, but that man is truly a legend.
Rym: That is that is you respect the game like it is.
Scott: Why did he not also bury weed?
Rym: It's like if John wick was real.
Rym: you don't respect killing killings bad.
Scott: Why not also throw a gun down there, but you respect the craft of it Even if what they did is bad anyway, so and then at 6 a.m.
Scott: They did some hoo-ha and then you started biking.
Scott: You're basically just biking on New York City streets.
Scott: There's no closed roads or anything unless you're doing the baby route and which means you start in Prospect Park And you just go fucking everywhere.
Scott: Right you go down.
Scott: You go down you go over the Brooklyn Bridge early enough in the morning that it's.
Scott: there's no one in your way You know.
Scott: you go over down Rockaway.
Scott: You're going past the beach.
Scott: He's going fucking everywhere Right way out East way north of the frogs neck And then you get back to Astoria Park.
Scott: It's like oh you think you're going back to Manhattan knows you go all the way to the Bronx past the Botanical Garden And then all the way ass back down And then it's over which
Rym: makes it when I think about it like I do like there's a 50-ish 50-60 mile ride.
Rym: that I do kind of often.
Rym: that's basically all the way down to Rockaway all the way across and then back around The long way mm-hmm, so that's already a long way.
Rym: I had 40 more miles to that.
Scott: So first of all even though the road is not closed You're with a bunch of people like.
Scott: I was worried that like because it's so long and there wasn't that many people doing it I might end up alone and lost yeah, but No, I was with a bunch of people pretty much the whole time.
Scott: There was always people.
Scott: so you know and when you're riding with the people I guess you get this sort of added.
Scott: you could you know safety benefit But some drunk driver hit people at like 8 in the morning or something whoa not where I was.
Scott: Also There's a bunch of rest stops So you can all you can stop and get bananas and water and food.
Rym: I'm a big fan of the supported ride.
Scott: watermelon there was.
Scott: watermelon was excellent But there was one rest stop the Throgs Neck one that was you know for 100 mile people only and that one was no good.
Scott: They had one kind of Clif Bar and that was it.
Scott: I didn't have fruit they had water and there's one kind of Clif Bar and nothing else.
Scott: It's just like really.
Scott: that's a shame and that was what I needed it the most because I was feeling like the worst around.
Scott: then right, but then Once we started going towards Astoria, which was a bad easy ride because it was such a familiar ride I like I got another wind and then I was like we the whole rest of the time.
Scott: I was like whatever.
Scott: I was getting slow out when I was out east you know like the Alipon Park And you know such.
Scott: but then once after that it was.
Scott: it was easy goings no problems.
Scott: There were a few basically because there's no There's not a whole lot of markings.
Scott: like basically someone goes around spray-painting on the street in yellow the letter C with an arrow And you can also get the q-sheet.
Scott: But the app to like load the GPS data in is like money every month.
Scott: so no one's paying for that shit, right?
Scott: So if you're not like reading the q-sheet there were a few times where we like missed a turn and had to turn around again.
Scott: One time I was with a whole bunch of people and we all went the wrong way That's the worst and one guy and then someone straightened us out And the whole group got back on track.
Scott: there was a couple parts that were real bad.
Scott: We were next to a highway and the path for biking that was next to the highway was like blocked by Construction and it's like didn't someone just make this route?
Scott: did this construction show up yesterday?
Scott: So we had to be York.
Rym: it probably did.
Scott: we had to throw our bikes over the guardrail walk on the Shoulder of the highway and then throw our bikes back over the guardrail.
Scott: Yeah, that was real bad.
Scott: No, I think there might have been another spot.
Scott: That was iffy like that.
Scott: That was no good.
Rym: So one of our mountain bike routes We actually we get to a spot and on the ski resort where we're like mountain biking through the woods.
Rym: There was construction and the trail we tried to get to it was closed.
Rym: So we had to go down a regular road instead like a dirt road.
Rym: That is way more dangerous than just biking through the like woods.
Scott: But yeah, there was.
Scott: no I mean cuz you're in New York City.
Scott: there there were no hills that were significant.
Scott: worry, right?
Scott: And the thing is it's like the funniest part was like after we finished We're at the north of Central Park and I got to go home and it's like oh, how do we get home?
Scott: And there's like that's the hill at the back of Central Park is right there.
Scott: Already biked over a hundred miles and to go home.
Scott: I gotta go of another stupid hill Right and it's like.
Scott: but then I was.
Scott: I was guess I was still had that other wind so it wasn't a problem.
Scott: But it's like it really puts into perspective Like normally just go up that hill no problem.
Scott: and there's these tourists struggling Yeah, but it's like I already did a hundred miles and this tourist struggling and I'm flying past them.
Rym: That's like a situation like on the way to packs Meanwhile my 50-pound bag.
Scott: But meanwhile when I'm doing the century the the pro lance armstrong type people are pushing past you.
Scott: We're flying past me like whoosh and I fly past this tourist and it's like wow the like amount of you know skill disparity of biking is so wide.
Scott: It's so yeah.
Rym: Well, I'm not even gonna say skill You know what?
Rym: It is.
Scott: Most people are not athletic at all or like not knowing how to use a gear.
Rym: Oh, yeah That's it.
Rym: That's who?
Rym: See at least on the mountain bike my smallest gear my front gear There's only one and it's tiny and my biggest gear in the back is bigger than the biggest gear on my current bike in the front.
Scott: But I think the thing is if you wanna, you know See a whole lot of New York City and bike a whole lot of New York City In a way that is generally safer than doing it on your own with a lot of rest stops and comfort And also bike a whole lot in one day.
Scott: We started 6 a.m We finished it like 5.
Scott: I got home more like 5 36 because you know, I waited at the end hung out and then biked home, right?
Scott: Yeah, and you're near New York City.
Scott: I don't know if I traveled in New York to do this.
Scott: you know, it's worth it, but It's gonna take you longer than doing a century somewhere else because of all the red lights and stuff.
Scott: if we did the hundred miles Somewhere else it would have been way faster without red lights.
Scott: Of course the hundred miles But it's less hilly because it's New York.
Scott: There were only like a couple hill situations And they weren't really.
Rym: that's the trouble that we could probably do the century on the Harlan Valley rail ride But that's more mountain mountain.
Scott: Well, I think I could do.
Scott: I could almost definitely do the leg.
Scott: They have a leg saving version.
Scott: Yeah, I could definitely do that.
Rym: I don't feel like that's the one I did.
Scott: It only has two hills, right?
Scott: Where's the one?
Scott: we'd be 70 we did last year.
Scott: this year had one hill.
Rym: I remember all the people who who got kicked out of the century and had to go like on the play route at the end Cuz I was talking to a bunch of them.
Rym: every everyone I met who got kicked out was doing the leg saver.
Rym: I didn't meet anyone got kicked out.
Rym: who did the real one?
Scott: I think no one does the real one unless they're you know, definitely for sure Pro, right?
Rym: Shane wants to know how sore you are you sore?
Scott: Not really.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I don't.
Scott: when I do athletic activities that goes way slow it does.
Scott: the only athletic activity I do is biking and I don't ever Exert myself to like.
Scott: if it's like, you know Rym like huffin puffin, right?
Rym: I like to go fast.
Scott: He's trying.
Scott: he's trying hard to act to try to go fast.
Scott: So pedal harder Yeah, whereas I'm always comfortable if I'm not comfortable I try less like I'll go in the lower gear and go doo doo doo doo doo doo doo just so.
Scott: I'm always like ah At all times.
Scott: I'm never huffin and puffin.
Rym: I'm trying to beat the times.
Scott: I mean, yeah, I don't pay attention to Strava times.
Scott: I push record when I start and I don't look at again till I'm done just to record the route.
Scott: I don't care about that.
Scott: I don't even know how many trophies I got But I guess you know, you still biked a hundred miles like the top of my thighs.
Scott: We're like, obviously Yes it's a little hard whenever I but even if I bike less than that, you know, it's hard to walk up and downstairs for a little while and That's about it.
Scott: yeah,
Rym: we're back from packs and expect like ten different shows of reviews of everything and The first news we got because this
Scott: is probably the we're gonna hit another packs before we run out of chose from Yeah from this bag unplugged
Rym: is real soon and
Scott: pursue and
Rym: oss is even sooner
Scott: not going to that.
Rym: if I hadn't changed jobs I would have been going to it, but I'm not going now.
Scott: Well, you don't have a plane ticket, right?
Scott: Do you?
Rym: I don't have a I don't have a free pass to go to it.
Scott: Well, I'm just saying you sure you didn't spend money on a plane ticket.
Scott: That's not being canceled or something.
Rym: No No, I do anything like that.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So while we were at packs this new like I saw Rumblings of this news mostly through people.
Rym: It's not really a news so much as it's a Conversation that has happened before was rekindled for various reasons, right?
Scott: So basically this is platforming game.
Scott: That's I don't know if it's a good platforming game.
Scott: I haven't played it but I've seen it for quite a while.
Rym: I played a demo of it.
Rym: The only thing I'll say is that it looks rolls felt really good, right?
Rym: They felt super meat boy tight.
Scott: the visuals of this platforming game look like an old-school Mickey Mouse cartoon Which is an aesthetic that is down my alley.
Scott: I love that shit.
Scott: So that makes me want to at least play a demo of this game if not pay for it and play it for real.
Scott: But regardless there's a platforming game that apparently has some difficulty to it.
Scott: It is not easy and there was a reviewer who was playing the game and they suck.
Rym: They suck so bad.
Rym: Oh did they suck?
Scott: They sucked.
Scott: so now that that's not news the gaming community was like Hey, are you qualified to fucking review this game if you suck so much?
Rym: Real clear being good.
Scott: Are you qualified to review a car?
Scott: If you suck at driving being are you qualified to review a guitar?
Scott: Yeah, you can't play it.
Rym: Well, so the probably games being good at games does not know.
Rym: it's not the important skill.
Rym: Having knowledge about games is the important skill.
Scott: That is correct.
Rym: So I'm not mad.
Rym: like I've reviewed board gauge of steam where.
Rym: Imagine if there was video of us playing age of steam before we reviewed it.
Rym: that game kicked our asses.
Scott: It sure did and I don't think I'm ever going to become good at age of steam But we knew the history of some train games at that.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I can understand age of steam without being good at it.
Scott: I can understand go without being good at it because I have a knowledge of games qualification.
Scott: the number one qualification for reviewing things it with text is writing and the number one qualification For reviewing things with words is eloquence.
Scott: And the number two qualification is knowledge.
Rym: Cisco.
Rym: a bird did not have the skills to make movies.
Scott: No, they didn't.
Scott: they knew what made movies good and Ebert tried.
Scott: Yeah, I think I think Hebrew is the one who tried and did not make a good movie, right?
Scott: But it's like I can't design anything for shit.
Scott: But at work I can sit there and look at websites and I can't really you know I can say the font is wrong, even though I couldn't tell you what font is right.
Rym: Yep Yeah, now we're.
Rym: so I don't want to get too deep into this because I feel like there's a whole show here.
Scott: Yeah, there is definitely a whole show about this thing.
Scott: We will make the next Tuesday show all about this unless something else comes up.
Scott: Yeah, but I just wanted to get that point across.
Rym: that like, you know, I feel like the way back.
Scott: There was a dude who reviewed something for Kotaku and like he hadn't played doom and it's like.
Scott: and I actually met him at PAX And asked him about it and he was like, yeah people tried to get me to do Z doom and I couldn't make it work.
Scott: And I was like that is a problem.
Scott: Yeah, like you don't you had you hadn't?
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's okay to suck at doom.
Scott: I'm not expecting you to like beat doom on nightmare, right?
Scott: But if you haven't played doom and you can't even get it to work I think that makes you unqualified to at least review FPS is on the PC.
Rym: now to be fair There is a space in general media review and critique for the naive commentary versus the expert commentary versus the academic.
Scott: Obviously if you're someone who's an expert platformer your review of this coming from even you know A great reviewer who doesn't a skilled platformer is not going to be good.
Scott: That can help you because there's that's pretty.
Scott: imagine the review looking for what you're looking for.
Rym: Imagine the review of the unmodified original tumbleseed by someone who is an ice cold beer champion.
Rym: Exactly that review would be very different and probably just as useless as someone who had never heard of ice cold beer.
Scott: that being said A good reviewer knows all their possible audience and can write to the whole.
Scott: You know multiple audiences such that no matter who's reading it.
Scott: They'll be able to figure out if it's for them or not.
Rym: It was or was not for the review But while simultaneously being very upfront and clear about where their review was coming from and what they know and don't know and what skills They have or don't have.
Scott: yes But the point is you don't need.
Scott: Skill is not as important as knowledge and writing skill.
Scott: game skill is like the third thing Even that it might be lower than that.
Rym: And I think most of the people who are making a big ruckus about this are Gomergate shitheads.
Rym: Well, I was the impression I got.
Scott: I think I empathize with them in the same way as when I watch someone in the Omega thon.
Scott: right is like if you're You know.
Scott: It's like if I could play Mario and I'm watching someone else play Mario and they hit the first Goomba and they don't get better.
Scott: I feel this like frustration like why you know better Why you know improve.
Scott: I must help you girl right and that You know, you might you know, express this anger by saying well, you're unqualified to be a reviewer Right.
Rym: No, you're unqualified to be an omega.
Scott: Not sure but it's like, you know how you express that anger might be with false Insulting statements or who knows how but I also have those feelings when I see someone.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I feel like most of the Rabid angry response to this was the gaming.
Rym: journalism must be objective types.
Rym: Which is this?
Rym: all other ballgame of the Venn diagram, which you can be objective while being shitty.
Rym: It's oh, yeah But the Venn diagram between people who say those keywords and people are a Gomer gator shitheads is nearly a circle.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So in some other news Metroid Samus returns comes out what real soon like a couple days, right?
Scott: I think we talked about this.
Scott: when they announced it was I farted real bad.
Scott: I'm sorry but they're basically they're remade Metroid 2 which is a game that there was a fan remake of because the game at Metroid 2 if you don't know is a Game Boy game only right?
Scott: That was it.
Scott: There was no.
Scott: I guess it was also for the Super Game Boy Technically speaking like the old Mario Land.
Rym: Yeah, I led one.
Scott: Yes like that, right?
Scott: So if you played it on the Super Game Boy It had better colors and it I don't remember exactly it may have been re-released on a DX cartridge Which meant it has slightly better colors if you played it on a Game Boy color But could still be played on a regular Game Boy in black and white As well as Super Game Boy and I guess could also be played in a GBA with Game Boy color colors.
Scott: but that was it.
Scott: it was never released anything else and Most a lot of people have access to play Metroid 1 because that game was re-released in virtual consoles and things Right and people can obviously play Super Metroid very easily.
Scott: Yeah, but Metroid 2 has been hard to play without an emulator and now it's finally, you know Metroid zero mission came out for GBA and stuff right there remakes.
Scott: Metroid 2 is not remade so people don't know.
Scott: in Metroid 1 Samus goes to planet Zeebs where the space pirates are Using Metroids to conduct evil experiments and whatnot, you know You don't see any Metroids until basically the end of the game, right?
Scott: Because that's in the mother brain secret lab is where the Metroids are.
Scott: It's yeah, right.
Scott: and then in Metroid Super Metroid the game starts and it's like the last Metroid is in captivity.
Scott: The galaxy is at peace, right?
Scott: It's like what happened in Metroid 2.
Scott: Well, every Metroid except for the last one Was in captivity because of what happens in Metroid 2. right in Metroid 2 Samus goes to the homeworld of Metroids and Fucking murders.
Scott: all spoilers all the Metroids except one and that is Metroid 2 and a lot of people have missed out on that shit because it's an original Gameboy game.
Rym: now, this is a Remake meaning it is very different from Metroid 2. it is.
Scott: It is a bionic commando rearmed or maybe even more than that, but it is still.
Scott: go to planet sr 388 and kill all the Metroids.
Rym: Yeah, I think the biggest difference is.
Rym: I haven't played it yet.
Rym: I didn't get a review copy or anything.
Rym: It's a much more modern game, but I don't know.
Rym: cuz you have three you have fine-grain aiming.
Rym: Yep, which was not a thing.
Rym: No old days You just had eight-way aiming and there's this weird sort of like Counter-attack system like a fighting game.
Scott: Yeah, it's an action platformer.
Scott: Yeah, that's the kind of thing that's in Metroid games.
Rym: I'm very curious How much like a Metroid game it'll feel.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it'll be a very similar map.
Scott: You know a very similar enemy location the same story same general deal, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know I don't trust reviews really but it's getting good reviews, but I heard getting very good reviews.
Scott: I heard the Pete the studio that made.
Scott: it has not had a good track record, but it doesn't matter.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: I can finally play Metroid 2 in a tolerable fashion.
Scott: the fan remake got shut down.
Scott: This is your chance because even if you do emulate the original Metroid 2, it's not the greatest experience.
Scott: But you still want to get the whole Metroid experience.
Scott: It's still a great game.
Scott: So I think this is gonna be good.
Scott: I'm gonna play it.
Rym: Yep So in some other news while I was gone at PAX the season of overwatch ended new season began and all that nonsense They added.
Rym: because they keep adding modes.
Rym: But if you haven't played overwatch, it has like the regular quick play.
Rym: play the normal game and it doesn't matter for fun.
Rym: It has competitive which is serious and ranked and it has the arcade where basically that Replaces the mods that would be in the old FPS.
Rym: is that people in hopes themselves?
Rym: But they actually do game design on the mods and change them.
Rym: so like the the arcade rotates in these game modes and A lot of them are pretty great.
Rym: But they added something that I didn't think they would actually add.
Rym: they actually added straight-up deathmatch.
Rym: Eight people pick a character fucking frags win.
Scott: Is there a character that's OP in deathmatch?
Scott: So because you're not trying to area control or anything.
Rym: So I've noticed that I played like 10 or 15 games of it last night just to see so I could talk about it.
Rym: It seems like people who are Exceptionally good snipers are invincible and win all the time.
Scott: that makes sense.
Rym: people who are not exceptional snipers But who choose a sniper are garbage worthless and get like zero kills.
Scott: That makes sense.
Scott: That's what's true.
Rym: for FPS junk rat There's a man equivalent.
Rym: the throw bombs everywhere seems to win most games.
Scott: Really yeah Interesting.
Scott: I noticed that and that is not typical of all the sniper thing You just said it's not true since they've made a sniper rifle in an FPS.
Scott: So it kind of makes sense because when I buy the demo man thing, it's not new.
Rym: So when I played and that is new the equivalent of the demo man back in like weapons factory and we played in deathmatch modes I would just spam common areas and people would just die.
Scott: You think it's because it's low skill people.
Scott: well, but you think the dough.
Scott: I think it's good.
Rym: I kill people spamming.
Scott: Right, but it say it's low skill people walking into this.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah If it was a game of all high skill people that spamming tactic wouldn't be worth anything because no one would go in there.
Rym: Farah a flying rocket marine doesn't seem to do so well because she gets snapped out of the sky all the time Because it's not as fast as the self healers do pretty well like people who can heal themselves.
Rym: But uh, I I've won like one one.
Scott: give up less frags that way even if you get less.
Rym: for yeah I won one of them that I played and I want a hard and the one I won.
Rym: I Picked the character who can leave six little centuries around and I made death rooms and people just walked into them and died similar to the demo man strategy of spamming.
Rym: and when I did that people were Man, it's not you're so overpowered man.
Rym: Stop being so cheap you cheap piece of shit and I won Eat it.
Rym: and also when someone else tried to do the same thing, it's trivial to counters.
Rym: I don't know what these kids are complaining about.
Scott: They said
Rym: yeah But I'm very happy that the overwatch team is continuing to invest significant design resources in the like weird mod arcade because they keep changing these modes like they had a Lockout mode where it's like two teams and you fight to the death over and over again.
Rym: There's all this stuff in there.
Rym: they keep modifying the rules of that mode to make it fairer and more interesting.
Scott: This is the thing that I find the most interesting right?
Scott: Is that you know, forgive my heart stone They keep investing in it and it's like well, yeah, cuz if you play you gotta keep spending more fucking money.
Scott: Yeah, right, but overwatch get me wrong is $50 once and that's it.
Scott: You get everything for.
Scott: you can buy Packages of loot boxes, but those are like skins and shit.
Rym: Yeah People appear to buy them.
Rym: Okay I mean I got like I like.
Rym: I'd give them to you.
Rym: I forgot about those.
Rym: good.
Rym: You can't trade them.
Rym: They're just in my account not opening up.
Scott: I Did forget about those.
Scott: All right, so that's why they continue to invest in the game.
Rym: also It appears that there is a constant like new players joining the game.
Rym: You got to have a.
Scott: no Yeah, but I'm just you know.
Scott: I'm just wondering how long that can't last forever.
Scott: the new player part you the skin part is what keeps it going like dota.
Rym: Yep, right the competitive aspect might keep a core going forever.
Rym: Counter-Strike style and the eSports can write.
Scott: But as long as that as long as the eSports continues people have an interest in playing and competing and I guess some of those people like skins.
Rym: so think of this though.
Rym: remember tribes to even Counter-Strike had the issue.
Rym: that was both a positive and a negative for people can make mods and like there was an error when even When I tried to play Counter-Strike half the servers were like this World of Warcraft like the bullshittiest of bullshit mods.
Rym: And yet people want that stuff but fans who make mods tend to be garbage at it.
Rym: So Blizzard Realized what to do.
Rym: They make all the crazy mods, but they make them good.
Scott: Yeah Well, let me tell you that I read the story.
Scott: Do you read the story about the pub G guy how it happened?
Rym: No, I did not.
Scott: I'll tell you that.
Rym: Okay, cuz I'm gonna play pub G so we can talk about it.
Scott: It's the pub G seems like this unavoidable thing.
Scott: I don't want to do it.
Scott: It's just so it but it seems like I got to do it just because it's so big.
Scott: You see anything we talked about when like everyone's talking about my house Akai time.
Scott: I'm a house Akai tie Magica, I guess if you know everyone's talking about this my little pony I guess we got to go see what the deal is.
Scott: Well pub G is at that level where it's like, alright I guess we still might not get the best game.
Rym: I guess we got to see what the deal is.
Rym: stories that are coming out of it are pretty good.
Scott: I'm still.
Scott: I need to find the tutorial how to mute everyone though.
Scott: Yeah Someone said somebody send me the tutorial and had a mute everyone in pub G and then maybe we'll try it out.
Rym: We should team up.
Scott: Yeah, that sounds good.
Rym: 50% chance of winning.
Scott: Well, how do we know if we found each other?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean, I barely know how the game works.
Scott: I can explain it to you after.
Rym: I mean I know the gist of it.
Scott: I actually I did a lot.
Scott: I did a ton of research on it.
Scott: I just haven't played it.
Scott: I'm just gonna play it.
Scott: You should probably do that.
Scott: We should probably combine the research in the playing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah But anyway things of the day, so what do you got?
Scott: So someone posted this is their thing of the day in our forum which where you should go to see things like this And I thought it was so good.
Scott: I'll steal it and make it my thing of the day.
Scott: It's real good.
Scott: So this is B2k balls big adventure part 2.
Scott: I presume there's a part 1. who knows if there's a part 3?
Scott: It seems like it's from a Japanese television show.
Scott: Perhaps a children's Japanese television show would be my guess.
Rym: I'm pretty sure it's in the same universe as tumbleseed and Yeah Pythagoras Ouichi, right?
Scott: so what the deal is?
Scott: it's basically sort of a Rube Goldberg machine that is telling a story about B2k ball who's a character who is a ball and It's like usually you see a Rope Goldberg machine and it has to be like an impressive machine to like.
Scott: really, you know Impress you but this one because they incorporate a story into it.
Scott: It really gives a lot of life And I guess whimsy to what's otherwise just a pretty good Rube Goldberg machine.
Scott: This is real good yeah, so this is a a video that brings joy and happiness to the world and therefore you should watch it.
Rym: so We're old enough to where I went to LAN parties as a kid meaning I took my computer.
Rym: I took a 19 inch C a Pentium 2 computer my Pentium 2 with 200 megahertz yep, and a 19 inch.
Scott: how many how many how many megabytes of RAM did that computer have?
Scott: it had 32?
Rym: I think it only had 16.
Rym: I think I upgraded it at one point Megabytes.
Rym: Oh, right and I had.
Rym: I bought a really good sound card.
Scott: It had a floppy drive Yeah, but it only.
Rym: it only had the three and a quarter not that not the five and a half But I remember sitting in a car with my giant CRT in my lap.
Scott: LCD monitors did not exist.
Rym: Yeah, it's not even like existed, but we're good for gaming did not.
Rym: Yet now this picture is from way later than that But it is.
Scott: this is when we were in perhaps college the early 2000s.
Rym: You see a primitive LCD that probably does not have a sufficient refresh rate to actually play games.
Rym: You see old counter-strike on a CRT.
Rym: Mm-hmm real counter-strike.
Scott: the guy I played And more.
Rym: this picture is obviously taken with a non digital camera.
Scott: it appears Oh, yeah, and or a really shitty digital camera that used floppy disks for its storage.
Rym: We had one of those and there's a kid duct-taped Hanging from the ceiling playing a game on his computer.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's the.
Rym: this is my thing of the day because some reporters.
Rym: basically this picture is kind of famous.
Rym: I could see it off and on.
Rym: I've seen this Blessed image before someone tracked these kids down and figured out exactly what happened.
Rym: All right, he was on the ceiling.
Rym: Where are they now?
Rym: How did this?
Rym: is a?
Rym: where are they now?
Rym: This was a the the kid on the ceiling.
Rym: That was the second attempt because the first attempt almost ended in loss of limbs due to loss of blood flow to said limbs.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that's not an easy.
Scott: you got it.
Scott: You know, you're not gonna figure that out in the first attempt, right?
Scott: It's a learning experience a little trial and error going on.
Rym: I love when there is a weird like Widely known image on the internet and someone goes and figures out the story behind it because those stories are often Way more interesting than you'd expect.
Scott: I mean, we know the story of the goatse guy, right?
Rym: Uh, yeah, we do.
Rym: I know.
Rym: actually I know the story of a couple images.
Rym: I won't share cuz I was there and I've for that.
Rym: I'm not gonna ever talk about them because I do not want the Internet's baleful gaze to find the people that were involved For obvious reasons.
Rym: if you know what those images were what images are you talking about?
Rym: You know the the kid you won the prize that image The mentally challenged kid getting an award.
Rym: I know the names of everyone in that image.
Scott: Okay, yeah, let me see if I can find this image.
Rym: I'm not gonna pull it up here cuz I'm on the stream and I just don't want anyone to find these kids.
Rym: But yeah, they're.
Rym: not only does this reporting find all the people involved in that image, but it finds additional images From that event from other angles.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, this is pretty cool.
Scott: Oh this Boy Scout related image.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I have seen that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I know all those.
Rym: Actually, I am there behind the cat.
Rym: I did not take that picture but I am behind the camera in that picture.
Scott: Yeah, that image is not that popular.
Scott: But yes, I do remember you telling me this previously.
Rym: So this is a instance of Rym not lying the other Rare, this is my thing of the day.
Rym: Is that?
Rym: most of you will look at this image and say wow What an ancient and crazy era for that.
Rym: like old wizards Enjoyed gaming the good days.
Rym: my land party days were way before this image was taken.
Rym: To put it in perspective Play counter-strike.
Scott: You had to play doom.
Scott: And yeah, I liked it.
Rym: We were playing doom to quake.
Scott: one is for the rich kids.
Rym: Yeah, we were playing The game we played the most at this land party was action quake Mm-hmm, and it was also the land party that I saw.
Rym: father frags best.
Rym: Mm-hmm In the meta moment.
Rym: the book club book is the fifth season.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I am reading this book.
Scott: I'm basically like 40% done with his book.
Rym: I read the first chapter and I like it a lot.
Rym: You haven't even seen the second planet there on reminds me of that planet at the end of player of game.
Scott: That's also the first thing that I thought of when I thought of planets.
Rym: You don't want to live that planet at the end of player of games.
Rym: Is it a plus planet?
Scott: This is also.
Scott: there's a lot of elements of the planet from The one.
Scott: no the one with the thieves lock Lamora.
Scott: Oh, yeah with this ancient shit lying around No one knows what the hell who's from?
Rym: Yo guy, if you want to get my goat when it comes to like a book if you've got precursor technology This has more precursor shit than any Thing I've read since like star control precursor tax.
Scott: I control three which is little complicated magic system star control three Which is literally about precursors and it's like you are in the precursor vessel.
Scott: this is the Second most precursor thing.
Rym: but yeah, this is the book club.
Rym: We're both reading it.
Rym: We'll do the show at some point in the near future.
Rym: I feel like we're gonna blow through it.
Scott: It won the Hugo Award two years ago and the sequel won the Hugo Award this year and the third I guess assume final.
Scott: Maybe book is out now.
Rym: the hardcover of this apparently.
Scott: How could it be bad when it's that kind of is apparently hard to get because there's only one for sale on Amazon for 250 bucks meaning I got anyone that is made of electrons.
Rym: I also got.
Scott: that way was the cheapest version and is the most convenient regardless of its DRM.
Rym: Some people have said that books two and three are good, but not as good.
Scott: I've heard I heard wide variety of opinions on book two and three but so far reading book one and I'm you know.
Scott: Why not read book two?
Scott: if it I can go firm or deny for myself and then if book two is bad Then I can skip on three.
Rym: Yeah, it's not like the Imagine.
Scott: how could this thing that usually you know, we just talked about pub G, right?
Scott: How can a thing when it is so acclaimed by so many it almost always turns out to be there's a reason for it Except ready player one, which is trash.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I still think that was because it was.
Rym: it was sent to its perfect audience.
Scott: I just can't imagine.
Scott: How could book two of this be bad?
Scott: Anyway, you only have to read book one for the book club.
Scott: So do that.
Scott: Yep I have not heard anyone say anything bad about book one and I haven't read anything bad in book one.
Scott: So go for it.
Rym: And otherwise we were at PAX West.
Rym: we did a panel.
Rym: if you were there and you found this podcast Because of that panel and you're looking for all the videos.
Rym: We said you should watch.
Rym: You're already on the YouTube channel And if you're listening to the podcast go to our website and click on that.
Rym: live at PAX West 2017 and I linked to those videos.
Scott: I also have my own YouTube channel which is not this YouTube channel and I'm making videos on there more than I have in the past and I and somewhat consistently kept up with it.
Rym: ish and most importantly Scott produced a vlog of Our experiences daily at.
Rym: oh, yeah I did.
Scott: I made a video every day at PAX cuz.
Scott: someone said I couldn't do it and I did it the way.
Scott: I said I would do it and it worked just fine.
Scott: It was a pain in the ass because it'd be like what was already a pain in the ass because I had to edit video What in the morning it was?
Rym: No, it was a pain in the ass for me And all I had to do was stand next to you and talk for a couple minutes before I could go to bed And even that was kind of a pain in the ass.
Scott: Also, I didn't talk about it on this episode But big shake-ups are going on in the world of netrunner and I'm gonna Not talk about it on GeekNights because you don't want to hear that shit.
Scott: But I am gonna make netrunner with Scott one or two videos Probably just talking at the camera about what's going on.
Rym: You could talk about it in the first half of a show because how much do I talk about overwatch?
Rym: you can talk.
Scott: No, I know there's so much talk about netrunner.
Scott: No, cuz netrunner this so much now is like more has gone down in the past two days of netrunner.
Scott: It's like I could talk about it for like an hour.
Scott: No, I'm not gonna talk about it for an hour.
Rym: I don't even play netrunner and I get a lot of opinions about what's going down.
Rym: That's that's the scale of what's going down.
Scott: All I can say I'm gonna say on GeekNights is that if you've thought about netrunner, right?
Scott: Just wait a little bit.
Scott: they're gonna put out this new box.
Scott: just buy that one box and just play it as a two-player game with your friends and Don't buy any other stuff.
Scott: and then if you decide you want to be do tournaments and shit then come back to me.
Scott: Right, but the time for trying netrunner again is gonna be soon.
Scott: Not right now.
Rym: Yep, but soon like a couple months Maybe we probably will talk about the l5 our game at some point.
Scott: But are you buy that shit?
Scott: I'm not buying that.
Rym: I'm gonna look someone else to buy it who is not you or me.
Scott: Money on that.
Scott: I'm gonna read the room runner or bust if netrunner dies.
Scott: I'm sticking with digital games.
Rym: Yeah, I think it I got overwatch.
Rym: I'm good over.
Scott: I'll go back to regular old board games of netrunner days.
Rym: overwatch is on an upswing still.
Scott: So I mean I still play hearthstone every day.
Scott: I get to my quests.
Rym: Yeah, I uh by skipping hearthstone I have gained the world.
Rym: I can play so many other games Hearthstone Those are good games.
Rym: So now I got to play out west of loathing and hub G.
Scott: I'm gonna play west of Lothian pub G. I'm really maybe pub G, but definitely what's the loading?
Rym: Yeah west of loathing is it especially because at fax dev.
Rym: obviously I can't talk about fax dev other than that.
Rym: It was the best fax dev yet like.
Rym: for real.
Rym: for a lot of reasons I'm very happy.
Rym: I went to that fax dev but Kingdom of loathing came up like four times in independent discussions Independent of west of loathing and two of the people who brought up kingdom of loathing did not know that west of loathing came out.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Kingdom of loathing isn't?
Rym: it is more important than I had kind of expected it to be.
Rym: and Thinking back on my experiences with that game.
Rym: That game was real good.
Scott: The only thing I remember is goofballs and the misspelled cemetery.
Rym: Hey kid, you want some goofballs?
Rym: Yeah You know, it's funny because you tried the goofballs right.
Rym: I did not.
Rym: I knew better.
Scott: you never tried good Tried him several times.
Rym: I Knew better that that dude.
Rym: I did not trust him for shit.
Scott: I got on my balls I got off of goofballs, then I'm like, you know what?
Scott: Let's get on goofballs again.
Scott: I Had nothing better to do.
Rym: Let's goofball In the morning.
Rym: ask do you have any more goofballs?
Rym: The only answer to that is no one who uses goofballs has ever woken up in the morning and still had goofballs.
Rym: So We played a game with Chris Anthony and Tracy at PAX.
Rym: That is a good review because it was a. it's not a legacy game like write stuff on the board and then like it changes The story.
Rym: no, it's a game that you can play once because you destroy it physically in the course of playing.
Scott: Yes, it is a one-time use disposable board game.
Scott: you buy it.
Scott: How much does it cost?
Scott: 15 20 bucks?
Rym: Yeah, not much.
Scott: you open it you play it with your friends It takes about an hour and then it's done which actually you might think oh what a waste of money that is.
Scott: It's like hey asshole You probably spent fifteen dollars just for one movie ticket for one person down here for about the same amount of time And this is giving you four friends or five friends or more.
Scott: How many players is it?
Rym: Uh Many yeah six.
Scott: Yeah up to six people can have an hour of fun With the one but so it's only been the disposable part, right?
Scott: Right here.
Rym: I have an ogre box that I have played point five times.
Scott: I'll pay The amount of money it costs are one person to go to sit in one seat at one hockey game.
Scott: You could buy this.
Scott: How many times could you buy this game?
Rym: So this game.
Scott: so there's nothing wrong with the disposable factor of this game.
Rym: Yep, I had the fun per dollar was well within reason.
Rym: we played exit the game Secret lab and it's important to say the whole title because there's an entire series of exit games Including such titles as the Polar Station the Pharaoh's tomb The Forbidden Castle the Forgotten Island and the Abandoned Cave.
Scott: So what the deal is?
Rym: something something.
Scott: So what the deal with this is?
Scott: it's basically an escape room in a box, right?
Scott: It's made of paper and bits but it's an escape room.
Scott: Yep, and it's the fact it is.
Rym: I would say it is functionally indistinguishable from a real physical high money escape room.
Scott: For every escape room that I have seen I agree.
Rym: so I don't do the full disclosure I have done because Emily's company.
Rym: in the previous one We did like an outing where we all went to one of those like fancy escape rooms in Manhattan.
Rym: Mm-hmm It was real good like the production value was way higher than you would expect but not high enough for Scott.
Scott: How much did it cost?
Rym: I don't know nothing because I just went to it.
Scott: Okay, but I bet it cost more than $15 for six people.
Rym: Yeah, definitely definitely but the only benefit the only difference between the physical big-money escape room and this is that Some of the puzzles involved crazy complicated physical shit Like there's a bust in a room and if you move it somewhere else a door opens like it's
Scott: a silver monkey.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but it's all triggered with like switches and stuff.
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: it's actually like built to work for real.
Rym: Sure this Basically only has paper and cardboard.
Scott: Yeah There's a card mechanism where you can tell if you've solved the riddle or not and then it will take you.
Scott: you open up the Next thing and now you're in the next room and you get more stuff.
Scott: So you can solve more riddles to get more stuff to solve more riddles and eventually you saw the final riddle and it's like Congratulations.
Scott: in it you read the end of the story.
Rym: So this instance exit the game.
Rym: the secret lab won the 2017.
Scott: Kenner's field is yar Which is the kids field is yar which makes perfect sense because I thought Kenner Wasn't that the kinder spiel.
Rym: the Kenner is like the puzzle one.
Rym: I thought I don't know.
Scott: I don't figure it out.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's not the regular spiel the jar, but it's still great enough to be worthy of winning an award, right?
Scott: So here's the thing.
Scott: I'm really not a fan personally of escape rooms.
Scott: it's just like.
Scott: I don't like them.
Scott: and the number one reason I don't like them is because I Feel like yes Kenner's real is the connoisseur slash expert game.
Scott: This is not a connoisseur expert game.
Rym: Well, it's niche though It is.
Rym: this is you know You talk about gaming and how.
Rym: there's like niche market core market extent like all those different markets.
Rym: This is definitely at bet.
Rym: you could probably sell these extended market But this is definitely like aimed at niche slash core.
Scott: Yes But anyway, the thing I don't like about escape rooms is I think that they're basically it's a misnomer, right?
Scott: It's like when I think of an escape room.
Scott: if I'm gonna go to a physical place you think of saw Alright.
Scott: Like if I'm gonna pay to go to escape room, I'm thinking not this kind of random puzzle numerology bullshit.
Scott: It's like I want some Houdini shit, right?
Scott: Time me the fuck up with chains and locks.
Scott: It's like good luck motherfucker We're closing the safe on you.
Scott: Well, that's an escape.
Rym: You want to like break a window and now you're in.
Rym: basically American Ninja Warrior Had this idea.
Scott: It's similar to my feelings on haunted houses, right?
Scott: It's like you go to a haunted house and you know that it's some guy jumping out going boo And it's like whatever you want a haunted house or a guy comes out and actually cuts you a little like hey, that would be Okay.
Scott: But what I really want is a haunted house.
Scott: you go in the haunted house and then they're like they turn on the lights on And the fire alarm goes off and they're like and the guy takes off his ghost sheet and he's like, oh, sorry guys I guess we got to evacuate.
Rym: Oh and then three years later.
Rym: You're still in the game.
Rym: You go like home with your wife.
Scott: you open the emergency exit the emergency exit opens up you go out down some stairs.
Scott: You're obviously behind the scenes, you know, you're actually.
Scott: you know, you're.
Scott: you feel like you're not in the haunted house anymore but you.
Rym: So it's actually scary.
Rym: did you ever see the movie the game?
Scott: No, is that what that is?
Rym: That's what that is.
Rym: It's actually a pretty good movie.
Scott: How come I can't go to the game in real life?
Scott: There are places to do that in New York actually, but I would know that is that kind of place when I'm going there.
Rym: Well, that's the plot of this movie the game which I remember liking as a kid because I was in like high school.
Rym: I do not know if it holds up.
Scott: We have to set up what looks like a perfectly innocent haunted house at a tourist attraction.
Scott: That's not.
Rym: Well Scott, so the game was made by the same person who made seven.
Scott: so good movie.
Scott: That's it Anyway, so the point is the escape rooms.
Scott: what they really are what they should be called is solve stupid number and letter riddles.
Rym: They're way more specific than that.
Rym: escape rooms almost always follow a very specific pattern.
Rym: There are a number of gates and again the gate can be.
Rym: anything could be a lock It could be a pot doesn't matter.
Rym: It's a gate and the gates require between one and five alphanumeric inputs.
Rym: Mm-hmm So you the puzzle is the puzzle.
Rym: all like every puzzle all bakes down to What combination of things that I have access to.
Rym: can I convert somehow into the correct number of Inputs of the correct type.
Scott: It's really like open these five combination locks, but we're not gonna just give you the numbers We're gonna give you the numbers heavily heavily obvious gate.
Rym: So I tend to solve them by looking for all.
Rym: right, we need five inputs in this puzzle.
Rym: Is there five of anything anywhere?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Well, there's five balls on the ground.
Rym: So, let's see if there's a way to translate balls into numbers, right?
Rym: So it is but there's one other mechanic.
Rym: The other thing that these all have in common is you'll have at almost every moment multiple gates Some of which can be solved with the data you already have and some of which can be solved either With the data you already have coupled with external knowledge or the data You already have coupled with data you get when you get through further lock Parallel.
Scott: they don't give you.
Scott: They also give you data in advance that you don't need yet because the gate is not available yet and they'll give you gates You don't have the data for yet and so on and so forth.
Scott: So now you have to figure out not only how to you know Use the information to create the codes you need but also which information is relevant to which thing.
Rym: Yep So what they also do not do is they never.
Rym: they don't have fatal consequences like well you fucked it up.
Rym: They don't have just time.
Scott: it's like how fast can you get out?
Scott: or do you get out in time?
Rym: Yep, that's it.
Rym: They don't have triggers like oh You didn't diffuse the bomb right now the bombs gonna go off sooner or like one of your teammates is out of the game Or anything like that.
Scott: I would be better I think but no they don't.
Rym: so no, that'd be awesome.
Rym: You like open the wrong side.
Scott: It would be better if they did that.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it'd be better than what escape rooms are right if they had bombs that go off.
Scott: It's like up.
Scott: Sorry you paid for this escape room, but you didn't solve the bomb and it blew up everyone out.
Scott: Basically other than done the physical don't get to see the rest of the escape room.
Rym: pay and try again other than the physical Aesthetic of being in an actual physical room Exit the game is basically identical to the experience of an actual escape room Mm-hmm.
Scott: So while it is fun to solve riddles, I guess if you like solving, you know cryptogram type You know things.
Scott: it's fun to an extent, you know, you can get tired of it after a while, but it's okay.
Scott: It's more fun to do it with friends because they can help each other out You know, especially if no, you know, if you have a person who's smart enough They can just figure the whole thing out by themselves.
Scott: But it's more fun to sort of collaborate and also because there's multiple things to work on simultaneously.
Scott: You know It's like you can get through more efficiently with more people like me and Tracy were like puzzle over those flags.
Rym: Well, you guys working on a puzzle.
Scott: I didn't even really interact with yeah, but then the stuff comes together And you put your pieces together, right?
Scott: It's like y'all.
Scott: it's fun to solve riddles with friends and this will give you about an hour of fun riddle solving with friends Which is perfectly fine.
Scott: But I'm still not really into escape rooms.
Scott: It's like I wouldn't go out and like Obsessively go get the whole set of these.
Rym: These are a great convention game and I like convention.
Rym: if anyone brings one of these I haven't played to a convention I'm at.
Rym: I'll probably just play it.
Scott: It's the kind of thing where I'd be in the mood to do it once in a while.
Scott: Right, like I give you brought one out of these like say Scott.
Scott: Let's do one now.
Scott: I'd like no If you if you even brought one on the weekend with a bunch of people I'd be like no I just did that.
Scott: I'm not feeling that stupid thing again.
Rym: But I like next year a pad wax.
Scott: next year You got another one and it like if it's the Pharaoh's tomb one, I'd probably do it.
Scott: Yeah, but if it's what were the other lame ones, I don't the polar one.
Scott: Yeah, I'd be like, yeah I don't wanna do the polar one.
Rym: I don't know you're right.
Rym: Did you hear the terror, right?
Scott: I could do some polar and I didn't read the tower, but I don't care.
Rym: I mean, I might make that the next book club book even though I've read it before.
Rym: cuz that's cheating.
Scott: Oh, you want to do that?
Scott: All right, once the future King.
Scott: Here we go.
Scott: I've read it.
Rym: Have you read it?
Rym: Yeah, I'll read it again.
Scott: I love I'll have to find a book.
Rym: I've read that you haven't read a careful son cuz Katamani Christo is the sword of damn.
Rym: No, it's the book of Damocles hanging over you because if it fell on you would kill you just the same as a sword.
Scott: I just wouldn't read it.
Scott: what you can do about it.
Scott: Okay, make me you can't make me.
Rym: Yeah, you know ruin the book club the social contract.
Scott: I'll get the cliff.
Scott: note.
Scott: what you can do bad kinda You know what?
Scott: I'll watch a movie which you can do bad.
Scott: The movies are all I can fool you.
Scott: The clue.
Scott: I watch the anime.
Rym: I've also watched the anime.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I would know specifically if you only watch the anime because there are things I Forget most of the anime.
Rym: the anime is great.
Rym: Actually, like I think the anime Katamani Christo is more in the spirit of the book despite taking Gratuitous liberties than any other adaptation of the Katamani Christo anyone has ever made.
Rym: But the end to the anime is Bullshit, it is a terrible ending Like it is so bad and so poorly done that it kind of ruined.
Rym: like that is an a - B plus anime.
Rym: If you don't watch the last episode if you watch the last episode, it's like B. Maybe it'd be probably just a B maybe B - anyway.
Scott: Exit game thingy if you got enough friends who like solving number-letter Visual kind of puzzles.
Scott: Yeah, right the kind of friends who would be excited if you told them you had tickets to an escape room.
Scott: And if you don't mind spending 15 dollars for an hour of fun with five or six friends that you can only do one time Then buy one of these things and go for it.
Scott: And maybe if your friends are the kind who are way into it, you could buy a whole set of these things and go nuts.
Scott: Otherwise, you know, maybe let someone else like I did spend the money and just tag along and play for free Totally worth doing it at least one time.
Scott: You know, hey, yeah, and it's you know, it's pretty it's even if you don't like doing the thing.
Scott: The thing I think I enjoyed the most about it actually was not the solving of the puzzles cuz like I can get that just Like solving puzzles in a puzzle book from the drugstore.
Scott: Yeah, it was seeing how They put this thing together like whoa.
Scott: Oh, yeah The the double index look up right the double index with the cards and the paper you tear apart like how it was physically Constructed was very clever and like it's like oh the people who made this.
Scott: I see what they did there.
Scott: That is cool.
Scott: Yeah, how they do that.
Scott: There's like a Pete.
Scott: There's like a little clock and a compass we made and stuff.
Rym: Yeah, the only the only right herring we ran into was for a minute.
Rym: We were all like is this star tropics?
Rym: We need to make this wet.
Scott: so he's Licked my finger and then rubbed my spit on the paper cuz we didn't have any water available and I didn't want to make the Whole paper soggy Scott.
Rym: There was water 12 feet away from.
Scott: I didn't want to make the I didn't want like soggy the whole paper like destroy it right.
Scott: But I thought hey, maybe if I breathe on it like ink will magic ink will appear.
Scott: Yeah, they should have done that missed opportunity the physicality of $15.
Scott: They should be doing that.
Rym: Yeah, like we had to tear some stuff apart and we're like, oh we don't think we need to tell this.
Rym: No, we needed to tear it apart.
Rym: Yeah, the physicality of it was pretty good.
Rym: Mm-hmm the only problem with these games is that The puzzle like the logic of the puzzle a couple of times barely made sense.
Scott: Well, I mean the fiction of these things never make sense.
Scott: It's like oh I locked you in my lab and made yourself puzzles before you Know the fiction of this way.
Scott: I'm the riddler.
Rym: The fiction of this one was that we're mixing different chemicals together to make compounds.
Rym: Yeah, that was not Nonsense, but the problem is that the logic of like, how did they expect you to solve the puzzle?
Rym: Like what was the chain of logic that they expect you to solve it with?
Rym: We solved some of them not quite that way because you don't need to have a logical chain You just need to be able to convert the right number of inputs.
Scott: Yes I love basically as I was solving it.
Scott: I just looked past all the fiction and only looked at the numbers and letters Colors did.
Rym: did I?
Rym: did I do a transformation that made five alphanumeric characters come up?
Rym: that is almost definitely the answer.
Rym: Yep, and we were never wrong if we weren't able to make an output we were right.
Rym: The only times we were wrong is when we made an output from scratch Just like if you're looking to be immersed in the fiction Yeah, this is not gonna help you.
Scott: neither is even the most high-production quality escape room.
Scott: You're gonna need the Scott level escape room to be immersed in the picture.
Scott: That's the only way it's gonna happen.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon.
Rym: patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette roundabout dot.
Rym: mp3.
Rym: mystady.com.
Rym: William Isen rose.
Rym: Jeremy minor a genuine bonafide.
Rym: electrified six-car monorail Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Chinguac see Rebecca Dunn for two one creations.
Rym: Even if we were to pull out today and if they would come.
Rym: take our base Shervin about horrible rare Laval James David Wright Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboys sailor moon moon sailor Vista Don sh like Cuz our television.
Rym: Joe Shiro Joe star Sean Yeager star Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent drew open-lander.
Rym: Brian Cedroni thin Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We're back guys.
Rym: It's time for GeekNights.
Rym: We're gonna try to keep doing episodes right up until PAX Unplugged and then that'll probably cause another hiatus.
Rym: also stay tuned for a bunch of patreon specific content as Emily and I start reviewing every single Disney animated feature in Chronological order and we got some other reviews and things coming.
Rym: But now I leave you with.
Rym: The hunger is never ending.
Rym: the hunger Is never filling Always thrilling till it burdens your soul and you fall Into a bottomless hole.
Rym: the hunger Is never ending.
Rym: the hunger Is never filling Always thrilling till it burdens you up any play but you Look into the eyes of the wall Black and coal red and all and you look into the eyes of the beast.