Scott: It's Monday November 7th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We'll be discussing window managers and some other crap.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Hahaha.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: All right, so Paris is still burning When it's not burning like in the old.
Scott: now.
Rym: the picture on the news right now shows something burning.
Scott: Yeah, okay So there it's not burning down like when they'll burn the whole thing down.
Scott: now There's no Bastille going down, but I mean people are burning.
Scott: a lot of cars Houses.
Rym: yeah, they finally killed someone.
Scott: Okay, they got one guy great.
Rym: Though apparently the only real news now is that the police got someone.
Rym: no no some kids killed an old man.
Rym: They beat him up while he was trying to put out a trash fire.
Scott: I thought the police finally killed one rioter.
Rym: No, they've arrested thousands.
Rym: It's not doing okay.
Scott: They have a jail that big.
Scott: I don't know what they're doing.
Scott: They reopen the Bastille.
Rym: the news isn't so informative.
Rym: The only real news is that the rioting is spread to Belgium and apparently some German suburbs now, too.
Scott: I don't think it's that widespread there because I was listening to another podcast.
Scott: the guys in Belgium today?
Rym: Oh, no, it's not because both of those countries reacted immediately.
Scott: No, okay Yeah rioting Poor people.
Rym: yeah I mean everyone's.
Rym: a lot of people in the news are trying to blame this on the Muslims who are rioting in the North Africans are a rioting, but the only common threat is that they're all poor.
Scott: if you're poor You don't have a job.
Scott: you got nothing to do you got no money.
Rym: You're right Or you do something else.
Scott: So worse almost as bad as rioters is SEO, so what do they do now?
Scott: so SEO?
Scott: Has demanded from IBM Information about Linux kernel version Because that exists.
Scott: That's the story.
Rym: I Want 2.7.
Rym: I want that information now, too.
Scott: Well it so far.
Scott: They've discussed it.
Scott: on the mailing list There isn't I don't think a single line of code in it.
Scott: There's no 2.7.
Scott: There's a theoretical 2.7.
Rym: There's a three or a theoretical 9. yep You know I'd love to be there physically at the trial.
Rym: well I could see SEO standing there And they've made their claim and they know they say what they want and then the IBM guy stands up and says That doesn't exist.
Rym: you might all have asked me for the flying spaghetti monsters newly appendage But the flying one the spaghetti monster is real damn straight.
Rym: Uh Yeah, though that stupid intelligent design trial is over.
Rym: It's over.
Scott: Well if it's over How can the judge hasn't said anything?
Rym: now the judge is sitting in his room thinking about whether he's gonna side with science or crazy.
Scott: How what takes him so long to think?
Scott: okay?
Scott: You're judges you've heard everything.
Scott: There's nothing new to hear.
Rym: Maybe he only works like Monday through Friday, so we had the weekend off and now he's gonna make his decision today And he'll say it tomorrow.
Scott: Ah it was.
Scott: oh, so he's gonna say it on a different day, then he comes up with it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know how that works.
Scott: I think he's a lazy judge trying to get a little vacation.
Rym: Yeah, the only funny thing that came out of it was that the Vatican came out and said that ideas crap.
Scott: I don't know if that was just one.
Scott: no I don't know if that was the Vatican or just a guy.
Rym: is the official position of the Vatican unless the Pope says otherwise?
Scott: Yeah But me all.
Scott: there's a story about it.
Scott: on slash that I scrolled down.
Scott: yeah, and there was one guy who was like You know I'm an ID proponent whatever.
Scott: everyone else is just like science.
Scott: woot right uh-huh.
Scott: But even that guy didn't know what ID.
Scott: he didn't know what ID was and he was a proponent of it.
Scott: So yeah Yeah, yeah, of course some people are that way about Darwinism.
Scott: all are also her opponents of it.
Scott: They don't know what it is.
Rym: People tend to be opponents of things that they don't really understand.
Scott: It's gonna think they understand.
Scott: I mean they're proponents of what they think.
Scott: Anyone's a proponent of what they think.
Rym: yeah, cuz I'm very much a fan of.
Rym: Rym is awesome.
Scott: ice you think wrong.
Scott: Who is that?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: that's good.
Scott: that means you don't have to Pay attention, it's someone local.
Rym: I have no idea who it is.
Scott: I'll just yeah screw it.
Scott: Anyway, we'll have to cut that out or something.
Scott: leave it doesn't matter.
Scott: so that guy was on death row.
Rym: Okay, so a guy was on death row.
Rym: What do you do?
Scott: He escaped?
Rym: No?
Rym: No, I mean, what did he do to get on death row?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't read that part.
Rym: I mean is this a real murder?
Rym: ten kids.
Scott: Oh, yeah, he was.
Scott: he was a bad guy Anyway, but he escaped.
Scott: they thought that they're like someone helped him escape like this anti death row group But they they were acquitted.
Scott: they didn't do anything.
Scott: Uh-huh this guy just like I think he walked out like in.
Scott: I don't know how he got out But anyway, he was on the run.
Scott: So they made a huge manhunt of course, which is they should do yeah, and They got him.
Scott: He was drunk in a phone booth.
Scott: awesome Cuz you know when I escaped from prison, I'm gonna get drunk and hang out in phone booth where I won't get caught.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I mean I would have gone one step To go.
Rym: You know, hey escaped Serial killer looking for some.
Rym: I don't know whatever escaped serial killers are looking for.
Scott: I just go to freakin Mexico or something where they couldn't get me.
Scott: I wouldn't hang around and get drunk in the country that are running away from huh?
Rym: Obviously, let me put it this way.
Rym: He's on death row.
Rym: So whatever he did he got caught.
Rym: If you're not smart enough to avoid the police, you're probably not smart enough to avoid them again.
Rym: Yeah I could have run to Somalia Where the pirates are where the pirates are and we're apparently the reason there's pirates because there's no government at all.
Scott: There was a government.
Rym: There hasn't been a government in Somalia for a fairly long time So it's just anarchy.
Rym: pretty much ever since the ruling party was deposed There's really no consensus as to what the actual government of the country is.
Scott: So why don't we just go there and do something?
Rym: because the country's split into these five.
Scott: don't talk about you and me.
Rym: The country's fell into these five like fiefdoms and they're run by these warlords and each have their own army.
Scott: Okay, so this there is someone in charge.
Rym: Yeah, but there's no.
Scott: can't just go in and set up our own warlordness.
Rym: Yeah, Somalia is just a bunch of little like bickering countries now.
Scott: All right.
Scott: What are you gonna do?
Rym: So after this whole pirate attack the u.s.
Rym: Said hey clean up your act in Somalia said We're a bunch of warlords.
Scott: What are you gonna do?
Rym: We don't have ships.
Scott: Okay, we'll pirate you.
Rym: if you come to help us you can clear out the pirates.
Rym: we won't stop you.
Scott: yeah Pirates.
Rym: now, I wouldn't have even brought up the pirate attack.
Rym: I mean it that happens all the time is not that big a deal, but that's the captain was awesome.
Rym: This is probably the most interesting pirate attack in the last couple years.
Scott: Now there's some interesting pirate attacks.
Rym: Yeah, this one was pretty interesting.
Scott: I mean the thing is it is a cruise ship.
Scott: It wasn't like a boat full of stuff.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was a cruise ship and the pirates had RPGs.
Rym: they always have RPGs Yeah, and they fired a whole bunch of them at the cruise ship and they always do that.
Scott: that that's not the part.
Rym: That's they really only succeeded in breaking a few windows.
Scott: Well, no, they blew up one cabin, but no one was in it.
Rym: No, one person was in it.
Rym: She was taking a bath.
Rym: So she didn't get hit by the shrapnel.
Scott: That's not what I read.
Rym: That's what I read.
Scott: conflicting story.
Rym: In fact, I'm looking at that story right now.
Rym: There's another guy.
Rym: he's a World War two veteran and he was trying to take a picture of one of the pirates and Quote the man with the bazooka.
Rym: aimed it right at me and I saw a big flash.
Rym: Needless to say I dropped the camera and dived the grenade struck two decks above in about four rooms further forward.
Rym: I could tell the guy firing the bazooka was smiling Great.
Rym: Apparently.
Rym: the captain of the cruise ship tried to ram the pirates a couple times Yep, and he totally ran away with his ultra fast cruise ship.
Rym: Yep, there was some quote where the captain says something to the effect of.
Rym: I didn't know this thing could go that fast.
Scott: Yeah, but the stories I read didn't have passengers doing stuff.
Scott: it was like all the passengers were shoved into the center of the ship and the captain got everyone off the deck.
Scott: and You know, no one got hurt.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: No one got hurt.
Rym: They all got good stories.
Rym: I imagine they all get refunds or something.
Scott: Well, I can imagine they're gonna finish their cruise first.
Rym: Yeah, well the ship was kind of RPG.
Rym: I think they have to put him on a different ship.
Scott: No, it still works.
Scott: Boats very hard to sink.
Scott: a boat, you know, yeah Titanic it's sunk when it hit this iceberg.
Scott: It's so hard to do.
Scott: the iceberg was so big.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: I Mean, you know, you're like oil like spills here.
Rym: It is quote my quote.
Rym: a woman survived an explosion in her stateroom Simply because she was taken to Bath.
Rym: at the time.
Rym: others flung themselves to the floor to avoid bullets that were zipping through the ship.
Rym: They were only gathered after the pirates attacked the store.
Scott: The story I read was like an RPG hit the boat and exploded in.
Scott: it blew up a cabin but no one was in it.
Rym: Well, there was a woman in that cabin.
Scott: Oh, maybe it was a different cabin.
Scott: two different RPGs.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah so Some other down today Rocksters gone.
Scott: They were gone before now.
Rym: They're actually gone.
Rym: They had to pay 50 million and they're out of business.
Scott: All right One more p2p Network.
Scott: that's gone.
Rym: Luckily.
Rym: We still have the Pirates Bay Unlike the Somalian pirates.
Scott: Yeah, Pirates Bay has a Yeah, yeah It's much better at pirating and it doesn't kill people with RPGs.
Rym: Aha, unless they download Final Fantasy 7, but I'm It's bad.
Rym: that was awesome, yeah, that's bad.
Rym: That was awesome.
Scott: It's bad.
Scott: Well, you know, uh, even though Somalia has no government We have a government.
Rym: Yeah, what about it?
Scott: We vote for it tomorrow.
Scott: Oh, yeah Election Day, but it's just shitty town government.
Rym: See, I really I was excited because I like the town we live in beacon and I wanted to get active.
Rym: but I read the proposals of the two sides and It's all either FUD or just straight-up BS and neither one of them actually has a blue thing.
Scott: Is those are just like the vote for me pamphlets?
Scott: We have to find like the position things which is not easy to find because apparently the town is internet incompetent.
Rym: Yes Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I'm gonna go in and vote But I don't think I'm gonna vote for any people.
Rym: I'm only gonna vote on any propositions that may happen to be.
Scott: I'm gonna go in and I'll look at it and you know I'll look and I'll see if there's anything that looks like I want to vote for it.
Scott: I'll click it and everything else.
Scott: I just leave it whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, there's supposed to be some town propositions and stuff.
Rym: move and vote for a judge, but There's even a story on park today about how I think less than a quarter of people are gonna vote in this election because no One cares.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: Nothing's not nothing's at stake.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It is a school board voting.
Scott: I'll vote for the non-incumbent school board.
Rym: I think I'm gonna vote for a non-incumbent anything forever until things change.
Scott: Yeah, but that won't make things change.
Scott: I don't think it would have.
Rym: everyone did but not everyone will.
Scott: yeah Oh, well, what are you gonna do?
Rym: I'm gonna get me a DS and my Wi-Fi.
Scott: We already have a DS.
Scott: It already has Wi-Fi just doesn't have a game to play.
Rym: Yeah, Mario Kart's coming out.
Rym: When's it coming out?
Scott: the 14th?
Scott: I'm gonna be there ASAP And I'll become the grand master of Mario Kart DS as I was the grand master of Mario Kart.
Rym: GBA will see.
Scott: It's not even like a see it.
Scott: It's it's you will see because it will happen.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: it's like there isn't doubt But at least apparently works with every frickin router unless you're using WPA then it won't work.
Scott: yeah, but if you don't have a you know an open wireless or a WEP wireless or a Buffalo AOS s access point you can use.
Scott: You know, you can use the little USB Thingy, yeah the little dongle.
Scott: So like if there's.
Scott: only if the only access around is like a pay t-mobile hotspot.
Scott: Well, the DS can't really use that But your laptop can use that and then you put the USB thing in the laptop and then you're good.
Scott: But I don't know if it's Windows only which I'm pretty sure it is.
Rym: That's what I've read.
Rym: It's Windows XP only.
Scott: Oh, that's really kind of Blair.
Scott: I mean at least all Windows is and Mac.
Scott: I mean I can understand if you're not Linux II but you should be Linux II though Yeah, you should.
Scott: hell they should make it like Mac.
Rym: people are real tick that it's not Mac friendly.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: They could have done they could have made it like a Java app to start it up.
Scott: Who who would have thought of that, huh?
Scott: haha Yeah bastards You know now if I'm somewhere where you know, there's no, you know wireless that the DS can actually use them.
Rym: I'm SOL Yeah, but that's fine because I still have a million single-player games to beat.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just not gonna buy the USB thing.
Rym: I don't think we don't need it.
Scott: We don't need it in the house.
Scott: But what if we go somewhere?
Rym: I Imagine places like Otakon and All the other cons we go to here.
Scott: What do you do like a hotel and they have pay wireless?
Scott: I mean there are actually a couple hotels signed up to have DS access points the same way McDonald's does.
Scott: I think it was like participating Region sees or something like that.
Scott: I didn't I don't remember but you know, what if I go to like, you know Marriott was not one of the ones listed.
Rym: We wouldn't pay for that.
Rym: Anyway, I mean at the Renaissance where we stay for Otakon every year.
Rym: It's like 10 bucks a day to get access.
Scott: I can't believe they charge.
Scott: Oh my god business travelers pay it so dumb.
Rym: No, I'm a company.
Scott: what if I go somewhere in a business trip?
Scott: my company picks up the tab.
Scott: How am I need to?
Rym: uh, when is your company gonna send you on a business trip?
Scott: No, they almost sent me to Florida.
Scott: Great.
Rym: So you get to go to Florida.
Rym: I get to go to like Connecticut, Connecticut school Not Windsor, Connecticut, it's just a little suburb.
Scott: Yeah, most of Connecticut is a suburb.
Scott: In fact, the whole state is pretty much a suburb.
Scott: Haha, except for like two cities and a nuclear submarine factory The rest of its suburb all of it.
Scott: Yeah whole thing.
Scott: So on the internet today, well actually kinda yesterday there was this website.
Scott: I said greatest internet moments.
Rym: Is This a real list or is this a stupid list?
Scott: Well the list it wasn't any sort of official list, but the good thing about this site is it brought back many lost Artifacts.
Rym: welcome to Zombocom.
Scott: Zombocom wasn't one of them at least not one.
Scott: I saw what it might have been there.
Scott: I just didn't see it.
Scott: But it had.
Scott: it reminded me of the the Chow Chow a little stick figure fighting.
Scott: Oh And it reminded me Radisco.
Scott: I am the radis skull Yeah, and it reminded me of the long-lost.
Scott: Hi here you G.
Rym: Oh God, I'll have to link to that because I don't even know what to call it.
Scott: well, you know people haven't seen that.
Scott: a lot of people who've only been around since like You know Recently, they never saw this stuff.
Rym: Well, actually it was a while ago.
Rym: I was at work and So they'd all discovered banana phone, you know, oh great.
Rym: So they discovered it and they were laughing at it and I was like, oh, it's just like badgers and they're like what now badgers What's this?
Scott: He didn't know the badgers.
Rym: I had to show him the badgers.
Scott: There was a guy I heard in a podcast today.
Scott: It seemed like to me like he just discovered the Numa Numa dance.
Rym: Oh The Numa Numa dance is a Star Wars.
Scott: Yeah Yeah Star Wars kid and I think that's just.
Scott: you know, I can't think of any other ones but This website was just loaded with all that stuff and you bring it back home.
Scott: star was on there.
Rym: Yeah, home stars still going but I don't watch it anymore.
Scott: It was real good in the day But I just kind of lost interest.
Scott: I imagine it's still the same but it's just more of the same.
Rym: No, cuz remember the good old days before the gimmicks.
Scott: You know, I'm 75% sure that my email was the gimmick email.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I have it somewhere.
Rym: How'd you claim to fame here?
Scott: Of course, I think they changed, you know my name on it and stuff Whatever.
Scott: You see anything cool?
Rym: Actually, there's something weird out of Korea because everything weird that happened comes out of Korea Nowadays, yeah, but it isn't you isn't the usual stuff.
Rym: It isn't like kid dies playing video games or crazy moon water.
Rym: It's this eight-year-old who's going to university And it happens all the time.
Rym: Yeah song you win Wants to build flying cars and all this other stuff, apparently.
Scott: Yeah I remember when I was in second grade and they were like, what's it gonna be like in the year 2000?
Scott: and everyone was like Flying cars and I made a flying car to construct but it's year 2005.
Scott: There's no fucking flying cars.
Rym: the thing is the article isn't real informative and As I read it it looks there's no like.
Rym: oh you scored this well on this test or blah blah blah and There's a chance that this is some sort of crazy publicity stunt could be a crazy publicity stunt.
Rym: It was just a slow day on the internets and this was the coolest thing I saw.
Scott: Hmm, you know, I think if we actually educated kids properly though that they would be that smart at that age.
Scott: Yeah, or at least you know the ones that were smart.
Rym: I mean, I remember in fifth grade or no God for fourth or fifth grade one of those two years They had a little pilot program.
Rym: You can stay after school and they teach algebra.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I did that in fifth grade and We learned algebra and we learned that.
Rym: Oh, it's really easy.
Rym: Why didn't you teach us this sooner?
Scott: Yep I remember in first grade they gave us like math problems where there'd be a box and the box might be on the other side.
Scott: It'd be equal.
Scott: Oh, you might have you fill in the box and then later when they showed me algebra I was like, I could have done this in freaking first grade.
Scott: I've been bored in math class for five years.
Scott: Why did you freakin say something?
Rym: Yeah, I think the educators in this country really underestimate kids.
Scott: Well, you know no child left behind.
Rym: Yeah Yeah I gotta gotta go to that lowest common denominator and everyone underestimates kids.
Scott: if we ready we let kids run the country.
Scott: They who you wouldn't have a deficit.
Scott: He couldn't have a war.
Rym: Imagine we'd have some other problems like All the retirement money and Social Security probably disappear.
Scott: The kids like their grandparents, yeah grandparents spoil them.
Scott: they might let them have it.
Rym: I Picture wars starting over silly things.
Scott: at least it's bet young for his old is better than poor verse rich.
Rym: Yeah First remember the u.s.
Rym: Didn't sign the Human Rights Accord specifically because the Human Rights Accord gave rights to children.
Scott: Well, no, they specifically didn't sign it for other reasons.
Scott: That's just one of those.
Rym: one of the reasons one of the main ones because they didn't the way it was worded Technically you couldn't take you like America.
Rym: children aren't allowed to sign contracts and things like that And legally that would make it so.
Rym: children can sign contracts.
Scott: Those should be able to sign contracts.
Scott: Yeah, in fact, you know what?
Scott: There are some people who are old enough and allowed to sign contracts You shouldn't and there are children who can who aren't allowed to.
Scott: I say if you can understand the contract and prove you understand It then you can sign it.
Scott: It doesn't matter you can't.
Rym: age discrimination that what I can't really have.
Rym: subjective measures like.
Scott: well You know you.
Scott: someone reads the cut.
Rym: you say who says they're the authority?
Scott: No Someone reads the contract.
Scott: then they explain what they just read.
Scott: if they're accurate then they can sign it.
Rym: Who do they explain it to what if the lawyers?
Rym: ha because the lawyers are because the judge is always the smartest person Not just the elected schmo who even if he's not the smartest person.
Scott: He's a judge.
Scott: He judges.
Scott: That's his job.
Scott: Yeah, he's the one who judges.
Rym: I don't know how much I trust some judges.
Scott: sometimes Do you need a jury to sit there and listen to someone describe the contract?
Scott: They just read to prove that they don't know.
Rym: Crap people on a jury or people who can't.
Scott: it has to be someone who decides things.
Scott: We have we have people deciding things.
Scott: We need someone to decide.
Scott: that's who it is as a judge.
Scott: That's the way it works.
Scott: See the thing if you don't like what a judge decides you can get a smarter judge who's been a judge for longer.
Rym: Four tries it doesn't matter cuz that's not how it is.
Scott: It's not how it is.
Scott: That's how it should be and we'll see.
Rym: Well, we won't see you cuz things buy whatever change not anytime soon.
Scott: Anyway, no not soon.
Scott: unless we get some off Parising happening around here We're not gonna have Parising around now, but all of Europe might Paris.
Rym: I don't think Germany will no Italy they're fine.
Rym: They'll just ride their scooters.
Scott: France France will Paris.
Rym: I Mean if you look back historically, this isn't the first time that you know, the poor rioted in Paris.
Rym: Remember the whole Paris commune?
Scott: No, I remember a vivre la voix vivre la voix and it was a guy's name Horatio hornblower.
Scott: No, no, no, no, no the French guy.
Rym: That narrows it down a lot the.
Scott: how long a know the evil guy.
Rym: Who are Robespierre?
Rym: Yeah You just remember Robespierre because that game we used to play.
Scott: No I actually I didn't think of it until you said his name what they did.
Scott: the game did not come before in the.
Scott: You said Rose Pierre and I was like that was the guy and then the card appeared in my head with his face Afterwards and then you said it Nada Louis the 16. now he sucks.
Rym: Whoever was against a ratio in that one episode of hornblower.
Scott: No, he sucks.
Scott: Yeah Was that cake lady?
Rym: oh You mean Marie Antoinette?
Rym: Yeah that lady, you know, let them eat cake.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, they have no bread.
Scott: Let them eat cake.
Rym: Yes an accurate rendition of what she actually said in those faded final days Complete with the accurate period voice.
Scott: I might add off with your head.
Rym: So It's science and tech day Alright, and we can't argue about science.
Rym: So we'll argue about tech window managers.
Scott: You know, I've pretty much tried everyone to manage who there is.
Scott: I have tried four of them and they all suck Yeah, but in different ways always in a different way.
Rym: See I've noticed a lot of people just like people I talked to at work or people I talked to on the street Or just people who don't use Linux or they don't use it much.
Rym: You picking a window manager is one of the first problems they have because that's not even a consideration in windows.
Scott: It is there used to be that light step thing or I don't know if I think it still exists and all those things you Had to go out and get by default.
Rym: you install windows and you get windows.
Scott: by default.
Scott: If you install Ubuntu you get.
Scott: no.
Scott: if you install kubuntu you get KDE.
Scott: Yeah and there was just a thing.
Scott: my mark shuttleworth is using kubuntu and he wants kubuntu to become as cuz.
Scott: right now kubuntu is like The backseat.
Scott: he wants kubuntu to be like in the passenger seat right next to.
Rym: I don't like it.
Rym: he's so much.
Scott: I don't like it so much either but apparently some people do and Katie distributions are dying left and right.
Scott: so I Mean Katie.
Scott: he was the first window manager I used ever.
Scott: I mean it was back in the back back days.
Scott: It was Katie one.
Scott: Yeah, then Katie to came out and I was like what did then?
Rym: did three come out?
Scott: Yeah for well, no, no I don't know what versions out now, but when two gave up when two came out it was like a hundred times better than one and Then when three came out it was a little bit better than two.
Scott: and then I discovered other things and Katie was boo Yeah, yeah The real Katie would be good.
Scott: The problem is it uses this the QT library, which I don't like as much as the GTK library at all.
Scott: You know, it's all blitz not none of these skins for it even look good.
Scott: They're all ugly and bloated and not even considering the licensing issues.
Rym: Well, plus Katie itself I mean unless you pre-link it it's always fuck.
Scott: Oh, it's slow Horrendously slow.
Rym: pre-linking will fix that but a lot of people don't want to go through the trouble of free.
Scott: I don't pre-link.
Scott: it's not worth the effort.
Rym: I pre-link and I but I have an older slower computer and I need to pre-link.
Rym: now.
Scott: I'm thinking about buying a dual CPU Athlon 64 machine someday Maybe a dual dual core.
Scott: then I won't need to pre-link anything.
Scott: But the real problem with Katie is that there's just so many options.
Rym: It's like you open an options window is like a hajillion checkboxes and yet even though there's so many options Half the time I still wouldn't find exactly what I wanted to do.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: We're just not in there.
Scott: There are some good things at Katie like a parts.
Scott: Yeah, K parts is good, which lets you put any piece of a like pieces of programs in others.
Scott: It's like you'll be using one program and like a mail will creep into the same window, you know.
Scott: And some of the Katie programs are good.
Scott: I guess ko Pete is okay.
Scott: It's like the game of Katie.
Scott: Hey, right came out.
Scott: They're okay.
Rym: I mean, I guess I look at Katie and gnome as being pretty much equivalent because they're both the Giant window managers full of stuff because they're not just a window manager.
Scott: They're a desktop environment.
Rym: Yeah, they come with utilities.
Scott: It's like a gnome and gnome.
Scott: the window manager is Metasity.
Scott: you could use just Metasity if you want.
Rym: I actually use Metasity with ice wm.
Rym: Oh at work.
Scott: Look at that.
Rym: Yeah Well, I did.
Rym: I stopped doing that for reasons.
Rym: I won't get into now, but well Metasity is kind of slow on an old machine.
Rym: Yeah, Metasity is kind of slow, but not as slow as Anything that's even remotely related to Katie.
Scott: Well, you know, it's how it is But you know when you want.
Scott: people want all that stuff.
Scott: They want it to be comfortable and they want to have everything in a GUI and they want to be able to do all these Things.
Rym: and you know what I do too because I run gnome on my main machine.
Scott: Yeah There are some real useful things in in Katie and gnome that I you can do.
Scott: that You can't do without like.
Scott: I know Nautilus lets you Browse like SSH, you know sftps.
Scott: Yeah, that's really useful.
Scott: What else is really?
Scott: so you know what the thing is.
Scott: you use Katie your gnome you get a working system tray.
Scott: Yes, no matter any other Window manager desktop environment.
Scott: The system tray is always broken or fickle or something.
Rym: Yeah, or ice wm.
Rym: It's just ugly Ugly.
Scott: sometimes you can use a program like XY systray or things like that, but they're never perfect.
Scott: You have to move around and they're all broken and I mean gnome right here.
Rym: I've got my little system tray and I've got Oh, yeah, don't even think about calling it the notification area.
Rym: No, which is the proper name for it?
Rym: It's got my little game thing.
Rym: I got my little character input thing for Japanese and Korean and all that other stuff.
Rym: No Yeah, you know basically you got to choose between.
Rym: Do you want it?
Rym: Do you want?
Rym: I like an all-encompassing environment?
Rym: that'll just work and then you can tweak it within itself, or do you want more?
Rym: Customizability but comes with that great responsibility.
Scott: Well, it's not so much that you're losing Customizability because you can use fvwm which is infinite customizability.
Scott: Yeah, it's just not in a gooby and it's not easy.
Scott: and there's you know, if you know, it's not easy.
Rym: I tried to make an fvwm and I started stealing things from other people because other people have made these freaking amazing Fvwm desktops where things fly around and everything's pretty and perfect, but they're so customized to the person who made it I can't even use them.
Scott: The real problem with fvwm is that you can do anything technically But to do things that are outside the normal bounds of what fvwm does you do something crazy hackish.
Scott: Like if you want something to fly across the screen There isn't a function like make it fly across the screen to the right.
Scott: You pretty much have to like redraw it moving it to the right by X pixels and write a function that does it with a loop You know and you'd go.
Scott: you have to actually program stuff and sometimes you don't program it directly like that.
Scott: It's like use some other obscure thing and bind it to an event and then force the event to happen Artificially and make it do something scarily enough.
Rym: a lot of people do that.
Rym: Anyway, there are ricers for fvwm and they do crazy silly things.
Scott: Well, a lot of them just have stuff done and once you get to the point where most of its done You can just keep using it.
Scott: Yeah, and if you have a lot of free time like I did in college when I used fvwm you could do that.
Scott: But then as soon as I switched up monitor resolutions everything fell apart and now I just don't use it anymore cuz I don't have time, you know There's also the real simple little ones like I still you have.
Rym: it's just real tiny.
Rym: It looks like Windows 95, but it works.
Scott: Yeah, there's a EWM which is kind of like that.
Rym: What's that one?
Rym: Steve uses the really light cool one.
Scott: Well, that's ion.
Scott: that's the guys completely different Yeah, but there's terms a little do-nothing ones is like all the boxes.
Scott: F open box flux box You know, it's just they give you like a menu in a bar in a background Yeah, and everything else is up to you, you know, oh you can add desktops But those don't.
Scott: it's like people use those and they're like, oh, this is so great.
Scott: It's like you can't even it doesn't even do anything.
Scott: Yeah, I can't customize it to do stuff I want and it's really it's just like a tiny thing that just like it's like a placeholder.
Scott: It's like I need a window manager.
Scott: Here's one that does nothing.
Rym: I Mean if you're gonna do that, anyway, just why even have a go?
Rym: II what are you doing?
Scott: Well, they had they got like a menu and they get virtual desktop switcher.
Scott: Yeah, that's all they get.
Rym: pretty much telling you man She's terminals and rat poison rat poison.
Scott: I mean, I never used rat poison, but from what I gather it's really just terminals, yeah You can get like a window in a terminal kinda.
Scott: Yeah, that's about it.
Scott: It's really not that great, but it's like the most minimal minimal anything.
Rym: It's the most maximal a terminal is gonna be.
Scott: That's About right.
Scott: But yeah, I on the one that Steve Steve uses and that I'm starting to use It's actually pretty weird because that you can split up your screen you make it a grid out of it.
Scott: You can either you know, and it actually handles like separate monitors correctly and it handles all this stuff.
Scott: but you know you can get menus and you can do stuff like you can say bind so when I push whatever a little prompt pops up and Then I if I type in let's say me and me dotnet it'll open up a terminal in that frame That is already SSHing You know, it could do stuff like that.
Scott: But all it really is is just split the window up into frames resize them move them.
Scott: each frame can have as many windows as you want and they're all get tabbed.
Scott: and That's it.
Scott: And you get bindings.
Scott: you can bind keyboard things to stuff.
Rym: It also does your a dual screen properly.
Rym: I just said that I wasn't listening to at all.
Rym: I can't stop looking at this horrible picture from cluster edge.
Rym: Oh Yeah, remember cluster edge the show that that was.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: Well, there's this picture and I'll put a link in the post because I think it sums up everything that this show is very succinctly.
Scott: Hi, you're not gonna show the picture like the guys looking at each other anything.
Rym: I think this picture says it all.
Scott: Uh It's nothing to do with window managing.
Rym: I had the window open and I turned around and I saw it and it just distracted me.
Scott: Oh, you don't wouldn't imagine we forgot XFC.
Rym: Oh I've never used it.
Scott: You used it.
Scott: Remember using it.
Rym: Well, no, I didn't.
Rym: I read windows for a long time.
Scott: Anyway, XFC is like the in-between window manager.
Scott: I used it a whole lot.
Scott: But now I don't I kind of forgot about it.
Scott: It's like you get the nice gooey gnome stuff, but a lot less of it.
Scott: But you actually have stuff unlike flexbox.
Scott: We've like almost nothing.
Scott: Panel and you can customize the panel and there's a bunch of control panel settings You can set and you can get menus that do things.
Rym: you get themes Yeah, cuz those menus that don't do anything or just awesome.
Scott: It's like it.
Scott: Oh, it's a real light and it does stuff, you know, but it uses GTK like gnome does.
Scott: yeah, it's actually pretty good.
Scott: You know if someone has like a weak weak computer They can't and they're they.
Scott: it's not someone.
Scott: you would normally give Katie your gnome, but their computers too weak.
Scott: Xfce is like the trick.
Rym: that makes sense.
Rym: You don't want to give them like I still UM because they won't be able to make it Yeah, and if you can't make it look good Yeah, and if you're someone who like, you know is using something lesser and it's not enough.
Scott: But you don't like the slowness of gnome and Katie you can go to Xfce.
Scott: Yeah Oh Enlightenment that's right.
Scott: Yeah enlightenment is Interesting Enlightenment 16 which is what's currently stable?
Rym: Oh, yeah, we're not gonna not even 17 all the way.
Scott: Yeah, 16 like if you saw a few years ago, it blow you away.
Scott: It's so cool looking and it doesn't use as much resources as things that are less cool looking Yeah, but nowadays it's not so impressive.
Scott: that's really like.
Scott: the goal of it is to look cool You know while not using resources, but you know, it's not really something you can use.
Scott: I mean some people use it, but I can't.
Scott: it's like It's not practical for doing anything.
Rym: No Unless you want if you want a really cool desktop like you see in the movies where someone's doing stuff in a movie on a Computer.
Rym: you could make something awesome in enlightenment.
Scott: But enlightenment 17 actually looks like it's useful and it does all sorts of OS X things and it's you know.
Scott: It doesn't use a whole bunch of resources.
Scott: It's actually really wicked fast Uses your video card for everything like it should you know, it's all cool and I got it to work.
Scott: There's a live CD that you can get.
Scott: it's a live the enlightenment live CD.
Scott: You just put it in you choose enlightenment 17 and you can test it out on your computer to see what it's like and it worked great.
Scott: Yeah, but Can't get that to actually install permanently on my computer.
Scott: I mean I can.
Scott: I could install from the live CD.
Scott: You know the distribution that's on the live CD copied my hard drive But I want to use enlightenment 17 in gen 2 or Ubuntu.
Scott: I don't even think you can use it in Ubuntu or anything like that.
Scott: I mean people do it But it's so much effort and it's like you can ruin your computer like 10 different ways trying to get it to go.
Scott: I think it'll be stable though within like a year or so and you'll actually do.
Rym: To use in gen 2 don't you need to have like not even tilde but like star.
Scott: Yeah, it has the the hyphen star Keyword which is like beyond bleeding edge.
Rym: It's like the knife already cut you.
Scott: Yeah, you're pretty much just stabbing yourself.
Scott: You know They it's.
Scott: it's pretty much like we want to put these e builds in here because we made them and you put them in here If you really want to use them, but you should never use them.
Scott: Yeah, they're not for you.
Scott: The really the the trick behind - star is that It's so hard to actually get something with - star to install and work, you know, well, maybe we should clarify.
Rym: in gen 2 There are keywords.
Rym: Yeah, so like say that normally it's x86.
Scott: Well, it's X easy if you have an X 80 process.
Rym: Most of most people have an X 80.
Scott: some people have PPC.
Rym: Yeah AMD 64 Yeah, but anyway, so that's like the normal keyword and you compile things but some things are a little bleeding edge.
Rym: So like a version 9 of something will be out in x86, but nine point one will be released under tilde.
Rym: So you don't install that right away.
Rym: It only moves to x86 when it's stable.
Scott: Well, it's called tilde is testing.
Scott: So when they make a new e build right I made a new e build for the new version.
Scott: you put it in testing Yep, and then as soon as it's cover it been tested enough.
Scott: They take the tilde off.
Rym: Star is like Yeah, I haven't even really compiled this yet.
Rym: Here you go.
Scott: Yeah, it's like we made an e build.
Scott: Here it is you know.
Scott: and the thing about testing is like When it's stable, that means it works on any machine with you know, so if it's sometimes you'll see a package.
Scott: It'll be like stable x86 and PPC.
Scott: But if you have an AMD 64, it'll still be tilde.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: But if it's if it's regular x86 that means it's guaranteed to work on any x86 computer No matter what your combination of software is unless you have something broken.
Scott: It's not a guarantee or a warranty, but it is a function.
Rym: properly it will run on your processor.
Scott: Yeah, 99% but they don't make a guarantee about it, but it's very much guaranteed.
Scott: Minus star isn't a tilde is saying we don't guarantee.
Rym: It might screw you because I guarantee this will break your computer.
Scott: go away There's a very slim chance.
Scott: It won't break your computer.
Scott: You know, you have to be like a real magician.
Rym: Yeah, if you want to see enlightenment 17 get that CD and look at how pretty it is and then just forget about it Cuz you'll never get it.
Scott: You'll get it like a year from now and or you can just take that live CD and install from the live CD.
Scott: The problem is I had it be window manager crashed on me a bunch, but it does crash very gracefully.
Rym: Yeah, that's so much better than not crashing.
Scott: well windows You know it crashes right and then you can't do anything and pretty much your only Resource is to reset the whole computer with a hard reset when enlightenment crashes.
Scott: It's just like I've crashed.
Scott: will you please click this button and now we'll start up again and it starts up again in like two seconds, you know and That's the other good thing is that X won't crash but enlightenment will crash.
Scott: So they all your windows will just lose all their windowing and then they'll gain it all again.
Scott: So you don't actually lose anything.
Scott: Uh-huh window managers crashing isn't so bad X crashing you'll lose all your running X applications.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but that doesn't happen.
Rym: Actually, no, I haven't had it happen except when I had video card broken things a long time ago.
Scott: what's really funny is that I heard an interview with the enlightenment guy and Apparently he's developing enlightenment 17 using enlightenment 16 running on an X server in OS X. So he has a Mac running OS X with X running on that with enlightenment 16 running on that with an X nest running enlightenment 17 to test enlightenment 17 as he codes it.
Rym: that reminds me of back at RIT when you would SSH into a CS machine and then SSH from that back to your machine and then from that to another machine and then you try to X forward over all that.
Scott: Yeah with the with a 3d program.
Scott: Yeah, it worked.
Scott: Yeah, if you make a loop of SSH is or you tried to like go back at all SSH like freaking complaints.
Scott: It's like oh my god security someone spying on you.
Scott: Oh my god Which I guess is good.
Scott: It's that smart.
Scott: Yeah Can't fool SSH.
Scott: It's really secure.
Rym: Hey, you can fool SSH one.
Scott: Yeah, no one uses SSH one You'd be surprised.
Scott: No, no, I wouldn't.
Rym: I know a lot of people who there's a two Uh Mostly like.
Scott: well, I don't even I didn't even specify one or two.
Scott: two is the default But you can't use one.
Rym: a lot of people are running old like Red Hat seven machines that only support one.
Rym: unless you go.
Scott: did They click don't they notice that like red spinning thing.
Scott: This is update me.
Rym: No the update.
Rym: remember Red Hat.
Rym: seven point two is still supported and gets updates automatically.
Rym: 7.1 is seven point three.
Rym: You have to sign up for the Red Hat Network and you don't get all the updates and it doesn't work.
Rym: So well, don't use Red Hat.
Rym: seven point one or seven point three.
Scott: I never understood this like old version of Red Hat thing.
Scott: You know, it's like you get peace.
Rym: Red Hat does not even upgrade its kernel gracefully.
Rym: newer ones do but like old Red Hat if you tried to upgrade the kernel you Probably just hose your entire system.
Scott: It bothers me so much as like people there are companies out there trying to be good.
Scott: They make a Linux software.
Scott: Yeah, and they might be for sale.
Scott: It might be proprietary Linux.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: I just want software.
Scott: Yeah, they make software for Linux But they make it and they send it to you with like a distribution of like Red Hat seven.
Rym: Great.
Rym: I really wanted that.
Scott: they've tested it on Red Hat seven and they've tested it with like Linux standard base.
Rym: But then oh it uses this weird Red Hat thing or oh it doesn't do.
Scott: this won't work on any other distribution except for the one they've sent you.
Rym: I've had installers and I was I mean It was installer and the script started and it would check for some like system variable But it would check for it in a form that no modern Linux uses and then it wouldn't install because it.
Rym: oh you're not running The right blah blah blah.
Scott: Yeah, it's like what I would have to do is like under.
Scott: sometimes under the hood There's a program that will just work normally But they've written this whole suite of install scripts to get it to install.
Scott: I would go in and I would modify all the install scripts to make them just be Normal and just copy the files to my hard drive that needed to be copied, you know.
Scott: And then it would be in a normal L effect LSB executable, whatever.
Scott: I just run it and it would go.
Scott: Yeah, you know cuz I had I had this.
Scott: all the libraries are acquired and they were just newer versions But they were backwards compatible and it just worked.
Scott: But they write this crazy install system to make it easy for you.
Scott: on the Red Hat distribution They give you or something and then it just doesn't work.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well some companies they make like a standard like alright Our installs will always go with a certain way like IBM is real bad about this.
Rym: So all the IBM software out there that you can buy there are Linux versions of all the servers and the clients and the agents and everything.
Rym: But they install like Windows programs like they put all their stuff in like a folder somewhere on your file system And then they don't put their executable in bin.
Rym: They put it in like this crap plays.
Rym: Yeah, it hurts.
Scott: well, I mean sometimes you install Some things are supposed to go in opt Like.
Scott: if you install open office like, you know, it's supposed to go in slash opt Open office and then all the files are in there and then in slash user bin There's a sim link to the open office executable.
Scott: or you include slash ops open office slash bin in your path Right or something like that.
Rym: Yeah, there are multitude of ways.
Scott: Yeah, and that's the way it's supposed to be because it's like a pre-compiled program or you know anything That's like big like that will do that Congen to.
Scott: if you merge Firefox bin it goes in opt Firefox bin.
Scott: Yeah, but if you build it, it goes in usr and everything split up how it's supposed to be.
Scott: Yeah Which is the correct way.
Scott: but People they make things not and people look at.
Scott: people are making free software free for no money.
Rym: Alright, like new and they follow the standards.
Scott: they do things right and things work on every distribution with almost no effort You know.
Scott: and if it's a source-based distribution No one has to modify anything.
Scott: but then if it's a binary distribution one guy compiles it and it works on all the computers.
Rym: Yeah, what was the last time?
Rym: you tried to run an RPM and it didn't install and you were using the right version?
Scott: yeah, and you had all the dependencies and And then it's six.
Scott: you did force and it successfully installed and then it didn't run and you modified your path and you found The file and you ran it and it didn't run.
Rym: Yeah often with an obscure error message like nothing.
Scott: Yeah, it's cuz someone out there took the source for that program.
Rym: Are you sure it was a seg fault?
Rym: Are you sure it wasn't nothing nothing?
Scott: Cuz someone out there took the source for that program and compiled it to work on a machine and it worked on.
Scott: that machine worked On his machine, but they didn't test it on every other machine in the known universe and any other different Linux.
Scott: They only tested unlike a bear Red Hat 7 install, you know It's like you could have a Red Hat 7 install and if you add two pieces of software before you install theirs Doesn't work cuz the library got replaced.
Scott: These people just don't understand Linux and they make Linux software like Windows software.
Rym: It's just not good, but the people who do it for free often do a better job.
Scott: So you'll do it for free.
Scott: know what they're doing.
Scott: Yeah Problem is that the people who you know?
Scott: Trying to make something to sell don't listen to the people who do it for free And if they gave them some money, they could probably be rich, but no now they're just.
Scott: they're just most.
Rym: And That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at beads feed burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast.
Scott: We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.