Scott: It's Tuesday December 27th, and this is Geek Vines.
Scott: Tonight, we talk about the first-person shooters.
Scott: Let's do this so you might be familiar with the sort of slash dot competitor dig.
Scott: The way it works compared to slash dot is that instead of where slash dot you submit a story and then you know the editors Pick and choose it goes in the front page.
Scott: Dig is more democratic.
Scott: you can just kind of dig something and you know you submit something and everyone can see it.
Scott: And if they dig it and enough people dig it it gets to the front page.
Rym: It's both good and bad.
Rym: it has its pros and cons and some people like slash dot some like dig most people use both.
Scott: Yeah, I look at both.
Scott: usually digs a little faster slash that has good comments, whatever.
Scott: So I was unable to dig my own site and do things with dig and it was because I messed up some networking Configuration because it wasn't well documented at all.
Scott: so I fixed it and I tried to get on dig For with a with an entry on my site.
Scott: now I have a bunch of game pro magazines like ten years worth don't ask me why and When.
Scott: I was cleaning them up and getting ready to sell them on eBay which I'm gonna do soon.
Scott: I noticed in one of them that there was a little in the in the lab section where they talk about controllers and stuff.
Scott: There was a little blurb really tiny About this third-party PlayStation 1 controller, and it looked really familiar.
Scott: It looked exactly like I don't know a PlayStation 3 controller.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, we found that interesting.
Scott: Yep, so I took a picture of it and I put it on my site and I wrote a little thing about it And I said, you know, this is something I could get digged or dug.
Rym: so they dug dig that.
Scott: so I dug it and as I watched it got more digs and a little more digs.
Scott: and Then I went away and I came back and an old pile of digs and my blog had a whole Pile of comments and I was like whoo fair.
Scott: I got the front page of dig.
Scott: I'm awesome.
Scott: And yeah, it was pretty cool.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: That's all you have to say about that.
Scott: well, no, the interesting part was that when I looked at the stats I got about 10,000 people came to the site to look at it.
Scott: I got about 400 digs and I got about 16 comments on my blog about 50 comments on dig and none of those people spilled over into GeekNights.
Scott: No, not really and I Didn't.
Scott: yeah, I got a quite a few maybe a few hundred people subscribe to my RSS feed for my blog, which is cool.
Scott: So the numbers are really like way out.
Scott: It's like only about 10% of the people who come and visit will Click on your RSS feed.
Scott: at least of the dig population and Like out of 10,000 people only 400 will actually click dig it.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of like I use dig.
Rym: I never log in.
Rym: I've never dug anything.
Rym: I just look at the site and see what other people have dug.
Scott: Oh Yeah, that's if you really just want to read the news and use it the way you slash that.
Scott: That's all you got to do.
Rym: It's like slash down for the longest time.
Rym: I never had an account or anything.
Rym: I just went to the site every day and looked at the front page.
Scott: dig has some some hidden functions though.
Scott: They're like if you get into it, you can do cool stuff.
Scott: you just have to get into it like you can dig stuff and like everything you dig will go into like your digs and you can undig stuff.
Scott: and Yeah, it's all kind of crazy stuff going on in there.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is really missing is the nice commentary you get on a site like slash down.
Scott: Yeah, the comments on dig are like non-hierarchical and there's no moderation.
Scott: So you just get like these.
Scott: it looks like a blog And there's a bunch of people like woot.
Scott: This sucks.
Scott: No dig.
Scott: No dig Random crap it might as well be fart.
Rym: one word put now FARC is more Lucid than dig.
Rym: sometimes sometimes people post freaking essays to FARC and flame wars.
Scott: If dig put the comments and the moderating the way slash that does.
Scott: but also with the web 2.0 I think slash I'll be pretty much useless.
Scott: But for now as we need still need slash done.
Scott: Yeah for now for now You know, but they should slash.
Scott: that should also if slash.
Scott: I took a lesson from dig and they made a web 2.0 site and they got rid of all their stupid ads Everywhere that no one likes ads.
Rym: Yeah, the ones we don't see that we know Obviously, I always forget the slash that has ads and then every now and then I use like someone else's computer and I see an A and it's painful and it startles me.
Scott: Yeah, and if you know They did all the stuff that dig does like the firing their editors and just using a democratic system then dig would die.
Scott: So whatever.
Scott: but the point is I got dug and now I know the formula for getting dug.
Scott: and what will happen if I get Dug, yep.
Rym: So luckily if GeekNights gets dug we won't probably go over our bandwidth limit right away.
Scott: Oh, no, I barely used any bandwidth and CPU me my site the way I have it set up is so slick It doesn't even I could get a serious like pounding Yeah your site.
Rym: but if 10,000 people downloaded GeekNights suddenly with all the mp3 would be a problem.
Rym: Yeah, 20 megabytes times 10,000 is a lot of bandwidth.
Scott: Yeah, but that's alright.
Scott: so Buddy, uh, Elliot spitzer.
Scott: He's read it again the Attorney General of New York He's going to get some more bad guys.
Scott: Well, actually he's getting the same bad guys again, you know those record companies.
Rym: Yeah, he left him a nice Christmas gift the Christmas gift of Lawsuits Oh subpoenas.
Scott: Haha Yeah, so he's kind of pissed about their Price fix well before he got him for CD price fixing.
Scott: now, he's getting them for online.
Scott: You know iTunes price fixing.
Scott: and I say yeah They are fixing the prices.
Scott: CDs are worth nothing and music is worth nothing and they're selling it at more than nothing Which well, it's not even fixed.
Rym: His point is that he's saying that they're artificially Inflating the prices to make him uniform or more than the wholesale value would be and the RIAs response was that?
Rym: Our prices are perfectly valid and they're perfectly varied.
Rym: the price of a song on the wholesale can range from 60 to 90 Cents and Elliot said that's not enough.
Rym: That's not enough variance.
Scott: It's obviously collusion Yep, and the other thing is if you ever look on the there were lots of websites even RI a website.
Scott: there was a website made by the RA that says this is the breakdown of all the money you pay for a CD.
Scott: right and the number one item is Marketing and Advertising.
Scott: and all that is.
Scott: the is most of the cost of a CD is to pay to advertise that CD to get people to Buy it now.
Scott: I'd like to point out two things about that number one.
Scott: The only CDs that actually get marketed are like the super super hits.
Scott: You won't see like the normal Joe Schmoe's CD get marketed at all, but his CD cost the same.
Scott: So when you buy Joe Schmoe's CD from a record label you're paying to advertise.
Scott: You know the freakin pop stars CD Advertise Joe Schmoe's CD.
Rym: It's interesting that for some reason the CDs that could advertise more get bought more You think doesn't seem to have so much to do with the quality of the music But it seems to have a lot to do with how much they market it.
Scott: Well, that's because the the way their business model works is they can make more money selling a bunch of copies of a few CDs Instead of the same number of copies total, but more CDs, so that's how they operate.
Scott: But the second thing I wanted to point out is that Why don't?
Scott: why do they market at all?
Scott: the mp3 trading is the marketing?
Scott: That's what everyone's trying to tell them that they don't get.
Scott: you don't need to advertise music.
Scott: Just put it on the internet for free and people will discover it and once they tell you what they're going to buy That's what you make.
Scott: instead of telling people what to buy Let them tell you and you can make a zillion dollars just the same.
Rym: or put out a bunch of singles from like all these Different bands whatever see which ones get downloaded the most and then sell for a reasonable price albums from that band.
Scott: You don't have to pay for marketing.
Scott: you could sell the CD for like five bucks.
Scott: Hell you could make a super audio CD.
Scott: I'd pay five bucks for a super audio CD with surround sound and shit.
Scott: Yeah, I wouldn't pay.
Scott: maybe I'd pay two bucks for a real CD, but you know that's what you got to do.
Scott: That's what everyone's been telling you to do.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: They're so dumb Oh my god, and Ellie Spitzer's gonna kick their ass.
Rym: yeah I mean they really have no case here, and I they've issued a bunch of statements saying oh, don't worry This isn't a big deal to their stockholders, but if you actually read those statements I'm gonna bother quoting them.
Rym: just they honest.
Rym: they obviously either don't realize the trouble They're in or trying to pretend.
Rym: They're not in trouble long enough to sell some stock.
Scott: Yeah Yeah Spitzer likes to kick people in the ass.
Scott: He's great in fact as he's read the only politician that I actually say yeah, go get him Like.
Rym: a lot of people are wondering about Elliot Spitzer because he seems to only be taking high-profile Cases that will get people riled up and get his name out there, and that he's just doing this to be elected governor.
Rym: But you know what if someone has a sinister purpose and does good along the way?
Rym: The good is fine, and you stop them when they do the sinister yep.
Scott: I mean it doesn't matter why he's doing the good as long as he's doing it.
Scott: And you know what.
Scott: that's how democracy is supposed to work.
Scott: is that no matter?
Scott: Who's the representative?
Scott: is that they're supposed to want to do the things that people?
Scott: That their constituents want them to do so that they stay in office?
Rym: Doesn't matter.
Rym: he's just doing it to stay in office or like say some guy's a pervert And he really gets off on putting money in poor boxes.
Rym: Hey.
Rym: He's still putting money in poor boxes.
Rym: It doesn't matter why he's doing it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He's doing it because he gets off.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: he's helping the poor.
Rym: yeah, cuz the good still happens.
Scott: in fact people Politicians are supposed to do good things that their constituents want them to do only because that will get them reelected.
Rym: You know I wouldn't mind so much if they even did bad things But they had good intentions.
Rym: it always seems that they have bad intentions, and they do bad things.
Rym: It's like the worst possible outcome every time.
Scott: that's how it seems.
Scott: yeah I think a lot of the problem is.
Scott: I think a lot of What they're doing are good and do good.
Scott: the problem is they believe things that are factually incorrect.
Rym: Well like look at the one who put forth that the latest horrible DRM Whatever legislation that we talked about a while ago He issued a statement saying he got a lot of flack from geeks in his email And he's mad because they accused him of taking bribes from the industry.
Rym: And he said that no I'm doing this because it's a just cause blah blah.
Rym: And he wrote this thing about how you got to protect the rights of the artist versus the rights.
Rym: And he talked about how he stands up for the artists too, and he doesn't like the industry But you can't just steal from him, and it looked like a real well-reasoned article, but then if you look around He accepted like tens of thousands of dollars from the RIAA right before he sponsored that law.
Scott: yep.
Rym: So even if he didn't actually do it because of that donation It looks really bad, and he probably shouldn't have accepted the donation.
Scott: see you know sometimes.
Scott: I think yeah, okay That's what happens, and you know what.
Scott: probably sometimes that is what happens.
Scott: But also you got to wonder I mean if I'm a politician right you don't actually talk to people People send you donations, and it just goes into the bank You don't actually like.
Rym: actually a lot of times you do talk to people you'll have like special fundraising dinners.
Scott: Oh, well yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: But I mean you know what if the RIAA's if I'm a politician like a senator and the RIAA Sends me a check, and it just goes right into my bank account.
Scott: I might even know about it I might not know that I accepted actually there because there's that was actually.
Rym: I learned about a problem that Police had with that where people would put money in a police officer's account and try to get him for bribery and stuff and you you can get bank accounts where no one can deposit money without your signature and It's trivial to do so.
Rym: any bank will do it.
Scott: so any politician who says he didn't know yeah But I mean the people in your office Would you just get a pile of checks and they just stamp them all with a thing and then they that's fine cuz that's your Signature.
Scott: yeah, but that's what I'm saying is that you personally don't realize that you took a check from the RIAA But you know what.
Rym: if that's the case then why is the RIAA giving you money if you don't even know it?
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: Maybe it's because he was on their side that they gave him money and not the other way around.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: cuz it now I look through and it doesn't seem like this was an issue for him until recently.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not saying that's how it is in fact.
Scott: I'm pretty sure he is sort of you know legally bribing whatever.
Scott: But I'm just trying to say that it's not a hundred percent, and yeah, it's not a hundred percent, but you know what.
Scott: it's 90% That's for sure All right.
Scott: though in other non-us news Galileo you mean the guy who said Gravity.
Rym: no, I mean.
Scott: I mean you know things fall at the same.
Rym: the GPS So I don't know how many of you know, but GPS.
Rym: You know a global positioning system is run by the US government.
Scott: I thought it was a bunch of like Geo stationary satellites owned by all different people all.
Rym: no no no they're all.
Rym: it's all run by the government.
Scott: Then why are there so many different systems?
Scott: for they're not.
Rym: they're all GPS.
Rym: It's all the same.
Scott: it is
Rym: Yeah, you can do GPS type stuff with cell towers and like triangulation, but GPS the official GPS is Has a heavy hand from the government because they have the ability one they limit the accuracy of it to within one meter Usually or ten meters depending and whenever there's a war or whenever the government of the United States decides that it doesn't want you to Know for whatever reason like say it's about to invade it where
Scott: you are.
Rym: Well say they don't want.
Rym: you'd say like a lot of militaries use GPS.
Rym: Yeah, so right before we invaded Iraq the US military put fake information in the GPS in the whole Middle East Mm-hmm.
Rym: so all the militaries who relied on it couldn't use it and They reserved the right to pretty much just turn off GPS whenever they want.
Rym: So Europe said hey, that's not cool.
Rym: We're gonna make a better GPS that anyone can use that will never be turned off for any reason and it'll also be more accurate and faster and more reliable.
Rym: Cool do it.
Rym: and the United States said fine But we reserve the right to shoot it down if a whore if a hostile power ever uses it against us.
Rym: Yeah, so Okay, here.
Scott: This is you know what.
Scott: if I was Europe you know what I would say That satellite is our property.
Scott: if you shoot down our satellite We're going to shoot down all of your satellites, and we're going to shoot missiles at you because that's a declaration of war.
Rym: You realize that's not gonna happen.
Scott: I know but that's what someone with balls would say.
Rym: See but the problem is think situations like that or what leads to world wars.
Rym: That's what led to World War one and two.
Rym: it was people posturing like that and then finally everyone just retaliated.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: some you know what.
Scott: in World Wars one and two there were fuckers and the first time it was a Kaiser And you know what okay?
Scott: Whatever, but the Kaiser was kind of a fucker and in two it was Hitler and Hitler was a real fucker And he had to get rid of the fuckers.
Scott: You know what the u.s.. Now is kind of a fucker.
Rym: all right with World War two you're spot-on But you World War one.
Rym: I don't really want to bust your balls here, but he wasn't alright.
Scott: The Kaiser wasn't as bad as you know.
Rym: Which Kaiser?
Rym: what are you talking about?
Rym: Wilhelm?
Rym: Yeah, he did.
Scott: World War one wasn't really started by Germany I know, but he was still kind of you know not so good.
Rym: Yeah, he wasn't the greatest guy, but mostly because he wasn't the smartest leader not because he was terribly belligerent.
Scott: No, he wasn't really evil, but you know it wasn't exact.
Scott: It's kind of like Saddam.
Scott: Saddam wasn't great But he wasn't like the Ayatollah Khomeini or like with those bad bad guys You know.
Rym: but getting rid of him wasn't so bad, but World War one basically started because of escalations in tension Like you said.
Scott: oh, yeah, it didn't start because of the.
Rym: you don't shoot missiles Just because someone shot down your satellite.
Scott: if someone shot down my satellite I shoot down their satellite.
Rym: You know maybe well the thing is no one can shoot down satellites, but us oh Not easily.
Scott: I should please you put up a satellite that has a laser to shoot other satellites one That's that violates international law.
Scott: no one has to know.
Scott: Yeah Doesn't matter.
Scott: cuz shooting down Europe satellites by relates international law.
Rym: well that the I've read articles.
Rym: basically the way They do it is they just have a big heavy satellite up there that they just ran into it.
Rym: So it's not really a weapon.
Rym: It's just a big heavy satellite that get.
Rym: dude.
Scott: That's gonna be the future of space wars.
Scott: It's just big chunks of metal with rockets on them slamming into each other.
Scott: That'll be so great.
Rym: I mean it's not something that's ever happened before.
Rym: conflict hasn't really entered space yet.
Rym: but I mean because China and Russia are backing this Galileo system heavily and plan to use it and If the u.s.. Ever enters conflict with Russia again or with China which while I'm not gonna be a crazy conspiracy guy and say yeah We're gonna go to war with China.
Rym: It's possible that within the next 40 years there might be some low-scale conflict between the two powers.
Rym: There's a good chance the u.s.. Might attack European satellite infrastructure as a part of that mmm trouble.
Rym: at least from a geek perspective Galileo is awesome.
Rym: It is far superior to the current GPS.
Scott: You know we should do.
Scott: See as technology gets smaller and easier and more accessible Eventually us nerds be able to put up our own GPS is because right now It's like before it was computers.
Scott: They were big things that only cut.
Scott: you know like countries had him and big companies had him and they were huge.
Rym: wait You're saying.
Rym: everyone's saying the geeks are gonna be able to just put up geosynchronous orbit satellites.
Scott: Look in 1920 if I would have told you everyone would have had like five.
Rym: There's a big difference from that.
Rym: there's no physical space limitation to how many computers you can have in the world.
Rym: No realistic one anyway.
Scott: What if one day satellites are like the size of a pea?
Scott: At the rate we're going to will.
Rym: in that case why do you even need a satellite if you have the technology to do that?
Rym: There are far better ways to send data than satellites.
Scott: So because the satellite can figure out where you are.
Scott: That's the point of the satellite.
Rym: you can figure out where you are as long as you have multiple points of reference and precise timing.
Rym: All they're all this.
Rym: all the GPS is is multiple points of reference and precise timing.
Rym: That's all you need was a satellite for because that makes it easier to give it to a large area unhindered.
Scott: See that's the point of it.
Rym: Yeah whatever Leary of your ultra optimistic idea that somehow we'll be able to love are some geeks.
Rym: within our lifetimes They'll be able to launch geosynchronous satellites into orbit all right.
Scott: well My point is is that in in a number of years within our lifetime This will become irrelevant because everyone will have awesome GPS because it'll just be you know consumer technology
Rym: as opposed to
Scott: Military technology,
Rym: I wonder if the US will put export limitations on it like they did with encryption back in the day.
Scott: lol Yeah, rofl.
Scott: So our things of the day are both videos today Yeah, the this one that I got I saw real early in the morning, and it was mad freaky.
Rym: Yeah, like if you ever seen speedgrapher.
Scott: Yeah, there's that character.
Scott: Yeah, we can make about a lot of jokes about that, but so apparently that character is real and is in this video.
Scott: Yeah, so it's his lady dancing, and I don't know where she's from looks like Eastern Europe.
Scott: Maybe I don't know but She's really really flexible like perhaps the most flexible person on earth, and she flexes in ways that make you go.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: Yeah, I got a little queasy watching it cuz I thought about trying to do that to my body and imagining how it would break.
Scott: Yeah, like she like flips her legs and put somewhere arms should be and then it's real scary.
Scott: And like the way like mostly the torso movements cuz like it's like each like she has torso joints that other people don't have.
Rym: Yeah, it's like a wave.
Rym: It's all googly.
Scott: Yeah, it's like your vertebrae like her spine is just like a piece of licorice or something.
Scott: it's freaky But anyway watch the video and be amazed.
Scott: yeah and be afraid.
Rym: and for my thing basically Remember water rockets.
Rym: when you were a kid you know you take a two-liter you fill it with some water you pump it up With an air pump, and then you let it fly into the air and you go
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: imagine taking like 20 of them and strapping them to your back and letting them all go at the same time.
Scott: Is that enough to get you going?
Rym: yes, yes, it is as Japanese television has shown us.
Scott: oh Those Japanese
Rym: I guess the most hilarious thing about this video is The guy they do this to does not at any point look either Amused or happy that this is happening to him
Scott: And he's also wearing one of those little yellow hats at the plus from the Megaman game.
Rym: Yeah, I know a little Megaman guys.
Rym: They shoot at you.
Scott: Yeah, yeah Like those helmets.
Rym: so it's hilarious.
Rym: and all I have to say is that Try this at home, but don't say I told you to try it at home because I want to see other people attempt this.
Scott: Yeah, that'd be hilarious.
Rym: And if you're gonna attempt it attempt it over water like this guy did.
Rym: this guy would have died if that hadn't been water.
Rym: That's all I gotta say.
Scott: oh my god.
Scott: It would have been you know a guy dying sad, but oh the hilarity.
Rym: Well now if you die in a funny way, it's schadenfreude.
Rym: if I die in a hilarious way I expect to be on Fark with some sort of amusing tag.
Scott: What if you didn't know about Fark?
Rym: Then I'd assume that at least my friends would laugh about how I died.
Rym: I mean I died in a funny way like say a Dildo fell out of a plane and was hit by a meteorite and then flew through the house and impaled me From the V from behind and killed me.
Scott: Wow that'd be kind of that's pretty creative.
Rym: yeah, I'm good on the fly like that.
Scott: yeah, I'm sure.
Scott: So today's video game day Not too many actual new video games or anything coming down.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there's no video games, but we're not playing any of them.
Rym: I mean ever there's probably a new spongebob game or whatever.
Scott: well actually there is a game I started playing the other day that hopefully will actually continue to play and we can eventually do a podcast with it.
Rym: Yeah, and I downloaded Civ 2 and started playing it again.
Rym: But I'd like to play it some more before I actually talk about it at length.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I downloaded and played it once or twice cuz.
Rym: I you know for the longing, but You know there's mostly the nostalgia trip because I played the hell out of that game when I was in high school.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much all I can get out of it now.
Rym: It's kind of sad Yeah, so we decided we're gonna go through a history of first-person shooters as they relate to the two of us.
Scott: Yeah, is you know we're not too big into the brand new ones although I did play a little Counter-Strike source the other day, but yeah, but I rebooted to Windows to check out I guess happening.
Rym: I just warn you ahead of time.
Rym: if we at all in this podcast sound pretentious or old-school Don't worry about it.
Rym: We're just we're old-school when it comes to first-person shooters.
Scott: Yeah, we sound pretentious cuz we are and sound like being an asshole.
Scott: It's cuz we are.
Rym: yeah Yeah, and yeah, we are but it's kind of that we play like we really.
Rym: we were really into first-person shooters back in the day Not because they were inherently better just because that's the kind of first-person shooters that we played and The newer better like that.
Scott: so anyone suck.
Rym: Yeah So we don't play the new one so much and there are a lot of reasons for that that we'll try get into.
Scott: they're not As good as the old ones.
Rym: We're starting right at the beginning just being so yeah Wolfenstein.
Rym: ah There were first-person shooters before Wolfenstein.
Rym: there were quite a few which ones I've seen them.
Scott: There wasn't anything.
Scott: Wolfenstein 3d as far as I know was the first first-person shooting game.
Scott: That was you know that was that that mattered that it was the first one.
Rym: It was the first.
Scott: the other ones like it was rise of the triad and there was another one.
Scott: those came a little bit after You know there was.
Scott: there were first-person shooters between Wolfenstein 3d and doom But Wolfenstein 3d was the was the first one that I.
Rym: well there were three dimensional walk around from the first person that interact with thing.
Scott: there were but a lot of those were.
Scott: you know You would like push north and the guy would go north, and then you would push like turn left.
Rym: And I guess my point was Wolfenstein 3d was the first.
Rym: Wolfenstein was the first game that it basically started the first-person genre to where it is now a genre.
Rym: Yep, it was the first one that mattered that anyone cares about.
Rym: that might have existed, and it was pretty awesome.
Scott: It was actually really awesome.
Rym: I remember being blown away when I saw it for the first time.
Scott: first time I saw it was At this guy's.
Scott: I'm not even gonna talk about this guy cuz it's such a story.
Scott: But he had a crap-doss computer, and it's playing Wolfenstein.
Scott: And I was like how do you play this?
Scott: and we were playing this game by pushing the mouth.
Scott: we were playing with mouse.
Scott: only Read you push the mouse forward to walk forward pick it up Put it at the back of the mouse pad push it forward again to move forward again.
Scott: You know one button shoots one buttons open doors.
Rym: I mean oh man if you've never played Wolfenstein I recommend you don't because it's it's really terrible game.
Rym: No It's not fun compared to modern games at all.
Rym: well.
Rym: It's tedious.
Rym: It's very difficult, but it's not difficult in a fun way I don't I disagree.
Scott: I mean Wolfenstein 3d is just.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's a first-person shooter in that you walk around you point it guys and you push the button to kill them But it's a different kind of first-person shooter.
Scott: I mean the game was more of a maze game of get the keys to open the doors and Push-button against the wall to open the secrets and collect the treasure to get points.
Scott: Yeah, you know that kind of stuff.
Scott: the shooting was just.
Scott: you know it was like a maze of bad guys.
Rym: You walk into a room, and there's five Nazis, and they're all shooting at you You should.
Scott: yeah, it wasn't really the skill of you know reflex and aiming that is present in the you know modern real FPS's because you really couldn't have that when it was fate.
Scott: You know the fake 3d that they had because it's really a 2d game.
Scott: Yes, I mean it's beyond 2d.
Rym: You can't have anything that wasn't a right angle in that game.
Scott: even yeah It was really just left and right and forward and back.
Scott: there was no up and down.
Rym: It's honestly while I was blown away by the graphics like when I saw it like wow it's 3d go I didn't know it was wasn't really 3d back then, but I didn't actually like the game so much.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't.
Scott: I didn't really care about the graphics cuz I'd seen games with better graphics than that.
Scott: that I thought you know And I don't really pay attention to graphics anyway But I just really like.
Scott: you know the the finding secrets maze kind of game And I like shooting the Nazis and it was popular, but it wasn't crazy popular.
Scott: No It was.
Scott: it was pretty big like the thing about Wolfenstein that actually like it.
Scott: It didn't sell as many as doom or other FPS's you know it's not.
Scott: it wasn't crazy numbers But it was weird because like my dad would have it on his work PC.
Scott: Yeah, and like people I knew that like weren't?
Scott: gamers would have it like pirated for their DOS boxes.
Scott: there at least They would have the shareware version with one level.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: You didn't see that so much with any other FPS.
Scott: Yeah, you know you don't see doom wasn't on.
Scott: you know people's work PCs that was.
Scott: that was when you know it was a thing the gamers did.
Scott: but when it was a DOS game Like that in those times.
Scott: You know it was businessmen that had.
Scott: you know PCs.
Scott: It wasn't really super PC gaming.
Scott: yet Wolfenstein kind of started the PC gaming.
Scott: actually Wolfenstein and doom in between there.
Scott: Yeah, so when Wolfenstein came out.
Scott: It was really the PCs were for you know business people.
Scott: So those.
Rym: that's where you saw a lot of Wolfenstein action, and then in 1993 the game that pretty much defined me as a PC gamer doom came out.
Scott: Doom doom doom.
Rym: that game was a revolution compared to Wolfenstein.
Scott: Still you know not all the way there But it was the.
Scott: it was less about the amazing and more about the shooting and it exploded Exploded huge.
Rym: everyone had the shareware like everyone.
Rym: I mean for those of you might be younger than us or older than us to the point where you this kind.
Rym: you skipped over This.
Rym: everyone had this game.
Rym: people bought new computers to play this game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean these days you can find like a hundred people with ps2s And you can't find a single game they all have.
Scott: I mean they don't even all have the stupid GTA game You know.
Scott: but L in those days you had a PC.
Scott: it had doom on it.
Rym: I mean I had to hold down f5 when DOS booted and then manually load the minimum number of drivers I needed to make do work, or I couldn't play it.
Scott: I Had a better PC than that.
Rym: well, then I bought four megabytes of RAM, and I was all good.
Rym: Okay, but doom actually do.
Rym: there was a lot of hype before doom came out.
Rym: a lot of people were talking about it.
Rym: We were like this game is gonna be crazy and apparently the original version of doom before they actually released It was going to have a lot more features than doom actually had and they were taken out due to Developmental and processing power constraints.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know that.
Rym: yeah like the original demo of doom if you fired a gun It would deface the textures on the map.
Rym: So there would be bullet holes and they were supposed to be shadows and all this stuff that they took out because there's no way It could be done back then.
Rym: uh-huh, and this is kind of cool, but Yeah, they will one the BFG.
Rym: this is the first game.
Rym: the BFG aka the big fucking gun yeah appeared in and Many of you who played doom remember the BFG was kind of weird Like it didn't really work the way you expected it to and I can explain in great detail How it actually works, but you probably don't care.
Scott: yeah I expected it just kill all the guys in the room because it was a giant green blob and then it exploded.
Scott: But that's not what it did at all.
Scott: But
Rym: well originally and you can find the demo of the original doom before it was actually released if you look hard enough I don't have it, but it's easy
Scott: to get and
Rym: The original BFG actually fired out various colored fireballs in like a 45 degree angle and just filled the room with death.
Rym: But that was too many sprites and most computers couldn't handle it and the game engine could barely handle it.
Rym: So they nerfed it and they made this really weird system where you fire the BFG Whatever direction you were facing when you fired.
Rym: it is the direction from which the damage will emanate.
Rym: And then so if you fire say you fire it into a room Like there's a long room and then you turn and you run into another room.
Rym: Then in the original room the BFG ball finally hits the wall.
Rym: when it hits the wall that triggers the damage.
Rym: and then the damage Will emanate from your character in the direction you were facing when you fired it into this new room and won't do anything in the old room.
Scott: See that's the kind of stuff you lose of the modern FPS is nowadays you push the button a bullet comes out.
Scott: Whatever the bullet hits is what happens.
Scott: Yep, you know this kind of cool stuff while Granted it doesn't make for the most Immersive perfect awesome gaming, you know world type things and stuff, but it's kind of this.
Rym: You know comfortable brokenness of Cool quirkiness that you kind of miss sometimes Like in the old NES games when you could glitch the game and go into like areas that you weren't supposed to get into.
Scott: Yeah, it's just like this, you know fun good brokenness in games that is really missing today.
Scott: and You know if I was a super game designer, I would totally put stuff into my games on purpose.
Scott: Yeah, at least it made it all the way to counter-strike, but we'll get to that now.
Rym: in addition to doom Just looking better and being a better game It had two key additions that these are what really revolutionized FPS gaming the shotgun and the plasma cannon.
Rym: I Wasn't gonna say that damn Though the plasma cannon was my gun.
Scott: plasma cannon was also my good.
Scott: hold that thing down blue balls coming out.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: All right, so one network Multiplayer.
Rym: well sort of well, basically if you if you were a businessman or if you had money You might have had a computer network.
Rym: I mean most people didn't have network cards Networking Ethernet.
Rym: most people didn't know what Ethernet was.
Rym: You probably had dial-up or in the very least you had a modem.
Rym: a lot of people back then had modems But not dial-up.
Rym: They would dial into things and do things.
Rym: Yep, BBS days.
Scott: That was fun.
Rym: and doom You could start a server where your computer would listen on the modem.
Rym: Your friend would then call you and you could play directly over your modem connection.
Rym: I did this for hours upon hours Back in the day with a couple of my friends.
Scott: We did it a few times But not hours upon hours upon hours, and we actually did it more later with heretic actually Because that game was like had the items.
Scott: Yeah, and then we did it again with command and conquer alert Which works scarily well.
Rym: It also had and I never got to play it back then if you had an IPX network not IP IPX like Novell network.
Rym: Yeah, if you don't know what it is, don't worry about it.
Rym: No one uses it anymore.
Rym: and Basically, you could play four player deathmatch.
Rym: That was like the holy grail of gaming to me and I spent much of my youth trying to do it.
Rym: Is there were crazy?
Rym: Softwares where you could like dial into one person and that person had two modems and then they dialed into someone else and three Of you could play.
Rym: we never got any of that stuff to work.
Scott: Nope but yeah, I mean You know nowadays you kind of take deathmatch for granted.
Scott: Imagine if like deathmatch was this ultra mode and only the most elite people could actually play multiplayer.
Scott: It was like whoa.
Scott: Yeah So while the deathmatch looking back on it really wasn't so great I mean you just kind of walked around with a bunch of broken weapons.
Scott: Yeah at each other.
Scott: It was something that you just never been done Couldn't be done and free.
Scott: it would be years and years before it was easy to do.
Rym: and if any of you ever want Play a doom deathmatch with me.
Rym: I am not kidding when I say I'm the almighty lord and god of doom deathmatch.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you know so many other people have played it.
Rym: I played a lot when I was in high school in middle school.
Scott: I think you played it a lot more than like pretty much anyone outside of ID software just because people couldn't.
Rym: Yeah, well because I got lucky like I grew up and like we got cable modems real early just because they happen to roll them Out as a test in my neighborhood.
Rym: We got a cable on a real early.
Scott: I didn't even know that doom could be played multiplayer for a long time because it was hidden in the setup menu.
Scott: It wasn't in the real.
Scott: it wasn't an option in the game.
Rym: I remember I found it and I tried to use it and my modem originally was 2400 baud which wasn't it not enough.
Scott: I had a 14-4 motor.
Scott: So I bought a 33 6 modem.
Rym: Oh, I'll do it.
Scott: Yeah at a 14-4 that I could do it with but it still wasn't very good.
Rym: And this is before 56 K which was digital.
Rym: This was analog all the way All right, so and the other that was the first thing.
Rym: the other main thing that came about.
Rym: this is more in 1994 when doom 2 came out which is just more of the same the double-barreled shotgun.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Nah Well, the double-barreled shotgun was there but it's modding.
Scott: I was saying double-barreled shotgun was the important thing.
Rym: people didn't really think to mod Wolfenstein when it came out.
Scott: You really couldn't doom - oh, no, we actually know there were mods for Wolfenstein.
Scott: I remember there was like a Barney mod where you could shoot Barney cuz you hated him so much.
Scott: Yeah, cuz he was.
Scott: that was the thing at the time.
Scott: was there like?
Rym: there was a?
Scott: not like Barney.
Rym: It wasn't like many people did it.
Rym: There was no real community around it.
Rym: Yeah, once doom 2 came out and Utilities started appearing like D hex and wadded.
Rym: Those are the two I use.
Rym: I heard those.
Scott: one you could buy in the store to like modify doom.
Scott: There was a program you could buy.
Scott: It was like it was like D or that exclamation point or something like that.
Rym: There was do there was win do There wadded was what I use.
Rym: the water was kind of buggy and there was D hex.
Rym: D hex actually edited the executable itself and this whole community of modding appeared and people made capture the flag type games and total conversions.
Rym: and Whenever you play counter-strike or any game like that today, you know mega TF team fortress.
Rym: Think back and remember just for a second that doom 2 is where that all began.
Scott: Yep, I mean if some guy hadn't decided that he wanted to add a weapon to doom 2 and that he found out that well He could do that if he wanted and he took the time to figure out this crazy cryptic Undocumented crap and maybe even bought a program or two to get it to work.
Scott: He hadn't done that The only game we wouldn't have any of those mods.
Scott: The only games would be playing would be half-life 1 half-life 2 Half-life deathmatch, yeah There would be no capture the flag games.
Scott: there would be no Plant the bomb rescue the hostage games.
Scott: There would be none of that.
Scott: There wouldn't be any team fortresses.
Scott: No two forts.
Scott: No, nothing.
Rym: Plus I got to admit it was easier back then just because there wasn't so much to the game.
Rym: I still remember to this day all everything it takes to mod doom the line like the line deaths and the side deaths.
Rym: you have to define the sectors and then compile The sector maps and and the the error maps and all the stuff that makes a doom level.
Rym: and I made Flamethrowers and the funniest thing ever made.
Rym: I made a clone gun and it shot.
Rym: Well, I made it with a friend of mine and it shot a clone of you that would sit there And if it saw anything it would shoot it with plasma gun the zoom guy.
Rym: However, we were dumb and we made it.
Rym: So basically it was this almighty god machine of death And if you fired one it just killed everyone and that was the end of the deathmatch.
Scott: Now was the clone that came out of the clone gun capable of you know playing doom like fully?
Rym: No, it would stand wherever it hit.
Scott: Okay, so you couldn't walk around to pick up items or anything.
Rym: Well, actually it was really difficult to make Complicated things because there was a certain number of frames of animation total in all of doom.
Rym: there was a list of them and Some of those frames Happened to have actions associated with them.
Rym: You could not associate an action with a frame that did not already have an action associated with it But you could change the action associated with a frame that had an action pointer.
Rym: Hmm, so there was a limited number of active things you could do.
Rym: so I made a flamethrower once but I had to destroy the Revenant so you couldn't have a revenant monster.
Rym: It was real complicated and real fun.
Scott: Yeah, I was gonna say maybe if the clone guy could get the clone gun and make a clone that would kill him.
Rym: Whoa that you know, well, my friend Ken made something funny.
Rym: He made a rocket that when it explodes it spawned three rockets great and It crashed the game pretty handily if you ever fired it.
Scott: I can imagine.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder if that would actually work in a more powerful computer though.
Rym: No, because the game maxes out.
Rym: there were a lot of hard coded limits in doom Mmm, like.
Rym: I forget that.
Rym: I forget the number of sectors, but there's a limited number of sectors and if you take the scale of the guy maps couldn't be bigger than a Like nine football fields at the absolute maximum.
Rym: It's pretty big though.
Scott: It is pretty big All right, so doom - and then yep.
Rym: now see the next thing.
Rym: It's a revolution in terms of what games were and how FPS is works, but it honestly personally I didn't like it at all.
Scott: Well, I didn't like it because my computer couldn't really do it so much.
Rym: my computer could do it.
Rym: I just it wasn't a fun game at first because the single-player was kind of blah.
Rym: But doom was not three-dimensional.
Rym: It was 2.5 dimensional.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Wake one And first Nukem 3d.
Rym: and yes and Duke Nukem 3d which came out shortly after that everyone forgets were the first Three-dimensional first-person shooters.
Rym: quake one was the first one.
Scott: I mean, this is where the mouse look was invented.
Scott: I mean because I kind of skipped this part for a little while.
Scott: I mean I didn't because I didn't have a great computer for a little couple more years.
Scott: I didn't get quake one and Duke Nukem 3d right away, you know Like I got my computer when they had been out for you know, some months and such.
Scott: so, you know I didn't.
Scott: when I started getting the real 3d FPS is I Didn't really realize it right away because I didn't learn along with everyone else.
Scott: Like I learned doom and Wolfenstein and everything.
Scott: Yep, so I didn't even know to use mouse.
Scott: look I was trying to control the games just the keyboard and look only left and right and I wasn't using like the straight.
Rym: But I I was totally messed up and also keep in mind that this was before open GL.
Rym: In fact GL.
Rym: quake came out after quake came out and it was a way to modify quake to use open GL.
Scott: If you happen to have an open GL card Yeah, cuz there was glide in those days, which is the voodoo thing.
Scott: It was glide direct 3d and open GL and everyone either used glide if they had a voodoo card or open GL Otherwise and back when it first came out.
Rym: No one had an open GL card right away.
Rym: They were expensive as hell.
Scott: Yep Open GL was like, oh my god, you have a real video card.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: I remember a friend of mine got a matrox mystique Yeah, and I had a creative graphics blaster extreme with two X's and an extra e.
Scott: I didn't have a card that could do it until I got my TNT too, which is way late way late.
Rym: And there's not much I can really say about quake.
Rym: one other than that it it was a technological improvement.
Scott: Yep, I mean quake one pretty much took out most of the amazing it took out, you know, I guess there's some key door action Yeah, but most of it was just run around and shoot guys and don't get shot and it's 3d.
Scott: You have to look up and down.
Scott: It's not automatic.
Rym: Oh most importantly Multiplayer was now on the internet with IP.
Rym: Yep, and type in an IP address connect to a server and fight with people.
Scott: There was no automatic game matching so you still had to find a game.
Scott: but there were things that you could get like Kali and M player and all kinds of services that would match you up with people, you know.
Rym: Now the thing is I mean even when quake 2 came out there was still no automatic.
Rym: It wasn't until steam that you're both one life one and one that you really had the match me up with games and play Yep, and even then it was crappy.
Rym: I mean back in the quake one quake two days.
Rym: you had to go to the CLQ the Champions League for quake Which was actually this cool site.
Rym: It's gone now and I wish I had an archive of it because I have a lot of shirts at archive that org or something or way back.
Rym: machine quake servers put out a lot of data and They set up this site where you it would if you use the same name all the time when you play it.
Rym: It would just collect stats on you and there was a long period of time where I was me and my two friends of mine were in the top 10 for weapons factory in quake 2 Mmm, I just thought I'd throw that in a little gloating moment.
Rym: I was very proud of that.
Scott: Your weapons factory was a crazy mod with crazy weapons for quake 2.
Rym: Yeah, cuz quake 1 mega TF and capture the flag.
Rym: That is when those first really appeared.
Rym: Yep, and You realize to this day There are hardcore people who still play a mega TF and consider it the pinnacle of first-person shooting.
Scott: not many people But a few.
Rym: yes It's a very close-knit community.
Rym: that with which actually we have a friend named Dan who?
Rym: I'm pretty sure is probably the best mega TF player in the world.
Scott: Yeah, if you weren't paying attention TF is Team Fortress, which is the original, you know Two forts capture the flag pick a class go at it, you know game.
Scott: Yeah, all the predicate TF is the mega version for quake 1.
Rym: Yep, and all the capture the flag type games nowadays have their roots in team fortress and mega team fortress.
Scott: Mm-hmm Team Fortress classic for half-life was actually a port of the original Team Fortress From quake 1 to the half-life engine.
Scott: that because valve purchased the guys who made the original Team Fortress and We're still waiting for Team Fortress 2 which was supposed to be out a hundred years ago.
Rym: Yeah, not so long as Duke Nukem forever.
Scott: Yeah Duke Nukem forever was supposed to like if I remember correctly was supposed to compete with quake 2 because Duke Duke him 3d Competed with quake 1 and actually Duke Nukem 3d was a real good game.
Rym: Yeah, I had it.
Scott: The reason Duke Nukem 3d didn't stick around the way quake did is because didn't really have the big multiplayer action.
Rym: It was well it did into in fact that it was all in the game and you could do it.
Rym: yeah, but no one did it.
Scott: yeah and Duke Nukem 3d was really a first player one player experience In fact, I think it's actually better than the quake one one player by a lot.
Scott: Yeah, it was a lot of funny stuff and there were a lot of you know Things going on and silly weapons and and actually I played a lot of the multiplayer and all I have to say is the game Came with bots.
Rym: Yeah, I think it was the first multiplayer first-person shooter to come with bots.
Rym: You could play with.
Rym: Mm-hmm Those bots fucking killed me.
Rym: I couldn't even move.
Rym: I'd spawned to kill me at spawn they kill me.
Rym: Yep, those bots if you ever play if you ever find this game play against the bots.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: So people actually, you know like Duke Nukem 3d and when quake 2 was gonna come out people like hey Where's the next?
Scott: where's the Duke Nukem 3d that's supposed to compete with it?
Scott: and it didn't come.
Rym: they said it was coming.
Rym: Yeah, that it was coming for all these years and that's what Duke Nukem forever is all about.
Scott: is That's the game that never came out and supposedly they're still working on and we're still waiting for it.
Rym: This quake came out in 1994.
Rym: It's now 2006 almost Yeah 12 years.
Rym: Yeah, great.
Rym: and 1990 or 1996.
Rym: Sorry, I can't read my own handwriting.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah Doom was 1993 doom 2 was 94 quake was 96 quake 2 was 97.
Scott: All right, so we've been waiting almost 10 years if not 10 years for this game, and it's still not out yet.
Scott: Yep Games usually take two to three years to make not 10.
Rym: But quake 2 which came out after quake 1 is considered by many people not definitely not most people but a large number of people Not just us to be the golden age of first-person shooters.
Scott: I wouldn't say it's the golden age of first-person shooters, but I would say that quake 2 was pretty much like the first Complete FPS.
Scott: I mean quake 1 had some problems.
Scott: Everyone knows quake 1 had some problems.
Scott: quake 2 pretty much solved all the problems and it was.
Scott: it was just an FPS.
Rym: It was it was modded to an extent that I don't think any game has been modded since.
Scott: yeah At least with playable in terms of quantity of playable.
Scott: maybe half-life might beat it out But it's.
Rym: I think half-life beats it out in some quality nowadays, but there were thousands of mods.
Scott: Yeah, there's thousands of half-life mods.
Scott: It's just it's just so hard to get them and stuff.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But anyway quake 2 had crazy modding and had crazy everything and every first-person shooter since really hasn't Added that much.
Scott: since quake 2 it mostly graphics have been added and stuff.
Rym: But because other than that I played I mean, you know counter-strike you like counter-strike.
Rym: The first game like that that was popular was action quake, which was a mod for quake 2 which actually was fantastic and I loved it to no end.
Scott: action quake was very good that if you if you Don't have quake or it's too hard for you to get action quake working You can get action half-life actually and you could run that on Steam.
Scott: You know what's going on?
Rym: Well, the thing is like we played weapons factory and action quake 2 and all that and lithium deathmatch incessantly and Quake 3 was on the horizon.
Rym: We couldn't wait like we thought it's gonna be a thousand times better.
Rym: This is oh my god Oh my god.
Rym: Oh my god, like the hype was unimaginable definitely out of control.
Rym: and then quake 3 came out and I bought it and I put it in my computer and I played it and I was really unimpressed with the single-player, but I thought all right they'll make the mods and sure enough shortly thereafter the weapons factory mod came out and an action quake like mod came out and the weapons factor was done by the same people and It was just.
Rym: it wasn't the same.
Rym: It was piss-poor.
Rym: It was just a worse game with better graphics.
Scott: Yep, quake 3. what they did is they concentrated a whole lot on the graphics.
Scott: They pretty much threw out the single-player game the single-player and quake 3 was pretty much play multiplayer with bots Different difficulty levels and to make it actually difficult.
Rym: They made the bots cheat at the end.
Scott: Yep like really they just cheated if you like the really hard difficulties in the.
Scott: in the single-player quake 3 the bots would just you know They have more ammo than they were supposed to have or they would do things that people couldn't do and they go fast and they'd Auto aim and god knows what.
Scott: it was just dumb.
Scott: But the multiplayer in quake 3 was you know It was just so generic and bland.
Scott: It wasn't it was slower.
Rym: I think a lot of you guys like just the movie like if you've ever played like quake 3.
Rym: It's very slow compared to quake 2.
Rym: Mm-hmm and quake 2 is about three times slower than the quake 1 mods.
Rym: Mega TF is so fast that if you tried to play it and you're not used to those old-school games Literally, it'd just be a blur of the screen.
Rym: You wouldn't know what's going on.
Rym: Then you die.
Scott: Yeah, I do think part of the reason well part of the reason quake 1 was so fast is probably because it was so broken.
Scott: it wasn't intended to be so crazy fast.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and The reason quake 3 was slower I think is because it made it more accessible.
Scott: like You know quake 1 and quake 2 were sort of this.
Scott: You know only super crazy people could play it because really no one had a computer to play it other than crazy gamers Yep.
Rym: Well also they were trying to make it look more realistic.
Rym: Yeah, like in quake 3 when someone's feet move they lined up with the ground properly things like that.
Rym: But that I mean if you move the game at quake 2 speeds that would look silly Mm-hmm, so they sacrificed gameplay for graphics basically.
Scott: Well, we're not sure that was the trade-off they made but they did do stuff like that.
Scott: and The thing about quake 3 was at that time is when you know.
Scott: That's when you know There were g-forces and stuff and you know Everyone had a computer that could kind of play quake 3 at some degree.
Scott: and they really want I think they really wanted to.
Scott: You know sell this game the way Wolfenstein was where everyone had Wolfenstein or had you know played it or doom where everyone had doom You know.
Scott: and so they're like quake 1 and quake 2 didn't quite do it.
Scott: It's quake 2 wasn't?
Scott: it was like really slow to build quake 1 like it started out like with anticipation But then it didn't explode.
Scott: it kind of was like here's quick one All right.
Scott: And then it kind of like quake 1 quake 1 quake 1 quake 1 quake 1.
Rym: quake 2 was just like this steady stream of Awesome.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: I just a steady stream.
Rym: It never exploded.
Rym: It just stated an exploded state for the entirety of its run.
Scott: Yeah, they wanted quake 3 to explode and I think the problem was they set the fuse wrong and it fizzled.
Rym: Yeah, because honestly more people probably play quake 2 and its mods today than play quake 3 and its mods Mm-hmm, because they're it's kind of scary but every mod that was popular for all these old games.
Rym: There is a hardcore group of individuals on the internet who play it regularly Mm-hmm, and sadly that's really where we stopped playing first-person shooters.
Scott: Well, no because we played a lot of counter-strike Before the quake 3 era.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Well half-life really was the the penultimate first like single-player Because it was the one the first game that like the story and the action were intertwined together into one thing.
Rym: I mean, what was doom story?
Rym: You're a marine you're in hell.
Rym: go for it.
Scott: Yeah, half-life had a story and It wasn't so much a maze.
Scott: It was actually pretty linear, but it was this like sort of task completion.
Scott: You know, how do I get over there?
Scott: crawling through the vents type of thing that had never been done before and Every you know Single-player FPS since is pretty much as the half-life clone of some sort trying to incorporate story.
Scott: Yeah jumping like doom 3 seemed to solving physical puzzles type of thing.
Scott: Yeah Doom 3 same kind of thing.
Rym: because you notice we really kind of went off on the quakes and we didn't mention half-life.
Rym: because half-life is Like this parallel other structure of first-person shooters at this point.
Rym: Yep now and it's just as good It's just cuz the quake era kind of ended.
Scott: Well, it's a different beast altogether.
Scott: I mean that games that you play half-life, you know had mods like counter-strike which you know, isn't it all?
Scott: the Fast-paced runaround shooting guys first-person shooter.
Scott: It's the walk around slow strategy Which is kind of like what the game half-life was, you know The single-player quake - is run through the level and kill all the demons that you can and get the hell out.
Scott: Half-life was you know.
Scott: proceed carefully and manage your ammunition and only shoot guys you have to and try to survive and solve all the things.
Scott: and You know, it's like these physical puzzles not like Tomb Raider where it's like a block puzzle or whatever.
Scott: But like, you know, how am I gonna get over there with this thing in the way?
Scott: Without dying and without using all my grenades and you know without You know falling in the pit.
Rym: Yeah, bro.
Rym: Oh, there's a whole bunch of soldiers in that other room And I avoid them or do I have to kill them?
Scott: Yeah, what would be what what you know?
Scott: Is there a way I can sneak around this room and kill all the soldiers that them seeing me?
Scott: You know?
Scott: or how does a giant alien that my weapons don't affect?
Scott: What do I do to get rid of it?
Scott: Yeah, half-life was pretty cool.
Rym: But yep Yeah counter-strike the new one the source one is still pretty much the most played first-person shooter online as far as I can tell.
Scott: I mean, I can't look at the numbers.
Rym: It used to be easy to find those numbers.
Scott: It's not so easy anymore Yeah, but think about this for a game.
Rym: That's like how many years old at least our strike was a beta 5 before I'd even heard Of it.
Scott: Yeah, I played beta 5 for the tiniest bit amount of time, but At least 7 years old if not more maybe 10 years old.
Scott: Right 8 years old.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's old and it's still played.
Scott: more than like 90% of probably Even brand new games will come out and everyone buys them and everyone immediately plays them and they still have less players than counter-strike has.
Rym: Is for every new game that came out like I'd get it and I play it and then I'd always end up just playing counter-strike Again, mm-hmm or playing actually natural selection is not hugely popular, but it has a very loyal fan base.
Scott: Yeah, well that comes way later.
Rym: the whole show on natural selection.
Scott: Yeah the thing that made counter-strike so crazy was that number one was the first game that really had real guns and That kind of turned a lot of people on was hey That's actually a gun that exists in the real world.
Rym: Yeah, because a lot of geeks seem to have this kind of like military fetish where they like pistols or weapons or desert eagle 5-0.
Scott: Yep, the second thing about counter-strike was It had these new and interesting maps But they eventually became like home like two-fort was something that became home for everyone from Team Fortress But it wasn't new or interesting.
Scott: It was two-forts, you know with a bridge and some water in between but dust is actually pretty interesting.
Scott: You've never been on it before and then eventually, you know, it feels like home and you don't like the back of your hand.
Rym: Yeah, you know every nook and cranny, you know where everyone's gonna be hiding.
Rym: It's just.
Scott: it's feels really good to play on.
Scott: you know those old maps and The real deal with counter-strike was the objectives and the the no respawn.
Scott: because Before counter-strike, it was just common sense if you die in an FPS you come back and you're trying to get the most frags.
Scott: That was the only.
Scott: that was it was the only game was kill the most guys.
Scott: If you get killed you reappear to kill more guys.
Rym: So actually you realize that action quake had two modes and one mode was exactly like counter-strike But no one ever played that mode.
Rym: actually that mode was played more.
Rym: That's the mode I played almost exclusively.
Rym: really you realize when I got action quake.
Rym: I didn't know there was a deathmatch Hmm.
Rym: I only knew the team game and that's the one I played.
Rym: I actually played in a clan and I thought I played against a lot of clans.
Rym: I kind of played in a clan Huh?
Rym: I never saw that it was the primary.
Scott: knew there was a team mode, but I thought it was just kill the other team.
Rym: No, it was team versus team and a lot of them were killed the other team But they were like like you'd be on two sides of a cliff.
Rym: There's a rail car between them like like suspended from raw wires going back and forth.
Rym: Or there'd be objectives like hit the switch or steal this briefcase or escape from this place.
Scott: No, that's not quite this but the thing is in counter-strike.
Scott: It was escape with the hostages or plant the bomb.
Scott: Oh and that the don't forget the the jail which they got rid of.
Rym: Yeah, yes escape maps and a s assassinate maps assassinate maps were my favorite.
Scott: But what are you gonna do?
Scott: They took him out, but also action.
Rym: quake definitely had the.
Rym: if you die you don't respawn.
Scott: Oh, yeah That was.
Scott: that was pretty huge Was that you know?
Scott: The the dying and then you have to watch the game until the round is over because in a team game you have rounds.
Scott: You know when one team wins you start again.
Scott: It doesn't really work in a deathmatch where people die.
Scott: people come back, you know.
Scott: But when you have a team game one team wins and the way it worked is as soon as you died You stayed out and I remember the first time someone told me that I was like what?
Scott: What are you talking?
Scott: That's crap.
Scott: I want to keep playing.
Scott: I want to play a game like that.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Scott: And then I realized Oh counter-strikes a free mod.
Scott: I didn't quite understand at that first and I got it and I was like, oh I get it.
Scott: And thus I played counter-strike up until I still played it yesterday day before.
Rym: Yeah I would have but I discovered when I booted into Windows that the fan on the GPU of my video card is not spinning anymore.
Rym: So my computer is fine in Linux because I don't really use the accelerated but the moment I start an OpenGL thing my computer crashes.
Rym: Hmm, so I got to fix that or buy a new computer.
Rym: All right, probably the latter.
Scott: Well, considering we haven't played a lot of the newer FPS is let's just fast forward.
Scott: tribes 2 is probably the best FPS ever Period.
Rym: yeah tribes 2 was a fantastic fucking game.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Oh my god, and now it's dead.
Scott: Yeah, it's so sad.
Scott: I mourn.
Scott: Half-life 2 was pretty much it was like the same thing as half-life 1, you know a great great awesome single-player.
Scott: They got this great physics engine, but it's really just like.
Scott: half-life is now upgraded.
Scott: They didn't really you know Revolutionize anything.
Scott: It's just a graphical and physical upgrade to half-life.
Rym: Yeah, so maybe in the future once we play more of these new games or have more to say about it.
Rym: We'll do another show a continuation.
Rym: But for now, that's really that's that's it.
Rym: FPS's are kind of a wayward thing for us.
Scott: Yeah Yes, that's partially because the Linux and partially because PC gaming is dying in general.
Rym: and yeah I mean, I'd like wanted to come back and maybe if the Xbox flops or depending on what happens.
Rym: But there haven't been many PC games that have excited me in a long time.
Scott: Yeah me either.
Rym: I mean, I'm more excited by counter-strike than I am about any game that's come out with the possible exception of Civ 4.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it seems like the PC's going.
Scott: mostly MMOs and there's still some FPS is like that.
Scott: battlefield 2 came out You know, my brother said it was pretty cool and he knows what's up because he plays counter.
Scott: He plays the real FPS's, you know, not the halos and things and I've been gonna talk about here because they're not really PC games.
Scott: but you know the More FPS is nowadays are just graphical upgrades not really adding anything.
Scott: Maybe there'll be an MMO FPS besides planetside.
Scott: that doesn't suck one day.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.