Scott: It's Monday November 28th, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: today We talked about well sort of nothing because it was kind of a crazy weekend since you know No, Thanksgiving show and the whole bunch of stuff, so We just keep talking about stuff for about 45 minutes.
Rym: Enjoy, let's do this do this.
Scott: So I'm walking to work from the train station.
Scott: Okay, and I'm next.
Scott: I'm on the the south side of the library near Bryant Park.
Scott: You know walk in west and I hear a scream from across the street alright, so it was kind of this weak-ass scream like And I thought it was just like some horse playing kids or something like that.
Scott: You know that's what it sounded like.
Scott: was you know?
Scott: just some people fooling around?
Scott: You know maybe a guy like you know messing with his girlfriend or something right, but they hear it again.
Scott: So of course I turned my head to the left to see what's up And I see a lady or a girl.
Scott: I couldn't really tell because I only looked for like a half second at this point like on the ground And I'm like oh, maybe someone pushed her or something right you know In a half second later.
Scott: I realized wait a minute.
Scott: There's a guy with a purse running and I'm like freaking purse snatcher.
Scott: There's no way Who would be so dumb to snatch a purse these days in a crowd of people.
Scott: I Can't.
Scott: it is a purse snatcher.
Rym: Okay, did someone stop him?
Scott: Three guys immediately like grabbed him and like smashed him into this car, and I was like oh Yeah, well that that's expected right there.
Scott: Yeah But it was just so amazing that someone could be so dumb.
Scott: It It's like alright.
Scott: There's a people who are dumb, and it's like okay that guy's dumb, but I understand his dumbness.
Rym: um You don't read FARC.
Scott: no no I see the things on FARC But I mean you see something on FARC like guy sets himself on fire attempting stupid stunt.
Rym: right and you know you see these Things.
Rym: on FARC like guy sets himself on fire because he lit a match to look inside of a gas tank All right, or guy Rob's Store with no weapons in broad daylight when there's a police officer in the store See, but things like that.
Scott: I can at least understand what the person who was doing it was thinking.
Rym: really.
Rym: So why did the person who robbed a store in broad daylight with no gun and there was a cop there?
Rym: What was he thinking?
Scott: He was thinking one.
Scott: he probably didn't have a weapon - he wanted to rob the store.
Scott: three He thought we'd get away with it.
Scott: and four he didn't notice the cop before he ran.
Rym: Oh the cop was a uniformed officer standing there.
Scott: He did he not notice the cop?
Scott: He must have not noticed the cop.
Rym: No, he was just dumb.
Rym: the cop just walked over and got him putting handcuffs on him.
Scott: He must have not seen the cop in the store.
Scott: There's no way he could rob the store after seeing the cop right there.
Rym: It was a small store.
Scott: I think he didn't see the cop.
Scott: There's no way anyone could be so dumb, but anyway the point is this purse snatcher It was just the dumbest guy.
Scott: It's like oh my god was just.
Scott: it was serical.
Scott: and then like a little crowd formed You know and I was like, you know, hey I took a few pictures and then I was kind of hoping they would kind of bugged me about taking pictures like a little You know, but they didn't bug me.
Rym: cuz wait, so this is the story you've been talking up all night.
Scott: I saw your snatcher that it's a good story, but you were talking it up so much cuz it's so rare and it's so It's like it's not really.
Rym: I mean I was mugged once.
Scott: it's not imagine if you were standing there when the dumb guy used a match To look in the gas tank.
Scott: That's what this is.
Scott: Like you're standing there watching FARC.
Scott: It doesn't happen every day.
Rym: Yeah, it does happen every day just in different place.
Scott: doesn't happen every day.
Scott: to you looking at it.
Rym: No, but I read about it every day.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean it was.
Scott: and then that I was standing over there You know and I got pictures of this guy lying on the ground, you know, I thought I would put a big poon on it eventually, but The the cop who showed up when someone ran to go get him was like, what are you looking at me?
Rym: You should have taken this picture.
Scott: I did.
Rym: All right, what do you do?
Scott: Oh So the the cop was like who saw it?
Scott: so I'm like, oh I saw it.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: I don't want to be a witness.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: you being a witness is like your dream?
Rym: You'd have a you'd have a forget you just be on the stand like No, so some ladies like I saw it.
Scott: I'm like, all right, I can go to work.
Scott: So I went to work.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I would have rather been witnessing than working.
Scott: Yeah Frankly though if I was gonna be a perfectly honest witness, I didn't actually see the guy take the purse.
Scott: I saw that guy with the purse.
Scott: I saw the lady on the ground and I saw three guys Apprehend him.
Rym: that's fine.
Rym: So you say that how do?
Rym: maybe it wasn't a person at your.
Rym: maybe those three guys were in cahoots?
Scott: No, no.
Scott: No, I'm 100% sure this guy was a person at you.
Rym: But uh, did you see him snatch the purse?
Scott: I saw him with the purse running.
Scott: Ah, I heard the scream and I saw the lady on the ground.
Scott: I think that doesn't leave much room for reasonable doubt.
Rym: That's for the course to decide.
Scott: it is for the court to decide.
Scott: Let's let them do so.
Scott: but I got.
Scott: I got some pictures, but I learned a couple lessons about picture-taking Number one don't have the camera way in the backpack.
Scott: If I would have gotten it out sooner, I could have taken pictures of his weak-ass kung fu He.
Scott: basically the only fight he put up was you know, trying to run away and and you know Get out of the grappling of the guys.
Scott: He managed to get his hands free and he did like a little flurry of blows up into the air.
Scott: Yeah, and if I would had a picture of that it would've been hilarious But I couldn't get the camera out fast enough.
Scott: The second thing I learned is keep well besides keeping the camera in your pocket ready to go in any moment You know is just hold the button down and take a zillion pictures Because
Rym: you can always crop things out later and because it's
Scott: a digital camera and I have so many megabytes of space in there.
Scott: I took four pictures because Number one I took a picture right and then I looked around to try to get another shot And then people started milling about in my way and that was just like screw damn.
Scott: So from now on if any if I ever see anything crazy, I'm just gonna be like whip it out.
Scott: click click click click.
Rym: Yeah, I noticed you got the camera sitting there at arm's length right now, yeah, you want to look at the pictures.
Scott: They're pretty funny.
Rym: Uh See it was a good story, but you talked it up so much all night.
Scott: Like I got this crazy story Happens to you doesn't happen every day.
Scott: It's like a once-in-a-year thing.
Rym: So you guys but honestly if that happened to me, I would have come home and I would said hey So I saw a purse snatcher.
Rym: Yeah, I just it's special for I would just said yeah Well, I grew up in Detroit.
Scott: So it's special for me because you know Not only is it not something you see every day, but I didn't think purse snatchers still existed.
Scott: Yeah, I grew up in the land of not just purse snatchers, but like outright muggers I mean he's like and if there was a purse snatcher you snatch a purse late at night in a dark alley where there's no one Else around.
Scott: you don't snatch a purse on a crowded street as people are walking to work.
Rym: It depends if you a snatch a purse in a crowd and you just keep walking like nothing's up and stick it under your trench By the time she goes.
Rym: hey someone stole my purse This guy first.
Scott: he had to wrestle it away from the woman.
Scott: This isn't like a pickpocket pickpocket.
Rym: You got to wait for the person walking by with the purse that's hanging by a thread.
Scott: Yeah, okay, that's good.
Scott: But this guy this was not.
Scott: this is actually the purse.
Scott: I was pretty surprised was freaking huge.
Scott: It was like half a suitcase man.
Scott: It had these giant handles.
Scott: I was like, whoa There must have been something really good in there or this guy needed some serious money to buy drugs or something To make him do something soda generally.
Rym: I've seen that the bigger purse someone has the less money they actually have in it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what was in there But there must have been something good that he knew was in there for him to take it.
Scott: so dumbly.
Rym: I'm glad I don't need to carry enough stuff on me to require a purse.
Rym: I carry a tiny wallet that has everything.
Scott: I got too many gizmos now, but I can fit him in all my pockets.
Rym: So it's all good sound have so many gizmos and usually if I go anywhere where I need gizmos I have my trench coat.
Scott: I only take the gizmos I need.
Scott: I don't take all my gizmos everywhere But I do take all my gizmos to working back every day because I can and have a backpack and stuff.
Rym: so Someone fixed at least one of the problems with the Xbox.
Scott: Oh the the crashing.
Rym: Yeah, they suspended the powers fly by a string and it didn't overheat anymore.
Scott: I guess that works.
Rym: Yeah, apparently the pot if you were looking the owner's manual and basically the only way to actually use the Xbox correctly is to Put it on a hard cool Surface away from any other object and put the power supply on a similarly hard cool surface far away from everything and they can't even Be near each other.
Scott: It's so weird because some people have the problem and some people don't and other people have kind of the problem and other people It's just crashing all over the place.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people do reports or numbers or anything.
Rym: It's definitely some sort of hardware overheating issue.
Scott: I heard one theory was that People were talking about how much money Microsoft loses on the Xbox 360.
Rym: Yeah about 140 bucks 126 whatever.
Scott: but the the point was is that guy basically did his calculations based on the normal prices of the components and then they were talking about how Microsoft bought in bulk and they got a Discount on the components that wasn't calculated in because of how much they bought.
Scott: and then they're like then they bought some.
Scott: maybe they bought Some cheaper components than you think in order to get the price down even more.
Scott: so they make less of a loss.
Scott: But maybe the cheaper components are why it's crashing.
Rym: Well part of the problem is honestly computer power supplies are very unreliable.
Rym: even top-end Server data center power supplies are actually pretty piss-poor and fail on a fairly regular basis.
Scott: I had one fail on me and I didn't even know that was it But I couldn't.
Scott: now I'm gonna remember it.
Rym: for the rest of my life I've had three power supplies fail on me in my time as a personal computer user.
Rym: two of them were Antec's.
Scott: I believe Antec makes power supplies.
Scott: Yeah That's when I bought my new computer.
Rym: I bought like this super and at work thing at work I've had at least ten servers have power supplies.
Rym: just go or start.
Scott: Like the more power says something has and the more power supply it has the more likely it is to just not work.
Rym: Actually the what what goes on there is that almost every power supply even from companies you think you trust that make power supplies They really really really overstate the power and when you buy a 500 watt power supply It can really only output 300 watts reliably.
Scott: Well, that must be why the 300 watt power supplies don't actually make the computers boot and you need to get the 400 watt one.
Rym: Yeah, unless you buy a real power supply from an actual company.
Rym: But those are very very expensive because switched power supplies are very expensive.
Scott: Yeah, see as long it doesn't really matter as long as it did they're consistent, you know It's like how many people who buy a 400 watt power supply for their computer?
Scott: Actually like are counting the watts and and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: They're just trying to get something that'll make the computer boot And as long as they know the right number to buy to make that happen, it's it's all good.
Rym: Though I mean with the Xbox at least it seems to be more an issue of Microsoft didn't test the Xbox in an actual environment where someone might use it that could be part of it.
Scott: I think also some people are right in that.
Scott: I think a lot of the giant power supply bricks are a mixture of different parts and all kinds of crazy things to cut costs.
Scott: Yeah, it seems very likely.
Rym: Well, the Xbox itself has its own issues because that if you've heard reports that it's loud.
Rym: That's an understatement.
Rym: It's louder than my computer.
Rym: My computer is a 70 pound Monstrosity in a giant tower with rattling fans.
Scott: I wish there was some way we could raise your computer off the ground with a string to prevent it from overheating.
Rym: My computer isn't actually overheat It beeps.
Rym: Yeah, it beeps and I fixed that by raising the threshold at which it beeps thing is my computer is fairly reliable and Yeah, I'm not buying a new one anytime soon.
Rym: Yeah, I guess though if I buy a new one I can record this cast in stereo instead of mono.
Scott: Hey, you just buy a new sound card for that.
Rym: No, my sound card does it.
Rym: it just post-production becomes really really slow because My computer takes a long time to condense a bunch of tracks into two as opposed to into one.
Rym: You
Scott: know you could use my computer or Pete's computer
Rym: now because the time the the time and effort of putting all the files on your computer doing it and then
Scott: You could use SSH and then you use some command line programs and yeah,
Rym: yeah I do that
Scott: don't have the skills.
Rym: No I just have to actually do it every day and then go over into your computer and do it or X forward into your computer.
Scott: You could use Pete's computer.
Rym: the server server is not that fast.
Scott: It's a lot faster than your computer.
Scott: How fast is it fast as my computer?
Scott: I think it's like a one point six gigahertz.
Rym: I think yeah I got a one gigahertz.
Scott: So you got point six more.
Scott: also, it's an Athlon XP not a Thunderbird.
Rym: Yeah, the problem the limiter still seems to be ran because the CPU doesn't max out most of the time.
Scott: Well, that computer also is a crap ton of rain.
Rym: My computer has almost a gig around.
Scott: Well, there you go.
Scott: my computer doesn't so much only is 512 but it's it's DDR 400s real fast Of course, I also got a crappy Sound Blaster live.
Rym: It's actually a platinum.
Scott: It's the best Sound Blaster live yet a Sound Blaster live value of my computer, but I don't use it anymore.
Scott: I use the enforce thing that's on the motherboard.
Rym: Yeah, you know the value and the platinum are the same except they solder some things to the point of breaking them.
Scott: Well values they don't have the original original value.
Scott: when I when I bought the value the only choices were value and gold Didn't exist.
Rym: I bought the platinum the day it came out.
Scott: platinum came way later like a year later.
Rym: wasn't that much later?
Rym: No, it was actually pretty quick because the platinum and the regular.
Rym: the only difference between them is the software they come with.
Scott: Yeah, they never really changed the card that much.
Scott: They just kept re-releasing it with different labels.
Scott: Remember they had like an mp3 plus and a game.
Rym: Yeah, the only one that's different is the value because the value is actually missing a lot of core functionality.
Scott: That's all I needed back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it gave me my 4.1 audio.
Scott: It sounded good.
Scott: It was cheap.
Scott: I was there.
Scott: Ah Nowadays, I got high quality stuff with the onboard whatever with the optical and my new speakers which do most of the work because Linux sure as hell doesn't do the work About speakers that do it instead.
Scott: Yeah, so U of R Developed this new thing where they can actually take pictures of retinas in people's eyeballs.
Rym: That's kind of old news actually.
Scott: But yeah, I saw that and apparently everyone has different cones and rods.
Rym: Yeah, didn't we talk about that?
Rym: Already I don't think so.
Scott: All right, I never saw this before Really?
Rym: Cuz I thought we talked about it not on the podcast just in general.
Scott: We might have talked about something related.
Rym: No, I'm pretty sure we talked about that itself.
Rym: I looked at my aim log at work tomorrow Maybe but the thing we talked about today on aim.
Scott: No, we didn't I think we did.
Scott: But anyway The thing is is that even though everyone has different cones and rods They're pretty sure that everyone's brain kind of arrives at a very similar result despite huge differences in the cones.
Rym: Yeah, we did talk about this.
Rym: It's the same reason why even though you see something like a room under yellow light.
Rym: You still know what color everything is and you still see it as red even though In terms of light, it's actually not red at all and nothing would detect it as red, but your eyes still sees it as red.
Scott: Yeah, but you'd think that people with like a bunch of red cones would see red stuff better, but maybe actually yeah They would see it better, but they still see it as red.
Scott: Yeah, but like maybe they would see green stuff more poorly.
Rym: But that's why that's one of the reasons why women tend to have.
Rym: women actually have more rods and cones in their eyes specifically a lot more cones and Women tend to actually be able to differentiate between colors much better than men.
Scott: Uh-huh That's cool.
Scott: Yeah, but you know nothing wrong with my eyeballs.
Rym: Yeah, even though you didn't seem to see the microphone stand sitting right next to the other microphone stands a Radio Shack.
Scott: Hey, it's nothing to do with it Mr.
Scott: Can't tell red from orange?
Rym: I Note that in mule the color of the characters on the orange team is orange not red.
Scott: There were things that are red and you point to them and say they're orange.
Scott: you point to things Advance wars which are red and you say they're orange now because if you look at the palette, they're actually orange.
Scott: Oh, they're not.
Scott: Yeah, they are.
Rym: Oh, they're not anyway Mmm, so Sony's rootkit fiasco is just getting better and better.
Scott: What the hell this kid.
Scott: this has to be over by now.
Rym: No, apparently the company that made the rootkit forum first for internet Someone found a couple of posts from an employee of theirs who was asking for help on these news groups.
Rym: He wanted people to give him the source code to lame and like to help him write everything and he was offering money for it.
Scott: So Sony basically hired this crap company to make something for them and they hired a crap programmer and that one crap Programmer who didn't know what the hell he was doing ended up making the giant giant butterfly effect type fiasco where his tiny tiny stupidity made a huge problem for everybody.
Rym: a Quote from his post.
Rym: I know it sounds like I'm just after some free code due to my laziness But I really don't have the time and I'm serious about the cash.
Rym: I really need this functionality.
Rym: I know that that was all one sentence a Winner.
Scott: Yeah, I think he's almost as big a winner as the purse snatcher.
Rym: I gotta say there are a lot of bad coders out there that seem to just copy stuff from other programs and clutch it together.
Scott: You mean like all the people who barely made it through?
Scott: You know like RIT the people who are like scraping together their projects and everything Yeah, or all the people in their cs4 class this year who cheated.
Scott: Oh Yeah, I heard that story.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I don't get it.
Rym: people cheat at RIT on a CS class And at RIT the way they do it is if you're caught cheating the minimum punishment is an automatic act And often they suspend or expel you.
Scott: Yeah, that's what they should do.
Scott: Yep, but I mean it's so obvious to any student looking at another student Like that guy actually knows what he's doing.
Scott: That guy is just doing the work and getting through, you know It's just obvious.
Scott: there you don't even need to like I'm pretty sure it's obvious the professor's also But they have to give the grade based on the syllabus and whatever, you know, they do.
Scott: but when it's so obvious You should just be like look seriously.
Scott: You don't belong here.
Scott: You don't know what you're doing.
Scott: You don't care You're not trying.
Scott: I mean, come on.
Scott: Why are you doing CS if you're if you're not and paying a billion dollars to go.
Scott: All right, you know what?
Rym: because then the retention rate would be even lower.
Scott: Well, you just you know, you accept more people in the first place, but then even more of them will fail out.
Scott: Well, you make the standards real high.
Rym: That's why they keep wanting to build more dorms and everything because they can't.
Rym: they can't accept more people They can't fit them and even though half of them will fail out They got to hold them all their standards But then not enough people will go and they won't make enough money.
Scott: You either have to raise the standards to make it really hard so that all kinds of awesome people come like You know at MIT and all those other high up schools or lower the standards and make it easier.
Scott: You can't have it be hard with low standards or else you get these dumb people doing hard stuff and not succeeding.
Scott: And you know what those people tend to give you money Yeah, but it'd be a lot better to have you know Other people to give you money who actually stay and keep giving and giving and giving and giving and giving and giving.
Rym: Yeah, but remember it costs a lot more per student to take care of upperclassmen in college than it does for freshmen.
Scott: Well, it's almost nothing to take care of lots and lots of upperclassmen doing lots and lots of expensive things.
Scott: You can afford to even more dorms for even more fodder freshmen who will go out?
Rym: Yeah, because there's not a lot of stuff at least in IT research money at least in IT.
Rym: You know the biggest major on campus they there's not so much useful research coming out of there.
Scott: See, that's the other thing.
Scott: is you got to actually have some useful research.
Rym: There's not so much useful IT research that universities can really do anymore.
Scott: There's plenty of stuff that can still be done.
Rym: this stuff being done even today Oh, yeah, but a lot of it's not.
Rym: no one cares about it.
Rym: and even companies that are looking for technology Don't care about new fields.
Rym: They don't care about things like ipv6 or high bandwidth carrier lines.
Rym: Most company you're still happy with their freaking t1 and their net.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not about companies It's about getting research money from like, you know, the National Science whatever is that money's drying up?
Scott: Yeah You know money is drying up which means fighting for it is even, you know more competitive.
Scott: So you really have to put up a fight or you're gonna get or just accept a bunch of students and get a whole bunch Of money from then instead, but then that's not a good long-term plan.
Scott: That's just what I'm saying.
Scott: is it works, but it's not a good long-term plan in the long term.
Scott: That'll fail.
Rym: I don't know though.
Rym: It's been working for a long time and it's slowly slowly not working as well.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: The attention rate isn't getting worse is staying about the same.
Scott: Yeah, people are getting dumber.
Scott: It's gonna hurt him now.
Rym: They'll just dumb their all the classes down.
Scott: They don't.
Scott: that's what I said.
Scott: They have to make it easier.
Rym: if you gonna have low acceptance or what they could do is make all these easy.
Rym: Oh if they want to be evil make all the class is easy Until the senior year and then suddenly they get really difficult.
Rym: So only the really smart people pass and all the other people just got suckered into spending a hundred grand on nothing.
Scott: I Guess you could.
Rym: I could see him doing that.
Scott: I don't know how that would profit for them.
Rym: How would it not profit him?
Scott: I just don't.
Scott: what's the point of not giving you someone one more year?
Rym: you get one more year money out of them because Then people will say oh RIT grads are crap because they would be.
Scott: a lot of them are Yeah.
Rym: But I've learned kind of scarily enough in my job workings that People from other like people who go to get learn IT or CS from a school that doesn't specialize in IT or CS.
Rym: No offense to anyone out there.
Rym: They often are terrible.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is is like it's so random That you know people just don't.
Scott: basically just don't trust college graduates, you know They only want to look at all kinds of other stuff They like some people would go to like a community college, right?
Scott: And little do you know that that community college had like one genius CS professor teacher of awesome and all his students learned amazing things.
Scott: But you know at some really awesome college you can get through by slacking off, you know 99% of college graduate guys who come to you they all suck.
Rym: Well, I think a lot of that is that people trust any of.
Rym: a lot of people in college don't have any real-world Experience and really can't live on their own.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's another problem That comes from even before in the high school days that I don't know into now like all the kids I remember from college whose parents visit him every weekend or every weekend.
Rym: They drove back home to be with their family.
Rym: Yeah Those kids need I knew one girl who her mom came and did her lot like took her laundry and did it and brought her Food so she wouldn't have to go shopping or eating the deed in the cafeteria with anyone.
Scott: Yeah, a little problem.
Rym: Yeah, she failed out after a couple years expected.
Scott: alright, so There's this guy and he has a let's see 12 satellite dishes on his front porch.
Scott: That's dumb and he's getting five thousand different radio and TV stations with it.
Rym: Alright, so he's getting more media than he can possibly consume and he's going about to buy his 13th dish.
Rym: I think he's obsessed.
Scott: He's a 54 year old former ice cream salesman.
Scott: I Think he's got a little problem.
Scott: Okay, unless he has let's see 12 TiVo's I Don't think he's watching as much as he can watch.
Rym: What was that statistic?
Rym: that more porn is made.
Rym: There is more than an hour's worth of porn made every hour in the world.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Rym: Yeah, so it is physically impossible to watch all of the pornography that has been created.
Scott: You could have multiple televisions and watch multiple porn simultaneously.
Rym: Yeah, but then you're multitasking.
Scott: Hey if you had two penises.
Rym: Uh-huh, though speaking of porn this guy in Utah Ralph Yarrow Wants to standardize like remember how when they wanted to make an xxx domain and all the porn in there
Scott: The xxx domain it would make it easier for people who want porn to find it and not easily block anyone who didn't know.
Rym: I disagree with it because one would you make a law saying porn has to go there?
Rym: Yes, what's porn?
Rym: How do you define pornography would have?
Rym: what a site about mammograms go there?
Rym: What about something you just disagree with?
Rym: what about a girl in a short skirt?
Rym: Some people are offended by people who don't wear a vane.
Scott: it is in the place You are.
Rym: any if you all right, so then does he realize that?
Rym: If you're in Utah, all right, all the porn from Utah is in xxx, but then in Southern, California There's a bunch of stuff that you would consider porn.
Rym: That's not an xxx.
Scott: Yeah, so if I was in California and a site was let's say normally something.com right, but in Utah that was considered porn I would have to go to something that That's not workable at all.
Scott: Why not one?
Rym: we are you gonna make it every who decides?
Rym: What's porn?
Rym: so someone who has a website say I'm in I'm in Southern, California, and they don't care about it, and I have a porn site and it's something calm.
Rym: You're saying I have to buy an xxx specifically for other places.
Scott: No, it's up to the other places to put you in xxx in their place.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: put you or the other places put you in xxx as?
Rym: In it is it basically you want them to give you a free domain?
Scott: No, it's.
Scott: if they want to make me xxx in their state then they have to take calm and make it xxx.
Rym: You can't do that.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: That's not how it works Scott.
Rym: That's not how DNS works.
Scott: That's tough.
Rym: there's really there's.
Scott: I do it.
Scott: that way you can do it.
Rym: Yeah, there's no technical way to do it.
Rym: plus.
Rym: I there would still be besides if you did that all right fine.
Rym: So it routes it.
Rym: see if you go dot xxx takes you calm.
Rym: the calm would still work Mmm.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think you understand how DNS works because that is an absolutely impossible thing to do.
Scott: No, maybe we should upgrade to have PVC.
Rym: that that still there's no way to.
Rym: that is nothing to do with DNS at all You realize.
Scott: yeah, how about just people who consider themselves to be poor?
Scott: I mean people who are porn sites want it because it'll make people find them easier.
Rym: Yeah, but they'll also keep their comms Don't?
Rym: the only people who've advocated for this seriously are people who think they can make laws that'll force all porn to be on xxx and nowhere else under penalty of law.
Rym: That way they can block xxx Define porn.
Scott: it would work, but you know you can't with my standards for porn in different places.
Rym: You know yeah, hence.
Rym: It's an unworkable idea.
Scott: You know it would be workable if you let me decide what was porn and what wasn't cuz I could decide pretty easily.
Scott: That's just like this naked It's.
Scott: it's basically hey our guys gonna look or guys or girls gonna look at this for the purpose of getting it off.
Rym: Yes, no, but so why should porn have its own domain?
Scott: Why is porn special to make it easier to find?
Rym: Google It's still You know it.
Scott: It's still not easy to find.
Rym: pull anyway.
Rym: This guy has about the same understanding of ports as you do of DNS.
Rym: apparently he wants there to be a porn ports.
Rym: Apparently he found out that there's sixty five thousand five hundred and thirty five ports on a computer that you access the interwebs with and Apparently he figured that right now everything comes in through this one port.
Rym: It's like a channel channel 80.
Rym: Why is porn coming in the same channel as kids entertainment?
Rym: There should be a separate channel for porn.
Rym: There's sixty five thousand channels.
Rym: most of them are being used.
Rym: We should set up a channel for porn channel for education channel for blah blah blah.
Rym: In other words this guy has probably got the least understanding of internet architecture of anyone I've ever.
Scott: what hurt us.
Scott: what we could do is we could have all web servers serving porn sites run on port 8,000 instead of 80.
Rym: you realize that's also silly I know, but that's what he wants right.
Rym: yeah He calls his initiative CP 80 or clean port 80.
Scott: He is Stupid.
Scott: he does not know about IP quote.
Rym: So why aren't more of the sixty five thousand plus ports being used for content their plight?
Rym: There's a plentiful amount of channels out there.
Rym: Why are we not making adult content and assigning it to its own channel?
Rym: doesn't that make sense?
Scott: No, because the ports aren't channels now.
Scott: That's not a synonymous analogy analogous thing.
Rym: Congruity yep equality Plus the fact that most corporate firewalls block everything, but port 80 anyway and Almost every bad thing in the world has been made to just proxy through port 80.
Scott: Yes, the thing is some people manage their corporate firewalls really well.
Scott: They say your company doesn't my company does not.
Scott: but most companies say anything can go out Nothing can come in.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: I gotta say That's the only setting you need.
Scott: anything can go out nothing come in.
Rym: What about servers you have?
Scott: if you have a server you put it in the DMZ?
Rym: All right, what if you want to dial in?
Rym: got a VPN set up?
Scott: You have a little separate.
Rym: you know VPN And I assume you mean stateful because if you just set up if you set up access list where anything go out nothing come in.
Rym: Nothing could get out either because you'd send a ping out and the reply would never get back to you, but you know no Incoming requests for connection you know?
Scott: yeah Yeah, I can take to a web server, and then it sends me back the web page.
Scott: it gets better.
Scott: He gets through.
Rym: yeah You realize that's pretty much if you set up a like a pick Cisco firewall.
Rym: if you do it the basic way That's the default.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: And the only way you'll have a crap your corporate firewalls if you go out of your way to make it bad.
Scott: Basically they went out of their way to basically do a bunch of hacky stuff to make a bunch of these weird proprietary things.
Scott: They've got do weird stuff And it basically screws everything up.
Rym: that sounds really dubious to me because there aren't many things that do weird things using ports.
Scott: They use just crazy Freaking weird software isn't there?
Scott: not a hundred percent awesome?
Scott: if you came in there you could clean it up probably real easily because seriously I don't even need to know what the application is.
Rym: you want something to go through a firewall And you don't know anything about it.
Rym: run it run ethereal.
Scott: The firewall is this sonic wall thing.
Scott: It's basically.
Scott: There's a piece of software called sonic wall.
Rym: ah but they oh God if you want to run a firewall you buy a router and you put access on.
Scott: so they bought this thing.
Scott: It's a sonic wall firewall.
Scott: It's basically this piece of hardware that runs this software.
Scott: right it's as if you.
Scott: it's like kind of like the Google box.
Scott: only it runs this firewall software and It has a web interface and everything like that And they just tinker with this thing and it does all kinds of things that firewalls aren't supposed to do Like you can block porn with it even though they turn that off after it basically blocked every internet site There was all
Rym: right, so this sounds like a kludgy slow Terrible thing.
Scott: it's not slow.
Scott: It's just misconfigured because the people handling it aren't perfect.
Scott: awesome.
Rym: Wait a minute, but how does it block porn?
Scott: It looks.
Rym: if it looks at the content does it?
Rym: do you mean it takes apart the HTV and looks for like keywords?
Scott: If you turn that feature on yeah, it looks for.
Rym: you know how slow that is.
Scott: yeah, it's slow.
Scott: if you turn that on yeah This thing isn't great trust me, but it's not so.
Scott: the thing could be great if they didn't mess it up.
Scott: Well, it wouldn't be great.
Scott: It would be a normal perfectly normal firewall.
Rym: Well, my consulting rate is $75 an hour.
Rym: if they want me to fix everything.
Scott: They don't want you to fix everything.
Scott: They think everything's working.
Scott: Alright Alright, so here's an awesome thing.
Scott: This is pretty awesome.
Rym: This is your thing of the day.
Scott: No what alright, so There's a game called Call of Duty 2. it's a. it's an army game right alright and as the case with many Multiplayer online type games the users are complaining.
Rym: What are they complaining about?
Scott: their number one complaint is legitimate in that the developers have not made any sort of anti-cheat anything?
Scott: So cheating is basically rampant.
Rym: alright like counter-strike was for most of his existence.
Scott: I counted right goes for most of his existence except now.
Scott: I think they do have a reasonable expectation that there should be anti cheating systems Because most big games do right.
Rym: Yeah, though there are ways around that you just only play with people You know.
Rym: or like.
Rym: the clan of the fossil rockers was good back in the day when back when people cheated just completely and There was no way to stop them there was this clan where pretty much all the only people are in.
Rym: it were cool people and cool people recommended by cool people and The.
Rym: all their servers were password protected and you were guaranteed to get a good game if you went to one of their servers.
Scott: Well, that's cool, but these people have found a I think an okay solution.
Scott: I'm not sure what I think about it yet, but they're gonna have.
Scott: oh All of the servers that are in on it are going to strike.
Scott: It's not a game like World of Warcraft where Blizzard run where the developer runs the servers.
Scott: this it's like counter-strike where the servers are all run by users.
Scott: So a bunch of the servers in fact a very very large portion of them are just gonna keep their servers on But change them to say they're on strike and not allow any users to use them.
Scott: So when people log in to play the game They're gonna see this list of servers that all say on strike with no one playing.
Rym: That's a good idea because I gotta say I've learned that it
Scott: basically destroys the game
Rym: Especially since that'll really work well just because it seems to be that the people the types of people who run servers for games like that Tend to be the type of people that organize themselves and they all seem to know each other pretty well And it's real easy to spread the word about something like that.
Scott: Yep, so they're gonna shut down all the servers for 24 hours and hopefully that will encourage the developers and the people who run the game and publisher or whatever to Develop an anti-cheat system and meet some other demands or else their game is gonna be Pretty poopy as anyone who tries to play it from now on won't have a server to go to.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, basically like either you make your game better or will kill your game and you won't make any more money off of it.
Rym: Well, I wish them the best of luck.
Rym: Yeah way to go thing of the day.
Rym: Okay thing of the day thing of the day Thing of the day is my thing.
Rym: What's your thing?
Scott: So I saw this.
Scott: it's pretty funny.
Scott: it today Wasn't really that exciting.
Rym: No, it wasn't.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: So so people make fun of the family circus, which isn't hard to make fun of.
Rym: Yeah, I mean honestly and I'm not one to say something's objectively bad.
Rym: But family circus as a comic or as literature or as a waste of ink on paper is Probably the worst like least entertaining thing I've ever experienced.
Scott: I must say I mildly enjoy that.
Rym: I was shot at once.
Scott: so I must say though I do mildly enjoy the family circuses with the dotted line and he runs around the yard and stuff.
Rym: Oh, I enjoyed it once the first time it was done.
Scott: Well, it's because in those at least you can look at all the interesting little like funny things that he does Along the line like oh look he jumped over the pool.
Rym: I never thought I'd be in a position where where you mister everything is crap was defending family sir.
Scott: No, no, all the rest of family circus is pretty much ninety nine nine nine percent crap.
Rym: You defended a little bit.
Rym: It's like saying yeah, Hitler was a bastard, but he didn't personally kill a baby.
Scott: Well, he was.
Scott: he was evil, but he was smart.
Scott: It's like, you know, he Stalin was paranoid, but he stayed in power long.
Scott: Oh god.
Rym: I heard this Wasn't really a joke the other day was just a Something but someone was talking.
Rym: They're like, what if Hitler?
Rym: Actually went to art school and graduated and became a mass murderer anyway And someone else was like it'd be even worse.
Rym: It would have been a more protest slightly more pretentious Hitler.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so anyway, someone remixed the family circus with a good buddy HP Lovecraft Cthulhu photography Really?
Rym: Ah, really?
Scott: Yeah, so it's pretty funny.
Scott: You got these.
Scott: you get these comics named.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: This one's named Mughal.
Rym: Ooh, I see one named photography and then one named photography.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Okay, the site was a little broken there for a second.
Scott: Hey, here's one called bomber.
Scott: I can't pass that.
Scott: Okay, so there's a picture of the dad in the car with the little girl Next to him and the girl is like rubbing her eye and you see her eyes are closed.
Scott: She seems kind of like oh.
Scott: And it says amidst a blinding glare of descending fire the voice of heaven resounded with the blasphemies of hell and the mingling agony of all the lost Reverberated in one apocalyptic planet rendering peel of cyclopean din.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I could do loop a target and the girls like Sorrow you know, it makes me very happy that HP Lovecraft work have gained such a Foothold in geek culture.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't even know who he was before I went to college.
Scott: really I guess my mom never even heard of it.
Rym: My mother was really into horror writing and science like dark science fiction type writing.
Rym: like.
Rym: she was fan of Stephen King and all those people.
Rym: But she was rich.
Rym: She always loved HP Lovecraft and at a very young age.
Rym: She gave me tales of horror in the macabre And I was hooked on Cthulhu from a very young age never even heard of it until Wow, you even know what it was.
Scott: and then people were like Lovecraft.
Scott: Cthulhu I'm like, what the hell you talking about?
Rym: But I mean it's got to the point where every gaming store that has even any sort of respectability has multiple Cthulhu Related dolls or plushies.
Rym: That's cuz.
Scott: there's that Cthulhu game.
Scott: There's multiple Cthulhu, you know, yeah It's cool.
Rym: Yeah, we actually played the Cthulhu real playing game once Did a little one-off.
Scott: Oh, well, we did also play pokey through.
Rym: now pokey through that game was fantastic.
Rym: It was Pokemon plus Cthulhu.
Rym: no more need be said I Liked it.
Scott: I think I'd like to play it again.
Rym: Ah All right.
Rym: so my thing of the day.
Rym: remember a long time ago super they had this car that had like this magic suspension with solenoids that Would like make it go over potholes or over stuff.
Scott: Well, it basically didn't.
Scott: basically shove the tires into holes and made other tires go up If the other tires were gonna hit a bump and it kept the car as level as could be done.
Rym: Yep Well, it's back and it's badass.
Rym: now Bo's made a system That's like that only a thousand times better and they're gonna put it in some new like luxury Lexus cars Eventually.
Scott: Yeah, why are they putting it in this luxury car?
Scott: So you need because it cost five thousand dollars.
Scott: Okay, but why don't you put it in a race car?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think it takes a lot of power.
Rym: I think it actually hurts the gas mileage.
Scott: Oh, does it hurt?
Rym: Yeah, there's not a lot.
Scott: But if you're in a race car that's not worried about gas mileage like a rally car doesn't need to worry about gas.
Scott: It just goes down the hill once or twice, you know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I mean there's not much information yet but they've got pictures and apparently this car will drive over a two by six piece of wood and Various other bits of debris.
Rym: without it like the driver won't even notice.
Rym: Yeah, you could run over a small child.
Scott: not even that would definitely help out.
Scott: I think monster trucks It would help out motorcycles that drive it like a motocross type things that drive in the dirt Yeah, yeah max type motocross type things.
Rym: and it would help out rally cars huge Rally, it'll help out drivers in Rochester Buffalo and Detroit, you know aka pothole cities.
Scott: Yeah, it'll help them out.
Rym: I don't think it'll help out someone like Formula One or NASCAR No, but in Formula One they could drive over that a red and white bit at the edge without going butter butter butter butter butter Maybe.
Scott: Somehow.
Scott: I don't think it doesn't matter.
Rym: that doesn't really slow them down Man, they should just bring back the vacuum cars.
Scott: Yeah, so everyone can die again, yeah, but you know what.
Rym: that's the risk you take.
Rym: you got a super license you're rich.
Scott: It's called first of all, the cars are called ground effects and second of all People stopped driving them because they were so dangerous.
Scott: What they need to do is make the car as fast as it can be Where they can still find someone who's willing to drive it who's good.
Scott: I mean, they can always be crazy.
Rym: I was about to say yeah, you can find anyone to do just about anything.
Rym: The problem is finding someone to do anything.
Scott: Basically what they do is they just take the current racers and if the current racer says this car is too fast I won't drive it then it's too fast.
Scott: They won't drive it.
Scott: if the car is you know Not fast enough then they'll say it's yes, this isn't.
Rym: even Schumacher lately is like yeah, the cars are too slow.
Scott: Well, it's it's like they're you know, one guy says yeah, the cars are too fast.
Scott: Another guy says no the cars are too slow.
Scott: Well, it's all because one guy can handle it.
Scott: one guy can't you know?
Scott: They have some people get in these things and there were a lot of people complain that with all the technology that goes into them That it basically driving Formula One is like a video game.
Scott: Anyone can do it.
Scott: Whatever Meanwhile people who test drive these things like damn that's too fast.
Scott: I can't drive that.
Scott: Oh my god You know, it's just the literal speed and acceleration of the car is more than people can handle.
Scott: It's like a feet Like what you need.
Scott: do you need to wait until you get like five levels?
Scott: you get another feet drive f1.
Rym: Yeah, well I can imagine cuz I when I was real young I went to a space camp.
Rym: Actually, I went to space Academy because I was a little too old for space camp and we got to go in the gravity simulator.
Rym: You know the thing.
Rym: they spin you around you make funny faces.
Rym: Yep, and Up around five six G's.
Rym: it's real hard to do anything.
Scott: Yeah, you know f1 is basically like you go into a turn.
Scott: It's five G's at your back and then it's your canes.
Scott: you turn left real quick and it's five G's in the other direction.
Scott: Yep, yep, you know, it's pretty crazy.
Scott: Multiple G's changing all the time as you turn speed up slow down.
Rym: Though there is one thing that is actually harder and more G's than that, you know flying a fighter jet.
Scott: Yeah, they were.
Scott: they actually mentioned fighter jets on this f1.
Rym: Yeah, so the difference is the reason I found.
Rym: I know the reason.
Scott: fighter jets don't just pass out immediately That don't they have like suits and thing.
Rym: But what the flight suit does is it actually puts pressure on the body Like on the abdomen to keep the blood from spilling out of the head and into the abdomen.
Rym: So the blood stays in the brain and you stay conscious.
Scott: Yes, that's good.
Rym: It squeezes your real hard All right.
Rym: It's actually kind of painful.
Rym: I didn't actually get to do it, but I got to wear a flight suit as part of a cool thing.
Rym: We did.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It sucks.
Rym: Don't ever fly a fighter jet.
Rym: It's it it sucks.
Scott: You know once I saw this lady who was like the morning talk show TV lady fly like an f-15 and She seemed to be having a good time.
Rym: Yeah, if you just fly it around I mean fighter jets.
Rym: modern fighter jets are so computer-controlled that other than Landing pretty much an idiot could fly them.
Scott: You see that's what they were talking about with f1.
Scott: is is that's why they compared it to the fighter jet?
Scott: because people complained When they were getting too computer-controlled and too easy to drive but the reality was no It's even though it might seem like that.
Rym: It's really hard Yep, but the thing is it's easy to fly a fighter jet in a straight line or to do a little turn But if you're actually fighting or flying hard, you'll just pass out and die Probably unless you're trained.
Scott: Yep, unless you spend a lot of time in this.
Rym: in course It's not like the US military has ever really fought against anyone else who had fighter jets.
Rym: Not since the Korean War makes yeah in the Korean War.
Rym: That was the last time our Air Force engaged another Air Force.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is Air Force is really aren't designed to take on Air Forces so much or fighter I have to take on other Forces.
Rym: fighter jets exist should be pretty much purely for air superiority to make sure that no one else has anything in the sky.
Scott: Well, I mean that's the thing is though.
Scott: Why why would you even put a plane in the sky in the first place?
Scott: Well, it's not to blow up another plane because if your planes are only to blow up other planes and that's it Just no one puts any planes up.
Rym: Well, that's why you have multiple kinds of the bombers, right?
Scott: The only the real goal is to have the bomber succeed in bombing something.
Scott: Yeah, but that's what the bomber doesn't get blowed up by.
Rym: You do realize.
Rym: that's what air superiority is.
Rym: All it means is you have fighter jets up that ensure that no one else can take off a fighter jet.
Rym: Thus no one else can take off anything.
Scott: Yeah but a little a on the ground takes out the whole thing.
Rym: actually know because Our technology is so advanced that any country we've ever fought didn't even have effective a a.
Scott: But I mean a a is so cheap.
Scott: you could just have so much of it that doesn't matter how techno.
Rym: But it just doesn't work.
Rym: because you just cruise missile.
Scott: it I guess.
Scott: but if you have a cruise missiles What do you need the bombers for?
Rym: because the bombers are more precision.
Rym: cruise missiles are not as accurate as the media would like you to?
Rym: Believe.
Scott: oh, they seem pretty accurate to me.
Rym: They're really not a sieve - they're really Yeah, they don't miss.
Rym: they never cause a civilian casualty ever.
Rym: they just destroy.
Scott: whatever unit you wanted to destroy Well destroys the topmost unit in the city because why would you put it anywhere, but a city?
Rym: I used it to take out guys that were standing in front of cities, okay?
Rym: If this I used it to take out.
Scott: I need to be clear.
Rym: I once used one to take out a transport full of troops that was going towards my capital And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds dot be burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: Also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.