Rym: It's Tuesday November 15th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: so uh Mario Kart came out today Mario and That's all we've been doing since we got it Mario.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: and uh it's video game day coincidentally enough, so we're gonna talk about Mario Kart, but we're gonna try to hold out and talk about anything else and We'll see how long it takes before we end up just talking about Mario Kart anyway,
Scott: so so start your timer and Yeah, it's not gonna last very long at all.
Scott: I mean It's it's hard enough trying not to talk about it any second.
Scott: I could just stop podcasting and go play.
Rym: Yeah, even though we can't play online, but we'll get to that.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: We talked about it.
Scott: We couldn't hold out for more than two seconds.
Rym: So anyway Did you go to a GameStop to get this?
Scott: I went to a GameStop And you didn't go to that GameStop though not the horrible GameStop in the mall near us with the with the angry girl in it The.
Scott: I went to the good GameStop in the city, and it is a good GameStop.
Scott: But I made the mistake of going during lunch, and it was kind of busy.
Scott: Well that was my first trip there, and they called me last night and said it'll be there afternoon.
Scott: So I went at like 12 31.
Rym: wait a minute.
Rym: you went at 12 31.
Scott: No no no no 12. between 12 30 and 1.
Rym: you realize afternoon goes all the way until about 4.
Scott: Yeah, I know, but they said they didn't say afternoon.
Scott: They said afternoon.
Rym: Did they say the words afternoon?
Scott: It was two words.
Rym: Okay, I'll just take your word on it.
Scott: They didn't say you can come pick it up in the afternoon.
Scott: They said you can come pick it up any time afternoon, and you trusted them.
Scott: well No, actually I didn't trust them, but that was the only time I figured.
Scott: You know I want to get it as soon as possible, and that was my opportunity to leave work, so hey I went to check.
Scott: huh it was better than sitting in my office doing nothing.
Scott: so of course It wasn't there.
Scott: But I you know it pissed me off.
Scott: not that it wasn't there because I kind of expected it to not be there that yet Because you know UPS or whatever always sucks.
Scott: I mean half the time I've ever gone to pick up a pre-ordered thing.
Scott: on the day it comes out It's just not there.
Scott: yet It happens all the time.
Rym: You know I've learned to just wait one day.
Scott: Yeah, but I couldn't wait one day for this And I'm glad I didn't.
Rym: but or I just tell you to buy it And then if it's there you spend the time and buy it for me And if it's not there I caused any time when I went back after work at like 4 30 to go get it.
Scott: There was no one in the store, and I just picked it up.
Rym: Yeah after I wasted all that time I didn't waste any more time.
Scott: well the point is is that it kind of pisses me off.
Scott: is that With barely you know not a large amount of money or effort Gamestop can make a system where you go online and you see the exact stock of every game stop And you see the exact hour and minute when things are going to arrive in what quantity.
Rym: you know why they don't do that?
Rym: Because people like us are actually not their primary customer.
Scott: Yeah But the point is is that there's a whole lot of people.
Scott: half there was a big long line at noon.
Scott: Half the people in that line were there for non for something else besides just buying a game.
Scott: they were pre-ordering They were doing something weird.
Scott: They were selling back something, and you know what.
Rym: you know what if?
Rym: Everyone who was standing around stayed no matter how long the way it was then they have no incentive.
Scott: Well some people were leaving.
Scott: the thing is is that the way they keep a lot of The the customers from leaving is they only have one guy at the register and everyone else is a salesman who tries to keep you from leaving.
Scott: But anyway Just bothers me when someone could do something that would benefit them and others very easily By using computers and things and they just don't do it.
Rym: See I I don't think it really would benefit them that much monetarily.
Scott: I think it would benefit them a whole lot because if you're go online And you know for sure that this minute they get that game stop down the road has what you want You'll go over there and grab it and you'll start doing that instead of going to the EV.
Scott: well I guess they're the same company now, but you'll you know as opposed to some other store You're sure that the game stop has it and you go online And but you just went back to the game.
Rym: same game stop.
Rym: that didn't have it before.
Scott: I had already pre-ordered the game.
Scott: Oh, oh, oh, but that's that's not the point.
Scott: Yeah, whatever the point thing about this right now.
Scott: I'm not really super loyal to any game store.
Scott: I go wherever I is convenient right, but if GameStop implemented something like that or EB Influented something like that, and I'm kind of anti-eb right now I would just go there exclusively because I could always be sure that it's not gonna be a wasted trip all right.
Rym: So what's this I hear about?
Scott: the Marines got a new weapon so they got this weapon in Iraq, and it's a thermal barrack in nature.
Scott: Apparently it's a shoulder-mounted sort of rocket thing with a warhead shoulder-mounted assault weapon right Is described as it as ne novel explosives?
Scott: Aha, it's a thermal barrack chemical thing which I don't know enough about because I'm not sciency enough.
Scott: But it ignites the air and then produces a shockwave of unparalleled destructive power Unparalleled.
Scott: and they see some pictures here.
Scott: They shoot this rocket at this brick square building right and The rocket goes into the building it blows up All right, and the explosion is kind of big and knocked the roof off right, but then there's this shockwave and What's left from four solid brick walls with a window in a doorway is?
Scott: Just a pile of bricks One rocket shoulder-mounted.
Rym: Well.
Rym: You know that's what you get when you spend Orders of magnitude more money than every other nation in the world combined.
Scott: on your military Yeah, but usually you know military stuff is pretty crappy.
Scott: This is pretty good.
Rym: Uh Don't you remember site?
Rym: Yet say and all those things it don't site was the prototype now.
Rym: It's called something else.
Scott: It's called something warrior something It's just all.
Scott: all site is is like it's a gun and a whole computer wearable computer combat suit thing.
Scott: Yeah, this is just a badass rocket.
Scott: That's really useful because you can frickin you know if there's a building Let's say there's a bunch of guys in a building shooting out the windows at you.
Scott: You shoot one of these things and they're building falls down.
Rym: Yeah, but we're the u.s..
Scott: We just send an airstrike or something Sometimes, but I think they're actually gonna use this.
Scott: they are actually using it right now in Iraq all the time apparently Uh-huh like they just got it shipped in and now they're using it.
Rym: Yeah, cuz uh the thing we need to be doing right now is destroying more buildings over there You know winning the hearts and minds of the population.
Scott: It's a cool weapon despite the bad uses.
Rym: yeah, yeah, I know I can't deny it because I got to say whenever I see a new fighter jet I always go It looks cool, and it's fast.
Rym: No you don't.
Rym: I live next to friggin Selfridge Air National Guard base for most of my childhood and The first time an f-16 flew over it was awesome the seven thousandth time.
Scott: I wanted to throw a baseball at it Yeah, but but I didn't live next to an Air Force Base.
Scott: And when I go to a sporting event and they have the flyover at the International Anthem is wicked cool every now And then they'd like break windows because they'd release the afterburner or something over a neighborhood geniuses.
Scott: Yeah, at least it's less damaged than a thermobaric rocket.
Scott: Haha.
Rym: So uh Mario Amazon Amazon is doing something kind of cool.
Rym: I mean Amazon generally is kind of on top of this whole internet business thing.
Scott: yeah considering how profitable they are you know normally You know you think that someone big and profitable like Amazon kind of evil.
Scott: no they're kind of normal.
Scott: I'm neutral on Amazon.
Scott: I buy stuff from them when it's good.
Rym: Yeah, well now they're trying to implement tagging.
Scott: Alright, so now it'll be that much easier to find stuff.
Rym: Yeah, and it's just a prototype System right now.
Rym: It's kind of a beta and they're letting about half their users see the tags Just so they can experiment and screw around with them.
Rym: I have no idea what the criteria are.
Rym: so uh if you have an Amazon account, and you log in you might see these tags And they're changing all the time, and they're not sure what they're gonna do with it yet.
Scott: hmm.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: I'd go around Amazon tag and some stuff.
Scott: You know people can come up with tags to be like Maybe kind of replace the the semi not so useful wish list thing you know.
Scott: yeah You set up some tags like these are the cool Somethings, and then you can have a page that you know for the tag that lists all those things and then share it with people.
Rym: Maybe this will be a prime opportunity for us to try to push our flimflam tag.
Scott: flimflam tag is a good idea.
Scott: I just I See people marking things as flimflam that aren't is the only problem.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing you could do about it.
Rym: I gotta try we gotta try.
Rym: plus one of the cool things is a lot of non geeks use Amazon and they'll see tags and Amazon will probably explain tags in a way that they'll understand and It'll make tagging hopefully a more Accepted technology, maybe people start finding the delicious.
Scott: a lot of people are using the tags on Flickr and stuff And they know what they're doing.
Rym: Yeah, those are generally more geeky people Generally, but you'd be surprised.
Rym: I think Amazon could be the tipping point.
Scott: might be You know, but I don't think that a lot of people are gonna go through the effort of tagging things And you know they're not gonna get the full power out of the tagging.
Scott: They're gonna kind of.
Rym: oh We could talk about our things of the day.
Scott: Yes, I knew you forgot something.
Scott: look at you not holding out you druggy.
Rym: my thing of the day.
Rym: I ran into a Picture that someone made and what they had done is they took every single Playboy centerfold for like a decade and they mathematically averaged all the images and the resulting image is Kind of neat looking.
Rym: that's all I got.
Scott: It just looks like this fleshy blob.
Rym: Yeah, the fun of the one thing I noticed is that you can very clearly see in this amalgam image some thighs.
Rym: It looks like generally the women are always standing in the same position in the picture.
Scott: Yeah, you know what else you can see.
Scott: you can kind of see this kind of little shadow of cleavage.
Scott: Yeah I wonder what uh this blob of hair.
Rym: I wonder what photographic elements the Playboy photographers were focusing on when they decided to set these centerfolds up.
Scott: All right, so my thing of the day Oh my god.
Scott: when I found this it was on.
Scott: it was on the anime news network.
Scott: I was just like rolling around the office practically Aha, so, you know the Ozumanga dial guy.
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: Azuma?
Scott: Yeah, his last name's Ozuma or his first name cuz it's Japan and they say the names backwards, right?
Scott: So he makes the Ozumanga dial which is pretty hilarious and he also makes the yotsuba which is his current Awesome, and it's it's equal if not more awesome.
Scott: But he's.
Scott: there's a site with I think it's by him or by a crazy fan.
Scott: It's a Japanese site so I can't read it and I can't know.
Scott: but it's got a bunch of flash Animations that are all with his stuff and one of them was the opener to Ozumanga dial.
Scott: but he replaced all the characters with yotsuba characters and yotsuba things and it's The hilarious if you know what those things are.
Rym: And if you don't know what those things are Find out.
Scott: Yeah, or else you suck.
Rym: I imagine we'll talk about them on one of our anime podcasts.
Scott: We definitely should.
Scott: there's a manga and an anime of Ozumanga dial and there's just a manga of yotsuba But it's coming out really quick and I imagine there will be an anime about it eventually.
Scott: Maybe one day.
Scott: I hope there is.
Rym: So Mario Kart.
Rym: Oh my god video game day.
Rym: Mario Kart is fantastic.
Scott: You know, I Before I played this Mario Kart, you know GBA Mario Kart was was the best because he unlike the other Mario karts Which are pretty much as random the computer cheats and items mean everything.
Scott: The the Game Boy one was actually racing was the most important.
Scott: if you raced Well, it didn't matter what items came up.
Scott: you won, right the ds1 It's.
Scott: they subtracted that a little bit But they fixed it because the items don't do as much damage.
Scott: you get hit by a shell you recover a lot quicker You know, so you can't avoid the shells anymore, but you recover and It's really good.
Scott: It's better than the GameCube one or the n64 one or anything.
Rym: Oh my god See I've got really no reference because the last one I played was for the Super Nintendo and I had no interest in the franchise for a long time and This game is awesome.
Rym: I really I can't deny it.
Rym: Yeah, it's Well, it's a Mario Kart game.
Rym: So, you know you pick a you pick a character you pick a car and then you race and you throw things at each other Mm-hmm.
Scott: They got a lot of good track selection.
Scott: So my good tracks from the Game Boy one are in there.
Scott: You know, they the new tracks are really high quality, especially the the Waluigi pinball.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, freaking speed tube.
Scott: What are?
Scott: the tracks are really good.
Rym: I like Delfino Plaza myself.
Rym: A long drift around that fountain.
Scott: the new rainbow road is alright, but it's not.
Scott: it's easier than previous rainbow roads But it's not easier than previous rainbow roads if you want to really turn up the speed Which it's a good balance.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: The main thing about this game is that one because it's on the DS.
Rym: It's wireless.
Rym: So you can just play with eight people in one room and all race.
Scott: you could do that for people with the Game Boy, but It was terrible to sit near each other.
Scott: with the cables.
Rym: you sit near you mean hunch over each other.
Scott: Those cables were like four feet and you can play with eight people on the GameCube.
Scott: But you needed two GameCubes and two TVs and two land adapters and a wire.
Rym: No one has that.
Rym: people have it but not no one no one in the world.
Scott: There are people but not many.
Rym: Now the main thing about it is that this is not just Mario Kart.
Rym: This is kind of the launch of the Nintendo DS Wi-Fi.
Scott: Well, there was also Tony Hawk skater land Oh SK the number eight Erland is also using the Wi-Fi.
Rym: Yeah, cuz that's gonna be a fantastic game.
Scott: It's oh my god It's out now, but and kids are playing it, but not me Don't catch me with that.
Scott: Now.
Rym: We actually got to play some of the online and It's perfect.
Rym: There's no lag.
Rym: It just works.
Scott: It just works.
Scott: The only thing is you can't drag items around other than that.
Scott: Oh and you can only play with four players.
Scott: Yeah, but other than that, it's flawless.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You can play with anyone you've ever played with locally.
Rym: It saves a little key a little friend code and you can always play with those people anywhere As long as they're online.
Rym: and you're online.
Scott: you can always type in friend codes to people that you know You talk to.
Rym: yep, and our friend codes will be in our forum.
Scott: Yep, or somewhere else maybe in the comments probably everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, so if you got the Mario Kart, you know put up your friend codes and you know We'll give you ours.
Rym: you give us your will lay down some blue sparks bitches.
Rym: There is a problem though the Wi-Fi online play and we're really not sure at this point What is wrong, but it is well known that it's not currently working.
Rym: So well, if you actually find someone and connect to them is fantastic, but half the time it just craps out before it connects to anyone.
Scott: Yeah, well you see before it was the game was released.
Scott: today People who had preview editions of the game were playing and they only reported Problems when they had a bunch of people in the same room on one access point Which is what they had because they were going to Nintendo and doing this, you know with a whole bunch of press people.
Scott: but The problem if you go to the Nintendo Wi-Fi site today, it says there's a message that Mario Kart has like intermittent issues.
Rym: so We don't know.
Scott: yeah so what happens is if you try to play without friend codes if you try to just play worldwide or regional or Rival mode you sit there waiting for quite a while for anyone to join and usually no one joins and You don't find any opponents.
Scott: I imagine that'll be fixed pretty soon should be fixed soon, but if you find opponents Most of the time what happens.
Scott: is you get like it just cancels out and you get this error Instead of starting to play the game like error eight.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: I am error.
Scott: Should I talk to Riverman?
Scott: Bagu knows the way Bagu lives in the woods.
Scott: Does he play Mario Kart because I could play with him even though he's in the middle of the woods?
Rym: if he's got a wireless Access point I should log into high space and see who has some friend code.
Scott: What's Bagu's friend code?
Scott: Dangerous Yeah, but the online play is great, oh, there's a few tracks missing from online play, but whatever.
Rym: yeah Yeah This game is probably the turning point as not really the turning point of the DS being awesome But the turning point as in I'm not going to play any system But my DS for probably the next month or two.
Scott: Yeah, I'm Stupid.
Scott: trauma center is the only DS game I got that haven't beat.
Scott: cuz I'm on a really hard mission surgery.
Scott: Yeah but Mario Kart basically killed any chances of that being fixed.
Scott: cuz now I've got to get a gold and An S super rank and every single Grand Prix on every single CC rating.
Rym: I'm very happy that just before it came out.
Rym: I finally beat, Castlevania.
Rym: Yeah got it out of my system.
Rym: Dracula's dead again.
Scott: Why doesn't he just stay dead?
Rym: Honestly, it wasn't really Dracula at the end.
Rym: Oh The end is dumb, but it's dumb in the way that all modern Castlevania game endings are dumb.
Scott: All right, as long as it was fun to play.
Scott: who cares with the ending?
Scott: I haven't been good game endings in like forever and the last boss is kind of a challenge.
Scott: That's always good because I don't think the last boss and Mario Kart's gonna be a challenge.
Rym: Oh you mean uh me the internet.
Rym: Oh You know what the boss and Mario Kart is.
Rym: the one Japanese kid who got the game the day it came out has been playing non-stop ever since with an IV.
Scott: You know if I play against that kid, I'm just gonna be like shit my pants Great.
Scott: Hopefully I'll get like 20 bike shells and I'll have a chance of winning.
Rym: We done about Mario Kart, oh, yeah, I think we got it out of our system till we play some more.
Rym: but uh if you haven't gotten a DS yet and You're on the fence It's done.
Rym: It is now the time to buy one.
Scott: Yeah, you really can't.
Scott: I don't see any other better way to spend video game money.
Rym: I mean the DS.
Rym: the DS stands alone as a primary console.
Rym: at this point You could have just a DS and be just fine.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the other consoles are kind of dwindling and even though the Xbox 360 is coming next week or this week or whenever It's mostly sports games, so unless you're a sports game nut just get DS.
Scott: Yeah Yeah.
Scott: So the other game that we we rediscover.
Scott: well, I knew about this game for a long time, but I never really got into it.
Scott: Yeah, and we rediscovered it during our emulator.
Scott: It's called mule m?
Scott: u le with dots in between.
Rym: Yeah, it stands for multiple use labor element equipment equipment.
Rym: I thought it was element.
Scott: No equipment Basically, we realized.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't realize it before it.
Scott: It's a German board game for a Computer.
Rym: it's kind of an old-school German board game.
Rym: in that it's a good solid game But there is kind of a lot of randomness.
Scott: There's a little bit too much randomness, and I'm trying to figure out a way to design to redesign the game.
Scott: We're a little less randomness, but it's hard because the game itself is solid.
Rym: It's actually really cool.
Rym: You're uh well, there's a plot and a story, but forget all that.
Scott: so basically you're four dudes.
Rym: there's four dudes, and you're one of them and You get plots of land that you develop and on those plots of land you can produce one of a number of commodities and some Commodities are useful for different things.
Rym: one commodity is only useful for selling to make money And at the end of the game wherever the highest net worth wins.
Scott: yep There's some things about the game that are kind of tricky But it's because of the nature of it being a really really really old game.
Rym: Yeah Like getting your plots of land there this box goes to each plot of land and whoever hits their button first gets that plot of Land, but it goes real fast, and it's pretty much a crapshoot.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can practice a lot and try to get the really good plots of land adjacent to each other for max bonuses.
Rym: but Yeah, it kind of detracts from the German board game this of it not any more than the random random-ass events like oh Pirates came and stole everything or a meteor just destroyed one of your plots of land or oh a monster came and ate all your Food.
Rym: ah that stupid monster.
Scott: Yeah, the monster is pretty scary.
Scott: But you know German board games have things like that, but at least when they're in a German board game.
Scott: Technically they're.
Scott: they're like.
Scott: you know they're coming.
Scott: it's like Kind of like in settlers the robber can happen But you know
Rym: there is a way to protect yourself from the Rob
Scott: and you know about the robber and you can Predict him and prevent him and there is
Rym: no way to predict prepare or deal with any disaster in mule.
Scott: yeah They're just completely random like oh no way makes it more like a simulation of real-life Economics.
Rym: you get randomly fucked by the world and there's nothing you can do about it.
Scott: It's true however It's a little more random than real life.
Scott: I mean you pretty much win at gambling every day.
Scott: Yeah, how do you win at gambling every single time because that's a game mechanic?
Rym: Yeah to reward you for taking your turn quicker.
Scott: It is that's good But it seems like you know you can't get over.
Rym: see the main.
Rym: I mean the main part of the game is making commodities, and you make them one of the different commodities And then you bid and the bidding is kind of cool.
Rym: you say if you're a buyer or a seller for each commodity and then all the buyers stand at the bottom and all the sellers stand at the top of the screen and Then you it says go and you move your little guy And you stop at whatever point you decide it would be valid.
Rym: you would want to buy or sell and whenever two of these lines Intersect the transaction occurs,
Scott: so if I'm a buyer, and I'm willing to pay $50 per unit of Energy and Rym is willing to see is trying to sell his energy You know let's say he walks down a bit, and he stops at like $100 and I stop at $50.
Scott: He's standing there looking at each other and nothing happens.
Scott: Then someone caves in and walks over and touches the other guy and say Rym walks down and touches my line And he'll sell me one unit of whatever 50 bucks.
Rym: Or there's always the hilarity of say I've got the only energy left in the game And there's none left in like the store because there's a store, but sometimes it runs out of stuff.
Rym: yeah, because the store is only filled by the players and Everyone else needs energy, and they're trying to bid on it.
Rym: But I won't sell it and the price just keeps going up.
Scott: And then if you have a partner who's down low on the buying side He just keeps walking up and up and up and that forces other players who want it more to keep going up and up And up even if he doesn't really want it.
Scott: Yeah, you can definitely play apples and oranges and collude with people And then at the last second when You know someone when the time is about to run out on the auction you walk down.
Scott: the other guy walks up.
Scott: Oh, you sold him one energy for like $2,000.
Rym: The biggest problem we had with the game was that we weren't sure how to win at first.
Rym: We weren't sure how many points anything was worth.
Scott: We're still not really sure how many points things are worth.
Rym: Oh, I am now I finally figured it out.
Scott: You figured out exactly?
Rym: Most.
Rym: the only thing I haven't figured out exactly is land.
Rym: But it looks like land is just a base price plus the price of any mules you've put on it Plus the price of any equipment you've put on mules on it.
Rym: Yeah, that's what it looks like.
Rym: Okay, and goods are just the.
Rym: you get a one point for each good times the value of that good at the end of the game.
Scott: How do you know what the value of the good is?
Rym: Whatever it sells for at the end of the game in the store in the store, or if it sells normally Whatever the price ends up at.
Scott: Yeah, all right, all right, that's okay.
Rym: But so by selling a good you'll drive the price down so that other people have to sell to get something from it.
Scott: Yeah But the idea is that you wanna you only want to sell a good if the price now is Higher than what it will be at the end of the game.
Rym: Yeah, because there's no inherent value in having a good or having a money.
Rym: You just want to have as much of everything as you can at the end.
Scott: I get it now.
Scott: It's that's a lot of you because I was wondering it's like how much is this good gonna be worth at the end of?
Rym: Yeah, it's not nearly as complicated as we were making it out to be.
Scott: Yeah, it's like cuz I'd have like extra Smith or and I'd be like it would the price would be $50.
Scott: I'd be like should I sell it for 50 or?
Scott: Will it be worth more than 50 at the end of the game?
Scott: meaning selling it is dumb because you get one point for $1 Right, so I just you couldn't.
Scott: I couldn't make a decision because they didn't know how the game worked.
Scott: But now that we kind of know how it works.
Scott: It's a lot better.
Rym: Yep, and if it were the bag we had Mario Kart, we'd probably play the game again.
Scott: Yeah, we're probably play it again sometime.
Scott: Anyway, if we can get maybe some four USB thingies we can do a little four score action.
Rym: Yeah, I'd like to play with humans instead of computers.
Scott: Yeah The thing is this game has been you know is real popular back in the day and it still has like the 80s Following but it hasn't been remade in a long long time.
Rym: We're gonna try to remake it at least at the very least.
Scott: I'm gonna redesign it in a more German style fashion Without trying to destroy what makes the game great.
Rym: See the game also has one other aspect that you can choose to ignore if you want But there's.
Rym: each individual player has their value, but the colony as a whole as a value, too.
Rym: And There are kind of two games here.
Rym: You want to be better than every other player?
Rym: But at the same time you want the colony as a whole to survive and it's not really such a big thing in the game.
Rym: It talks about it like it'll say.
Rym: Oh the colony failed and you all lose.
Scott: It's just some text at the bottom of the screen that has no effect on anything.
Rym: I think it should be if we remake it something more prominent like the colony can fail and then you all lose And I don't know cuz.
Rym: then it's more of a you know tragedy of the commons prisoner's dilemma Getting in commodity if you could.
Scott: what would be good is if you set some sort of System where if the players don't Collectively do good enough So if one guy just bandits everyone else and the colony as a whole doesn't do well enough That it ends up just hurting people in the game.
Scott: Well, I have to play around with it, yeah, like imagine if you're you're playing Kind of like that Lord of the Rings game, even though I don't like that.
Scott: I love that game where you know, it's like you have to put the tokens in to help everyone, you know.
Scott: But if you don't put the tokens in you might do better than everyone else, but Sauron moves closer Yeah, and it's kind of scary.
Scott: Something like that where if not everyone contributes and makes enough
Rym: stuff
Scott: Then you know all the Smith or sucks
Rym: kind of like in a Chrononauts where if everyone was real neglectful and too many cards were faced down The world ended and the game was over and you all lost.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good way to put it.
Scott: That's a lot better mechanic than just at the end of the game.
Scott: There's some text that means nothing.
Rym: Yeah, it's just flavor Because the game was designed to be one of those edutainment games to teach children about supply and demand.
Scott: Yep It was actually designed by this Guy who turned into a woman and there's like a whole story behind it and how she's dead.
Rym: Yeah, the developers of this game have kind of a cult following.
Rym: It's cool and creepy at the same time.
Scott: Yeah, and there's a version for the Atari a version for the Commodore a version for the NES.
Rym: We found this DOS version.
Scott: that was a remake.
Scott: That was a clone remake.
Rym: Yes a remake, but it's identical.
Scott: Yeah Well, it's somewhat identity.
Rym: The only difference is the graphics.
Rym: I looked yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty good.
Scott: But didn't they change the themes like under the water?
Rym: no, no that that was an xcom.
Rym: XCOM 2 was underwater.
Rym: XCOM 1 was on the land damn underwater.
Rym: Nothing to do with mule underwater aliens.
Scott: Don't like those underwater aliens.
Rym: I didn't like XCOM 2.
Rym: Yeah It was the same game only crappier and with worse graphics.
Scott: You know I like XCOM just so bad at it and it's so hard for me to do it for some reason that I don't play It's.
Rym: not only was XCOM one of my favorite games ever, but XCOM was the first game I ever pirated.
Rym: I didn't even know I pirated it.
Rym: Someone just gave me these discs and then there was a game on it.
Scott: I. the first X time I ever played was the demo of XCOM apocalypse.
Scott: Oh god, it was okay.
Scott: But the the alien invasion one is obviously the best everyone knows.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it's an incredibly difficult game.
Scott: Don't make no bones about it, but you know what honestly it's not as good as Mario Kart.
Rym: Oh Mario Kart I really want to play it right now.
Rym: I think I will cuz there's a chance that I'll run into some crazy crazy crazy kid from Japan Who's just good at it and it'll beat me.
Scott: Maybe you'll have a really awesome emblem.
Scott: That's just scary.
Rym: Yeah, you can't.
Rym: I mean, you know Nintendo you can't talk in the game.
Rym: There's almost no way to convey obscenities to other players except You can have a name and you know, they're going to be people named various things.
Rym: Aha hockey jockey, man And you can actually draw a picture that will be on your car while you race.
Scott: It's also floating above your head And it has the players name and a little thumbnail of what their picture is so you can know.
Scott: if you learn someone's picture You can see where they are on the track.
Rym: Yeah, like I ran the first guy ever raced online.
Rym: He had a little Yoshi egg and it had a little skull on it.
Scott: That's pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah We also found this program you can use to turn graphics and like make good icons.
Scott: Well, it's a website and you upload a JPEG or a gift to the website and it puts on the screen.
Scott: You know basically they.
Scott: it resizes and figures out the image into the same resolution as the emblem And then it's up to you to copy the emblem off the screen and onto your DS.
Scott: You can just do that in the gimp if you want you could but this website does it really well.
Scott: Yeah, it's not just a simple resize.
Scott: It's still.
Rym: it's easier than making a spray for the old one based Natural selection counter-strike half-life.
Scott: Yeah, you know, what's actually surprising is steam now is really easy to make the sprays.
Scott: Yeah added a whole spray thing.
Rym: See I never got to see that because I switched to Linux and Try as I might.
Rym: Steam does not work in wine.
Scott: Yeah, I I got to see it because I use steam and half-life 2 and I played it and even though I use Linux 99% of the time now, but I didn't use it because it didn't make a spray for it.
Rym: So I take that back.
Rym: steam works just fine.
Rym: The games in steam don't work.
Scott: No, it's true.
Scott: It's true Steam is great.
Rym: Steam is just some windows and they open up.
Rym: I mean, yeah, it's not hard to make that work.
Scott: It actually changed steam recently.
Scott: I don't like it as much now, but what are you gonna do?
Rym: If I get sick of Mario Kart, I might boot into Windows so I can play some natural selection.
Scott: I played natural selection once the other day.
Scott: It was pretty good.
Rym: I got to say natural selection is probably my favorite.
Rym: I guess new era or like this current era of FPS is online.
Scott: yeah, I'm definitely all out of like, you know, my list of things to buy gizmos and whatnot a New computers way at the bottom.
Scott: But one day I'm probably gonna buy like an AMD 64 type machine awesome, and I'm either gonna buy like a wicked gaming computer and then Use my current computer as something awesome or I'll buy a wicked non gaming computer to make that my primary PC and then I'll turn my computer into a gaming computer that can be all windows all the time or
Rym: VMware.
Scott: VMware would be good if it was free.
Scott: Well kind of isn't a new thing.
Rym: But yeah, we still have to see how that new thing pans out.
Scott: It panned out pretty good.
Scott: I just don't know how useful it would be for playing steam.
Rym: I think it will be eventually but right now at least our computers are not fast enough to do that as well as we would like to.
Rym: Yeah, see I'm still running a Thunderbird gigahertz with a gig of RAM and Yeah, it's real old slow.
Rym: Yeah, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds dot be burner.
Scott: comm.
Scott: slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: also, please visit our website at www.front row crew comm for the latest updates and forum discussion.
Scott: and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.