Scott: It's Thursday November 3rd, and this is keep nights with Rym and Scott.
Scott: All right Let's do this.
Rym: So I couldn't get home from work today.
Scott: Yeah, and again my phone sucks at telling me when I have voicemail.
Rym: So I'm at work and I figure I'm gonna leave around you like 530 cuz I got there late.
Rym: if you're I'll leave late.
Rym: And then they announce something over the PA system Which is a big deal because when they use the PA system usually means like there's been a chemical leak or or Something like.
Scott: we have a PA system But the work doesn't use it.
Scott: only the building can use it and it's usually like there is to fire drill.
Rym: But now I They announce that I-84 the way I go home is Blocked due to an accident.
Scott: it gets blocked all the time like when it rains.
Rym: Yeah, whenever it rains whenever it snows whenever it's dark out people just get into accidents and block it Which I wouldn't care about except that it's the only way home.
Scott: You can take the side road.
Rym: Oh, there's one side road.
Rym: There are only two roads that go east and west here I-84.
Rym: and there's another crap road with a bunch of stoplights in small towns on it.
Rym: I Took the crap road because the freeway was blocked and it took me two hours to drive six miles.
Scott: I think this just might be only the stretch of 84 between your work in here because when I take 84 Home to Connecticut.
Scott: I never have a problem.
Scott: I freakin fly down that road.
Rym: You're going east and I go west.
Scott: West not so good.
Rym: No West not so good because right at the end of going home.
Scott: You're going east right?
Rym: No coming home I'm going west.
Rym: Oh We live next to the Hudson River.
Rym: I work East of the Hudson River.
Scott: Ah suck.
Rym: Yeah, mr.
Rym: Geography.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah But remember the only Hudson River crossing anywhere around here Newberg beacon bridge right there Hudson, whatever bridge.
Rym: Yeah, that's like 20.
Scott: and then if he goes south Tappan Zee bridge.
Rym: Yeah, so that's farther say many miles That's near New Jersey.
Rym: So all the traffic from all the commuters funnels into the one way.
Rym: I go home Awesome.
Scott: Yeah Just go the other way home.
Rym: There is no other way home.
Scott: the side road with the small towns.
Rym: see whenever I 84 blocks all the traffic all the people get off I84 and get on that road.
Scott: So why don't you go like this really roundabout way?
Rym: Because even though you'll be really I can't get to the roundabout way.
Rym: You realize there aren't many roads Around.
Scott: couldn't you go like way north and then take 90?
Rym: All right.
Rym: What do I get on to?
Rym: go way north?
Scott: That road near IBM.
Rym: Oh that little short road that is also full of traffic from people avoiding I 84 Yeah.
Rym: So I hate people and I think if you ever get in a car accident They just take your license away or something see.
Scott: while I like I don't like Being far away from work and having to commute.
Scott: at least I'm gonna deal with shit like that.
Rym: No, no, you just get on the train and it always gets there.
Scott: Well, you know, you never know when it might be canceled or something.
Rym: They almost never cancel Metro north.
Scott: Yeah, but it could happen.
Rym: last year during that crazy blizzard They were delayed like 10 minutes.
Rym: That was it.
Scott: That's about right.
Rym: So It was a slow news day real slow.
Scott: I mean half the news is just Yesterday's news.
Rym: Yeah again.
Rym: Oh news flash news flash.
Scott: Libby pleaded, uh, not guilty, you know Whether you did it or not.
Scott: Let's say you did it right when you got those kind of charges.
Scott: Yeah You don't say guilty because you're gonna die like the next day when they kill you.
Scott: So you're freaking say not guilty no matter what if only to delay imminent death and prison and in prison.
Scott: So that's not a surprise at all.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: He did waive his right to a speedy trial Which means he wants to drag this out Like I just said yeah.
Scott: Yeah, if you're guilty and you know You're gonna be found guilty and there's this pile of evidence that Fitzgerald found you want to delay it as long as possible.
Rym: So, uh, you know how long they're delaying it a year the uh next hearing which just another hearing.
Rym: This isn't even the trial yet February 3rd, that's not too far away.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, but that's not think about how much time was between when OJ was driving his Ford Bronco and when OJ was actually in court.
Rym: You know, I don't even remember I was in middle school any month there many months.
Rym: I just remember that when the trial ended in middle school, they showed it on all the TVs in the school.
Scott: They didn't show it but someone ran around the building.
Rym: So they showed it and it was not guilty.
Rym: and I remember going son of a.
Scott: but then half my class jumped up and cheered like whoa, I Didn't even you know it had gone on so long Like I thought he did it.
Scott: I thought he might have not done it that I was pretty sure he did it and then I just didn't care by the time It was over.
Scott: So when they said not guilty, I was just like oh I just remember it.
Rym: at the height of the stupid popularity of this thing I remember going to the Gibraltar Trade Center, which is like a giant flea market in Michigan where I used to live.
Scott: Okay, you see the Trade Center.
Scott: I'm like an office building.
Rym: No, no, like imagine a flea market bigger than RIT's entire campus.
Rym: All right All right in a big building.
Rym: It's a big warehouse for like.
Scott: I know those kind of things.
Rym: Yeah, they have in Florida and back then pogs were real big.
Scott: I went to a flea market in Florida when pogs are real big.
Scott: I got them pogs.
Scott: I should get them.
Scott: They're fun.
Rym: Not only were there OJ Simpson pogs.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: There was one guy who sold nothing but OJ Simpson's pogs.
Rym: Oh my god, and he was doing brisk business.
Rym: He had a half of them that were like the juice is loose or innocent and the other half were like guilty or he's gonna Fry and they were selling in equal portions.
Rym: Yes, he was selling slammers.
Rym: He was selling the regular land.
Scott: See that was the problem with pogs is like.
Scott: they had the official pog brand pogs and they were high Quality like and then they had the cheap-ass third-party knockoff pogs everywhere and wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute High quality.
Rym: you realize that the game of pogs is probably the stupidest game in the world second only to Conker's.
Rym: But I think even Conker's has.
Rym: I don't know Conker's but Conker's is a game they play in Britain when they were kids when people were kids.
Rym: I don't think anyone plays anymore.
Rym: Well, you take like a chestnut and you tie a string to it and you take turns hitting your chestnut against other people's chestnuts Until when your chestnut breaks you're out of it.
Rym: And then the last standing chestnut wins.
Scott: All right, Tiddlywinks is better than that.
Rym: I kind of like Conker's Pogs is at least.
Scott: It's not a game of strategy or skill or smartness, but it is.
Scott: it's like a manual dexterity game.
Scott: You got to throw this thing Really hard and really accurately straight down to the ground And you have to hit a target that's the same size as the thing you throw.
Scott: But even if you weren't playing it for the I Really never actually played the game.
Scott: that much, you know, I never played it ever.
Scott: I only played it once in like middle school at lunch when I really did them.
Rym: They banned him from my school right away because some kid like threw one and it hit some kid in the face whatever, but I remember because I Would always they were basically I was collecting them when I was into him.
Scott: I didn't collect that many like I remember.
Scott: I only bought him like maybe three times ever.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I was a little impressionable kid and Cuz there was really nothing else to collect at that time.
Scott: It was like I was like in between things, you know It's like magic was getting kind of.
Scott: You know and you know comic books were already done.
Scott: the complex store in the mall went out of business.
Rym: See back then I had D&D and that was all I needed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway Pogs that that's not news.
Scott: Yeah, Pogs is definitely not new.
Rym: I'll bet they come back someday.
Scott: Dude, why don't we bring back Pogs and make a business out of it and then make an internet pog thing.
Scott: Oh my god I'm sure there's an internet pog thing.
Rym: I'm sure there is.
Rym: All right, I'll bet someone made an online version of Pogs.
Scott: All right, that was in flash.
Scott: Oh my god, that'd just be so dumb.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyway, what else is news?
Rym: Uh, Congress got rid of that act that would have let us take unlimited amounts of money from Congressmen to uh do political advertising on our little cast here.
Scott: That's not what I thought the law said.
Rym: What do you think the law said?
Scott: I think the law said that we could say whatever we wanted on blogs about the FCC interfering.
Rym: Oh, yeah No, what the law said was that campaign finance laws don't apply to the earth do should apply should not apply to the internet.
Rym: Currently they do.
Rym: Okay, the law said oh they won't which would mean that anyone who was running for an office could spend infinite money on the internet And they wouldn't even have to say they were spending that money or say who they were given that money to.
Scott: Right now candidates can spend infinite internet money.
Rym: No right now.
Rym: They cannot.
Rym: the law was gonna make it so that they can.
Scott: oh So they can't.
Rym: they can't okay, so That's it.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I don't want them to spend any money.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: That's all the law, dude People are really making a big deal on what because it seemed like some.
Scott: it was described differently.
Scott: I think you're missing some.
Rym: no No Because you got the slash dot summary and I read the actual law.
Rym: It also had a thing about oil drilling in it and all this other crap.
Scott: Well, you know that crap.
Scott: whatever It's a Christmas tree law.
Scott: There's a bunch of ornaments all over it.
Scott: You have nothing to do with the trunk or the little pine needles.
Scott: In fact, usually all the pine needles fall off.
Scott: That's why it's a Christmas.
Rym: Yeah, all the bill really was is to Let make it so.
Rym: the internet was just free grain completely when it came to political speech, but that also included No more finance laws.
Rym: So you could just pay a bunch of bloggers a whole bunch of money to shill you and not have to account for that.
Rym: But yet you still have to account for if you bought a TV ad.
Scott: huh, but it seems like a lot of people are saying this is they wanted the law to go through because it would allow bloggers to Do something that they can't do currently.
Rym: What can't we do currently?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It seemed like they said what what?
Rym: What can't we do?
Scott: it said that like, you know now we could if the law passed We would have been free to to accept a lot of money.
Rym: We can be as political as we want right now.
Scott: Oh So now we can accept money for our politics.
Rym: No, we can't accept.
Rym: Well we can but it has to be disclosed.
Rym: It's like if someone buys a political ad on TV, they have to disclose.
Rym: I spent this much on the ad blah blah blah.
Scott: Oh, so this would have a lot.
Scott: So we wanted the bill to pass so we could make out like bandits.
Rym: Yeah, basically, ah isn't nearly the free speech issue that a lot of people on slashdot and Fark were making it out to be and People in the blogosphere just busting a nut over this?
Rym: nothing that happened?
Scott: Maybe I'll go read it more in depth to see if we're a hundred percent accurate because that's basically Fleecing with a lot of the things I read.
Rym: a lot of people are not that I read them very and a lot of people Are real alarmist about things.
Scott: Hey, so, um Brown the FEMA guy, right?
Scott: Mike Brown that genius the genius of FEMA.
Scott: So, um, they got his emails.
Scott: He sent during the hurricane Great any gems in there all of them.
Rym: All right, let's uh here.
Rym: All right.
Scott: All right These these can be summed up in one word Hilarious.
Rym: is he our new Jack Thompson?
Scott: No, he's not evil or anything.
Scott: He's just dumb.
Rym: Jack Thompson's not evil.
Rym: He's just crazy All right.
Scott: So anyway here and One email sent.
Scott: this is from CBS News, but uh-huh and one email sent on August 29th This Katrina was pummeling the Gulf.
Scott: a FEMA public affairs Official Tells Brown the outfit he wore on a television appearance looked fabulous to which Brown replies.
Scott: I got it Nordstrom's.
Scott: then he adds.
Scott: Are you proud of me?
Scott: Can I quit now?
Scott: Can I go home?
Scott: What that was Eve?
Scott: This is the email he was sending when he was supposed to be dealing with a disaster.
Rym: Was he trying to be funny or is he just that Tom?
Scott: Mm-hmm CBS News correspondent Bob or reports that an hour later as thousands of evacuees huddled in the Superdome shelter of last resort Brown fired off another email.
Scott: The email said if you look at my lovely FEMA attire, you'll really vomit.
Rym: I am a fashion god Alright, so we're two for two on fashion and over two on saving poor people from a hurricane.
Scott: I'm here's the girl.
Scott: Here's a good one.
Scott: This is the last one I'll do.
Scott: After the levees failed the situation grew even more desperate.
Scott: FEMA's point man in New Orleans pleaded for Brown to send more help.
Scott: That this is what the guy said to Brown, you know, the situation is past critical.
Scott: Estimates are many will die within hours.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah, just four minutes later Brown wrote back.
Scott: Thanks for the update.
Scott: anything specific.
Scott: I need to do or tweak.
Rym: Wow This guy is uh, I don't even know what to say.
Scott: the following day Brown wrote to a fellow FEMA employee.
Scott: I feel like I'm getting the shit beat out of me.
Scott: that that that.
Rym: So, uh, if we learn anything from this, it's that in the event of an actual Emergency the federal government isn't gonna be anywhere to interfere with us at all.
Scott: good.
Scott: They're incompetent.
Scott: I don't want them anyone near.
Scott: they'll just fuck it up.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So if there's ever some crazy disaster, like I don't know angels attack like Evangelion or something Whatever the government says to do.
Rym: I'll just do the opposite.
Scott: I'll just.
Scott: I won't do the opposite of whatever they say because you know, I'll figure out what to do best.
Rym: Oh, yeah, regardless of what they I wouldn't be sitting in that dome.
Scott: I'll tell you what, yeah, definitely not sitting in the dome.
Rym: So, uh, STI silicon graphics isn't doing so well.
Scott: Well, no kidding because um, their computers are Crazy more powerful versus expensive than anyone needs.
Scott: Yep, and no one needs Irix know and pretty much you can do a bunch of cheap You know supercomputers Linux to do better than what they give you hell depending on I mean from what they used to give you.
Rym: You could buy just one Windows machine to do some of those things now.
Scott: now.
Scott: Yeah They were good back in the day when they were the only machines that could really do the graphic action.
Rym: But yeah, plus they've been real pro open source.
Rym: Yeah, they have been but hasn't helped him Yeah, so I feel bad that a company like that that they kind of cool.
Rym: Okay, there was.
Scott: they're in the same business as Sun.
Scott: only Sun has other Java business stuff.
Scott: So yeah, it doesn't have anything else at all.
Scott: Yeah, though Sun also has its IBM stuff now Yeah, but hopefully we'll be able to get some cheap SDI machines.
Rym: Oh, that'd be awesome.
Scott: Yeah, just nice little good-looking SDI machine.
Rym: Maybe some air on chairs air on chairs.
Rym: Those aren't SDI Yeah, but if they're if they really go down there all the way they sell those to businesses though You can't get them.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I'm a business.
Scott: Yeah So, you know Radio City and every winter they have the Christmas spectacular show the ladies kicking their legs in the air.
Scott: Those are the Rockettes.
Scott: Yeah, they're not.
Scott: they're in the show, but they're not.
Scott: the show doesn't?
Scott: they're not the only thing The show has.
Rym: yeah, cuz I'm just not interested in that at all.
Scott: I don't know why I've seen the show once.
Scott: It's not really the greatest show.
Scott: But anyway, the the musicians.
Scott: Yeah, they went on strike.
Rym: Aha that's this because there's another strike going on in New York right now.
Rym: So that's two strikes.
Scott: Okay, so, um They're using recorded music.
Scott: They're just playing it over the speakers.
Rym: But all the people who bought tickets sir, they're going to watch the show.
Scott: they don't care do they know?
Rym: yeah Are they getting her?
Scott: the musicians are sitting outside the theater during the little strike protest.
Scott: people just walk right into the theater and watch the show.
Scott: Wow Wow That that's it.
Rym: This wasn't canceled like our video game concert was.
Scott: yeah And the last tiny bit of news do it would is Firefox now has 10% market share.
Scott: Yeah, I saw that one in ten computers at the Firefox.
Scott: Well one in ten internet web browsers.
Rym: That's not so bad at all It's not bad.
Scott: Is it the point where you can start giving the finger to nine out of ten people?
Scott: Yeah People were saying that Firefox growth is slowing down.
Scott: well Shows them.
Rym: So my thing of the day It's not anything new.
Rym: In fact, it's very old.
Rym: It's uh, two million or two billion years old.
Rym: It's real old and It's just something that a lot of you probably know about.
Rym: but I didn't know about it.
Rym: I found out about it and it was really cool.
Rym: I read a bunch of stuff.
Rym: All right, but in Gabon which is a country in Africa I never heard of this country.
Scott: there City or an area or something called, Oklahoma Okay.
Rym: Hello and In the 1970s a bunch of scientists there noticed something odd and to cut to the chase because I'm not gonna go on about this Forever there was a naturally existing nuclear reactor there Naturally existing it.
Rym: just it happened when some geological events put uranium 235 and water in such a configuration That a nuclear reactor was formed and it reacted for thousands and thousands of years.
Scott: It says uranium heating up a water.
Scott: The water is cooling the uranium and steam is coming out.
Rym: Actually, what was happening is the uranium was visioning with itself.
Rym: The water was acting.
Rym: there's like the stream went through this uranium.
Rym: So the water was acting as a neutron What you might call it gun, no, no, no, but maybe uranium.
Rym: It facilitated fission, but then when it got too hot where it would like it would have exploded.
Scott: water is cooling it off.
Rym: No with all those water would evaporate away into steam and then there wouldn't be any water there and the reaction would stop and then The water come back in.
Scott: it was just like a little river with a piece of uranium in it.
Rym: Basically it a lot of uranium and it went fall.
Scott: It needs to be a lot Thousands of years if you got that much uranium.
Rym: the half-life is pretty long You know, and it's a really interesting site and they're doing a lot of cool research there.
Rym: because of the unique properties of the soil It's not reacting anymore.
Scott: Nuclear reactors are real easy to make and we shouldn't be worrying about like I ran.
Rym: actually what a lot of people are talking about Is that?
Rym: This made nuclear waste.
Rym: it made nuclear waste very similar to the nuclear waste our nuclear reactors make it did.
Scott: Yeah, it would have to and you know what.
Rym: it didn't get into the groundwater.
Rym: It didn't contaminate shit.
Rym: it just stayed exactly where it was buried.
Rym: and The way it's set up is a lot like the way didn't like.
Scott: alpha particles fly off of it and shit.
Rym: alpha particles would get about a Millimeter.
Scott: Well, it's not releasing gamma rays.
Scott: I know that.
Scott: so the only other.
Scott: you could get some beta particles on there.
Rym: Um alpha particles are stopped by anything.
Scott: Well, it's like a Helium and a something an alpha particle.
Rym: an alpha particle is pretty much an atom that gets shot out.
Rym: Yeah, a beta particle is an electron.
Rym: a gamma ray is a gamma ray.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty sure that the alpha particles like a helium.
Rym: The point is yeah that Yuka mountain is very similar and everyone who's afraid of it all the scientists know they're talking about are saying look if we bury Our waste and you come out and nothing bad will happen to it.
Rym: Aha There you go and as a result a lot of anti nuclear activists are decrying.
Rym: this is a false or a forgery or didn't really happen or It's a fluke.
Scott: We should take them to see it.
Rym: I'd like to go see it.
Scott: a green piece is outside the train station on my way home.
Scott: Oh great They were talking about some forest crap.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: They're like save the forest and I was like.
Scott: and then there's one guy who's always there and he's like save the homeless people.
Scott: And I'm like, yeah, we should cut down the forest to build homes for the homeless people.
Rym: Well, the thing is most of the logging industry outside of like the rainforest where they're just clear-cutting and they are doing kind of bad things.
Rym: They're actually a really good industry and they plan 40 years ahead and they plan enough trees to make sure there will always be Trees for them to cut down.
Rym: Yeah, see I'm not a preservationist But I'm definitely a conservationist and you maximize your use of the resources and minimize your negative impacts.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is Greenpeace seems to want to minimize everything and maximize Their own money making they're just nuts.
Scott: Yeah, so my thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, so so me.
Scott: Sony has this DRM on their CDs which puts in the root kits.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yep Yep, a lot of people know about that and do we talk about that before?
Rym: I don't know if we did or not.
Rym: I don't remember anyway.
Scott: So if you want to put it you want to play a Sony CD in your Windows computer.
Scott: it installs this DRM.
Rym: Is it incredibly difficult to remove incredibly powerful?
Scott: Well, it's just a little root kit and it goes and it makes.
Scott: if you try to remove it just by deleting files You end up deleting your CD ROM driver.
Rym: What it does is it kind of infects your CD ROM driver and what it does is it makes it so.
Rym: any file that has A certain prefix in the file name is 100% hidden from the operating.
Scott: It's the file name starts with dollar signs.
Scott: SYS dollar sign.
Rym: It's invisible even in safe mode even to antivirus to anything.
Rym: You can't see it.
Scott: Well, you can see it if you use a rootkit revealer.
Scott: because what it does is is it replaces the code in the operating system?
Scott: For listing the contents of directories.
Scott: So when you make the operating system call and you say hey operating system What's what files are here?
Scott: It won't list anything.
Scott: that begins a dollar score.
Scott: SYS dollar sign.
Rym: Yep, or you can just boot into a lie.
Rym: dollar sign.
Scott: SYS dollar sign.
Rym: Yeah, good game.
Scott: Anyway, World of Warcraft has spyware.
Rym: Uh, yeah, it makes sure that I'm not cheap.
Scott: Make sure that you're not cheating.
Scott: but it is a spyware even though that currently everyone's pretty sure they're not doing anything evil with it.
Scott: They are sending your list of processes and such to to Processes.
Rym: also a list of the title of every window you have open.
Scott: Yep And all kinds of you have to have Firefox open to like one page and the name of the page is like child porn.
Rym: They got a list of whatever websites you're looking at while you're playing World of Warcraft.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well the page you're looking at right now Yeah, but anyway, you know, I don't think they're actually looking at that information.
Scott: I think they're really just looking for cheating.
Rym: I figure they have no vested interest in finding out but that's not the point.
Scott: The point is that they shouldn't be doing that with the spyware or such.
Scott: Yeah, here's the trick.
Scott: if you install the Sony DRM and you rename your cheat files to dollar sign SYS dollar sign World of Warcraft can't get you cheating.
Rym: You know fight fire with flamethrower, you know, you know, I got one thing to say to that Leroy Jenkins.
Scott: So, uh, who would think this is DRM you would want?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I wonder how many people are gonna start cheating?
Scott: crazily At least a few.
Rym: Yeah, and especially as the internet spreads this should be interesting when a bunch of people are running around with like 50 gold.
Rym: Yeah, 50 gold.
Scott: That's like nothing.
Rym: That's a lot in that game.
Rym: Apparently one gold piece is real valuable in World of Warcraft, but it's like silver the most current common piece or what?
Rym: There's just gold and there's just gold and it's rare.
Rym: as far as I can tell.
Rym: I don't play the game.
Scott: Maybe that's why this those gold miners in China.
Scott: Because apparently if one gold is rare you could freakin find a way to get a bunch of it.
Scott: You're freaking damn There's.
Rym: it's easy to get a bunch of it.
Rym: You get a bunch of Minimum wage or low wage workers to sit there and play World of Warcraft.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: All right.
Rym: so, uh Yeah It's Thursday night and we miss college.
Rym: We do a lot a whole lot see, we wonder really geeky school.
Rym: we went to RIT and We were surrounded and immersed but surrounded by an immersed in geekery 24/7 for pretty much four years.
Scott: It is the geekiest geekiest school.
Scott: There is in fact, there was that comic recently about how geeky RIT was.
Scott: It's also like the center of like all piracy in the you internet piracy.
Rym: Remember the big piracy group drink or die.
Rym: They were an international piracy group and they were busted by the feds a couple years ago.
Rym: They were run entirely out of RIT.
Scott: Yep RIT is is nerd capital of the world.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean it has the biggest anime club in America.
Rym: It has the scariest gaming club in the world.
Scott: I've seen scarier gaming clubs.
Rym: But yeah, it used to have a. it has a gaming convention.
Rym: It has an anime convention edit yep, and If you walk through the dorms at 3 a.m you'll either hear the sounds of people playing a counter-strike or you'll hear the sounds of Lonely nerds Some non lonely nerds like frat boys or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, or or uh deaf people having sex Connected to RIT is NT ID the National Technical Institute for the Deaf and it's a good school and they're cool people but Goddamn, they can't hear how much noise they're making.
Scott: and some of them, you know because RIT is a is a cross-section of nerd them, which is typically more intelligent and NT ID is a cross-section of society.
Scott: the average Smartness of NT ID is less smart.
Rym: well Actually, alrighty when I worked for RIT I always delivered stuff around and I ended up seeing a study that some professor was doing where Apparently most of the crime committed at RIT I don't know if it was most but was definitely the majority was committed by NT ID students to NT ID students To the point that well even while we went there there were security cameras all over the NT ID side of campus But nowhere else.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Scott: You know what it was is They were the only ones who could think that.
Scott: you know, they wouldn't hear him coming.
Rym: I Sneak in grab a laptop run away, you know One of the big problems are right here actually because it's mostly geeks were real smart At least smart in terms of figuring out how to pull something off.
Rym: Alright, he had a lot of projectors real expensive projectors like 10 $20,000 project in every classroom and they were stolen at a rate that you would not believe Scary rate.
Scott: and then they replaced them all.
Rym: but they still they get stolen constantly.
Scott: So eventually, well, I think there was one guy with like an epidemic of stealing, but I think they eventually I don't know if they Caught him, but I think it eventually stopped.
Rym: Yeah I mean cuz.
Rym: first of all they had a mounted to the ceiling and they had like a cable that connected to it and if The cable got cut or disconnected it called security immediately.
Rym: So what are the nerds do?
Rym: they left the cable intact and cut all the stuff holding it up?
Rym: They cut everything except the cable.
Rym: then when they were ready to bolt they cut the cable and ran.
Rym: works worked real.
Rym: Well, I Just have many of them since we left the school locked down and locked down a little bit.
Rym: Well, the dorms are locked all the time now and you can't get in without a key.
Rym: Yeah, but someone lets you in and stuff, you know, yeah, but remember when we were there the doors just open all the time.
Scott: yeah, there was a school in Europe actually did something.
Scott: cool is if you wanted to get into the dorm - with Your boyfriend or girlfriend from outside the school at night, then you'd have to pay like so many pounds British pounds Which is - it's basically like, you know, this isn't your house.
Scott: if you want to stay here You got to pay because you know the students who were there got to pay.
Scott: So if anyone wants to spend the night, they may know that's crap.
Rym: Cuz say I have an apartment.
Rym: My landlord it was only the dorms.
Rym: Alright dorms like an apartment say I have an apartment.
Rym: My landlord can't charge me extra five bucks.
Rym: Cuz I had my girlfriend stay over one.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is is that you're not technically renting the.
Scott: the dorm is that they're letting you stay there.
Scott: It's like a hotel.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a hotel.
Scott: if they find out you have an extra person You know what?
Rym: That's still crap.
Scott: But anyway, the point is is that people paid this happily and they even like guys are showing off their receipts to be like Hey, I stayed in the dorms of some chick
Rym: Wow,
Scott: and the
Rym: school made
Scott: a lot of money off of it to do cool stuff like renovate the dorms.
Rym: Yeah But I mean the college lifestyle, oh, yeah, let's see we would get up late and skip whatever morning classes we had.
Rym: We'd go to class and either sleep or not pay attention or do work for other classes.
Rym: Yeah And then we do crazy stuff all night until real late.
Rym: then we'd all go out like a diner and eat and then we'd stay Up later and then we'd eventually fall asleep and wake up and repeat the next day.
Rym: Yeah We would go to our anime club hundreds of people milling around yelling at each other.
Rym: Yeah, we'd go to our board game club play board games and yell at scary people.
Scott: I think that's about it.
Scott: Got a hockey RIT hockey.
Rym: see it's such a geeky school But it had a really good hockey team.
Rym: it had.
Rym: well relative to the hockey teams They play it had a top-tier division 2 hockey 3.
Rym: No, it was division 2.
Scott: vision 2 doesn't exist.
Rym: That's the point.
Rym: It was a top-tier division 2 hockey team back in the day because he didn't let me finish here and then they got rid of division 2 in hockey and Instead of putting RIT in division 1 where they should have been they put him in division 3.
Scott: They're in division 1 now, but they're only doing their win-lose win-lose win-lose, you know, that was their first year in division 1.
Rym: That's a big leap when you're in division 3 for a long time.
Rym: But in division 3 they were just unstoppable.
Rym: they won a game our freshman year Against the worst team ever 24 to 0 in hockey.
Scott: Hey once playing ice hockey on the NES against my cousin.
Scott: I won 125 to like 0.
Rym: I can't imagine how that's even possible.
Scott: I did it.
Scott: I Remember it very clearly.
Rym: no because I can't imagine anyone you were playing with putting up with that and continuing to play.
Scott: Oh, you know, you also.
Scott: there were a lot of games He kicked my ass at like the stupid championship bowling game like that.
Scott: I couldn't beat him at all.
Scott: You get like a 300 I get like 60, but I missed that.
Rym: I mean in college I pay a dollar and I could see an awesome hockey game and then hang out all night.
Scott: It was three dollars, I think that was two bucks.
Scott: I think it raised the price.
Rym: They raised the prize our senior year.
Rym: Yeah Now nothing if I want to see a Rangers game I can pay like 70 bucks Yeah, and I got a drive down there.
Scott: man I went from do whatever I want whenever I want with literal no responsibility, but I complained about having homework.
Scott: now I got no homework But it's wake up go to work.
Scott: Come home do stuff eat Yeah, go to bed.
Rym: we can only really do stuff on the weekends when you're in college.
Rym: the weekends We're just like extra bonus time and we just have all the time.
Scott: Yep, man I used to make fun of people for wake up go to work Come home watch TV go to bed.
Scott: now of all those things except I replaced watch TV with some other stuff Yeah like this like this.
Rym: I mean The biggest problem is that we had all our friends together.
Rym: we had a huge posse we had our front row crew.
Scott: Well, we made the posse there.
Rym: Yeah And we had a posse there because we made it there and we were real close.
Scott: and now we got a fine.
Scott: You got to make a new posse here But there's.
Rym: no it's not easy because you don't have a giant pile of nerds to to run through the sieve But it's cool because we moved out here and bit by bit as all our friends from college graduate or get jobs Or whatever.
Rym: They're moving out here.
Rym: Yeah, kinda Yeah, we got a good bit.
Rym: We're better off than staying there.
Rym: Definitely better off than staying because there was a time when I thought You know living here at RIT is great I could just live in this town forever and have the same awesome forever and then I realized that no because everyone else will leave and I won't get a good job because the market there is glutted with kids who all want to do the same thing and It's kind of a crappy area outside of the college.
Rym: The only thing that made RIT great was the people.
Scott: Giant pile of nerds in one basket.
Scott: We don't live near a game store anymore.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the best game store I've ever been in in my life is still Millennium in Rochester.
Scott: I think it's the biggest game store.
Rym: It's one of the biggest.
Rym: I don't know if it's the biggest but it's up there.
Scott: But it's like even though you know, alright, so now we can buy all the board games We didn't have before but now we have no people to play them with.
Rym: But I mean it's not like we have no people because we have a lot of friends who live near enough where they can hang Out for a weekend.
Rym: We've had at least one big party where everyone came and we had a job.
Scott: We're gonna have a bigger party where everyone comes in New Year's.
Rym: Oh God on New Year's I think we're gonna have more people than our house can hold.
Scott: we should get even like the such Extraneous people like like my family and your family and make it crazy.
Rym: I've been invited pretty much.
Rym: I have told everyone I think is cool and I haven't gotten to everyone yet because it's still a ways off and I'm pretty much trying to contact everyone.
Scott: I know and I'm being like like even really like like can even like.
Rym: yeah Everyone.
Scott: we should get every Warm and even some cold bodies and I wonder if Dwayne's still alive.
Scott: No, we don't want to ain't God.
Rym: Dwayne was when we first got to RIT and we all like.
Rym: the first.
Rym: the way we all met was because we went to this gaming club and We're all standing there were all a little freshman.
Rym: And then we hear a guy yell in the distance, I'm running a third edition.
Rym: He wasn't in the distance like in the other side of the room.
Scott: No, he was well Maybe you were on the other side of the room.
Rym: Yeah, I wasn't cuz I saw me stood up on a table.
Rym: He's like I run in a third at D&D game.
Rym: I ran over there and I met a bunch of geeks.
Scott: I know I walked in expecting to play some battle take on the battle tank and Katsu was there with his crazy umbrella and I talked to him.
Scott: cuz he was like in the battle tech even though It was.
Scott: he didn't play it for so many years Even though we had already played it out in all those times in.
Scott: Peterson 3 had never played Battle tank until like two years later.
Scott: Yeah, Katsu was awesome But he's not good at battle Even though I saw I met him before anyone else.
Scott: and then do I was right there with all the group of people and this Guy was like, yeah, there's like third ed D&D.
Rym: So we all make our characters.
Scott: I never I had last D&D I saw was second.
Scott: It was like third ed.
Rym: Holy crap I had just bought third ed and I had just converted a character to third ed.
Rym: So I barely knew it.
Rym: and it was awesome because this guy seemed really cool and it was a huge group.
Rym: So we split it up into like two groups.
Rym: There's gonna be a DM and a co DM this crazy D&D game and the first session was awesome.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Rym: So we uh go the next week to play again and we learned that Dwayne apparently Has all like this amount of awesome in his body and he spent it all that night and all that was left was this pot smoking.
Rym: Doofus husk just a husk of a man with like pot smoke floating.
Scott: other DM guy was actually cool, but he disappeared.
Rym: Yeah, he like literally disappeared.
Rym: I never heard from him again.
Rym: Yep Yeah D&D we used to play.
Scott: people say, you know, oh we should make marijuana legal.
Scott: It doesn't hurt you It doesn't?
Scott: you know?
Scott: chemically you don't get addicted.
Scott: Yeah, but it turns you into a Stupid.
Rym: Dwayne would have probably been addicted to like Tylenol.
Scott: I don't think there was any stop in his proliferary proliferary His proclivity toward addiction But he could have been addicted to something that wouldn't turn you into a doofus.
Scott: I could play World of Warcraft You know while World of Warcraft it eats up all your time and some of your money It doesn't turn you into a doofus Doofus.
Rym: Yo, I Miss D&D though.
Scott: We used to play Dungeons & Dragons for hours And now I guess you could think people do play two-person D&D.
Rym: I'll be the DM.
Rym: All right, let's play right now.
Rym: All right, you're you're like a human fighter.
Scott: No, I don't wanna be a fighter.
Scott: I'll be wizard.
Rym: find your wizard sweet You're level five.
Scott: Oh, sweet fireball fireball.
Rym: So you're standing at the entrance to a dungeon.
Scott: Alright, there's a sign that says dungeon I don't go in the dungeon cuz I have no reason to go in there and it's scary and dangerous.
Rym: All right, I turn around a New blocks your way.
Rym: Oh What a new I can do.
Scott: as in the creature.
Scott: Yes Is it a normal canoe or is it?
Scott: somehow I detect magic on it.
Rym: It is magical.
Scott: it is Magic.
Rym: text is written on the side that says the dungeon master wants you to go into the cave.
Scott: Oh, well, I must defy the dungeon master with all my power.
Rym: You know what a dragon eats you?
Scott: Where did the dragon come from?
Scott: I would.
Scott: That's why you don't play two-person D&D.
Rym: We're trying to play a forum game of D&D and it's fun, but it's kind of dragon mostly because we all have dragon dragons Dungeons & Dragons dragon.
Rym: Yeah after this podcast.
Rym: I'm gonna go drain the dragon.
Scott: drain the dragon.
Rym: Yeah dragon is a little full.
Rym: What was the thing in order of the stick the the trouser Titan the trouser Titan coxmanship?
Rym: I have a plus five to coxmanship.
Scott: I wish there was someone to play D&D with besides Me.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we're playing the online game, but it's kind of slow.
Scott: But if everyone moves out here, I'll totally run a game And everyone who'll run a game we'll have a game every night of the week of the crazy Yeah cops.
Rym: who wants to run a game or find Alex our DM wants to run a game?
Scott: Yeah Let's run games Let's play a lot.
Scott: What do you want?
Scott: all we want to do is play lots of games and just crap gets in our way.
Scott: So then we obsess about getting rid of the crap and we totally lose sight.
Scott: All we want to do is sit around and play games the rest of our lives One of the happiest summers of my life.
Rym: we stayed in RIT over the summer and we paid like half rent because that's how it worked back then and You took like one class and I worked at a sub shop and our friend Alex worked at a sub shop And we just played German board games specifically Puerto Rico Every day
Scott: man.
Scott: I realize if there's no bullshit in this entire world.
Scott: All we would do is eat and Play games all day Bike a lot and stuff.
Scott: It would be part of a game.
Rym: Most of our time would be spent Yeah Playing games and eating in college The only time we stopped playing games if we had bigger things to do or we were too tired to continue playing physically.
Scott: Yeah But even then there are some games that don't take so much like apples to apples.
Rym: Yeah, apples to apples is a great game.
Scott: Definitely great game.
Scott: They actually sell that in stores.
Scott: Now Carcassone is actually in.
Scott: Toys R Us is some place.
Rym: Nanofictionary was always fun.
Scott: We haven't played that in a while.
Scott: I think I don't know the instruction book.
Scott: is it to find it?
Scott: Yeah Such a drum line anyway.
Rym: See there's no real moral here because we're still kind of in the transition to the real world which the real world generally sucks, but Don't think that you can stay in college because it won't work.
Rym: But don't give up on trying to live the college lifestyle and become a nine-to-five schlub.
Rym: Definitely you got to live the college lifestyle somehow outside of college.
Rym: But that can't happen if you stay in college because every generate like.
Rym: think about it.
Rym: You're at RIT Then you graduate but you stay at RIT.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So now you've got some low-paying job because it's Rochester, but your rent's low.
Rym: So it's okay and you know people are in school.
Rym: So you still hang out there.
Rym: then another year goes by.
Rym: Now, you know people who know people in school and you only kind of know people in the school.
Rym: So when you hang out people are always like who's that?
Rym: Then the next year now you kind of know people who kind of know people who go to the school and you're just that old Creepy guy who's hanging around in the corner trying to get people to play apples to apples with him.
Scott: Don't be that guy.
Scott: Yeah, there are a lot of guys you don't want to be.
Scott: that's one of the guys You don't want to be.
Scott: but by that logic What you should do is you should stay at the school for like an extra year and then leave Yeah, which I kind of did.
Rym: I could have left a year early and I stayed.
Rym: yeah came back after that co-op Left.
Scott: see now it would be extra school as if they were like nerdy towns.
Scott: Yeah, it's like my house would be part of like a nerd condo and everyone in the whole condo is like a friendly nerd.
Scott: So it's like I live in an awesome college dorm with college awesome nerd action, but I go to work somewhere.
Scott: Yep, even better if all the nerds living in that condo were the work and then it was just awesome.
Rym: Now, I think the biggest thing is if you have enough money You can continue to live the college life no matter where you live Because then you don't have to work as much.
Rym: Yeah Or you have enough money to get all your friends together or to travel to go to Otakon is the wrong.
Scott: Imagine if one of us had like a 20 like a super Time-consuming CEO job of millions of dollars and the rest of us were just supported by that guy.
Scott: One guy basically gets the stick and all these other people go.
Rym: Yeah, but then he quits and you still have enough money to live out your day.
Scott: Well, you just had you'd have to quit when he got enough money to live off the interest or form some sort of Skinner Colony.
Rym: Yeah, those don't work so well, but we've realized Cuz if you just stay in your college town It's probably a dead end in the long run because everyone's gonna leave to get you know.
Scott: Real jobs unless you get everyone to stay but then you all suffer together.
Rym: Yeah, because no matter what people tell you unless you live in a military town or a factory town Many factory towns that have colleges anymore.
Rym: You're not gonna get a good job unless you do something crazy like start your own business because Everyone has the same idea you do and they can always hire some fresh punk kid out of college for a lot less money than They'll pay you.
Scott: I remember when I was in college I had to find a co-op and it was so hard because I had to put limits like where it was.
Scott: Yeah, I found co-ops like in California like ding.
Scott: I could have just gotten them.
Scott: It would pay needed jobs.
Rym: I looked like I need a job and there were jobs everywhere just not in any college.
Scott: But if I limited myself by where I would have gotten a job much later.
Scott: I got a job two weeks after grad after I was Back home.
Scott: Yeah two weeks.
Rym: I've technically been employed from while I was still in school until now.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I went home.
Scott: I did a little relaxing at home, you know built a robot did some internetting Put my resume about and even put that much effort into it.
Scott: Not as much as I had done previously.
Scott: Put the resume on Craigslist You know, I got one email that was just kind of like I wasn't even really because it was a job involving something that I Wasn't 100% about.
Scott: but then you know, I replied cuz someone emailed me.
Scott: Now I have a job.
Rym: I still have the job and at first I thought not so bad Oh this sucks cuz I moved away and I was working for IBM and I was living out in the Mid Hudson Valley all alone.
Rym: But then after the initial, you know leaving and establishing myself somewhere once one person is established somewhere It's easy for other people to go to the same type of area.
Rym: Hmm, so then one of my friends moved in nearby and then one of my friends moved in with me and then two more of my friends are thinking of moving into the area and I got a friend who has like he stays nearby like kind of far away but much closer than the old college town.
Scott: One of these days will come with an idea and someone will give us money to do something Yep, and then we can quit and do that.
Rym: but the best way to keep live in college is to flee college and Get the money and find a place to establish yourself and then reconvene.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes hard to reconvene though, depending on what your situation is.
Rym: Yeah, we got real lucky.
Rym: We found a great house We both got jobs easily and of course We're looking to New York City area where there's a million million million tech jobs million million jobs in New York City.
Scott: Just sucks to live in New York City.
Rym: Yeah, not so bad to live in the suburbs.
Scott: I mean we're paying my cousin just who works in the city.
Scott: she just got an apartment in the city with another person and Basically, they've got.
Scott: it's so small to one bedroom one person's in the bedroom and they put like a wall like in the living room To split it in half.
Scott: It's so small and they pay a lot as much as we do for this whole house.
Scott: Yep, but she doesn't lose two hours a day to train.
Rym: Yeah, but eventually you could telecommute or we could start our own company.
Scott: or definitely I'm not keeping this job.
Scott: You know, well the job itself is good It's.
Scott: it's really just you know, the time it takes to do the job.
Scott: that kills me.
Scott: I You know, I would.
Scott: I'm probably not gonna keep it before I'm 30.
Scott: I won't be working there.
Rym: Oh, definitely I won't be at IBM when I'm 30 I could tell you 100% guarantee Unless they make me some sort of crazy manager.
Scott: Even if I become one of those guys who tries a business it fails tries business it fails.
Rym: I won't Yeah, because a lot of people they have great aspirations, but then they aren't willing to take the risk Mmm-hmm.
Rym: We are definitely willing to risk.
Rym: We're definitely willing to risk our middle-class Lifestyle for the possibility of leading an awesome life.
Scott: There's no other way to lead the awesome life.
Rym: We have to yeah, unless we get more else.
Scott: We're basically saying we give up.
Scott: We don't want an awesome life.
Rym: Yeah The moment we give up we cease to have the college in us and all that's left is the nine-to-five husky Like all your co-workers.
Rym: Yeah, like most of my co-workers like pretty much everyone I've met in the tech industry who has worked in the tech industry for more than a few years hmm sucks Yeah, we're not gonna be that way.
Rym: if we ever get that way We'd probably just say fuck it and quit and like do some credit card scam and then run off and do something crazy like Mexico.
Scott: I don't want to do something like that.
Rym: I forgot to that point.
Rym: I'd rather do that than continue to live nine to five until I am old enough to retire And just don't want to do anything.
Scott: we're at the run to Mexico.
Rym: we could run somewhere nice like France it's not with their Riots, yeah All right Yeah.
Scott: So do we have a daily thing?
Rym: Not really.
Rym: This was just kind of a pseudo angsty rant about how we miss college.
Scott: It's not so angsty.
Rym: Not really.
Rym: Thanks.
Scott: You'd be like, so my college days are Forgone.
Rym: oh for now, I am against the LARP and I cannot LARP anymore.
Scott: Oh But secretly inside have a strong desire to learn.
Scott: Oh But I will not.
Rym: that will not say if you get one thing out of this Live-action role-playing LARPing.
Scott: It's a cool thing.
Rym: It's not however, it is not cool in Rochester, New York.
Scott: It's not cool.
Rym: It's cool.
Scott: I saw a thing on TV people doing in, Texas.
Scott: They were exactly like the people in Rochester.
Scott: But there are people who aren't that way very few and they won't play with you because you're not as cool as they are.
Rym: well, I guess the moral is be leery of people who LARP and Stay in college as long as you can but when it's time to leave college fucking leave Yeah, and go to college because if you don't you'll just be a dumb waste.
Rym: Unless you become a plumber or something, then you'll make more money than we do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I should have been a plumber or an underwater welder.
Scott: Dangerous though.
Rym: Yeah dangerous, but working five years.
Scott: I did.
Scott: I didn't realize there was one bad thing about being the plumber.
Rym: Uh-huh poop.
Rym: Yeah, yeah fine electrician.
Rym: Yeah, there's no poop in electricity unless you're really bad at it.
Scott: You could be doing bathroom electrician in this, you know, you generally.
Rym: you don't put electricity into the poop hole.
Scott: You never know.
Rym: people want those like LED toilets and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the music and promotional consideration was provided by no one.