Scott: It's Tuesday November 1st, and this is GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Let's do this alright, so Today I stayed home sick.
Rym: Yeah, I noticed cuz I woke up and I didn't notice that you were home.
Rym: I was just up and I was doing my thing and I figured you wouldn't notice.
Scott: I was home cuz you don't go my room and you saw my car outside, right?
Rym: Well, I walked out and your car was there and for a second I thought did he ride his bike?
Rym: and then I realized no, he's a lazy fuck.
Rym: He won't ride his bike.
Rym: So I walk in I walk upstairs and you're in bed and I assumed you just overslept or you Didn't set an alarm or you know what happens.
Scott: I woke up 2 30 a.m Oh 2 30 and my stomach was on fire on Fire on fire.
Scott: Well, basically what happened is I woke up my stomach hurt and I was like, oh great I'm gonna have a bad stomach day.
Scott: Then I looked at the clock and I saw it was 2 30 and I was like my stomach hurt bad enough to wake me up.
Scott: so after I aroused I I went to the.
Scott: well not aroused sexually aroused the other way.
Scott: Yeah, I went to the to the bathroom And I tried to get out some diarrhea and it didn't want to come out.
Scott: So so I was like, oh, this is great.
Scott: It hurts.
Scott: So I went back to bed.
Rym: So well, but you think maybe it could have been the lasagna you had at the diner last night.
Scott: I'm betting it was but but let me finish the story here.
Scott: This is gets weirder Great.
Scott: so it's all in bed After pooping out like the tiniest poop not even diarrhea or anything and it the fire doubles.
Rym: This doesn't end in something disgusting does it?
Scott: It's not that disgusting.
Rym: This doesn't involve your bed.
Scott: I already said the word diarrhea doesn't get more disgusting than that.
Rym: It could be like diarrhea that doesn't go into a toilet.
Scott: No, it goes through it.
Rym: all of it all of it all of it all of you sure sure?
Scott: Okay, so I sit on the toilet and finally the diarrhea comes and get some relief, right?
Scott: You know, I'm just kind of sitting there Wetten, you know a little chilly, you know Stomach hurts some gas moves around, you know, that sort of thing.
Scott: then it starts to hurt.
Scott: worse, you know It's building up some worse ness.
Scott: So I'm like, alright, I'm gonna barge.
Rym: You haven't bargled in a long time and bargled.
Scott: I got a streak better than Seinfeld to my bargaining.
Rym: I almost lost it.
Scott: So so I get down on to the.
Scott: eventually I decide alright I just want relief.
Scott: this hurts real bad.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna bargo even though I wasn't that nauseous I just let me guess you couldn't.
Scott: I got down on the floor naked on my knees in front of the toilet.
Rym: Thank the gods.
Rym: I didn't wake up and go take a pee.
Rym: in the middle of the night.
Scott: I heard you rustling and I was like, damn he sleeps light.
Rym: I Wasn't awake.
Rym: you realize you've seen my bed.
Rym: My bed turns into just a twisted mass of sheets every night.
Scott: Yeah, but you do sleep real light.
Scott: I mean I came in to like just change your clock and you woke up.
Rym: I I sleep real heavily actually But it's like when I'm asleep, and if there's something going on around me, I'll become aware of it.
Rym: But I'm still asleep like in my dream and I can choose I should wake up because someone's about to do something to me or What I was gonna do the.
Scott: I was changing your clock correctly.
Scott: See you know, I don't want it.
Scott: I was wondering.
Rym: I have a nightingale floor like the samurai of old.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and as you walk into my room, it goes Creek very clearly.
Scott: It's not that loud.
Rym: It's real loud.
Scott: It's not as loud as my house.
Rym: My house is like But I don't sleep lightly.
Rym: I slept through a house exploding an entire house.
Scott: All right Tell that story someday.
Scott: So so I'm on the floor my hands and knees trying to bargo and not getting anything.
Rym: Did you stick your finger down your throat?
Scott: No, I don't do that.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: It would have worked Because I couldn't bring myself to do that.
Scott: You know I tried to push a little bit and once I got some coughing and it felt like the coughing was gonna bring something out of Esophagus.
Scott: but no, I got some mucus like a spec.
Rym: is this story going anywhere?
Scott: It does go somewhere.
Scott: So I'm sitting on on the floor in the bathroom not getting anywhere.
Scott: All right, and Not feeling good.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: So the next thing I did was I was getting a little tired.
Rym: Did you fall asleep naked on your knees in the bathroom?
Scott: No, no, I did.
Scott: I took a rest.
Scott: I laid down on the bathroom floor on the cold bathroom floor naked.
Rym: Now now wait It's like right next to.
Rym: I could have just walked out.
Rym: now the door.
Scott: what the door is closed.
Rym: I probably just opened it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, but cuz I would have I wasn't I wasn't sleeping.
Scott: I was resting I was I was kind of.
Rym: but imagine my consternation if I were to wake up and I walked into the bathroom naked myself Mind you and I see you already in the bathroom naked and looks like you're asleep on the bathroom floor.
Scott: Hey, I'm not sure I might have boxes on I don't remember.
Rym: I'm not sure what I would have done.
Scott: Anyway As soon as I laid down on that floor, I start feeling better.
Scott: uh-huh, I don't know why my Bed didn't feel good.
Scott: But bathroom floor felt great.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: You didn't take some percocet.
Scott: I Don't take the drugs little percadine.
Scott: No, nothing.
Scott: Nothing.
Rym: Nothing.
Scott: So so Then after I feel a little better, you know, I got to do a little more diarrhea.
Scott: get up do a little diarrhea You know and I'm feeling pretty good.
Scott: Just you know, I'm still all But I'm feeling better than stomach on fire.
Scott: the fire was put out couched Once again, is this going anywhere?
Scott: Yeah so I took a shower and then I went into my room and it was a 330 and I was like damn I spent an hour in there.
Scott: Oh, you spent a good six minutes talking about this Yeah, and then I used my little blackberry to emailed the boss turn off the alarm went to sleep woke up.
Scott: I was at home today Uh-huh.
Scott: It's pretty good Except really go anywhere except for the not eat.
Rym: I was sleeping on the floor Yeah, but then I asked you if the story was going anywhere and you said yeah, it's going somewhere.
Scott: Well, that was the climax me a little little rundown afterwards a little rundown.
Scott: Just climax the end.
Rym: I mean you had a little rundown, but There you go.
Rym: Yeah, so the Senate.
Rym: I had a crazy thing today, but it wasn't as crazy as everyone made it out to be.
Scott: See I didn't think it was that crazy.
Rym: Well, I wasn't sure.
Rym: cuz I was at work and I was about to leave you.
Scott: you exaggerate many things.
Rym: I cuz I went.
Rym: I checked the FARC before I left work just in case, you know, maybe something happened.
Rym: I always check part and FARC has a story newsflash mind you and there's not even a link associated with it.
Rym: It's such breaking news and the actual FARC headline was Democratic minority leader Harry Reid calls private closed-door session in Senate to scrutinize pre-iraq war intelligence.
Rym: And I thought Shits something's going down and actually something did go down.
Scott: But it's not crazy exciting.
Scott: It's just all.
Scott: they had a closed-door meeting.
Rym: Whoo Well, it is fairly exciting because it's the beginning of a congressional committee to look into Certain things that happen during the Iraq war.
Scott: a congressional committee that will find nothing exciting.
Rym: No, because the kid that everyone really nor is three Democrats and three Republicans.
Scott: Yeah, okay, 9/11 Commission found all this bad stuff And meanwhile, everyone was like, oh look what they found and then that was it.
Scott: No one did anything.
Rym: Yeah, I'm trying to be optimistic here.
Rym: Yeah, apparently you're a pessimist.
Scott: Look who's talking.
Rym: what I was all.
Rym: I really assumed that Fitzgerald was gonna get some people and he got someone and he's still getting People.
Scott: yeah, we'll see they can indict people.
Scott: if you know like a witness during the trial says something You know a lot of people think that was the strategy that he got the one guy.
Rym: so we can get other people.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if like you kill someone Who You know was robbing your store or something, you know.
Scott: and during your testimony you say this guy was robbed my store Well, they just indict him right there.
Rym: But the FARC threat on this pretty much has turned into a flame war.
Scott: great.
Rym: Oh, really really?
Scott: Yeah, really so ice hockey.
Rym: Yeah, I'm really liking the fact that hockey's back.
Rym: Yeah hockey Hockey is very much a geek sport in that Traditionally geeks seem to like the sport.
Rym: I mean MIT didn't have a good hockey team, but the fans were real into it and real nerdly.
Rym: RIT RIT very big geek school very big.
Scott: I think it's cuz all the geek schools are from the cold areas.
Scott: You don't see the geeks at like.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute Caltech.
Scott: You don't see the geeks at Caltech or Georgia Tech like in the ice hockey.
Rym: Yeah, they don't have the ice.
Rym: Well, they do have the ice hockey just not so much not so good It's the cold schools.
Scott: and telling you it's a northerner thing, you know the Messier line.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well also I think it is a very good game in terms of Something that you can watch and appreciate on multiple levels.
Scott: Yeah as opposed to basketball, yeah, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, man, that sounds so racist because basketball is so black and hockey so white but it Basketball is a good sport.
Rym: The NBA is not basketball.
Rym: That is how I say it.
Scott: Yeah, but that still sounds racist to those people.
Rym: I like women's basketball a lot.
Scott: Yeah And that's saying it is racist because I'm totally on the side.
Scott: that it's not you know And that you know, but a lot of what I say those kind of things.
Rym: I do have to point out that my red wings are really taking advantage of these new rules and They're leading the league far and away and no one's even close to late.
Scott: a bunch of crap teams.
Scott: No, they played good teams and not so much and they're in the easier division.
Rym: Ah, actually they're in one of the hardest divisions The only other team in there it's.
Scott: it's so weird because all the teams that were no good are now good like the Nashville Predators like the.
Scott: they're different Nashville enough big cheerleaders that they're hockey.
Scott: That's so much.
Scott: They don't know about how they're doing good.
Scott: And the New York Rangers haven't done good since 94 when they won.
Rym: They're not doing good at all.
Scott: They're doing great.
Rym: No, they're doing terribly.
Scott: No, they're not.
Rym: I'll pull up Something else but I'll pull up the NHL standings.
Rym: we can talk about that.
Scott: All right, the Rangers are actually doing really good.
Scott: They're in first place.
Rym: Oh, no, the Red Wings are.
Scott: That's the other part of hockey.
Rym: You realize that it's divisional and it's also reads broken up in two tiers.
Scott: now It's always been broken up, but now they're doing it strictly.
Rym: There's fewer games now.
Rym: Intercross division.
Rym: That's why the Red Wings are only playing the Rangers once.
Scott: Yeah, that's why the Red Wings are playing the easy teams and the Rangers of any.
Rym: what other news you got?
Rym: I'll show you the Rangers standings.
Scott: Yeah, they're doing really well.
Scott: There was ten news stories about the revolution today and all of them were conflicting.
Scott: Aha, so it's coming out in June or October or May or April or December.
Rym: Did any of these people cite a source?
Scott: Yeah, they all cited different sources.
Scott: There was like one thing from Iwata and a thing from Miyamoto today, and it was all confusing and no one could be final.
Scott: So I just kind of ignored all of it and I'll read the final deal tomorrow.
Rym: Ah I'm still looking forward to it.
Scott: Yeah gonna buy it when it comes out.
Rym: Yeah, and I'm gonna use yours.
Rym: I'll buy a controller for it.
Scott: Better I think they're gonna be expensive.
Scott: They'll probably be like 40 bucks.
Rym: Yeah, that's fine.
Rym: I own my one GameCube controller.
Rym: I'm all on my one revolution controller.
Rym: I own my one PlayStation one DualShock controller.
Scott: I gotta get one of those.
Scott: those are hard to find Not really.
Scott: you just only looked in one store a store which had a zillion regular PlayStation one controllers But no PlayStation one DualShock controller.
Scott: I think PlayStation 2 controllers might work.
Scott: I just don't know.
Rym: Well, that's all you.
Scott: Yeah, so I saw you were looking at the Rangers standings.
Scott: Did you?
Rym: yeah, like the Rangers are five and five Not five five and they've lost five.
Scott: That's why it says New York Rangers six for I don't know that that doesn't count.
Rym: All that counts is within the division and in the division, they're five and five.
Scott: Where does it say that?
Scott: it says five and four and one four and one.
Rym: one is overtime loss?
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: There's six and four.
Scott: they have 13 points.
Scott: No, they're very play.
Rym: No, they have 15 points even better.
Rym: The Red Wings have 22 points.
Scott: The Red Wings are in the other half.
Rym: Montreal is 17 Carolina has 17 Vancouver has.
Scott: those are all in the other half of hockey in the Western Conference.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: the Western Conference?
Rym: Traditionally tends to win.
Scott: No, not so much.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, look at the last 50 years of the Stanley Cup.
Scott: I do not see a Stanley Cup in your future.
Rym: Uh, you know what?
Rym: I'll bet you 50 bucks.
Rym: the Red Wings win the Stanley Cup versus whatever team you sail winning and if neither one wins it Not the Red Wings so what that's a stupid fine.
Rym: then I get at least ten to one odds.
Scott: no Oh, so you're saying that they don't have a good chance.
Rym: No, I'm saying that I'm sure ball I'm sure they have a good chance.
Scott: if you're gonna take such a blanket blanket bet I'm just saying the Red Wings are not gonna win.
Rym: I think they're gonna say it's way.
Scott: early in the season They haven't played any good teams and in the playoffs when they're forced to place real teams Then they're not gonna win.
Rym: you realize they are a real good hockey team and every year they do really really well.
Rym: and You got you know, in fact, they're tied with the Jersey Devils for the best teams in the last ten years.
Scott: You're just biased.
Scott: You're not actually haven't even watched a hockey game this season.
Scott: You don't know anything about it.
Scott: You just look at those numbers and you're a Red Wings fan and you go woo.
Scott: They're gonna win.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: No I want to read about the games - my dad calls me after every game and tells me what happens.
Scott: your dad's a hockey expert.
Rym: My dad's a hockey nut.
Scott: He's not a hockey expert.
Rym: You realize I grew up in hockey town.
Rym: I grew up in Detroit.
Rym: My family is Probably more fanatical about hockey than I am about anime board games hockey Geekery and computers combined.
Scott: we're fanatical about hockey, but I still contend you are not hockey experts.
Scott: Actually your analysis of hockey is not.
Rym: My analysis is based on what I hear from other people.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, we'll see we'll see.
Rym: I think the Red Wings got a good chance.
Scott: Yeah So Sony the new Sony record company their DRM CDs are the root kit.
Scott: They just install a root kit on you so that you can't remove the DRM software.
Rym: Um great See I'd care but one I don't.
Rym: You know because the last CD I bought was Metallica and justice for all yep But the real issue here is that I want to while I would never buy CD you only get the root kit or use Windows.
Rym: I want to Have them go to jail for hacking, but it's not hacking because you bought the CD and it warns you that it dissolves copy protection.
Rym: Yeah, but it's kind of like and I heard but I can't verify that the CD itself doesn't actually have the CD logo that says It's a fully compliant.
Scott: Oh, none of those CDs.
Scott: so CD logo from Philips.
Rym: technically nothing illegal was done.
Scott: It doesn't say it's gonna install a root kid.
Scott: I mean if you come and I come to your house I say I'm gonna work on your computer.
Rym: basically says it's going to but it says it in legalese and it I don't think it Said you can't get them there.
Rym: They pretty much got it gold.
Rym: The only thing you can do is either not buy their product or pirate their products.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't think anyone's going to.
Scott: I think they're definitely gonna be in trouble over this and I don't think they will be.
Rym: Unless a third party exploits this rootkit people are gonna get them.
Scott: It's not gonna fly.
Rym: I don't think anyone cares except us and our fellow geeks.
Scott: No plenty of people care.
Rym: No, they don't cuz they don't even know.
Rym: most people have a Windows computer Don't even know that the spyware they already have is causing their problems.
Scott: Yeah, but you realize that other nerdy things are only nerds care like broadcast flag.
Scott: We beat back ferociously.
Rym: Actually, I'm very pro broadcast flag.
Scott: You know, you can be pro or against any of these things.
Scott: as if you're pro you say good It'll hurt everyone and then they'll wake up.
Scott: Yes, or no?
Scott: because then that's the right way.
Rym: I used to be very very on the side of good But now I'm on the side of evil because I want people to get their bad medicine and realize they need to change.
Scott: I don't like I'm going.
Scott: I was Just keep it the good way.
Scott: if we start letting them get the bad way We might turn out that it doesn't work and the people still don't do anything about it.
Scott: And then we're stuck in this crap.
Scott: That's fine Cuz.
Rym: that makes us.
Rym: the more people let themselves be locked down in their media their push technology The more people like us have power over those people because we exist outside of that.
Rym: Mac and I I couldn't come up with a funny word.
Scott: Yeah, but then it'll be easier to find out who we are and get us.
Rym: get us for what?
Scott: You know, it'll turn into a 1984.
Scott: It'll be screwed.
Rym: We're the only ones who'd be smart enough to run a 1984.
Scott: No, you don't have to be smart to run a 1984. the Very top half the 1984 runs itself.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, it depends on the 1984.
Rym: I mean, is it a Brazil?
Rym: Is it?
Scott: And the people are just cogs in the machine.
Scott: you don't need anyone to run them.
Rym: Yeah But it could be.
Rym: it could be like a Harrison Berger on 1984 where there's smart people who run it because they're the only ones who know how to smile.
Rym: people are running it then it doesn't Matter because they're smart, but they're also evil or stupid.
Scott: if they're also evil then, you know, you know, they could be savants.
Rym: They're real good at running an Aurelian society, but they're real bad at everything else.
Rym: hmm, so a SEO.
Rym: finally finally finally finally Actually said what they're suing IBM over specifically.
Scott: What was it?
Rym: It's sealed and only the judge could read it.
Scott: So it's made up.
Rym: Yeah, but they actually filed it and they said this is it?
Rym: They said there are two hundred and seventeen bits of code that they believe IBM or sequence 200 pieces Not bits.
Scott: You can't say bits if we're talking about code.
Rym: I can say bits.
Rym: we call all the bits on the show bits.
Scott: Are they lines?
Scott: Are they functions?
Scott: Are they whole file areas?
Rym: The specific word used in the brief is areas 217 areas where they think that IBM Took their code and put it in open source code.
Rym: and they're not claiming that it was a copyright infringement.
Rym: They're only claiming that IBM violated the contract that they signed with SEO.
Rym: except IBM didn't sign that contract with SEO.
Rym: They signed that contract with.
Rym: Was it AT&T or it was a long time ago and SEO really had nothing to do with this anyway?
Rym: Aha, so it's still BS and the whole thing is just crap.
Rym: But SEO finally said what they claim IBM might have stolen.
Rym: I'm sure Grok law has the the whole stuff now because it's sealed and until Either it's unsealed or the court case concludes.
Rym: We can't read it.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: They're not going anywhere.
Scott: I can't believe this is still happening.
Scott: I haven't heard news about it for months.
Rym: I thought we considering that I mean I work for IBM and Most people inside IBM have never even heard of SEO.
Rym: That's how little IBM cares about this.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Though there there was some funny news.
Rym: This is kind of weird news.
Rym: It's not really news.
Rym: It's just a weird thing.
Rym: There's this time.
Rym: I saw it because it happened in Rochester.
Rym: we used to go to school.
Rym: there's this family and they have their garage and they moved into the house and they found a Negative like of old film like 1920s 1930s film of pictures laying on the floor in the middle of the garage whatever.
Rym: they thought that they were just Like something the previous owner left behind.
Rym: so they moved in they threw the pictures away, whatever.
Rym: See this is kind of a ghost story to go with the fact that yesterday was Halloween.
Scott: Oh great.
Scott: Don't worry.
Rym: Don't worry Because everyone involved is smart except that they're lacking one critical skill, which is problem-solving.
Rym: so a few weeks go by and One and then they go out and another negative is in the middle of their locked garage on the floor.
Rym: That's weird.
Rym: And then another one appears the next day Mm-hmm.
Rym: So at this point the lady who like the head of the household Thinks something's going on and you'd think most people would be like it's a ghost She was like, there's got to be some film somewhere in this garage that's fallen from somewhere.
Rym: So she's looking through all the rafters.
Rym: You can't find anything.
Rym: She cleans out the whole garage can't find anything.
Rym: So she calls the police like hey, this is weird.
Rym: So the police look and they noticed that they're Chew marks like squirrels or rats were chewing on the film.
Scott: So squirrels are stealing film from Kodak and putting in their house.
Rym: the best guess anyone's come up with is that there is a stash somewhere of These film.
Rym: it looks like pictures from the 1920s and 30s.
Rym: some of them are of this house and of the neighborhood somewhere in the neighborhood and Some squirrels or some rats must have gotten into it and are trying to use it for something or carrying it around And they're carrying it through this garage in their path.
Scott: Why don't they grab a squirrel put a tag on it?
Rym: because the odds of getting the right squirrel there's no way.
Rym: now This is cool.
Rym: And I really would like to know like what this is.
Rym: Maybe there's some cool pictures that we'll get out of this But it doesn't seem like anyone involved had the bright idea to I don't know put a camera in the garage and see where the film comes from or put a motion sensor or Stand there until a rat runs by carrying some film.
Scott: I guess they just don't care that much.
Scott: No So the last thing I got here is in the Olympics, I don't know which Olympics.
Scott: I think a winter or summer.
Scott: It must be a summer because it's weightlifting.
Scott: I read I didn't read all the details, but there's gonna be one team Korea whoa Not North Korea, not South Korea.
Scott: Just Korea.
Rym: I Guess that's a good thing.
Scott: I guess I mean are they putting on a show?
Rym: or I mean, I'm real pro South Korea I'm real leery of North Korea.
Rym: I'd like to see them unify in some sort of good way.
Scott: Yeah, that'd be good.
Rym: Yeah, at least you know, I think as long as they don't unify like in 2009 lost memories.
Scott: I think the real thing is is that yeah, they they want to win something.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: Yeah, that'd be good for national pride on both ends.
Rym: Yeah So my thing of the day is awesome, all right, it's Not anything cool on the internet.
Rym: It's just something that happened that I found deliciously ironic Mm-hmm.
Rym: So a green piece.
Scott: Oh Great.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh way back they got their ship the rainbow warrior and The French Secret Service blew it up Because green piece is awesome and the Secret Service decided they had to do something about them being awesome.
Rym: Great blow up their ship.
Scott: awesome.
Rym: They have a second ship the rainbow warrior - and they've been using it for a while.
Rym: They do stuff with it and They were out in the ocean.
Scott: What ocean doesn't matter.
Rym: They were out in the ocean.
Rym: There's some reefs and they pulled the boat up to these reefs to do a protest about people damaging the reefs.
Rym: They damn they screwed up and they rammed into the reef and caused a whole bunch of damage to it.
Rym: Great, and they got fined by the Mexican government $15,000 which they can't seem to pay.
Scott: they got plenty of money from people.
Scott: What the hell?
Rym: Yeah, I don't know the whole deal.
Rym: All I know is that they were you know saying they're gonna protect this reef and then they rammed their boat into it.
Rym: They're ugly rusting leaky Environmentally on the sound giant boat full of dirty hippies.
Scott: It's because they're not actually they're people who like lichen.
Rym: Yeah, they're not environmentalists.
Rym: Of course Environmentalists are rare nowadays because a lot of people are very.
Rym: they say they're pro-environment, but they don't actually understand what?
Rym: What any of that means like they'll be anti nuclear power Oh, but then they're also anti coal power, but then they're also anti hydroelectric.
Rym: and then how the hell do you want some?
Rym: Do you want any electricity?
Scott: Mm-hmm?
Rym: I don't know what they want.
Scott: They wanna there you go on your power But they don't really want that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, I don't think they really want that.
Scott: They don't.
Rym: so, uh, yeah They just say like wanted to use a word from the vernacular.
Rym: They're shit talkers.
Scott: They're definitely shit talkers.
Scott: Oh My thing of the day is so cool.
Scott: is this website?
Scott: 20 the number 20 - go to - 10. calm Uh-huh.
Scott: This guy made a website But his website looks like DOS like there's no links or anything.
Scott: It doesn't look like a normal website.
Scott: it like comes up in a new window, it looks like a terminal and There's a C colon in it and you type commands to look at the different parts of his webpage.
Rym: That's kind of cool.
Scott: I thought it was very very slick.
Scott: I should make one.
Scott: That's Linux II.
Rym: Make one.
Rym: that's just just make one.
Rym: That's a full Linux shell and hidden around it or thing.
Scott: Well, actually this website you can go to where it actually gives you a Linux desktop in your.
Rym: yeah You actually showed that to me.
Rym: Yeah You should probably pull.
Scott: actually I heard there's another company now where they'll give you a Linux desktop with storage space and you get an Account.
Scott: so basically it's like you're buying a computer.
Scott: you get a free computer and you can access it from any computer.
Rym: It's kind of handy.
Rym: Yeah, kind of cool.
Scott: You just keep things on the desktop there and you go to another computer and up There it is.
Scott: Yeah, if only it had a static IP or whatever.
Scott: you could really do stuff, yep All right.
Rym: So we talked a long time about things that aren't video games.
Scott: with how much time?
Scott: 25 minutes, that's good.
Scott: We can talk about video games.
Rym: for time We were always shooting for you know, 10 minutes of news and then getting right to the bit But it'll be a short bit.
Rym: 40 40 minutes is about the time totally were shooting for because I've only been playing one game And that's Castlevania DS which I beat.
Rym: and then I realized That there are multiple endings and it's not like the old Castlevania games where there's the bad ending words in black and white And then the good ending words in color and then the really good ending were like it's in color and then a hand appears at The end.
Scott: Yeah, that's the best ending.
Rym: So, uh to not spoil the game there is a point at which you can kill a dude and if you kill this dude the game ends and It's the lamest ending to a video game that there has ever been.
Rym: Like I felt less satisfaction from that ending that I felt from the ending of Mario 1.
Rym: Congratulations, you win and then you start over.
Rym: less than that.
Rym: Well nothing it was horrid And it was about 10 seconds long Awesome, and then there were some credits that I just I was so far.
Rym: I just turned the game off.
Scott: well
Rym: Then I discovered that you have to do some Regame facts to figure out how to do it thing or be Perceptive and you'll figure it out and then there's a whole nother game and the game keeps going for a long time And there's more stuff to do and then you get real endings.
Scott: That's just evil.
Scott: Yeah, because I would have stopped playing at the first ending.
Scott: It's been pissed.
Rym: I would have accepted if you're smart, you'll get the first ending and then you'll realize wait a minute What was that thing?
Rym: I wonder if I could have done a thing to it.
Rym: Mmm, the only reason that's a game facts thing is because if you don't have the thing to do the thing And you don't know where to get the thing that'll let you do the thing.
Rym: You'll think there's a thing I can do something to it and you won't know how and you won't be able to do it.
Scott: I hate games like that.
Rym: Yeah, that was prize.
Scott: I wonder if the Gameboy ones were like that also.
Rym: Well, they all have the same main character and they're basically the same plot thread.
Rym: apparently Mmm, and they're apparently rare and hard to find.
Scott: really I know people have them.
Rym: Oh, yeah a lot of people have them.
Rym: They're not super rare, but they didn't print or they didn't make so many of the Gameboy Castlevania cartridges.
Scott: The first one I know is common.
Rym: I don't know about the second one though Like they're not rare rare rare, but you won't find them for less than 20 bucks even.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Yeah Boxes don't have a good game.
Scott: You can't even get like Mario Kart Gameboy Advance for cheap.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's you know, it's it's a good game.
Scott: only the bad games are cheap.
Rym: So how's a Phoenix Wright coming?
Scott: I beat Phoenix, right?
Rym: Yeah, is it good?
Scott: He was excellent.
Scott: It's like Carmen San Diego, but better awesomer.
Scott: Apparently there are three Gameboy Advance games of Phoenix Wright in Japan.
Rym: Aha,
Scott: and this game for the DS is actually just a copy of the first GBA game and you can tell because the first four Episodes don't really involve the DS at all
Rym: Uh-huh,
Scott: and then the fifth extra episode is a special DS episode and it's come, you know It's got different characters and everything.
Rym: Ooh, so I imagine that we'll get more of these games.
Scott: The fifth episode is also the longest and I would say possibly In terms of plot, I don't think it's the best episode.
Scott: I think the fourth one would be the best in terms of plot Uh-huh, and the third would be the funniest but the fifth one was definitely the highest quality game There it get a lot of parts.
Scott: He just didn't know what to do.
Scott: I was stumped.
Scott: I had to try crazy things and there's a lot more evidence tons of evidence a lot more investigating interacting with the evidence.
Scott: You know, you know the evidence is like 3d.
Scott: you could rotate it and stuff and it's pretty cool Pretty cool.
Scott: But the ending is also kind of bleh.
Scott: And there's two.
Scott: this at the end of episode four after you beat it because it's like the game they don't need a big ending Because you know the game itself the plot of itself is.
Scott: it stands good, you know You don't need a big thing at the after the plot is over to do stuff.
Scott: But the end of episode four someone says, you know show this show the evidence that something something You know.
Scott: and you have to pick the really one chance and I picked the wrong one.
Scott: Episode five.
Scott: they do it again, but it's different and I picked the wrong one.
Scott: yeah, but apparently that only gets you like an extra sentence of content a Whole sentence.
Scott: Yeah, or two sentences.
Scott: It only gets you a tiny bit of content if you pick right.
Rym: see that's where Castlevania goes.
Rym: If you pick right you get a 20% bonus game.
Rym: It just keeps going and there's more.
Rym: get more stuff and more bosses.
Scott: Yeah, this you pick right.
Scott: it just changes the ending a tiny bit.
Scott: And I'd say the ending after episode four is a lot better than the ending of episode five.
Rym: Still a good game.
Scott: Very good game.
Scott: Everyone should get it.
Scott: I'm probably gonna get all of them if they come out with more.
Rym: once I finish Castlevania and kill Dracula again, I'll Trade up with you.
Scott: Yep Trauma Center, I actually I beat that hard hard hard mission.
Rym: haven't beat the game though Have you know?
Scott: and then there was a harder mission and then a harder mission and a harder mission.
Scott: I just brute-forced my way, but I'm not a mission again.
Scott: That's too hard.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: I can't play it on the train cuz it shakes.
Scott: So much of the thought of that when they made the DS.
Scott: you can't play it on anything.
Scott: You can't play it.
Scott: a car if you need precision for a game like Trauma Center with the stylus Can't play it in a car can't play it in train.
Scott: Maybe a plane with no turbulence, but if it shakes you can't play.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think they were thinking specifically of your commute when they made that game.
Scott: But I mean they had there's a picture on the Nintendo DS website of a kid in the subway playing.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you can play every other game that way.
Scott: Yeah, you can play a lot of games that way.
Scott: You play Phoenix Wright easily.
Scott: Yeah, just not trauma center.
Rym: So we picked up siphon filter and Gran Turismo 2 for our modded ps1.
Scott: that until now Fine it's Japanese there you go, but we can play English Huh?
Rym: I wonder why it has only ever played dance dance revolution.
Scott: So when we went to the GameStop and we saw the ps1 games like two bucks We figured might as well play those games.
Scott: You never played right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yep, and I learned that.
Rym: Well, I guess I remembered that the PlayStation one is graphics are kind of crappy.
Scott: If you play it with an emulator, they can improve.
Scott: it improves the or not.
Rym: We're playing it.
Scott: I don't play a ps1 game and a ps2.
Scott: Does it improve the graphics?
Scott: I don't think so I heard maybe it did.
Scott: maybe didn't.
Scott: maybe that's one of those things that Sony lied about and then changed up.
Scott: You know, yeah, I never heard anything about it.
Rym: So Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Yeah So siphon filter.
Scott: actually I play the game and I could tell it's a good game, but it makes you really Realize how far games have come.
Scott: Yeah, the control of the game is is painful Like to switch weapons.
Scott: you hold select and you do LR and l2.
Scott: Ah, or you can just push select to cycle through.
Rym: See that's.
Rym: the one thing I really like about the GameCube is that it's so much more intuitive that kind of control I mean all PlayStation games because there's so many buttons and they're not a B X Y or one two, three, four five.
Rym: They're shape shape shape shape.
Scott: I guess we get used to the shape shape shape shape.
Rym: Yeah, but it's also hard that Japanese games and English games reverse the function of X and O.
Scott: I think in Gran Turismo 2 X and O do the same thing and square is go back.
Rym: Yeah, see that's the thing.
Rym: There's no consistency and every Nintendo game ever a is select and B is go back.
Scott: Yeah, that's the way it is.
Rym: Plus I learned that I can't play driving games without a wheel.
Scott: You just suck.
Scott: I played it just fine cuz I don't like.
Rym: driving is not the wheel.
Rym: It doesn't seem.
Rym: it's not a driving game anymore it's a Manipulate the analog stick precisely game.
Scott: Yeah, what do you think with the wheel?
Scott: It's the same thing only instead of a stick.
Scott: You've got a wheel.
Rym: Yeah, which makes it driving.
Scott: No, one of those bugs you said only shows up in my room is in your room.
Rym: Yeah, there's more of them.
Rym: your room total.
Scott: Yeah, well there aren't.
Rym: haven't been any my room for weeks so I'll put it in your room then that'll even things out.
Scott: That's no good That's definitely not good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, uh, what are the games?
Rym: So you ever been playing so many games?
Rym: we're busy doing you know life.
Scott: I'm playing plenty of games Just playing the same games a lot.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I started playing cuz I. actually it's my secret shame.
Rym: I never played Ocarina of Time, yeah, so I'm playing through it now, but I haven't played it in like two weeks because I've been busy.
Scott: Yeah, I'm playing Resident Evil 1 But I haven't played that in a while cuz it DS games kind of got me and as soon as Mario Kart comes out every Other game is just gonna be like play me play me play me.
Scott: Sorry Mario Kart is here.
Scott: I Played my GBA Mario Kart to rebuild my skills.
Scott: I Still got it.
Rym: I imagine the game will be different enough to where your skills won't carry over so much.
Scott: I played it.
Scott: I played Mario Kart DS at the digital life show.
Scott: Yeah, and my skills carry over quite well, you're all in trouble.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: We'll see it.
Scott: The one thing I don't know is that in Mario Kart gameboy Super Circuit if you're racing is perfect Items can't bother you.
Scott: even the spike shell will just go right behind you and if you don't slow down you stay at top speed.
Scott: The spike shell will not get you.
Scott: I don't know if that's the case.
Scott: in Mario Kart DS the spike shell might get you no matter what because that's the way it Is.
Scott: that's a in n64 and double dash?
Scott: The the items and luck matter a lot more than rich pure racing.
Rym: Honestly, I didn't like double dash.
Rym: I didn't like it so much like the two-player - I mean I'm not one to call things Nintendo does gimmicky because I like most of the things they do.
Rym: but the two guys in one car thing was real gimmicky because it always ended up just being the one guy who's good drives and The friend who's not so good at the game just sits there with the items and goes L R L R L R L R.
Scott: Well, the thing is is that you were supposed it was up to the other person to give you this boost by shifting the weight.
Rym: Yeah, but that is no.
Rym: that was pretty much just brain dead.
Rym: And if you couldn't it was such a basic thing to do properly that you could play the game where you just controlled You know everything.
Scott: but then switching the drivers was kind of yeah.
Scott: I do like the the not having.
Scott: you can actually change carts.
Scott: like there's different carts And the DS one has that where you pick a person you pick a cart.
Rym: Oh, I like that.
Scott: Yeah, at least that's what it looked like to me You know, but yeah, it's good cuz I'll pick Luigi and I'll pick the standard Luigi cart and I'll rock everybody.
Rym: Cuz.
Rym: no game has ever really surpassed that wonderful level of ice hockey.
Scott: for the original NES I will a smash and if I a smash enough you will be put in the penalty box and not me.
Rym: that game is Probably one of my favorite multiplayer games ever.
Scott: do they need to make an online version of ice hockey?
Rym: Ah, we could make it.
Scott: we could actually I guess if you use emulators.
Scott: they play over on the internet But kind of piss poorly that's cuz.
Scott: what they do is instead of having like a ROM and synchronizing it What they do is they just send the controls that you push over the network Yep, and you each run your own local copy of the ROM.
Rym: So if anything gets out of whack the whole thing is just crazy and broken and you're done.
Scott: Yep, and they don't use the PIP and they don't you know?
Rym: set the timings perfectly Yeah, and normally when we talk about a game that we play multiplayer Both of us will contend that we're the best ever.
Rym: Some sort of argument.
Rym: but at ice hockey.
Rym: We've pretty much fought each other to a dead Stalemate on the best ever.
Scott: haven't lost a long time.
Rym: We haven't played in a long time and I won the last time.
Scott: We didn't win last time.
Rym: I was definitely.
Scott: no you didn't Not at all.
Rym: I'll throw some witnesses.
Rym: next time we play we'll have to have some certified witnesses sitting there Start keeping score and like a website.
Rym: I mean, yeah, we should plus you can't deny Uh air hockey at the shore.
Scott: Hey air hockey.
Scott: I pooned um.
Rym: Do I need to remind you how many games I won how many games you won during the week at wild?
Scott: Yeah, I won and then you waited until I was tired from you But okay And then you wanted to play some more and then we played.
Scott: uh, and then whenever I wanted to play cuz I was ready To win you were like no and then you played later when you were ready to.
Rym: not only is that not true That's true.
Rym: I got witnesses.
Rym: Yeah, I got Greg or not?
Rym: Greg God.
Rym: I haven't Greg's dead as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: I got Pete.
Scott: Yeah the sign it said he wasn't dead.
Rym: Yeah, but I haven't seen him or talked to him and I've messaged him a couple times.
Rym: He never answers me.
Scott: Mm-hmm Maybe he's pretended to be dead like a possum.
Rym: Ah But I got Pete.
Rym: I got a katsu.
Rym: I got some Alex.
Scott: I Changed his mind.
Rym: See he wouldn't take a bribe for something like that.
Scott: Yeah, he would.
Rym: no not for something like that.
Rym: cuz he'd say first he'd take the bribe.
Rym: then when someone asked him He'd say yeah Scott totally bribed me to say that he was the best.
Scott: So yeah, so then why would he lie and say you wanted air hockey unless you bribed him?
Rym: Cuz I do win at air hockey.
Scott: He or you just bribed Scott Johnson to say so and then say something like that and then you can't bribe Scott Johnson.
Rym: He's like a rock.
Rym: That's what someone who bribes him says All right, what about Pete and Alex and Don?
Scott: Ton wasn't paying attention as far as I know.
Rym: No Don was there.
Scott: I don't think she was noticing our air hockey scores Only I was uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, I think we're done.
Rym: Yeah So, uh, we were thinking of adding a bit to the show.
Scott: Oh, oh we tell a story.
Rym: where we tell a story?
Rym: Because we realized that in all the years in college We told a lot of funny stories and all of us had a bunch of good stories and some of them were uproariously hilarious.
Rym: Well, we can only ever tell him once unless we were made new friends.
Rym: Yeah, and whenever a new friend joined the group we told all the stories again immediately and Now we got a whole bunch of new friends or at least people people podcast listen, yeah.
Rym: So, uh, we're thinking and we might start telling some stories.
Scott: tell my what.
Scott: how much minutes did we go so far?
Rym: Ah, it's been 40 minutes.
Rym: So if we tell a story to be a quick one, he already told your diarrhea story.
Scott: Does that count?
Rym: that was that was a story you used up all of our leader time to tell us about how you?
Rym: Had diarrhea this morning.
Rym: I'm sure everyone's gonna love that.
Scott: Hey, it could be a worse story.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: 30 bargles.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, all right.
Rym: All right, that's our story.
Scott: then since this is the uh, tell the story tomorrow Often.
Rym: oh you got a star so I'll get a story.
Rym: This will be our daily SIG.
Rym: It'll be a long say.
Rym: It'll be a story unless you have a better SIG.
Scott: No, we're good.
Rym: So, uh Got some food poisoning.
Rym: I'm not really sure what it was.
Rym: They gave me the food poisoning, but something gave me the food poisoning and I believe you were awake into the sound of me vomiting 30 times in one night.
Scott: Definitely vomiting very loud.
Scott: It definitely keeping me awake.
Rym: It was awesome.
Rym: I Wake up and vomit and then I diarrhea and then I'd lay in my bed.
Scott: then I'd wake up then I'd vomit diarrhea lay in My bed now, I wasn't the one vomiting but I was very unhappy from Waking up so many times and hearing the bargaining and your bedroom is fairly far away from the base very far away You were.
Rym: you're bargaining very loud But was very loud because after a while There was nothing left to borrow the one.
Scott: the only good thing that came out of this for me was Knowing that Rym was in pain of bargaining.
Rym: Yeah We'll see what happens when I give you some more Yankee Clipper lasagna, you know what I'm not.
Scott: the Yankee Clipper is great But I'm not eating lasagna there anymore.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I had diarrhea the last time I ate their lasagna.
Scott: In fact, why don't we just go to the Yankee Clipper for breakfast only and go to the 84 for dinner?
Scott: That sounds like a plan cuz they have those nice potato skins.
Rym: Yeah, but honestly, I do like the Yankee Clippers breakfast better.
Scott: I do like their.
Scott: they have the.
Scott: they have the banana waffle.
Rym: The only thing they don't have is my favorite meal the Belgian waffle with every kind of breakfast meat That might make you bargo Every time I've gone.
Scott: how many times did you bargo that night?
Rym: Oh, oh, it was like 19 or 20.
Rym: It wasn't actually 30, but it was like 19 or 20 awesome.
Rym: It was the second worst I've ever been sick to my stomach.
Scott: Oh, you could tell the first words tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, we'll tell that story another day All right, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the music and promotional consideration was provided by no one.