Scott: It's Tuesday November 7th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discussed the awesome board game Ultraman.
Scott: Let's do this Today.
Rym: I interacted with the federal government in the only legal way I have to change the federal government.
Scott: I did so as well a few minutes prior to you doing so.
Rym: yeah, it was funny.
Rym: I drove home from work And I kind of went the back mountain way because that goes right into beacon.
Rym: so I could stop and vote On the way home and sure enough I get there to vote and I see Scott about four people ahead of me in line.
Scott: Yeah, it was kind of annoying.
Scott: last time I didn't know what ward and district I was in and I had a little map and I just found myself on the map and I found out that I was in.
Scott: I think Like district 3 Ward 1 or Ward 1 district 3.
Scott: I forget what or which one is Ward 3 district 1.
Scott: It's 3 - 1. that's all I got to know.
Scott: But this time they didn't have the map.
Scott: so it was really kind of hectic and people had to keep at.
Scott: there had to be Someone.
Scott: they're telling you which frickin voting machine to use.
Scott: Annoying.
Rym: you see I walked in and there was a lady standing at the door, and she said what's your address?
Rym: And I said my address.
Scott: that lady wasn't at the door when I got there.
Rym: good game.
Rym: Yeah, though more importantly There's a proposition up for vote in beacon that I have feelings about and it seems like all the hippies in town and old people Have opposite feelings about.
Rym: yeah It's this thing about.
Rym: the city wants to borrow a million dollars in order to buy a bunch of land so developers can't develop on It and I don't want to get into how stupid this thing actually was and it's not at all a good idea.
Rym: but the point is old people and hippies are really for it and It's almost all old people local volunteers running the election.
Scott: Yeah, there was one semi young lady who looked like someone's mom and There was some other lady, but everyone else was a senior citizen usually female.
Rym: Well, there's that one black lady who seemed to be the head official at this event.
Rym: Okay, she knew what she was doing.
Rym: she was telling people what to do and directing everything.
Scott: That's cool.
Rym: And I noticed while I was standing in line that a few of the old people kept mentioning to people right before they walked in.
Rym: don't forget to vote for the proposition at the top and They were really phrasing it in a way to try to get people to vote yes, and finally that this election official notices this and Starts yelling at one of the old ladies about how what she's doing is a violation of federal law and all sorts of things.
Rym: She's gonna kick her out.
Rym: She doesn't stop it.
Rym: She's influencing the vote.
Rym: It's a terrible thing to do and the lady got all kind of indignant and I saw her talking with all the other old ladies A few minutes later while I was still in line about.
Rym: she shouldn't tell me what to do.
Scott: I can tell people how to vote if I want and yeah, there's nothing I can't stand more than people being indignant Even if they're right, it's like don't be indignant god damn it.
Rym: Yeah, I got stories about indignant people.
Rym: I should probably save all of them.
Scott: You know, there's not short of just outright evil people like crazy Genocidal killers.
Scott: I think the number one personality trait I dislike is indignancy.
Rym: now remember There's a fine line between asserting your rights and being indignant.
Rym: We could probably do a whole Thursday describing exactly what the differences are.
Scott: We probably could but that's besides the point.
Rym: Yeah, I think the most indignant person I ever saw in my life Was waiting in line to get over the Lewiston bridge into Canada on my way home for the holidays many years ago.
Scott: You know, I think I don't like indignancies because it's the exact opposite of personal responsibility.
Scott: You know You're either saying I didn't do anything wrong when you did or or you're saying it's okay for me to do something wrong.
Scott: You know, no one can tell.
Scott: you know, everything I do is perfect.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, no one can tell me anything.
Rym: It's always the.
Rym: you're not the boss of me Yeah, but yeah at least luckily I'm pretty sure our votes got counted because there's no d-bold anywhere near our election.
Scott: No, we use my favorite style of voting machine, which is sadly when I was a kid.
Scott: These are the kind of voting machines that were used in my town and I'm pretty sure they still are.
Rym: They're the ones that were used back where I grew up because I remember going in with my mom when she voted.
Scott: Okay, not only are they incredibly fun to vote in but I don't see how they're so fun.
Scott: You get to pull this lever and a curtain closes behind you and then you go click click click click And then you put lever again I could make a lever that closed the curtains if you wanted.
Rym: dude I would sit there all day pulling the lever put a bunch of buttons on it with different names next to the buttons and Don't do that.
Scott: I'll be in trouble.
Scott: We'll go to work.
Scott: Yeah No, but the other thing about this machine that I never actually realized before because they never paid attention Is that you can't pull the lever unless the election official pushes a button on the outside of the machine?
Scott: So if you try to go into the machine and like pull the lever vote Pull the lever two times and vote again It won't work because you won't be able to put lever be until the person on the outside pushes a button.
Rym: Now it seemed that there were really two kinds of people voting.
Rym: I noticed a lot of people who I'm pretty sure had never voted before or something because you know Most people would get in line and you know, they'd be their turn.
Rym: they walk in they pull the lever and then they unpull the lever Like a minute later.
Rym: at most.
Scott: I think they're just slow.
Rym: No, no, no, but some people would walk in and kind of stand there not really sure what to do And they try to move a lever like not the lever But the voting switches they wouldn't move and they tap at it and they look around.
Rym: then by then the election official walk around And pull the lever for him to shut the curtain.
Scott: Yep I think it's just that a lot of people aren't smart and even if they do it every year every few years It's like they don't remember how the stupid thing works.
Scott: They just can't figure out machines at all.
Scott: Like Lewis Black said he's not mechanical.
Rym: There's a big sign right next to the lever.
Rym: It says pull lever to these people who barely make selections.
Rym: when finished pull lever in opposite direction Curtain will open.
Scott: these people are barely literate.
Scott: You can't expect too much from them.
Rym: Luckily.
Rym: The machine doesn't let you fuck up.
Rym: Yeah vote for too many people.
Scott: Yeah, if you try to vote for like You know a for governor and also vote for B for governor you click down.
Scott: BA pops up.
Scott: This machine is perfect in every way for voting.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: The thing is the company that makes these machines has been out of business for as long as I have lived.
Scott: I think like I remember when I would be like in kindergarten I go to vote with my mom and they would talk about how these machines are no longer made and no one knew how to maintain them or anything But they still work because they're so awesome and purely mechanical computers.
Rym: It's just kind of like the difference in the state of voting in America at this point bothers me a lot.
Rym: I mean I saw a survey recently that a Very large number of Americans have no confidence at all that their votes are actually counted properly anymore.
Scott: Yeah, I have confidence in that machine because it is a mechanical machine that will function even if the power is out.
Scott: Do I have confidence that the people reading the numbers on those machines will report them correctly and send them to the right place?
Rym: Probably I don't think the thing is at least that's so distributed that it would take a lot of people working together To pull off a conspiracy.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, a few places could mess up easily or purposefully screw things up, but it would take a mass crazy Improbable conspiracy to do it everywhere in a significant fashion.
Rym: That's how I feel when it comes to Anything that you need to protect like voting or something where there is the chance that someone could do something shady or have a conspiracy Among other people to change the results.
Scott: Yeah, like the person who sends the forms to the election whatever for the state Just change, you know, oh no this many people voted for so-and-so.
Rym: Yeah well No but my point is that the best way to prevent crazy conspiracies from happening is to involve a Lot of people in the process in incremental menial ways.
Rym: that way in order to actually pull off conspiracy you need so many people involved all of whom now have to keep this secret and the more people involved the more likely it is Someone's gonna go to Fox News and tell a story.
Scott: I don't think this Fox News is gonna put up the story.
Rym: They would Fox News Remember they may lean to the right, but I don't think that is any part of ideology.
Rym: I think it's simply money.
Rym: Yeah, CNN leans a little bit to the left for money.
Rym: BBC leans a little bit toward Britain for money.
Scott: Well, BBC isn't make money because they're funded by the state.
Scott: They make money sort of like NPR and PR doesn't do it for the BBC sells DVDs and things.
Scott: Yeah, but that's that's sort of like to you know to get more make it so they have to tax the Britain's less.
Scott: Of course, they still tax on the high heaven.
Rym: Anyway, I like how you call them the Britain's.
Scott: what else am I gonna call them?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: United Kingdom.
Scott: errs al Bien ers al Bien ites.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right, so do we got in the news?
Scott: So muzzah city mother three for those of you who don't speak crazy Scott aka earthbound 3 because if you don't know there's a game called earthbound, which is an awesome RPG That came out in Japan for the NES.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't come out in the u.s.
Scott: For the NES.
Rym: It quickly gained a cult following in Japan.
Rym: Yeah, then it came over to America and gained an even larger.
Rym: Well, it didn't.
Scott: the NES didn't come to America.
Rym: Oh the SNES one.
Scott: right and that game was called mother the game.
Scott: then there was a game called mother 2 for the SNES And they released that one in the US and they called it earthbound now.
Rym: They're both.
Rym: I mean, they're the same game.
Rym: Effectively just it's on the SNES.
Rym: So it's longer and better.
Scott: Yeah, the NES one it's good to go look at it just to see but there's no point in playing it.
Rym: You know what play it because the first five minutes are great.
Rym: You're a little kid.
Scott: There's no point in playing the whole thing.
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Rym: It's a fun game.
Scott: The NES one.
Rym: Yeah, I played through a good half of it Maybe but you start in a room and then you hear weird noises.
Rym: So you try to walk over to your door and suddenly the lamp on the table that you thought was a background item Just suddenly jumps out and attacks your ass.
Scott: It's funny because you get on the street you fight hippies.
Scott: Yeah, like literally it looks like a hippie and it says the word hippie.
Rym: But yeah earthbound is where Ness came from.
Rym: for those of you who aren't so up He played Smash Brothers.
Scott: you seen Ness and you see his little town.
Scott: That's earthbound because mother 2 in Japan for the SNES is the same game as earthbound for the SNES in the US.
Rym: now pretty much Immediately after earthbound came out all the cult fans in America were saying is there ever gonna be another one?
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's so awesome.
Scott: now in Japan There is a GBA cartridge for a Game Boy Advance game that contains mother 1 & 2 on a single GBA cartridge.
Scott: This does not exist in the United States bastards.
Scott: About seven months ago a game called mother 3 was released for the Game Boy Advance in Japan.
Scott: It turns out that the odds of mother 3 getting an official English translation and being sold in the United States Are decreasing rapidly and you can you might as well give up on it right now.
Scott: It's it's the end.
Scott: I think the guy says He wouldn't look forward to a mother 3 translation in the immediate future.
Scott: Adding that none of the writers are currently working on one though.
Scott: Maybe some of the translators that did not work for him may be in discussion So they haven't even started working on this thing.
Scott: You know what I envision?
Scott: If they were doing it they probably would have been working on it already.
Rym: My guess and I'll bet that within two years this happens that two years from now or so They'll release a DS cart that has mother 1 2 & 3 on it.
Scott: They got to put this shit I'm telling you I think Virtual console virtual consoles where we're gonna see at least earthbound for the SNES on the virtual console.
Scott: Regardless there is a mother 3 fan translation project.
Rym: I'm a big fan of fans lations.
Scott: now what these people are doing is they have a Game Boy Advance Programmer a Game Boy Advance programming is actually pretty not too complicated and they have some translators.
Scott: And what they're doing is they're translating the game then they are creating a patch.
Scott: Not they're not gonna give you the ROM for mother 3.
Scott: They're making a program or a patch that you apply to the ROM from mother 3 Which you get from somewhere else to create a new GBA ROM that is translated mother 3. when you will then Play this ROM in some sort of Game Boy emulator or maybe you'll put it on a GBA flash cart and then put that in your GBA or Maybe you'll turn it into a DS ROM and put that in your DS Flash cart and play it on your DS or who knows what you'll do with it.
Scott: But that is currently your best bet for playing mother 3 in English, but it's not done yet.
Rym: It's cool that they're doing it the same way.
Rym: It used to be done back in the day I mean, I remember when I when emulation started getting really big and I got an SNES emulator that actually worked and I found ROMs for Final Fantasy 5 a game that I've never seen or played or anything and There were people out there who did the same thing for that that they're doing now for mother.
Rym: They made patches that would translate the game and I beat Final Fantasy 5 way way way back because of these awesome people Mm-hmm.
Scott: I love me.
Scott: some translation action.
Rym: Yeah, fans who do things like this just for the love of the game?
Scott: It's basically a fan sub of a video game when you think about it Except it's just a lot harder to do than a fan sub of an anime.
Rym: is it's better than that?
Rym: It's more pure in that the way they're doing it.
Rym: It doesn't facilitate you pirating the thing.
Scott: It'd be like if fan subbers just released subtitle tracks and you had to go get the Japanese DVD and then put the subtitles attached to it.
Scott: Yeah I Think really what it is is they just want to keep their site from getting shut down?
Scott: and if they do it this way The site won't get shut down and the ROM isn't hard to find Whereas if fan subbers only put out subtitle patches or equivalent it would be pretty hard to find the.
Scott: you know The raws.
Rym: I'm not saying that things should change in the anime industry.
Rym: I'm just saying that at least You can point at these people and say that we are sure they are doing this purely for the love of the game and not For any other reason.
Scott: I just find it really.
Scott: I I continue to fail to understand why There are these obvious and simple ways to make money and these for profit video game companies.
Scott: Do not release games in America.
Scott: Look at every time they've done it.
Scott: Phoenix, right?
Rym: Katamari Right would do well at all.
Rym: Yeah, and then it's sold out immediately.
Scott: All these games that are Japan only They don't bring about in the u.s.
Scott: Because I don't know what fucking reason they're just too damn lazy.
Scott: And then when the few times they actually do it's a super mega hit and they make a hajillion dollars Fucking bring every game here.
Scott: Japan should get the fucking shaft.
Scott: They don't buy.
Scott: they only buy his freaking RPGs.
Scott: They don't buy all these.
Scott: FPS is in crap.
Rym: Yeah, the people get there.
Rym: barely buy an Xbox 360s over there, but people here want the RPGs more than anything.
Scott: That's what we want.
Scott: Well, I don't necessarily want the RPGs so much But the thing is the RPGs that I might actually buy are the ones we don't get.
Scott: The RPGs that we actually get are the ones I don't care about.
Scott: there are plenty of cool Japanese RPGs that I might possibly Want.
Rym: see what I want are all those Japanese adventure games, which is very different from American adventure games.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a choose your own adventure.
Rym: Not a Just very very complex.
Scott: choose your own adventure story kind of I forgot to tell you Dave from Dave and Joel He mentioned quest for glory Really?
Scott: Yeah, he apparently played it.
Scott: Like he said it just like Sutton quest for glory something, but then I was like, aha You know what?
Rym: He is now in my top 50 list of people ever.
Scott: Yeah, cuz not many gonna send him an email You know what?
Rym: In fact, I want to ask all of our listeners out there How many of you out there have actually played more than one quest for glory?
Scott: How many who've played any quest for glory game or even heard of one heard of a game called quest for glory?
Rym: I mean these are probably some of the greatest games to come out of the 80s and 90s for the PC.
Scott: Like I know of them, but I never actually played them all the way through.
Rym: It seems like many most people haven't played him But everyone who has played him is usually a lot older than me for one and to absolutely love them There's really no middle ground.
Scott: also cool.
Scott: I haven't known any uncool people who knew or played quest for glory.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of like people who played King's Quest even though that was a lot more widespread.
Scott: That was a lot more widespread, but quest for glory even though better.
Rym: now, yeah quest for glory I mean King's Quest games were fun, but they weren't the greatest games Especially later on the the other quest games are much better like Space Quest Police Quest.
Scott: Police Quest is the freaking best quest game.
Rym: Yeah hard as fuck though.
Scott: Yeah I only played one of them the one we like it's.
Scott: it's always cool cuz you're in the police station with the elevator To the different floors or you do different stuff.
Scott: It's it's way cool.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, yeah, maybe I'll have to do a show about quest for glory and police quest Just a show about asterisk quest.
Rym: That's a really good idea because Also all those LucasArts adventure games.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Um, yeah, but yeah, Japanese adventure games are not like LucasArts adventure games.
Scott: They're more like choose your own adventure books kind of like Phoenix, right?
Scott: That's that's like a Japanese adventure game pretty much.
Rym: So I probably don't need to tell all of you this but from my news is very simply that Child's Play the penny arcade charity for children and hospitals has launched for this year.
Scott: Give money to kiddies so that they could play video games before they get sick and possibly die.
Rym: We're not gonna really set up any sort of GeekNights direct fund because penny arcade certainly doesn't need our help now.
Scott: We'll put a little banner on our site in case you can't find Child's Play.
Rym: Yeah, but all I want to say is that all of you out there if you can spare it It's really worthwhile to donate to this.
Rym: I have donated every year whatever piddly amount I could afford to donate.
Scott: Yeah, I think I was actually our local hospitals.
Scott: The one Rym works at the Montefiore.
Rym: It is in fact one of the hospitals I work at.
Rym: it is actually a very large children's hospital.
Rym: I've met many of the children who have been there.
Scott: Yeah anyway I was looking at that because there's two ways you can give to Child's Play.
Scott: way number one is just give money straight up through PayPal.
Scott: if you do that Then they just make a big pool of money and they distribute it evenly to all the hospitals.
Scott: The other way is you pick a specific hospital and each specific hospital has an Amazon wish list of stuff which might be video games, but also might be toys and other things and You can buy a specific thing for that hospital.
Scott: So if you go and look at say Montefiore Hospital and apparently some kid there really wants to play.
Scott: I don't know some GBA Naruto game or something.
Scott: you can specifically buy that game because that's what you want to give them.
Rym: in the coming weeks I'm going to try to get in touch with the person at the hospitals I work at who is the contact for this charity and hopefully I'll be able to actually work with this firsthand.
Rym: So I might be able to give you guys a lot more specific information as to what's really needed.
Scott: Yeah, I think I saw in one of the Amazon wish lists a Fisher-Price pirate boat.
Scott: Ooh, I was all about because I was like damn.
Scott: I wish I had that when I was a kid because Fisher-Price Main Street was hot shit.
Scott: But there was no Fisher-Price pirate ship when I was a kid.
Rym: Honestly, I'll probably just donate money this year.
Scott: Yeah, I totally.
Scott: if I had a kid I would totally get the Fisher-Price pirate ship.
Scott: I kind of want it now.
Scott: Maybe let's go to Toys R Us.
Rym: I'll get it You want to.
Rym: we might have a little bit.
Rym: We might have a free weekend coming up.
Scott: Yeah We're not doing anything this weekend.
Scott: quite possibly Oh Noah's.
Rym: so yeah Child's Play is a wonderful thing.
Rym: I recommend you donate to it.
Rym: Even if you don't like penny arcade though I don't think there is anyone out there who doesn't like penny arcade.
Scott: Oh, wait I just want to mention the other purpose of Child's Play.
Scott: I think Possibly one of the original purposes was that people are hating the media in general hates a lot on video gamers and as a Stereotype of couch potatoes who are sitting there all degenerate and such not.
Scott: So the part of the point of Child's Play is not just to help children in need because video games help sick Sick children, which they actually do help sick children by distracting them from their pain.
Scott: But it also makes gamers not look like degenerates who sit on the couch all day twiddling their thumbs Even though many of you are many of you are but fight the stereo.
Scott: There are enough of us who aren't that we can get hundreds of thousands of dollars together every year.
Rym: things of the day Snaps.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So this is called Mario's life and it's it's looks at first glance like one of those You know sad clown flipping flapjacks Licking.
Rym: a girl art house kid in college made this film for a grade film.
Scott: I generally like to watch those movies just because they're different from normal movies But most of them honestly aren't good or entertaining.
Rym: Well, it's really weird It's you know, it starts out like one of those weird kind of.
Rym: oh something's going on.
Rym: This is a an art house film.
Rym: Aha, you know sad music's playing the background.
Rym: This guy's laying in bed staring at a clock blinking 12.
Rym: He gets up and slowly goes through this ritual of getting dressed and then suddenly part of it Is that he puts on a big fake mustache and then the mario 1 music starts playing and he goes about his daily life And it is nothing but hilarious.
Scott: so it starts out as an art house movie and then becomes a YouTube movie.
Rym: pretty much my favorite part is when he gets the Star and is invincible.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good part.
Scott: I like the part where he sees Luigi on the bridge.
Rym: Yep Now the cool thing is at the end.
Rym: It goes back to the scary crazy sad art house thing.
Rym: Oh Yeah, it's kind of comes full circle.
Scott: You think there's some sort of social commentary going on here?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I could make up a whole bunch of social commentary I'll stick with.
Scott: it talks about the escapism of video games and how you know Runaway from our shitty lives into these fantasy worlds and blah blah blah Yeah.
Rym: Or at the same time we play video games so much that while because we're escaping it ends up affecting our real lives.
Rym: We end up living our real life in the escape world And then we live what we see is a fake life in the real world, or maybe it's just a silly video on YouTube?
Rym: Maybe maybe it's pretty funny.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: It's definitely better than banana spider eating a grub.
Scott: Yeah Alright.
Scott: so I don't know how many people who know this but there are some karate guys out there and they think that through the power of he or some say she that they can do such things as Knock you out just by touching one part of your body.
Rym: now These people have videos all over the place professing to prove their power where one of them will go up to another one and go like And then the guy will just go and fall over.
Scott: Yep, they all some of them are even crazier and they think that they can knock you out without touching you.
Scott: They just yell at you or put their hands at you and then you fall over and don't wake up.
Rym: They stand there in kind of a hadouken pose.
Scott: Yeah So one of these guys who thinks he can do this is George Dillman Who is some he is.
Scott: I mean this guy is a badass karate guy and if you tried to fight him He'd probably beat you up.
Scott: He does know real martial arts of fighting.
Scott: I don't know cuz he also seems to think he knows crazy martial arts of non-existent like dim bach Yeah, that sort of stuff.
Scott: So National Geographic went and videotaped these guys and in this video, you're gonna see a whole lot of people getting knocked out without being touched.
Scott: now pretty much the explanation is By those guys is that this do using his magical ki powers?
Scott: The real explanation these people are expecting to be knocked out and they're essentially Suggested to.
Scott: as in the way hypnotism works, which is not a hundred percent Well understood but is well understood enough that there's not ki power.
Rym: Of course many of the people involved are most likely just faking it straight up to not look bad or get embarrassed.
Scott: Yep Now at the end of the video comes the interesting part Which is sort of sad because it's only the last minute of this video and that is where this awesome Science guy comes up and he says alright try to knock me out without touching me and it totally doesn't work
Rym: at all.
Rym: he just stands there with a smirk on his face while the guys like Nothing happens.
Scott: Yep, because it's a Bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: What's sad?
Rym: What's really sad is this magic karate guys explanation for why it didn't work.
Scott: That is the funny part which I'm not going to spoil.
Scott: That is the reason to watch.
Scott: this video is the very last bit where the karate guy Explains why the science guy wasn't knocked out.
Scott: the other the thick.
Scott: one thing I ain't gonna spoil is that he says he's a non Believer.
Scott: so what if I don't believe I'm gonna be knocked out?
Scott: your magic karate powers don't work then what the hell's the point?
Rym: Yeah, no muggers gonna believe that shit.
Scott: and if I believe you can knock me out without touching me I'm not gonna fight you.
Scott: so he's admitting his own power is useless.
Scott: But then he has some other explanations which are hilarious.
Rym: now the way the other explanations go.
Rym: I am now pretty much a hundred percent convinced that the guy isn't just a Misguided guy who thinks he has something cool.
Rym: I'm pretty sure he is a straight-up and fully aware charlatan.
Scott: I'm giving it an 80% chance of charlatanism going on here.
Rym: Maybe he'll listen to the show and I'll call in and maybe we can get him to try to do this to us.
Scott: Somehow I doubt it.
Scott: I mean he didn't even do it himself for National Geographic.
Scott: He had his top student do it instead of himself.
Rym: Yeah, he'll do it on his own students, but not on you or me, yeah Yeah, right.
Rym: so we decided we'd get back to our board game roots a bit and talk about a board game that we played at Uber con.
Scott: the game is called ultra mayor.
Scott: Oh L. T. R. E space M. A. R. E.
Rym: I've seen it without the space.
Scott: Yeah, I've also seen it without the space.
Scott: It's also known as merchants of Venice or ultra mayor - merchants of Venice.
Scott: Donut confuse this with the other game merchants of Venus, which this is not God.
Rym: Yeah, I'll bet that one came second.
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: Yeah, it's put up by Rio Grande, which they've made many of the games.
Rym: We like yep.
Scott: I think the designer is a man.
Rym: well or Nella has he made anything else we've played.
Scott: That's a good question.
Scott: Let me open that up here while you say something.
Rym: Well, you see most of the people who make the games we like are very German with very German sounding names.
Rym: I mean is yeah, yep, Iman.
Scott: well or Naya has made fantasy pub Hair my gore.
Rym: has he made anything we care about?
Scott: ill Prince it I think I've heard of that one.
Scott: But ultra mayor is by far his most popular game.
Scott: just looking at the board game geek rankings Ultra mayor is number one seven four and his second most popular game ill Prince it is four twelve.
Scott: The next one is six seventy eight and the next one is twelve seventeen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, this is most popular game.
Scott: He's no Knizia and it says here that it takes two to five players and the box says it lasts 60 minutes.
Scott: But I say if you playing with us and you don't suck it won't take nearly that long.
Rym: now this is one of those games and there seem to be a number of games like this that are out or have been out in many In the last five or six years where you'll have a lot of cards and while it's on a board and it acts like a Board game.
Rym: It's really more of a card game and furthermore the cards are Multipurpose.
Rym: they'll have a whole bunch of different stuff on them and depending on when you use the card and how The different stuff matters at different times and does different things.
Scott: Yeah, there's really two important things in this game and that is the cards.
Scott: it's a card drafting game kind of like ticket to ride with the card drafting and It's a trading game.
Scott: and it's not a trading game like like settlers where you can trade and the option is there or like traders of Genoa where trading is there and you can Do it but you don't have to.
Scott: it's a game where trading is sort of mandatory with a pretty clever system.
Rym: Yeah, except that I'll note that in the game we played there was almost no trading.
Rym: everyone would say, you know what fuck you I'm just not gonna trade because I know it's gonna screw you.
Scott: But at the same time I traded as often as I possibly could and I won.
Rym: I came in a close second place only having traded once or twice ever.
Scott: Yeah, so it's a tough call.
Scott: I gotta make a disclaimer.
Scott: We only played this game once but it is a simple game and I do remember the play very well Yeah, and it was with all newbies.
Rym: We all learned how to play the game right.
Scott: then Yeah, it was us two and two strangers at uber con some pretty cool strangers.
Scott: I got to say Yeah, usually people at gaming conventions if they don't smell they're pretty cool and they didn't smell.
Scott: What is a girl even?
Scott: Oh my god, huh?
Rym: And they really like to play Puerto Rico Yeah, and the guy we were playing with, you know, he was real quiet at first.
Rym: But then when we started playing that guy had his shit together when it came to board gaming.
Scott: Oh, he freaky he was smart.
Scott: He knew what he was doing.
Scott: Definitely a good old board gaming guy Yeah, and above average at least definitely outplayed.
Scott: if I met that guy again, I'll play a game with him now.
Rym: one other disclaimer I have is that this is one of those games like goa that Reading the rules which aren't put together that well.
Rym: in my opinion, especially in a loud room It's very difficult to learn how to play this game Without someone who has played this game before showing you because the game is so much simpler than it makes itself out to be.
Scott: Yeah I think the real problem with this game goa and some others if they have cards that have a whole bunch of symbols on them and You kind of have to learn the symbols and what they mean when they're in different because you'll
Rym: see you were gonna use a word Like symbology, I
Scott: know.
Scott: but yeah, you have to learn the symbology There we go.
Scott: And there you'll see the same symbols in many different locations.
Scott: So not only do you have to figure out the meanings of symbols?
Scott: But to figure out their meanings in different locations in different contexts and all sorts of things.
Scott: So, you know unless someone explains it to you It's pretty hard to figure that out without stumbling through an entire game and then playing it correctly the second time through.
Rym: there's also the issue that there are a lot of disparate game mechanics where Disparate.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, if you do things in different parts of the game like different parts of your turn are like totally different games with Totally different mechanics that a lot of games are very unified where every part of your turn feels like part of this unified whole.
Rym: But this game is a lot more disjoint.
Rym: So you have to learn all of these very specific and very different things in order to play.
Scott: Well, yeah now the bit.
Scott: I'm not gonna go into all the details But the basic mechanic of the game is you have cards in your hand and you have a card in front of you and the Card and for all cards are the same but on every card are two important plot spaces.
Scott: There's a number at the top and there's a bunch of card symbols at the bottom.
Scott: So let's say the card that's out in front of me right now.
Scott: The number at the top is four.
Scott: that means I can have four cards in my hand.
Scott: That's my hand limit.
Scott: then at the bottom there are three card symbols.
Scott: That means I have to play three cards this turn.
Rym: now have to Must if you on your previous turn play a card.
Rym: This is the whole game that says on the next turn you have to play four cards.
Rym: That's not an option.
Rym: you must Must must must play exactly four cards no more No less.
Rym: and if you have put yourself in a position where you cannot easily play four cards The game just basically takes out a dildo and rapes you with it until you are able to play four cards.
Scott: Yeah, if you can't if you don't have enough cards to play you can either trade other people in hopes of you know Trading a card for two cards or trading away victory points for some cards and victory points are money in this game Which is which I like that Mike.
Rym: Yeah, you can.
Rym: you can trade victory points and money.
Rym: You can trade pretty much anything you've got.
Scott: Yeah Also, you can always buy cards.
Rym: the buying mechanic is very simple.
Scott: It costs you a bunch of victory points to buy very few cards unless you've done something Clever to get cards from the cheap, but even then you're better off not buying cards.
Rym: Yeah, now it might think all right if the game has this trading mechanic But you're really trading with someone whose turn it is because the train is like a settlers You can only trade with the person whose turn it is.
Rym: well generally always help them.
Rym: So why would you ever trade with anyone they add to make sure that trading will happen?
Rym: a really cool incentive Where any time you trade with someone else when it's their turn that they don't get anything other than the trade.
Rym: But you get a little token and whoever has the most of these tokens gets a bunch of bonus points.
Scott: Yeah So if you want if you pull off trades that help other players Maybe a little bit but also help you a little bit like you can make an even trade.
Scott: And if it's not your turn you actually come out ahead because you get a prestige token You.
Scott: just if you're way ahead in prestige tokens You don't want to trade because getting one more doesn't help you.
Scott: and if you're not gonna get enough prestige tokens to score points Then you still don't want to trade because it's not unless you're ripping the other guy.
Rym: Yeah, so you might want to anyway because your turns coming and you might need cards.
Scott: you might need cards.
Scott: But I'm saying is it if you're unless you're ripping a guy off Then you don't want to trade?
Scott: if the prestige token isn't gonna help you?
Rym: I'd say an even trade can often be especially or don't forget King making always trade with someone who's losing.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: If you are the winner you do want to trade with the losers.
Rym: Yeah, if you're in second place you trade with the third and fourth place people.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: Okay, so What happens is let's say I'm sitting here and I have a hand limit of four and I have to play three cards.
Scott: Well, I take three cards from my hand and I lay them out there in the order of my choosing.
Scott: now I have to be smart about this because whichever card I put out last or on top is Going to be the card for next turn.
Scott: that determines my hand limit and how many cards I'm gonna play next turn.
Scott: So if all the cards in my hand say next turn you will play one card.
Scott: Well, guess what next turn I'm gonna be playing one card.
Rym: Yeah, basically you're all playing this solitaire solo not really interactive.
Rym: Well, basically solitaire drafting game with these goods cards But at the same time you're trading and interacting with all the other players in order to augment what you're doing on your own little board
Scott: Yep,
Rym: and pay attention what they're doing and trying to do anything you can to screw them up.
Scott: Yeah Now the thing is the game.
Scott: the scoring comes at two spots halfway through the game.
Scott: Well halfway through the deck of cards.
Scott: There is a card that has a line on both sides that says alright This is halftime.
Scott: We're gonna score.
Scott: then you score again when the deck runs out and the game is over.
Scott: So to score a lot of points you generally want to play more cards.
Scott: But also if you play too many cards You'll have to buy more cards with your points that you just got and that's not so cool.
Rym: Yeah, it even has Things in place for if you buy so much or you get screwed so much that you go into negative points Oh, yeah that you can just get totally ruined in this game.
Scott: It's not easy to get totally ruined But if you suck you will be just destroyed and you won't be able to do anything.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's about 10,000 times easier than age of steam, so don't worry.
Scott: Yeah It's not like age of steam where you'll get raped every turn.
Scott: But if you make dumb moves like if you have a hand limit of one you have one card And then you play a card.
Scott: that means next turn you had to play five cards Which means you're gonna have to get four more cards.
Scott: You're gonna get ruined Don't you got to not get in those situations.
Rym: now the way scoring works is actually very simple And I think pretty elegant.
Rym: you'll have these goods and when you play the card say I play three in a row.
Rym: you can play Whatever goods you want whatever order you want and there are different types of goods worth different amount of points depending on how many you have played Consecutively, so let's say I've played.
Rym: I'm just gonna make stuff up because I don't remember the goods from the game.
Scott: Ruby salt.
Rym: We all right God that's right.
Rym: We were playing the game with these other people and we're used to.
Rym: we've been playing you know Verator and motor and those kind of games which we bought in German Mm-hmm, so when I see rubies I say Rubine and when I see salt I say Saul's.
Scott: that's what I say.
Scott: It's only in a German board game context like if I go to the jewelry store, and there's a Ruby I say ooh a Ruby.
Scott: I don't say ooh a Rubine even though I might for hilarity.
Scott: But if I'm playing a German board game or any board game and I see a Ruby or assault It's Rubine and Saul's.
Rym: the worst thing is we weren't even doing it to be funny It just came naturally.
Rym: and then the other people like what the fuck you talking about the Rubines.
Rym: and we're like oh Oh, I'm like yeah the Rubines.
Scott: What do you what you don't?
Rym: Like it was obvious, but all right, let's say I got I played three Saul's and two Rubines Okay, and then five corn all right.
Rym: now the the scoring works on.
Rym: if you played one of something you get x points one point Pretty much.
Rym: if you played two of something you get y points three of something and it the scale is different for every good And you have a piece of paper in front of you that shows you all of these things.
Rym: You really want to try to optimize this by getting the optimal number.
Rym: I mean say Rubine maxes out at four cards.
Rym: so playing four Rubines in a row gets you a bunch of points.
Rym: if you Play eight in a row you get the same number of points because it's not per card that you get points It's per set of cards.
Scott: Yeah, so if I play two Rubine one Rubine and then one wheat then one Rubine That's not so good.
Rym: Yeah, but if you play two Rubines then one wheat you get a lot more points.
Scott: Oh you get mad points for two Rubines.
Rym: so that's another reason you want to trade is to try to get the Optimal sets and also to deny other people optimal sets in order to get the most points.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is like at most three Rubines And I'm not sure if it's three But like Ruby is a rare of course.
Scott: so if you play three in a row you'll get maximum points.
Scott: playing four in a row Or five in a row doesn't get you any more points than that you got the maximum already.
Scott: So sometimes you want to break it up.
Scott: if you have a whole bunch of something because you want to play like five in A row then something else then five in a row again because ten in a row is the same as five in a row.
Rym: Now the only other mechanic is that the game comes with these really little nice cardboard paper ships.
Scott: Oh the boats.
Scott: Yeah, the boats.
Scott: They're a lot like those boats from that Pirates of the Spanish Maine collectible boat game.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: And the way these work is whatever card you put on top that determines which how many cards you have to play on the next round Will also have some sim.
Rym: It'll also have a symbol on it.
Scott: all the cards you play have symbols.
Rym: Yeah, but it's another symbol that will say how far the ship moves.
Scott: no It's.
Scott: it's how many boat symbols on all the cards you play remember.
Rym: Oh, yeah, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, when you play all the cards you play.
Scott: Let's say I play three cards on my turn There's four sim.
Scott: There's four potential symbols on the side of any card.
Scott: There's money pirate boat and Draw card.
Rym: they might not all appear on a given card.
Rym: in fact most cards have very few if any yeah.
Scott: So then there's a little chart, so let's say I play one card, and it has a money symbol, and that's it.
Scott: I get one money when I play that card.
Scott: Let's say I play two cards, and they both have money symbols.
Scott: well according to the chart two money symbols means I get three money.
Scott: I'm just making it up You know.
Scott: let's say I play three cards and all of them have a money symbol.
Scott: according to the chart three money symbols means five money, it's the same as the other.
Rym: scoring is just a chart of Increasing returns.
Scott: yeah, so pirate is pretty bad.
Scott: pirate means Let's say I play a card with a pirate symbol.
Scott: that means I draw a card from the deck And I put it in my pirate pile at the end of your game.
Scott: the pirate pile is minus one point per card in the pirate Pile.
Rym: you don't want pirate cards Yep But there are a whole bunch of ways around that because there's a mechanic where you can buy cards out of your pirate pile and all sorts of things.
Scott: yes There's also a way we'll describe shortly in which you can avoid putting anything in your pirate pile.
Rym: now There's also a board and your ship sits on the board at a port and all the ports have little Symbols on little tokens to start and they have different symbols.
Rym: the tokens all do different things.
Rym: So if you move your ship based on how many movement you were given by the cards you played Which like everything else you must use if you get to ship movement you must move to ship spaces no matter what.
Scott: yes Let me break it down.
Scott: you play three cards.
Scott: two of them have boat symbols.
Scott: You have to move your boat three spaces.
Scott: you move it three spaces And you end up on a spot on the board.
Scott: the spot on the board has a little disc.
Scott: you take that disc and you Put it in front of you, and if you have a disc in front of you already you that one's gone.
Rym: now generally I mean, I'm not gonna go into all the discs It doesn't really matter But they'll be active as long as you sit in that port.
Rym: so if you get to a port that has a nice one like one I really like is the anti pirate which protects you from pirates.
Scott: Yep, it's great because you get that and you play all the pirate cards you want.
Rym: if you keep playing cards that don't have ships You'll stay in that port every round, but you keep the anti pirates.
Rym: You can play as many pirates as you want.
Rym: the girl in our game Did very well early on by finding a place that gave her money and just camping there dumping cards.
Scott: Yep, but as soon as you play a card that has a boat symbol on it You're gonna have to move your boat And you're gonna have to lose.
Scott: that ever token you have and if you don't land on a spot that has another token Then you're not gonna have a token.
Scott: that gives you a boost.
Scott: you pretty much want to keep a heart in their Harbor tokens.
Scott: You're pretty much going to keep one of them in front of you the whole time And you also want to strategically Have the right one for the right situation because some of them really aren't that useful.
Rym: so you've got this car drafting game You've got this trading game, and you've got this move around the board game all linked together into this game.
Rym: There's a hole.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's a whole lot of fun.
Rym: Yeah It's.
Rym: I really recommend if you want to play this game find someone who has played it before and ask them to teach you how To play.
Rym: you'll learn so much easier than quicker than trying to actually read those Probably really poorly written instructions.
Scott: Yeah, I tried to start reading the instructions And I was pretty confused and thank you to the guy who?
Scott: Saw us trying to learn the game and came over and just taught us randomly that guy's awesome.
Rym: Yep, it looked like he really wanted to play too, but he had something else to do.
Scott: Yeah, it looked like he had to play in some other game.
Scott: I think for his company or something.
Scott: I think he was a Wheeler dealer game company guy.
Rym: yeah, and while the game's difficult to learn It's actually a much simpler game than the other game.
Rym: We played at UberCon Mesopotamia Which had or the T&E card game.
Rym: yeah, Mesopotamia had an infinite number of arbitrary rules.
Rym: this game wasn't so arbitrary.
Scott: Yeah, this game once you figure.
Scott: It's difficult to figure out, but once you've got it It's actually easy, and it's actually awesome.
Scott: and while it's got that mechanic Where if you don't know what you're doing you can still play, but you'll suck And then if you know what you're doing, you'll be awesome at it.
Rym: Yeah, but even when you're sucking It's a game where you can still enjoy yourself Not like age of steam where the moment you lose it's done, and it's not even worth playing.
Scott: yeah I think my moment of revelation was about halfway through the game because like the first half of the game I was just trying to play lots of cards, and you know I was working with the symbols on the side.
Scott: So I was trying to use the symbols to draw more cards and get more points directly But then at the halftime when I realized oh I play the resources in order I get a shit ton of points because at the halftime I broke away in a huge lead.
Rym: probably my favorite thing about the game is just the trading.
Rym: because it's so open-ended.
Rym: I could trade Two of my cards for your card.
Rym: I could give you my entire head.
Rym: I could say I'll buy a card from you for four victory points meaning I'll give up four victory points and give you four victory points.
Rym: you can trade anything You've got except for the tokens which are location dependent and the prestige tiles which can't be traded because that would be silly.
Scott: yeah But all you've got are cards and victory points.
Rym: Yes, are also money, but being able to trade cards and victory points is a very interesting mechanic.
Scott: It is very interesting.
Scott: for example Rym might have just played.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Three card symbols on his last turn therefore drawing a crap ton of cards But his new hand limit is only four and he's got a bunch of extra cards on my turn.
Scott: I don't have enough cards and I need to play one more and it cost three to buy one from the day.
Scott: cause three to buy one from the deck.
Rym: so Let's say I'll just sell my card to Scott for two.
Scott: yeah But I think if you have too many cards in your hand.
Scott: don't the extras go in the pirate pile?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I think they do so.
Scott: at this point I might be able to buy a card from Rym for less than it would cost to buy it from the deck and Rym also doesn't have to put a card in his pirate pile.
Scott: so what you can work out cool stuff like that.
Rym: The trading could be really interesting.
Rym: of course it seems like it'll suffer from settlers syndrome Where if you're playing with all experienced players they'll tend to not trade much at all Because they don't want to help anyone out unless when they're king making.
Scott: yeah People will only trade if they're smart when they're king making or when there's an obvious advantage And I think the introduction of the prestige tokens.
Scott: Actually, it makes a slight advantage for someone to trade an even trade because the settlers you would never make an even trade almost ever.
Scott: You know or you might you know do it arbitrarily because it's so even.
Rym: well I did something kind of asked near the end of the game or I was like you know what and I went to all the Other players.
Rym: I was like I'll give you a victory point for nothing.
Rym: I'll give you a victory point for nothing to to get some prestige tokens.
Rym: that gave me a bunch more points than I gave up.
Scott: Ah, I think the thing was is that when you did that eventually all the players are like all right I'll do it too.
Scott: I'll do it too.
Scott: And then everyone ends up giving every player three victory points on every turn, and then it gets silly.
Scott: yeah I mean yeah giving more than one puts you at a loss.
Rym: not really it depends It does.
Scott: it does depend like if I was.
Scott: you know for example If you were way ahead in the game and the amount of points you got from prestige tokens might put me ahead.
Scott: You know would people trade me?
Scott: You know would let me give them a victory point for nothing so I can get You.
Rym: that's the reason the game falls victim to settler's center.
Rym: very easily Experienced players see right through that sort of crap and know exactly what you're trying to do when you trade with anyone.
Rym: So among experienced players in a game like this typically any trade will only happen if Both people are desperate or the disparity between the two players point wise is so great that the player on Top is not worried about the player on the bottom.
Scott: I could see in close games a symptom of pick the winner where You know the guy in first and the guy in second and if they're close enough that the prestige tokens will matter The two players who are losing and might not be able to win might choose for the second the second place player to win by making sure that they win on the prestige tokens if that makes The difference.
Rym: well if they wanted to do that remember they could just give all of their victory points to another person.
Scott: Oh, that is true.
Rym: You're so doesn't matter you're right great.
Rym: It's not really a problem because if you play with the kind of people who would do that just don't play board games with them Yeah, but it does leave open the possibility, which is a slight flaw.
Rym: Yeah But a lot of games have that even in Tigers and Euphrates.
Rym: if you're losing you can just use your Disasters to screw people or just throw Conflicts out just to screw someone and let someone else win.
Scott: that is true But it's not as openly blatant as giving someone all your victory points, and you know trading them cards Just to help them out perfectly.
Rym: Yeah in the end though.
Rym: I think it's a game We'll probably buy because I'd like to play it again in the quietude of my own home.
Scott: Yeah, it was $40 at the convention.
Scott: I wasn't about to pay that much.
Scott: I would pay 30 probably.
Rym: We'll probably buy it the next time we go to Rochester.
Scott: Yeah, I think most of the reason I didn't want to shell out so much money is because it's primarily a card game.
Scott: You can play the game pretty much entirely with this deck of cards, and there's a big board.
Scott: That's all fancy with these fancy boats and a scoring track around the edge.
Scott: That's barely.
Scott: that's like one fraction of the game.
Scott: yet when you play the game.
Scott: That's the big centerpiece It doesn't really make sense.
Scott: It feels sort of like I'm getting ripped off buying this big fancy board that I barely use.
Rym: Yeah The game is definitely in some ways a throwback to the old high production value syndrome with games like end decker where they really Overproduce a game in order to charge a lot more money for it or to make the game really impressive looking.
Scott: It's sort of like st.
Scott: Petersburg, which is basically just a card game.
Scott: yet They if you buy it nowadays you get a board and you get a few wooden pieces.
Scott: That is pretty much just a map of.
Scott: put the cards here.
Scott: You know when you could just put the cards.
Rym: arrange them on your own and Decker came with so many gratuitous pieces.
Scott: Yeah, the huts.
Rym: Yeah, the huts were good event a lot simpler.
Scott: I like the huts though.
Scott: They're fun.
Scott: Yeah, they're fun I'm not gonna argue.
Scott: They're a good game mechanic, but they're fun, and I like they're an okay game mechanic.
Rym: But we'll talk about end decker some other day.
Scott: We will talk about the Hudson and deck or some other day.
Rym: stay tuned.
Rym: tomorrow We will probably talk about anime maybe manga.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.