Rym: It's Tuesday June 6th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review the new Super Mario Brothers for the DS.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So today I was walking around at my job doing various things.
Scott: I ended up sitting in a waiting room for a while While you work at the hospital and you had to sit in the waiting room with the patients.
Rym: Well, no not with patients with other employers.
Rym: Oh, it was a waiting room.
Rym: It was not the waiting room.
Rym: So I'm sitting in there and people are talking about the fact that today is 6606, you know the devil's day and all that bullshit.
Rym: Now a couple of the people were funny and they were like, oh, yeah, haha, but one girl woman was Kind of like no, but seriously, it's a bad day.
Rym: It's not over yet.
Rym: And this other guy was trying to explain to her that you know.
Rym: The calendars moved all around and for all you know, it could have been any day.
Rym: It wasn't really this day.
Scott: It could have been four years ago.
Scott: the calendar messed up.
Scott: It could be six one.
Scott: six is the real number.
Scott: So it's not even today.
Rym: and but the woman was like, it's a bad day.
Rym: It's a bad day.
Rym: I'm just going straight home and going to bed.
Rym: I don't want anything bad to happen.
Rym: Okay, yeah That's that's all I got.
Scott: I got some real news, but Wow I know people who are a little bit, you know superstitious.
Rym: Scott.
Rym: mr.
Rym: Throw salt over his shoulders.
Scott: No superstition associated with it.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, wait, you're saying so why do you throw salt?
Rym: I got to bring this up now that I got an audience.
Rym: Why do you when you knock salt over and spill some choose to waste more of it by throwing it over your shoulder?
Scott: I got a new explanation for this one because my other explanations weren't good enough for you.
Rym: Well, your other explanation was because something bad would happen.
Scott: No, it wasn't my other explanation at all.
Rym: What was your other explanation then?
Scott: Doesn't matter.
Scott: I have a new explanation.
Rym: Okay tradition tradition Tentacles tentacles.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's got his salt superstition.
Scott: It's not as superstition as it is.
Rym: you you used to tell us that you throw the salt over your shoulder because something bad might Happen if you don't but you wouldn't say what might happen.
Scott: if I do it's not gonna change the odds.
Rym: then why do it?
Rym: You're doing something.
Rym: You're doing something suboptimal and wasting resources because I like to.
Scott: Okay Not allowed to like doing something.
Rym: could you deal with not doing it?
Rym: You seem to get agitated if it doesn't happen or if someone prevents you from doing it.
Rym: Man Yeah, that was that was a good answer.
Rym: Yeah, I I I encourage everyone in the forums, you know Especially since someone yelled at me for making fun of Scott on the show too much.
Rym: So I'm gonna lay in today.
Scott: Why do you put your pants on right leg first?
Scott: Why don't you put on left leg first?
Rym: Oh, um I usually put them on both legs at the same time.
Scott: Oh, why don't you do one leg at a time?
Rym: Sometimes I do.
Rym: Oh You know what though?
Rym: Nothing bad will happen if I put my body.
Scott: Why do you put the bits of lettuce in the in a celery in the salad?
Scott: that shouldn't go in the salad?
Rym: They should go in the salad.
Rym: Oh, there's no greens.
Scott: No restaurant puts that in the salad.
Rym: You're the same person who won't eat dandelions.
Scott: Ten lines aren't food.
Scott: head lines are most definitely only if you're a dirty hippie who will eat grass and shit.
Rym: Anyway, I would just like to behoove all of our wonderful forum people out there especially the people who have argued with Scott about religion or superstition in the past months to uh Talk about his salt superstition.
Scott: It's not a superstition.
Rym: Yeah, all right.
Rym: then in some real news the six bone Which I'll explain what that is in a minute is finally going away.
Scott: It's not the sixth bone in your body No, nor does it have anything to do with paleontology or archaeology or Anatomy.
Rym: it however has a lot to do with my experiences at RIT as an IIT student.
Rym: You okay there Scott?
Scott: I'm still laughing from one of the things.
Scott: I laugh too hard at one of the things of the day and I screwed up my Throat, uh-huh.
Scott: So I'm coughing a lot.
Rym: It could be the chemicals wafting in from the hallway.
Rym: So I went to RIT to study information technology and as a result I did a lot of networking stuff and a project that I actually never completed because I dropped out of the class But I started it low involved ipv6 Which is the theoretical successor to ipv4, which is what is currently running the internet.
Rym: Now I could go into great detail about this But I'm sure none of you care because it's not tech day or anything and you're just here for your gaming.
Rym: But you know IP addresses, you know, like 129 21 21.1 Though there aren't that many of those.
Rym: There are only so many of those numbers that we can use and we're running out.
Rym: The proposed solution is ipv6 or IP version 6 as opposed to version 4 which Basically gives you enough IP addresses to assign Millions of them to every square meter of the Earth's surface including the oceans and still have plenty of spare.
Scott: so the idea of ipv6 is that Every single electronic device in the entire world could have an IP address and it wouldn't matter.
Scott: even if you had everyone carried around like a hundred devices and They were all like minuscule nano devices.
Scott: It wouldn't matter.
Rym: It also solves a lot of the problems we currently have with IP like multicasting doesn't work so well and load balancing has to be done in kind of hackish ways and DHCP which is a way to get IP addresses out of the ether.
Rym: We need that.
Rym: while an ipv6 you could really set up a network where that's not necessary.
Rym: IPv6 is all-around good, but for a variety of reasons No one has really gotten into it and it really hasn't taken off in the real world.
Rym: The six bone was a testbed a branch of IPv6 that was dedicated to students and professors and technical experts to study play with test and generally muck around with ipv6.
Rym: I Myself had a fairly large swath of six bone addresses to use in a project for a class I was taking at RIT.
Scott: considering there are millions and millions and millions and millions of addresses Billions of addresses.
Scott: even having a large swath of them is not difficult to get I hooked to quill.
Rym: It was difficult to get if you weren't in a school.
Scott: Oh, yeah, of course, but if you ask they just gave you look.
Rym: Yeah, but you had to be going to a school that had the ability to ask of course.
Rym: I mean went to RIT.
Rym: We had the friggin best internet connection in the world.
Rym: there close to it We had two oc3s a t2 t3s and a bunch of asdl backups.
Scott: Yeah a DSL.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yep But anyway, I then dropped out of that class and didn't do much with the six bone though I did connect two computers to it at one point.
Rym: Ooh, and now it's going away.
Rym: They're finished testing.
Rym: They no longer need the six bone.
Rym: It is gone.
Rym: It is dead.
Scott: IPV6 isn't dead.
Rym: You can still do it the right way even though no one is really doing it and IPV6 Probably isn't going to take off anytime soon.
Scott: Yeah If you really want to do experiments with IPV6 the thing is out there.
Scott: Pretty much all the software in the world supports it at least all the good software now have.
Rym: most software doesn't support it.
Scott: Oh, if you have a Linux machine, it supports it 90% perfectly But the actual internet doesn't support it and nor does your internet service provider.
Scott: So what you can do is you can set up a LAN in your house that uses IPV6 all you want.
Scott: You just can't.
Scott: you know, the internet isn't running IPV6 yet.
Scott: They'd need to upgrade all sorts of routers and things which isn't gonna happen.
Scott: Okay, I got two combined.
Scott: news is here.
Rym: Yeah, he changed his news suddenly on me.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: first news some guy in with the Ukraine Kiev Kiev.
Rym: He
Scott: went to a lion cage and He was going down a rope into the lion cage and he said if a god exists he won't let me die or something like that probably in Russian and He was mauled and killed immediately by the Lions who slit his jugular vein.
Scott: Okay, God did not protect him from the Lions.
Scott: another story Unrelated but related There was a big storm somewhere and this woman went outside to pray That her family would be protected from the storm.
Scott: She was immediately struck by lightning.
Scott: There was no God.
Scott: I don't think.
Rym: I don't think that's news But I think you're discounting the possibilities that there is a God and he's an asshole That there is a God and he has a sense of humor.
Rym: That there is a God and he wanted to make an example out of these people That there are a whole bunch of gods and they weren't paying attention That there's a great dragon in the sky and he was just pissed at this woman.
Scott: Yeah, you know what believing any of those things is better than what most of the religious not bags believe because they don't believe any of that.
Rym: So that's your news.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: All right, great.
Rym: Let's go to things today.
Scott: Like there wasn't any gaming news.
Scott: What do you want from me?
Rym: I got a thing today here and Once again, I haven't found anything really particularly new or exciting on the internet in quite some time And I've run out of cool retro things to link to.
Rym: So I just wandered around and I stumbled upon an old Photoshop or not actually Photoshop Friday But a comedy goldmine on something awful truth in gaming and it's you know, just funny, you know cover of a game and The truth about that game.
Scott: well board games.
Rym: Yeah, it could have been any game.
Rym: just no one did video games But the best one far and away was to Magic the Gathering and it was money the wasting.
Rym: ha ha That's the best I can do.
Rym: the internet has not amused me in several weeks.
Scott: There are some other good ones in there.
Scott: I did learn from this Photoshop that clue.
Scott: the game of clue is Actually called clue do in Britain.
Scott: It was originally a British game and they changed it to clue when they brought it over to America.
Scott: I will now forever call the game clue do.
Scott: Also, they changed the guy, you know, mr.
Scott: Body include the guy who gets killed.
Scott: apparently he's really named.
Scott: Dr Black.
Scott: I will now call him.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Black.
Rym: Well, you couldn't have a racist game in the US.
Rym: I mean who dies first the black dude, but you have mrs.
Scott: White.
Rym: Yeah, that's fine.
Scott: What about general Custer Colonel custard?
Rym: Well, he'll go out mustard.
Rym: He'll go after miss Scarlett because she's you know red.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I I'm not sure why they actually changed the name.
Rym: I wouldn't be surprised if it was some sort of fear of racism charges.
Scott: Why did they just call him doctor?
Scott: I don't know some other color that wasn't in there.
Scott: Dr.
Rym: Orange, dr.
Rym: African Dr.
Rym: Black bastard, dr.
Scott: Gray.
Rym: Ah, yeah anyway You got a thing of the day.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So there's these two videos not sure if they were actually real commercials or if they were just made.
Scott: I think they were made by a marketing company, but they're pretty funny.
Scott: They're commercials for Street Fighter or some Street Fighter game.
Scott: Probably I think a Street Fighter alpha anthology of some sorts.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: and The funny one is two of them.
Scott: One of them is less funny.
Scott: I'll let you watch that on your own.
Scott: The first one this guy makes a popcorn in the microwave and it explodes.
Scott: I think it's a jiffy pops.
Scott: You're not even supposed to put it in a microwave.
Rym: Well, yeah, it was metal.
Rym: I think that's the point.
Scott: Yeah, so after it explodes it says on the screen bad move.
Scott: then he goes and he puts the popcorn on the counter and he Hadouken's it and a little fireball comes out and it hits the popcorn and it turns into a bowl of popcorn.
Scott: After the Hadouken hits it and says good move.
Rym: Honestly, uh these I didn't really find these that funny.
Rym: They happen to reference the game and that's really the only thing they have going for him.
Scott: Oh, I think it's funny.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't see it coming.
Rym: Yeah, I saw it coming because I knew what they were ahead of time.
Scott: Yeah, plus it was just kind of forget what I said and go click on the link.
Rym: It was just kind of lame.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: No, you suck.
Rym: We haven't had good things of the day lately.
Scott: It is going after me today.
Scott: You're thinking today sucked.
Rym: Yeah, I did.
Rym: I fully admitted to it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I just couldn't find anything funny on the internet.
Rym: There wasn't old-school like.
Rym: I've seen it a million times and it's all I mean I could do Numa Numa.
Rym: Yeah, we've never linked to Numa Numa.
Scott: Maybe we should start having a like users submit.
Scott: Oh, no, give users submit thing of the days.
Scott: They'll just submit things.
Scott: We've seen a hundred times.
Scott: Well think of something.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway today being gaming day We decided we would talk about the new Mario game for the DS that came out since we both finally fully beaten it.
Scott: Yep, I've beaten every level but I'm still working on getting all the big coins.
Rym: Yep I've eaten every level and I haven't had time to bother with going after the coins.
Scott: Alright, so let's talk about the game a bit.
Rym: It's a standard 2d Platformer old-school kind of Mario with a little bit of twists.
Scott: Well, the first thing that's different from normal Mario is that not only can you jump and shoot fireballs?
Scott: But you can do a lot of the moves that you can do in Mario 64 like triple jump ground pound ground pound wall jump Etc.
Scott: that helps a lot and provides for a lot of interesting new things.
Scott: There are a lot of maps where if you were say Mario from Mario 3 It would just be impossible because you don't have the moves to do the map or you don't have the moves to get the coins In certain places,
Rym: but at the same time the control which we'll talk about more later Mario's a little bit full of momentum and a little loose.
Scott: Yeah in Mario 3 you would let go of the arrows and Mario would stop like very quickly like stopped.
Scott: You know I mean if you went if you're running right and you push left Mario would go and stop almost immediately and this one Mario kind of Slows down like whoa.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: It's it's you're on ice Basically on a little bit of ice constantly until you get to the ice world until you're on the ice world Then you're on super ice.
Scott: You get used to it after a while But the first time you play if you're used to other Mario games It can be slightly annoying and yet to just keep playing until you get used to it and then it's alright.
Rym: The main effect of this is that playing the game is more.
Rym: I mean Mario 3.
Rym: The cool way to play and really all the Mario's was to generally be running all the time and going through the game very quickly But also getting all the important secrets.
Scott: So if there were two paths one with coins and one without you would jump and get the coins And if there was a pipe you would stop and go in it Etc.
Rym: But at the same time you could also almost always like if a thing looked dangerous Stop and do it real slowly and carefully and almost always get through it.
Rym: Yep, the new Mario game because you're so full of momentum and so kind of loosey-goosey.
Rym: I don't know why I said loosey-goosey.
Rym: That's a terrible thing to say.
Rym: It's fine It really enforces the.
Rym: you have to be pretty much running through the game at full tilt and any time you hesitate the game Punishes you and I think what happens is early.
Scott: when I was first playing that's what the situation was But later on as I got used to these slight loosey-goose enos I would stop earlier and I had better control over it.
Scott: So I was able to stop and do certain things but overall Is an example.
Scott: there's a part in the game where you know The spiky ceiling comes down and goes up and there are areas that you make it from one safe area to the next.
Scott: You can run from one safe area to the next but it's kind of crummy.
Scott: It's actually easier to run like go full tilt and do every second or every third safe area.
Scott: You know if you try to stop and do it carefully It's more likely that the spikes will get you then.
Scott: if you were to just run run run run run jump stop.
Rym: Now the game also adds two new items.
Rym: I mean Mario 3 was famous because I added a whole bunch of items.
Rym: know the frog suit the tanuki suit the hammer suit The leaf.
Rym: yeah, this game goes back to the basics with two little twists.
Scott: Well three three twists.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there's the mushroom duh There's the fire flower duh, there's the star duh.
Scott: The first twist is the mega mushroom.
Scott: now, you've probably seen the mega mushroom in action.
Scott: It makes Mario or Luigi Ridiculously huge and they smash everything.
Rym: you get a meter at the top while you're big and it goes up the more things you smash And then you get a bunch of one-ups based on how much stuff you've destroyed while you were big.
Scott: Yep No, it's not.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's a lot of fun, but it's not everything.
Rym: It's cracked up to be It's not useful in most worlds and it doesn't really do much for you.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there are some worlds where at the beginning of the world there'd be a million bricks and bad guys And it's like the perfect spot to use the mega mushroom.
Scott: but there are other worlds where you know, even though giant Mario or giant Luigi can just kick pipes out of the way and Completely destroy any bad guys and bricks and whatnot.
Scott: There will be holes.
Scott: You can't get over or there will be.
Scott: you know Whole places you can't fit into because you're too big and you can't get.
Scott: you can't proceed in the levels.
Scott: You just have to wait for the giant mushroom to wear off before you can keep going.
Rym: Luckily the game won't let you pick up a big mushroom if you're in an area where you couldn't use it at all.
Scott: Yeah, but it won't hurt you.
Scott: if you try to use your big mushroom and somewhere you can't it won't take it away from you It just won't let you use it.
Rym: Now the item number two they added is the turtle shell.
Scott: Turtle shell is sort of its ass.
Scott: It's a double-edged sword.
Scott: It's a double-edged sword if you practice like hell.
Rym: you could become good at it but you'll beat the game into the ground long before you would have practiced it enough and The multiplayer is not that good as we'll get to.
Rym: so there's really no purpose to ever use the shell.
Scott: Okay There are two purposes for the shell.
Scott: first purpose for the shell.
Scott: It lets you go if you're in the water a water level.
Scott: the shell is awesome because Mario can swim like a mofo with the shell.
Scott: Yeah, even though I'd rather still have my fire flower I would I'd say the fire flower and the shell are equal But it does depend on the water level.
Scott: if there's a lot of cheeps and a lot of bloopers you want the fire But if it's one with a lot of blowing pipes, then you want the turtle shell.
Scott: The turtle shell also is used to get into some secrets on occasion and that can be useful and certain levels are designed With hills in such a way that the shell can let you just burn right through and kill a bunch of bad guys.
Scott: But that really very few levels are like that other than that if you use the shell.
Scott: The way it works is that you run full tilt and then you duck into the shell and now you don't even have to duck.
Rym: If you start running fast enough you automatically shell.
Scott: yeah, you turn into a turtle shell you'll bounce off walls You can jump But you can't really change direction or slow down and you can undo the shell at any time and turn back into Mario.
Rym: But the action to do it is kind of counterintuitive, and I've never done it reflexively.
Scott: Yeah, you do it by I think letting go of B right.
Rym: I think in hitting out for something You just let go of B.
Scott: The thing is when I'm in the shell You know it's kind of I feel like I'm ducking and I want to push up to get out of the shell.
Scott: So it's like I have to consciously think let go of B.
Rym: Most likely if you're in shell mode you will go you bump bump into a hole.
Scott: That's what happens most of the time.
Rym: luckily you don't really need the shell for anything.
Rym: It's just something to play with.
Rym: you do need it to get a few of the secrets like the cannons in certain levels Yeah, but you can do that with a bunch of turtle shells and a lot of tenacity.
Scott: Well what I do is I keep a turtle shell in the reserve I get to the secret I turn the turtle shell on I get the secret
Rym: I just go harvesting Koopa Troopas and throwing them at whatever secret it is and then
Scott: there are some secrets where you can't get The the Koopa Troopa near it.
Scott: like there are secrets They make the level in such a way where the only way to get through is if you have the turtle shell.
Rym: yeah luckily I beat almost the entire game, and I just ignored all those secrets, and I didn't miss much.
Scott: yep They're mostly warp zones and that sort of thing.
Scott: some of them will help you get to there.
Scott: basically a lot of secrets that get you the same result and Some secrets will get you the result easier or more Difficultly and you can pick either one you want.
Rym: the last item is the mini mushroom Which is basically only a skip levels real easily and go to secret areas item.
Scott: Yeah, the mini mushroom makes you really really small Which helps you get into secret areas where the there's a really really small hole or an extra small pipe to go into.
Rym: now being Small any hit kills you.
Rym: you can't even squash goombas.
Rym: Yeah, if you jump on a goomba you just bounce off you can ground pound the goomba though You could jump really really high and really really far and you can fit into holes.
Rym: Mm-hmm that's it.
Scott: Yeah, it basically makes playing the game normally harder But it allows you to play the game differently where you can go real far real fast and go into secrets.
Scott: There are quite a few secrets that require the mini mushroom Because you need to kick off a wall and go flying really far to reach an opposite ledge with the mini mushroom Or in fact the two secret worlds that they're on the board.
Rym: They're not much of a secret But you know there's world one two three four five six seven eight.
Rym: two of the worlds are optional four and well Three and four.
Scott: it's one then two then three or four kind of like outrun where if you go left you go to world Three and you go to.
Scott: if you go right you go to world four.
Scott: well to get to world four You have to beat world three as micro Mario.
Rym: Yeah the same with world seven.
Scott: There is another way to get to world seven with a cannon and that's how I got there.
Rym: Yeah, I got there the normal way because it was easier.
Scott: Yeah, I got there by using a turtle shell on a secret which actually wasn't too hard because I had the shell in the reserve.
Rym: So I got to the secret normally and then but I like the way the game clues you in because you beat You know the final castle area against a kid Koopa, and then you write like he runs off and you run after him.
Rym: But right there before he runs off.
Rym: There's a little hole that Mario just runs over.
Rym: So I thought to myself huh, and I beat it again as a little Mario and instead of going across He fell in the hole and went to a different world.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty obvious.
Scott: You had to be an idiot not to realize it.
Scott: when you see it You know she'd beat world two.
Scott: you would see that secret.
Scott: you'd go back to world two.
Scott: you'd get the secret the same thing in World five.
Scott: you would do the same exact thing to get to world seven.
Rym: these worlds Don't unlock anything other than you get to play the world and they're fun.
Scott: You really need to play all the worlds.
Scott: what?
Scott: level seven is a really really crazy world.
Scott: level seven is great All right, what else serious about this game?
Scott: now?
Rym: the gameplay itself.
Rym: I mean the game is fun.
Rym: It's I'd say it's a lot easier than say Mario 3.
Scott: Oh, it's hella easier than Mario 3 or Mario world.
Scott: It has a lot of levels, but once you get the hang of it.
Scott: You can just blow right through it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I blew through the game to the end in a couple days.
Scott: Yeah I think it took me under a week And I beat the game and then I unlocked World seven and I beat every world in that.
Rym: so and the game has some decent replay value because you can go around and try To get all the big coins, which you you basically just used to unlock areas on the map that are obvious like mushroom houses.
Scott: Another thing is that the this big replay value and that if you burn through all the levels you didn't really fully Experience them and they have a lot more to offer than just running through them quickly.
Scott: So by the time you've beaten the game you have a lot of skill.
Scott: So going back and playing all the levels over trying to collect the three giant coins in each level You'll actually then you will.
Rym: it will be the first time you play out the levels and don't want to do them anymore But at the same time I don't find the game as expansive or as long-term replayable as Mario 3 and Mario World.
Scott: No, I definitely don't.
Rym: I mean Mario world is just massive.
Rym: There's so much to that game and Mario 3. there are so many levels you almost never played because you know You can't save your game or anything.
Scott: Yep I think that in.
Scott: I think whether they're like 80 levels in this game or something crazy like that You know, I don't even know.
Rym: I just blew through it.
Rym: I didn't really notice.
Scott: I think that's what they said.
Scott: there's something like 80 levels, but it does doesn't feel as big as Mario World or Mario 3.
Rym: I mean Mario 3's levels are actually really really short compared to this game.
Scott: Yeah, and they're really complex too, but I don't know.
Scott: I played Mario 3 a zillion times But this game after I get all we'll see how long I can keep Collecting giant coins before I get sick of it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I got sick of collecting stars in Mario 64. right quick Oh, yeah.
Scott: Well the first time I played Mario 64 I beat it and then I started collecting stars But I never got all of them.
Scott: I got bored around star 90 or 80 or something like that.
Rym: Yeah, I think I made it on the DS.
Scott: I collected like two extra stars and I was done Yeah on the DS once I beat the game.
Rym: I didn't bother.
Rym: I never got another star.
Scott: Yeah this game I'm still collecting the big coins because a lot of levels it is ran through just trying to get to the end and There's a lot more in those levels.
Scott: So it's kind of like I'm still playing them for the first time But eventually I'm gonna when there's no more to experience.
Scott: It's gonna dry up.
Rym: I guess I just I was so used to you know old Mario games that the game is great and fun But it's really really easy at least to me.
Scott: Yeah, I wish there was some sort of hard mode like you beat it and then all the goombas turned to beetles.
Rym: You know just like Mario 1 that would have been cool Yeah, or like Mario World where if you want you can go to the crazy star world and beat those Ridiculously difficult levels that they just threw in at the end.
Scott: I really think that they should have added some sort of unlocked a bunch of extra stuff when you beat it.
Scott: Granted if it was just the original Mario or maybe the original Mario 2 or something.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know I mean granted I haven't looked on game facts or anything.
Rym: I don't know what all is in there to unlock.
Scott: I don't think there's that much more than what I've already got.
Scott: I'm going to try to get all the big coins But I am gonna look on game facts to see what that gets me because if it's not a big prize I'm probably gonna stop eventually.
Rym: now the game also comes with all the mini.
Rym: Well, most of the mini games from the original Mario 64 port to the DS.
Scott: Yeah, Mario 64 DS had a bunch of touchscreen demo games Which are little tiny mini games that were.
Scott: they're just kind of thrown in there on the main menu screen like oh by the way.
Rym: Now the one nice thing the upgrade I guess from the original 64 DS was that one.
Rym: most of these games are multiplayer.
Scott: I think there's more multiplayer games than there are single-player minigames.
Rym: Yeah, and two there the games are somewhat better.
Scott: Yeah, they took out my favorite game the shell bowling but they added quite a few other games that are real good.
Rym: Yeah, the Othello is alright.
Scott: Well, the Othello I think is one of the ones is only in multiplayer, but it's Bob-omb Othello.
Scott: Yeah, I'll get four people playing Othello on the same map with four color Bob-ombs.
Scott: That's cool.
Rym: now the other multiplayer the actual like touted multiplayer that everyone was talking about is Kinda-ass.
Scott: It's I think what it is disappointing.
Rym: It's it's no better or worse than the multiplayer in Mario 64.
Scott: Yes, see when I saw the screenshots in the videos, I thought oh look at that You're going to have Mario and Luigi play the actual game cooperatively with two DS's wirelessly.
Scott: So like me and Rym could team up to beat the game.
Scott: that is not the case.
Rym: It is just a four tiny maps and Mario and Luigi run around Collecting stars and fighting with each other.
Rym: the fighting becomes whoever gets the fire flower first wins.
Scott: Yeah, if you jump on the other guy if you turtle shell the other guy if the other guy falls in a hole if the Guy dies if you fireball then a star pops out of his head.
Scott: you collect the star.
Scott: now you have one more star.
Scott: Also stars appear in the level in random locations if they happen to appear near you and far away from the other guy.
Scott: Good for you now
Rym: granted I learned because I played this game a bit multiplayer with Adam for a while and I discovered that if you set it to where you need like ten stars to win like a huge number of stars and you give Each other like three lives because you can give it.
Rym: so people have lives and when you die you lose.
Rym: It'd be the stars are there and everyone's going after them, but it's more a game of kill the other person Which is much more entertaining.
Scott: yeah, but even that runs dry pretty quick.
Rym: Yeah, it's just a quick quick pickup game Like you can just play it a little bit and then be done with it.
Scott: It doesn't have a long term.
Scott: It's not something you're gonna keep breaking out at conventions like Mario Kart or Tetris.
Rym: It's something you'd use to show people the game, and that's probably it.
Scott: yeah The multiplayer doesn't have a lot of reuse But you will play it a few times.
Rym: it does have a really awesome loading screen if you play single cart mode.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: I'll let you discover that on your own.
Rym: Yep, okay?
Scott: What else does new Mario have to offer?
Scott: a lot of retro awesomeness?
Rym: Yeah, like if you beat.
Rym: you know in the original Mario you get fireworks.
Rym: This isn't for a prize or anything But if someone could post how you got fireworks in Mario brought when Super Mario Brothers one.
Scott: I know how you get fireworks in all the Mario games that have fireworks yep as do I and you know what they're in this Game too, and they actually do something.
Scott: you can strategically get fireworks to help you out in your game.
Rym: Yeah, well they just make mushroom houses appear and give you points and different kinds of mushroom houses room on the numbers.
Scott: So if you need a big giant mushroom you can go for the big giant mushroom house by hitting the flag at a certain time.
Rym: And yeah, they also extended the flag.
Rym: it is no longer Trivial to get to the top of the flag.
Scott: yeah in Mario Super Mario Brothers if you were good You got what was.
Scott: the top of the flag is 5,000 right?
Rym: Yep?
Scott: Yep now the flag goes 4,000 8,000 one up and also you know 2000 100 500 yeah all that crap pretty pretty much in every level you're either going to get low on the flag or Ridiculously high in the flag one time.
Rym: I jumped way way over the flag and you got a one up.
Scott: Yeah, you can actually go down the other side of the flag to know if you jump just right.
Rym: Yep, I mean, that's it.
Rym: It's just it's a Mario game.
Rym: It's definitely worth buying.
Scott: I'd say it's worth buying.
Scott: if you're not a huge Fan of 2d platform games, then you should wait until the price goes down a little bit or maybe buy a used copy.
Scott: But yeah, if you got a DS.
Scott: You should get this and it will entertain you when you are bored alone.
Scott: Not so much the multiplayer definitely not the multiplayer, but once you beat it You're pretty much done with it, but that's okay.
Scott: cuz Phoenix Wright is the same way.
Rym: yeah, and you know what's right?
Scott: It's freaking awesome.
Rym: Yeah, I still think back to Phoenix.
Rym: I mean now it's weird, but I get a replay value from Phoenix right not for me playing it But from other people playing it and they'll say oh, I just got to the part where blah happens And I can say you haven't met blah yet.
Scott: Oh, yeah new Mario doesn't have that but it is a great one-player DS game.
Rym: yes now That was a kind of a short episode which is fine.
Rym: We've been doing long episodes almost every night for quite some time now Rims being a wuss and he wants to go to bed.
Rym: well that and we kind of exhausted our topic earlier than we expected.
Rym: Yep, there wasn't too much to say.
Rym: the game is just a solid game with nothing special at all to it other than I just remembered.
Rym: There's one really cool thing The mechanic of killing Bowser in the castles is the same in this game as it was in Super Mario Brothers 1 Except Bowser's in the castle.
Rym: at the end of the first world you've knocked that bridge out from under him.
Rym: He falls in the lava and sinks.
Rym: Now.
Rym: the other game didn't really address the physics of what happens if you fall into lava.
Rym: So then a second later his dry dry bones float back up and then sink down and Bowser is dead Like dead as in dead and buried in bone, and that's the plot of the game.
Scott: Yeah Like who would think that a side-scrolling game like this would have plot during the game?
Scott: I mean Mario.
Scott: all the other Mario games had plot But the plot was taken care of in the instruction book and at the ending.
Scott: it was never taken care of.
Scott: in the middle of the game This Mario side-scroller actually has plot that it takes place at the first boss I think the and at the end of the game.
Rym: Yeah, there's not.
Rym: I mean there's not much there don't go expecting like a masterpiece of subtle allegory.
Scott: no No, you won't but it's pretty interesting what goes on and it explains away Something in the original Super Mario Brothers that has everyone, you know that you might say.
Scott: Hey, how did that make sense?
Scott: Well, here you go Sort of a back fix.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: So the story of Mario.
Rym: unlike Princess Peach, which has a long unskippable opener that shows you all the plot.
Rym: This game has the shortest flimsiest get-right-to-the-point opener ever.
Rym: It shows Mario and the princess.
Rym: the princess gets kidnapped.
Rym: Mario goes to save her.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Go go go Oh and one last.
Rym: you can skip it.
Scott: You just push start.
Scott: you can turn this game on to be playing Mario in seconds.
Rym: I'm gonna reveal a secret that was revealed to us when we beat the game and I thought I'd like the way it was.
Scott: Everyone knows the secret but that's okay.
Rym: Not if they haven't beaten it and they're not assholes who look at game facts before they play a game.
Rym: But after you beat the game if you you know, all the credits roll by and it says the end.
Rym: you can continue.
Rym: But if you notice the background image because they don't say it anywhere just the background image real lightly says over and over again like L plus R plus A equals Luigi huh Isn't it just L plus A?
Rym: Yeah, I think you just hit L R and A.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I can't remember if there's an R. try both.
Scott: Yeah, regardless R couldn't hurt.
Rym: Yeah, if you do it and you hit A and you start your game you get to be Luigi.
Scott: Yeah, I saw it in the background when I beat the game and I was like, huh?
Scott: And then I was like, oh And then and then I did it and then I was like, yeah, I'm Luigi Yes, and then after I turned it off and came back to play again, I completely forgot about it.
Scott: Yeah, and I hadn't been Luigi until recently when I remembered again.
Rym: I played Luigi pretty much constantly afterwards And I didn't look yet.
Rym: I don't think Luigi is different.
Scott: Luigi is absolutely not different in any way other than color and Psychosomatic effects.
Rym: that is the best he feels different even though he isn't.
Scott: He's green which is infinitely better than red and the way they draw him.
Rym: He feels taller even though he isn't Nope hit by.
Scott: everything's the same about him.
Scott: You can duck under the same stuff and everything.
Scott: One thing that actually adds to this game a lot I think are the is new interesting twists on the bad guys true like this.
Scott: cool booze cool bloopers cool bullet bills for sure.
Rym: cool hammer brothers you know the game is just incredibly solid and well put together like Remember when the GameCube came out and then smash brothers melee came out and that game was just like so well put together and so Good at what it was.
Rym: Yep, this game's like that like every little element is put exactly where it should be.
Rym: It's as good as this game.
Scott: will ever know how Smash Brothers Melee was so much better than Smash Brothers original on the 64.
Scott: It was just that kind of improvement.
Scott: this is that kind of improvement on Super Mario Brothers 1 yeah, and That's it.
Rym: We got a bunch of meta bits though because we forgot to talk about him yesterday.
Scott: Oh meta bits good thing you remember.
Rym: Yep, first off Welcome to all of our new listeners who are finally Coming out of their lurking depths because we can see your IP addresses and joining the forums.
Rym: Hooray It's really cool that many many many of our listeners are in foreign countries though.
Rym: We have said that before and For those of you who've been paying attention for quite some time now We've been having our logo contest for GeekNights because we don't have a good logo.
Rym: We have a deadline now.
Rym: We have.
Rym: we have a couple of tentative winners already.
Rym: So if you want to come out and bust out with a logo for GeekNights and win the $50 in prize money in Addition to the fame and fortune and all the other coolness associated with that.
Scott: Well, no fortune just just fame and $50.
Rym: That's a fortune to some people.
Rym: All right, especially college bums.
Rym: Yeah, imagine back if we were at RIT and someone gave us 50 bucks.
Rym: Yep But Midnight on Sunday 1159 p.m.
Rym: This Sunday the contest is over Over over over and done.
Rym: You cannot enter it after that.
Rym: I don't care how awesome it is.
Scott: Yeah until somewhat recently we had a lot of we had we had enough submissions, but none of them really were like, okay That's the one now.
Scott: We've got some that are like, alright, we can go with that.
Rym: Yep, and we've been sitting on them for a while.
Rym: We just we got to pick a logo.
Rym: We got to move with this because I want to make my business cards and t-shirts and all that other good stuff.
Rym: Yep, and once again once we have all our merch because we'll definitely have some awesome t-shirts and things I'll tell you right now that we're going to sell them at cost.
Rym: We're not gonna make money off of them?
Scott: Yeah, no, at least not for now.
Rym: Not not.
Rym: if we ever do start making money off and we'll tell you.
Rym: but right now We're more interested in getting cool stuff to people than we are in making money.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: What are the meta bits do we have?
Rym: not so much.
Rym: people are joining the forums like we told them to yep.
Scott: Visit the website Recruit.com.
Rym: Yep Libsyn informed me that we had our 10,000 unique IP hit in Some amount of time.
Rym: I don't know what the crap was about that.
Scott: So there are theoretically 10,000 people in the world that have heard at least one of ours or downloaded at least one of our shows.
Scott: But who knows how many people have used like 10 IP addresses each?
Rym: Yeah, so It's weird looking at the stats for episodes because we still we have a lot of listeners.
Rym: now We're starting to have enough people to where the data we get from the site actually is useful Like we can spot trends now that aren't just aberrations.
Rym: It's just still weird how some episodes get downloaded like a lot more than others, but it's not a pattern.
Scott: Yeah, we can't seem like if an episode is downloaded a hundred more times than another episode.
Scott: I try to find maybe a popular site linking to it and I never do.
Scott: There's no rhyme or reason to it Yeah.
Rym: But yet we noticed like one time someone must have submitted us to fart because we got a bunch of hits from total fart.
Scott: Yep, but one of our I think whatever most popular episode was the favorite video games episode.
Scott: What's all that?
Rym: Yep, and actually of toys of our youth was real huge.
Scott: Yeah, that's another very popular episode.
Rym: interestingly enough the way I can we can usually tell if an episode was Popular for its subject matter as opposed to for some other.
Rym: weird reason was that every time an episode gets a whole bunch of crazy Downloads, it's almost always people clicking on the link on the web page and not using the feed or iTunes or anything.
Rym: Yep, and on that note tomorrow Wednesday being anime manga comics day.
Rym: We went to another convention.
Rym: We didn't talk so much about going to this one as we have about other ones.
Rym: No, but we will have our full coverage of Wizard World Philly.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That is correct.
Rym: I got some interviews in the spirit of the anime world order guys.
Rym: I did my own little search for the truth comic search for the truth.
Rym: I discovered a truth about comic fans as opposed to anime fans and how there are two very distinct geekeries Mm-hmm.
Rym: And while there are a lot of Anime fans who like comics there aren't so many comic fans who like anime.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: also, I ran into some cosplayers at Wizard World Philly who had never been to a comic-con before and they had some interesting things to Say.
Scott: mmm, and if somehow we don't fill up the whole episode I can talk about Some of the comics we got.
Rym: and oh, yeah the one I'm holding in my hand right now that I'm very proud of.
Scott: Yeah, that's a great comic.
Rym: Yeah I Got an interview with the guy who did this comic to any sign the comic for me Pretty much any.
Scott: if you buy anyone's comic from them at a comic-con they sign it for you.
Scott: It's so weird because other all these comic nerds are walking up with giant piles of stuff like sign all these things that I own That you wrote or that you drew and they there's worried about them being collectible and shit.
Scott: And I'm just like hey, you don't have to sign if you don't want to I don't care Whatever cool.
Scott: Thanks.
Scott: Yeah, they're awesome.
Rym: So I got to say the one comic I bought the guy who wrote it Gets the prize for best showmanship at a comic convention.
Scott: He does indeed.
Rym: I Want to talk about it, but I got to save her for tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, let's hold it.
Scott: Let's hold everyone in suspense till tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, I think I mentioned it briefly at the beginning of this episode so you can probably go figure it out And That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.