Rym: It's Thursday August 3rd, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: We're at Otakon right now.
Rym: in fact exactly at this minute We are probably either in the pool or in the hotel having a wine and cheese party.
Scott: Well at the moment that this was released.
Rym: well of course at the moment now.
Rym: We're still in beacon recording ahead.
Scott: Yeah, well if you're listening to this the day it came out odds are you aren't at Otakon?
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at two oh six three three three one five three seven.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.