Rym: It's Tuesday October 31st.
Scott: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we bring you our interview with Luke crane the creator of burning wheel.
Rym: Let's do this And welcome to the very first episode of season 2 of GeekNights.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: We're actually really excited.
Rym: We want really want to kick this off with this fantastic Interview we got a couple weekends ago.
Rym: In fact, we're so excited and the interview was so long that we're going to skip the news and we're only going to have one thing of the day.
Scott: I'm sure everyone's all disappointed.
Scott: We're gonna start off a new season doing a weird-ass episode.
Rym: Yeah, but don't worry about it because this interview is utterly fantastic.
Rym: I enjoyed listening to it while I was editing it which is usually something I can't say about the interviews We've done.
Scott: Yeah, I listened to it and I was like, wow This is an awesome interview like another podcast did it but we did it And at first or the beginning of the interview I was kind of but then I have my interviewing skills Quintupled within about two minutes.
Rym: Yes to Scott's credit.
Rym: He hadn't actually interviewed anyone for GeekNights before and he learned quick.
Rym: I'm real proud.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah now we weren't even gonna have things of the day.
Rym: And in fact, we're now only gonna have one thing of the day because this is just too hilarious to pass up.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So one of our favorite people in the whole entire world MC Chris nerdcore hip-hop superstar.
Rym: I shook his hand at Katsucon.
Scott: Yeah apparently he had this rant about Kingdom Hearts 2 and Resident Evil 4 and some people took this rant and put some little video behind it and It's freaking hilarious.
Scott: It's like our new shtick.
Scott: We're gonna be like quoting this and referencing it all the time from now on.
Scott: we would have been doing it yesterday and you know Recent episodes, but we hadn't done it as a thing of the day yet.
Scott: So we didn't know if anyone to get the joke.
Scott: Yep, but you can expect us to be yelling push Hey push.
Scott: Hey zombies in your room.
Scott: It killed your parents.
Scott: zombies open the hell right now.
Rym: Yeah, this might even be up there with.
Rym: you can't blank ten blank.
Scott: I think it's gonna be up there with.
Scott: you can't blank ten blank.
Scott: You have to watch this thing of the day.
Scott: It's a mandatory thing of the day for everyone and also on the website There's a bunch of other videos that might amuse you.
Scott: So this interview we did was with Luke Crane the creator of the Fantastic burning wheel role-playing game system and also his right-hand man Tor Olav's rude.
Scott: The interview was taken at uber con 8 late on Saturday night when we were all tired and finished With a whole bunch of gaming.
Rym: it was very late and there was loud horrible karaoke going on not too far away.
Scott: Yes, we talked about his game.
Scott: We talked about metal.
Scott: We talked about.
Scott: you know What is the life of an RPG creator like all sorts of awesomeness?
Scott: and the interview is incredibly entertaining?
Scott: I'm even entertained by it and I gave the interview.
Scott: so I'm sure you will find it amusing Especially if you are a fan of RPGs.
Scott: and even if you're not a fan of tabletop RPGs and to all of our regular Listeners don't despair.
Rym: starting tomorrow.
Rym: We'll be back with the normal format of GeekNights at least until we get the normal season 2 format.
Rym: Oh, yes, the season 2 format, which is so different from season 1.
Guest 0: Yes I am the doom that came to sokokis All right.
Scott: Yes, Luke Crane the creator of the famous or infamous burning wheel.
Scott: Yes, role-playing game who you requested an interview with here is for your amusement.
Scott: So Let's see.
Scott: Where are you from?
Guest 0: That's fine.
Guest 0: I don't.
Guest 0: I don't remember where I'm front or where are you from Norway, Norway, right?
Guest 0: I'm not from Poland.
Guest 0: That's really all I can remember All right.
Scott: How did you um first start role-playing?
Guest 0: with some dice in the basement?
Guest 0: No, maybe maybe dice at a kitchen table and a maybe D&D expert set.
Guest 1: I started with the red box.
Guest 0: red box.
Guest 0: Yeah blue box.
Scott: All right I don't even know like the difference in the boxes.
Scott: Everyone talks about like white box pink box.
Guest 0: I'm like, you know why?
Scott: cuz you're a week Probably think that might have something to do with it.
Guest 1: It's what do you start with?
Scott: What I think I've played D&D second ed at summer camp.
Guest 1: So you're a kid 24.
Guest 0: Oh, oh god Somebody stab me a knife through my ribs.
Guest 0: My name is Luke.
Guest 0: Hey, I've been gaming for 20 years and I've been GMing for for 15.
Guest 0: I'm not telling you how old I am.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: If I were you I probably wouldn't tell me how old I was either.
Guest 0: I used to be the young guy in my in my peer circle, and I'm not anymore.
Rym: I'm pretty much the oldest one here among our group of friends.
Rym: So I just had to feel your pain.
Guest 0: but old man Yeah, I'm an old man.
Guest 0: He gets that a lot.
Guest 1: He was actually raised by a pack of wild old men.
Scott: You're only three months older than I am.
Scott: I know you're talking about that.
Guest 0: three months can mean a lot when you're 24 Alright.
Scott: so let's talk about burning wheel.
Scott: Where did burning wheel originate from?
Scott: like when did you first get the idea?
Scott: How did you actually you know go from thinking about it to actually doing it?
Scott: Because that seems to be most people's problem taking the idea, you know execution.
Scott: Let's see Who what why once we already know who.
Guest 0: I had a bad role-playing game session And I got really mad and I dragged my friend Dan out to a restaurant in the east West Village West Village called dojo's and I sat down and I said Dan we need to make our own game.
Guest 0: This game sucks.
Guest 0: and Dan said okay.
Guest 0: Awesome.
Guest 0: We should use eight-sided dice.
Scott: So what happened between then?
Scott: and publishing books and running around to every convention in the universe?
Scott: And being interviewed on podcast?
Guest 0: 14 years A lot a lot of stuff more funerals than weddings.
Guest 1: Oh Well, originally I mean you didn't even intend to publish burning wheel.
Guest 0: that's right, that's right Burning right.
Guest 0: burning wheel was just made to fix problems at my table.
Guest 0: It wasn't even called burning mill to start.
Guest 0: It wasn't even a fantasy game to start.
Guest 0: It was a science-fiction role-playing games.
Guest 0: this it was a science-fiction role-playing game We didn't intend to publish.
Guest 0: it was just to fix our deal to fix our damage.
Guest 0: damn it.
Guest 1: Actually, it was really neat last year when we held the release party for burning wheel revised and Luke brought out all of the old editions of burning wheel Everything from the pamphlets to the little black cover books.
Guest 0: How many yeah, I would basically Every six months or a year.
Guest 0: I would rewrite the whole game.
Guest 0: Actually, I kept translating it at one point.
Guest 0: I was translating it back from fantasy to science fiction science fiction.
Guest 0: I just rewrite the whole thing each time.
Guest 0: It's a good good exercise actually a painful, but good.
Guest 0: and then I would stay in Starting like 96.
Guest 0: I would start printing them myself I would do kinko's versions of the books and just print out.
Guest 0: print like a run of 12.
Guest 0: And I was so excited and I give them out to my friends and we'd have big burning wheel parties and play it.
Guest 0: That's fun.
Guest 0: It was terrible, but I mean it was fun.
Guest 0: fun to do.
Scott: So what makes burning wheel different and more awesome than every other role-playing system?
Scott: Because I agree that it is different and more awesome.
Scott: other role-playing system.
Scott: a lot of people go and they say I'm gonna make my RPG system and I'm gonna fix D&D cuz these are all the problems with it and they completely and utterly fail and no one plays Their game.
Guest 0: tour tours gonna answer this question doors gonna feel this one.
Guest 0: I met Tori at uber con and this very hotel Four years ago three years ago Three or four years ago, I think.
Guest 0: All right.
Guest 0: So right so and Torah since become pretty much my right leg Kicking me in the ass.
Guest 0: So alright, so tour what makes burning wheel special and rad.
Guest 1: Well, I think for me it's about the focus on I guess choices and consequences and I think that's the essence of good drama and The fact that burning wheel really supports that and Pushes you toward that Is is what makes it really special.
Guest 0: So how does it support choices and consequences?
Guest 0: better than well?
Guest 1: I think that it's.
Guest 1: it's simply the focus.
Guest 1: I mean first you've got your beliefs which are really what drive play.
Guest 1: every character has them every player writes them for his character and they're really about how the character gets rewarded and The GM is there to test those beliefs and you've constantly got to make choices About how strongly you believe in something and whether that belief is is worth it.
Guest 0: Sure.
Guest 0: Sure Interesting.
Guest 0: So alright, then that's pretty good.
Guest 0: I actually agree with Tor But you you played in my game last year.
Guest 0: Yeah, or even last February played inheritance last February.
Guest 0: So what tweaked your geek, what did you like?
Scott: oh man
Rym: Well, I actually played in a demo the previous year And I remember I saw you guys and I walked by and I saw you're running some game and I saw you at this Big placard and it you someone walked over and said, oh, this is burning wheels other role-playing system.
Rym: I said what whatever it's for some nerds making some things by terrible.
Guest 0: You were sure you were right because I've run into a bunch of terrible systems me too I'm one of them.
Rym: and then you actually came out and convinced me like hey, come here.
Rym: We're gonna do a demo.
Rym: We need a third person.
Guest 0: Oh great.
Rym: Yes, I sat down.
Rym: It was elves fighting dwarves and I thought this is dumb.
Rym: This is dumb.
Rym: This is dumb until we actually started using the game mechanics and I just thought wow a really big Combat took like a minute and a half to resolve.
Guest 0: That's amazing.
Rym: And then I'd look at it more and you said that there was a social conflict Thing and the idea of that was just fascinating.
Rym: I'd never seen a system that incorporated that before and it just it drove me wild.
Rym: So when I saw you were at this con the next year, I grabbed all my friends that we have to play this game.
Guest 0: Right, right.
Scott: Yeah, I know that rims biggest peeve is that whenever we play D&D it's you know Normal role-playing because we're okay role players and then as soon as there's a combat It's five hours of rolling dice and moving guys around a map.
Scott: So, you know See the fact that burning wheel compresses that into like ten seconds of people standing up and yelling instead of people lazing about bored.
Guest 0: Well, I mean ten seconds is perhaps But
Scott: relatively yeah,
Guest 1: but we definitely have some knockdown drag-out fights.
Guest 0: Yeah, every so often there's an aberrant burning wheel combat that will take three hours But more often than not maybe maybe an hour at the most and you're done and hard.
Scott: I guess what I really noticed about it is I played the the demo with like the thief You play the sword.
Scott: Yeah the sword and you know, it didn't you D&D It's really if the players are work.
Scott: You have to kind of work together.
Scott: Oh, it's like a party but in burning wheel you can all it's.
Scott: you're fighting the other PCs But you're all really going towards the same goal, which is not necessarily to achieve an in-game goal But to have an awesome role-playing game sure no matter what the result is.
Guest 1: Running the sword is really interesting actually because you can actually see When a person's comprehension there's lights up that they don't have to just go along with what everyone else is doing, right?
Guest 0: Right, right.
Guest 0: Right.
Guest 0: Yeah, it's not about that.
Guest 0: It's about.
Guest 0: It's about getting what you want and making it cool for everyone else.
Guest 0: And I mean that's not the only way to play burning wheel But it's definitely a way that it supports and it's functional and it's fun.
Rym: I mean playing that specific demo with Scott and Pete and you it did I had.
Rym: the revelation I had was that there can be Interpart or intra party conflict.
Rym: that doesn't ruin the game, right?
Rym: Then you can have characters that don't like each other and that fight with each other and that can make the story better.
Rym: Yes worse.
Guest 0: Yeah, and I actually try to foster that In my games.
Guest 0: I always have and I design burning wheel around that play priority.
Guest 1: Well part of that is just that you had players that would do that.
Guest 0: Anyway, yeah, my players are bastards.
Guest 0: So right, but I but I like it too.
Guest 0: I would I would engender it and you know It was one of my play priorities as a as a GM because one of the things that I just intuitively realized I did not I was not able to articulate until a few years ago Is it really the only thing happening at the table is the interaction between the players?
Guest 0: That is almost always the most exciting thing, you know, and the GM is a player.
Guest 0: in this case Sometimes every so often the GM hauls out some awesome description and everyone's like, yeah But other times, you know tour and I are going at it or arguing or whatever like torn I. actually we were playing a game recently and we clashed and got to a tussle and fought and and One of the other players thought it was over thought it was like the whole game was gonna end.
Guest 0: You know cuz you know, we threw each other into the into the bay or whatever.
Guest 1: We were having a blast Yeah, right.
Guest 0: or and I were like, right?
Guest 0: We were red-faced and bad.
Guest 0: But afterwards I was like, no, that was awesome That was totally what we would do and it was great and like.
Guest 0: and now we move on.
Guest 0: You know wasn't the end of the game.
Guest 0: It wasn't bad feelings, you know tour and I weren't Firing off angry emails to each other and it's been coloring everything that we've been playing since right.
Guest 0: so yeah that kind of conflict and strife or what it's all about for me and to Get that energy between the players and that kind of electricity going I think adds a lot to the game.
Scott: Yes, definitely what I felt when I played inheritance because usually, you know role-playing game is fun No matter which one you're playing, but it was always kind of easygoing.
Scott: No one was really passionate about what happened.
Scott: But when we played inheritance, we were screaming like someone would when someone was gonna roll an important role the whole table would stand Like a you know what a full count at a baseball game, you know with two outs.
Scott: Yeah, like come on and they're like sixes would come out to be screaming and yelling.
Guest 1: Yeah Yeah, that also brings up the other side of the equation that I mentioned earlier, which is choices and consequences.
Guest 1: Failure really means something in burning wheel.
Guest 1: There are consequences and It's interesting that failure can drive the game a lot of times.
Guest 1: you're moving from failure to failure and that's what's causing the players To send their characters in different directions different interesting directions that are really fascinating.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: Yeah in our recent game I would so I was kind of irritated with a lot of forum posts recently.
Guest 0: just people not kind of not getting the Not getting the failure stuff on the forums when I'm really just not getting the basic like die rolling stuff and burning wheel like Surrounding intent and task and failure and stuff like that.
Guest 0: So I made a character destined to fail and everything he did and I have so much fun playing this guy and he's not a Fuck-up, he's got dreams.
Guest 0: He's a real character.
Guest 0: You know, he's got a little depth I feel but you know, I love going.
Guest 0: I love saying, you know, alright I want to take this test and I know I'm gonna fail.
Guest 0: and I'm just looking at the GM with big puppy-dog eyes.
Guest 0: Please screw me.
Guest 0: Tell me what happens now.
Guest 1: As a matter of fact one of the first things that Luke did with that character was to make a circles role Which is a mechanic that allows you to bring in a new NPC And you get to describe how much you want to be able to determine about the NPC.
Guest 1: But if you fail the GM takes over and he can decide and he can invoke something called the enmity clause.
Guest 1: So Luke set himself up to fail that role and one die to roll one d6 Brought in a great villain that has been part of the game now for three four sessions.
Guest 0: Yeah Oh, yeah, I basically just threw a softball to the GM our friend my urn and he just hit it out of the park.
Guest 0: Just like yeah this dude You know just gave this dude a little character a name and a little character and so much fun.
Guest 0: all from failure.
Guest 1: I'm failure and the fact that we created him Just makes it really personal like we really care right what this guy does, right?
Guest 0: Oh, I like it Like I want to be him.
Scott: So anyway, so that blah blah blah boring bring real stuff boring boring boring Alright, so for someone out there who you know may or may not already be a gamer or not What do you suggest they do?
Scott: if they want to learn burning wheel get into it start playing it.
Guest 0: They should play If they're not a gamer if they are or they aren't well things if they're not a gamer they should play.
Guest 1: Prime time in prime time inspectors.
Guest 0: Yeah by Jared Sorenson.
Guest 0: prime time adventures by Matt Wilson dust devils by Matt Snyder writer.
Guest 0: Yeah other small press games which are designed for elegance and simplicity And but they have the same.
Guest 0: they have a very similar Aesthetic is burning wheel surrounding beliefs and consequences and stuff like that.
Guest 0: But they do not have the say tactical depth that my game Slavishly reproduces at the table.
Scott: I have to check those out and never heard of them.
Guest 0: Oh, yeah.
Guest 0: Yeah, they fantastic games really the pinnacle of Contemporary game design.
Guest 0: excellent stuff inspectors is is in my opinion.
Guest 0: Well up till very recently was the best game best role-playing game ever produced.
Guest 0: that may still be damn inspectors.
Guest 1: Damn it.
Guest 1: Are you thinking of lacuna?
Guest 0: I love lacuna Jared my friend Jared Sorenson's new game.
Guest 1: He's a rock star.
Guest 0: He is a game rock star.
Guest 0: this game you play these.
Guest 0: it's so easy.
Guest 0: I actually introduced someone to role-playing with it recently.
Guest 0: with using lacuna.
Guest 0: You play members of this mysterious company who have tapped the collective unconsciousness and you lie down on these like Slabs and they hook into your dreams.
Guest 0: and then you go into this into the collective unconsciousness and you eradicate aberrant personalities from people like you're like.
Guest 0: so you lie next to the slab like you're.
Guest 0: you're all in your slabs and the.
Guest 0: basically your Target is lying on a slab next to you And who's like a psychotic or you know, you know, hyper neurotic or something or schizophrenic or whatever.
Guest 0: And then you go into the collective unconsciousness you hunt down their aberrant personality and you destroy it and cure them.
Guest 1: Right.
Guest 1: Did you see the quotation marks there?
Guest 0: And oh, yeah, can you hear the quote?
Guest 0: you hear the quotation marks?
Guest 0: Thank you.
Guest 0: And the way gameplay works is It's all based on your heartbeat.
Guest 0: Anytime you want to do something.
Guest 0: You're just trying to.
Guest 0: Anytime you do something you increase your heart rate.
Guest 0: And so it.
Guest 0: it is incredibly simple incredibly elegant and it's so much fun to play.
Guest 0: It's got a great element of mystery But the GM actually can't make any rolls.
Guest 0: the GM can introduce tests and conflicts.
Guest 0: the GM doesn't actually roll anything.
Guest 0: It's so neat.
Guest 0: It's such a simple neat game design.
Guest 0: and so yeah, I've run it twice recently and had a blast yet or played in both games and I just Will find that and link to it.
Guest 0: Yeah lacuna.
Guest 0: Absolutely.
Guest 0: Um on Memento Mori Yeah, it's 20 bucks.
Guest 1: It's I'm telling you guys you can find inspectors there too.
Scott: Yeah, it's All right.
Scott: so if someone's already played these amazing games and they want to play burning wheel because they're listening to this show and they've been.
Scott: Somehow can sure sure.
Guest 0: Sure.
Guest 0: My first recommendation is come to a convention even one that.
Guest 0: Go to a convention and play games with other people.
Guest 0: go to convention.
Guest 0: ask people if they know about other games burning wheel or whatever.
Guest 0: What I found.
Guest 0: I've been doing the convention circuit for about four years now.
Guest 0: It conventions are a great way to meet other gamers.
Guest 0: who?
Guest 0: Suit your gaming type and get in games that you would not normally get because your group well, you know They like playing this one game.
Guest 0: So go to a convention.
Guest 0: try other things.
Guest 0: try new things.
Guest 0: push the limit if you see burning wheel.
Guest 1: But specifically for burning wheel if you can't get the full Luke crane experience we recommend going to our wiki and Downloading our demo the sword.
Guest 1: Yeah and running it for the group or players for players for pre-made characters You can run it in two to four hours.
Guest 0: Yeah, depending.
Guest 1: Yeah, it's a small commitment But it it will show you the possibilities.
Guest 0: Yeah Yeah.
Rym: So when you run these games at conventions and usually the scenarios you set up seem to be very much centered around Conflict within the party.
Rym: Yeah, you seem to act more like a director than a dungeon master Like these are people playing out a play out.
Rym: Just talk a little bit about how you get people to roleplay and how you draw out of them these emotions Just what you're thinking while you're running sure.
Guest 0: Yeah, I don't know how I get people to do anything really but um First of all, we start it starts at burning wheel headquarters with me and tour.
Guest 0: I'm serious.
Guest 0: and we where we design these characters we really carefully design the characters to make sure that all of the characters have a reason to be in the scenario and That we try to tie them all to each other.
Guest 0: Why?
Guest 0: One because my my goal at these demos is to teach people The game and to have them rolling dice in as much as possible using the mechanics of the game.
Guest 0: Now if I do that in a traditional game format You guys know there's a lot of like waiting your turn and stuff in a traditional game format Especially when you do not know the rules and you're not comfortable with the game.
Guest 0: So you're kind of like.
Guest 0: can I do this?
Guest 0: Can I do you know, so you're.
Guest 0: so there's waiting involved.
Guest 0: So I was like so I I ran the.
Guest 0: my initial demos were traditional role-playing games, you know We're you know traditional like go and solve this thing and get into a fight and win.
Guest 0: and Godin's predicament I'm going to predicament was the original one.
Guest 0: You had to rescue some guy from the roof of a house.
Guest 0: There were orcs in the house.
Guest 0: So and I was like, this is boring it sucked.
Guest 0: people were sitting around waiting their turn and and so I tried I tried something Different.
Guest 0: I tried to.
Guest 0: I tried the original poisonous ambition.
Guest 0: I tried to turn I tried to give them an external goal and an internal goal and it just lit on fire.
Guest 1: so poisonous ambition was a scenario in which you all played the members of an orc clan that was disintegrating just falling apart and the power structure was failing.
Guest 1: right and Everybody had you know a reason to go in there and just really tear stuff apart, right?
Guest 0: Right, and so I mean right.
Guest 0: you tell people right orcs Disintegrating clan, you know power struggle and immediately everyone gets it and they go.
Guest 0: I mean, yeah, the scenario was problematic but regardless though by basically giving all the players a stake giving them a tie to another character and Encouraging that behavior I if you played with me, you know, I go around.
Guest 0: I whisper in your ear.
Guest 0: Why are you sitting there?
Guest 0: What are you doing?
Guest 0: What do you want?
Guest 0: I looked.
Guest 0: I had players tonight whisper You freaking yell at people.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Guest 0: I get as the night goes on I I get a little testy but because I get Frustrated bored like you guys do and you guys have all the power in these scenarios.
Guest 0: But tonight there were.
Guest 0: I tried with two kids.
Guest 0: I did not succeed but I looked them in the eye and I said they were they were turtling they were sitting there just like Oh, and I said, what do you want from this?
Guest 0: What do you want to happen?
Guest 0: and they were like I want him to be punished then do it fight for it.
Guest 0: Don't back down and you know, they it.
Guest 0: this works and you know.
Guest 0: talking players is saying, you know And saying reminding players people that you can get what you want in the next four hours and you can have fun doing it Of course because you know you guys have played, you know, all right I'm gonna go for what I want and suddenly you get Sideswiped by someone else who want.
Guest 0: you know who wants something different or wants what you want But then somebody's saying well, but but wait you want that?
Guest 0: Well, then I'll ally with you I'll help you and suddenly you're in the mix.
Guest 0: Suddenly.
Guest 0: You can't get out.
Guest 0: It works really well.
Guest 0: It's it's really just by right knitting everything together with with beliefs and goals and Relationships and relationships right right and making everyone, you know, like I'm your son.
Guest 0: I'm your second-in-command.
Guest 0: I'm this on that.
Scott: It's hard to explain.
Scott: Um, so Burning Empires is your new.
Scott: Can you tell us a little about where that came from?
Scott: What it is?
Guest 0: Didn't you see the obelisk?
Scott: I did see the obelisk.
Scott: It was impressive.
Guest 0: Burning Empires is an evolution.
Guest 0: It's basically Burning Wheel 3.0.
Guest 0: So it is.
Guest 0: it's Burning Wheel that uses science fiction rules has vehicles and firefights and psychic powers and aliens and space and stuff and it's a It's.
Guest 0: but it's also an experimental game design.
Guest 0: We decided Tor and I Last year we said if we were gonna do this game based on these these comic books these burned these iron empires comic books Awesome.
Guest 0: Yeah, great.
Guest 0: Great comic books.
Guest 0: We needed to make the game different.
Guest 0: We needed to push Kind of push the envelope of design.
Guest 0: so so burning empires ended up being a game that combines strategy game elements And role-playing game elements and it works.
Guest 0: It's fun.
Guest 0: It's hard though.
Guest 0: It's like it's like you come out of that game and you're like damn that took a lot out of me.
Guest 0: Yeah, I mean you're.
Guest 0: it engages you on levels that that it uses muscles that you're not used to using in role-playing games.
Guest 1: well, I mean part of what we really consciously tried to do with this game was to Create the rules so that people who played it had to play the way that we play At our table, right which drives people drive some people crazy.
Guest 1: Some people love it.
Guest 1: Yeah, so I mean we really you know we set up this whole scene structure and that sort of thing to really pass the spotlight around and And make people really drive toward conflict, right?
Guest 1: Just like we do at home, right?
Guest 0: Yeah, that was one of our main conceits.
Guest 0: It was like people can run can turtle and run away from conflict and burning wheel and we're like Let's see if we can build it into the game design.
Guest 0: We literally cannot escape the spotlight where you know, you are thrust into the fire like, you know at every step And pretty a person's.
Guest 0: a pretty damn good attempt at that.
Guest 0: not perfect but pretty damn good attempt in that regard.
Scott: And it's got pretty art All right, so you talk about you know, how you trying to make people game the way you game at your table.
Scott: How do you game at your table?
Scott: And it's like I feel myself like like I want to gain like I can get an idea of the way you game at your Table even though I've never been there and like I want to get there but now I'm somewhere else.
Scott: What advice did you give someone who wants to game as awesomely as you do and just doesn't have the Cojones, all right Every game at our table is super hot.
Guest 0: Awesome.
Guest 0: Ah, you know, we we do the best we can with what we have.
Guest 0: Like all good things that arose from boredom We just basically got bored of fucking around and jerking off at the gaming table and we became conscious of these moments in play That we liked and we kind of look at each other.
Guest 0: So how can we keep doing the thing that we like to do and cut out the boring part?
Guest 0: and You know if and in my opinion if you play burning wheel as written Again, if you can like if you literally could void your mind of all the other concepts you have a role-playing that would happen.
Guest 0: Whether or not that's true.
Guest 0: I don't know but you know in my little imaginative game designer world That's what happens.
Guest 0: but I mean ultimately it comes down to a little a little communication Saying these are the things I would like in this game And then honestly the guts or the balls to step up and go for what you want.
Guest 1: I think it really comes back to the choices and consequences that I mentioned earlier.
Guest 1: We really try to To build those into each character and the GM is there to really focus on the Choices and consequences that you're interested in by looking at your beliefs and trying to challenge them.
Guest 1: right GM's gotta have balls, too and part of it is the.
Guest 1: the players have to have some empathy for each other and really focus on on what On the arc that someone wants for their character and try to shove them into the spotlight and make them make You know the hard choice that's really going to illuminate what that character is all about.
Guest 0: Yeah, I read this one a actual play report from a group out in like Arkansas or something.
Guest 0: These guys are really cool.
Guest 0: I ended up meeting them afterwards But they like they got it this they got the style of play when they realized that it was okay to build characters Destined to succeed or fail basically to end right and they played a game and they'd set up this big epic game and they were gonna play for months and they finish it in like three or four games and like Wham-bang crazy conflict like and the GM.
Guest 0: like realized at one point like somebody confronted like the Baron and it was his father and like You know like the Baron was there, and he's yelling at you and like the other player kind of you know I read this AP report.
Guest 0: kind of like got it.
Guest 0: He's like wait now is my chance like I have this belief about confronting my father And you know not letting him be an evil man.
Guest 0: well now is my chance.
Guest 0: right now and the boom game explodes things go crazy and it's over and Afterwards like they posted they were like they were delirious.
Guest 0: They're like oh my god.
Guest 0: That was it we get it.
Guest 0: We were like.
Guest 0: you know we we wrote you know we decided we want to play a game like this And we didn't pussyfoot around.
Guest 0: we did it you know.
Guest 0: and they said afterwards like wow well It could have gone longer would have been cool, but it's also cool that we Set out what we accomplished to set out and you know so they had a great understanding like oh well So we if we sculpt our goals in this particular way, then we can extend it we can make it longer.
Guest 0: I was like oh, yeah You know I'm just reading this I had nothing to do with that.
Guest 1: I I think actually that clarifies a point.
Guest 1: I was trying to make earlier, and maybe I didn't quite succeed in that Make characters that are in conflict with themselves That have competing goals that are mutually exclusive.
Guest 1: Yeah, eventually that character is gonna have to make a choice yeah, and go one way or the other and man that choice is awesome.
Guest 0: Right I mean in doing that it was something I realized recently.
Guest 0: doing that is making your character vulnerable rather than making a character with a tight concept.
Guest 0: rather You know I'm the loner.
Guest 0: I'm competent.
Guest 0: I can do everything I can handle it.
Guest 0: No problem.
Guest 0: That's cool.
Guest 0: That's fine.
Guest 0: That's for another game.
Guest 0: That's not for burning wheel.
Guest 0: a Character in burning wheel is vulnerable is at risk is at risk in himself is at risk in his environment Because that's where the tension comes from in these games.
Guest 0: is that because you're gonna
Scott: have to test to get by this
Guest 0: you're gonna have To push it you're gonna have to sweat it to do it And you know and it takes a little trust in yourself and a little trust in your other players to make your character Vulnerable to make your character open to danger and like whether it be like right you know getting pressured by your mom To do something that you don't want to do or like you know or starting off saying well You know I can make this character super badass swordsman But it would be much more interesting and dangerous to start as a guy who wants to be a badass swordsman you know and and Shove that into play or is pretending to be a badass swordsman and see it.
Guest 0: You know see if I can pull it off.
Guest 1: Well one of the character that I'm playing right now in the game that I'm playing with Luke is The only character in the group that has a combat skill, but it's a really really really low combat and You know and he's a character that wants to do the right thing.
Guest 1: But in the world that we're in doing the right thing all often means waiting into combat and pirates Terrifying every time.
Guest 1: every time I weighed in You know it could be the time that I die right you know and and I'm not very good at combat And I'm also You know I don't have very high steel.
Guest 1: steel is the morale mechanic in burning will.
Guest 1: so if I if I ever get wounded or Anything like that.
Guest 1: I'm gonna run right.
Guest 0: It's great.
Guest 0: And so it like.
Guest 0: on the other side of that we think of him as our hero and our you know and our you know Our heavy whatever, so we're like.
Guest 0: you know he'll take care of it He'll do it, but at the same time because of the way we've sculpted our world In order to create additional tension we hate him for it.
Guest 0: You know we hate that he kills people.
Guest 0: We don't none of our other characters kill anyone.
Guest 1: He hates himself for killing people too, right I mean.
Guest 0: so like you know we just we try to just knit together all these various motivations And and you know all these various vulnerabilities for the characters.
Guest 0: and just just see what happens to see.
Guest 0: See if it it's any more interesting than the shit.
Guest 0: We basically been doing for 20 or 30 years.
Guest 0: Wow depending how old you are That's the heavy shit all right.
Scott: Let's get.
Scott: let's get geeky and fun great.
Scott: Let's If it's not the funniest time tell us a funny story from a session.
Scott: Jesus like something hilarious that happened like where everyone was just laughing for 10 minutes and couldn't stop one time when we were playing D&D.
Guest 0: This was after burning wheels already in development.
Guest 0: I They were fighting a what are those things called a?
Guest 0: you want II.
Guest 0: come on coolest snake man with snake head You know with scimitars, and he was a sorcerer.
Guest 0: and I Recited an entire Slayer song.
Guest 0: I got up on the chair and screamed out No, what's it called?
Guest 0: the witch one on raining blood?
Guest 0: I know the words each layer, and I know the words, but I'm not gonna recite them now regardless.
Guest 0: I okay Slayer sound like Slayer Don't just not know this don't diss Slayer.
Scott: No you have no idea.
Guest 0: Okay.
Guest 0: Good good.
Guest 0: Good.
Scott: Good very good.
Guest 0: so I recited the whole Slayer song and then I rolled a 20 and I started running around screaming and like was awesome.
Guest 0: and then My and all they're all laughing at me all my players laughing at me.
Guest 0: and my friend Andy turns to my friend Pete and says Pete the chairs are empty for meaning basically.
Guest 0: I'm in the room alone and you know just playing by myself and and and pretty much it was true.
Guest 0: and And we we all laughing.
Guest 0: Hey, yeah, so there you go Slayer empty chairs alone.
Scott: You have a different one.
Guest 1: better I think that my funniest moment was probably during a kill puppies for Satan game.
Scott: No, I never heard of this game, but I suddenly have an urge by Vincent by Vincent Baker the same guy that did The vineyard.
Guest 1: yeah awesome, but kill puppies for Satan is is a different game than than dogs in the vineyard.
Guest 1: Yeah, you play loser Satanists who kill Fluffy little animals for Satan.
Guest 0: yeah, because that's all they can really master.
Guest 0: Anyway, go on come on tell the fucking story.
Guest 0: So don't milk it.
Guest 1: So near the near the end of the session someone has gotten the Necronomicon, and this is summoned this big massive demon.
Guest 1: and This guy was his total cut up during the entire game.
Guest 0: He was hysterical boy named Jill right.
Guest 1: yeah We were laughing non-stop.
Guest 1: So at one point someone goes to command the demon and he just steps forward and and rubs out the circle Right Protecting the demon.
Guest 1: and is this dog demon type thing?
Guest 1: Tentacles also tentacles, and I don't know who said what but his response was well fuck me.
Guest 1: and And the demon did.
Guest 1: Luke jumped up on the table.
Guest 1: Yeah, and did you hump his leg?
Guest 1: I got behind him.
Guest 1: I crawled over him got behind him And yeah, I think I think we were laughing non-stop for about 10 minutes.
Guest 1: other people in the room complained.
Guest 1: I think Khan security was called.
Scott: Yeah, we We were.
Scott: it was at Ubercon Wild gazebo.
Guest 1: it was a gazebo.
Guest 0: It was at a gazebo con.
Guest 0: Yeah Yeah, yeah, yeah, that's right.
Guest 0: Yeah, I actually described the Demon fucking him and yeah, and he loved it, and he yeah, he actually begged for more if I'm not mistaken So I don't know.
Guest 0: hopefully someone out there who's listening to this right now is laughing at that or maybe you Steve You're listening to.
Guest 1: if you are laughing you will like kill puppies for Satan.
Scott: Yeah All right, what do you guys do besides?
Scott: like?
Scott: what are you into besides role-playing making and playing role-playing games any other?
Scott: Things you do to entertain yourselves?
Guest 1: We go to a lot of metal shows yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Guest 0: I go to a lot of underground music shows in general metal hard coke punk Metal shows predominantly, but yeah, yeah, I that is Mike I do some my best thinking At metal shows surrounded by distortion.
Scott: name some bands.
Guest 0: Well, let's see let's go back in time.
Guest 0: Who have who do we just see we just saw the Melvin's and big business.
Guest 0: Melvin's a big business also Joe Lolly and his all-star.
Guest 0: yeah All-star cast.
Guest 0: Anyway, that was that actually show.
Guest 0: that show was religious.
Guest 0: I hadn't seen the Melvin's for about 10 years, and yeah I I came home basically a disciple of Christ.
Guest 1: any any band that does not have two drummers is only half alive.
Guest 0: They had they had two bands.
Guest 0: Yeah, and really I'm just not listening to any other bands Isis.
Guest 0: We saw Isis.
Guest 0: I saw we saw Isis twice and within a week pelican.
Guest 0: Yeah, that's a long time ago though with didn't we see to sphere.
Guest 0: since then we saw just fear mastodon.
Guest 1: mastodon sure tides.
Scott: More than one of these.
Guest 0: so your mouth of the architect That was one of the best shows I saw this summer.
Guest 0: black cobra Yeah, yeah, we I mean there's a there's a lot of opportunity to see underground music one of the best reasons for living in New York.
Guest 0: Yeah, zombie Not metal, but awesome Totally awesome.
Guest 0: saw John Spencer in the heavy trash, too.
Guest 0: That was good.
Scott: um So like metal we recently saw wearing the Isis shirt right now and Poughkeepsie operatic or whoever they are.
Scott: but yeah It sucks.
Scott: They were okay.
Guest 0: No.
Guest 0: I have no idea what any of that is.
Guest 0: so it's good They're.
Guest 0: yeah tastes are equally obscure.
Guest 0: Yeah, that is good.
Guest 0: It would it would suck if we actually like the same.
Guest 0: I can.
Scott: I supremacy what's what mock?
Scott: and I supremacy.
Scott: They're Swedish or Norwegian.
Scott: I don't know.
Guest 0: we even listen to that shit.
Guest 0: We go overseas for our music.
Guest 0: Okay.
Guest 0: Okay link link link link.
Guest 1: my supremacy Clear that Drozdul is falling apart on us.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: He's he's the pole that finds most of our music.
Guest 1: Yeah, that's it.
Guest 1: That's his job.
Guest 0: He just likes black metal now.
Guest 1: He's retreated into his black metal turtle shot, dude Let's say it's all Zyklon which Luke is really New enslaved dude.
Guest 0: dark throne dark throne all right.
Guest 0: and the wire that's the other thing that we do pretty much.
Guest 0: we watch the wire and And we go to metal shows and go out for good food.
Scott: Do you have a day job or is burning wheel it?
Guest 0: Talk about work.
Guest 0: You don't have to say is work is the most colossally boring?
Guest 0: is this what you?
Guest 0: so?
Guest 0: What do you do when you go to a party?
Guest 0: is that what you ask?
Scott: no no, but?
Guest 0: Why?
Guest 1: Now you're getting the full luke crane treatment.
Guest 0: my burning wheel does not pay my bills Which is a sad thing.
Guest 0: I sell a lot of copies of burning wheel and I sell a burning wheel is Probably the best-selling underground role-playing game out there.
Guest 0: Maybe even the best-selling press role-playing game out there it.
Guest 0: I do not make a living from it.
Guest 0: I wish I could buy more games.
Guest 0: Support your designers.
Guest 0: support your favorite designers Kevin Sambieta.
Guest 0: support Kevin Sambieta by by Palladium.
Guest 0: Well, how do you know what your listeners care about?
Scott: We have a forum we know just like you.
Scott: you know your players care about.
Guest 0: I don't know.
Guest 0: I don't care anymore.
Guest 1: I just do what I want lies damn lies.
Guest 0: If you got you looked at me like quizzically when I said the wire Yeah What's the wire?
Guest 0: HBO.com dude?
Guest 0: Oh, we don't watch television, so I don't watch television either I really don't.
Guest 0: but Tor got me hooked on this.
Guest 0: the show that's out We do.
Scott: we watch things on DVDs and maybe Netflix first.
Guest 0: three seasons are on DVD.
Guest 0: Do you like police dramas?
Guest 0: you like cop track my grandma.
Scott: what my grandma if I go to Florida to visit my grandmother?
Scott: I don't sit there because this is what she does.
Scott: and what can I do?
Scott: I'm in this house in the old folks home in Florida right oh shit.
Scott: all she does is watch Shows involving police and lawyers and detectives.
Scott: the wire is nothing like those she wakes up until like dinner.
Guest 0: But she might like the wire even though yeah, it's hard to describe It's a procedural police drama, and it is completely unknown.
Guest 0: No one watches it.
Guest 0: It's got rave reviews and It kills me.
Guest 0: It's my Lord of the Rings it.
Scott: are we gonna make Burning Wheel the wire?
Guest 0: no never it's.
Guest 1: We're not good enough.
Guest 0: frankly It's It's so good.
Guest 0: Yeah, I enjoy watching that television very much.
Guest 0: It satisfies me.
Guest 0: I'm telling you it's my Lord of the Rings.
Rym: so a couple of fun questions before we get on with our busy hectic convention.
Rym: live Real not your favorite movie ever because that's a stupid questions.
Guest 0: heart seven samurai.
Rym: oh Wow That's a very good choice.
Rym: You win.
Guest 0: wow.
Rym: so name a favorite movie
Guest 0: to our spot on-spot oh
Guest 1: Spirited away.
Guest 0: Wow all right.
Guest 0: wow we just did.
Guest 0: we're such geeks to Japanese movies, so are you an anime fan?
Guest 1: I'm not.
Guest 1: actually I mean I appreciate it.
Guest 1: There are certain things that I love Ghost in the Shell - Rockin, but uh I'm not thoroughly versed in anime.
Guest 1: I I love good fiction.
Guest 1: I love good drama.
Guest 1: I love good movies.
Scott: Do you read comics manga?
Guest 0: Anything?
Guest 0: yeah a little bit Ford to buy new comics.
Guest 0: And I actually people can.
Guest 0: I love the comics medium.
Guest 0: I love the way stories are told in comic books.
Guest 0: I love it like I love the wire, but um But obviously iron empires right we dig the the Dark Horse stuff.
Guest 0: Yeah Iron Empire stuff, but um I don't like the format that comics are produced in anymore.
Guest 0: as I get older I I hate comic books.
Rym: We have a motherfucking rant about that.
Rym: Don't get us started on the comic book distribution model and diamond and trade Paperbacks and how things should be and why manga is doing well in comics art and underwear perverts and superheroes.
Guest 0: Sure, okay.
Guest 0: I'm not.
Guest 0: I underwear perverts pretty much puts the brakes on anything.
Rym: I'm gonna say Do you know about the underwear pervert thing like what we're referring to?
Guest 0: oh Jesus?
Guest 1: I have.
Rym: no We've explained this for our listeners before.
Rym: we'll do it again because this will be humorous.
Rym: Marvel in DC Trademarked superhero and super - hero.
Rym: Yeah, I know a long time ago Yeah.
Rym: So recently Boeing Boeing this blog found out and they said well We're going to respect their trademark from now on any comic involving superheroes.
Rym: We're going to call it underwear pervert comic.
Rym: and it caught on on the internet.
Rym: And now that's what a lot of hip internet types call Comics underwear pervert comics or underwear pervert picture books.
Guest 0: right we tour And I were at Harvard for a con last year for very con very con.
Guest 0: and who's that dude that spoke we saw some dude who's.
Guest 0: Who did a lecture on the on the medium?
Guest 1: I can't remember.
Guest 1: It was really fast.
Guest 0: He did a lecture.
Guest 0: remember that genre fiction in comic books comics as genre, and it was awesome.
Guest 0: And he talked about underwear pervert not in not using those words and how like how they can get Twisted and reformatted into like we're like Superman's got a day job.
Guest 0: He's wearing normal clothes, but he's still Superman.
Guest 0: He's dealing with all that stuff and like why it appeals You know as genre fiction, and what like how it taps into the main.
Guest 0: Superman is like geist.
Guest 0: Really fascinating lecture.
Guest 0: so yeah, we geek out about comic books on occasion.
Rym: Have you read any of Alan Moore's stuff?
Guest 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I haven't been able to make it through from hell, but I haven't able to get a copy all right.
Scott: So really yeah, I have.
Scott: I have a pretty pretty good soon because I think I don't know who it's from anyway.
Scott: How about webcomics you read?
Guest 0: Uh I read.
Guest 0: I spend so much time on the web.
Guest 0: I don't have any time to read and our friend our friend Storn cook Does true.
Guest 1: does it really cool comic?
Guest 1: What's it called?
Guest 0: It's sword and sorcery or sword and sorcery or cats paw cats paw sword and sorcery.
Guest 0: The thread on our forums is called sword and sorcery comic, so I'm like.
Guest 0: it's called sword and sorcery.
Guest 0: Yeah, it's called cat spa And that's that's really neat.
Guest 1: and then there were some.
Guest 1: There are two dudes.
Guest 1: Someone someone linked to their webcomic on our forums also a dire destiny, which is really freaking cool.
Guest 0: Oh, yeah, I haven't read that one, but you know I ever so often if you searched all my IP logs Are you'd find that some order of the stick or some?
Guest 0: That other guys on the West Coast the penny arcade guys you know everything.
Guest 0: I chuckle But I have so much forum duty and blog duty that I just have no time for anything.
Scott: So you say you spend a lot of time on the web.
Scott: is that all form and blog or are there like other sites you?
Guest 0: Visit regularly on my wiki.
Guest 0: Yeah, I I visit RPG net indie RPGs calm story games calm and world the RPG site Burning wheel doc bring wheel calm like I nerd NYC nerd NYC calm.
Guest 0: right I mean just.
Guest 0: I'm cycling through them constantly answering questions about the game promoting the game.
Guest 0: You know chatting with my friends You know I'm always.
Guest 0: I'm slavishly read ken heights blog because I'm a can't hide fanboy now.
Guest 0: I don't even know why.
Guest 0: and Yeah, my friends blogs all I hate.
Guest 0: all my friends have blogs now And I gotta go read them.
Guest 0: see just to keep up with the conversation.
Guest 0: I have to go read the blogs.
Guest 0: I don't know if you experience that but like suddenly everyone will be talking about something I'll have no clue and I'll be like oh, it's on his blog.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I hate that shit, too.
Scott: Web listen any podcast.
Scott: Do you know what a podcast was before we approach you?
Guest 0: Yes?
Guest 0: I do.
Guest 0: I mean sons of cryos Have games will travel.
Guest 1: Durham three.
Guest 0: Durham three.
Guest 0: Murrell's podcasts recently.
Guest 0: listen to that.
Guest 0: David Newton and my girls.
Guest 0: David Newton The game says just had me on those crazy kids from like Alabama or something.
Guest 0: They had me on for an interview recently.
Guest 0: never listen to their podcast, but I. but I like podcasts But I don't have any time.
Guest 0: I'm so busy listening to all that metal.
Scott: Yeah, I really only have time because I commute in the car and I'm a programmer so I can sit at work and listen at The same time.
Guest 0: right I actually sometimes I'll listen at work, but For most of the time what I do I can't have like words or voices.
Guest 0: Yeah, because I'll start typing what I'm writing is just fine right.
Guest 0: well metal is.
Guest 0: I mean I'm right I'm listening to the rhythm and whatever.
Guest 1: So you can't listen to hip-hop while working.
Guest 0: yeah, I can't.
Guest 0: I love hip-hop But I can't let's do it while working right because I start like just sitting there listening to the rhymes.
Rym: You're like new hip-hop old hip-hop.
Rym: What kind of hip-hop?
Rym: I like.
Guest 0: I recently made my brother a 2 CD hip-hop mix that goes from 1984 to 2006. oh It starts.
Guest 0: it starts off with I think hard times by run DMC.
Guest 0: so They're coming to your town and it ends with some Dalek.
Guest 1: Dalek.
Guest 1: I listen to Saul Williams New hip-hop artists.
Guest 0: There's all our geeky boring details.
Guest 0: man See I got a really that on fast.
Scott: I got a random question.
Scott: Where's the burning wheel logo come from?
Scott: obviously?
Scott: It's a wheel on fire.
Scott: But is there like some sort of symbolism with the with the?
Scott: you know one cog or something or the spoke or is it just?
Guest 0: Some guy Did some guy design it yet some guy obviously pretty wheel is not a unique symbol.
Guest 0: It's not an original symbol as evidenced by Chris Muller's comics.
Guest 0: the burning wheel The burning wheel is a symbol into bedding mythology.
Guest 0: There's a wheel of life.
Guest 0: There's the wheel of fate in medieval Europe.
Guest 0: one of the reasons Why I wanted this symbol, and I actually it was a symbol in my game before it was anything else.
Guest 0: I'm not getting all dreamy like looking out there into the past.
Guest 1: It was actually an artifact in your game, right?
Guest 0: It was a symbol first and then an artifact.
Guest 0: The design is based on a sketch by Joseph Campbell in Primitive mythology I think from a rock found at Lake Baikal.
Guest 0: I'm fairly certain and it is essentially You know imagine the imagine the wheel But with just the the lines pointing inward just like it was if someone just scratched it in without actual the wheel circumference.
Guest 0: And he said basically the that the spiral and the star and whatnot were symbols of gateways to the other world placed at gravesites.
Guest 0: and so I said I Let's say that's fucking awesome.
Guest 0: And so I made a stylized version of that.
Guest 0: And and this so I made a solid version.
Guest 0: I introduced it as an artifact in the game And it just stuck it just and it this thing became a symbol of gateway to the other world.
Guest 1: And your players totally geeked out when you actually named your game that.
Guest 0: Yeah Kind of I got mixed reviews, then they gave me skeptical looks.
Guest 0: they were too close to it.
Guest 0: Yeah, I've actually I've never released the stats for the damn wheel I keep meaning to.
Scott: It will burn your heart All right, so to finish give all your you know infos your websites And you're how people can give you monies and all that good stuff.
Guest 0: Sure sure.
Guest 0: yeah, who the hell is this?
Guest 0: who's this guy that Babylon about metal and wheels?
Guest 0: Blake my call?
Guest 0: what the fuck?
Guest 0: I want to go to Lake Baikal, but it scares me.
Guest 0: So yeah, I live at Lake Baikal.
Guest 0: Sorry my name is Luke crane.
Guest 0: I published the burning wheel fantasy role-playing system and the burning empires Role-playing game.
Guest 0: you can find me on the web at burning wheel calm and burning empires calm And I am always happy to chat on my forums or even via email if you have any questions about what I do.
Guest 1: Tor Olives rude.
Guest 1: I'm also at burning wheel calm and burning empires calm.
Guest 1: also my blog The well averred which is at a Erdwell dot blog spot.
Guest 0: calm all right.
Guest 0: Thank you so much guys for having us on.
Guest 0: It was great really appreciate it.
Guest 0: Thanks.
Guest 0: Thank you for Participating.
Guest 0: yeah, yeah, I can't wait to hear it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.