Scott: It's Wednesday November 15th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight We discussed the comic ex machina.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So today down at Fordham Plaza I was done with some work and I had to go to an ATM to get enough money to pay for the parking to Get out of the parking garage.
Rym: I was in so on my way back from getting a bunch of money out of this really dodgy looking ATM on the street near Grand Concourse in the Bronx.
Scott: I would never use an ATM on the street ever.
Rym: Well, I found one legitimate looking ATM, right?
Rym: And it was out of order and I needed money cuz I had to pay to get my car out of this garage.
Rym: I was parked there for an hour.
Rym: So it was like 20 bucks.
Rym: I Mean my company's gonna pay me back.
Rym: It's not like it's a big deal.
Scott: But yeah, I know it's just annoying.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so as I'm on my way out I decided to get a smoothie and there's another gentleman who is standing there waiting for his smoothie while I order mine and he looks like a punk kid a. he looks about my age maybe a little younger and he's talking into a cell phone kind of hunched over and I hear him say the words Man, man, there's there's an emergency.
Rym: Yeah, this is deep shit.
Rym: One of my boys was over on like I forget what Street he said and he saw James.
Rym: Yeah that fucker.
Rym: Well, tell you what rounded boys up and we're gonna go get him.
Rym: meet me at blah and he talks for a while.
Rym: Then he hangs up takes a smoothie and walks away and I think My guess is that this is some sort of gang-related violence that was being planned in line for my smoothie.
Scott: Yeah, if you're not lying It would be hard to disagree.
Rym: I mean the guy had a blue kind of bandana around his head and all that and the conversation was very very not up to The standards of moral behavior.
Scott: Sounding was he a crip or a blood or perhaps a hoodlum?
Rym: Well considering that he was wearing a lot of blue if he's anything he was probably a crip.
Rym: Not that I know much about.
Scott: I don't know shit about that.
Scott: I know as much as I knew from that South Park.
Scott: Yeah, Timmy Yeah That wasn't even in that episode was because remember they would go in there and he'd be like just take my money.
Rym: But he didn't say okay.
Rym: I guess he did kind of yeah.
Rym: Yeah Actually, we've been watching a lot of South Park lately.
Rym: We have indeed and we've been trying not to let the South Park slip in.
Rym: but it's real easy to quote South Park.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically taken over for the Simpsons.
Rym: Yeah, the only thing bigger than that for us is still you can't watch Tim Simpson.
Scott: Yeah, you can't.
Scott: you can't prevent ten South Park things.
Rym: It's not Snorlax.
Rym: That's Borlax Borlax.
Rym: Anyway, we actually are gonna take a trend from.
Rym: you know, anime world order and all that.
Rym: We've got two Anime related newses for anime manga comics day.
Scott: You can't have two anime related newses.
Rym: I Don't know why but I didn't expect you to say that I really didn't know where.
Rym: Yeah, so bust out with your news.
Scott: so at the New York Comic Con Great.
Rym: Great.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't know the New York Comic Con is a new comma convention That's in New York City at the Jacob Javits Center.
Scott: The first one ever was last year in February.
Scott: I tried to go to it and failed because they had it in the small.
Scott: if you ever been to the Javits Center There's a big ass open room that can be divided into three pieces But usually it's one big ass room and when someone has a convention there They use the whole big ass upstairs room.
Scott: Like the car show uses the whole upstairs There's also a downstairs for smaller shows.
Scott: the New York Comic Convention used one half of the downstairs and Sold way more tickets than they could fit people in there, which was dumb.
Scott: So after not being able to get into the convention, I was like fuck these people don't know how to run a convention.
Rym: Yeah, Scott wasn't the only one boned.
Rym: I'd say the majority of people who tried to go to this convention got boned.
Scott: Yeah, there are people with pre-orders who couldn't get in.
Rym: there were guests.
Scott: there were guests who were in like Doug Rushkoff who was there, you know signing his book that he writes at the DC table was in there signing his book.
Scott: Then he went out.
Scott: then he couldn't get back in.
Scott: Yeah, it was the president of DC Comics.
Scott: Can you anyway?
Scott: This convention which is going to be held again this year and will supposedly Be using the upstairs and have all the space it needs and not be crowded and impossible to get into but still have all the high high-profile guests Apparently is going to also have the American Anime Awards at it this year.
Scott: Now the American Anime Awards are apparently just gonna be some of you know official awards ceremony for American anime and manga or not.
Scott: so much American anime and manga but Manga and anime that has been released in America this year, you know.
Scott: So why?
Scott: I guess Ava is never gonna win But I gave someone puts out a new release of it this year.
Scott: ATV puts out a release this year.
Scott: Maybe that release might be eligible for a prize or something.
Rym: Yeah, they got a whole bunch of categories here Like the best actor best actress best actor in a comedy.
Rym: they break off comedy from.
Scott: it's weird because they have special Awards for comedy, but they don't have special awards for any other genre.
Scott: Comedy is the only genre breakdown and I can kind of see why.
Scott: being that in comedy not being serious I mean dramas serious most action or kind of serious at least an anime, you know, but comedies are never serious.
Scott: So it's hard to win a best something award when your show isn't serious.
Scott: So comedy would be the first genre you would break out.
Scott: But yeah best DVD package design Yeah best anime theme.
Scott: so here's the ones I don't get.
Scott: if these are the American anime Awards, right?
Scott: Why you can't really give the awards based on the quality of the anime itself because the anime is made by people in Japan.
Scott: You know, it's not you got to give awards for the work done by the American.
Scott: necessarily what?
Rym: because I mean what you could do at least what I would do for the words like this is it's the American awards Being given to whoever so they're given.
Scott: But I'd still say the focus should at least in my opinion be on the work that is done Bringing it over to America and not on the work creating the original work because that's not the American animals.
Scott: No, just beat the anime Awards.
Rym: I don't know I would.
Rym: I mean I see what they're doing here.
Rym: You know, I see what you did here.
Rym: Yeah they're trying to bring anime into the mainstream because this is the kind of thing that would generate a lot of press releases and The news would at least pay lip service like and blah blah blah won the anime Awards last weekend at the New York City comic-con.
Scott: Yeah, I think what it really is.
Scott: if you look at any other sort of products DVDs in general books They always put labels on them of awards they've won.
Scott: like you go to the store and you look at a DVD and it's always got those like this.
Scott: would all these awards at These film festivals and they've got those little like wheat kind of little icons.
Scott: You know you go buy books in the store and books always have like.
Scott: I was in the New York Times bestseller list and I won The author won Hugo and Nebula Awards for sci-fi science fiction and blah blah blah.
Scott: But anime can't say really anything about awards except for the occasional oscar-nominated Miyazaki movie.
Rym: Well, there are words in Japan that Americans don't know anything about.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even know if there are words in Japan.
Scott: Well, I think about them at all.
Rym: I have seen or heard of anime that have won various awards, but I don't think they're that big.
Rym: even in Japan They might be like, I mean GeekNights can give out awards.
Rym: Yeah, I hereby give the award for best podcast to GeekNights.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Oh, but even comic books in America They've got Eisner Awards and Harvey Awards and stuff, but anime doesn't.
Scott: so the reason they're having this is probably you know one to generate a lot of.
Scott: you know, anime action in an industry that's not doing as well as it was before media play without a business and To now when they put anime, you know, you go into the store You see all this anime and if you don't keep up with it on the internet You don't know what's good and what's bad, but if they can start putting stuff like one best anime of 2001 You know, it'll sort of bring stuff out to people who just walk around looking at the shelf.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I imagine what's going to happen is they're going to be announced and all the super fans who watch everything You know the day after it comes out in Japan fan sub from bit torrent are gonna bitch about how?
Rym: Oh, but they didn't.
Rym: they don't know anything about Nana and ergo proxy and whatever I'm watching right now.
Rym: Therefore they're crap and they're wrong.
Rym: I Imagine a lot of other people are going to complain about how the show that should have won Didn't win and the people who think that the show that won deserved it Probably won't say anything because they won't even know.
Scott: so the same shit that everyone does for every other stupid meaningless award.
Rym: Yeah, I I mean as a person I could.
Rym: I couldn't care less about all these words.
Rym: the Academy Awards.
Rym: I haven't even known who won for the last several years.
Scott: I just find it funny that they're giving out the American Anime Awards at the New York Comic Con instead of that Oh to count a car anime Expo.
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: It's like they're just totally disrespecting the anime conventions to go to the comic convention.
Scott: Anime is putting comics.
Scott: Yeah, they're there.
Scott: I don't get it.
Scott: I don't know what the logic is with that one.
Rym: Yeah, well, did they say anything in the article?
Rym: I didn't read the whole article as to why they chose the New York Comic Con.
Scott: No, I have no idea.
Scott: Anime and manga are an important part of what the New York Comic Con is here to celebrate.
Scott: We're proud to be hosting this special event.
Rym: All right, something must have changed hand somewhere.
Scott: I mean, maybe I could see anime was a relatively had a pretty good presence at the Comic Con.
Scott: It is primarily a comic convention.
Scott: Well, the thing the anime people were doing stuff there.
Rym: Here's what I've noticed.
Scott: What's her name?
Scott: the macross min-may.
Rym: yeah, they did there last year but going like going to the one comic-con I went to and Hearing reports from other people who go to comic cons It seems like a lot of anime fans are really starved for more cons and more anime stuff.
Rym: so a lot of anime fans end up going to comic cons and I guess spoiling the fun of the super fans who are angry that there's people dressed up as Naruto at their comic convention.
Scott: Yeah, there were a bunch of narutards in line when I was waiting outside.
Rym: Well at the Philly wizard world that comic-con the only people who would interview with me other than those two guys who were looking for Silver Age comics and only Silver Age comics were all these people who actually weren't having a good time But they were all anime fans cosplaying as anime things who didn't know that comic conventions aren't like anime cons.
Scott: Yeah, and there were some anime type people in the artist alley.
Rym: Yeah, there were.
Scott: but yeah, I'm just saying you know, this is I Don't know and the American Anime Awards at the New York comic convention.
Scott: What are you gonna do?
Rym: Well, the thing is I don't want to ever bother with the New York comic convention after what happened last year.
Scott: Yeah, I really don't want to.
Rym: but now it's kind of like We're gonna have to send someone to cover this thing.
Scott: now I might just go like for the what's that?
Scott: I think I'm gonna go with my original plan of.
Scott: I'm gonna let people who are gonna go on Friday Well, tell me what happened there and then on Saturday, I'll go down.
Rym: if the word is good Well what I might do because now our situation is reversed.
Rym: I work in the city.
Rym: Mm-hmm So I might just go there Friday.
Scott: Oh good.
Scott: Then you could tell me if it was worth going.
Scott: Yeah There is the thing about the New York Comic Con that other comic cons don't have is they really do have Lots and lots and lots of high-profile people in you know comics and a whole bunch of other related industries
Rym: Except I've found and even the anime cons even even if I really like a guest and I really want to hear what they have to say usually Even big names that conventions tend to either Answer a lot of stupid questions from people in the audience that are just completely Retarded because people ask the craft that you can find in Wikipedia.
Rym: They're like, so what was your favorite thing that you ever directed?
Scott: I hate that shit.
Rym: Yeah, no one
Scott: ever don't ask a question that Google can answer Yeah,
Rym: or a question that's just lame or the kind of question that everyone in the world would ask ask something weird Or something cool or something interesting Mm-hmm, and I wish I wish
Scott: I kind of questions the GeekNights would ask if they were interviewing the person for a show
Rym: or Even anime world order.
Rym: Yeah what I have always wanted and I pushed this at Cinecon But the con really wasn't set up for it and I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm trying to push this as some other cons But instead of having a panel where the guest comes up does their spiel and then the audience asks questions I'd rather see a moderated discussion or an interview panel where?
Rym: Someone is up front and the guest is up front and the someone interviews the guests like it was a talk show Like like Stephen Colbert interviewing someone.
Scott: or even better if people wanted to ask questions at the panel they would have to write them and they had a single line to write them on.
Scott: none of this pair because The one thing I hate.
Scott: this bothered me a lot because I was watching a Video of Richard Dawkins asking a question and people when they're at panels or lectures They just ask some of them not everyone.
Scott: They ask questions so poorly like they they just keep saying a whole bunch of extra words.
Scott: It's like just say your fucking question.
Scott: This guy was like well considering blah blah blah blah blah in relation to blah blah blah blah and blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: The question.
Scott: you should have just said the question because some people not not to you know.
Rym: Call a kettle.
Rym: that may be a certain color a certain color But some people like to hear the sound of their own voice And - really and this bothers me a lot because I see this is so many cons people Want to sound smart and look cool?
Rym: So they get up front and they try to ask a smart question and they use all those big words and semi-colons.
Scott: The way it is to look cool when asking a question is to have a really short question.
Scott: That's really direct and it is also really witty.
Rym: You mean like when I asked Magic Johnson how it was to work with?
Rym: Captain Lou Albano on the Super Mario Brothers Super Show.
Rym: That is a perfect exam and wait That was one of my favorite moments in life.
Scott: Mm-hmm When his head hits his answer just or the other way to do it is to ask a perfectly normal question Like when are you going to do blah?
Scott: And then you know to have like a witty answer like if he says yes Then I'll say this.
Scott: if he says no, then I'll say this and it'll be funny.
Scott: either way It's like when are you going to do blah?
Scott: Never you suck, you know, but not you suck something clever.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right Yeah, but I just I'd love to see you know A David Letterman style kind of just interview the guest in front of an audience Mm-hmm because things like having one guy talk at you.
Rym: you guys who heard the only Rym Episode or the only Scott episode of the show know that one guy talking is a lot less Interesting and a lot harder to do than two guys talking.
Scott: Yep, also, you know that way the time won't be wasted asking all these questions that are just like no comment.
Scott: What's your favorite color?
Rym: How old are you?
Scott: what they should do really is they should have.
Scott: the people who want to ask a question should submit the question Beforehand like I don't know maybe on a website or something and then someone will take this list of questions Submitted by people at the panel somehow.
Scott: Maybe use technology to do it in some way and then cross off all the ones that are stupid and just ask all the good questions.
Rym: or or and I Did this to a degree at the Anime Club Summit at Otakana?
Rym: I think two years ago one of them where instead of sitting on the panel I decided to be the main DMC and I walked around with the microphone and while they were answering a question up there I'd wander around the audience with my mic off Talk sit down next to the people who had questions and talk to him a bit like so what do you want to ask blah?
Rym: Alright, uh, you want to ask this or that and I'd get it out of them and I'd kind of assess him and if they Were cool, I'd hand him the mic and let him ask the question.
Rym: Otherwise I would ask the question for them or I would just wouldn't ask their question.
Rym: that way No one dumb could get a hold of that microphone.
Scott: Yeah If you had like two or three staff Two could probably do it for a small panel easily because one person is there with the current question and the other person Is looking for the next question just goes and screens the questions, you know, then it works out.
Rym: Great Alright, so to get on to some other news.
Scott: Wow, that was long news.
Rym: Yeah, it was but there's a lot to say.
Rym: Dragon Ball Z. Oh god is being.
Scott: you can't watch ten Dragon Ball Z.
Rym: How about you can't watch?
Rym: 290 or more Dragon Ball Z There?
Scott: I guess you could because there are that many.
Scott: there are over 290 episodes of Dragon Ball Z Actual half-hour episodes or the 15-minute one actual episode.
Rym: Now the awesome thing is that Dragon Ball Z due to popular demand is being Remastered frame for frame by Funimation for a super uber ultimate awesome DVD box set release of all of it.
Scott: Well, I guess that's sort of a good thing.
Scott: in 1080p That's sort of silly.
Rym: with digital Remastering and everything they're removing It's a little bit excessive.
Rym: They're doing a brand new print from the well a brand new transfer from the original prints and They're remastering it entirely frame by frame in 1080p.
Rym: They're going to sell it season by season for 4998 which is season.
Rym: Yeah, which is like 900 minutes of anime for 50 bucks.
Rym: It might in other words in other words for 50 bucks you get one and a half fights.
Scott: But I'm sure so it might.
Scott: actually being not a fan of Dragon Ball Z at all Actually being a hater of Dragon Ball Z. It might be worth it to just buy season one.
Rym: See I remember in high school I'd always come home and I set my VCR to take Pokemon.
Scott: Wait, are these gonna be HD DVDs?
Scott: Or blu-rays?
Scott: cuz how else is it gonna be 1080p?
Rym: They're just gonna be DVDs.
Scott: How is it gonna be 1080p?
Rym: I think they're they're remastering it in 1080p, but then they're gonna transfer to DVD when they're done.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know that's kind of weird, but it's very specifically says DVD okay.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I don't know if anyone's gonna release much on blu-ray or HD DVD anytime soon Considering the market for it.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I do think it's a good idea though because you know the anime industry not Like I said before not doing as well as it was doing in a few years ago Since the media play thing and everything and you know They brought out over a lot of new shows, but none of the new shows are really the smash hits, you know.
Rym: Oh, oh, hey dinner up, but I just I read the article more thoroughly.
Rym: 1080p is what they did.
Rym: the transfer in and the remastering in.
Rym: okay So they'll have it ready.
Rym: if they want to release it in the future on whatever HD format there is It'll be ready to go.
Rym: But anyway continue.
Scott: Yeah, but You know, they they pretty much already re-released all the hit series.
Scott: I mean, they've re-released Ava six times.
Scott: They already re-released cowboy bebop super remixed.
Scott: They Akira movie super remixed.
Scott: Yeah, everything is either in a nice slim case box or whatever.
Scott: Dragon Ball Z the DVD releases of Dragon Ball Z and Dragon Ball and Dragon Ball GT and all those Dragon Ball shows are still there's pretty sure.
Scott: there's only been one legal American release of all those things and they've all been pretty terrible and difficult to collect all of them and Not easily affordable and all that jazz.
Scott: So I really think this is kind of a good idea.
Scott: to make a big cash Brian, you know get some monies plus.
Rym: I mean Dragon Ball Z has a lot of fans and Well, I've seen maybe 15 episodes of it random ones maybe three and it's got some funny stuff in it.
Rym: It's not a great show and the fact that people take it at face value scares me.
Rym: But then again when I was a kid, I took project a co at face value.
Rym: It's like wow.
Rym: She's a superhero.
Rym: This is awesome.
Rym: Oh my god, the school's gonna get destroyed.
Scott: Well, they do.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't know.
Rym: I didn't know it was a joke.
Rym: You know, they're all cross-dressers on the spaceship.
Rym: But Dragon Ball Z is kind of funny because it's kind of a parody of fighting shows except that you know People took it seriously.
Scott: Yeah, I do.
Scott: While I don't like Dragon Ball Z I think there's a good way for funimation to get a bunch of money so that they can buy some real and better anime series.
Scott: Bring those over, you know funimation does a pretty good job with most of their releases.
Scott: kind of well that and you know What they do average job, I would never begrudge a fan of a show Anything.
Rym: if someone really likes, I don't know MD guys It's cool.
Rym: If they put out like an MD guys awesome box that comes with a football.
Scott: Yeah, I won't buy it.
Scott: but If that's your thing good for you.
Scott: And I think this is gonna make a lot of Dragon Ball fans happy because there's still shit tons of Dragon Ball fans out there And this will probably make them more money than any other anime release of the next few years.
Rym: at RIT I worked in a sub shop one summer and at that sub shop and there were no geeks.
Rym: There was all like normal people.
Rym: Most of them weren't even in college.
Rym: they're all like high school punk kids or punk kids who didn't go to college and One of them none of them knew anything about anime or anything.
Rym: But one of them watched Dragon Ball Z all the time and I didn't realize this the one day he was mopping.
Rym: He's like come here And then he'd run across the room with the mop and then he'd turn around and do it again.
Scott: Oh god, how old is this kid?
Rym: He was probably like two years younger than me.
Scott: All right, okay.
Scott: So you want to hear people talk about Japanese cartoons, you know anime But you think the other anime podcasters just aren't nerdy enough.
Rym: sounds like you need to join forces with the anime world order Where each week three self-proclaimed experts offer you reviews of titles both new and classic news and commentary Rants convention reports interviews with fandom and some hentai and yaoi.
Rym: for good measure So search for anime in the iTunes music store or visit our website at anime world order.
Rym: calm Anime world order revealing the truth about anime.
Rym: one podcast at a time.
Rym: things of the day Now in a land in a world in a place in a time in a land before time.
Scott: No, not a land before time.
Scott: it sucks.
Rym: it's from land before time.
Rym: one was a pretty damn good movie for a seven-year-old All right for a seven-year-old.
Scott: It was okay.
Rym: land before time.
Rym: eight not so good.
Scott: Someone to tell us how many there are now.
Rym: I know there it.
Scott: I know there's a lot because I saw Something with a lot of roman numerals on it at the store.
Rym: There's at least like four or five, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, but but I think the day here there someone did this video some radio station or TV station or something.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: I barely paid attention to it, but the important part is it is a video about the guy Who does pretty much every movie trailer in America?
Rym: Don LaFontaine.
Rym: he is that guy who does that voice.
Scott: yeah, you know every movie trailer.
Scott: You know is like something something something something.
Scott: That's the.
Scott: Don LaFontaine is the guy who does those trailers, and he does that voice.
Rym: He's been doing this for a long time as how long has he been doing it?
Rym: He was doing work in the 60s and 70s Holy crap.
Rym: and to this day.
Rym: He does like 50 or 60 a week.
Rym: He does everything.
Scott: He must really crank these things out.
Rym: He does.
Rym: he does up to 35 in a day according to Wikipedia.
Scott: I guess is this you're not doing anything else.
Rym: That's not too hard I mean, what a thing this guy's talent is that he has an awesome voice kind of like the Lionel guy.
Scott: Yeah, that guy no well whatever.
Scott: Lionel is a.
Rym: Lionel is a train company that I visited when I was a kid.
Scott: yes I often mix the two out trains and Thundercats.
Rym: who knew You could make some kind of animated gif about that Lionel Lionel Thunder Thunder Thunder train.
Rym: Anyway This is just kind of a funny video with this guy really Taking himself not seriously and being funny.
Scott: Yeah, it's good to see that He's actually a cool guy who's not all weird and reclusive or anything like that.
Rym: Well, you know what he makes six or seven figures.
Scott: Well, he has to because all these movies are making a fortune and without his voice your trailers got nothing.
Scott: Yeah, so you got to get the guy.
Scott: It's it's like in V for Vendetta when they the voice of fate changes and it's such a big deal.
Scott: Imagine when this guy's no more and they had to find different people to do movie voiceovers.
Scott: That's gonna be in our lifetime probably when this guy retires.
Scott: No by then all movie trailers are gonna be totally weird not having this guy by then.
Rym: We'll have computers to perfectly do it.
Scott: Maybe we'll be able to have a computer to recreate Don LaFontaine's voice for all time.
Rym: Well, luckily this guy looks real healthy and real strong and the cool thing is from what you see guy to be to have that Voice, well, they call him the voice of God or Thunder throats.
Scott: That sounds right to me.
Rym: But the cool thing is you know most people who do voices for stuff.
Rym: They'd have a different voice in the real world.
Rym: This guy always sounds like that.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's just that's the voice He has.
Rym: like he can turn it up and do it more like double but his normal talking voice is just like that.
Rym: It's really cool.
Scott: Yeah, just watch the video and we don't need to explain it anymore.
Scott: Yeah Okay, my thing of the day is a high Larry.
Rym: his video rofl copter times a million.
Scott: The title of the video is stupidest robber ever stupidest criminal ever, right?
Scott: it starts out where this guy is going to rob a convenience store and Obviously, you know from the title of the video.
Scott: He's gonna do something dumb.
Scott: Perhaps he's going to I don't know Get shot by the convenience store clerk or he's gonna steal Something and try to run out the door but hit his head on the door and fall over.
Rym: It's stuck in a chimney somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, who does so?
Scott: it starts out where he's behind the store.
Scott: now everything he does they they use all the security cameras in the store.
Scott: the store must have like six or seven cameras and They show you what he's doing from all sorts of angles at all sorts of different times.
Scott: First he tries to climb up on the roof outside the store with predictable results.
Scott: And there's a. there's a camera outside the store watching him outside trying to climb on the roof.
Scott: You can guess what happens.
Scott: then he tries to get into the store by making a hole in the roof.
Scott: You can guess what happens there.
Rym: It's so great.
Rym: You see like debris Falls Debris Falls debris Falls debris Falls dude falls and lands on his head.
Scott: Yep Surprisingly, he never like injures himself enough to be knocked out that first fall.
Rym: It looks like he dies.
Rym: if I fell like that I would be dead.
Rym: and yet he gets right off and he's like, oh great So he.
Scott: so the Sun is coming up and he's proceeding to rob the store.
Rym: You know, actually I'll bet he was passed out for a while there He could have been.
Scott: I mean it was day when he got up.
Scott: He probably was passed out for a long time.
Scott: Anyway Gets up starts robbing the store.
Scott: He gets a 40.
Scott: He's smoking in the store, you know.
Scott: Then he tries to get out of the store and he can't get out the front door.
Rym: Yeah, the door is locked.
Rym: So first he's like bang.
Rym: He's trying to bust it open and he can't.
Rym: he's trying to pry it open In really poorly thought-out ways.
Scott: this guy.
Scott: he got into his store.
Scott: He robbed it a little bit and now he can't get out.
Scott: So he tries to exit.
Scott: he takes he finds a ladder and he tries to get out the hole in the roof.
Scott: that ends hilariously as well.
Scott: Basically the video goes on and he does more and more dumb shit until finally the police are at the front door of the store.
Scott: He can't get out.
Scott: He he lays down with his face on the ground that his hands behind his head.
Scott: then the cops come in and arrest him.
Rym: I think one of my favorite parts other than you know The two big Falls are is when he sees the camera there finally and he tries to throw something.
Scott: I don't know if he threw something at the camera.
Scott: I think he threw something for the sake of throwing something.
Rym: Yeah, but it looked like he was aiming at the camera.
Scott: It could have been.
Scott: it doesn't really matter.
Scott: The point is he's just like pissed off and he can't do anything cuz he's dumb ass.
Rym: So he takes like a big giant bottle and throws it now when you think the video is over Watch it until the end because they do a quick reprise of all the major events in the video.
Scott: Yeah It's just so entertaining cuz you watch it and you think okay There's you know, you see him fall once and you're like, okay, that's the end of that.
Scott: No, it gets dumber and dumber.
Scott: I couldn't really imagine it being any worse.
Rym: I'd almost want to talk to this guy just to see what he'd have to say for himself.
Scott: I don't want I don't think he's smart enough to eloquently express what he was thinking.
Rym: No, here's my idea my Multi-million-dollar idea.
Rym: All right, so we get this guy.
Rym: He's Brian jail who get out.
Rym: eventually we get him We take this video we pay him to do commentary on the video and then we sell that DVD.
Rym: I would imagine the commentaries like.
Rym: I don't know what I was trying to do there.
Rym: I was high.
Rym: I Was high lol, man.
Rym: I was passed out for like a day.
Rym: I don't know when I got up but the Sun was coming up.
Scott: Yeah, they obviously cut out lots of boring parts of the video where he just walks around and does nothing.
Rym: Yeah, they get right back to him.
Rym: He's trying to climb out the roof in desperation.
Rym: Yeah All right, so it's been a while since we've talked about anything other than anime on anime day.
Scott: So we're gonna talk about some comics.
Scott: Well, not the manga kind.
Rym: Yeah, but not so much the underwear pervert kind either.
Scott: Well, it's 25% Underwear pervert.
Scott: I would say we're going to talk about a comic called ex machina written by the man Brian K Vaughn with art by Tony Harris and it is published by Wildstorm which is really just DC with a different name on it.
Scott: So it's an imprint Brian K.
Rym: What else has he done?
Rym: of note, huh?
Scott: Brian K Vaughn is only like the best comic writer right now.
Scott: He's written wide.
Scott: last man, which is gonna end soon.
Scott: He's written runaways, which he's gonna stop writing and Joss Whedon's gonna write that.
Scott: I think that was in news a while ago.
Scott: He's doing a miniseries of Doctor Strange comics, which you can find on the shelves right now.
Scott: He's Doing ex machina right now.
Scott: It was something else.
Scott: oh he did a miniseries of the escapist for Dark Horse.
Scott: He's basically writing comics left and right and up and down and they're all.
Scott: most of them are awesome.
Scott: He's basically as far as I'm concerned could do no wrong when it comes to writing comics.
Scott: everything He is written that I have read has been great.
Scott: Oh pride of Baghdad.
Scott: He wrote pride of Baghdad.
Rym: I haven't read that yet, but Emily did and I think you did too.
Rym: Yep, and I want to.
Rym: I just haven't got a chance.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I'll read it before you read anything by Brian K Vaughn.
Scott: read pride of Baghdad.
Scott: It's a one-shot comic.
Scott: It's only hardcover right now But it's pretty cheap.
Scott: if you want just wait for the softcover to come out and buy it.
Scott: It's a single graphic novel.
Scott: Just one book.
Scott: you read it.
Scott: You're done warning.
Rym: It's sad.
Scott: It's real sad.
Rym: It's not a happy thing if it's your birthday.
Rym: You probably don't want to read this.
Rym: No, sorry on your birthday Don't read it on a sad day either when other sad things happen Yeah Like if your pet just died or it's your birthday and you have a pet lion.
Scott: Read it on a perfectly normal day like before you go to bed or something.
Rym: So you have horrible nightmares about being a lion and Baghdad.
Scott: So Ex Machina, it's awesome.
Rym: it's really good and remember this is coming from me the man who Absolutely hates 99% of underwear perfect comics and I mean, I can't read this shit.
Scott: I tried to read something to review it with Scott and I couldn't finish it Alright, so let me sum up the plot of Ex Machina pretty quickly.
Scott: There's a guy named Mitchell hundred as in his last name is hundred as in one zero zero and He's a dude in New York.
Scott: I forget what his original job was.
Scott: It wasn't something it wasn't very high-profile and One day he randomly gets some superpowers.
Scott: The superpower is that he can communicate with and control technology.
Scott: if the technology is too simple like a hammer He can't really do anything.
Scott: But if you've got like a gun he can just say jam and the gun will jam.
Scott: if you've got a computer He doesn't even touch the keyboard.
Scott: He just talks to it with his brain or with his mouth and he commands it and he tells the computer what to do.
Scott: I'm not gonna tell you how he got the powers or the origin or anything like that because it's kind of silly.
Scott: Well, it's not entirely silly.
Scott: well, it's but it's sort of spoilery.
Rym: compared to most superhero comic type stuff.
Rym: It's actually really more sci-fi than anything.
Scott: It is very sci-fi sort of like the Rocketeer is really how far it goes with the sci-fi superhero kind of stuff Because I mean the dude gets a jetpack that some crazy Russian guy made for him and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: So as far as the super Russian guy is my favorite character Yeah, as far as the superhero wing part of it goes think the Rocketeer.
Scott: But that's not why this comic is awesome.
Scott: anyone could write You know a Rocketeer clone with a different power and it would be okay.
Scott: Why this is awesome is because the story starts not when he has superpowers and is fighting villains or?
Scott: Saving one of the towers of the World Trade Center from falling down.
Rym: Yeah, that's a really cool thing I want to talk about in a minute.
Scott: Okay, that's not where the story begins.
Scott: the story begins Where he is the mayor of New York because he's decided he could do better to help the city by being the mayor then by being a superhero that flies around with a jetpack and most of the plot lines are mostly the political in nature like Someone makes a controversial piece of artwork and wants to put it in a museum.
Scott: So he has to deal with it and he has to deal with you know, what the people think.
Scott: and yeah He's the mayor of New York and he's dealing with things that are kind of realistic in a West Wing TV show sort of way for what the mayor of New York would have to do.
Rym: Yeah, and the characters really well fleshed out and the politics are interesting in that they're not all Consistently to the left to the right to center.
Rym: They're all over the place.
Scott: Yeah, he's not like some bleeding-heart liberal guy He's not some wicked war hawk conservative guy.
Scott: He sort of does things that make sense and sometimes you agree and sometimes you disagree and sometimes you're like, yeah That's what you should do.
Scott: And sometimes you're like, why are you doing that?
Rym: That's kind of weird Yeah, and he disagrees with things that he does like.
Rym: at one point he ends up banning smoking in New York City But at the same time he's pissed off about it and he goes to smoke cigarettes all the time.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's.
Scott: it's pretty cool because he does things a lot of times for you know political reasons.
Scott: I think it's a very well not in 100% realistic.
Scott: It's a more realistic political scenario than other things would have you then and say sanctuary or Eagle.
Scott: Yeah Our Captain America Captain America.
Rym: What's the moral of sanctuary is if you're a badass you can rape your way to the top.
Scott: Yeah, ex-mocking is a little more realistic than that.
Scott: and what's cool is, you know, there's superhero wing but It provides sort of this background sort of like fancy Lala.
Scott: It's a magical girl show but it has this dinosaur plot hiding in the background, you know.
Scott: So whenever the magical girl stuff gets a little boring They always have this little dinosaur plot going on to keep it together.
Scott: You know, I work, you know has this political mayor of New York story this little superhero thing going on in the background.
Rym: I worry one day that we're gonna actually see the end of fancy Lala and find out what that dinosaur things about.
Scott: It's gonna be disappointing as all hell.
Rym: It's gonna be totally lame and will feel cheated out of the previous seven years.
Scott: That's why I'm probably never going to watch the end of fancy Lala.
Rym: It's just like Black Samurai.
Scott: We can't watch it, but I am going to read all of ex-mocking it.
Rym: now one thing that's cool it's got mention know the World Trade Center and there are other little things like this, but History pretty much diverges from actual American history at the point at which this guy gets his superpowers.
Rym: So they won't show any of this stuff like.
Rym: they don't show him doing all these things.
Rym: In fact, they skip over a lot of his past and reveal it in tiny flashbacks throughout the reading and they allude to things like They kind of allude to the fact that the towers were saved by this guy And then
Scott: they allude
Rym: to it more and more and it's kind
Scott: of this
Rym: slightly altered history Like wow, things are a little bit different in this world as a result of this with far-reaching consequences.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely really cool that you know, there were.
Scott: there were a bunch of superheroing standard Underwear pervert adventures at some point in the timeline of this story.
Scott: But though those events do not take place on the pages of ex-mocking it They have taken place in the way past.
Scott: so they could write a whole prequel comic to this.
Scott: That would be just as big and crazy as every other superhero comic, but they don't.
Scott: they're only telling this story Which is way cooler because it has lots of political action and not so much flying around Talking to guns action.
Rym: and also the thing that I think is really cool Is that almost every superhero thing suffers from supervillain syndrome where all right, you have a superhero.
Rym: Well, the only thing that a superhero could ever have trouble with is an equally powerful supervillain.
Rym: Thus there's a flimsy excuse for some supervillain for them to fight in this.
Rym: there aren't really supervillains per se.
Rym: there are Things that happen for the same reasons that this guy has his power But they're really not at all like the classic.
Rym: I am the evil magneto and I am going to oppose everything professor Xavier does.
Scott: Yeah, occasionally I mean I think there's a couple plot lines where there is someone making mischief or people targeting him in some way You know, but it's never like a supervillain It's more of a. it's like if he finds out what's going on He can usually fix it.
Scott: most of the time he fixes it with his mayoral powers and very rarely He fixes it with his superhero powers Which he's not supposed to use because I think the government told him not to.
Scott: yeah Cuz it's all secret and everything and he has like this room.
Scott: He can go into where his powers won't work but yeah, it's.
Scott: There aren't any villains in the classic sense of you know, haha.
Scott: I'm the monster of the week.
Scott: You must defeat me in a fight.
Scott: It's like oh, here's the political situation of the week.
Scott: or there'll be two situations going on at the same time.
Scott: One of them will be strictly a political thing and one of them will be strict You know, he's got both hands full all the time.
Scott: There's never just one thing He's paying attention to which is like I said pretty realistic as mayor's got to deal with all kinds of shit.
Scott: You know some council guy is going crazy.
Scott: There's something going down to some labor strike and there's also a crazy killer going around making people feel unsafe.
Rym: Yep, and he wants to go stop the killer, but all the government is like no you're the mayor The police will take care of that.
Scott: Yeah That's one of the best things to love about this book is that most of the characters are The people around the mayor all his advisors and he's got a bunch of different crazy advisors.
Scott: He got the guy with the dreads.
Scott: He's got the really tough police commissioner woman the Hispanic one and there's all these cast of characters directly around him and He sends them off on assignments like, you know to go do things and you see them do it.
Scott: Well, because they're all awesome But he'll get into fights with like the.
Scott: you know The police commissioner like he says.
Scott: I read there's a law that says there can't be any psychics.
Scott: go out and bust the psychics And the police lady's like no, we don't want to do it.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: you're gonna do it as a law.
Scott: go enforce it.
Scott: go do it now because he doesn't like psychics Which is good because I don't like psychics either.
Scott: But yet all there's all this cool stuff going on with those people as they disagree with him agree with him do his bidding Don't do his bidding tell him what to do, you know and you'll see.
Scott: sometimes he will.
Scott: he'll Disagree with the advisor and what he says is what goes and sometimes the advisors will convince him of something when he doesn't know better.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah, I've said this about other things before.
Rym: I think gassaraki was a big example.
Rym: But as far as this sort of thing goes, it's very realistic.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's hard to say that about a superhero comic or a giant robot.
Scott: superhero parts of this comic are not realistic but
Rym: in terms of it's it's realistic and that suspension of disbelief is easy to Maintain and that peep I mean something non-believable may happen But the way the people in the story react to it and the way it plays out is Very realistic as it.
Rym: if that happened in the real world.
Rym: This is probably how people would tend to react to it.
Scott: What else can be said about this awesome comic besides that?
Scott: You should all go and read it.
Scott: I don't know times.
Rym: You should all go and read it at least once.
Rym: Yeah, I don't read comics more than once really.
Rym: Yeah, except maybe I want to read sanctuary again.
Rym: Yeah kind of I want to read it knowing what happens in the end.
Scott: Maybe I will read this again when the next volume comes out.
Scott: right now There are three volumes of ex machina available trade paperbacks But it is a monthly comic that you can buy in comic book form.
Scott: You know one issue at a time and it comes out once a month.
Scott: I don't know if you'll be able to get all the previous issues But you can definitely get the new issue when it comes out each month.
Scott: There's also an ex machina special.
Scott: that is just two issues.
Scott: That is a special side story from the past or whatever and I have them But I don't know if they're gonna.
Scott: they might publish those in a future trade paperback or not It's.
Scott: it's unclear if that's gonna happen.
Scott: But yeah, it's totally cool.
Rym: So before we close up the show for tonight, I got a couple of little metal meta things.
Rym: well one thing that I really want to tell all of you out there because I know you don't all go to the forums but Way back.
Rym: We did a show on Big O to a Final Thoughts episode where we spoiled the whole show and we talked about all of it.
Rym: you know we analyzed the show from our perspective as viewers and we We really kind of did our final like.
Rym: here's what I think of the way this show ended and the way you know when this Character died and when this thing exploded and blah blah blah in a way that we really can't talk about a show when we're reviewing It because you know spoiling things for people is not cool and I hate to do a show Where all the people who haven't seen the show?
Rym: Though the other show that we're talking about on our show have to not listen.
Scott: Yeah It's.
Scott: it's nice to say that moat ninety nine point nine percent of the episodes of GeekNights Anyone can listen to without prerequisite other than understanding and comprehending the English language, you know.
Scott: It's like if all of a sudden in order to listen to GeekNights You had to have already seen a show or already played a video game in order to get Entertainment value out of it, you know, you know as opposed to negative entertainment out of it.
Scott: That's not a good thing because it basically alienates a bunch of listeners But at the same time that episode is really fun to do.
Rym: it was very very popular And more importantly many of you have been asking us to do that for other shows.
Rym: So now is your chance week.
Rym: We could do them every week.
Rym: There's a lot of anime.
Rym: We've seen that we could talk about an excruciating pain.
Scott: I need to refresh my mind But yeah,
Rym: well, yeah and hence in order to make this the best for everyone I made a thread in the forums where I want you to nominate What shows you want us to do this for and then once not after another week or so when all the nominations?
Rym: I think that are worth that are in.
Rym: I'm gonna make a poll and whatever show wins the poll We are going to as soon as is feasible do a final thoughts.
Rym: Here's exactly what we think about this show and how it ended.
Rym: show.
Scott: Mm-hmm yeah, basically we're looking for shows that most people have seen in their entirety and would be interested in hearing an in-depth analysis of.
Rym: Right now the frontrunners seem to be utenna and try gun.
Scott: Yeah, those are pretty good ones.
Rym: now Of course, we can't do a show that we haven't seen and whatever show it is We're probably gonna watch it through real quick again to refer at least watch the important episodes or you know Watch each episode for a few minutes to remind us.
Scott: Oh, yeah, then this episode.
Scott: then that one.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: Like if you want us to talk about Gundam seed, I need a little bit of time.
Scott: Yep 50 episode monster.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I think is that shows easy to talk about.
Scott: Yeah Gundam see that actually be a pretty good one.
Scott: I wouldn't mind if people voted for that, especially since I'm watching it and I've seen it.
Scott: I've seen it like one point seven five times Because I watched it three quarters of the way through on fan sub and then I watched the whole thing through on DVD.
Scott: So it wouldn't be too bad to do that show.
Rym: Yeah, I'm having a lot of fun watching the end of the show again.
Scott: I gotta say it's a fun show even though it's not the best show ever.
Rym: Yeah, other than when Certain characters cry.
Scott: Yeah God Not the fact that they're Okay, okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Stay tuned tomorrow for something.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.