Rym: It's Monday January 16th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We start talking about how to build and maintain a website, but then we get off into a rant about myspace and live journal.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we spent the better part of Saturday test driving cars.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I think I already discussed.
Scott: I need a new car for work.
Scott: Let's see what do we drive?
Rym: We drove Mazda 3 Mazda 3 Mazda 6 Chevy Aveo.
Rym: yeah, I never heard of the Chevy Aveo before.
Rym: we saw it and I Got a lot near us, and we went over and drove it and we saw this Chevy.
Scott: We drove the Chevy Cobalt.
Rym: That's the worst car ever.
Scott: that's not the worst car.
Scott: It was pretty terrible.
Rym: It's pretty pissed for.
Scott: but the more and more I look around at cars The more and more the Mazda 3 looks like the car to get.
Scott: I just know.
Scott: Telescoping steering wheel.
Scott: yeah, what can I say I mean?
Scott: It's a little car.
Scott: It's a hatchback.
Scott: The price is right.
Scott: It's got the right features.
Scott: It's got the right everything You know.
Scott: no other.
Scott: every other car.
Scott: I've looked at always has something about it.
Scott: That's not quite right.
Scott: You know for what I need and what I want.
Rym: So it'll be fun when we actually go into the dealers to purchase because many of you may not be aware, but we're assholes And When it comes to car dealers we pull no punches.
Scott: I even feel kind of bad because the guy I talked to at the Mazda dealer would seem like this nice young guy.
Scott: It was kind of cool whatever, but I'm just gonna go and be like all right.
Scott: I might be an asshole to you, but if you don't stick around we'll get along better.
Rym: so in the news Major.com is reporting something that most people who are familiar with designing websites know But this is a nice recent article that talks about it.
Rym: Do you realize that most people when they see a website?
Rym: They judge whether or not that website is worth looking at in a fraction of a second based on the initial impression Whatever it looks like and nothing you do after that point really matters.
Scott: I judge websites in a fraction of a second somewhat consciously and So I completely believe this study especially because nature is like a real scientific journal of realness.
Rym: yep I mean basically the study they did is they take people and they'd show them a website for Less than a second and then they show a bunch of websites like this and ask them to rate each one based on various factors And then they use the same groups and different groups.
Rym: And they also had them set websites they could see for a whole second two seconds a minute a half hour Like various times basically no matter how much time you gave them.
Rym: They always rated certain websites highly in certain websites lowly and basically all this comes down to is that if your website is poorly designed to The point that someone looking at it for a fraction of a second can't tell what it's about You've already lost the web game.
Scott: Typography is important Readability clean design.
Scott: don't put too much clutter all over the place.
Scott: I mean come on no one has to tell you what a good website looks like.
Scott: you go around the internet And you can tell just looking at sites.
Scott: Hey, that looks like a real professional site that has useful stuff on it.
Scott: Hey that looks like a crappy store I would never buy anything from.
Rym: yeah, it's like come on and there's a nice quote here.
Rym: This is from the actual article these days and lightened web users who want to see a want to see a Puritan approach.
Rym: It's about getting information across in the quickest simplest way possible.
Rym: So I know a lot of people like to have very flashy sites.
Rym: They like to have well flash Animated things and big logos, and you know what that doesn't work in the modern way.
Scott: notice Google's number one and Google doesn't have any of that crap.
Scott: if you're having all that crap you might think you're cool.
Scott: That's just because you're not reading your own website because you made it.
Scott: Now you want people to read your site.
Rym: you got to be like Google, but of course we're talking about You know websites that are there to convey information.
Rym: I mean if your website is in itself art or you're an artist or a webcomic dude or anything like that It doesn't apply as much.
Rym: This is really two sites that are trying to provide information.
Scott: Yeah, if you're creating a website You know as art you know you can show it to people as you would show people a painting or a drawing or any other Art you know.
Scott: or maybe like you're a photographer or something you have your little photo site.
Scott: But if you're trying to give them information like say you know your resume or something You know that might not be the most effective way to use all kinds of fancy stuff.
Scott: speaking of websites Someone did another Firefox Market share study.
Rym: the results might be surprising mostly to people who don't use Firefox.
Scott: Yeah, so this is actually a real real research study of I can't tell it says X capital X lowercase I capital T lowercase I. I Don't know who they are, but they're supposedly like they're up.
Rym: They're a research institute in France, and they're like all the research institutes in the US.
Rym: They just happen to be in France and do things in French.
Scott: Yeah, they monitor markets Okay, but anyway They're real reliable and trustworthy.
Scott: and they made a little map of Europe And they also did the US.
Scott: of what percent of web people use Firefox.
Rym: as opposed to anything else It's up to 15% in the US and 20% in Europe.
Scott: Yeah, look at some of these European countries.
Scott: in Finland, which is the highest percent of usage that I see 38.4% of people use Firefox.
Scott: That's a lot of people really.
Rym: the only ones who are behind the curve are Ukraine the UK and Spain.
Rym: Oh Italy Italy is not doing so great.
Scott: Well.
Scott: He's doing all right now.
Rym: They're below the u.s Yeah, but u.s.
Scott: Lithuania is not doing so good either.
Rym: I find it interesting that the u.s.
Rym: Is actually fairly low on Firefox Usage compared to Europe.
Rym: hmm.
Rym: I wonder why I mean are Europeans actually more web astute Or does this have to do with the fact that The internet isn't such a big deal in Europe.
Rym: So the people who use it are people who know more about it already.
Scott: It could be that I noticed that when you look in like open source communities like you be looking like Where gen 2 developers are from?
Scott: It's like about half of them are from the US and about half of them are from Europe and that's a lot more percentage than you see in other web places.
Scott: like if you go to like Like World of Warcraft you can't say half the players are in the US not the players here in Europe.
Scott: You know it.
Scott: there's a whole lot More US players than any other country.
Rym: I mean even just technical documents and for open source software everything I see that's good.
Rym: It always comes from Europe.
Rym: mostly you know Nordic countries, but mostly Europe.
Scott: Yeah, whenever you look at like forums You can always see like they have special European language sections like the German section of the forums and the French section of the forums.
Scott: You only really see that when in the you know places where they're talking about computery stuff.
Scott: So maybe just as a whole lot of computer nerds in Europe that aren't over here But regardless I mean Firefox.
Rym: back when it hit 10% a lot of naysayers were saying that yeah, you know what?
Rym: It's gonna Peter out.
Rym: It'll never get more than 10%.
Rym: Well, it's already at 15% and it's been Not even a year since the 10% mark.
Rym: so Firefox is on the rise.
Scott: Oh Here's a pictures of all the different continents.
Scott: So Europe is 20%.
Rym: how's Antarctica doing?
Scott: Zero zero.
Rym: you're telling me that everyone who's actually in Antarctica with the computers use an IE.
Scott: It doesn't actually have an article listed.
Rym: What the hell.
Scott: what kind of study is this, but here's something crazy Asia including Russia and such Africa 9.4% huh.
Scott: South and Central America including Mexico is 5.79% and Oceania Not.
Scott: it doesn't look like includes Indonesia or the Philippines, but 18.6% in Australia.
Rym: those numbers are actually kind of surprising and not what I expected.
Scott: Yeah, and Apparently not everyone's even upgraded to one and a half.
Scott: yet 61% of Firefox users are still using Firefox one.
Rym: Honestly at work.
Rym: I'm using one and all those me.
Rym: I built 300 or so machines and they're using one.
Rym: You know, well I have my reasons because I heavily modified the Zuul for certain reasons.
Rym: in the ones I did at work the Zuul is the thing that controls how Firefox looks and works and They change the Zuul in 1.5 and I just haven't gotten around to rewriting it.
Scott: It always Amazes me like when they upgrade Firefox how They actually change it in a way that I couldn't imagine but I still want really badly.
Scott: I
Rym: Would just like to note that while Scott was talking there I witnessed something hilarious as he accidentally pulled the plug out of his laptop and then like Slid along the floor trying to reach out and plug it back in while maintaining the microphone in front of his face.
Scott: It worked No, but like every time they upgrade Firefox, I'm like, what could they possibly add to make this better?
Scott: What can they possibly do?
Scott: and then up it's always better It's always better and it's so much better that I can't even like Like 1.0 was great when I had it and now I got 1.5 and 1.0 is crap.
Scott: How did that happen?
Rym: Like for anyone who hasn't upgraded one little example and this is something that existed in 1.0 But didn't really work and cause some problems, you know, sometimes a link opens in a new window or something stupid You can tell it with a nice little gooey to either Open links like that in new tabs or open them in the same window or whatever you want them to do
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's actually really useful because a lot of sites are designed in the old web way and they have all their links to external sites Popping new windows which takes me off immeasurably.
Scott: And a side note bug me not was fixed today.
Scott: So it works again.
Scott: So everyone update your bug me not.
Rym: extension Oh bug me not for those of you don't know is fantastic.
Rym: You know those sites like New York Times Washington Post and they want you to register.
Rym: Well, uh, there used to be the convention slashed out two thousand slashed out two thousand worked on any site because people just set that up.
Rym: but bug me bug me not.
Rym: basically people sign up for accounts on these things and They give their account to the world.
Rym: and if you use bug me not when you go to one of those sites It just automatically logs you in with a random account so you can see the content without having to say who you are.
Scott: Yep, if you hate registering at all the news sites get the bug me not.
Scott: extension for Firefox and all you do is when you Get to the site and it says login You right-click on the login box and say bug me not and it just logs you in and you see your article now.
Rym: Surprisingly not all but a lot of pay websites.
Rym: People actually put working user IDs into bug me not and you can often get a lot of content that cause money for free.
Rym: I'm not officially advocating that but it's something to poke into because I've discovered some interesting things that way Occasionally, it works well in porn sites.
Rym: I'm just saying yeah, I know you're just saying I never.
Scott: you know, honestly, I never actually tried to use it on a porn site.
Rym: I'm sure yeah.
Rym: Yeah, CYA.
Scott: No, seriously, though.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, really?
Rym: So More than once I've picked a thing of the day.
Rym: That wasn't cool.
Rym: It's just something that in some way pissed me off and This is one of the things that it's really a hot-button issue for me.
Rym: But I brought this up partly because more than one person has asked me recently what I have against chiropractors everything.
Rym: yeah, I mean, I'm very much anti flim-flam anti quackery and Despite anyone who says anything to the contrary, there's no evidence that Chiropractic provides any benefits whatsoever.
Rym: In fact, there's only evidence that at best it's dangerous.
Scott: Chiropractic is not doctor.
Rym: It was made up a long time ago by a crazy quack Like literally this guy was just some crazy quack who believed in magnetic energy Holy magic quack healing and he started a school called chiropractic and he made a lot of money and then he died.
Rym: and for some reason chiropractic still around and the fact that people believe it and study it or respect it in any way is mind-boggling to me.
Scott: I mean There's a real problem in this country where there are doctors who can kind of heal you but not perfectly You know.
Scott: because well no matter what we'll probably never able to heal people perfectly until we have a perfect understanding of biology.
Scott: And that's the way it is, you know and a lot of times, you know people are hypochondriacs or people think there's something wrong with them and there isn't.
Scott: or You know the the only medicine we can have is horrible side effects or There's just no way to cure what you've got.
Rym: and people in these cases, you know will turn to Chiropractor or someone who will tell them oh I can fix you do this magic thing and you'll be fine.
Scott: Yeah, they'll go to anyone who says that they can heal them in some way.
Scott: crazy herbal medicines Crazy homeopathy medicines, but you know, none of these things are medicine.
Scott: They're all just made up bullshit.
Scott: You might as well go to the witch doctor who will wave a stick over you and say, you know, walla walla Washington You're healed.
Rym: now There are a lot of ways I could prove to you or show you at least the specific reasons why I'm so adamantly opposed to chiropractic and Luckily the other day I ran across this video and it's a video of a lecture done by dr.
Scott: William Kin singer a real doctor.
Rym: he's a real doctor is not a chiropractor.
Rym: and basically, it's a nice concise summary of everything that's wrong with chiropractic and why you should Avoid them at all costs.
Rym: and if you know anyone who is going to a chiropractor and you consider them a friend Show them this video or at least talk to them and try to convince them that it's not helping.
Rym: Now a lot of people make the argument that chiropractic at least feels good.
Rym: or it's a nice back rub or it can do anything.
Scott: Your physical therapist can just go to one of those Asian ladies who gives you a back rub.
Scott: It's cheaper.
Rym: Or I mean the fact chiropractic is just bullshit That even if you just go for the back rub, it's actually very dangerous and it can kill you.
Scott: Well, there's the adjustments.
Scott: or what can kill you?
Scott: just rubbing you?
Rym: does you realize all they give you are adjustments?
Rym: Basically what chiropractors do is they massage you but they massage you along your spine Which I've taken massage therapy classes and the first rule was you never touch the area around the spine ever Ever ever ever.
Rym: they drill that into your head every single day.
Rym: It's terribly dangerous.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So if you have any doubts as to what I've said about chiropractic watch this video.
Scott: Yep, it'll Hopefully change your mind.
Scott: and well if you keep going to the chiropractor and you know better and you get hurt You get notably about yourself.
Rym: Now Scott's thing of the day is much more fun.
Scott: Well, you might remember my previous thing a day with the Japanese Super Nintendo Zelda commercial.
Scott: You can consider this part two of Scott's ongoing old Nintendo commercial thing of the day series.
Rym: I remember seeing this one on TV when I was a kid.
Scott: Yeah so far, you know There have been quite a few Nintendo commercials go around the net but this one I remember quite well.
Rym: it's the original NES Tetris commercial and The one with the singing opera lady and the exploding building.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one.
Scott: so if you remember it, it should nostalgia you and if you don't well Then now you can be a little more old-school instead of being a loser lemur.
Rym: Now the one thing that always bothered me about this commercial and I was reminded of it when I saw it They they show all these shapes in Tetris.
Rym: They're like square Rectangle blah blah blah and at one point He says trapezoid and it shows a picture of a trapezoid.
Rym: and yet in no way does the trapezoid ever appear in Tetris.
Scott: He wasn't trying to show Pieces that appear in Tetris, but you can't even make a trapezoid in Tetris.
Scott: No, no, you didn't get that part of the.
Scott: the bit is that he was.
Scott: he was like, this is a square This is a rectangle.
Scott: This is a trapezoid.
Scott: He wasn't saying that they're in Tetris.
Scott: He was just showing you some shapes and then the last shape he showed you is a Tetrisoid.
Scott: you see.
Rym: but why is the trapezoid?
Rym: I think that's intellectually dishonest.
Scott: They were just trying to be silly saying look a Tetrisoid is a new type of shape, you know, it's Tetris.
Scott: Ooh, the other things weren't in Tetris.
Scott: They know that.
Rym: no, I don't like it.
Rym: I think you should have done some research maybe presented some sort of evidence.
Scott: I think you're just nuts.
Scott: I Think you need to let it slide.
Rym: All right, then you should let a chiropractic slide You first All right.
Rym: Tell you what, I'll try to make a trapezoid in Tetris and you go to a chiropractic.
Scott: No, you don't get it at all.
Scott: There are no And they're not trying to say they are either.
Rym: God yeah, so Today being Monday in science and tech day and considering that we just in about an hour Designed an entire web community for a local group around here We decided we talked about what it takes to actually make a website or a web community.
Scott: Well, the first thing you need to know is how website works.
Scott: now I'm gonna try to avoid horrible technical details as much as I can But you might have to suffer and if I say something you don't know and I don't explain it Wikipedia is your friend and so was Google.
Rym: So so you have HTML and CSS and blah blah blah blah blah patchy posterior e.
Scott: Yeah, that's the kind of stuff that you need to look up.
Scott: So the way the web works is you have a web server.
Scott: It's basically you have a computer and it just sits there and it has a bunch of web pages sitting on it and it just sits.
Scott: and If someone wants to visit the website, they open up their browser and they type in the address of the web server The web browser goes and says hey web server give me this page.
Scott: the web service is okay.
Scott: it gives them the page and then your web browser takes that page which is just a bunch of text and It turns it into the website that you see on your screen.
Rym: simple.
Scott: Very simple.
Scott: So standard web browsers are like Firefox Internet Explorer Opera and web servers are like Apache Is whatever but almost everyone uses Apache as it's the way to go and The text that gets sent across from the browser from the server to the browser is the HTMLs that everyone talks about.
Scott: It's really like if you right-click in your browser on any page and say view source, you'll see what HTML looks like.
Scott: It's not really that scary.
Scott: It's just text with some little tags in it to say like hey, this text is bold.
Scott: This is a paragraph.
Scott: put a picture here make a table here that sort of thing.
Scott: It's it's really.
Scott: it's brain dead.
Scott: and That's how website works.
Scott: Now that you know that The next step is to make those fancy websites where you can actually do stuff, you know, like a forum website a blog blog you know anything a shopping site that sort of thing.
Rym: now we can use GeekNights as an example because we made GeekNights and Despite the fact that it's fairly polished and looks pretty good and has a lot of complex functionality It took almost zero effort on our part to build it in about five minutes.
Rym: Basically, you just read a thing and if you follow the directions, you'll get something like what we have.
Scott: Well starting with the way it works is with the normal web page I first described is you just have HTML and it's just a file and When you ask the browser for a page it sends you that file.
Scott: Now, let's say with with these other sorts of powerful websites that are different all the time.
Scott: They're called dynamic websites.
Scott: And that's because well the there is no page just in a file on the web server.
Rym: Yep When my browser asks for a file the server says he asked for this file and then the server looks into a database figures out what it needs to make the page you Asked for and then sends HTML that will recreate that page.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So the page itself doesn't actually exist until you try to view it Yep.
Scott: So there's a program on the web server and you you send either in the URL or in a form Information to the web server.
Scott: the web server takes that information and runs a program and the Result of that program is that the program prints out HTML?
Scott: So you can write like a program that says if someone visits one if someone visits a page named one print out the number one.
Scott: if someone visits a page name to print out the number two and You know, it'll print out that and send it back.
Scott: and that's that's how that works.
Scott: So The good news is you don't have to learn how to program crap Because people have already programmed everything cool for you.
Rym: I mean, I guess the point we're trying to make through this whole show here Is that it's really easy to make really professional looking websites, even if you don't know anything about web publishing.
Scott: Mm-hmm Especially since a lot of hosts just take care of this stuff for you.
Scott: I mean with the way we do is we have like, you know a host or we actually have to administer a Linux computer Sort of yeah, we have our own computer in the sky and we can basically do whatever we want with it.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: But a lot of hosts just already set up Apache PHP my SQL all these sorts of things that you need these acronyms that you need to have available in order for these things to work and all you have to know is that You have to figure out what you want to use and you have to figure out what?
Scott: Acronyms you need to have in order to make that work.
Scott: You don't have to worry about what the acronyms are anything.
Scott: So the one thing that I I like a lot is WordPress.
Rym: It's really the only good free one out there.
Scott: Yeah, there are a lot of them but WordPress it really especially since WordPress 2.0 just came out.
Scott: It really takes the cake.
Scott: It's hot.
Rym: basically You download it and you just follow the instructions on how to make it work on whatever server or hosting.
Rym: you're using
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and it gives you a little page and you administer the entire website from the website you can you log into the site and it gives you a little like editor boxes and things and you just make pages and Put them around your site and it'll just glue everything together on its own.
Scott: Yeah once it's installed anyone who has the mind enough to be able to use something like Microsoft Word can use WordPress to make an awesome blog and stuff and enter all their content and make blog posts and categorize blog posts and post comments and all that sort of good stuff.
Rym: I mean It's real extensible and real flexible and you can get down into the nitty-gritty and alter the style sheets or do whatever you want But if you don't know any of that stuff you still get a lot of power.
Rym: You can change a lot of things really easily just by pointing and clicking and following directions
Scott: and to install it All you really do is download it go to the web server Unzip it and then point your web browser at it and you go to like install that PHP.
Scott: You just visit the install website That you set up and then it just says click next click next do this do that and then it's set up.
Rym: You basically do everything through the web browser.
Rym: It's just like it's a website where when you visit it you see your cool administrator stuff and when everyone else visits They see your cool website.
Scott: Mm-hmm You don't actually have to write a single HTML or a style sheet or a PHP or anything.
Scott: Of course, it does require you have a MySQL and a PHP and an Apache.
Scott: of course You don't have to have an Apache technically, but you need a my.
Scott: you need a database and a PHP That's for sure.
Rym: Of course, if you don't have any of that.
Rym: you don't want to pay for hosting or whatever.
Rym: There are a million places various blog type places.
Rym: That'll just give you all that already.
Scott: Yeah, I think they even set up like wordpress.com or something like where you get WordPress blogs now.
Scott: They just came out with that now.
Rym: We'll have to look.
Scott: Yeah, so there are other places you can go to like Google with their blogger calm blog spot type thing and Microsoft has one.
Scott: You know when they're not WordPress these other ones.
Scott: but you just visit them and you say hey I want a blog and they say here's a blog.
Scott: You know, you don't get to do all sorts of.
Scott: you know You don't have as a hundred percent freedom as if you had your own web server, but for 90% of people it's plenty.
Rym: I mean basically Making a website or a forum or anything like this the technical part of it.
Rym: a lot of people say oh, I'd make a website I just don't know how.
Rym: Knowing how is probably the least of your worries because making the getting the website up and getting it to work is Trivial in most cases.
Rym: So, I mean the real problem.
Rym: the real issue is do you actually have a reason to make a website?
Rym: What are you gonna do with it?
Rym: Why would people visit it?
Scott: Mmm They're 90% of websites out there just completely useless or no one updates them or whatever you know when They just don't get visited and there's no purpose.
Scott: a lot of people put a lot of effort into making them and it just doesn't.
Scott: They don't mean anything.
Scott: It's like they're just taking up space somewhere.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: So if you're gonna make a website don't just be like.
Scott: I want to make a website.
Rym: yeah Think about why you're doing it.
Rym: Do you care if people look at it or not?
Rym: Well, do you need to make money?
Rym: Do you want to make money?
Rym: Do you not care about losing money on it?
Rym: Mm-hmm?
Scott: Yeah, only make a website if you have a purpose, you know.
Scott: I mean you're free to make one if you don't have a purpose.
Scott: But you know don't put too much into it if you have no reason for doing it And you're not getting anything out of it.
Rym: I mean we made GeekNights for fun.
Rym: We don't expect to make money off of it Even if it gets crazy crazy crazy popular with millions of listeners.
Rym: We really would continue doing it for free forever because we enjoy it, but we are You know making a website for a purpose.
Scott: We're not just oh, let's make a thing.
Scott: Whatever There's a reason for it to exist and that's what's important now it.
Rym: that doesn't mean that it has to be a reason for other people to visit it.
Rym: if you make a website just for You and maybe a few of your friends and you're happy with that Don't feel bad if you only get like five hits a day or five hits a year or whatever Because as long as you got the enjoyment out of making it and it's serving its purpose you win.
Scott: Now if you want something like a forum or something you do it pretty much the same way.
Scott: you install WordPress You just install a forum software instead of a blog software.
Rym: I mean, I wish we were exaggerating but no it's that simple.
Rym: you just go into Google and type like free forum software And you'll find a bunch of sites.
Rym: you pick one you download it you follow the instructions and it just works.
Scott: the most popular one You've probably seen around the internet is PHP BB.
Rym: Yeah, we run some game forums with it A lot.
Rym: a lot of blogs use it as their forum.
Scott: Yep, but I've decided for the for the front row crew GeekNights forum to use Lucemo vanilla, which well you said ah like six times there damn it.
Scott: Yeah Fine, I'll say it again.
Scott: I Decided there for the GeekNights front row crew forum.
Scott: I would use Lucemo vanilla, which is much more modern much more hot Doesn't have is the same sort of old-school web 1.0 ness of PHP BB.
Scott: It's like a web 2.0 forum.
Rym: And now that I've upgraded it with the avatars and such And yeah, yeah, I got to admit Scott you he has a real nice boo avatar.
Scott: I love my boo avatar.
Scott: That's the best avatar ever had.
Rym: my toga is okay But I'm thinking about changing it to some sort of Mario or maybe a dry bones maybe a boo.
Rym: Now basically, you'll notice that we didn't really go into a lot of detail on the specifics like download this then do this then do This, you know put it in this directory or any really any kind of specific technical details.
Rym: now I'd say the main reason for that is that it really is that simple one.
Rym: if you just go to a site and Google around you'll find all the information you need.
Rym: if you really get stuck just ask us and we could show you because we We've done it so many times.
Rym: It's just trivial and Basically, you have no.
Rym: if you want to make a website or you have something to say to the world you can't use not understanding technology or Not knowing where to begin or not knowing how to make a website as an excuse not to do it.
Rym: Because seriously, it's that easy to just make a website.
Rym: So if you've got something to say go out and do it make a website and it'll be awesome.
Scott: And don't make one of those scary myspace websites or anything.
Rym: because God I mean honestly this is just what we're switching from Technological advice mode to rant mode.
Rym: but to me myspace and live journal are pretty much the cesspool of the internet.
Rym: There I consider them one step above 4chan which itself is only a scant step above the style project.
Scott: I mean the technology behind live journal and myspace is really nothing wrong with the technology itself.
Rym: It's a culture.
Scott: it did.
Scott: the culture behind those sites Means most of the people using that technology are making bad bad websites.
Rym: I mean if you had bad way have you ever seriously looked around myspace?
Rym: Because the first time I actually ever went to a myspace site was when we met this cool band at Otakon.
Rym: We've talked about him before.
Rym: what were they called?
Rym: Entertainment entertainment system and the guy who ran the band is really cool And we want to know what their website was.
Rym: and they had some high space or myspace site.
Rym: Yeah, not high space.
Rym: high space is actually awesome high space But it's just this horrible cesspool of like early 90s era Geocities type sites with like horrible pictures and cam girls and drugs and it's just a mess.
Scott: It's really frightening.
Scott: I mean I It the backgrounds the tiled backgrounds of blinking colors.
Scott: I haven't seen those in like 10 years.
Rym: now I'll be tiled blinking backgrounds, but tiled blinking backgrounds that aren't the right size to begin with.
Rym: Wow, what are these people thinking?
Rym: do they think these sites look good?
Scott: It's like they look at their web.
Scott: They they must not look at their own website or try to actually read it.
Scott: It's like they just use as many things as they can use like oh I can make things blink.
Scott: I'll make things blink.
Scott: Oh, I can use lots of colors and make text big and different fonts.
Scott: I'll do as much different stuff as I can possibly do and put a graphic in every single spot I can possibly put.
Scott: oh, I found a cool picture on the internet like a little funny animated gif.
Scott: I'll put that on my site.
Scott: Also, it just God it makes completely useless and painful things to look at.
Scott: Don't make any more of those sites, please.
Rym: Yeah and live journal while it's a lot more tasteful I just I have some a lot of friends who I mean I refuse to use live journal.
Rym: I don't even go to it unless people like really make me Which actually one time was funny because I found out that a friend of mine was a father because I went to his live journal.
Rym: I hadn't talked to him in a while.
Rym: But it seems that I know a lot of people who use the live journal as a way to communicate with their friends.
Rym: in lieu of actually talking to and continuing to be friends with their friends I Mean I'll talk to someone I haven't talked to a while like hey, how you doing?
Rym: What's up?
Rym: and they'll say oh, do you read my live journal?
Rym: and I say no.
Rym: And then I end up trying to have a real conversation with them where they try to actually explain these events to a person Because they've they're used to just having people read the live journal then they never have to talk to anyone.
Scott: It makes this sort of scary like Sub world communication like People say things or they write things down and other people read them But they didn't actually say them directly to that person, so it's kind of like there's information.
Scott: That's known Like to some people who read it and it makes really weird situations when you hang out with a lot of live journal people
Rym: Because I mean we've had friends who post something in a live journal and then get absolutely pissed when other people are talking about it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean hello.
Rym: You posted it to the internet.
Rym: That's the equivalent of standing on rooftops and shouting at 24/7.
Scott: Yeah, there's the other thing where people will put it in their live journal, and then when you don't know it.
Scott: They're like You didn't read my like.
Scott: no And they're like you don't care about me like Get away from me.
Scott: Yeah, Gary
Rym: Or I had a friend not too long ago who I talked to this person off and on But I talked to someone else and I mentioned this person's name and the other guy was like well I haven't heard from her and like ages is she dead or something?
Rym: I was like what I talked to her like two days ago and then the guy was like oh, but she hasn't updated a live journal in months.
Rym: I figured something happened and The I did really took all my effort to not say and maybe she got a life.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: Maybe she got a life.
Rym: Now Highspace on the other hand that's quality.
Scott: highspace should be a thing of the day.
Rym: Yeah, I Was highspace a thing of the day, or did we talk about it back in the like?
Rym: Pre-production beta GeekNights that aren't on the internet anymore.
Scott: I don't know, but highspace recently updated, so it's still going.
Rym: Yeah, if anyone doesn't know you can find it pretty easily, but highspace is a funny completely fake knockoff of myspace with all the characters from every Zelda game in them It.
Scott: some of them are really hilarious, especially old man.
Rym: I don't know I'm a big fan of error.
Scott: old man is still the best one.
Rym: See if this sort of thing sounds hilarious to you then you're gonna love this site.
Rym: And if you have no idea what we're talking about don't worry because you're not missing anything you care about.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to we're not gonna tell you how to get to highspace now in the podcast.
Scott: But if you visit front row crew calm there'll be a link in today's post.
Rym: Oh, well there that means I have to put a link in today's post.
Scott: That's already done means I have to go in and edit and then yeah great Yeah, but it means that people have to visit our site, and then hopefully also join our forum.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I gotta say once again We see how many of you are out there listening to this and it's a lot more than the number of people who are visiting the site on a regular basis.
Rym: And also, this is a complete aside because we've kind of gone off topic anyway But someone is listening to GeekNights on a regular basis on their PSP.
Scott: Alright,
Rym: whoever you are come forward I'm curious because I don't know anyone who owns a PSP and I'd really like some first-hand accounts as to how cool It is or not because I'm I'm basically firmly in the DS camp at this point and so is everyone I know in the world and
Scott: they saw DS is sold out in Japan and PSP's are plentiful.
Rym: so well what they sold 15 million DS's so far, and I think four or five million PSP's Like that worldwide.
Rym: there won't even be DS DS's in Japan until February, but like I'm not knocking you I think it's cool that you're listening to GeekNights on a PSP But I want to know who you are and I want to.
Rym: I want to.
Rym: I mean if you live near me Can I try your PSP out?
Scott: Yeah?
Scott: I don't know what you're using to download GeekNights on the PSP.
Scott: you have like an RSS reader on there a podcatcher.
Rym: I read somewhere that because it looks like from as far as feed burner tells me It's a built-in pot or podcast thingy or a built-in RSS thingy for the PSP.
Scott: I really like to see You know GeekNights on there.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Scott: So like I take like a picture of it or something because I mean It's also.
Rym: it'd be a nice test for us if the site doesn't work so well on a PSP or a little screen like that.
Rym: Let us know because if there's a demand we'll definitely make a portable mobile version of the site on a separate feed or something.
Scott: Yeah, I'm definitely I'm not really too happy with the current theme on the website.
Scott: You know I change the theme on the forum.
Scott: So I'm gonna try to change the theme on the actual website to something more custom.
Scott: Maybe looks more like the forum or at least has better typography.
Scott: That's more readable and you know just better overall.
Rym: Yeah, so since we've moved into meta bits expect the website look to change a little bit as we fiddle with it Yeah, but still visit it often.
Rym: Yes, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com, and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.