Scott: It's Tuesday, June 27th, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, we give a session report on our weekend of board gaming.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: It's Monkey Tuesday!
Rym: Doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: Doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: Alright, Juan, if any of you don't listen to Penn Jillette's podcast, or radio show, whatever, on free FM, free FM, lightning lightning, here you can be free, whatever, yeah, well one, check it out.
Rym: Two, check it out on Tuesdays if you do nothing else.
Scott: They should have a separate Tuesday only feed for that show.
Rym: Monkey Tuesday!
Rym: Doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: Well anyway, he has Monkey Tuesday, which is, it's just monkeys.
Rym: They'll talk about monkeys every Tuesday.
Scott: Listeners will all call in or mail in stories about monkeys that are humorous, usually involving smoking monkeys, monkey hiring a prostitute, that sort of thing.
Scott: All kinds of craziness, and it's high-larious.
Rym: Now for the 4th of July, because he went on about how Monkey Tuesday falls on the 4th of July this year, he is looking for patriotic monkey stories.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: Now Scott and I, this was Scott's idea, and I think it's a wonderful idea, we are going to try to make up the most hilarious and awesome, patriotically themed monkey story in the world, record it, send it to Penn, and see if he'll play it on the air.
Scott: Yup, or read it on the air if it's an email, or maybe he'll call us when he's on the air because we won't be in the car or anything.
Rym: Yeah, no, I'll be at work or something.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, but, yeah, he actually said, you know, if you don't have any stories, make them up and send them in.
Scott: He won't check to see if it's the real deal.
Rym: Our story's gonna have freaking monkeys.
Scott: I was thinking it'd be an open air circus, monkeys, fireworks, yeah you get the idea.
Rym: We're talking about monkeys liberating their fellow monkey friends with fireworks.
Scott: On the 4th of July, at a circus.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: Monkey Tuesday.
Rym: Anyway, in the actual non-monkey related news, the Supreme Court in 1989 ruled that flag burning is constitutionally protected free speech.
Scott: Yup, I mean, it's just a cloth with a design on it.
Rym: Yeah, and burning it, I mean, as long as you don't burn someone else's flag.
Scott: Or as long as you don't set anything else on fire, or harm anyone with the fire, you're allowed to make fires.
Rym: Well, a lot of places you aren't, but that's a whole different-
Scott: As long as you don't, if you make a fire somewhere, you're not allowed to make a fire because it's dangerous, you know, but you can start a fire in your backyard, or on a campground, or in the street, as long as it's, you know, not like a fire, like a campfire in the middle Or what,
Rym: I could burn a tiny little flag, and then it's no more dangerous than a cigarette.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: You're allowed to do that.
Rym: Well, for anyone who isn't aware of this, very periodically, the Congress of the United States will rally around, particularly around election times, and try to pass a constitutional amendment to ban flag burning.
Rym: This has been coming up every single election year in some form for a long time.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: The difference is that just today, the Senate voted on whether or not they should put forth the measure that would actually put the flag burning amendment to a ratification bid.
Scott: Now, if you don't know, flag burning is still okay, which means this still, this has never passed.
Scott: They tried a zillion times, and it's never passed.
Rym: This time, the vote was 66 in favor of the amendment, 34 against.
Scott: So only one, you're one guy away, one senator away from possibly not being allowed to burn flags.
Rym: Now, even scarier than this, it turns out that about 56% of Americans fully support this amendment and want flag burning to be banned.
Scott: If anyone comes up to me and says they want flag burning to be banned, I'll say, "You hate
Scott: freedom.".
Rym: Now, the interesting thing is that there were three Republicans who voted against this, and one of them was the Republican whip, Mitch McConnell.
Rym: Mitch, one-gallon-challenge McConnell.
Scott: That's an inside joke about another guy named Mitch.
Rym: Yeah, we know this guy Mitch, who is not a senator.
Scott: No, but he did do the one-gallon challenge.
Rym: Well, he attempted the one-gallon challenge.
Scott: Yes, anyway, that's why it's a challenge.
Rym: I wonder if Mitch McConnell's ever attempted the one-gallon challenge.
Rym: Might have to get him on the show and ask him.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: God, if we got Mitch McConnell on the show.
Scott: That'd be crazy.
Rym: We'd just ask him that one question.
Scott: Well, we'd also be like, "Hey, so, uh, congratulations for having some nuts, unlike your other friends there in the
Scott: Senate.".
Rym: Yeah, but I mean, he's the whip of the Republicans, and he voted against this, but other than that, it was pretty much a straight party-line vote, and the fact that it was only one vote away from going to a ratification bit kind of scares me.
Scott: It's kind of frightening, and it's kind of weird that, you know, what is it?
Scott: Democrats voting for freedom?
Scott: That's kind of frightening.
Scott: Well, I mean, the Republicans- They're usually, like, if you look at what should be the official Democratic party line, the Republicans are actually supposed to be more freedom than the Democrats.
Rym: Yeah, well, isn't?
Rym: it used to be that the conservatives and the Republicans will cut taxes and save money and be frugal, and the Democrats are tax-and-spend liberals, but it's gotten now to where the Democrats are the fiscally conservative ones, and the Republicans are tax-and-spend.
Rym: Well, no, no, no, they're tax-cut-and-spend.
Scott: The other guys are tax-and-spend.
Scott: Spending is across- we need a no-spend party to get voted in.
Rym: The problem is, we can't cut spending on most things without creating holy hellfire.
Scott: Oh, you're just gonna have to deal with some holy hellfire now, or, in the future, you won't-.
Scott: you know, if we have a little bit of holy hellfire now, we can survive later.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: If we don't have holy hellfire now, later we're doomed and there's no way we can fix it.
Scott: It's either suffer now to fix it forever, or for a long time, or we're gonna get to a point where it can't be fixed and it's all over.
Rym: I guess it just frightens me that the government in general has been more and more attacking the First Amendment from every possible front.
Rym: I mean, the FCC's powers have been expanded recently.
Rym: They've greatly increased the fines for, you know, speaking obscenities on the radio, fuck.
Scott: Fuck.
Scott: Fuck them.
Rym: And, now, this bill almost passed that would further- I mean, it would pass an amendment to restrict the First Amendment.
Scott: You know, it's really so dumb, it's like, I can't tell if the people who are voting for this amendment, maybe some of them really are for flag burning and for freedom, and they just know that if the amendment passes, that there will be a glut of extra flag burning.
Scott: 'Cause right now, there isn't a problem with flag burning.
Rym: I gotta say, if that amendment passed, I would be out on the street burning flags.
Scott: You know what, I would start a company to sell flags made out of extremely flammable materials.
Rym: No, you gotta make 'em out of a special wick so they burn for a long time.
Scott: Well, they would be, but they would be easy to light on fire, they would burn safely- To sell flags.
Scott: They would burn safely, slowly, and brightly.
Scott: Special burning flags.
Rym: Just make flags that have wicks on 'em.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, no, they'd also be all, like, waxed up, and they'd have some pyro in them to get, like, red, white, and blue fire.
Scott: It'd be so great.
Rym: I think that would be patriotic, having a red, white, and blue fireball.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now, I could talk more about this, but it's just a news bit, and not a- What if a firework I buy has a little tiny flag on it?
Scott: Like, on the cardboard?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It depends on the specific wording of the amendment, and the laws that would thereby be passed.
Rym: Though I'll note, I'll note that if this were passed, there has only been, in the history of this country, one other amendment ever that restricted freedom.
Scott: Every amendment- Prohibition.
Rym: Every amendment we've ever had has either increased freedom, or had nothing to do with freedom.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And the only amendment that ever restricted freedom was the Prohibition.
Scott: And when Prohibition said, "You can't drink alcohol," and you know what?
Scott: There was more alcohol drinking during Prohibition than ever.
Rym: And the fact that it was repealed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, if there was a flag burning amendment, I bet you there would be more flag burning than has ever happened in the history of the world within a week, and then they would have to repeal it.
Scott: Or, they would be putting so many people in jail.
Scott: Yeah, we really, we should start a company now that makes special burning flags.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Though, if something like that ever actually passed, I don't know what I'd do, other than burn flags.
Scott: I'd burn a lot of flags.
Rym: Yeah, but what else?
Rym: What deeper inner meaning could we impart into that flag burning?
Scott: I would burn lots and lots of flags.
Scott: Big ones.
Scott: All right, so I'd burn- In crazy places, in crazy creative ways.
Scott: I'd burn a thousand flags.
Scott: I would make little paper airplanes out of flags and throw them through fire hoops and all kinds of crazy stuff.
Rym: So what would you call this act of yours?
Scott: The aristocrats.
Rym: See, without any prompting, I'm just glad you said that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, I have nothing else to say about this unless I did a whole episode on it.
Rym: I'm not going to get into a political rant, but goddamn, one vote, just now, Senate, first amendment, bye bye.
Scott: Thank you, One Gallon Challenge Mitch.
Rym: Yes, you're my man, Mitch One Gallon McConnell.
Scott: Yes, you saved me a lot of money on flags and matches.
Scott: Okay, meanwhile, the Supreme Court and the other one third of our government- Yeah, I don't think we need to talk about the administrative branch.
Scott: No, we don't.
Scott: You mean the executive branch.
Rym: Yeah, well, they're also administrative to a degree.
Scott: So they are going to do some judgment, as judges do, on this case of KSR International Incorporated versus Teleflex.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Teleflex, apparently, has a patent covering, quote, "gas pedal," quote, "technology for cars and light
Scott: trucks.".
Rym: Um, uh, what could this possibly be?
Scott: I think they've really just patented the gas pedal.
Rym: You know, I gotta say, it doesn't surprise me, because I mentioned this before, but when I worked at IBM, I did, you know, crap for them all the time, and after I left, they emailed me, and they needed my information, my contact info, because they were trying to patent one of the things I had done for them.
Rym: Something that was trivial and just like part of my normal duties, like, I wouldn't even consider signing my name on what I had done.
Rym: It was like a bash script.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But no, they want a patent on it, and it'll probably pass.
Scott: Yeah, okay, so, KSR, the good company, has argued that the Federal Circuit, which is all the federal courts, have been improperly interpreting patent law for years when it comes to deciding whether an invention is obvious.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: Do you agree?
Rym: Yeah, but I wonder what the Supreme Court's gonna rule.
Scott: Well, the court has ruled in the past, for instance, that even a combination of preexisting, off-the-shelf components, in which each component performs exactly the same function that it had been known and was designed to perform, could be patentable.
Scott: Such an interpretation, KSR argued--I'm reading the article.
Rym: Oh, obviously.
Scott: Such an interpretation, KSR argued, isn't consistent with the provision of federal patent law that dates to 1952, which I actually kind of like.
Scott: It says, "A person having ordinary--".
Scott: uh, okay, "An invention is not eligible for a patent if a person having an ordinary skill in the art would consider it
Scott: obvious.".
Scott: I think that's pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is that people in the patent office aren't skilled in any art that would be patented.
Scott: Exactly, but all they have to do is call up one guy who is a person having ordinary skill in the art and ask him if that's obvious or not.
Rym: They could call me.
Scott: They could call me.
Scott: I mean, the thing is-- If it's a car thing, call Joe the Mechanic, you know?
Rym: Yeah, though what do you do if it's an art where everyone is very intelligent?
Scott: If you call Joe the Mechanic and say, "Hey, Joe the Mechanic, uh, look at this design for a gas pedal.
Scott: Is that--is that
Scott: obvious?".
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty obvious.
Scott: Okay, no patent.
Scott: Takes five seconds.
Scott: Five seconds to call Joe the Mechanic.
Rym: Yeah, but first they gotta vet out Joe the Mechanic's credentials, make sure he's a real mechanic, get the opinions of five other mechanics, then do the whole thing again?
Rym: because No, you don't!
Scott: If you could just walk to a mechanic shop and show him the thing, that's all you need!
Rym: You realize the government can't do anything unless they can fully document the process from start to finish.
Scott: I went to Joe the Mechanic on Fourth and Main--.
Rym: No, no, as in, what is the specific procedure for finding a specific mechanic for each patent?
Scott: This is the problem we have, is there's too much just useless paperwork in the way.
Rym: That's not even paperwork, it's just you gotta have some sort of procedure.
Scott: Yeah, the procedure is, you call someone who is having ordinary skill in the art.
Rym: Who do you call?
Scott: Anyone in the Yellow Pages.
Rym: Um, what do you mean "anyone in the Yellow Pages"?
Rym: There's a lot of non-mechanics in the Yellow Pages.
Scott: Anyone who has ordinary skill in the art.
Rym: How do you determine who has ordinary skill in the art?
Scott: If it's a mechanic, you look under the mechanics section in the Yellow Pages.
Rym: What if it's a mechanic who happens to specialize in jaguars, and he doesn't know anything about any of their cars?
Scott: Then you call-- if he knows about any car, he knows about gas pedals.
Scott: What if he just lies?
Rym: What if you call a mechanic and just some punk kid who works there answers, he says, "Yeah, I'm Joe,".
Rym: and then he just says, "Yeah, that's obvious,
Rym: whatever.".
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Fun.
Rym: No it's not.
Rym: Yes it is.
Rym: It doesn't matter!
Scott: I'm not even Joe the Mechanic, and the gas pedal is obvious.
Scott: It's obvious.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh my god, who the hell is working in the patent office?
Scott: Retards?
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: It's a gas pedal.
Scott: It's obvious.
Scott: Every car has one.
Scott: You can't patent it.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Scott, have you ever read a patent?
Scott: It's not-- I've seen a few.
Rym: It's not obvious when something is obvious, because if you actually read a patent, the way patents have to be written, and many of them are written this way specifically to prevent the USPTO from investigating them, patents are written in a way that is almost indecipherable to normal humans.
Scott: I say if a patent is indecipherable to normal humans, it's immediately void.
Rym: No, because they won't accept patents that aren't written that way.
Scott: They shouldn't.
Scott: There should be a new way of submitting patents.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: a new way?
Scott: You write one paragraph that describes in plain English what your invention is, the end.
Rym: That doesn't work at all.
Rym: We're going to dive one picture.
Rym: Because what a patent is is you have to describe in excruciating detail what something does.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: If your thing is only different from other things in a very small, very, very tiny way, then it's not different enough, fuck you.
Rym: I submit that with many very intricate manufacturing processes, in fact, it is very different.
Scott: You shouldn't be able to patent stuff like that.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: I think you should only be able to patent physical inventions, that's it.
Rym: They are physical inventions.
Scott: What kind of physical invention is it, a machine?
Rym: A physical invention of a type of machine that can create a certain kind of glass-ceramic hybrid chip.
Scott: Good, here are the plans for my machine, there it is, the end.
Rym: Okay, what if I make a machine that's better, or does something in a new, innovative way?
Scott: The patent office gets the plans for the new machine, compares them to existing machine plans.
Rym: They have no idea how this stuff works.
Scott: You look at the plans for the machine, you look at all the other plans for machines, you say, "Oh, it's not the same as all these other machines,".
Scott: there you go.
Rym: What if they are the same, and they're just written differently?
Rym: What if they are substantially similar, or in fact, derivative, and you just didn't notice because you didn't vet the whole thing out fully?
Rym: It's not an easy problem to solve, and I think you're really taking a naive viewpoint.
Scott: When it's a gas pedal, it is.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You shouldn't have to do all the bullshit for the gas pedal patent.
Rym: See, I'm very much of the mind that the government should have to do all of the bullshit for everything.
Scott: No.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Less bullshit is better.
Scott: No, because-- More common sense is needed.
Rym: Common sense is never going to enter into it.
Rym: There's no common sense in anywhere.
Scott: So-- There is common sense right here.
Rym: Yeah, that doesn't work on a mass scale.
Rym: I'd like to see you try to run the country.
Scott: I could run the patent office real easy.
Rym: Nah.
Scott: In fact, I could do every patent, put them all on my desk.
Scott: Um, do you know-- I'll take every single one, I'll have a yes stamp and a no stamp, and you know what?
Scott: That no stamp's gonna wear out real quick, so get me like 20 of 'em.
Rym: Do you know how many patents are submitted to the patent office?
Scott: Thousands upon thousands.
Rym: So what, you're just not gonna read 'em?
Scott: I'll read 'em.
Scott: If they each get 10 seconds.
Rym: That's terrible.
Rym: I hope you're not serious.
Scott: I'm serious.
Scott: That's a terrible-- If your invention is an obvious, so pain--.
Scott: See, here's the problem, is that we-- we're trying to weed out the patents that are obviously not patentable.
Scott: I say, your invention has to be so obviously new and amazing.
Rym: If it's not incredibly new and amazing, fuck it, if it's only slightly new and amazing, A lot of things wouldn't be in any way amazing to you, because they increase the yields of a factory by 0.8%.
Scott: That's not patentable, fuck you.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: It's just as complex, in fact, more complex, and more valuable.
Scott: Has nothing to do with complexity or value.
Rym: Then what's it have to do with?
Scott: Has to do with usefulness on a whole to people.
Rym: That's a huge usefulness.
Rym: to be able to increase the efficiency of a factory by that much?
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: I just really don't think you thought this through.
Scott: People like that, you shouldn't be patenting it, it should be given away to everyone, so everyone can do it.
Rym: Oh, so you just-- why even have patents then, because you seem to want to not have them.
Scott: You have patents for certain things.
Rym: But you just said if anything's actually valuable, you have to give it away to the people.
Scott: That useful?
Scott: I don't think it is that useful.
Rym: So what's the line then?
Scott: The line is what Scott says.
Rym: That's a terrible idea, because you don't know anything about most patents.
Scott: That's why you haven't--.
Scott: I could do all the computer patents, definitely, and you'd have someone else just like me, who just knows something about mechanics, who knows something about factories.
Rym: Scott, how do we decide which person?
Scott: It's someone who knows.
Scott: It's obvious when someone who knows.
Rym: Who decides that?
Scott: The same way it's obvious when a gas pedal patent is obvious.
Scott: You don't need someone to decide, you say, look, here's a mechanic, he knows how to fix cars.
Rym: Who says that?
Rym: Who picks the mechanic?
Scott: Anyone.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: anyone?
Scott: Anyone can do it.
Scott: Any Joe on the street could pick out a mechanic.
Rym: So you're saying Congress should pass a law where they pick a guy off the street and then he goes and picks a mechanic.
Scott: That works.
Rym: That's the stupidest thing.
Scott: I guarantee it, 99 million times out of 100 million times, most of the time you're going to get someone who's going to pick someone just fine.
Rym: One, I highly doubt that.
Rym: Two, that would never work in the real world.
Scott: Yes, it would.
Scott: No.
Scott: It would work just fine.
Scott: All right, we'll go on the street and we'll ask someone who's not a crazy old person from the crazy old folks' home and we'll say, all right, can you find a mechanic?
Scott: Where's the closest mechanic?
Scott: And the point at the gas station, we'll go there and we'll say, is there a mechanic here?
Scott: And there will be.
Scott: And he'll be just a fine mechanic and he'll be able to pick out all the obvious mechanic patents.
Rym: One, are you going to pay him?
Scott: If you make that his new job, then yeah.
Rym: That's still, you'll need more than just him to look at all these patents.
Rym: Two, what if he makes a mistake?
Rym: Who is he accountable to?
Rym: Is there any sort of peer review here at all?
Rym: Who gives you the authority to pick the guy off the street?
Scott: It's just obvious.
Scott: Everything is obvious here.
Scott: It's all about obviousness.
Rym: That doesn't work on a large scale at all.
Scott: We don't need all this bullshit.
Scott: We need to get rid of the bullshit and it's obvious to everyone.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: Who is it not obvious to?
Scott: Those are the people in the patent office.
Scott: That's who it's not obvious to.
Rym: I really think you haven't thought this through at all.
Scott: I think it's just fine and
Scott: that anyone
Scott: who doesn't
Scott: have enough common sense
Scott: to be able to say, yes, that person knows what they're talking about and that person doesn't, shouldn't be involved in the patent process anyway and the rest of us can go about it in a completely normal, cheap, and efficient fashion.
Rym: An individual person may be able to say that, but that's their belief.
Rym: That doesn't in any way reflect the beliefs of the masses in a democracy.
Rym: You have to have some sort of process to put this all in place.
Scott: So it doesn't make, so you're saying we have a process, then no matter what process it is, if we have one, then that will uphold the beliefs of the democracy?
Rym: How would you implement your idea?
Rym: You haven't given any actual useful details.
Scott: Pick a random person.
Scott: It doesn't matter who.
Scott: How do you pick?
Scott: Me.
Scott: I do it.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: Scott, no.
Scott: The president does it.
Scott: The secretary of something does it.
Scott: It doesn't matter who.
Scott: Anyone who's not retarded, anyone who doesn't work for the patent office because they're obviously retarded, and anyone who isn't evil and corrupt and paid for by any weird company.
Rym: How do you determine that?
Scott: Any way you want.
Scott: You can elect them.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: any way you want?
Scott: The president can appoint them.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: No, pick a way because you haven't.
Scott: Any of those ways is equally good.
Scott: No, they're not at all.
Scott: They're all equally good.
Rym: That's just pathetic.
Scott: No.
Scott: If we elect someone, it's fine.
Scott: If the president appoints someone, that's fine.
Scott: If Congress picks someone, that's fine.
Rym: Because there's a whole procedure in place and there's a lot of peer review and debate and there's a very specific way to do all of those things that is well documented and well understood.
Scott: And it's not working.
Scott: so we should throw it the fuck out.
Rym: It works fine for the vast majority of people.
Scott: No it doesn't.
Scott: It works horribly.
Scott: You'll look through the patents.
Scott: 99% of patents are just useless.
Rym: Oh, you're talking about patents specifically.
Rym: Even then, it works fine for the vast majority of people because the vast majority of people don't care.
Scott: Which means they shouldn't care about it.
Scott: They got nothing to do with it.
Scott: We're the only ones who have to deal with this.
Scott: So we should be the ones deciding it.
Scott: If you don't care and you don't care about something, you have no say in it.
Scott: Only the people who care should have a say.
Rym: One, that's not the way it is.
Scott: That's how it should be.
Rym: How are you going to make it be that way?
Scott: That's the way it should be.
Rym: I really think arguing ideals like that is silly.
Rym: You gotta have some sort of actual plan or there's really no use in it.
Scott: Here's my plan, we go set all the patents on fire and we start from scratch and Scott's in charge.
Rym: Yeah, that's a terrible idea.
Scott: I become the new patent general guy and I'm in charge of everything.
Rym: Anyway, no one wants to hear you yell about your crazy plans.
Rym: Let's talk about games.
Scott: Things of the day.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: I got this, for anyone who doesn't know, there's another game that's not DDR.
Scott: that's a lot like DDR called Pump It Up.
Rym: Which honestly I'm not really a fan of.
Scott: You know, the thing about Pump It Up is the songs aren't as good, the game as a whole isn't as good of a game, but because of the arrows set up, if you get into it, there is greater capability of awesome dancing.
Scott: But you know, there's this capability for awesome dancing in DDR too, just Pump It Up has a little bit more because it has four diagonal arrows and a big circle in the middle.
Scott: So there's, you know, more things you can do, especially with a two pad set up.
Scott: So here's this video on YouTube of a guy doing a song, I think the song's called Don't Bother Me because that's the name of the YouTube video.
Scott: And he does, basically if you took the pad away and you just saw him dance, you wouldn't know that he was doing a dancing game.
Scott: It's so awesome.
Scott: Not to mention that, but not only is he dancing, he's dancing amazingly.
Scott: Like I want to learn how to dance like that.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: I mean, it's a good dance.
Rym: I've seen a lot of other people do similar things before.
Rym: It's not really...
Scott: I have, but I think this is the best one I've seen.
Rym: It only stood out because it was a Pump It Up video, honestly.
Scott: I don't know, I think it's just...
Rym: That and the fact that the crowd was giving him crap before he started dancing, and then they shut up.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, I've seen other videos of like DJ 8-Ball doing DDR, and he's really good, but you know, compared to the videos of him that I've seen, you know, there might be videos I haven't seen.
Scott: And this video, I'd have to say this video is number one right now.
Rym: Yeah, you know what though, compared to actual dancers, he's got nothing.
Scott: Well, because actual dancers, just dancing period, of course.
Scott: They are the best.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Because you don't have to be confined to some arrows at all.
Scott: They're just dancing without arrows.
Scott: But apparently, the Pump It Up World Championship last year had $8,000 for first place, and this year is $30,000 for first place.
Scott: This guy entered last year and didn't win.
Scott: So I wanna see the guy who did win last year, and who does win this year, because if it's better than this, holy crap.
Rym: I remember when we found, we didn't have DDR in Rochester, but there was this crap, crap arcade place that had a Pump It Up machine.
Scott: Yup, that place, yeah.
Rym: It was a broken Pump It Up machine, it was a terrible arcade, it wasn't really an arcade, it was kind of a family center, and it eventually got shut down because a bunch of kids came from the inner city for an event, and they trashed the place, and the police came.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And after that, the police were like, "You can't have this place anymore, it causes
Rym: trouble.".
Scott: Why does everything, you know, see our rant about old people taking away the fun things for kids to do, and then kids becoming drug dealers.
Rym: Yeah, yet in this case, the kids pulled knives on each other, and there was a big fight.
Scott: Yeah, see, because the kids didn't have anything fun, so they didn't know how to handle a fun thing.
Scott: It's like, if a kid's never had a playground, and then all of a sudden you gave them one, you know, they'd go on it and hurt themselves.
Scott: Like, you know, if they had a playground all along, then it wouldn't have happened.
Rym: Anyway, so, there's this guy here, on my thing of the day, who had never played Mario 1, ever.
Rym: Ever?
Rym: Ever.
Scott: How could you, okay, how old was he?
Rym: No, no, second, he was Japanese.
Scott: Whoa, whoa, so had he seen Mario?
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: It was hard to follow.
Rym: It was, basically, they're on this talk show, and he's, you know, "This guy's never played Mario, blah, blah, blah, let's watch him play,".
Rym: and they show his face in the upper left-hand corner of the screen, and then the rest of the screen is him playing Mario, and he doesn't know what to do.
Rym: He barely gets by the first Goomba, and he doesn't hit any blocks, and he's like cautious and cautious, and he almost falls off of things, takes a while to jump over a pipe, and then he dies on a Goomba, and he's like, "Oh, son of a
Rym: bitch!".
Rym: The best part is the second time through, he dies on the first Goomba.
Scott: Dying on the first Goomba is always hilarious.
Rym: Then they're yelling at him, "Hit the blocks, hit the question mark blocks,".
Rym: and he hits one, and this mushroom comes out, and it comes around, and it's coming down at him, and you can see him panic, and he's running away from it because he's afraid he's going to get him, and he barely jumps over it, runs away, and meanwhile the crowd's just exploding with laughter.
Scott: See, so I guess it is rare for someone in Japan, you know, everyone there knew how to play Mario.
Rym: Except this guy.
Scott: As a related note, actually, I just remembered that the three last polls on GameFAQs, which are always interesting, in fact, that's probably the best part of GameFAQs.com, is the polls, the three
Scott: last polls were,
Scott: "Have you ever played the original Mario
Scott: Bros.,
Scott: have you ever played the original Final Fantasy, and have you ever played the original Legend of
Scott: Zelda?".
Scott: You know what the results are?
Scott: Have you ever played the original Super Mario
Scott: Bros.?
Scott: ? 47.67%
Scott: say yes, and I still own the original cartridge, 42.58% say yes way back on the NES, about 13% say yes on an emulated version, and about, let's see, six, seven and a half percent say no.
Scott: They've never played Mario.
Rym: Pretty much every gamer in the world has played Mario.
Scott: Well, actually, 1.36% have never played a single Mario game ever, any Mario game at all.
Rym: Huh.
Scott: 6% say they played another Mario game, but not the original.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it was just, it was crazy that this guy had never played Mario, because he looked like a young, kinda hip dude, and just the video of watching someone play it for the first time, even
Scott: though, I
Rym: gotta say, I wasn't that bad the first time I played Mario.
Scott: I wasn't that bad the first time I played Mario either.
Rym: I figured it right the fuck out, hit those question marks, get big, jump on things, get a fire flower.
Scott: Yep, I saw someone do it once before me, a little mediocrely, and then I was set.
Scott: As soon as I, my hard try was getting the controls, because I'd never used a gamepad before in my life, but as soon as I got that down, I was set.
Scott: I knew exactly what I wanted to do.
Rym: I found the first Warp Zone on my first time through that level.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: 'Cause I saw I could jump up there, so I was like, ooh, maybe I'll break the game, and I jumped up there and there's a thing.
Scott: Yep, the Warp Zone, I think the first Warp Zone in 2-1 was the first thing I found on my own, a secret in any game.
Rym: Were y'all excited, and then you found out that everyone in the world knew about it?
Scott: Nah, you know, it was still, I think it still had this sort of like, gleam, like ooh, the Warp Zone, even though everyone knew about it.
Scott: You know, it's like, ooh, you went to the Warp Zone, ooh!
Rym: Those are back in the days when I would throw the holy water in Castlevania 2 at every single goddamn brick in every single square of that game, looking for anything I could find.
Scott: You wanna hear the results of the other polls about Zelda and Final Fantasy?
Scott: They're gonna make you feel real bad.
Rym: Eh, we could save that for a show we should do on old school gaming.
Scott: Well, let me just, I'll just do it real quick.
Rym: Real quick!
Rym: Okay, have you ever- 'Cause the show's already long.
Scott: I know, have you ever played the original Legend of Zelda?
Scott: There are, let's see.
Scott: I'm just gonna do the no's.
Scott: Assume everyone else is yes, alright?
Scott: Anyone who isn't no either owns the cartridge, played it on the NES, or has a remade, emulated version.
Scott: 17.33% say no, they have never played the original Zelda, but they've played other Zelda games.
Scott: 6.5% have never played a Zelda game, ever.
Rym: That's better than I expected.
Rym: That's not so bad, really.
Scott: Original Final Fantasy.
Scott: 28.82% have never played the original Final Fantasy, but have played other Final Fantasy games.
Scott: About 13% have never played a Final Fantasy game, ever.
Rym: Eh, once again, kind of expected, considering that these games came out a long time ago.
Scott: I know, but only 26% of people have played Final Fantasy 1 on the original NES.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: I guess I'm no longer- Most people haven't.
Rym: I'm no longer jaded by those sorts of things.
Scott: Uh, uh, I'm telling you, nowadays in schools, you know, they give you the classic books to read, you know, the Shakespeares.
Scott: In the future, they're gonna give you the classic video games.
Scott: You gotta play Zelda, that's your homework.
Scott: Bring it back and write an essay.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: After you beat Ganon.
Rym: So anyway, we, we're gonna do something a little different today, because over the weekend, we had all but one member of the original, original core front row crew over.
Rym: And we played games all weekend.
Scott: A whole lot of games.
Rym: Now, instead of reviewing all the games, or just talking about the weekend in general, which we might do another day, we're just really gonna go through every game we play the weekend, in order, and kind of do a half session report, half just thoughts on the game while we played it, what happened.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna, you know, basically how our instance of the game happened and what we did and how other people played.
Rym: So I guess just consider this as a look into the gaming lives of Rym, Scott, Alex, Pete, and while Katsu wasn't there this weekend, he is very often right there with all of it.
Scott: And one guy at Moz.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We'll just dig right into this.
Scott: Okay, so we get to Moz, which is where we played our first game.
Rym: Yep, it's a gaming group that we run the website for, it's actually on the same hosting.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And this guy there had a game that we'd never played before that looked kind of interesting called Timbuktu.
Rym: Now, he warns us ahead of time, "This game's a real brain buster.
Rym: This game made my brain
Rym: hurt.".
Scott: It's a deductive game.
Rym: It'll blow your mind, it's so difficult, you'll need a pen and paper.
Scott: And we were like, "Wait a minute, unless the instruction book says we can have pen and paper, we can't have
Scott: it.".
Rym: And it did say.
Scott: It did say we could have pen and paper, so okay.
Rym: I was a little worried, I thought, "Is this game gonna be real
Rym: complicated?".
Scott: Yeah, 'cause it didn't look that complicated, and then, you know, we actually got down to it and I read the rules.
Scott: I was trying to ignore the guy explaining the rules, 'cause he's not good at explaining.
Scott: And I read them, and I was like, "Oh, this game is simple as all
Scott: hell.".
Rym: Now, we actually played the game, and we, you know, we start going through, and let's see, the game was, at least to me, well, you know what, I'll give my impression of it, then Scott can give his.
Rym: The game was laughable.
Rym: Before we even started playing, when I sat down and the cards were in my hand, and it clicked, and I realized how the game worked, I had fully, fully mathematically solved the game in my head.
Rym: I knew exactly what to do to win, no matter what, unless everyone else did the exact same thing.
Rym: And then it would be random chance.
Rym: I perfectly solved the game, and I made no decisions for the entire game.
Rym: I just did exactly what the odds told me to do.
Rym: And I won.
Rym: I had more points than everyone else combined.
Rym: I won.
Scott: You didn't have more points than everyone else combined.
Rym: I had over a hundred, I had like 170 points, and the rest of you, like one guy had 40.
Scott: We had like 90 something points.
Scott: Barely.
Scott: I think I had over a hundred points.
Rym: No one broke a hundred.
Rym: Except me.
Scott: We had lots of points.
Rym: In fact, I think I have the scores written down, because it was amazing.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: You didn't have more than everyone else combined.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I did.
Scott: No.
Rym: None of you broke a hundred.
Scott: We had 90s of points.
Scott: We had plenty of points.
Rym: I only lost five goods in the whole game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I, on the other hand, I figured the game out after the first round.
Scott: So the way the game kind of works, I'm just gonna be real quick, is you have these camels and you move them forward and you get these cards that tell you where the thieves are.
Scott: And you want to move the camels into places where there are no thieves.
Rym: Basically you just logically think and you know if you have a 150 or 25 percent chance of being thieved of any number of goods on a certain square.
Rym: And you just act accordingly.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You know where one thief is and then eventually you know where three thieves are.
Scott: Three out of five thieves.
Rym: There was absolutely no decision making at all in this game, unless you really aren't smart enough to figure the game out.
Scott: In the first round, I just kind of... The problem was is that my initial placement of guys was really crummy.
Scott: So in the first round, after the first move and the first time I saw another thief, I was like, "Oh,
Scott: okay."
Scott: And then I knew exactly where to move all my guys for the rest of the game.
Scott: The problem was is my initial placement was terrible, like absolutely terrible.
Scott: So I ended up either having to pay a whole bunch of, you know, lose a whole bunch of goods to get my guys out of harm's way, or just lose a whole bunch of goods and it was about equal.
Scott: So in the first round, I lost a whole bunch of goods because my initial placement was based on basically randomness because I didn't know what to do then.
Rym: Yeah, though honestly, initial placement doesn't seem to be a big deal.
Scott: It doesn't, but I put them all like in the same row.
Scott: That was my problem.
Rym: Granted, I'll note that in the third camel round, all but one of my camels were in fact in the same row, and I didn't have information about the two rows I could get to from there, and I still didn't lose any goods.
Scott: Yeah, well, that's actually the situation that happened to me in the final round, see.
Scott: The game is five rounds.
Scott: So in round one, I lost a bunch because I didn't know what I was doing.
Scott: In rounds two, three, and four, I didn't lose a single good because I knew what I was doing then.
Rym: But it was too late because I had lost no goods in the first round, too.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So, and then in the final round, I ran into the same situation that RimRent just said.
Scott: he ran into where all his guys were in the same row and he had no information.
Scott: So I ended up losing two goods in the final round.
Scott: If I had known what I knew in the second round before the game started, I probably would have lost just as many goods as Rym lost.
Rym: So the game was basically a no-brainer.
Rym: It was just, play the game, and the game is just the same thing, iterated five times.
Scott: So once you-- You could play the game four, you could just do four rounds if you wanted to.
Rym: Once you've solved the game, like once you figure out how to win every time, there's no reason to ever play the game again.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: By the end of the game, we'd all figured it out and we were just done.
Scott: There was a different way to play the game where instead of starting with the default goods, you draft goods.
Scott: And I'm trying to figure out if that will-- All that'll do is change your starting goods in addition to your starting position.
Rym: To me, all it does is make the deduction a lot easier.
Scott: I think it does make it a lot easier because you can either A, give your guys a bunch of diverse goods.
Scott: That way, if other people lose a whole bunch of goods, then you'll always have whatever's worth a lot.
Rym: Actually, I don't want to describe it now, but I thought about that and I came up with what I'm pretty sure is the optimal draft.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Or at least an optimal draft.
Scott: Because then I was thinking what you could do is, let's say your guy was gonna get thiefed of a valuable gold, you could instead sacrifice one of his worthless peppers to go somewhere else.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Rym: I'm just saying we probably shouldn't go into that much detail.
Scott: I'm not gonna go into that much detail, but yeah, that's Timbuktu.
Scott: It's a game worth playing once.
Rym: Once and only once.
Rym: There's no reason to ever play it again.
Scott: And then maybe, if you really want to, play it again with the draft rule.
Rym: I just found it funny.
Rym: I mean, the guy we play with, the Moz guy, he's a cool guy, but he kept talking about how hard the game was.
Scott: And it wasn't hard at all.
Rym: And I think he was kind of miffed that at the end of the game he was trying to talk about his strategy, and all four of us were like, "The game is just this.
Rym: It's this equation.
Rym: It's this thing.
Rym: There's nothing to
Rym: it.".
Rym: And he was like,
Rym: "Eh."
Rym: Yup.
Scott: It's sort of a wide open game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Alright, what do we play next?
Scott: We play Tinkers and Euphrates.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: One of our favorite games.
Rym: I'd say it's my favorite game right now.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: We haven't played it in a while, though.
Rym: Yeah, and it felt real good to play it again.
Scott: It did.
Scott: It was pretty good.
Rym: Tinkers and Euphrates is a very difficult, complex game.
Rym: to not explain how it works.
Rym: And once again, I ran away with the game, partly because I made a good position early on, and I made it so it wasn't easily attacked.
Rym: Scott and Alex and Pete, none of them attacked me, and then it was too late.
Scott: See, the thing is, I was getting ready to attack you, actually, with a black external conflict early on.
Rym: But I didn't put any black tiles in there.
Scott: No, I had my black guy down low, and all I needed was water tile tile to come in and get you.
Rym: Oh yeah, but I didn't put black tiles in there, specifically so you couldn't get any points from that.
Scott: I know I wouldn't get points from it, but I would get the half of the monument, which is good enough for me.
Rym: I probably would have just internaled right back in, because I had four red tiles.
Scott: Yeah, but I had all my red guys.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: The point was, is that, you know, Rym had the monument early, we could have challenged it, we didn't.
Rym: Honestly, Pete could have beaten me, because Pete did the same thing.
Rym: I did, almost, in the other corner of the board one round after me, and the game was just between me and Pete.
Scott: Yeah, I just, I was gonna build a monument, like, a turn or two later, and then someone put some tiles in the way of it or something, and I couldn't do it.
Scott: It was really annoying.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But they didn't even realize they were blocking my monument, I don't think.
Scott: I just had, like, two greens adjacent, I had two greens in my hand, and somehow, like, a black tile got over there in the way.
Rym: Yeah, well part of it is that I played a really completely off strategy from the way I usually play.
Scott: I played off strategy, I played the way Pete usually plays.
Rym: Yep, and I played a new way, because usually I play the way Rym plays, which no one played that way this game.
Scott: You know what, the way you played reminds me of the, now that I think about it, and I'm remembering, because he hadn't played it in so long, that was the way that I was playing right before we stopped playing, where I was building monuments right away and being all crazy.
Rym: Yep, though I know a good counter to it, but I didn't have to do it because no one else did what I did, except Pete, and he was too far away to use the counter.
Scott: I think I gotta go back to playing like that.
Scott: You know why?
Scott: Because not only, even if it doesn't win all the time, it's definitely more successful than playing the way I just played, and it's a lot more fun.
Rym: Yeah, well the way you played works really well, but the problem is, strategy, you can't just strategize outside the game, because wherever everyone starts initially, the game is totally different.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Like, the strategy I picked worked so well, I think, mostly because no one else was in that area of the board.
Scott: So I should have really started in, when you didn't pick the normal middle starting place You should have started there.
Scott: I should have started there.
Scott: Because that's a damn good place.
Scott: I was, I was thinking of starting there with the green guy to scoop up treasures.
Rym: Because I almost always start in this one place with my black and red guys, like I always start the exact same way, and the fact that I didn't, I chose a less optimal starting point, and no one chose the optimal starting point, at least the optimal in my mind.
Rym: You know, optimal to my strategy, not optimal to the game.
Scott: You know what else, if I think about this game that we just played, usually it feels like games have more and bigger conflicts than the one we just played has.
Scott: Well, I think that might be the fact that- The game did, if you think about it, it did have a bunch of conflicts that made the board crazy, but it didn't feel like the conflicts you usually have.
Rym: Well, because Pete and I kept, you know, just pulling out whenever there was about to be a conflict, because we didn't want to give anyone else points.
Rym: Anytime anyone got close to me, I just abandoned a kingdom.
Rym: I just run away.
Scott: Yup, that was also part of the strategy I was using.
Scott: I gotta go back to that.
Rym: Plus, honestly, while it didn't make me win, the fact that I had like 11 blue tiles in a row.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I just- That was the thing, is another time in the game.
Scott: I was gonna go, "That's right, early on in the game I had 3 blue tiles, and I was gonna come after you, and then, as the turn, I was gonna do it, you laid out 3 blue tiles in the river behind
Scott: you.".
Scott: And I said, "Okay, next
Scott: turn.".
Scott: And then you laid out 3 more, and I was like- Well,
Scott: 2. 2
Scott: more, and I was like,
Scott: "Nooooo.".
Rym: I just kept jumping those bastards out there.
Scott: And you just kept putting them out in the river, and I was like, "Well, there goes my
Scott: plan.".
Rym: I just kept drawing them, and I was pissed, because I needed red tiles, because I wanted to internal Pete out of his monument.
Scott: I so wanted to come after you with the blue, and you just kept laying them down, it was ugh.
Rym: I didn't even put a blue guy in there for a while.
Scott: It was just bad.
Rym: I was hoping that you would connect our two kingdoms, right?
Rym: And then you'd have the blue army, and then I was gonna pull my black dude out of his massive red fortification, internal your blue guy out, and then put my black dude back in.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, the game, that was a good game.
Scott: That was a good game.
Scott: What did we play next?
Rym: Then we played Attica.
Scott: Oh, right, Attica.
Rym: Which was, the game basically was just between me and Alex, as to who would win.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Rym: Well I don't wanna sound, I don't wanna gloat, but I'm pretty sure I've solved Attica, 'cause I've won like every time we've played it in recent memory.
Scott: Yeah, the thing about Attica is, I just, it's not my favorite game.
Scott: Honestly?
Rym: I discovered, 'cause I was looking for a review of it to link to, and I just linked to Board Game Geek, but two people compared Attica to Puerto Rico.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yeah, which I'm not- That's really weird.
Rym: Yeah, they, in terms of the level of thought and strategy and tactics, and I'm not sure if I agree with them at all.
Scott: I don't think I agree with them one bit.
Scott: Attica is so much less than Puerto Rico in terms of strategy and tactics.
Rym: See, I'm not sure yet.
Rym: The only thing I know is that about ten games ago, maybe eight or nine, I came up with a ratio of drawing and playing tiles, and a ratio of cards in my hand- Well, two to three, right?
Rym: Actually, no.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It changes as the game, it's really complicated.
Rym: I really can't write it down, but if you want, we could sit down and I could show it to you.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And the ratio changes depending on how many of each Amphora-generating bit I've got, and based on how many cards are in my hand and whatever.
Rym: And I play by this formula, and I always win.
Rym: But that was two player.
Rym: Then we played this four player game, and it worked just as well, except Alex went for the connect two temples and win strategy.
Scott: Yeah, there you go.
Rym: And he was right there, and he almost did it, and basically, I couldn't stop him.
Rym: Pete could have stopped him, but chose not to.
Rym: So, Scott, the only reason he stopped him is because he had a way to do it that didn't really hurt him.
Rym: It was neutral to Scott, and it prevented Alex from ending the game right then.
Rym: Which eventually caused me to win.
Scott: See, that's the thing I like about Attica, is the territory and the placement of the buildings.
Scott: What I don't like is that if the placement of the buildings just ends up kinda bleh, the game just turns into a race, and a race isn't really that fun to see who can build everything quick.
Scott: It's kinda boring.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is, the race is usually over really quickly because there aren't many decisions to make.
Scott: I know, that's why.
Scott: I wish that the playing, the positioning of tiles was more important and more throughout the game.
Rym: See, I think it is more important.
Rym: The thing is, usually, the game is a foregone conclusion at some point.
Rym: There's a point at which you can say, "Alright, Scott's gonna win," or "Alright, Rym's gonna
Rym: win.".
Scott: Yeah, because it's only as if it doesn't matter where you place your late things.
Scott: Where you place your early things and where other people place the early things is what matters a lot.
Scott: And where the tiles are added can kind of matter a lot.
Rym: I guess I wanna play the game more before I say if there's a lot to the game or not, but I do really like the game.
Scott: Yeah, I kinda like it.
Scott: It's not a bad game.
Scott: You know, I enjoy playing it, but it's not like, "Woo hoo, let's play
Scott: Attica!".
Scott: It's like, "Alright, I'll play
Scott: Attica.".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I guess I'm done two player.
Rym: I've solved two player.
Rym: I'm not sure yet if I've solved four player, so I wanna play it more.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I just wish that, you know, if it mattered where you put each and every building throughout the game and sort of like a territorial combat type of thing, that if it was more territory grabbing and less race to build everything, I would like it more.
Rym: Though I kinda like the race to build everything.
Rym: But that partly because it's like this mathematical web and I can just get my mind around it and it's fun.
Rym: But it's not fun because I'm playing a game with other people.
Rym: It's fun because I'm doing all this math, which is weird.
Scott: Like I could play- The race, to me, feels no better than Candyland.
Rym: This'll sound weird, but I think I could play Attica with myself and enjoy it.
Rym: I think I could sit there and control all four guys and have a hell of a time playing that game.
Rym: Which, actually, I think I might do.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: 'Cause I did that once with Settlers to prove to myself that the game was completely broken.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Then, that was the end of Moz.
Rym: We went and got Indian food.
Rym: Scott didn't eat much because he was- No, it'd be recent bargaining.
Scott: But I had a mango lassi, which is, you know, it's worth going to the Indian restaurant just for a mango lassi.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Rym: Actually, I really wish I could have one right now.
Scott: Yeah, that'd be good.
Scott: We should learn how to make them.
Scott: It's just like yogurt and mango and something.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's just like, we could make- I'm sure we could make one.
Scott: It's yogurt, mango, and ice, and maybe something else.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: A straw.
Rym: Let's try to figure that out before the weekend.
Scott: Good idea.
Rym: And then we'll make them at the shore.
Scott: We need mangoes.
Scott: We need yogurts.
Rym: That'll be badass.
Scott: That would be badass.
Scott: And ice.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: Anyway, then we went home after that.
Rym: We hung out a bit.
Rym: Then we played Four Swords.
Scott: Oh, Four Swords.
Rym: Now, we're not going to talk in depth about Four Swords.
Scott: Not the Four Swords for the GBA, the Four Swords for the GameCube.
Rym: Suffice to say, Alex hadn't played it before, so he was not quite aware.
Scott: For a little while, before he got the hang of the game, he was sort of a ball and chain on the rest of us.
Rym: But then he figured it out right away.
Scott: Then he figured it out within a couple minutes and we were good to go.
Rym: But then we got to see his reactions to things like, "Oh shit, Rym has
Rym: bombs."
Rym: Or...
Scott: Yeah, it was kind of disappointing because we started our saved game in Death Mountain World 3 and there was no fire rods and barely any bombs and there wasn't any level 2 bombs and anything that's really exciting and crazy in that game didn't happen.
Rym: Granted, the fucking searchlights and the fact that we broke the game, but that's a story for another time.
Scott: Yeah, Four Swords is great, but sometimes the only way we would make Four Swords perfect is if there are some times where you just get stuck and you don't know how to proceed and you need to solve some sort of non-obvious, it's not a typical Zelda puzzle.
Scott: It's sort of like this weird mystery thing.
Scott: Like that one town in Faxanadu that was all misty and it wasn't just obvious how to get out of there and keep going in the game.
Rym: Yeah, at least most of the puzzles, if you just walk around, you'll figure it out.
Rym: Except we found one that we couldn't figure out and then it turned out that the game had broken and the key had disappeared and eventually the game just glitched itself to death.
Scott: Yeah, but there were other puzzles that we were stuck in, like running around looking for a moon.
Scott: pearl took us a long time.
Rym: Part of that was because we were infighting and yelling at each other a lot.
Scott: That is true, but that's supposed to happen.
Scott: The thing is, the only thing that keeps that game from being super amazing instead of just awesome is the fact that sometimes you sit around for a long time milling about trying to figure out what to do next.
Rym: Wii plus DS's could be like the baddest of ass.
Scott: If there was four swords for the DS or the Wii or a combination of both.
Rym: Hell yeah, just the DS.
Scott: Yeah, just the DS.
Scott: That would be the best.
Rym: Anyway, we should do a whole show on that, but we played this for hours yelling and screaming at each other.
Scott: Then we went to bed.
Scott: I think.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Did we?
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
Rym: we just went to bed after that.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Well, in addition to staying up late yelling at each other some more.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So sad.
Rym: Well, then the next day.
Scott: What did we do the next day?
Scott: We played some games.
Rym: Yeah, we played a whole bunch of games.
Scott: What games do we play?
Rym: Vinci.
Scott: That's right, because Alex had purchased Vinci at the Dragon's Den store where Ma's meets.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: In fact, we might have played that Saturday night before.
Rym: we played four swords.
Scott: It was a game that was on the discount rack and I had heard about this game on the Board Games To Go podcast and I was kind of interested in it, but I didn't buy it because someone told me there was something wrong with the version that was on sale there or something.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The thing wrong with it is just a misprint in some of the rules.
Scott: Yeah, we printed out the rules from BoardGameGeek and we were good to go.
Scott: If there's anything else wrong with it, I'd like to know because we totally missed it.
Rym: We won't talk about the specifics of the game because that's going to be a whole episode, but it's basically build civilizations, decline those civilizations, drop them into decline, and then start new ones.
Scott: The idea is that declining civilizations that are big can still get you points, so you want to start declining your civilization while it's at its maximum, so that way you get points from your new civilization and you continue getting points from the old one at the same time because it's a race to see who gets 120 points first.
Scott: So if you decline your civilizations at the right times and build your new ones well and get good ones, then you can get more points in less turns than everyone else and therefore win.
Rym: Now we're not entirely sure how deep the game is yet, but it's very fun, it's very challenging.
Rym: Pete won the first game and Alex won the second game.
Scott: I came real close to winning both times and I think that the difference between me winning and losing was, like, I could see very small things around the game that would have made the difference.
Rym: Yup, and a lot of it seems to be the actions of other players and the placement on the board.
Scott: Like, in the second game.
Scott: In the second game Rym got fucked.
Rym: I was way ahead.
Rym: I had made an awesome civilization and then I made another awesome civilization with rebirth and I was just shooting away.
Rym: and then Pete had these mountain militia type guys and he in one round busted into the mountains, destroyed pretty much my entire civilization, and then just destroyed me.
Scott: And then I destroyed you a bit more.
Rym: And then Scott, like, swept up the remains and I went from winning to losing in one round.
Scott: Yeah, I think what this game comes down to is, you know, you look at the civilizations and what we've been doing is picking civilizations based on their merits alone.
Scott: I think what you have to do is pick civilizations not just based on that, but based on the current situation of the board and based on what other players' civilizations have.
Scott: If everyone else has the extra point civilizations, like farming, mining, agriculture, you want to take the barbarians and that sort of, and the revolutionaries, to just destroy them so they don't get points and make a giant civilization that reduces them and then decline that and then take the points getting civilizations.
Rym: But, I mean, anyway, the game's a lot of fun and we played it twice because it was that good and it was new and then Alex took it home with him so we couldn't play it again.
Scott: It is really good and I want to play Vinci a lot more.
Scott: You can play it online at this French website, but it has such a bad interface, it's not worth it.
Scott: It's not worth playing on the French website because the interface is so bad.
Rym: It's a stinker.
Scott: It's real bad.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Now, we played a game of Fury of Dracula.
Scott: Oh, Dracula.
Scott: Yeah, that wasn't the first thing we were playing.
Rym: Well, Scott was the Dracula the first time we played way back and then I was a Dracula.
Rym: Pete was the most veteran of all of us who had not yet been Draculas.
Rym: We made him Dracula.
Scott: And he sucked at playing Dracula.
Rym: We're sorry, Pete.
Scott: And he knows it.
Rym: You were the worst Dracula ever.
Scott: He was so, he was worst, I accidentally cheated as Dracula, but he freaking just cheated as Dracula like terrible.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: That didn't matter.
Rym: He would have lost anyway because he, all right, the hunters start in four places, right?
Rym: Now, he started, there were basically two cities, two places that were like the obvious places Dracula could start because they were the two points that were furthest away from all the hunters.
Rym: And instead of doing something clever or starting somewhere weird, he started in the most obvious place.
Rym: And basically I had decided, you know, I had a little plan and I was going to just march over that way and sweep.
Rym: And I marched straight over to him and unearthed him and he was like, "Ah, shits,".
Rym: and I attacked him and he ran away to the sea and then he cheated by accident because he screwed up.
Scott: He thought that two seas were adjacent when they weren't.
Rym: And then he ran away more and then he cheated again and we killed him and there was no contest.
Rym: At no point could he shake us from the trail.
Scott: No, he really, he had no chance.
Scott: As soon as he cheated that first time and we knew where he was, it was game over because he just pounced on him and chopped him up.
Scott: I think what really helped us win, and I think this is going to be the hunter strategy in the future.
Rym: The starvation?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You take events and items as much as you can in the early game.
Scott: As soon as you see Dracula and you're getting ready to deal with him, and you have enough events that you can beat Dracula, because we drew some pretty good events early on.
Scott: We loaded up.
Scott: Use the events you have sparingly and don't draw new ones unless you're forced to.
Rym: Now I'd suggested this idea half-heartedly several times, but we'd never gone along.
Scott: We'd never really done it.
Rym: This time we all looked at each other and we're like, "Let's do
Rym: it.".
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And it worked.
Scott: We just didn't take any events at all, and Dracula was totally starving for events.
Scott: He didn't have any.
Scott: He couldn't escape.
Scott: All he could use were his normal powers and his normal weapons.
Rym: He must have felt such a different game.
Scott: And he drew really bad encounters.
Rym: When I played Dracula, I felt so powerful, and I was just walking around having my way with the board and just killing anyone who could hear me.
Scott: I felt so powerful, like I was doing all sorts of mischievous things, but I also felt so weird that I was me versus everyone, you know?
Rym: So everyone won that game except Pete.
Scott: I think that the way I have to look at Dracula now is not as a game of hunters versus Dracula, but Dracula is the DM creating a good hunting experience for the hunters, and that's what it's really about.
Scott: So if someone's really good at staying away and keeping the hunters on edge, like maybe Dracula sometimes should let the hunters catch onto his trail a little bit to keep the game from getting sour, just to make it more fun.
Scott: I think that's the way the game has to be looked at for maximum fun, because if you just look at it as plain versus, it's not so great.
Rym: Now the last game we played is one of our old favorites.
Scott: Well, you played Vinci again.
Rym: Well, yeah, but I said we played that twice.
Rym: We played Amor.
Scott: Amor.
Rym: That is our favorite five player game, even though we played it four player, which is just as good.
Scott: It's pretty close, but it's real damn good.
Rym: I can't think of a five player game I like more.
Scott: Uh, Calus is pretty good, but that's six players actually.
Rym: Amor maxes out at five.
Scott: Yeah, so, hey.
Rym: Now, I won this one handily, because I tried a completely new strategy, well not a new strategy, but a strategy that-.
Scott: Well, first of all, we hadn't been playing Amor correctly.
Rym: Yeah, a long time.
Rym: This time is the first time I had ever played the game correctly with the real rules.
Scott: I think we played it correctly early on and then accidentally forgot the rules and messed them up.
Rym: Yeah, we just sucked.
Scott: And then playing it online, I learned the real rules.
Rym: Yep, but I went with a whole new strategy this time, because way back we played a game with someone we really don't like and don't know anymore, but he- I don't know if he didn't understand the-.
Rym: I'm not sure if he did this by design or by accident, but he didn't get a single victory point in the first kingdom.
Rym: Then it ended and it was scored, he had zero.
Rym: Then in the second kingdom he had a pile of money and he almost won the game, he came in second place.
Rym: So, I played the strategy of get as much money as I can, I fucked the gods every step of the way, and I got all the money I could in the first kingdom.
Rym: And I built a bare minimum, I just built three pyramids, and I got some power cards and that was it.
Scott: Yeah, it was good to buy two power cards though.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That's what I tried to do, is buy more power cards.
Rym: I specifically avoided places that wouldn't let me buy more than one.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And I just ripped everyone's asses in the second kingdom.
Rym: I bought all the best provinces and I built giant piles of pyramids on them with my giant piles of money.
Scott: I'm beginning to think that's the way to go, because- Unless everyone goes that way.
Scott: Yes, that's true, but it seems from playing online, you know, like I really just not winning, but I'm doing okay.
Scott: And I've won a couple times, but I try- I use the same strategy here that I use online, which doesn't really result in winning, I really should change it.
Scott: But for some reason it just doesn't, like when it comes to my turn to make a move, I look and I go, well that's the obvious move, and obviously that's not the right move.
Rym: Well, I used to play the way where I'd try- I'd always try to build the most pyramids on at least one side in the first kingdom.
Scott: I did try to build the most pyramids on one side in the second kingdom, and the first kingdom, but- I think you got it in the first kingdom.
Scott: I did get it in the first kingdom, then in the second kingdom I got punned.
Scott: I was able to buy back my place that I had all those pyramids in, but the other places I built a ton of pyramids, I wasn't able to get back.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Mainly because I had so much money, and Pete also had an insane amount of money.
Scott: I think what I should've done is put all those pyramids from the first kingdom in one place instead of getting the sets of pyramids, then I could've just gotten the one place and been set.
Rym: And Alex did really well because he got all the temples the first time around.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Got a pile of points.
Scott: The one time I did win online was- no, the two times I won online were because of temples, and the thing- I was trying to get the temples, but Damanhur never came up, and there were only four players.
Scott: See, Amun-Re with four players, not every province comes up, and that really screwed with me, 'cause online, every province always comes up, so I can just say, "I'll get Damanhur,".
Scott: and then it doesn't- it's not in the game.
Scott: What do I do?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Plus, now that I've played the game more, I've realized that bidding is a lot more important than I ever really decided.
Scott: Bidding is very important.
Scott: And I'm now willing to spend so much more to get the right province.
Rym: I mean, I'd throw down 10 and 15 on provinces that only had, like, two pyramids on 'em.
Scott: Mm.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But it was a fun game, and we played it, and I think that was all the major gaming we did.
Scott: Besides playing Vinci again.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But I think we actually talked about both times he played.
Rym: Yes, we did.
Scott: I think the first time we played, we all just kinda fooled around.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, Vinci's the only- I didn't win Vinci, either time.
Scott: I think I wanna play that game a lot more.
Rym: I do, 'cause I haven't figured it out at all.
Rym: I got some vague notions.
Scott: I got a little bit better than vague notions.
Scott: I've got some right ideas about the timing of choosing declines, and how to choose your next civilization.
Scott: Well, when we realized- But anything but end, I can kinda figure out, you know, the thing I'm unsure on is where the best place is to put civilizations, you know?
Scott: Is it good to go after- is it better to just build a big place, or to screw someone else who's ahead of you?
Scott: That's a tough call, you know?
Scott: Like, should you just screw over each player once, that way, you haven't been screwed?
Scott: Is that a good idea?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, all I know is that we realized that it's kinda like F1, in that you have a pit strategy, because- That's definitely the- Declining a kingdom is like going into the pit.
Rym: You can go with a three-pit strategy, or a four-pit strategy, and you gotta decide.
Scott: Yeah, it's kinda crazy that in a board game, the strategy of when and how many times to decline your civilizations is the same exact strategy as in Formula 1 racing of when to go into the pits.
Rym: We realized that, and it's gotten ahead a moment of, "Ahhhh...".
Scott: If only that, you know, your civilization went fa-.
Scott: Oh, your civilization does-.
Scott: No.
Scott: Civilizations seem to go faster when they have lots of fuel, not low on fuel, so it's sorta backwards.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: When it's low on, you know, it's like, your civilization goes faster when it has more fuel.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: They're electric F1 cars.
Scott: Yeah, awesome.
Scott: Awesome, that's exactly what they are.
Rym: Yeah, we played a whole bunch of board games.
Scott: And we just told you about all the ones we played.
Scott: Okay, on Thursday of this week, so not tomorrow, but the next day- On to the Metabits.
Scott: Yes, we are doing an episode of Ask Rimm and Scott.
Scott: You can send in any question via audio feedback, email geeknights@gmail.com.
Scott: If you want audio feedback, just attach an MP3 or something to that.
Rym: Also geeknights@frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: Alright, geeknights@frontrowcrew.com.
Rym: They're both the same.
Scott: They're the same.
Scott: The front row crew.
Scott: one's probably better, 'cause that one's more guaranteed to work in the distant future.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Or go to our forum, join, and there's a thread that says, "Ask Rimm and
Scott: Scott.".
Scott: Ask any question you want, and we will spend all Thursday answering people's questions.
Rym: We've got a lot of good questions, but we want more.
Scott: We want as many questions as you can get, and we will try to answer as many as we can.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also, because we were asked to, and I would like to say this, even though this will be more of my news tomorrow, but for any of you who are considering going to Otakon, pre-register now.
Rym: The deadline for the discount for early registration is the 4th of July.
Scott: Yeah, so if you do not go to the Otakon.com website and register for the convention now, or before January, July 4th, you will have to pay more money if you decide to go.
Rym: Yes, it's definitely worth it to pre-register.
Scott: In fact, you should pre-register for Otakon as soon as possible to pay the least amount of money possible.
Rym: Yeah, the only exception to that is if you are someone who does panels at cons.
Scott: In which case, you get in for free.
Scott: Or if you're press, legitimate press.
Rym: You can't be pressed at Otakon.
Rym: You can't be a bear.
Scott: Or if you're a guest, or if you're staff, then you don't have to register.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But all you normal people have to register.
Rym: A lot of their muggles out there.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: The unwashed masses.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: Any other bits?
Rym: I think that's it until tomorrow when we're going to do something we haven't been able to do in a long time.
Scott: What's that?
Rym: We're going to review some goddamn anime.
Scott: Holy crap, what anime are we going to review?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: We have a backlog of all this stuff.
Rym: we watched months ago before con season started, and we haven't gotten around to doing any of it because we keep going to cons.
Rym: And in fact, after the 4th of July, we're going to a con.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Yeah, Kinetacon.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And then we got Otakon coming up, and then it'll be Fall again, and all the Fall cons come.
Rym: You know, Ubercon, and all those other ones.
Scott: Uhhh.
Scott: Alrighty then.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're out.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com.
Scott: And if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight, Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.