Scott: It's Tuesday December 26th.
Scott: I'm Scott, and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we talk about Mario party.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: it's 10 o'clock on with Tuesday and Rym says all right.
Scott: Let's do high energy.
Rym: all right I'm like yeah, fuck you see the thing is I can do high energy no matter how fucking tired I am and I'm really fucking tired right now.
Scott: You can't fucking yeah, okay?
Scott: I did it do 10 high energies.
Rym: I think I pulled off quite a bit of high energy despite the late night drunken tired stupor that I was in at Otakon.
Scott: Oh, I guess yeah, but Otakon is different.
Scott: It's like by the.
Scott: in Otakon you have a second wind.
Rym: you know When you're doing something yeah, and I'd already had my first second and fifth wins by that point.
Scott: yeah But when we're at home We don't even use one win.
Scott: We don't even know we're near 10 wins.
Rym: well We would have but instead we bought some.
Rym: well when we bought all the stuff for the annual front-row crew New Year's bash Extravaganza which for various reasons we have ended up in charge of for the last many years That's fine.
Scott: Just have everyone else do everything else.
Rym: and well We let someone else do it once when way back when we were at RIT.
Scott: That was before we did it.
Scott: it was they did it was their thing and they screwed it up.
Scott: So then we took it.
Rym: yeah well before that we always like.
Rym: New Year's was always like okay, and father wasn't anything great.
Rym: And then that New Year's was the lamest New Year's party ever like.
Rym: so lame that it forced us To take upon the mantle of requiring everyone to do something awesome every year.
Rym: I mean not only was that New Year's so lame But we're probably gonna do a show about New Year's is on Thursday now, so I can tell the story all right all right.
Scott: anyway Let's go with the planned Open e bit.
Rym: oh the plate, but you can't let on that.
Rym: we plan the opening But it's supposed to be like fast karate where it's kind of this Organic.
Rym: we just were talking about something.
Rym: It's like you're a little boy Is a secret.
Scott: fast karate plans quite a bit.
Rym: Here's a secret there.
Rym: We plan everything.
Scott: Okay, so when I was a kid you might not know this game echo the dolphin.
Scott: It's the Sega Genesis game.
Rym: It was an extremely hyped game that lived up to a lot of the hype.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't remember there being too much hype about it there.
Rym: I saw ads about it every goddamn day.
Scott: all right whatever I only I never bought the game But I played it at the dentist's office.
Scott: and when I played it at the dentist's office on his you know multi cartridge Sega Genesis No I could never get like echo starts in this first little pond and all you can really do is talk to these other dolphins and Swim around.
Scott: and I was never able to escape this beginning pond like I was always stuck in it.
Rym: now I'll note that if you haven't played this game It's not like Mario won, but like say I can't get past the first level those goombas Just get me.
Rym: this is like if you can't get past not even the first Goomba, but if you can't start walking, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like you're in a pond, and there's no way out.
Scott: There's obviously this path to the right, but it's got these two bricks in the way And it's like well is these two bricks in the way?
Scott: How am I supposed to get out of here?
Scott: And I was never as a kid playing it in the dentist's office waiting to go get my teeth cleaned Ever able to figure out what the hell to do to escape this pond.
Scott: well today.
Scott: You know we want don't ask why but we bought Mario one for five bucks in the virtual console.
Rym: We could answer why but not today.
Scott: and while we were doing that I bought freaking echo the dolphin.
Scott: Why not piss away more money on games?
Scott: I could emulate for free.
Scott: what?
Scott: whatever?
Scott: No, it's stupid Cares.
Rym: see that's how Nintendo wins because the normal people buy stuff on the virtual console anyway because they don't know better.
Rym: We know better, and it's painful when we do it, but we do it anyway.
Scott: We're just masochists over here video game masochists.
Scott: But I bought echo the dolphin and I played it and I escaped the first pond.
Scott: it was amazing.
Scott: I was like oh shit.
Scott: I escaped the first part.
Scott: He did.
Scott: it took me 24 years.
Scott: it is easy.
Rym: at first bond I mean, it's not like.
Scott: I guess I'll take me 24 years cuz I'm older than echo the dolphin.
Scott: But you get the point seriously.
Rym: you've sat down and with no effort escape the first part.
Rym: It was like.
Scott: and then I proceeded to the right and started to explore.
Scott: All of a sudden I'm exploring all over the place You know and I'm finding all this good stuff and eventually I find this big blue gem.
Scott: It's huge It's bigger than me, and I'm like oh shit.
Scott: That's got to be something good, so I start poking it you know trying to figure out what the hell to do to make it.
Scott: you know do its Jimmy thing.
Scott: and I got stuck under the gem and I couldn't move.
Scott: I Was stuck under the gem and I couldn't move.
Rym: now I'm sitting there and Scott's dolphin is is upright like Sitting there with his nose stuck in the ground and he keeps hitting buttons and screaming and for a minute I wasn't screaming.
Rym: No the dolphin was screaming.
Scott: Oh the dolphin.
Scott: We have every time I push the squeak button the dolphin goes Kind of like a thought bird or like a dolphin.
Rym: yeah like a dolphin bird right thought.
Rym: So I'm watching him.
Scott: I'm thinking is there evolutionarily related.
Rym: I'm thinking why doesn't Scott move?
Rym: Why is he just sitting there?
Rym: I could it's obvious what you have to do move and then before I can say anything and he's or he could say anything I think oh Did the game glitch?
Rym: is he stuck?
Rym: and then Scott says I think I'm stuck I?
Scott: Was the dolphin was most definitely stuck at the bottom of the ocean?
Scott: Tomorrow for the second time.
Scott: well, I guess maybe not.
Rym: no you've got to wait 10 years.
Rym: come back to it.
Scott: I know whatever.
Scott: the next time I decide to play my $8 echo the dolphin I will have to and I escaped that first pond for the second time of my life.
Scott: I'll have to avoid getting stuck somehow.
Scott: I don't know how But I'll try right.
Rym: so instead of a news today.
Rym: I'm gonna do something kind of crazy something We haven't done in a long time Something for which we don't even have music because we do it so infrequently.
Rym: I got a geek back.
Scott: Oh shit That's no good no all right.
Rym: This is from Maximilian and a couple weeks ago We were talking about Germany.
Scott: and when did he send us this email?
Scott: Oh god December 16, okay?
Scott: What's what's today?
Rym: December?
Rym: Something far later days ago.
Rym: not that bad all right.
Rym: But he said the feedback pretty much right after the episode where we talked about the crazy the batshit crazy Legislation that some people in Germany are trying to put forward to criminalize violent video games.
Scott: all right They want to just like put FPS designers in jail or whatever.
Rym: something crazy and crazy.
Rym: well knowing a bit about Germany I mean being in Germany at least.
Rym: I assume he's in Germany And I assume he's probably one of our listeners.
Rym: I just don't know his screen name because I'm lazy, and I don't pay attention anymore.
Scott: obviously he listens to the show.
Scott: Yeah I think that's got to be.
Scott: if you didn't listen to the show we better call Randy cuz.
Scott: he's gonna win a prize.
Rym: The thing is we have a not an insignificant number of German listeners and more than one of them is in the forums.
Rym: So I so if I see another person who talks about Germany I'm not sure which person it is or if it's a new person entirely Whatever but anyway He has some really good insight into this whole thing.
Rym: cuz we're not really experts on Germany in any.
Rym: I mean I I know a lot about Germany back when Rome was around, but not so much about modern German.
Scott: I know about as much about Germany as I know about most major countries that aren't my own country and not Japan.
Scott: And I guess I know more about Israel.
Scott: I didn't about Germany, but that's about it.
Rym: Yeah, so I'll read this.
Rym: I may or may not paraphrase.
Rym: We'll see how it goes.
Rym: It's kind of long, but I think it stands on its own and it'll add some I guess clarification to what we had said about Germany.
Rym: hi Rym and Scott, I thought I should write something about the whole thing with the game ratings in Germany.
Rym: I just wrote all this for a different site and thought you might want to read it.
Rym: first of all We're not Nazis winky face.
Rym: second this whole discussion started in like 2003 so it's actually old news.
Rym: Germany is split into 16 states only two of which want to have this law that you're not allowed to play or develop violent games.
Scott: Stop right there.
Scott: Why don't those two states?
Scott: Just become like Utah and the rest of Germany can be all cool.
Rym: You know Utah is kind of shitty, and I wish it wasn't that way, so I don't know.
Rym: I don't know how Germany works But I'm glad that Utah is Utah and Utah doesn't spread its snow because if Utah spread out There'd be like one of them well Maybe like 20 of them in every state, and then they wouldn't get anything they wanted.
Scott: I'm glad Utah only affects, Utah.
Scott: It doesn't affect anyone else, but if they were spread out not only were there not be Yeah, I'm not I mean spread out as if their power was more.
Rym: I agree with you, but if we spread them out their power would be.
Scott: yet We have to contain them to where they can't affect other people.
Rym: We've got to garymander them.
Rym: yes right anyway Germany blah blah blah.
Rym: This will never go through Never I'm not sure because I think that they are all the same political party And I guess that the other parties will just say no to get them pissed off.
Rym: So you know German political stuff.
Rym: that and the board game die bacher is all I know about German government.
Rym: Yeah, the rating system is pretty harsh.
Rym: red steel is an 18-plus call of duty 18-plus Star Wars Battlefront 16-plus Etc.
Rym: you see German politicians aren't scared of us being nazis again since Germany is overprotective.
Rym: This may make a little more sense.
Rym: some guy shoots 20 people in a school in 2003.
Rym: German politicians say to themselves What was so special about him?
Rym: Let's see?
Rym: Here's music.
Rym: know that he reads books know that.
Rym: oh, what's this doom to encounter?
Rym: strike first?
Rym: Everyone says it was because of the games, but then they find out that he didn't pass the final school exam for the second time.
Rym: I guess that's what caused it, and they forgot all about that.
Rym: Now I think one month ago this guy goes to school hurts 14 people.
Rym: no one even died And they killed himself and everyone says all caps computer games.
Rym: No nose.
Rym: I'll bet now Knows anything about that anymore.
Rym: it got brought up in the news like twice.
Rym: most Germans understand that the main problem You know isn't video games.
Rym: It's quote.
Rym: Where do you get that rifle unquote?
Scott: Yeah, isn't it a lot harder to get guns in Germany than it is here?
Scott: Yeah, I guess I have a lot stricter gun control than we do I believe.
Scott: so I don't think they have a Second Amendment.
Rym: So I guess it's a lot like America.
Rym: Germany has its Jack Thompson's who make a big ruckus or like the people in America are like yeah Bring back the draft, and then the news reports.
Rym: They're trying to bring back the draft.
Rym: But the actual reality is one guy is trying to bring back the draft And he wasn't even trying to bring it back.
Scott: well like seriously.
Scott: He was trying to bring it back to make a point.
Rym: Yeah, ironically, so I guess in this case Germany's not as crazy as the world thought they were.
Rym: It's just that because this thing was so crazy like they all the gamers who read this probably thought of Germany What the rest of the world thinks about the u.s.. When they read about Jack Thompson.
Rym: yeah?
Scott: I think it's a little worse than Jack Thompson.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, you know what it tells me Jack Thompson He should move to Germany cuz they'll find some friends there cuz he ain't finding any here.
Scott: well in at least two states It was a funny thing with Jack Thompson on like in 60 minutes or some show I don't even know and they were just totally the guy who is totally Laugh.
Scott: it had him.
Rym: It's not hard to laugh at Jack But I can't talk about Jack Thompson cuz he hasn't done anything newsworthy in a while.
Scott: He's just been his usual crazy self.
Rym: Yes, I mean at this point.
Rym: He would have to like murder a baby in order for me to talk about him again.
Scott: I don't think that's gonna happen.
Scott: We'll see all right, so I got some news here.
Scott: quite often I do stories about video game advertising because it's becoming more and more of a Problem, I guess yeah, I don't play PC games anymore not through lack of desire Just through lack of new game.
Scott: No this advertising and on PC games.
Scott: so at some point.
Rym: well monkey ball.
Scott: Yeah, right No are the dole ads still in monkey ball, I didn't see them in the one we have.
Rym: uh I didn't look.
Rym: there weren't so many bananas in the minigames.
Rym: I didn't notice.
Scott: yeah anyway someone did a study.
Scott: who did the study?
Scott: bunnyfoot.
Scott: a Behavioral research agency called bunnyfoot did a study.
Rym: That's a pretty awesome name for a behavioral research institute.
Scott: yeah, I wonder if it's this is BS or not, but Maybe I should just not do this story.
Scott: I'll do it anyway, but basically they did a study with some video games.
Scott: They had a hundred and twenty people playing who were age 18 or older And they played them.
Scott: they've had them play sports games such as Gran Turismo 3 NBA live and Project Gotham racing.
Rym: wait Wait wait wait.
Rym: sports games such as Gran Turismo 3 that's not much of a sport as driving in circles.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, whatever I was hoping for a NASCAR argument or something never mind I get.
Scott: NASCAR is a sport in you know.
Scott: I mean it is it's not the greatest but it's a sport.
Scott: anyway, they had people play these video games and According to them recall recall and recognition of in-game ads was low across the board.
Scott: NBA live and some wrestling game came out on top and Project Gotham Racing 3 had no consumer engagement at all.
Scott: Wow, so I think that's obvious is that in a racing game where the ads are flying by you You're really not going to notice them at all.
Scott: but in a game like what are the other ones are pro wrestling which isn't a sport and Basketball you're pretty much looking at the same thing the whole time.
Scott: so the ad is just constantly there.
Scott: That's definitely gonna have more of an effect, but it was still low across the board.
Scott: No one pays attention to in-game ads even when they're there.
Rym: see here's my worry.
Rym: most people don't pay attention to TV ads either.
Rym: most I mean other than Internet ads where you could actually like how many people click on them and all that as dubious as those metrics may be I have a feeling that Advertised depend I mean in the chain the people who do the studies or?
Rym: Understand how ineffective ads are?
Rym: are not the people buying the ads?
Rym: and I don't think that studies like this no matter how many you're Done would have any effect on the number of ads in video games.
Scott: No, I don't think so either.
Scott: Here's the problem right is you have The advertising industry itself which while they do things We don't like they're good people working in that industry, and if we stop buying ads people are out of jobs.
Scott: Oh well - you've got a lot of things that we do like.
Scott: that can only exist because of advertising.
Scott: Without advertising they wouldn't exist because they have no way to make money.
Scott: They would either have to just do it for free or not do it And there's really no way for them to make money.
Scott: at least no currently existing business model.
Rym: Ha like slashdot.
Scott: Yeah exactly Three if People don't pay attention to ads and they don't like ads.
Scott: But people seem to some people seem to think ads work.
Scott: if someone ever puts two and two together this whole shit house is gonna go.
Rym: I Mean the nerds all figured it out, and we just use adblock.
Scott: yeah, I know.
Scott: but Someday some advertise.
Scott: some people who buy ads from ad agencies are gonna start to realize hey our ads don't do shit Let's stop buying them.
Scott: then the ad agency is gonna go.
Scott: shit We're out of customers is gonna be no ads.
Scott: then the people who do things supported by selling advertising space They're gonna be in the shit like a network TV.
Scott: Oh, yeah, all all at once are gonna have no network television.
Scott: all the advertisers are gonna be out of jobs.
Scott: well look now Who make products and services are gonna save a lot of and network TV.
Rym: as soon as things like TiVo appeared suddenly people started skipping ads and the executives in the TV industry got really nervous real quick and doing everything they can to make sure that time-shifting is either illegal or Limited or coming up with any way to force you to watch those ads.
Scott: I mean I go to the movie theater And they've got the freaking ads lined up at the front.
Rym: You know what bothers me more than that when I go to the movie theater and the ads are playing And I continue to talk because the ads are playing and not the actual movie, and I get shushed by someone around me.
Scott: Yeah, what I've never been sure.
Rym: I've been sure.
Rym: I've been shushed by making noise during the coca-cola ad that comes before every So much shush me during the ads.
Scott: I would start yelling it like it's a freaking ad.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: my altercation went along those lines?
Rym: And it was responded to with a louder shush and a look of exasperation.
Scott: I Would have done it again to see how far that exasperation would go.
Rym: it was a big fat lady.
Rym: I don't think she was gonna do much.
Rym: You couldn't catch me.
Scott: I get her as indignant as possible So she would get kicked out of the theater.
Rym: No.
Rym: I didn't really want to bother with that.
Scott: I thought it's all that would be more entertaining than the movie.
Scott: What movie is there That'd be more entertaining than a diggin fat lady?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I was I'd go to the theater and sit through ads just to see indignant fat lady.
Rym: Let's make a movie.
Scott: Indignant fat lady.
Rym: Why don't we?
Rym: why don't we just make a movie like, you know, Jackass and Borat and all those movies?
Rym: But all we do is go around Find the type of person who is conducive to being made indignant.
Rym: make them indignant.
Rym: the way John Cleese used to irritate people Sounds good.
Rym: and never buying the release.
Rym: never do.
Rym: never push them over the edge to where they get so indignant that they turn to Anger and punch.
Scott: All right, everyone start sending us money and we will go buy a camera and make this movie or Film yourselves making people indignant.
Rym: Well, no because that requires many cameras No And it's none of which we own and then just put them on YouTube and then we can watch him or we can skip That whole movie thing.
Scott: Well, no, see I'm hoping to actually like, you know, because I know that's not actually gonna happen.
Scott: We're just shit talkers.
Scott: I want to get like a camera here.
Scott: Yeah, that's the only electronic gadget.
Scott: We don't have All right.
Rym: Yeah send us money lots of money.
Rym: send us cameras and go to dig and dig us and then give us money.
Scott: Yeah, right Give us money for nothing.
Rym: things of the day.
Scott: Oh Man, I got a nice backlog of things of the day here for you people.
Rym: All right, so pop one out of the queue or push one out of the depending on what you're using.
Rym: Yeah got a stack or a queue.
Scott: this here is a pretty good article that came up today and it was around the Nets and I think I didn't read it at all actually, but I know that it's gonna be interesting.
Scott: The title of the article is the history of computer role-playing games part 1 the early years 1980 Through 1983. it starts out by talking about tabletop games and how they took those systems and ported them into the computer.
Scott: and then You know, it starts off with like mainframe games.
Scott: and let's see 1983. this article ends with games like Dungeons of Dagorath tunnels of doom.
Rym: Wow, you know what?
Rym: These games can't?
Scott: I mean much like the Italian guard the Atari Role-playing adventure games that we picked up, you know These actually look more playable than those because you actually have the controls of a computer.
Scott: They talk about Ultima 1 in here.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, Ultima 1 was not a good game.
Scott: No, none of these are really good games.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: This one looks pretty good.
Scott: temple of aps.
Scott: Hi I mean, I'll even kind of fun.
Rym: even a lot of the later games like the gold box D&D games and all that and Even although a lot of the later Ultima's as much nostalgia and joy as I gained and have from these games They're a bit shit.
Scott: All these games are pretty bad.
Scott: But back in their day they were it, you know And it was a lot easier than you know to play if you're a loser sitting at home and you had a computer.
Scott: There's a lot easier to play these games and to find some friends for some real D&D action.
Rym: Ah true true Yeah, I guess we're lucky that I mean we grew up in the era of online gaming and MMOs.
Scott: Yeah, you know some of these are better than MMOs.
Scott: I got to say depends
Rym: on the MMO,
Scott: but either way if you are, you know Someone who is a fan of role-playing games of any sort and especially the video role-playing games, you know Those all came from somewhere, you know, the Japanese didn't invent them, you know, it's like we.
Scott: it's like most things in Japan.
Scott: We invented it.
Scott: They took it made it better and sold it back to us.
Scott: Yeah, like that whole samurai thing or that language More like I know the car the anime the manga Yeah, all that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway all the stuff that we actually like.
Scott: but Yeah, so the role-playing game is yet another thing like that and here you can read the history because I'm pretty sure that Most of our listeners, you know, I mean we got some old listeners who are playing these games But most of you probably weren't playing Computer RPGs when I was zero years old.
Scott: So this article will enlighten you to many things enlighten me to many things and I'm about to read it.
Scott: So have it out loud.
Rym: You're gonna read the whole thing for us.
Scott: No, it's fucking long and it's only part one God damn.
Rym: Okay, cuz I'm definitely not reading my thing, which is an entire Wikipedia entry.
Scott: You're gonna see these a Wikipedia entry for your thing of the day.
Rym: I am because actually the story was dug up and I was just gonna use that because whatever it was dug up But it got dug up and then it got waned.
Rym: Okay, or dug or whatever you want to call it penny arcade it slash dotted.
Rym: But I know that I mean most people in continental Europe and Britain know about this and I know a lot of Americans do But I also know that a lot of Americans don't and that saddens me.
Rym: you see during World War one Which was probably the most pointless of all the wars of the modern era Probably one of the most pointless wars ever with the possible exception of the Crimean War Which as far as I can tell served no purpose other than to add a chapter to my history book And to give me the charge of the light Brigade, but the Christmas truce.
Rym: World War one horrible war.
Rym: basically they were just sending people into no man's land to die against machine guns and the primary battle strategy was to send more guys than the other guy and gas warfare.
Rym: and it was you know, the modern Industrialized way of civil war and just it was.
Rym: it was a horrible thing.
Rym: No one argues that it was not a horrible thing But it was also one of the last wars where something like this it could happen let alone did happen.
Rym: You see in the December of 1914 along the front between Germany and France the troops basically stopped fighting and in many places celebrated Christmas together and And even in some point snuck to each other's trenches or into no-man's land and had small parties exchanged gifts.
Scott: What about the land mines in the way land mines?
Rym: there weren't so many land mines.
Rym: Okay, no man's land was no man's land mostly because of the machine guns.
Scott: I know mostly because the machine guns, but I figured if you walk there you is no good.
Rym: well base, I mean the thing is these troops there started to be this wave of people who just said we're not gonna fight anymore and It got pretty bad as far as the military commanders were Concerned.
Rym: and actually it didn't really happen in any year or any war since then.
Rym: Because the commanders after seeing what happened did everything in their power to make sure that that sort of thing could never happen again.
Rym: But I guess at least for this one moment in one of the bloodiest wars in the history of the world The people fighting realized that it was all just bullshit and at least until they were forced to start shooting at each other again In a few areas they stopped.
Rym: and if you don't know anything about this I highly suggest you read the Wikipedia article provided.
Rym: It doesn't become vandalized in the next seven seconds.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of a change though because you think oh that happened to World War one, right?
Rym: Well, that was almost a hundred years ago.
Scott: I know I know but in the Revolutionary War, which is a 200 years ago You had George Washington attacking people on Christmas.
Rym: Well, yeah, but not only that.
Rym: Well, I mean Americans were some of the first terrorists.
Rym: But think of this.
Rym: during the American Civil War the battles were so like regular and pitched that many battles had tourists and Civilians having picnics in the nearby fields watching.
Rym: Yeah, think about that.
Rym: That doesn't happen anymore That can't happen.
Scott: Well, you know before they had football war was the only thing on the telly.
Rym: I mean I'm not saying that we should go back to the time when war was noble or Noble in the stupid ironic not actually noble sense Yeah, but I don't know it.
Scott: in some ways war would used to be more brutal But in some ways it used to be more civil.
Scott: Yeah gasp only if we could get rid of it entire.
Rym: Oh, no a complex view of history that cannot be expressed in short sound bites.
Rym: Yes Yeah, just read about this.
Rym: This is something interesting that really says a lot about.
Rym: no matter how shitty people are There are still good people even in the worst situations Sometimes.
Scott: yeah, I mean two ugly fat Nazis having a fistfight Fat ladies one of them's talking during the ads and the other one doesn't like it.
Rym: Yeah, there's no good there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Wow There was more good in no man's land in World War one on December 24th 1914 and there wasn't a movie theater.
Rym: I was at once.
Scott: Yeah We're just gasping all over the place today.
Rym: Yeah, we got some gasping stories for another day.
Scott: We do.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: What were you gonna talk about?
Scott: I forget Mario Party Mario Party.
Rym: It's me Mario.
Scott: All right I think we're mostly gonna talk about Mario Party's four and five because those are the ones we have played the most.
Rym: I think we're gonna Talk mostly about the idea of Mario Party and the pros and cons of that.
Scott: I think that's a good way to start Okay.
Scott: So what is Mario Party?
Scott: Well, it started a long time ago and In the Nintendo 64 they came out with a game called Mario Party.
Scott: now by the name of it You can guess the point of Mario Party was that you and three of your friends could have a party and Mario would help you Out.
Rym: now in gaming terms.
Rym: It was basically just an American style board game.
Scott: Yeah Well, I mean the classic American board game is Candy Land or Uncle Wiggly Which is roll the dice move the pawn roll the dice move the pawn And then maybe the spot will say move back to or move forward for you know.
Scott: And eventually whoever gets to the end first wins.
Scott: That's Candy Land.
Scott: Mario Party sort of puts a twist on that.
Scott: The first thing they do is they make the track a circle and it has different branching paths and there are different maps that you can play on in case you like one better than the other.
Scott: but all you really do is roll the dice and Mario walks that many spaces and then Luigi rolls the dice and he moves that many spaces.
Scott: and The thing is the track is a circle.
Scott: You don't end anywhere You're just going around and around and around and as you go around you're trying to get stars and there's a number of turns.
Scott: so you can play a 10 turn game or you can play a 50 turn game or a 25-turn game and after however many turns let's say you pick 10 turns.
Scott: So everyone takes 10 turns at the end of the 10th turn over as the most stars wins.
Scott: and that's Mario Party.
Rym: Now in terms of actual game mechanics and the way the game worked it was very simple and generally consisted of minigames and You know random movement and possibly very light tactical decisions.
Scott: Yeah Tactical decisions are pretty much when do I use the item?
Scott: Which item do I use?
Scott: Who do I use it on?
Scott: Should I go left or should I go right?
Rym: and the answer is always which way is the star?
Scott: Yes, it is always.
Rym: I go the way to the star or I avoid the star on purpose.
Rym: Yep Now we can't talking about the gameplay.
Rym: isn't really the spirit of Mario Party cuz gameplay by itself?
Rym: These games are pretty piss poor.
Scott: Yeah I mean the main problem with Mario Party is that it could be very quick But it ends up being very slow.
Scott: You spend a lot of time watching animations and watching characters walk around the board slowly all unskippable.
Scott: I mean, yeah, it's most of it is completely unskippable and very slow.
Scott: I mean if you were playing Candyland, you could do it a lot faster because you just be like you wouldn't go one two Three four you just be like six ten.
Scott: you're moving ten spaces forward immediately, you know You know this waiting business.
Scott: it gets really pretty annoying because Mario Party is an otherwise fun game But you end up spending a lot of time playing it like way too long and now lose interest.
Rym: Yep Now the thing is the reason that these games are noteworthy at all Aside for the fact that the mini games from these eventually spawned such amazing games as WarioWare Yeah, and the like but that playing the game straight up is not fun at all.
Rym: In fact, it's stupid.
Rym: In fact, if you played this game just you against the computer.
Rym: I submit that you have no life.
Scott: I did it only to unlock the maps for multiplayer.
Rym: Well, that is understandable slightly detestable, but understandable.
Scott: It was a detestable experience.
Scott: I did it while mostly reading a book and pushing air And practice.
Scott: I did also build my minigame skills.
Rym: So yeah, they have a benefit Yes, but the game itself, like I said is pretty crap.
Rym: but the reason that these games are so iconic and the fact that and not just in our front-row crew group but in a lot Of social groups particularly in colleges and among kids These games take on a dimension unto themselves.
Rym: because while the game itself is shit the risk/reward ratio of the game is Such that playing it with three other adults or people of equal intelligence to you and equal gaming skill to you With the requisite amount of trash-talking and getting more into it than an intelligent person should Makes for one hell of a time.
Scott: I mean imagine if you know Pretty much anything in the world can be awesome if you get into it.
Scott: I mean, yeah candy land.
Rym: if you get a bunch of people and you sit around some of you drinking some of you not Really fucking getting into candy lad and yelling and screaming and trash-talking You can make that game at least three times more enjoyable than it is.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you look at we're just talking about NASCAR.
Scott: right NASCAR is pretty boring.
Scott: But if you really you know Make yourself a fan of a car or a driver and you really want them to win and you start paying attention to all the Crazy shit that you know the details and everything and you really pay attention And you like paying attention to it and you get excited about it and you have someone next to you Who's also excited about it, you know that you sort of feeds off, you know, and all of a sudden you're a NASCAR fan.
Rym: Yep, and I talked about the risk/reward thing because one of the things that many Mario parties did very well and that the ratios changed a Little bit is indoor games.
Rym: But the goal of the game is to get stars and in the end pretty much.
Rym: whoever has the most stars wins.
Rym: now How many stars will you get in an average game of Mario Party?
Scott: It varies Somewhat wildly but it depends on how many turns are in the game.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's like a 10 turn game.
Scott: Someone gets three stars.
Scott: They're doing real.
Scott: Well.
Scott: Yeah in a 50 turn game.
Rym: You're gonna need like ten stars, but think about that it So few stars are available.
Rym: It's like hockey.
Rym: I mean in basketball someone makes a basket you don't even blink because you expect them to you blink when they don't make a basket.
Rym: Yep, but it will ease men's basketball Future.
Rym: I'm a joke, but never mind.
Rym: Just giving past all that good fundamentals.
Rym: But in hockey if someone scores a goal especially in some of the older days when the rules were a little different That was a huge fucking deal.
Rym: you get up and yell and scream, and it's the man of the year moment of the century.
Scott: Mario Party is the same way.
Scott: you get a star.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: I got a star you.
Rym: And if you get a star as opposed to a star Which is basically a black star that takes a star away.
Rym: That's like if you're playing Monopoly, and then someone was.
Scott: a star is not present in every version.
Scott: Oh, no, it's not.
Rym: But that's like if you're playing Monopoly, and then someone just gets a card and takes away boardwalk and park place from you.
Scott: yeah now Yeah There's the thing that really makes Mario Party different from just walking around.
Scott: the board is of course the mini games and the items.
Scott: That's pretty much what it comes down to as mini games and items.
Scott: That's why the game doesn't suck, and it's fun.
Scott: the mini games Let's say me and remember the only people playing right I go I roll the dice I move.
Scott: you know I land on a spot and sometimes a spot does something random.
Scott: sometimes It doesn't but it's usually not a big deal.
Scott: Rym rolls the dice.
Scott: He moves Then we play a mini game.
Scott: whoever wins the mini game gets a lot of points and coins and all sorts of good stuff and ever lose.
Scott: the mini game gets dick and Then every turn you all play a mini game.
Scott: now at the end of the game Whoever well depends on which version of Mario Party you're playing.
Scott: But whoever won the most mini games gets a
Rym: star and not only that but since they won more mini games They had more coins or whatever and they probably got more stars in the course of the game, too
Scott: Yeah, which means they probably got more stars during the game, but also there's another star you get at the end of the game for Getting the most coins.
Scott: in mini games They're having the most coins something to do with coins and usually if you win the most mini games you have the most coins.
Scott: You're gonna get that start to.
Scott: so winning all the mini games is really where the game is at.
Scott: They really should just have you play 10 mini games and say who won.
Scott: Let's see get rid of the whole walking around the board business.
Rym: the reason they don't is that if the game I mean I always said that I want Mario Party to be where I could skip the stupid animation so I could get on with Yep, but if you did that you'd be able to play Mario Party a lot more often you play those mini games a lot more and I think the game would lose its charm a lot quicker.
Rym: because now the game is it takes you have to have a time set Aside and people are willing to spend those hours playing this game.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean you could just play a short game like 15 turns in like an hour.
Scott: So but it doesn't really get the excitement because it's over as soon as you started.
Scott: You know when you had the big long game that's and it can get pretty epic with lots of big heavy-duty items like chain chomps and booze flying around and a lot of Wigglers and genies and shit.
Rym: It's one of those rare games where it does something.
Rym: That's really annoying You know, you have to wait through all this stuff.
Rym: It takes forever to play and in this case Adding that forces you to not play the game often.
Rym: So when you do playing Mario Party becomes an event as opposed to just a game.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is, you know, even if you set the time aside to play if you actually get down to playing it It's sort of like setting off cheap firecrackers.
Scott: Some of them might be duds and some of them might work.
Scott: You know, you got to make sure that when you play Mario Party, sometimes it just doesn't work and you go.
Scott: Ah shit This isn't fun anymore.
Scott: Let's not play it and sometimes you sit down and it's fun the whole time.
Scott: Yep, depends on the group the time the mood what's going on all kinds of stuff.
Rym: And it's also one of those games where, you know, winning the minigames means you're more likely to win the game itself.
Rym: And basically whoever has the most skill at these minigames as long as they don't they make proper tactical decisions will win.
Scott: Except there's a very slight chance of you winning by luck.
Rym: Yeah We'll see there's enough randomness in the game to where no matter how good you are The game might just totally dick you and make, you know, your Wendy win.
Scott: Yeah I mean there there is a certain You know ratio of luck to skill in the game and the luck is significant enough that occasionally I'd say about 5% of the time luck matters and skill doesn't mean anything.
Rym: Well, actually the also the closer you are in skill to your friends the more luck matters because the closer the game is.
Scott: that is True.
Scott: if everyone is really awesome at all the minigames then it pretty much comes down to luck because otherwise you're gonna win an equal number Of minigames supposedly.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Such-and-such and also make the best decisions.
Rym: But like in a German board game if I you know If I get dicked by luck, like if a game is made poorly and the game just totally screws me There is not a single moment of enjoyment in that experience.
Rym: All I do is go Ah, fuck the game fucked me and maybe someone will say yeah, you suck Haha.
Rym: Then we just continue in Mario Party if you lose by complete luck.
Rym: if Scott was winning the whole game and he won every minigame.
Rym: But I happen to land on a thing and duel and win like one thing and then I get the like the bonus star And he steals all my stars and like I win by complete and utter like like imagine if we're playing a game, right?
Scott: We played a hundred minigames and I've won all of them and I have ten stars.
Scott: Rym is one nothing, right?
Scott: The last turn he lands on a spot and he gets to fight me in one minigame and in that one minigame I don't know something happens and he wins.
Scott: he can steal all my stars.
Scott: It's possible sometimes.
Rym: Yeah, like the game totally dicks and there's stars flying around and I win and Scott loses Even though Scott was obviously better playing.
Rym: That is one of the awesome things about Mario Party because no matter how good you are.
Rym: You might get dicked.
Scott: Yeah, no one's gonna come out of a game like that and say alright Like there you are better than you.
Rym: Hahaha like you almost everyone kind of hopes that crazy stuff like that will happen like the more crazy and Broken.
Rym: the game you played was the more you'll remember it the more fun you'll have.
Rym: I mean, it's well like when we were playing against Ian in the champ world championship bout.
Rym: we got totally dicked like totally dick.
Rym: We probably lost anyway, we're doing that Well, but we were hanging on.
Rym: we had a decent chance of winning We were right there with him and the game just raped us repeatedly into the ground got stars.
Rym: They're stolen star star and then we didn't have enough money from all that to buy the star.
Rym: It was horrible.
Rym: It was terrible, but that random dicking was so hilarious.
Scott: We would play Mario Party where there was this one map this Bowser map where in the middle of the map if you got In there, it was a little tiny circle that you could just keep running around in circles in there And the whole circle is full of bad news real bad news And we would just try to get in there and try to run around in circles on purpose to make all the worst shit happen.
Rym: It's a game where winning is fun and losing is probably in many cases more fun.
Scott: Yep, you know if you like WarioWare with all kinds of minigame action.
Scott: The thing is the WarioWare minigames.
Scott: they tend to be single-player.
Scott: It's like, alright, everyone play your own little minigame.
Scott: We'll see who could do it.
Scott: Well, they call them micro games, right micro whatever.
Scott: Well, they are.
Scott: they are a bit more micro.
Rym: I consider them a subset of minigames.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but The minigames in Mario Party are less micro and they often involve direct competition between players.
Rym: Yeah, and like three versus one two versus two every man for himself all sorts of things.
Scott: Yeah, this is bunch of different combinations and a bunch of different skill sets.
Scott: I mean some of the minigames are complete luck.
Scott: It's you know, pull straws who wins.
Scott: some of them are push a really fast.
Scott: He pushes a the fastest our favorite kind of game.
Scott: Yeah, the best was like dungeon duos is one of the best ones where you know, it's teamwork.
Scott: You got two people.
Scott: one of them has to do one thing and the other person has to do something else in concert or The can can which is the game where the best at well That's the bet.
Rym: that is a game that Scott and I are straight up over many games totally undefeated.
Rym: There's no chance anyone could ever beat us at it.
Scott: Yeah It's like I have to stop and then Rym has to stop and then I stop and then he stomps in order to open this Work.
Scott: this can opener in tandem, you know It's all sorts of fun stuff like that.
Scott: If it's just for the minigames, I would still recommend getting some Mario Party Yep
Rym: or even if even if you end up not liking Mario Party at all in the very least if you like Wario where Remember that this is kind of where that kind of game came from.
Scott: Yeah a little bit of history Yeah and some even if you don't like the annoying Incredibly long board game part if you don't have a bunch of friends to play that with.
Scott: you know There's seven Mario parties out now three for the n64 Four for the GameCube and the.
Scott: there's gonna be number eight is gonna come out for the Wii pretty soon.
Rym: the the um, what?
Rym: what were you gonna say?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think there's actually Mario Party GBA.
Rym: I think there was.
Scott: there's this Mario Party advance.
Scott: So there are eight Mario parties.
Scott: There's also Mario Party e-reader.
Scott: It's terrible.
Rym: Yeah, the e-reader is in the pile with the Virtual Boy and the u-force and the Power Glove, right?
Scott: Wow the e-reader did you force?
Scott: yeah But Yeah, if it's worth it to get all those games just because they have different minigames and but they come up with a new Mario Party every year, you know, I mean the game came out seven years ago.
Scott: That was the first Mario Party in 19 2000.
Rym: I think Wow again, I'm feeling old.
Scott: Yeah, so or 99 maybe was 99 1957.
Scott: Yeah But Yeah, it just for the mini cuz there are.
Scott: you could just play the minigames if you want.
Scott: You don't have to play the board game.
Scott: So just to play all the awesome minigames is worth it.
Scott: The thing is each new Mario Party has new minigames and new maps and everything.
Scott: But they also keep some of the old Popular minigames over from the previous versions like we have four and five.
Scott: five is probably a better game I think but it has some minigames that we're also in for.
Scott: so it's kind of like Didn't get all new minigames.
Scott: I got mostly new minigames All right.
Scott: So you're gonna get some redundancy buying all the versions.
Scott: Yeah, it's still better off than buying Madden and then buying Madden the next year where the roster is updated Yeah, and nothing else Unless you have friends nearby.
Rym: don't buy all the Mario Party I don't know.
Scott: You don't buy them all, you know n64 games are emulatable or you know Just borrow them.
Rym: someone, you know has Mario Party.
Scott: Probably if you haven't played Mario Party at all It's worth playing at least one time in your life as long as you have four human beings.
Rym: Yeah my recommendation is either play it with three other people who also don't know how to play or Be the only one who doesn't know how to play but don't bother learning how before you play and don't ask anyone.
Scott: Yeah, because that's another thing about Mario Party is that you know new.
Scott: every time you're about to play a minigame You can practice the minigame before actually playing it for real and when you're first starting to play you tend to use that practice A lot.
Scott: I mean we use the practice a lot but Later on, it's just like screw the practice.
Scott: Let's try it.
Scott: Whoo, and it's a lot more fun that way.
Scott: So I recommend not practicing minigames.
Rym: You can really if none of you have played the games before.
Scott: Yeah, it's okay to read the instructions to figure out what buttons do what but don't actually Do the practice mode just play the game.
Rym: So I guess before we close this off A big welcome to all you dig users who seem to have found us since dig Podcasts appeared you and your crazy dig podcast.
Scott: I just don't care anymore.
Rym: I don't care either I'm just.
Rym: I noticed we seem to have some new listeners.
Rym: Don't forget that.
Rym: There's Three other nights of GeekNights.
Scott: No, there wasn't one yesterday.
Rym: Yeah, but there usually is.
Rym: I mean yesterday was was Festivus.
Rym: I can't really do a show on Festivus.
Scott: Sure, I think Festivus might have been the day before yesterday.
Scott: I gotta go look we didn't even really celebrate it.
Rym: We haven't had the feats of strength or the airing of grief.
Scott: We didn't even add the steel pole.
Scott: All right, we got nothing.
Rym: We got a wooden pole.
Rym: I feel kind of sacrilegious.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime Manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.