Rym: It's Thursday June 8th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk rather generically about concerts and live music.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know it's funny.
Rym: How as soon as we say we've just about picked a logo of the deadlines this weekend We're pretty much done with this.
Rym: Suddenly the submissions come flooding in.
Scott: maybe we should have just set a deadline in the beginning.
Scott: Yeah And that would have forced people to send them in.
Scott: It seemed like without a deadline people are like oh, I'll just wait forever.
Scott: and now it's okay You have until Sunday night right?
Scott: is that we said?
Scott: that's what we said Sunday at midnight meaning what June?
Rym: Whatever, I don't know what day it is.
Rym: At least probably you want to get it in before then because if you submit it at that time We're probably gonna decide like Saturday or Sunday June 11th new Midnight.
Scott: Eastern Standard Time, that's GMT minus 4.
Rym: Well are we EDT right now?
Scott: Yes, that's why it's GMT minus 4 instead of 5.
Rym: Yes You should have said Eastern Daylight Savings Time as opposed to Eastern Standard Time.
Rym: That's right EST EDT.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: You're right.
Rym: that thing that most people who try to use NTP don't do properly.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: That's why I always just when I set a time zone on a computer.
Scott: I just set New York That way the computer knows.
Rym: yep, no used to not be that way.
Scott: That way.
Rym: you said to manually switch between EST and EDT or there were a lot of programs that would do it.
Rym: It was kind of amazing that Windows did it on its own even though it didn't really do it so well.
Scott: all the time I just say my time zone is America's slash New York, and I'm all good.
Rym: No, I'll save it for another day.
Rym: But I have a rant about how we should always be an EDT and we should just drop EST entirely but Or just keep EST.
Rym: no, we should go to Daylight Savings Time mode and stay there forever.
Scott: Why not stay in non Daylight Savings Time?
Rym: because staying in Daylight Savings Time means that we generally get more daylight hours all year round.
Rym: In fact, we the US did do that in the past.
Rym: They switched to EDT and they stayed that way.
Rym: and the only reason we undid that Was and I kid you not because Parents were lobbying that it was endangering their children by because the children had to wake up while it was still dark out and go To school and they're being hit by cars.
Scott: Were they being hit by cars.
Scott: is the rate of car hitting changed?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I really don't know.
Rym: I'm pretty sure the argument was just a Bullshit, I tend to agree.
Scott: Yeah, but I still there could have been.
Scott: really is you know what?
Rym: you know what?
Rym: that's fine That's Darwin.
Rym: Yeah, I learned at a young age.
Rym: Don't step in front of large moving objects.
Scott: I also learned that I did not wait for the school bus in the middle of the road No speaking of large moving objects.
Rym: I read a news article today about a coming crisis in the United States.
Scott: Is this fear-mongering?
Rym: No, this is something that's actually going to happen.
Rym: Okay Now stay with me on this.
Rym: currently our roads in the u.s.
Rym: Especially in urban centers are pretty taxed as it is and There are many places where there just aren't enough roads and it's hard to get around.
Rym: But at the same time there is no alternate means of transportation.
Rym: Driving is really the only way to get around the United States with rare exceptions in large urban centers.
Rym: now Driving especially in the u.s.
Rym: Is somewhat difficult in that traffic is moving very fast Even though illegally most of the time.
Rym: there are a lot of windy roads a lot of rules there are a lot of car collisions in this country and The most dangerous both to themselves and others demographic per capita on the road is people over the age of 65.
Rym: I Agree old people.
Rym: No, no offense to anyone but old people really they it's proven they don't drive as well.
Rym: They are in general now.
Rym: There are a lot of specific Counter-examples, but yeah you can find.
Scott: if I wanted to I could find a person of any age who couldn't drive at all and I could find a 90 year old guy who was the best driver you ever seen.
Scott: But I'm sure Michael Schumacher when he's 90 can still outdrive all of us.
Scott: But the point is is that on average old people can't drive for shit And if you don't believe me go to Florida now.
Rym: at the same time They're actually almost neck-and-neck with the second most dangerous group teenagers.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep Now the teenagers just don't know what they're doing and the old people know what they're doing.
Rym: They just physically can't do it anymore.
Scott: But the fact remains that both groups are dangerous Now at least more dangerous than the other than everyone else.
Rym: Yes far above average statistically now Because young people can't vote.
Rym: I mean you can't vote until you turn 18, but you can drive depending on where you live as soon as you're 14. now because of this teenagers have Increasingly bad restrictions on their licenses and it's been getting worse and worse as time has gone on.
Rym: When I was in Michigan, I was a kid when I was 14 like end of 14 I got a car and I turned 50 now and then 15 ish driver's license per learner's permit thing the day I turned 16.
Rym: I got my driver's license.
Rym: Now you don't really get your driver's license until you're 18 and there are people trying to push it to 21 But the fact that was your 21 because the 18 19 and 20 year olds will come out to vote.
Rym: Yeah, but you can push it to 18 because no one younger than that can vote against it.
Rym: That's correct.
Rym: Now in addition to being the most dangerous group of people on the road the elderly are the most prolific voters in the country.
Scott: That is also correct.
Rym: so it is very difficult to restrict their ability to drive both from a practical standpoint and from a political standpoint.
Rym: any politician who advocates anything like Testing people and to prove that they can still drive every 10 years gets voted right out because all the old people don't like it.
Rym: Yep now normally this works out because there aren't so many elderly people on the roads.
Rym: But there's a something coming that people aren't really thinking about so much yet.
Scott: The baby boomers are getting old and they're going to retire and become old people.
Scott: there's Florida.
Rym: in the next 20 years There's going to be a sudden dramatic influx in the number of elderly drivers Partly because there's gonna be a whole bunch of people getting old all at once because there was a boom in the population.
Scott: Yeah, if you think driving is getting worse, and there are more and more old people driving around slowly There are now two and this one is.
Rym: this isn't really empirical, but it seems very interesting nonetheless.
Rym: Baby boomers as a generation tend to very much value their independence tend to have very long drives to commute tend to live far away from urban centers and have to travel a lot by road.
Scott: as A result they are probably not going to give up driving no matter how bad they are at it and the generation prior to them is living longer and longer and Is also going to continue driving as they get older and older now.
Rym: It's not an easy issue to solve.
Rym: I mean you can't just take away like oh after your 70 Logan's run You can't drive anymore, and you really can't even even if you restrict it based on skill or ability.
Rym: You're now stranding countless people who really in the way America's set up.
Rym: They have no way to get around.
Rym: now They are trapped in their home.
Scott: Yeah, if my grandma didn't couldn't drive, and I mean she can kind of drive She.
Scott: you know she's not the best driver in the universe, but she drives better than a lot of other old people.
Scott: Actually my other grandma drives better than I'd say 90% of old people But I know plenty of old people who can't drive at all like they drive worse than 13 year olds now drive in the initial d arcade game.
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: I mean, I'm very much an advocate of every 10 years.
Rym: You should be tested to prove you can still drive.
Scott: I'm the advocate of every 10 years should be.
Scott: you should be tested and then once you get old you should start getting tested every Year or every two years more frequently as you cross the line into where you are losing physical abilities such as vision and hearing.
Scott: However that could be considered age discrimination among many circles, but here's the thing Discrimination and prejudice in any ism racism sexism Whatever is bad because what you were doing is you're judging people based on a criteria.
Scott: That doesn't mean anything.
Scott: a black person is no more or less capable than a white person.
Scott: in most Circumstances I say ninety nine point nine nine nine percent of circumstance because that other point oh one is being black bastard.
Scott: Yes, it doesn't matter if you're black or white if you're a computer program What the hell You never heard that Michael Jackson song.
Scott: no black or white, okay, whatever You know a black person isn't necessarily better computers than a white person.
Scott: a woman isn't necessarily better It you know driving than a man.
Scott: It's it all depends on your driving skill.
Rym: Wow you went skill.
Rym: You actually avoided making a funny sexist joke.
Scott: I expected women can't drive.
Rym: I don't know what you're gonna.
Rym: Say.
Scott: I just kind of one guys say hey, yeah But you know what.
Rym: neither can UGE day Asian something.
Scott: well Asian women half of them can't drive for shit and half of them are like race car drivers.
Scott: Uh-huh, but anyway at least every single one I've ever met.
Scott: Okay, but the point is that Oldness does have an effect on driving skill and therefore it is perfectly okay to discriminate Against old people because it does matter except it isn't because it's a democracy and they can just vote and say no No, we're not doing that.
Scott: democracy ain't perfect.
Rym: Yeah, so what do we do?
Rym: do we do we go against the principles of democracy and do something that is an anathema to the population or Do we let the population have their way knowing that will only hurt them in the end?
Rym: and even then no matter what we do If we take if we don't do anything the roads get more dangerous.
Rym: if we take their licenses away We have now basically condemned them to a slow lonely death mm-hmm.
Rym: well obviously the answer is we need mass transit, but Yeah mm-hmm.
Scott: Maybe the old people who can drive should drive around the old people who can't.
Rym: Maybe the old people who vote in such record numbers every year and are really the true deciders of American domestic policy Should vote for mass fucking transit.
Scott: Maybe if we could force them and take their cars away Then they would vote for mass transit if they were all stranded.
Rym: But we can't force them without taking away their ability to vote, but if we take away their ability to vote They're not gonna vote for the mass transit.
Rym: Why oh, why does she swallow the fly?
Rym: There's really All right, yeah, I was just a rant.
Rym: I don't have an answer.
Rym: well I have an answer, but no one other than probably you listeners is gonna go along with it.
Rym: Yeah, that's transit mass fucking transit.
Scott: my answer is the trainee.
Scott: people Assume that democracy equals freedom.
Scott: You can have a free society in a free government without it being a hundred percent or mostly democratic government.
Scott: Just the same way you can have communism without a dictatorship although you know that there's things to say about that.
Rym: Yeah, well communism has worked very well in very small scales.
Scott: Yes, especially when it's not it doesn't have a dictatorship associated with it.
Rym: I mean our house is generally communist.
Scott: I guess.
Rym: But so with two people you can pull it off.
Rym: So I you can expect any day to find Scott dead with an ice pick in his eye.
Scott: I Don't have any incentive to do the housework anymore.
Scott: Oh wait this I don't do the housework.
Scott: I guess communism's failings even show with two people.
Rym: see actually not too long ago We I think it was with Scott Johnson We were talking and we've determined that Scott right here Scott of GeekNights is actually a living tragedy of the Commons.
Rym: Scott is the tragedy of the Commons.
Rym: we considered calling him TC for a little bit Whatever and anytime there's a common Scott is there defouling it I?
Scott: Gotta take advantage.
Scott: what can I say?
Scott: That's why I'm in such in favor of a commons in which there is no tragedy, but the point is is that I personally I'm in favor of some form of government that is somewhat democratic and somewhat technocratic or Meritocratic.
Rym: I'm more and more a fan of the government in the book I'm reading right now, which I'll probably talk about when I finish the book.
Scott: yes, even though I normally Like you know people always compare technocracies and meritocracies to just having a giant computer run the government.
Scott: But I've read too many stories Where that doesn't work.
Rym: yeah, but they're all stories.
Rym: No one's ever tried it.
Rym: I know I know plus it's hard to pick the first set of people.
Scott: stories are so convincing especially Phoenix.
Scott: So convincing yeah, because there's always some robot right a story to convince the old people they can't drive.
Rym: They'd have to be able to read it.
Rym: damn Okay see we're very pro feet freedom.
Rym: But you can take away certain freedoms like I'm okay with the government or somebody taking away Everyone's freedom to murder each other.
Scott: that yeah, it's not a freedom.
Scott: That's a protecting of her right.
Rym: yeah well No there is a freedom to murder But that also infringes on a right and every time you can give up a freedom to get something.
Rym: Every time you give up a freedom you get something in return as long as what you get.
Rym: Oh, it might not be something good.
Rym: You can give up your freedom to free speech and get a horrible life But you can still do it.
Rym: And I guess people need to realize that every freedom has an associated risk.
Rym: The freedom of murder has the associated risk of people will murder.
Scott: the thing here Is that I don't think freedom enters into the driving discussion because driving drive driving is a privilege Not a right, but travel is a right.
Scott: travel is indeed all right, and that's that makes a problem.
Rym: Yeah, so what do we do when the only way left to travel in this country is something that is not a right but a privilege?
Scott: That's not about that before GM.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you know what we should have thought of.
Rym: yeah We should have thought about a lot of things.
Scott: you know Anyone who doesn't understand the background history of this issue, and why there are only roads in America?
Scott: go watch Who Framed Roger?
Rym: Was about.
Rym: I thought you're gonna say some documentary, and I was gonna say a documentary about the same issue.
Scott: Yeah, cuz that really happened.
Scott: there were streetcars everywhere in fact.
Rym: There are remnants of streetcars and fish kill right next to us.
Scott: yep and GM bought them all and got rid of them all and replaced them with shitty-ass Buses so that everyone would buy cars and build roads and highways.
Rym: yeah, they bought successful train lines and shut them down and put crappy buses in place.
Rym: And they made them crappy on purpose to make people hate them enough to buy cars.
Scott: And they also made the buses so.
Scott: even if people just bought buses They were still good.
Scott: yeah, and that is why we don't have trains, and that is why we're having this problem.
Rym: Yeah, it's so sad.
Scott: just take helicopter lessons.
Rym: You know helicopters are real freaking hard to fly.
Rym: I know.
Scott: that's why we should start taking lessons now before the old people kill Us with their cars.
Rym: Why don't we just learn how to fly planes or a thousand times easier?
Scott: Not as versatile.
Rym: They're quite versatile.
Scott: You can't land on top of a building with them Yeah, but no one.
Rym: there's no one we know who would let us land on their building.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there is who?
Scott: We could land on the BCC and go to Otakon.
Rym: I don't think that.
Rym: maybe if we become big enough guests after they can easily do it.
Scott: It's it.
Scott: I know a lot rich people with helicopters.
Rym: We're not rich.
Scott: I know, but they just call ahead.
Scott: Normal people don't have helicopters.
Scott: You call ahead to any helipad.
Scott: what wait a minute was it's in a Hospital helipad or an emergency helipad?
Scott: you just call ahead to it And then you get a landing whatever and then you go to it, so we'll pull up and are like gasoline powered Lawnmower modified into a helicopter damn straight Okay alright, so let's let's skip the let's finish that rant alright.
Rym: Yeah, I just wanted to rant about it.
Scott: That's finest Thursday, yeah, so Today our episodes about concerts right Yeah, yeah, so I'm gonna talk about the Otakon concert, which is not fully announced.
Rym: They've only announced two musical guests so far Yep, and we talked a bit with Jim Vowels the chair of Otakon a while ago And he didn't say much, but he seemed real excited about upcoming Bits about the concert.
Scott: I can guarantee there will be more Musical guests at Otakon and that they will all be.
Scott: announcements will get bigger and bigger as time goes on Yep, and I can't even imagine next Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, so the first me who will guest Otakon announced quite a while ago is muck and you CC muck luck.
Scott: I didn't know who muck was until it was announced, and I say apparently there are Japanese j-rockers whatever.
Rym: oh Japanese j-rockers a yep, you're gonna buy tickets with your ATM machine and your PIN number.
Rym: that's right.
Scott: Apparently they're not like some huge amazing crazy popular band, but they're pretty popular.
Scott: they're a myspace band, but one of the bigger ones.
Scott: and listening to some of their music and Personally I didn't find it to be amazing But it was pretty standard normal.
Scott: It wasn't bad.
Scott: You know it's just normal j-rock kind of action.
Scott: So I'm sure that will make all the j-rockers happy.
Scott: The second musical guest is this girl announced very recently I think this week Nana Kitade.
Rym: Nana yeah, Nana like from the show which we'll talk about because that shows freaking awesome.
Rym: Yes, now.
Scott: She is famous for doing the closing song to the first part of full the first closer to full metal alchemist.
Rym: It's a good song.
Scott: That's a good song which I like.
Scott: so that's cool, but now I read this thing about her and Well let me just tell you some of the important facts.
Scott: she's 18 years old.
Scott: She Was like playing piano at age 3 so she's been doing music her whole life.
Rym: What if I can put her in a box?
Scott: She became she was discovered at an audition for Sony music in 2002.
Scott: Her songs appear in TV dramas animation video games etc.
Scott: She had four top-selling singles, whatever whatever Let's see.
Scott: wait where's the line that's?
Scott: Oh famous for her signature Gothic Lolita.
Scott: look Nana has become a fashion icon for teenage girls.
Scott: Her face adorns the covers of countless fashion magazines and the streets of Harajuku Overflow with Nana wannabes dressed in her elaborate style of corsets ruffles and lace.
Rym: Now this whole gothic Lolita thing is actually been taking off in the US at conventions, too Mm-hmm.
Rym: if you don't know what that is you'll find out at Otakon or just Google for it.
Scott: It's pretty distinctive Yeah, so it seems like this girl has some musical talent, and I might enjoy listening to her sing but her style is search for the truth worthy.
Rym: Hey Hey, I like the one song of hers I know.
Scott: yeah, I haven't heard any of her other songs But they are hit singles from Sony music.
Scott: You can all be the judge of that.
Rym: So the thing of the day drought is finally ended.
Rym: I have a thing of the day that I thought was cool, and I didn't have to resort to looking for something old.
Scott: Oh my god, I'm still in the thing of the day drought I kind of picked something normal, but it's awesome anyway.
Rym: Whatever now people who know me know that I have between one and one point five eyebrows.
Scott: as In I have to I would say you have between one point two five and one point seven five eyebrows.
Rym: Well it depends on how much I groom and how much someone plucks the middle of it out.
Rym: Yes, if someone plucks them you are down to one eyebrow two eyebrows because I Know I am a wuss and I can't even pluck my own eyebrow because it hurts too much, and I almost cry.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: It is.
Rym: I'm just but anyway I Have it.
Rym: what is called a unibrow like one?
Rym: I have one big eyebrow that goes across even though it's thin around the nose, so it's it kind of.
Rym: it's in between.
Rym: It's not a full-on.
Rym: I wouldn't call it a monobrow But it is a unibrow.
Rym: Keeps the sweat out of my eyes.
Rym: I find it very utilitarian and functional I agree.
Rym: Now I discovered this website Monobrow.com.
Rym: it is a testament to men and women who have women Oh God who have but one eyebrow.
Rym: yeah, and let me tell you they put my unibrow to shame.
Scott: They do indeed.
Scott: There's some of them.
Scott: Do?
Rym: there's this one guy on the front page.
Rym: It is just a solid thick one All the way across in a perfect arch with absolutely no differentiation at all.
Scott: this thing is like 3/4 of an inch tall.
Rym: It's one hell of a.
Scott: it's just a big long rectangle.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: Now the best thing is you can submit monobrows and they have the monobrow of the week.
Scott: We should send yours in.
Scott: I'm gonna send myself and grow it out and send it in.
Scott: maybe we should get some of that spray That turns into hair, and then I don't want any more hair.
Rym: I spend enough time shaving.
Scott: That's the way to become the monobrow of the week.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe it'll be like oh, there's a subtle monobrow or it's pointy could be could be.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Gotta get someone to help me pluck it again.
Scott: I have two separate eyebrows, but they're large And powerful.
Rym: yes mine.
Rym: I've combined their powers to keep sweat out of my eyes.
Scott: It's pretty much exactly like Burton Ernie.
Rym: Yeah Wait that means you're the slovenly one.
Scott: Ernie's the one everyone likes.
Scott: no one likes Bert.
Scott: He's all annoying.
Rym: Bert's awesome.
Rym: No Bert's the man.
Scott: Bert hangs a little.
Scott: Tom bin Laden.
Scott: Ernie hangs with the rubber ducky on the bathtub.
Rym: Bert joined the KKK - yeah in fact I have a I have a funny Bert story, and then you do your thing of the day.
Rym: Now way back when I was in high school I think it was - was 10th or 11th grade thing was 11th grade, but it was.
Rym: it was early 11th grade or late 10th grade I don't remember.
Rym: Well, I feel old that I barely remember my high school years.
Rym: Anyway, I made with a bunch of friends this long photo montage thing for a class of history and part of the history we had to do was slavery reconstruction Gilded Age and We decided you know we had all these pictures of you know lynchings and various things set to music and historical stuff thrown about and Snuck in.
Rym: there.
Rym: There's one picture of a bunch of KKK guys standing around a real picture, but super imposed on the picture was Bert lol and No one noticed.
Rym: teacher didn't notice it at all.
Rym: we got our a. he noticed it not the day We presented it But a month later when we were asked to present it again to the school board because they were impressed with it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and then during the presentation mr.. Lurch turns to us And he gives us this look right after Bert is off of the screen And he looks at us and he mouths the word.
Rym: I think he mouths something like I'll see you later Something like that and afterwards he comes out and like we leave the room.
Rym: He's like So why did you sneak Bert in there?
Rym: I'm gonna have to punish you for that.
Rym: And we were like watch your original Bert's been in there from the beginning.
Rym: you gave us an A on that Bert.
Rym: You can't take it away now.
Scott: Did you actually say you gave us an A on that Bert?
Rym: yes I didn't actually say it, but a friend of mine actually said the words.
Rym: you gave us an A on that Bert.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: That's classic.
Scott: fear the power of the monobrow Alright, so in keeping with the talking about concerts today I have linked to an awesome video from ancient black-and-white times of Led Zeppelin performing communication breakdown lot.
Scott: now While this particular video is incredibly wicked awesome and Led Zeppelin is like the greatest rock band ever to walk the earth And this is like one of the greatest songs, and it's a particularly good performance The video is not high quality video wise.
Rym: what do you want is some ancient time?
Rym: I know there's probably dinosaur stepping on the cables behind it.
Scott: well.
Scott: No, but there were a bunch of your parents Or perhaps you all.
Scott: you old listeners all make you feel old.
Rym: yeah, you know what a lot of our old listeners are also foreign.
Scott: They weren't here no, but Led Zeppelin is British.
Scott: I guess kind of anyway.
Rym: We don't have so many British listeners though.
Scott: Yeah, we have a few.
Scott: we have a few all right.
Scott: my point is is Not just this video, but my thing of the day is that YouTube is a haven for many many many Concert videos and concert bootleg videos that you could not see on DVD VHS Television movie theater anywhere.
Scott: search for the word live or possibly concert bootleg or search for the band you're looking for.
Scott: there is a particularly good video that I enjoy which has James Brown and Wilson pick it together.
Scott: The particular advantage of this is even if you know stuff isn't You know?
Scott: The point is a lot of these videos have dead people in them and They died before I was born.
Scott: I didn't have an opportunity to see their concerts.
Rym: That was the least eloquent way you could have put that.
Scott: I know I did.
Scott: I changed my mind, and I wanted to word it.
Scott: Wilson pick it recently died and John bottom died around the time I was born.
Rym: in fact our freaks and geeks made a reference to that.
Scott: yes And well you know the Beatles are dead most of them half of them Ringo still kicking yeah, and so is Paul McCartney.
Scott: yes, but you know the point is a lot of people are dead And you can't see them anymore.
Scott: wait a minute News flash.
Rym: a lot of people are dead a lot of me.
Scott: just musicians are dead famous ones.
Scott: I still see them on YouTube.
Rym: Good thing meatloaf hasn't died yet.
Scott: You can see him on YouTube also.
Scott: I bet it.
Rym: You know what I haven't even looked.
Scott: Yeah, I bet we could find some good ones.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: his videos are kind of long.
Scott: Well you don't want to watch the music videos you want to watch the concert.
Scott: You know the guy with a camera at the concert true, but I wouldn't mind watching the music videos.
Rym: I haven't seen those in a long time.
Scott: some of them were just kind of long and boring.
Scott: Oh, yeah, them were also awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I think that the first one ever was the best one the one that showed on the midnight.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: yeah, I forget what that was called.
Rym: You know what I'll do a show on meatloaf sometime.
Rym: I could do a whole Thursday on meatloaf.
Scott: It's all you I'll.
Rym: half of it'll be dedicated to the man and half of it will be dedicated to the meal.
Rym: We'll be dedicated into the band after the blimp, okay Anyway it we decided While I was at work today that we were gonna talk about live music Mm-hmm partly because it's a real easy topic for us to talk about until we run out of time.
Rym: And then that's a wrap for the week and also its concert season.
Rym: well It's always concert season But even though I'm saying it now on the air so I can't forget we got to buy tickets to Camelot And we have to buy tickets to the pillows.
Scott: Oh shit right the pillows.
Rym: Yeah, tell you what you dig you get the pillows I'll get Camelot all right and all of our listeners out there remind us.
Scott: Yes, and if you want to know about these concerts Camelot, and who's the other band Camelot's the only one I cared about I think yeah, it's performing in Poughkeepsie, New York, which is very close to us.
Scott: In when do they?
Scott: that's a long time for now isn't it?
Rym: It's in September.
Scott: the pillows are performing in New York City at the knitting factory later this month.
Scott: If you don't know the pillows do all the music in FLCL among many other.
Scott: Awesome song.
Rym: they're really badass.
Scott: They are really badass.
Scott: I like they were one of my top picks for you know band to appear at Otakon.
Scott: Yeah So the fact that I can just go see them in New York is like woohoo.
Scott: now if Otakon gets say I don't know Asian kungfu generation or Maybe a Yumi then and it's all good.
Rym: I don't know if they could get a Yumi.
Scott: I don't think they could but they said they might get other venues.
Scott: Yeah, if they get the football stadium Because no one's using that in the summer.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: is the Yumi ever played in the
Rym: u.s.?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: someone find that out for us quick.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I anyway, but anyway, let's start talking about different types of live music.
Scott: Let's start with the easy one the DJ party.
Scott: All right now the rave.
Scott: They're similar.
Rym: All right We'll skip on.
Rym: you know weddings and all that crap.
Scott: Yeah, screw that.
Scott: We're talking about a nightclub or an anime con an anime con or an actual raves Or what?
Scott: any of those things?
Rym: Yes Okay, yeah When you I don't really like that kind of dance or that kind of live music because it's not really live music.
Rym: I mean a lot of people talk about the skill of the DJ spinning.
Rym: But honestly if I'm on the dance floor and I'm dancing to music and the music changes to different kinds of music over the night.
Rym: I Really couldn't care less if it was a person up there or win amp.
Scott: Yeah, it I like electronic music But I don't really care about the performance of the electronic music.
Scott: if a DJ does it once records it and plays it again It's the same thing.
Scott: No one's playing instruments.
Rym: So I mean granted they always you know, the DJ will know They'll craft the music to bring the crowd to some sort of understanding and take them on a musical journey.
Scott: But the crowd management and all that sort of stuff, but you can do that.
Rym: I don't see it as it's cool, but I don't really particularly like it as a performance art.
Scott: But I do like the music and I do like dancing.
Scott: now when you go to these things The ear here's what you got to know.
Scott: number one Don't wear too many clothes.
Scott: You will get sweaty from dancing.
Rym: Yeah, number two wear fucking deodorant - if you don't like dancing don't go.
Rym: Okay, if you don't like dancing don't go for Don't try to form a circle of people around someone who looks like they're dancing cool.
Rym: No, I will personally appear.
Rym: I will rise up like a demon in the night at whatever rave you're at and beat you down if you try that.
Scott: Mm-hmm Do not.
Scott: This could be how not to suck at concert.
Scott: How did that suck at concert?
Rym: I think that's what this is turning into.
Scott: All right You want to don't worry about how well you dance but know that if you dance well You should make adequate space for your awesome dancing.
Scott: And if you dance poorly, you know, just don't stand in the middle of the dance floor trying to make a show of your poor Ass dancing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: No one will make fun of you for dancing poorly off to the side with you know Whoever, you know trying to hit on chicks, but or men depending.
Rym: But if you try to be like a woo and you suck Well, a lot of these things will have a stage area which oftentimes people can dance up there, too.
Rym: Now if that's the case and you're in any way Uncomfortable about your dancing abilities do not get on that stage.
Scott: If you've never taken a dancing class, you probably shouldn't go up there.
Scott: And if you're one of those guys, you know who you are who can do acro You can do a backflip or any of that sort of stuff, but you can't actually dance.
Scott: Don't do that shit.
Scott: It's annoying and everyone goes and rolls their eyes except for little kids Which is why that stuff flies in anime cons, but it won't fly at a real rave Or a real party.
Rym: Yeah We're not gonna talk about the rave scene or anything cuz I don't really care about it.
Scott: Basically you just go You dance you have a good time when you get tired.
Scott: Stop.
Scott: Take a drink rest dance some more Hang out with people go home.
Scott: That's what that's like.
Rym: Now my favorite kind of live music is the small venue concert.
Scott: Rock and roll can't see any kind of music.
Scott: Well, depending on the kind of music could be different.
Scott: It was a small venue Say folk music.
Scott: you would sit at your table and you would tap your fingers on the table.
Scott: applause appropriately True.
Rym: Well, I'm just talking in general because I've been to yes jazz concerts.
Rym: I've been to j-rock concerts.
Scott: if it's a rock concert.
Scott: It is significantly different because there will be some mosh action Potentially depending on the rock and its heaviness.
Rym: now before we continue whether any metal is included We're gonna talk about these kind of concerts, but I'd like to say right now Always bring earplugs.
Rym: You might not need them.
Rym: But if you do and you don't have them it sucks.
Scott: Yeah, if you're going to a rock concert any amount of rock even May I say light rock or soft rock?
Scott: earplugs are a good idea.
Scott: now if you go to any kind of concert even ones you need earplugs.
Scott: if You just go without earplugs.
Scott: It might hurt at first but you can get used to it But that will damage your hearing severely and permanently.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I've gone to a few account actually, I went to a despair is right concert with Emily and we forgot to buy earplugs and It was still really awesome and my ears recovered because the concert wasn't that long.
Rym: But you don't want to do that more than a couple times in your life at most.
Scott: Seriously going to one Say, I don't know a CDC concert ever without earplugs unless you're in the way way way Back and it's a big place.
Scott: Your hearing is permanently damaged.
Scott: period.
Scott: The end earplugs are awesome.
Scott: You really want to get are They?
Scott: they make special earplugs.
Scott: They cost a lot of money, but they're worth it and that they decrease the volume of all frequencies equally.
Scott: So the music sounds perfect.
Scott: a lot of times you get the wrong kind of earplugs and they might muffle certain frequencies more than others.
Scott: So you'll lose perhaps some bass or some treble or mid range or who knows and it music will be all a.
Rym: I just said Earplugs like that for back when I played the trumpet and it probably saved me a significant amount of hearing damage.
Scott: Yep But they're not really good for a concert.
Rym: No, no, but they were real good for playing.
Scott: Yeah They're designed for that because that mostly the ones that say specific instrument earplugs are the ones you want to avoid.
Scott: They actually make ones that say concert earplugs, and I'm not 100% sure but I think drummers earplugs are also Decrease all frequencies equally.
Rym: when in doubt any earplugs will work and they work pretty much.
Scott: Yeah Even if you will hurt the music of the concert better to save your ears and Enjoy the concert for what you can hear then, you know to take the alternative.
Rym: Yep granted We all forgot earplugs to that Laraku concert.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But we were kind of far back.
Scott: So it was okay.
Rym: Yep Okay, but small venues are a lot of fun and whenever people hear concert they always think you know the stadium concert.
Scott: No stadium is very different.
Scott: arena and Rita and Stadium are the same thing on the outside and inside.
Rym: but yep But people always seem to picture that when you say concert and they always think oh I go to Ticketmaster I buy my big tickets.
Rym: small venues don't work that way.
Rym: a lot of small venue concerts are quite literally just walk in.
Rym: You got to be 21 at most of them just because that's how they make their money off of bars and selling you alcohol.
Rym: So if you don't drink These things are a gold mine of music.
Scott: because you just pay a low price because they expect you to drink you get in Enjoy awesome concerts and then you bust out and you didn't pay for any alcoholic beverages, but don't buy the water from the bar.
Scott: It's a ripoff.
Rym: Yeah, if you're gonna buy the water, you might as well buy the alcohol.
Rym: They cost the same.
Scott: I know And you barely get any water.
Scott: Hope there's a water fountain.
Rym: But the nice thing about a concert like that is usually in a small venue you'll be sitting or standing I don't know 10 15 feet from the artists.
Rym: They're right there.
Rym: They'll usually talk to the crowd after the concert.
Rym: It's usually really fun and usually catch like five or six bands in a row.
Scott: Yeah, small venue place will never have.
Scott: well pretty much no concert will ever have just one band.
Scott: There's always a bunch of opening bands and you know, maybe even a closing band.
Scott: Yeah, you know if it's like a Bar late at night after the main act goes away.
Scott: There'll be some other closing act.
Scott: Just kind of mellow things out, you know center been home.
Rym: So what small venue concerts have you been to Scott?
Scott: Let's see, we went to.
Scott: I went to the enter WK concert.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I missed that one.
Scott: Yeah, that was like the perfect concert in terms of execution, you know, the place had an upstairs and the downstairs There's a stage.
Scott: You know, there are people who didn't want to get all in the mess could stay back at.
Scott: you know About halfway through the place near where the bar was the crowd pretty much ended right where the bar began.
Scott: And starting at the bar up to the stage is a mass of people all making a nice mosh pit.
Scott: But it wasn't one of those.
Scott: see mosh pits here.
Scott: let's talk about mosh pits now.
Rym: All right real quick is what.
Rym: this is kind of a rambling episode.
Scott: people when people say mosh pit people a lot of people haven't Seen one or been in real one get a bad idea.
Rym: mosh pit does not mean beat the ever-living shit out of the people around.
Scott: You know, that's not true.
Scott: Mosh pit does not always mean There are levels of.
Rym: mosh pit is correct and know what you're getting into know what the crowd is and Don't one.
Rym: don't get into a mosh pit that's bigger than you can handle or worse than you can handle.
Rym: but two Don't escalate a mosh pit that doesn't want to be escalated.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: My the mosh my mosh pitting level is a bunch of guys bumping into each other and not stopping for a good ten minutes.
Rym: I Don't sound gay The evidence is really.
Scott: That's what a monster is a bunch of people, you know, you just bump into each other you push each other around.
Rym: Yeah, but the fact that you specifically said guys as opposed to people whatever.
Rym: When I say guys I mean that in a very general way My mosh my ideal mosh pit consists entirely of me and thousands upon thousands of beautiful women, okay, okay Me too, but I meant realistically yeah, but it's.
Rym: it's a. it's a way to experience the music.
Rym: wait It's kind of.
Rym: it's almost I don't want to say like tribal or to your roots, but it's very.
Scott: It puts you in a different state of mind, you know, and it's Even if I'm at a concert that has some nice comfortable mosh pits.
Scott: You don't do that the whole time, you know It's like all right.
Scott: Here's a good part.
Scott: Let's make a little mosh pit.
Scott: All right, and then a few minutes later You're like, all right.
Scott: Let's just jump up and down and wave our hands in the air, you know make little horns.
Scott: Jesus threw up the horns.
Scott: No way.
Scott: Yeah You know, but then you know.
Scott: and then a little ballad comes on, you know, you light up your lighter you open up your cell Phone.
Rym: Yeah, but the goal of mosh pits is not to hurt each other It's to have fun except for some mosh pits.
Scott: if you go to a scary death metal concert.
Scott: There will be people with nasty spikes.
Rym: Yeah, rings of spikes on them, but even then really big biker and trucker guys They're trying to hurt each other, but they also expect that to be true.
Rym: for people to try and hurt them.
Rym: Yeah, two-way street you
Scott: can tell looking at a mosh pit if it's a bunch of teenage to college age people maybe some 30 year old people and You know, they seem to make a little clearing with a bunch of people bouncing around in the clearing, you know then that's that you're pretty safe unless you're really small or really weak.
Scott: and If it's a bunch of people larger than you just don't go near there.
Scott: No one's gonna drag you into a mosh pit that you shouldn't be dragged into.
Scott: You know, if you're too close to one and you get caught in it, then that's you know, you shouldn't have gone there.
Rym: Now the first real like big mosh pit we ever experienced was when me and Scott and who else when I think was Greg Yeah, and Julie.
Rym: Yeah, and what was brother?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yep, and we went to a tool concert in Albany and this is an arena concert.
Scott: it took up the Pepsi arena.
Rym: arena concerts are big and Big big it take up the.
Scott: it was basically they play hockey and stuff here It's big.
Rym: now the thing about arena concerts is The real advantage of a small venue concert is that the sound quality is usually really good and really right there.
Rym: And in an arena concert, it's just so big loudness almost always Trump's good.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's more of a Experience the band with a hundred thousand people or ten thousand people as opposed to sit and listen to the music.
Scott: It's not really a better or worse experience.
Scott: It's a different experience.
Scott: Yeah Now one thing you have to know about arena concerts is that you can get general admission.
Scott: Usually if it's a rock type of thing You can get general admission or seating if you get.
Scott: if you don't want to be in any scary mosh pits or anything Just get a seat sit down listen to the music and no one will think worse of you.
Scott: In fact, no one will think anything of you because they won't see you Just be sitting there in the dark listening to your band that you like and if you want you can stand up in front of Your seat dance around a bit.
Rym: Yeah, if you're adventurous you can jump into general admission.
Scott: They when you get seats a lot of people get seats scope out the security and as soon as the concert starts for real They jump right into the GA and most of the people don't get caught and no one cares.
Scott: They expect that.
Scott: if they don't expect that there will be enough security to prevent you from doing so and you won't do it.
Rym: Yep, but this was our first like this was a Big concert and we were general admission.
Rym: We were right down there in the pit with all the tool fans.
Scott: Yeah, you're basically on the floor.
Scott: They cover a hockey running hockey rink Sized area with basically interlocking rubber mats.
Scott: I think it was some sort of rubber that way They don't they could just wipe it clean.
Scott: Yeah from all the human slime on it, you know, and then everyone, you know Does all kinds of head banging and smashing and mashing.
Rym: now a concert like that.
Rym: You're running a lot of interesting elements.
Rym: There are some gentlemen.
Rym: I use the term very liberally to the front of us smoking marijuana.
Scott: Yeah, that's gonna happen at a. now.
Rym: answer the.
Rym: that's not the story.
Rym: The story is they kept puffing on it and puffing on.
Rym: apparently They only had one little joint and they got down to this like tiny little bit.
Scott: It was smaller than a dime.
Scott: I don't mean a dime bag I mean a ten cent thing with Eisenhower like it was.
Scott: that it was.
Rym: it was like the size of the head of an eraser On a pencil like it was this little nub and one guy passes to another guy and he drops it and it falls on the Ground.
Scott: they had it on the.
Scott: it was.
Scott: imagine They're a pink eraser from the end of a pencil on the end of a paperclip and they were passing the paperclip around.
Rym: So then it falls on the ground and they go around looking for it Like they just crawled around looking for this thing amidst the horrible slime that is humankind.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Oh My god, I don't know what they thought they were gonna do.
Scott: eat the last little bit of it.
Scott: Yeah, it was on fire.
Scott: What they was like eating ash?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Well, that was all.
Rym: phantomas was on phantomas.
Rym: That was the worst band I've ever heard.
Rym: all right anyway.
Scott: Now here's one piece of Scott advice for any rock concert whatsoever.
Rym: Is this your frickin carabiner?
Scott: Well, it's related.
Scott: Okay only bring in things which you Hope to leave which you don't care if you don't leave with them.
Scott: So if you take something to the concert and You would be disappointed if it remained at the concert for all eternity and you couldn't take it out with you.
Scott: Don't bring it.
Scott: You should take this is this is what I recommend you take to a rock concert minimal wallet ready Sneakers that you don't care if they are completely stepped on and torn to shreds.
Scott: Socks because if you don't have socks, you're gonna have some mad smelly fungus action Jeans, I don't care what the weather is.
Scott: You need to protect those legs.
Scott: Yeah, right a White t-shirt or other plain t-shirt that you do not care if this last time you ever wear this t-shirt in your entire life.
Scott: You should pretend that taking the t-shirt into the concert.
Scott: It is going to be set on fire and then you are going to leave.
Scott: One form of identification with a photo perhaps your driver's license.
Scott: Enough money to get a cab home.
Scott: No The ticket to the concert.
Rym: now, what do you key to your car?
Rym: Yeah, you know, what do you not bring?
Scott: You do not bring a coat Because you will want to take it off and you can't cuz nor to put it and Wearing it sucks and it'll just get ruined and it smell like smoke.
Scott: It's bad.
Scott: Don't bring a coat.
Scott: Don't bring anything.
Scott: You don't want to be damaged.
Scott: Don't bring anything made of metal.
Scott: Don't bring anything that's expensive.
Rym: Don't bring your iPod.
Scott: to bring your iPod.
Scott: Don't bring a recorder or camera or anything like that unless you're a professional Concert bootlegger and you can get away with it.
Scott: Don't bring drugs unless you're a professional druggie and you can hide it and get away with it.
Rym: My anti-drug is Robitussin.
Scott: Yes, don't bring Robitussin.
Scott: Do attempt to sneak in things like water even though you probably won't be able to Do.
Rym: not bring a carabiner.
Scott: No Don't bring anything made of metal that Someone might think could potentially be a weapon because the bigger the concert the more likely they are to.
Scott: just they don't care Anything that they'll put the line real low, you know, if you have a metal Earring that they don't like they'll make you take it off and they'll probably just throw it away or turn you away.
Scott: That's your choice.
Scott: So don't bring anything questionable at all.
Scott: Yeah Plus not having that shit makes it a lot easier to enjoy the concert without Constantly fiddling with shit, you know, you see people in there with headphones and they're you know They're mosh and they're like, oh no my headphones mosh.
Scott: Oh, no my headphones.
Scott: Yeah, it's much better.
Scott: You know wearing jeans in a t-shirt you get everything stuck in your pocket where you know, it's it's good.
Scott: It's secure You're good to go.
Scott: You don't have to worry about shit.
Scott: You can just have fun at the concert Not constantly fiddling with crap.
Scott: It's much better.
Scott: Trust me.
Scott: I mean, I know P. at the Andrew WK concert I think one of the people who went with me Wore a leather coat and it had these straps on it and I think one of the little buckles on the straps was lost Gone forever.
Scott: Goodbye, you know, you don't bring that shit.
Scott: if you are more of the cultured geek Yeah, you might go on perchance to see an orchestra on perchance.
Rym: a.
Scott: on perchance For chance you might see an orchestra or visit one.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I've seen many.
Scott: I've seen three or four.
Rym: one You don't need earplugs.
Scott: You do not need earplugs to go see an orchestra.
Scott: In fact wearing your plugs would probably make it terrible.
Rym: now I'm not really gonna.
Rym: I mean, you know what orchestras sound like.
Rym: go see the kind of music you like.
Rym: and All I really want to say is that if you're going to see a symphony orchestra and you are not dressed nicely Once again, I will rise up from my horrible demon lair and destroy you.
Scott: It is the exact opposite of going to see the rock concert where you must wear jeans and a t-shirt Or the t-shirt of the band.
Rym: I guess I forgot that I feel old But I really it bothers me when I go to a nice concert and I see just Shlubby kids and jeans and t-shirts like just shuffling in and sitting down picking their nose.
Scott: Yep I don't mind if you wear just nice pants and a collared shirt.
Scott: You're good to go.
Scott: Yeah, even a short sleeve collared shirt is fine.
Rym: I'll often wear a sport jacket or something.
Scott: You know, it depends on how fancy the concert is and where it is.
Scott: If you're going to Carnegie Hall sitting in the front row probably want to wear a suit.
Scott: Yeah, if you're going to you know local state symphony orchestra in the convention center sitting in the mezzanine You can wear, you know slacks and a collared shirt.
Scott: Yeah, let's leave whatever maybe even a polo shirt.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: Now the same really applies to I don't opera ballet.
Scott: Yes, one thing though that you almost always consider when going to see an orchestra perform is the timing of your applause.
Scott: Nothing is worse than when you don't know and you applaud at the incorrect time.
Rym: now Here's the the.
Rym: the complex answer is watch the conductor and you'll know exactly when to applaud.
Rym: if you're not sure That my my rims own advice is a bunch of other people do wait until the rest of the clouds.
Scott: The crowd is applauding then applaud and the amazing example of this is of course ten planets.
Rym: Oh Gods I've seen the planets well heard the planets perform live twice on two different occasions in two different venues and at both events Some people just started clapping in between planets.
Rym: now that you do not do that The rules are.
Rym: I'm not gonna get technical but I could be very like horribly technical about this.
Rym: You do not clap between movements of the same piece.
Rym: Mm-hmm You do not clap between parts of the same.
Rym: Ah, well it Nevermind.
Rym: you don't clap between until the conductor puts his baton down or turns around and looks at you.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: You don't really care about the different names for the different types of cons of parts of concert.
Scott: No.
Scott: No, we don't.
Scott: Yeah Even know or care.
Rym: if anyone wants to know I'll explain it in the forums.
Scott: But that is one thing you have to be very sure of.
Scott: when you go to see some sort of classical music being performed Is you clap at the appropriate times and at all other times you shut up.
Scott: It's not like going to see a movie where you know a little whispering at a funny part in the movie is okay.
Scott: There's something like that, you know making noise when people are there to experience some sound is Disturbing the sound greatly.
Rym: So now it varies right?
Scott: I don't even care if people next to me in movies talk.
Scott: You know normally as long as they don't do it constantly, but it got a. you know music like that.
Scott: Oh Just hit you.
Rym: Well, it's different for different types of this kind of music orchestral music you clap when the conductor turns around bows there'll be some sort of signal and a Musical like Broadway.
Rym: It is perfectly okay to clap After a virtuoso song or after a song within an act even before the current.
Scott: between acts, of course Yeah, the intermission.
Scott: but even during an act I mean an actress or an actor finishes or as soon as often, you know To Broadway play and they're like and now the play is starting.
Scott: Yeah before even anything happens.
Rym: But Broadway is really the only place where you people will clap or applaud during an act after someone finished something.
Rym: Yeah, well also actually jazz concerts.
Rym: It is acceptable and in fact encouraged to clap and applaud after a soloist finishes in the middle of a song.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: That is very much expected.
Rym: Don't feel shy about that.
Rym: Of course when in doubt don't do it because he might not be done soloing.
Scott: It might be some sort of bebop new wave jazz Where if it's kind of music you're into and you're comfortable with you know what to do.
Scott: yeah, if you're going to a new experience go with the crowd or Be an idiot.
Scott: now problem is normally I would say who cares if people think you're being stupid and normally I wouldn't care.
Scott: The thing is there can be dire consequences Though it's changed a lot over time.
Rym: Hundreds of years ago in you know France, especially in France.
Rym: This seems to be the hotbed of this though.
Rym: Italy was pretty bad too.
Rym: when people went to the Opera.
Rym: They it was actually a social occasion and the Opera be going out on the stage But they'd mostly ignore it and sit and talk and have all their intrigue and cry.
Scott: when you watch movies that show Old-timey people going to operas like you know movies about Mozart and shit It wasn't like that.
Scott: people didn't sit there with their little glasses Perfectly quiet and silent and noble watching the Opera.
Rym: It wasn't really until the days of Beethoven that that shifted.
Rym: Yep, I mean the Opera was a social occasion.
Rym: you went you sat down as soon as everything started You'd wander off and do whatever crap intrigue you were doing or talk to people or you're playing on your side.
Scott: Yeah, all the noble shit.
Rym: I mean it wasn't like it is in the count of Monte Cristo But it's not that far from the truth at all.
Scott: nope All right.
Scott: any other varieties of concert.
Rym: uh jazz concerts are not really Particularly special though I am a big fan of the jazz lounge concert But basically you go and eat dinner and there's music playing while you're eating dinner.
Rym: Yep, like a piano piano jazz or and just lounges as opposed to clubs or venues You're expected to socialize whatever during a lounge concert.
Scott: Yep And remember you can always.
Scott: it's it depending on the lounge.
Scott: You can go up to the guy playing the piano or whatnot and put some money in his little tippy jar And get him to do what you want depending on what's going on.
Scott: Yeah, it isn't dueling pianos going on or something like that.
Scott: you obviously don't go up and say hey play this one.
Scott: But if you're in a Casablanca type of situation Sam what's up?
Scott: And of course if you're that guy who yells play free bird You're awesome, but the second guy who does it isn't Because the first guy who yells it is the guy who thought of it first.
Scott: Everyone has to do it at least once at a concert.
Rym: I just remember at RIT after a hockey game We stopped by the some concert that was going on at the Ritz, which was this bar on RIT's campus.
Rym: We all stopped by it and some guy was playing some music.
Rym: I think it was a cover band mostly and Some drunk frat guy yells play free bird.
Rym: The guy stops playing walks over drags him up on stage and says, all right, I'll play it you sing it.
Rym: Didn't even know the words didn't even know how free bird went.
Rym: Nope He just heard the word free bird and thought it'd be cool thing to yell.
Rym: awesome All right We should probably wrap this up a bit since we ended up talking more about how to not suck at going to concerts as opposed To concerts we like.
Rym: yeah What's your favorite couple of concerts ever of all the concerts you've been to?
Scott: all the ones I've been to?
Rym: yeah Not the you know concerts you haven't been to but you assume we're awesome.
Rym: I'm talking about concerts.
Scott: You've been to Because they didn't go to too many super awesome ones.
Rym: I mean, I would really say the laraku concert at Otakon was particularly awesome.
Scott: Yeah, that one was pretty awesome.
Scott: The Andrew WK concert was worth the money.
Scott: Very awesome.
Rym: Yep, actually on Emily's birthday a while ago.
Rym: We went to the Blue Note to see Oh God What was his name famous jazz pianist and it was freaking amazing?
Rym: We were sitting close enough.
Rym: I could have reached up and just pounded on the keyboard and run away.
Rym: You should have Hit a lot of money to get into that place.
Rym: Not so much.
Rym: See the places like that.
Scott: You paid a lot of money.
Scott: You deserve to be able to bang on that piano Yeah, but places like that some of the key.
Rym: It's funny the tickets to get into the concert weren't that much but the meals there were real expensive.
Rym: Of course, the food was really good.
Scott: But yeah that and that laraku concert there was a I Concert like if you go to see like Bruce Springsteen or Any of those new musicians old people listen to like the stuff your parents listen to.
Scott: those kind of concerts generally are all seating and pretty much as people stand up and kind of wiggle around and You know cheer and you know, that's about it.
Scott: You know, yeah, you know That's only how pop music concerts are.
Scott: if there's no Standing room if it's just seating out pop music you always have the.
Scott: That's the only difference in concerts like that are stand around Possibly wiggle.
Scott: There's no real dancing.
Scott: There's no moshing just standing up potentially wiggling hand waving Clapping in tune with the music, you know that usual sort of thing.
Scott: It's just sort of a natural Everyone goes with the flow not too much energy sort of deal.
Scott: Yeah, so it doesn't require that much explanation.
Scott: But in case you haven't been to a concert like that That's what you should expect.
Rym: Any other types, I don't know.
Rym: I think we're winding down here.
Scott: Oh, oh I got one more type.
Scott: All right, if you go to some badass funk concert with some And some flavor going on then you totally gotta get with the groove and do some funky dancing.
Scott: That's how that works.
Scott: Just pretend you're on American Bandstand or something and let loose.
Rym: I don't think many of our listeners know what American Bandstand is Awesome, because I barely know what it is.
Rym: You know, what's great?
Rym: every time I start to feel old I realize that every time I say I feel old after something it makes the people older than me feel really old Yeah, which makes me feel very young.
Rym: Hooray.
Scott: Haha I would tell you what to do at a hip-hop in concert But I have never been to a serious hardcore hip-hop and the closest thing I got to was a nerdcore concert at Katsucon.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can see on TV what goes on there, but I don't know how much to trust that.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I know I know what to do at a nerdcore concert.
Rym: Yeah, you jump around and scream like an idiot and you hold your DS in the air.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: That's what you do.
Rym: Remember when we all pulled out our DS's at that entertainment system concert Awesome and the guy sing it like the guy in the guitar was you playing real?
Rym: furiously looks up and he sees us all Waving around holding our DS's and he stares at us and gives us the look of you guys are awesome.
Rym: Yep, that story doesn't go anywhere.
Rym: the concert wasn't very heavily populated So, but it formed a mosh pit.
Scott: that lasted about shows you how good their music was.
Scott: Is that you know?
Scott: and is that they could get a lot of energy out of the people?
Scott: when?
Scott: There wasn't a lot of energy Transfer between people going on.
Rym: that mosh pit lasted about the length of time it took for an Otakon staffer to run over and yell Oh my god, stop doing that.
Scott: and I went.
Scott: oh And everyone just kind of stood there sullen for a minute and then we got back to going Before we even knew about the.
Rym: we All right, that was kind of a random episode, yep, so Don't fear going to concerts now.
Scott: use our advice.
Rym: Yeah I know you're all.
Rym: keep various shades of geek and nerd and dork out there.
Rym: go to concerts.
Rym: It's not hard.
Rym: Just go to Ticketmaster or whatever and do it if you're not 21.
Rym: It's a lot harder and that sucks.
Rym: and my only advice is get older.
Scott: Yeah even if you're not sure even if there's no music you like coming to your area or you don't like a wide variety of music a crappy live band is Always better than a recorded good band.
Scott: Yeah, there's just.
Scott: that's how a lot of you know, these little indie guys stay in business.
Scott: you know you download some indie musics indie bands mp3s and you listen to them and you go.
Scott: and But I guarantee if you had never heard their songs before and you saw them at some random club you would go.
Scott: Cuz music sounds ten times better.
Scott: live no matter what the hell it is.
Scott: It's just something about live music.
Rym: Yep, except of course for some forms of electronica where one there is no live version and two if there were it'd be identical or objectively bad music.
Rym: Exactly So we actually got into an argument with some people over phantomas.
Scott: Apparently so everyone knows Fantomas was a band that when we got to that tool concert We already mentioned phantomas was one of the opening acts already playing when we got there.
Scott: now Apparently phantomas consists of some highly talented musicians.
Rym: However the music that phantomas makes how dare you defile the word music with what that was?
Scott: I say my personal definitions that music is almost anything right now.
Scott: I'm making music but it was not song.
Scott: Those were not songs.
Scott: They were just noises that somehow and notes and
Rym: now when we walked in
Scott: things
Rym: They were between songs because we got to the concert a little bit late because we I was trying to finish my Rasta fries
Scott: yep,
Rym: and The crowd is chanting get the fuck off the stage.
Scott: get the fuck off the stage or something similar like phantomas sucks.
Scott: Yeah Like there was a couple scary fat guys with phantomas shirts that were kind of faded and worn.
Scott: But after phantomas was done those guys left.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I don't know why they didn't take their opportunity for a free tool concert But whatever the crowd was incredibly hostile to phantomas.
Scott: after they played a few sets We stood there and we're like, oh give him a break, you know, they can't be that bad.
Scott: after five minutes We said get the fuck off the stage.
Rym: So then we go to the shore.
Rym: it was either that summer.
Rym: the next I think was the next summer and We need a bunch of Scott Johnson's friends and they're really into this kind of music and out of the blue.
Rym: We're just talking about music and we make an off-the-cuff like it couldn't be as bad as phantomas.
Rym: And we figured no one ever heard of this band or anything.
Rym: and they're like what phantomas is awesome.
Scott: We're like, oh ha ha ha ha.
Rym: and that spiraling are quite the argument Apparently, you know.
Scott: and he didn't like Andrew WK either.
Scott: and I was like, okay He was like.
Rym: Andrew WK is senseless crap.
Scott: his lyrics Argument that I used to defeat phantomas.
Scott: that And it was like.
Scott: vice versa, you know He was saying phantomas is great musical talent and I was saying but their songs suck.
Scott: then he was saying Andrew WK is lyric Suck.
Scott: all he says is party party party.
Scott: I'm like, yeah, but his songs are enjoyable and he has great musical talent also According to you.
Scott: It doesn't matter if the songs suck because phantomas is song suck.
Scott: Download a phantomas mp3.
Scott: You know, I'm like.
Scott: Andrew WK is great musical talent.
Scott: Therefore if you like phantomas because if they have great musical talent, you must like Andrew WK No, he didn't like that.
Scott: Every word was party party party.
Scott: Yeah Of course, if you know Andrew WK is music.
Scott: every other word is party, but that's cool Party party.
Rym: All right, so I think we've rambled enough.
Rym: We killed a nice Thursday.
Rym: We got some meta bits.
Rym: Just keep in mind that this is the end of the logo contest.
Rym: if you want to make a logo Send it to us.
Rym: We will be deciding most likely this weekend.
Scott: Yep On this Saturday meaning two days from now We are going to the mocha.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, we might go.
Rym: Sunday depends on weather and everything.
Scott: It does depend on whether but this weekend most likely on Saturday.
Scott: I'd say 70/30 chance abouts.
Rym: Yeah, cuz the weather's looking up better and better.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: We'll be in New York City.
Scott: It'll be in New York City.
Scott: I think it's the York, but I'm not sure.
Scott: Maybe we should just put the link in the show notes.
Rym: Uh Yeah, I'll put it in the comments or in the forum or something.
Scott: Yeah The Museum of comic and cartoon art is having an exhibition.
Scott: basically It's gonna be a bunch of indie comic people in a artists alley type of situation with some panels and I think some awards.
Scott: But we'll mostly just be doing the artists alley type stuff.
Rym: Yep It'll just be us and our good friend Yuko as well as many other people.
Rym: I know no, it'll just be us three.
Rym: No one else is going to this.
Scott: I know there's gonna be a at least two or three cool comics I know of and two or at least three other awesome podcasts that relate to comic specifically, but yep I'll have my terrible little Sony recording bit.
Rym: I may interview some people.
Scott: Yep, so you can check us out there the weekend after this weekend.
Scott: Anime next at the Meadowlands in New Jersey.
Scott: We'll probably only go one day probably Saturday and Everything else we'll tell you about later.
Rym: Yeah, like ConnectiCon is up in the air I'm gonna see if I can get us a panel or something.
Scott: Yep but yeah, so anime next and Mocha in opposite order and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.