Rym: It's Wednesday April 12th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about Shinigami no ballad, and we have some final thoughts on mushishi.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: You might notice that I'm not here and Rym's doing the news on his own.
Rym: yes indeed in fact We recorded this many days ago now.
Scott: the reason for this is because it's Passover Which means I don't go to work and I go do stuff with my family.
Rym: now I'll say that Scott wanted to do this disclaimer mostly for the same reason that I don't have a Darwin fish on my car even Though I used to.
Rym: now.
Rym: the reason I don't have a Darwin fish on my car is because from a distance It looks a lot like a Jesus fish.
Rym: Didn't want to confuse anyone.
Scott: I don't want anyone to be confused and think that because I'm not here on Passover that I somehow believe in an omnipotent deity despite my atheism.
Scott: you see I'm not religiously Jewish.
Scott: I'm sort of ethnically culturally Jewish sort of freaking Jewish.
Scott: well Think about this.
Scott: right an Irish guy.
Scott: right Irish isn't really a religion.
Scott: It's sort of like a nationality culture.
Scott: You know you drink in pubs, and you have leprechauns.
Rym: That's not the best example Scott.
Scott: No you got a better example.
Rym: Just do your bit.
Rym: Oh my god if anyone out there is Irish.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: Scott for the longest time actually didn't know the difference between Ireland and Scotland.
Rym: He'd asked me like so which one has the leprechauns?
Rym: yeah, which one has golf right?
Scott: Scotland's a good one Scotland.
Scott: Yeah, you got kilts, and you got Loch Ness monsters, and you got all those things right, but they don't involve any particular like you know Fantastical beliefs.
Scott: you can be both Scottish and atheist at the same time.
Rym: What about magic runes?
Scott: Magic runes you can ignore.
Scott: so I'm sort of like that like I'm Jewish because it's cool and fun in a cultural sort of Ethnic way, but I don't believe any of the crazy like.
Scott: oh, no if I'm not kosher.
Scott: It's terrible.
Rym: Oh, you don't cast spells from the Kabbalah.
Scott: No no that that's not even Jewish.
Scott: That's like crazy Jewish.
Scott: Yeah, it's like Wow, I'm not even gonna get into that.
Scott: That's all I need to do.
Scott: a show on that Yeah, a Jew show or even just a Kabbalah show cuz it's really becoming popular among idiots All right, yeah, so no one be confused and start screaming about how Scott's really Jewish or something cuz.
Scott: yeah
Rym: Well, it's like how I often end up celebrating like Christmas or Easter or Thanksgiving though Thanksgiving doesn't really apply, but I celebrate a lot of holidays just with my family or Emily's family or Just various people, but I only like I celebrate being with family and having fun, and I'm really not Caring so much that someone may or may not have died 2,000 years ago.
Scott: Well you know what the godfather says a man who doesn't spend time with his family can never be a real man.
Scott: Yeah That's what that's about.
Scott: so I see you next week.
Rym: now that Scott's actually gone I can talk about the forum goings-on.
Rym: You see for those of you who haven't been following the forums too closely Flaming geek who we somewhat called out yesterday Decided not to accept our offer of amnesty.
Rym: He was lying about various things and we offered him to come clean.
Rym: he decided not to and I realized that we hadn't actually planned for the possibility of actually banning people from the forum Or how we would deal with that since we currently only actually have three moderators two of which are myself and Scott And then mr.. Period who would probably not actually ban anyone without talking to us.
Rym: so Scott is out of town And I decided that the best way to do this is to set up some sort of overly complicated and extremely fun to implement court-martial system.
Rym: Now I'll talk to Scott to see what he thinks of it But I'm very pleased with it.
Rym: basically if someone on the forum is For whatever reason doing something that is worthy of being banned I will put them in the group that marks them for a forum based court-martial.
Rym: All of their posts will be flagged and they will not be able to alter their profile or post anywhere At least for 24 hours while we have a thread that will be sticky describing the goings-on Why we feel he should be banned and asking for any comments from the forum at large After 24 hours.
Rym: if it is found that the person should indeed be banned We will ban them.
Rym: if anyone feels that there should be they should be given some sort of second chance.
Rym: I can put them in a probationary mode where they'll be able to speak in their own defense But only we'll be able to post in certain specific threads Our categories, and then we could see where it goes from there.
Rym: now as for the flamming geek No offense I hate to lose a listener.
Rym: I'd love you to keep listening, but I really can't have you in our forums anymore.
Rym: The votes are thus far unanimous and unless something drastic happens overnight I'm going to ban you.
Rym: come tomorrow.
Rym: now again since Scott's not here I'm only going to do one news and one thing of the day obviously since he didn't record any ahead of time And then I'll go into an anime episode that we actually recorded some time ago in preparation for events Just like this.
Rym: so without further ado in the news I'm sure you're all aware of the lawsuit and scandals surrounding the fact that AT&T has allegedly been allowing the NSA to basically look over all of their records and databases for many years and In fact have been helping the NSA to spy on Americans.
Rym: Now these allegations are fairly serious And there are numerous lawsuits around this.
Rym: now the interesting news is not that this is going on because this was actually announced quite some Time ago.
Rym: the interesting part is that AT&T the defendant here has decided that they are going to try to Remove from the evidence all of the incriminating documents that they originally submitted.
Rym: Now these are documents that for various reasons.
Rym: I'm not really going to go into the details about it But they described the spying program how it was undertaken These specific means that were used and all sorts of juicy tidbits.
Rym: AT&T feels for various reasons that these documents should be stricken from the record and Not used in the lawsuit against them.
Rym: now AT&T's rationale here is somewhat interesting.
Rym: they are saying that the widespread criticism and press coverage about the case has been causing quote grave injury to AT&T and they furthermore claim that it is Releasing their trade secrets to the wild and making them vulnerable to attacks by hackers.
Rym: personally I find these claims laughable.
Rym: AT&T got caught doing something They shouldn't be doing and they're doing everything within their power to get out of it.
Rym: now on a more broad level This isn't the only spying scandal going on.
Rym: I mean aside from AT&T spying on all of us.
Rym: I know you all know that President Bush had a while ago authorized the spying on American citizens who were calling foreign countries and He also recently admitted and even was proud of the fact that they're also Authorizing the spying of entirely domestic conversations despite the fact that he has at no point ever gone to a FISA court to get warrants for this Despite the fact that even as previous presidents have indicated is quite trivial to do.
Rym: Now, I don't know about you, but I really don't like the idea of my government spying on me Particularly when my government has been rather shall we say rash Even evil or wellian lately.
Rym: It's kind of a slippery slope scary trend.
Rym: I hate to use the term slippery slope and I hate to use that sort of argument But this is a very slippery slope.
Rym: I mean every it just.
Rym: it's getting worse every day.
Rym: and the scary thing is it's not that the spying is getting worse every Day, it's that we're finding out more about it every day.
Rym: now I know we actually have a lot of listeners who aren't inside of the United States and all I really have to say to you Is that despite what other problems the countries you live in may have?
Rym: I would consider you fairly lucky in many ways that you don't have to deal with the things that we're dealing with as a nation right now and If things continue on the trend they're continuing I mean actually continuing exactly the way they are and getting worse at the same rate Then I really can't see myself continuing to live in this country within the next I don't know decade or so maybe even sooner.
Rym: But that's all talk for another time since this is GeekNights anime day and not GeekNights politics day.
Rym: So without further ado, so my thing of the day Now I didn't actually find this today.
Rym: I found it while Scott found it yesterday and we were both reading it and we almost used it as a thing of the day.
Rym: It just got lost out to other things.
Rym: But I thought this was very interesting and I'm glad that they have.
Rym: I have the opportunity to share it with all of you today.
Rym: Now if you know David Copperfield the magician He has a fairly famous flying trick that many people really have no idea how he did it.
Rym: He flies around a stage in front of a live audience.
Rym: He flies through hoops.
Rym: He flies into this glass container and then they put a lid on it, but he can still fly and This website very succinctly and very clearly shows you exactly how this trick is done in a very clear and easy to understand way.
Rym: Basically all he was doing is he has two incredibly incredibly thin special Wires and a little harness around his waist and the wires are almost invisible.
Rym: They're tiny tiny tiny little wires and that's it.
Rym: when he goes into the little box the wires are so thin that they slide to the side and They're still.
Rym: they just go to the side around the cover.
Rym: they put on the box and then they still go up to the winch.
Rym: He doesn't actually fly through the hoops.
Rym: He does some sort of trick that you could.
Rym: they explain it with a little animation on this site.
Rym: Now the site itself went down fairly quickly.
Rym: I Wonder if anything was done.
Rym: I mean I know magicians are traditionally very secretive about the way they do their magic and I wonder if this was any sort of retaliation for someone revealing it.
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: all I know is that I'm linking to the Google cache that has the vast majority of the content for you all of you to See complete with the pictures.
Rym: So it being Wednesday and anime day.
Rym: We have two shows.
Rym: yet again We are going to review and have our final thoughts on mushishi and Actually, there are going to be no spoilers in that part because mushishi doesn't have spoilers.
Scott: yeah, really like if we told you how any particular episode ended.
Scott: that might be a spoiler for that episode, but There is no overarching plot of mushishi.
Scott: It's purely episodic that and we're going to talk about preview Shinigami Which we saw one episode of and we're probably not gonna watch anymore.
Rym: it started out.
Rym: Yeah, and it went.
Scott: It's see.
Scott: basically the story of the show is there's this.
Scott: Well, if you don't know a shinigami is like a grim reaper a god of death god of death and they go around Collecting souls of dead people or writing in death notes, right?
Scott: But that's in other comics and such and there's an anime even it's not even a comic.
Scott: So it's a story of this girl who's a shinigami and Her little shinigami cat which is cute and has little devil wings and he's really an asshole.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like a kamako.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: I forgot all about a kamako And It seemed.
Scott: we don't know if it's episodic or serial, but it seems like each episode She goes and kills someone and you basically you don't see a lot of this girl who's the shinigami so much.
Scott: you see more of like the characters that are involved with the death and It's like, you know, you get to know a few characters over the course of the episode and you know what their story is and you know you get along with them and then someone dies and then The shinigami appears and the episodes over
Rym: now, it seemed like a neat idea to me at first, you know we have a very heartwarming show where you can explore death and the way people react to it and the Reactions of the shinigami who actually has to do it and you know something nice.
Rym: It's really just kind of contrived and boring.
Scott: honestly, yeah, it seemed really silly and Plain very plain Like there's a guy There's a girl the guys with the girl.
Rym: the girl has a sickness.
Scott: The girl and the guy are working together to take care of the stray cat.
Rym: the girl dies.
Scott: The guy was well refers.
Scott: the other important plot is the guy wants to hang out and play soccer with his friends But oh he feels bad for the girl cuz she's gonna die.
Rym: And then sure enough she dies and he decides he wants to kill the cat because it's the cat's fault that she died Kinda kinda sorta.
Rym: and then the shinigami appears.
Rym: We're ruining the whole first episode.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: The show's not good Yeah, and basically says oh if you leave the cat out in the rain, it'll die.
Rym: Do you want that?
Rym: And he's like, yeah, whatever.
Rym: and then she tries to kill the cat because she's a shinigami and he saves it and It just really doesn't go anywhere.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: That's the end of the episode pretty much You know, then it's like oh, it's sad the girl died, but it's okay.
Scott: She would have.
Scott: you know, it's the way of the world Be happy and that's it.
Rym: The show just feels a lot less inspired than a show that has so much potential it should be.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if they made the show maybe like about the shinigami like observing people or something
Rym: or if they just did what they're Doing where it's just 26 or however many one-shot treatments of death and how people react to it Yeah, but no no, I mean it is that but it just wasn't good.
Rym: I didn't there was.
Rym: no I didn't really empathize with the characters.
Rym: I didn't really feel anything.
Rym: I didn't really care.
Rym: I Definitely spent more time yelling.
Rym: I'll bet the girl dies.
Rym: No, I'll bet the guy dies.
Rym: No, they're the cats gonna fucking die.
Rym: then we did, you know actually caring.
Scott: Yeah, I think The problem is is that the real characters don't get enough time at all.
Scott: I mean the awesome devil cat was on the screen for maybe a minute and
Rym: Actually the devil cat and the shinigami they come in right away and They don't say anything and they're on the screen for maybe 30 seconds And then you don't really see him again until the last few minutes of the episode.
Rym: They don't when they kill they don't actually really do anything which would be fine again.
Rym: It's just I guess.
Rym: here's what the main thing that bothered me about the show.
Rym: A lot of shows are very atmospheric and I usually like that.
Rym: You know the camera will pan around a lot and they spend time looking at the environment.
Rym: characters are in and it's not just face shot Face shot face shot action shot like American shows tend to be but I mean a place promise did that really well.
Rym: now this show Seems to be trying to do that, but it's not good.
Rym: It's hard to explain.
Rym: but like the camera kept panning to things that just it looked like they were lazy And they didn't want to animate the whole show So they kept panning the camera to static useless shots of like half of a tin of cat food.
Scott: Yeah, it's not exactly the highest production value show.
Rym: I mean the animation is basically standard for modern-day animation and honestly, I don't think the voice acting is that good.
Scott: I Wasn't really paying attention, but it sounded just like people talking.
Scott: It wasn't like Sounded.
Rym: it sounded like people talking.
Scott: Hey, yeah Well, you know actually the voice actor for the devil cat was good and you know what.
Scott: the only thing the show has going for It is a double kit.
Scott: Yeah, say that right now.
Scott: Yeah, they should just make a show about that cat Whatever his name is.
Rym: Well, actually the Shinigami is very cool-looking.
Rym: I like the way she was drawn.
Scott: Yeah, she's kind of glowy with the red shoes and I don't know about the red shoes.
Scott: and then with the big sigh it's it's sort of.
Scott: it looks like a. You know either a you know Taku kind of look like the kind of things.
Scott: Oh, Taku like like they'll probably go like little models of her.
Rym: and and Yeah, she's definitely designed in the same vein that like Chi from Chobits was designed.
Scott: Yeah, it appeals to a certain demographic not us No, but the devil cat right up our alley.
Rym: Well, the devil cats an asshole.
Scott: That's the idea.
Rym: So really we're not gonna say any more about the show.
Rym: it's probably not worth watching.
Scott: Actually, we can contrast the show with mushishi.
Scott: You see mushishi, which is what we're gonna talk about now Which we're gonna semi spoil because there really isn't an overarching plot to spoil.
Scott: But we might say what happens at the end of a few of the episodes.
Rym: so now mushishi just y'all know We've talked about it before we reviewed it when we'd seen I don't know five or six episodes And if you search through the archives, you'll find that We've seen the whole show now.
Scott: It's a 20 episode show now unlike Shinigami.
Scott: no valid.
Scott: We're like the strongest characters being the Shinigami and the devil cat barely appear.
Scott: You know the strongest character in mushishi is ginkgo who's the main dude and he always appears.
Scott: he's all around Even though it's also episodic and the story is never except for one episode.
Scott: The story is never about ginkgo.
Scott: It's always about some other people and he's just they're helping or figuring it out, but he's always there enough and he's awesome.
Scott: So it kind of works out whereas in Shinigami no valid it's.
Scott: you know, it's also not about the Shinigami But the Shinigami is not there.
Rym: Yeah Now, I mean we talked about it before so I'm not gonna explain the whole concept of the show in detail again.
Rym: But basically mushishi is about.
Rym: well It's a world that it's kind of hard to place.
Rym: what era the show the story is set in Like.
Rym: it could be medieval or like late medieval Japan.
Rym: It could be modern Japan.
Rym: It's really hard to tell.
Scott: I Don't think it's modern Japan because everyone seems to be living in villages in the mountains somewhere through villages in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: so it's like pre.
Scott: you know modern Japan when people still had some sort of traditional stuff and you know everyone.
Scott: you wore kimonos all the time and of course, it is definitely a Non-standard historical timeline because there are mushi about yeah, and there are not samurais or ninjas about Which tells you something.
Rym: but basically in this world There are these mushi which are like a cross between a ghost and a spirit and a bacteria.
Scott: Yeah, I think they describe them as like creatures that are somewhat in-between plant and animal and nothing and they go around in the world just like bacteria and everything would and they're most.
Rym: people can't see him and don't interact with them.
Rym: and Whenever mushi or mushi and humans come together Strange things tend to happen.
Scott: I mean some mushi cause good things some bad things some have no effect Some just cause a weird effect that doesn't actually do anything like oh my god The mountain looks like it has a hole in it, but nothing happens.
Rym: now some people called mushishi are mushi catchers or mushi doctors and for whatever reason they can see the mushi and As a result mushi are attracted to them so they really can't stay in one place for long or mushi.
Scott: I don't know if mushi are attracted to all the mushishi or if that was just ginkgo's thing because of what happened to him In the episode that told us about him.
Rym: Yeah, it's hard to say but they've.
Rym: they've mentioned that a couple times about other mushishi - did they?
Rym: yeah I'm pretty sure I don't remember that but anyway all the way it's obvious that all the mushishi tend to travel around and Just help people with mushi.
Rym: they study mushi they kill mushi they capture mushi.
Scott: Yeah, it's like imagine if it it's sort of like Pokemon where there's these creatures about that.
Scott: You know are a new class of creature, and they do stuff, but people aren't collecting them to fight against each other They're.
Scott: they treat them more like you know diseases.
Scott: I guess kinda.
Scott: It's like They.
Scott: they do things and people go around correcting them.
Scott: You know they're not.
Scott: some of you know some of them are good and some of them are bad.
Scott: But you won't see like two mushishi meet up and all of a sudden whip out their mushishi and see which ones are higher level.
Scott: It's not about that.
Scott: It's it's Sort of like these spiritual stories of things in fact.
Rym: We never really run into any other mushishi until the last episode.
Scott: Yeah, well there are some mushishi about but you don't really care about them now.
Rym: like we said we've seen the whole show now and For starters the show is very episodic.
Rym: every episode is basically entirely on its own with the tiniest vague bit of continuity in that ginkgo the main character has been around and he's been to all these places already mm-hmm and That is done very well.
Scott: Yeah, you know it seems like everything.
Scott: I most of the media that I engage nowadays is Siri is if not completely serial at least somewhat serial in that you know it's Last time on such-and-such next time on such-and-such, and it just continues.
Scott: comics just continue.
Scott: You know it's like you got to wait for the next issue with the next something you know to continue the story And you forget that.
Scott: hey episodic stuff You know is also good.
Scott: you get.
Scott: you know shows like The Simpsons are episodic.
Scott: every episode is different and When in most anime are not episodic so when one is it's like kind of weird, but it can still be good.
Rym: Now if any of you are wondering like we said no there is no overarching plot at all And it's one of those shows that doesn't end it simply stops.
Rym: There's no resolution nothing special happens in the last episode.
Rym: It's just the show's over.
Scott: Yeah at the end of episode 20 They're like that's it.
Scott: We're not making any more, and they give you.
Scott: they put a picture on the screen.
Scott: That's like the end.
Rym: Thank you for watching Bye-bye, and I guess the fact that I wasn't at all disappointed with that really really makes me respect the show and enjoy it.
Scott: Yeah, it is definitely a excellent show, but you know as with any episodic show You can always want for more episodes.
Rym: I would love to see the show go on forever Yeah, as long as the quality didn't diminish.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the cool thing about the show is that it's definitely not for the most part as far as I can tell based on any actual legends.
Scott: It's but all the it is based on legends.
Scott: It's based on obscure ones We don't know,
Rym: but all the stories have this very like Japanese fairytale folktale feeling to them
Scott: like if you told someone it was a legend they would believe you easily and
Rym: It really had this neat idea of like a lot of times People even in the show would talk about the legend of such-and-such and Ginkgo the mushishi.
Rym: would you know hear about this and realize that it's not anything magical.
Rym: It's just a mushi.
Rym: I know exactly what mushi that is.
Rym: I'm gonna go kill it or stop it or whatever.
Rym: mm-hmm.
Scott: Of course he usually solves the problems not by killing mushi, but by you know doing something to him.
Rym: or yeah You get the impression that most mushishi tend to go around just killing mushi or capturing them for fun.
Scott: Yeah, but ginkgo the main guy he kind of goes around like fixing him like a doctor.
Rym: Yeah, well he very much seems to have the philosophy that they live in their world We live in ours, and we all just have to live together.
Rym: Yeah, now if you wonder about ginkgo's past because the show is very episodic We will say that there is one episode that basically it's ginkgo's origin story.
Rym: It basically gives you everything you actually need to know about ginkgo.
Scott: Yeah, it tells you why he's got one eyeball And why he doesn't remember.
Scott: like before He was mushishi, and why are mushi following him around everywhere?
Scott: He can't stay in one place for too long, and it explains all of that stuff, but other than that It's just like every other episode.
Scott: You know there's a mushi problem, and he runs into it.
Rym: Yep, and not one nice thing is that it's not a very predictable show.
Rym: I mean some episodes.
Rym: He saves whoever was caught by mushi some episodes.
Rym: They die.
Rym: some episodes.
Rym: something horrible ends up happening.
Rym: It's really random and you really can't predict how an episode will go based on any sort of meta.
Rym: Oh, they always save the girl in the end logic.
Scott: Yeah, there is one thing though.
Scott: it seemed like There were certain components that each story was made out of and they seem to be running out of new components with which to make stories.
Scott: like.
Scott: You know it started to follow sort of a formula towards the end of shows up in town.
Scott: Someone's sick with something He can't figure out what it is He tries to figure it out.
Scott: He does something he leaves he comes back.
Scott: the situation is different than it was when he left Then he does something else and then it's over.
Rym: yeah, though at that point in the show it seemed like they started introducing more elements Like we're not gonna spoil this one, but mushi mail.
Rym: no Even though actually I thought that episode was really cool.
Scott: It was an okay episode.
Scott: Yeah with the blanket and whatnot.
Rym: yeah the best part in the show is when the mud monster appears.
Scott: Yeah, it's like certain parts of the show like stuff.
Scott: That's sort of the show moves kind of like not story wise But physically slowly like there aren't.
Scott: there isn't a lot of quick action or cutting or things zooming around quick.
Scott: It's like everything's kind of calm and moving around nicely and everyone walks and talks slowly
Rym: Which is really really interesting because whenever there is action which is rare But when something is happening immediately, it's such a stark contrast between ginkgo walking slowly You know through the wasteland for hours and hours and suddenly crazy action for three seconds.
Scott: Yeah, it's like all of a sudden.
Scott: You know the monsters coming out of the mud.
Scott: It's like whoa cuz.
Scott: usually the show is like nice and calm and peaceful like And then all of a sudden a monster.
Scott: Oh my god, but no it's not a monster It's just ginkgo coming out of the mud, and then you laugh hysterically.
Rym: And the show is very I don't want to say realistic, but it's realistic in the sense that it's Sad happy humorous dark all at once.
Rym: It's just there's no real pattern to it.
Rym: I mean the show is it's very real feeling.
Rym: The characters feel very realistic in that they react to things in the way that people would probably actually react to them.
Scott: Yeah, it's never like.
Scott: you know it doesn't seem like any of the characters like usually in a show You have like that guy is the comic relief and each character is associated with some sort of emotion like that's the angry guy And that's the sad girl, and that's the what you know.
Scott: everyone seems to be everything.
Scott: You know sometimes ginkgo's like oh You're sick.
Scott: I don't think you're gonna get better, and he's all kind of Sad about that, but then another time something he'll joke about something and he's like hey, what's up?
Scott: It's funny.
Rym: Now despite the generally very serious nature of the show it is often humorous But the humor is very subtle and very wry.
Rym: oh very subtle and I mean to the point of we and you.
Rym: really once you Start watching the show more.
Rym: This is my favorite aspect of the show.
Rym: It's that you you learn about how the show and how the world works as you watch.
Rym: But they don't tell you anything outright.
Rym: They don't say these kind of moosh here like this and these kind of like this.
Rym: But as you watch and you watch ginkgo solve these problems you start figuring out How you would solve them if you were him yeah?
Scott: Well he's also figuring out cuz you know he doesn't know everything about.
Scott: there is to know about mushi.
Scott: so a lot of times He'll show up in town, and there'll be a problem, and he'll be like huh I don't know what kind of mushi it is and then he'll figure it out And he'd like ah I know now yep
Rym: And you'll figure it out right along with him.
Rym: after you watch the first half the show and you start figuring out how these things Work because they're very self consistent.
Scott: the other brought the other thing.
Scott: that was Sometimes he'll come in in town and be like oh, it's the blugga blugga blugga mushi.
Scott: I know what kind that is.
Scott: it does this and this and this and he'll tell you the story about how that mushi works.
Rym: But in terms of the humor like once it's like once you get to know ginkgo I mean he seems like a very mysterious character in fact in the first episode.
Rym: I didn't know he was the main character.
Scott: Yeah, well, I kind of guess yeah Shows called mushishi, and he is a mushishi so true, but I mean the show starts with his boy.
Scott: well at first I didn't realize the show was gonna be episodic.
Scott: that was the thing.
Scott: yeah It was gonna be episodic.
Rym: I would have known that Ginkgo is the main character right away, so it does tell you at the end of the first episode when they basically say I Never found out what happened to that boy, but I knew he would do great things or something like that.
Rym: yep Now one temporarily the show tends to skip around Into the future a lot like he'll do something in a village And then he'll leave and then the narrator will say you know two years hence.
Rym: And then you find out like what happened two years later to the people he helped.
Rym: mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't seem to actually care about time at all.
Scott: like you could probably rearrange the episodes a whole lot And it wouldn't make a lot of difference at all.
Scott: I Mean some of them might make some difference.
Scott: like if you find out the story of ginkgo right away Then you might not understand because you didn't learn about mushi enough for the previous episodes.
Rym: Yeah Or you might miss a lot of the humor in later episodes because you can really only spot it if you've gotten to know ginkgo from the previous 15 episodes.
Scott: Yeah, I think the funniest part was when this is one guy who seems to recur in a few episodes that he sells.
Scott: Oh that guy that guy there is there is a recurring character.
Scott: He's a guy that ginkgo sells interesting artifacts to things that he collects along the way while he's mushi-ing not mushi themselves But like physical things there's.
Rym: and there's this one time where he kind of rips the guy off.
Scott: Yeah, like most of the time.
Scott: He doesn't rip the guy off.
Scott: He sells him the real stuff for a fair price, and this is a smart guy.
Scott: He's actually the guy's a doctor not in mushi-shi, but a doctor.
Scott: But one time he goes and he has this he wants to get this coat.
Scott: There's like magic coat sort of thing to sell to the guy.
Scott: But the guy who owns the coat won't give it to ginkgo.
Scott: so ginkgo is like how about you just make me an exact copy?
Rym: And then he goes and sells it to the guy and he's like hey Now the scene when he sells it to him is just great because like it's outwardly just very simple business transaction.
Rym: But you're if you look at ginkgo.
Rym: He's got this very subtle expression on his face.
Rym: That's different from an expression You've ever seen him make before and it's obvious that he just can't contain the fact that he's ripping this guy off.
Scott: Yeah, and he's like yeah, cuz the real coat has like magic like smoke appears on it.
Scott: It's sort of magical, but It's not magic.
Scott: It's mushi-ical.
Rym: That's a perfectly cromulant word.
Scott: It is perfectly cromulant, but what he tells this guy is he's like yes smoke appears on it once every seven years And the guy's like oh, I hope it happens soon.
Rym: Ginkgo's like yeah, yeah, we'll see I Just really like.
Rym: it sounds weird, but getting to know ginkgo as I watch the show Like you really start to feel like you know this guy.
Scott: He's a cool guy.
Scott: yeah It's like you know right away.
Scott: it's like you know not.
Scott: a lot of the people in some of the episodes you like like.
Scott: some of them are cool and some of them are dumb and Some of them are just naive or whatever, but ginkgo is always cool, and he's in control and knows.
Scott: It's up You know and the way he handles things is a good way like he doesn't force it on anyone, but you know he doesn't Just let shit be.
Scott: he tries to fix it without being evil.
Rym: Now I noticed one kind of interesting trend, and I don't know if it was on purpose or what but it seemed that Whenever there is a situation where a man and a woman are together in some way and Amushi affects one of them It always seemed to affect the woman.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what was up with that.
Rym: I just I don't know if that was a conscious decision if it just ended up that way because it's not true 100% of The time, but it just seems like a trend.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what it was But there was the episode where the guy had the pillow.
Scott: remember like you think he killed everyone in the village.
Scott: Yeah, yeah Yeah, that one was kind of that was one of my favorite ones too.
Scott: Actually.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I like the baby swamps baby swamps.
Scott: See it seems like the women were affected by mushi more But I don't think they.
Scott: you know there are plenty of men affected by mushi.
Scott: It wasn't like some sexist thing is just the store that just happened to be the stories plus.
Scott: It was based on a manga that I haven't read.
Rym: I'd like to read it now.
Scott: Yeah, and we have to find it I don't know and it's not an English yet.
Scott: I don't think it's gonna be for I don't know if it's licensed it.
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: I'll make Emily happy.
Scott: we could talk it We.
Scott: she she is apparently animated where it's called two Z's or something.
Scott: doesn't that what you said?
Rym: Oh, I don't remember offhand.
Scott: Yeah, it's like usually there's like.
Scott: Basically for every three frames of animation in a normal anime There are two.
Scott: or is it for every one frame of animation in a normal anime?
Scott: There's two frames of animation in mushishi or something like that.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: all I remember is that we should probably ask her and get her to send us a wave file from Japan.
Scott: Just to put it I know for sure that the there are more frames of animation per second in mushishi and as a result the animation is Smoother and higher quality.
Scott: I know that for sure.
Rym: So I guess in the end our recommendation since we've seen the show from start to finish Is that it's probably the best show to have come out recently that we've seen so far and it's well worth watching.
Rym: It also hasn't been licensed yet.
Rym: So it's readily available.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Go hit them bit Torrance.
Scott: There should be some Torrance that'll have all 20 episodes pretty soon.
Rym: Plus it's definitely one of those shows that cuz.
Rym: I'm not one who buys a lot of anime Netflix and I only buy something that I would want to own Because it's just so awesome.
Rym: I'd want to show to people and I think mushishi is a show that I would like to own.
Scott: You know, I probably normally wouldn't want to own it But because it's only 20 episodes it might be in like some really nice for DVD box set.
Scott: That's that's small and cheap for like 30 or 40 bucks even like all the slayers box.
Rym: That's our.
Scott: yeah because of that It might be worth it.
Scott: because you know If it was a 26 episode show that cost like a hundred bucks, then maybe I wouldn't want it.
Scott: But yeah, if it's only if if it comes out and it's four DVDs in a little tiny box, then that's totally worth it.
Scott: Especially if you get a nice sale at a con or something.
Scott: Yeah Or maybe a TV will pick it up and you can wait three years and get it cheap on a holiday when they have a Supercell.
Rym: if they'll take your credit card.
Scott: Yeah, we'll say oh Right stuff is the one who doesn't take the credit card.
Rym: and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1 5 3 7.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.