Scott: It's Wednesday May 17th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We talk about the worst anime ever.
Rym: Let's do this Despite purchasing the new Mario game for the DS.
Rym: We were very productive today.
Scott: that's because we purchased many other things and We ate and we did all kinds of stuff before we played it.
Rym: Yeah, we were very non geek kind of normal person I mean we put a new clothesline out in the back which took quite a bit of doing Yeah, but you know what?
Scott: as soon as they're done recording this shit.
Scott: It's gonna be Mario Mario Mario Mario Yeah, some Mario multiplayer, and you won't get to find out about it until next Tuesday.
Rym: All I'll say is I like the game a lot.
Rym: I've already beaten world world one And those mega mushrooms are fantastic.
Scott: Oh God yeah, like.
Scott: I thought they were just gonna like be bleh, but the way they're the way they work is really cool.
Rym: Plus this is one thing and I got to say something about this now.
Rym: The music is always like dupe dupe dupe dupe and some people like a little choir goes like ha ha.
Rym: Whenever the music goes ha all the goombas do a little jump in unison if they're on the screen and all the turtles go do Like a little dance like ha ha and it's just.
Rym: it's hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: there's really good stuff going on.
Rym: There's lots of little stuff like that.
Rym: Nintendo's really got it going with the little and we've only played level one.
Scott: So wait till next Tuesday.
Rym: Yeah, so in the actual news Normally, I wouldn't really talk about something like this or I'd wait until a Monday, but this is just too ludicrous.
Rym: The RIAA has sued XM radio.
Scott: Did XM radio download some mp3s with Kazaa?
Rym: Well their basic argument is that the XM radio technology can store songs on it You know time shifting and such or even just storing it temporarily while it buffers or plays to you.
Rym: Therefore it has quote-unquote iPod like capabilities.
Rym: Therefore they claim that it's all sorts of violations and vague laws and stupid crap and they want to renegotiate the royalties and charge more.
Scott: But there's an iPod.
Rym: Yeah, and they don't like that either.
Rym: remember when they sued the the first because you don't like it.
Rym: tough shit No, but it's there.
Rym: remember that's the way America works.
Rym: You can sue anyone for anything at any time.
Rym: There's nothing to stop you from suing people.
Scott: Well, I'm sure XM won't take this lying down because they're all who they haven't.
Scott: they're already kind of losing to serious.
Scott: So they're not gonna take a lawsuit that'll put them away for good.
Rym: XM said they're going to fight this to the end to the bitter horrid end.
Rym: They're putting their entire team behind and they will not back down.
Scott: All I can think about is how.
Scott: You know people were talking a few weeks ago about how the if you took all the technology companies versus all the music companies and record companies in the US Like just Microsoft or just Google could buy and sell them all the record companies together like over and over again Multiple times.
Scott: it's insane that these record companies which are so measly and worthless are pushing around these giant powerful technology companies because they dump all this money to lobbyists.
Rym: and All the technology companies are busy making more technology and they don't really worry about it so much.
Scott: And they're not really good at lobbyists because you don't need to lobby to do perfectly normal and legitimate goods.
Scott: Yeah for now You only need to lobby when you're doing bad shit and you need to make sure the government doesn't stop you from doing bad shit.
Scott: If you're doing perfectly normal stuff, like let's say I'm a manufacturer of goods.
Scott: I buy raw materials I process them into you know, worked goods and I sell them.
Scott: I don't need to lobby because I'm not doing anything wrong.
Rym: You need to lobby if you have other people lobbying against you.
Scott: if my business model depends on a law Existing then I need to lobby.
Rym: Yeah, but what if the some lobbyists against may see you make milk and some anti milk lobbyists are making your milk industry collapse?
Scott: Yeah The exact opposite is.
Scott: no one's trying to get rid of milk But there's a billion people trying to make milk plus plus more than its worth.
Rym: I'm more worried about this bacon trend that we've been noticing though It might just be that we don't eat it.
Rym: like most stuff on the walls normal restaurants Every single item on the menu at TGI Friday's had bacon and cheese Literally, we're not kidding other than like the appetizers which most of them actually had bacon anyway, and the vegetarian menu.
Rym: Everything had bacon.
Rym: every single burger listed on the menu had bacon and cheese on it.
Scott: It went to quiz knows bacon and cheese, even though it tastes good.
Scott: I had it but bacon and cheese.
Rym: We're thinking that it has to do with the fact that pigs are fed mostly on corn Which is made very easily and cheaply in the United States.
Scott: ergo bacon and of course cheese.
Rym: Yeah, cheese.
Rym: It'd be fine if it wasn't that processed yellow crap cheese.
Scott: I think bacon cheese and corn are the three foods that like if you look ask any American Or you just look inside the stomach of an average American 90% of what's in there is gonna be bacon cheese and corn.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think our friend Dave tips the scale entirely toward bologna and my Wonder bread.
Scott: Well Wonder breads corn Not so much.
Scott: Yeah, really go look.
Scott: It's scary.
Scott: There's a lot of corn syrup in there.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there's corn syrup and a lot of things but it's mostly wheat.
Rym: Yeah There's not so much call.
Scott: It's really.
Scott: it's less we eat or else it would be wheat bread.
Scott: It's more really bleached as crap bear, you know, but that's still wheat.
Scott: You're not whole wheat.
Rym: It's still a wheat though It's just bleached refined wheat.
Scott: Yeah, which is mostly flour.
Scott: It's almost flour.
Rym: flour is just wheat.
Rym: Yeah, it's all wheat Still unless you make oat bread.
Rym: It's all wheat.
Scott: Then why did they have wheat bread and white bread?
Rym: because wheat bread.
Rym: they call it that it's just less processed and there's more wheat.
Rym: Okay, whole wheat not a sweet Alright, so you got a news cuz there's nothing.
Rym: Alright, there's nothing I can say about my news other than that The RIAA is horrible corrupt bastardly evil Manipulative.
Rym: I could go on for a while.
Rym: I'm just gonna stop there.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: My news is anime related.
Scott: fear that This fall We're gonna be downloading because it surely won't be available in English on DVD at that time.
Scott: It'll just be coming on to Japanese TV An anime Hopefully fansubbed.
Scott: Well, I can guarantee it'll be fansubbed.
Rym: We'd better get a hold of this anime.
Rym: If I don't watch it, I might get all upside down II inside adding maybe some twisty turning.
Scott: Okay, um that note that note death note.
Scott: It could be some death note anime.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm still really really excited about the death note live-action.
Scott: Yeah, like I wasn't so excited I was like, yeah, I'll see it someday like the initial D live-action.
Scott: I'll see it something.
Rym: but we saw the trailer.
Scott: but then I saw the trailer which was Exactly like the manga only live-action.
Rym: like you're watching the trailer and the whole time you'll think like, ooh I hope they do this.
Rym: then they show you the scene.
Rym: You're like, oh they did it.
Rym: Oh, I wonder if they're gonna you and then you see it.
Rym: I wonder if he looks like oh everyone looks exactly the way they should.
Rym: Everyone looks like they're acting really well and then at the end you think wait a minute.
Rym: There's one character I didn't say there is.
Scott: yeah It's amazing.
Scott: go if you don't if you know about.
Scott: if you don't know about that note read the manga.
Scott: the manga is the best.
Scott: Death note is probably after you read the manga.
Scott: There are five volumes out in English right now.
Scott: The sixth one is coming soon.
Scott: go and watch the trailer for the movie and Then wait for this anime and keep buying the manga as it comes out in English.
Rym: I don't think it's gonna be a initial D movie.
Rym: In fact, I think it's going to be the exact opposite.
Scott: Yeah, I'm still skeptical.
Scott: the anime will be good.
Scott: I mean sure I'll download it and watch it all and maybe even buy all the DVDs.
Scott: just cuz I'm a huge Death Note fan.
Scott: But Death Note is a lot of it isn't moving in action.
Scott: It's internal monologue.
Rym: It's it's light thinking.
Scott: Yeah, it won't gain a lot by being animated.
Scott: You'll have if you if you do a not a very good translation from the manga.
Scott: You'll you either have to really speed things up and skip over a bunch of parts People are just standing there talking or a lot of minutes internal monologue, which is usually painful and terrible.
Scott: Yeah, at least in an anime.
Scott: so I really want to see how they do it without either a ruining my death note is about or be Being really boring anime.
Scott: now the movie I think has a much more Potential because in the movie you just take the key events and string them together and you skip all the boring stuff in.
Rym: Well, not only that but I like to look at it.
Rym: The initial D movie got all the wrong things right like they focused on like oh We're gonna have this thing from the show and this thing from the show and this thing from the show and they had him Exactly from the show.
Scott: The problem is that didn't add anything to the movie and the movie itself was crap as a result because the movie didn't have the good Things from the show it only took the bad things in the show.
Rym: now I have a feeling that the Death Note movie is gonna have the right things wrong Meaning they'll know which things need to be altered for the screen and that sort of thing.
Scott: Mm-hmm But then they'll do them wrong.
Scott: Not you said right things wrong.
Rym: Yeah Because before I said wrong things right Initial D had the wrong things right as opposed to the right things wrong.
Rym: You change the things to be wrong according.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: Okay, you just didn't get it.
Scott: It's not I can do.
Rym: I was being clever with words and you just missed it.
Scott: No, no, you weren't so clever.
Scott: You were just obtuse.
Rym: the right things wrong as opposed to the wrong things, right?
Rym: I think that's pretty clear.
Scott: I think you're just wrong.
Scott: Okay, okay Death Note anime baby.
Rym: All right I'm the juggernaut bitch.
Rym: I'm the juggernaut bitch Fucking Charles get out of my head.
Rym: What are you doing?
Rym: LSD fuck.
Rym: is this shit?
Rym: All right.
Rym: This is something that I saw a long time ago, and I thought it was stupid Like it was a good years on Google video.
Rym: And actually I think I saw it on a website somewhere and It was just this video of some guy dubbing over some voices in the x-men The original good Fox x-men cartoon, which is the only x-men that Scott likes pretty much.
Rym: I watched about 30 seconds of it and thought wow, this is just stupid.
Rym: didn't bother with it.
Rym: So today we were looking at funny cat videos on Google's top video top 100.
Scott: Yeah, if you're ever bored just go on Google video and search for funny cat videos.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Yeah, search like cat or puppy.
Rym: My favorite video along those lines is the cat versus a million puppies.
Rym: It's just this cat sitting there like man And like 11 puppies standing around the cat like ooh, look at that.
Rym: Ooh, what's this?
Rym: What's this?
Rym: Let's play Let's play and the cats like what the fuck Go away.
Scott: the Fox on the trampoline is also quite good.
Rym: Yeah, the Fox on the trampoline that things been getting everywhere.
Rym: I bet it'll hit Google's top hundred soon.
Rym: Probably it's just this Fox who finds the trampoline and goes nuts on it.
Rym: But anyway, I saw this thing on Google's video top 100 and I thought what the hell how can that be on top 100?
Rym: This thing is just ass.
Rym: So then I watched it all of it all nine minutes of it.
Rym: It's any individual moment of it.
Rym: Isn't that funny?
Rym: But in aggregate it just becomes more and more stupid and hilarious.
Scott: Get you my pimp cane My pick-pimp cane.
Rym: look at all this money.
Rym: I got bitch.
Rym: I'm the juggernaut The juggernaut bitch I'm not sure.
Rym: just watch it.
Rym: I'm not sure why it's funny.
Rym: The voice acting is It's not really well synced, but they really got into it the guys that were doing it and it.
Scott: It's got this like low level of humor throughout Yeah, and you don't even really have to know anything about the x-men or who these characters are to think it's funny.
Scott: But if you do know who they are, it'll be like it'll add a tiny bit.
Rym: It's real close to lowbrow really close.
Scott: Alright, my thing today is also a Google video that I found at work while I was bored.
Rym: This one's just kind of like creepy.
Scott: I Figured it's martial arts kind of.
Scott: so I guess it.
Rym: Yeah, if there's a martial art called to hurt yourself severely with no gain exactly my point.
Scott: So it fits in on anime day, I guess this is what from Malaysia, right?
Scott: So this is a video of some Malaysian people doing quote unquote extreme martial arts training.
Rym: I'm just picturing it again.
Scott: So the video starts with this guy who climbs up this tower.
Scott: It's like must be more than 50 feet tall like maybe 75 feet tall.
Rym: No, no, no It looks like it's about 30 or 40 feet tall.
Scott: It's pretty tall.
Rym: Anyway, I know what a 70 foot tall tower.
Scott: Anyway, it's tall enough where if I jumped off of it, I would die.
Rym: Yeah, I imagine a pile of Rym laying at the bottom of this thing.
Scott: So this guy jumps off and turns into a pile of him laying at the bottom of this thing.
Rym: But then they get him up.
Rym: they steady him.
Rym: His legs are obviously broken.
Scott: He's like his entire body turns purple and bruised and it's horrible and his legs have to be broken.
Scott: There's no way they can't be it's just obvious.
Rym: So he's standing there and he's breathing and he does himself off and they help him over and he climbs the thing again And does it again.
Rym: this time he lands on his face.
Scott: Yeah, this guy does this like three or four times.
Scott: It's quite like at first you're like, whoa, but then later you're like, oh god.
Rym: now there's obviously a little bit of trickery going on in that it's pretty obvious that the ground is Saturated with water and a little soft, but he obviously has a technique for landing.
Scott: But at the same time even so he is he is a wounded man.
Scott: He is severely wounded.
Scott: Now the second part of the video.
Scott: they show people jumping through glass.
Scott: now, this isn't really much of a trick.
Scott: They use really thin glass that breaks easily.
Rym: It's not a sugar glass so it can't hurt you.
Scott: They run then they jump and they put their hand their arms over their head.
Scott: They jump headfirst through the glass, of course their arm.
Scott: They're really going arm.
Scott: first the glass breaks They roll the rest of their body through the glass while minimally touching it.
Scott: Then they roll on the ground and they turn around and strike some cool martial arts pose.
Rym: That part's not so exciting.
Scott: then at the end of the video They combine the two.
Scott: a guy runs jumps through glass and Then basically out of a building and then he lands on the ground outside the building and he's not dead But I think he's close at this point.
Scott: Yeah, I think that guy is when he jumps out of that building just right face on the ground not move.
Scott: Yeah, this guy doesn't land on his legs with any trickery.
Scott: This guy lands like wump Big gash on his leg.
Scott: Yeah, the glass fell out of the window apparently and he must have landed on the glass and he fucked himself up.
Scott: So watch this video and go.
Scott: wow If you think you know crazy Christians and people who believe in Randy bullshit in this country I like how you started with crazy Christians, of course These people are infinitely more stupid now.
Rym: my best guess as to what's going on here This is rims best guest TM as opposed to my actual best guess.
Rym: I Imagine some people who went to Malaysia thinking I'm going to become the Malaysian martial arts master and I will find these people to train me like, you know the people who go to try to become kung-fu monks.
Rym: and Then a bunch of guys find him.
Rym: They're like, yes, we will train you Jump out of that building Repeatedly, it will make you strong and then he comes back a week later.
Rym: He's like I've been jumping out of that building.
Rym: I feel stronger and they're like Crap.
Rym: he's still alive.
Rym: What do we do now?
Rym: Tell him to jump through a plate glass window out of a building.
Rym: All right that finished him off.
Rym: You know what.
Scott: that's probably not true, but it makes a better story than the truth.
Rym: so well We'll pretend for now All right, so it's worst week and we're gonna talk about the worst anime ever.
Scott: Now there's some bad anime out there and there's some anime we hate like.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: What's a bad anime?
Rym: That's not the worst of air gear tactical roar.
Scott: Yeah air gear tactical roar Those are bad shows, but they're not the worst shows ever.
Scott: and Naruto.
Scott: We don't really like so much.
Scott: Well, we like the first few episodes, but then it's down hill.
Rym: Yeah, or like Yu Yu Hakusho was one episode of cute two episodes of cute.
Scott: Oh, yeah - two episodes followed by crap.
Scott: Yep, so in Dragon Ball Z We really don't like and it's just crap fighting but it's not the worst ever.
Rym: We're talking about the worst of the worst.
Scott: So terrible, you can't watch it Like like.
Scott: there's some things that are so bad.
Scott: you MST 3k them.
Scott: These are the things that are so bad.
Scott: you just Burn them in a fire now.
Rym: We're leaving out a lot of things that we haven't actually seen.
Rym: for yeah, I do megalopolis.
Scott: Yeah, do megalopolis is?
Scott: it looks like it's really bad and I've heard it's really bad from a lot of people.
Scott: And what's that about milk?
Rym: something super milk Sean?
Rym: Well, actually that comes out of the fact that right before the show I did some research on the Internet.
Rym: I went to a whole bunch of forums looking for threads about worst anime and going through them to see What the Internet as a whole seemed to think the worst anime are.
Rym: I'll note that one.
Rym: they systematically listed every anime ever.
Scott: Yeah, that doesn't really help.
Rym: and a lot of people listed things that weren't anime.
Scott: Yeah, that was also bad like totally spies or x-men.
Scott: yeah x-men is not an anime.
Scott: There is no x-men anime.
Rym: shut up But I mean there were people who were like yeah eska flow day is like the worst thing I've ever seen.
Rym: It's just slow and crappy and the music's terrible.
Rym: Did they walk?
Scott: Oh, and we're also gonna leave out things like the Fox eska flown a and What is it warriors of the wind the worst right thing to ever happen to anime?
Scott: So if someone took a good anime or at least an anime that wasn't the worst anime and they remixed it or edited it or Modified it in some way to make it the worst anime that doesn't count.
Scott: For example one piece on American television is crap compared to the real one piece anime in Japan but that doesn't count.
Rym: and Also while we're gonna leave a lot out after we name a few infamous shows We're gonna kind of try to do a generic.
Rym: here are the calling signs of the bad bad bad bad bad anime.
Scott: All right, let's save the worst for last and start with the big one.
Rym: Which one?
Rym: I think you were leaving a real bag hoping yeah Let's start with Legend of Lemnier Lemnier.
Scott: Yeah, um we didn't make a list.
Rym: I can explain the plot, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: There's something about the silver something.
Rym: There's a guy.
Scott: I don't remember the plot cuz I saw it once and I burned my eyes out So I'd never see it again, and then I forgot a girl.
Rym: There's swords and magic.
Rym: Everyone gets randomly naked.
Scott: yeah boobies boobies boobies boobies, but it's not pent I it's just you know how in fantasy stuff that or sci-fi stuff You'll often have the girls shirt gets torn off just randomly.
Rym: This happens a lot in Lemnier like what the plot is just like stupid deus ex machina crap.
Rym: There's really nothing to it.
Scott: animation is bad.
Scott: Everyone's ugly Thank God.
Scott: This is only like.
Scott: was it a movie or an OVA?
Rym: I don't know how long it was, but it felt like it was four hours.
Scott: I think it was just one movie, and I fell asleep during it.
Scott: probably and You just don't want to watch this ever.
Scott: if you see it's notice.
Scott: It's only on VHS not on DVD.
Scott: as far as I know.
Scott: You never want to see Legend of Lemniar LEM NEAR Lemnier.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we're not.
Rym: Some people have said in the forums when we talk about an anime.
Rym: That's not good like.
Rym: yeah I watched it cuz.
Rym: it sounded like it was so bad.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: We're telling you right now no show we mentioned is worth watching.
Rym: like not even for the humor value because there isn't any Watch at your own peril.
Rym: We're not kidding Because Lemnier is definitely not the worst of the bunch of the worst.
Scott: no But it is bad enough to be labeled one of the worst anime ever.
Rym: now far closer perhaps the bottom.
Rym: Perhaps this is tied with the worst anime down there at the very bottom, but gray the digital target.
Scott: Oh my god great digital tag.
Rym: now if you google.
Scott: I think great deals target is the worst.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: you haven't actually seen the other one.
Rym: We're gonna talk about.
Rym: well.
Scott: I have still My god Let's talk about great digital target all right now if you google for it.
Rym: great the digital target sounds kind of interesting.
Scott: Everyone is.
Scott: it's a sci-fi anime movie based on some manga that I never read.
Rym: everyone who?
Rym: Reviews it talks about the dystopian future and the the intricate Sociopolitical ramifications of what's going on and these long-glowing reviews, and that is what it's about.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: it's about a guy.
Rym: well No, it's a girl who randomly has boobs popping out yeah, and a bunch of fighting Yeah, and then the movie just stops because they ran out of money.
Scott: There's the robot with one arm.
Rym: all right There's a scene.
Rym: I mean the animation is so bad.
Rym: There is this robot guy.
Scott: What animation is just a bunch of still shots one after the other.
Rym: who gets so?
Rym: Wounded that eventually.
Rym: he's a torso with a head and one arm.
Scott: He's a robot.
Scott: now He's heading one arm right head and one arm one Head a torso a single arm no legs no second arm.
Scott: So you have a torso and a head with a single limb.
Rym: now point the first one Appended.
Rym: there is a scene where he climbs a mountain And they show him climbing and he reaches up with the arm And he pulls himself up.
Rym: then he lets it go with the arm Reaches up with the arm and pulls himself up further that this does he holding on with the teeth.
Rym: what he's talking in fact While he's climbing that's right now.
Rym: This wouldn't be so bad in and of itself.
Rym: Maybe they liked if they didn't actually show him climbing with.
Rym: it's the broken animation.
Rym: But to his climbing this mountain is critical.
Rym: critical to the plot.
Scott: yeah It is now.
Rym: I'm not gonna say that you have to be perfectly realistic in an anime or a movie or anything.
Rym: I mean dragons don't seem to really exist.
Rym: So we can't have a movie about dragons without making up some dragon stuff.
Rym: It's okay to futz with physics a little bit, but good God.
Scott: Yeah, I don't mind it when Lupin's car drives on the wall.
Scott: But if you're gonna have a one armed one headed one torsoed robot Climbing a mountain you got another thing coming now Especially if you're not being all slapstick in whatnot?
Scott: you're being dead serious.
Rym: This movie is serious.
Rym: They are not joking around.
Scott: No, they're not.
Rym: now you think all right that doesn't sound so bad.
Rym: It's kind of long and we're watching and we're not gonna stop watching.
Rym: because once we start watching a show We're not gonna stop until we see the end of it.
Rym: unless I fall asleep which often happens Like with that last Lupin movie we watch yeah, I gotta go finish that up.
Rym: But the movie it's moving toward conclusion, and I remember sitting there This is back in college thinking all right this fuckers gonna end.
Rym: I'm gonna find out what happened I'll have closure, and then I'll never speak of it again.
Rym: The movie doesn't end.
Scott: Okay, so just you know the way.
Scott: the plot is.
Scott: this is evil Supercomputer and they want to destroy it because it runs the world and enforces the dystopian society.
Scott: So they want to destroy this evil computer.
Scott: so at the end of the movie They go towards the evil computer to destroy it like they're finally gonna go do it like they're walking over with the guns toward the Horizon like we're gonna go and the movie and you think that you're gonna see.
Scott: after you're ready.
Scott: You're gonna see a big fight scene where they run into the giant computer place And they fight robots and they destroy the evil computer and maybe someone dies along the way And then the movie's over.
Rym: suddenly the animation stops.
Scott: If you don't get to see the action scene on their way over to the tower the animation stops.
Rym: it stops.
Rym: It shows the horizon and like their shadows in the distance And then those disappear.
Rym: then text appears over the screen And it says something like five hours later the supercomputer system stopped functioning and then The the image in the background gets kind of wavy like there's an explosion and then the credits roll.
Scott: I think they actually changed the frame to a second picture, which has an explosion on it and play an explosion noise.
Rym: I Remember screaming horseshit at the TV and then going to bed.
Scott: I remember everyone was like fuck this shit.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Wow we should have done the juggernaut bitch because now we're just all foul-mouthed today, that's fine.
Scott: the juggernaut bitch Motherfucking gray digital target no motherfucking ending.
Rym: what the hell not a goddamn thing you can do about it.
Scott: I got damn thing.
Rym: now Scott hasn't seen the other anime.
Rym: That's really down there with gray the digital target, but he's heard about it.
Scott: I heard about it on anime world order where they did a whole episode about it.
Rym: I've seen it.
Rym: I saw the sci-fi channel.
Rym: do it dubbed on TV?
Rym: once it is called Odin?
Rym: Yeah, we don't really want to call it Odin because that is disgraceful to Odin the god of various things Vikings with an eyepatch.
Rym: So yeah the reason you call it Odin Is because anime world order did that and you listen?
Rym: well
Scott: no no because in the movie Odin one of the voice actors for one girl at one point you know the girl screams Odin in in the movie and the voice actor did it like oh Now then they played that audio clip in the show and I thought it was hilarious.
Rym: this movie is ass.
Rym: it is ass ass ass Ass ass ass ass.
Rym: don't watch it.
Rym: So it's not good.
Scott: I'm gonna try to Summarize what I heard on an anime world order and what I remember from listening to it weeks ago.
Scott: But you should go and listen to their episode on Odin.
Scott: Yes, and if you want to know the whole story about this horrible horrible anime because they know every much everything about it.
Scott: It's called it's really called Odin something.
Scott: space sailors starlight something.
Rym: Yeah, they got ships that go through space with sails that light something something.
Scott: Yeah, who cares?
Scott: It was it's a very expensive movie.
Scott: They spent a lot of money on it.
Scott: They thought it was going to be the next big thing Whatever.
Scott: Yeah, whoever thought that should dine afire, but all the voice acting suck the anime.
Scott: everything sucked about it.
Scott: It was just so so terrible, but then they tried to sell it big time because they spent so much money on it.
Rym: And Yeah, yeah like Gundam f91 was really bad and suffered from the same problems of let's just dump a lot of money into an anime and it'll be Really popular and awesome, but nothing really came quite close to the absolute horror.
Rym: That is Odin Mm-hmm it I can't God.
Scott: Yeah now notables that really aren't on the list But we like to hold out that there's one that should be on the list But we haven't seen so we can't talk about it for more than a few seconds.
Scott: That's Final Fantasy Legend of the Crystal.
Rym: whatever everyone I've ever heard who's all who've seen this show said it was terrible.
Scott: now I the anime club at RIT has the VHS tape and I remember I Saw it once and I was like, huh?
Scott: Maybe I should watch that and every single person who had ever seen it or knew anything about it said Do not watch that.
Scott: it is so bad It's not you know, it's.
Scott: it's the worst thing ever and I've never heard a single positive statement about this show from anyone.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I think you're really gonna like it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, go ahead Go find an old VHS tape of Final Fantasy Legend of the Crystal, whatever it's called.
Scott: Yeah watch that.
Rym: I dare you the quote from the anime or Expo forums where I was.
Rym: I was going through forums and someone mentioned this.
Rym: they said It is physically painful to watch.
Rym: I was nauseous.
Scott: Yeah, so that's a terrible fucking anime.
Rym: Granted Final Fantasy unlimited wasn't much better.
Scott: No if I was in limited was also bad, but it wasn't terrible.
Rym: Yeah, it at least had one redeeming feature.
Rym: Tell that chocobo who would bite the girl's head.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Oh, oh I like.
Scott: I really like choke and the animation was newer and shinier and not painful.
Rym: Yeah, why couldn't?
Rym: they had just made it like Final Fantasy the chocobo and the cute girl.
Scott: Yeah chocobo the anime.
Rym: That'd be freaking great.
Scott: Yeah, they should also have Dragon Warrior the slime the anime.
Scott: Oh, no, the slide already has its own game.
Rym: the slime and the chocobo should team up.
Scott: Oh, yeah the other one company.
Scott: They can fucking do that.
Rym: Yeah, and they should.
Scott: I know I'm Chris a lot.
Scott: this episode.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, GeekNights is not rated G.
Scott: no, no, it's not.
Scott: it's rated like are But on some days and pg-13 on other days.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Rym: All right now some no other notables that really don't deserve to be on the list even though they're pretty bad.
Scott: the lens man Lensman I think is like it's real close to being on the list and I you know I haven't seen it but from what I've heard from people It's just about as bad as the Final Fantasy.
Scott: so which kind of should be?
Scott: it's just that it.
Rym: it's really maligned it Go.
Rym: it's based on what is supposedly a very good body of science fiction.
Scott: Oh, yeah The books supposedly are like the greatest side or well not the greatest but very good science fiction novels.
Rym: the movie is one of these.
Rym: like it tries to do too much with it and it it goes in all these different directions and It's long and plotting and the end is like typical Mid 80s anime end if that doesn't mean anything to you.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: Yeah, there's Imagine and it just has like a j-poppy early j-rock kind of like music over while the hero like escapes from the exploding thing at the end and this takes several minutes after the Big villain.
Rym: whatever explains whatever existential bullshit the movie was trying to be about.
Scott: The only reason the lens man isn't way down in the worst anime ever is that there are actually some people who like it.
Scott: No one likes the other anime we talked about.
Scott: I know one.
Rym: I Like the lens man.
Rym: All right in the same way that I like the game gear.
Rym: I grew up with it because you know I first saw anime in fourth grade when the sci-fi channel showed a whole bunch of anime on a Saturday and I watched it all and For about a year after that I watched any anime I could get my hands on and loved it.
Rym: Among that I got a tape of lens man, which was fantastic and I watched it a bunch of times Now that I'm older and wiser and even then there were twinges of like wow, this is really boring.
Rym: Wow, they don't explain anything about that thing that they just used to finish the plot with.
Scott: Wow hmm Let's see.
Scott: Oh, I want to give a special note about robot carnival.
Scott: Aha Robot carnival is a collection of short animated features by different people.
Scott: I think there's a katsuhiro tomo thing in there.
Scott: I don't really remember But you know, there's one that's kind of frankenstein II and there's one that's got these people in a balloon.
Rym: This was also shown on that early early, you know when I was in fourth grade sci-fi channel thing, right?
Scott: Now the thing about it is some of it has some artistic redeeming value Which is why it's not the absolute worst.
Scott: It's not like, you know, the same tier as lens men But most of it is just incredibly painful and useless and terrible.
Rym: Also, I just I thought of this out of the blue kashan robot hunter.
Scott: Well, no concern is terrible.
Rym: I'm talking about the anime which is worse.
Scott: Is it really that bad?
Rym: Oh when I when I found out that that movie that we thought was gonna be awesome from the trailer the live-action was Based on this thing I about cried because I saw this on the sci-fi channel back when I wanted any anime in the world.
Rym: I loved anime and I thought it was stupid.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, it it's it It's stupid.
Rym: I don't want to get into it.
Rym: Let's not talk about it.
Scott: That's a bad anime right there.
Scott: Notice how a lot of the bad animes are old like Any anime that's recent at least has decent enough art.
Scott: art to be not terrible.
Scott: I mean in order to be a really bad anime you have to have no story.
Scott: No art.
Scott: No music No, nothing.
Scott: if there's some anime out there that just have good music and the rest is terrible Those at least are not the worst because they have something good about them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They got the music.
Rym: They got the chocobo They got something.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: New animes seem to always have at least some redeeming value Of some such like tactical roar I guess had some mech stuff in it, I guess.
Rym: yeah I guess air gear was kind of hilarious because it was so stupid.
Scott: Yep See, but there are absolutely no redeeming qualities to these old old terrible shows because they're just old and terrible.
Rym: now I'd like to have a bunch of nods to ass things that more modern or Otherwise good anime have done to put them real close to being on this list.
Rym: My biggest one.
Rym: My biggest gripe is noir.
Rym: Now when we first heard about noir and people have been talking like there's a lot of buzz about it for some reason and it came out and we watched the first episode and only the first episode at anime club and It was awesome.
Rym: Anyone who's seen the first episode of noir?
Rym: It's like this crazy like really neat music Really like cool action scenes and the hint of what could be an awesome plot.
Scott: Yeah, and if you keep watching a few more episodes It's still kind of awesome and the show goes steadily downhill.
Rym: like it gets more and more outrageous.
Rym: I mean it goes from like there's the scene.
Rym: everyone who's seen the first episode will remember the one scene Where the girl hangs the guy by the necktie and it's just done really artistically and awesomely by halfway through the show.
Rym: fight scenes basically involve a little girl standing there with two pistols and Standing across from her are like a thousand guys with guns and she kills them all without moving.
Rym: Yep, and the end of noir is perhaps the stupidest ending.
Rym: Versus it's not the worst thing in any ending attending anime ever.
Rym: But compared to how good the first episode of noir was it is probably the greatest disparity in an anime ever Especially since it it was completely separate from what the show was.
Scott: I mean they had this dark cool Urban noir action and they should have just stuck with that.
Scott: But then a little ways into the show they brought in that Chloe Character and it got all weird and they got all weird and mystical.
Scott: and then at the end of the show They really brought that stuff in and it was like it's like the ending of the show Was nuns with guns.
Rym: Literally these nuns come out with these golden pistols and the nuns are like it's time to do what we've always been trained to do And they go out with the guns and they all fight and then nuns with guns.
Scott: It seems like they made two shows one was about nuns and a scary cult and whatever and one was noir.
Scott: and They ended up just taking the ending of one show and sticking it at the end of noir and they threw the ending of noir Away
Rym: plus the end doesn't make sense because the end involves this high priestess woman standing there and she's like you must kill me to become noir and seal your fate as the assassin blah blah blah blah blah and They end up killing her anyway, even though they avoid killing her in this specific situation.
Rym: they kill her a little bit later Yeah, and then they just like literally the end of the movie.
Rym: Just they.
Rym: the show is.
Rym: they walk away and the police arrived and they're all like We're gonna arrest you and they're like whatever and they walk away and that's the end.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's just it's dumb and there's a lot of a pit.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the love bits cool lava pit nuns with guns lives.
Scott: Yeah, another thing that a lot of shows do that makes them suck is Fighting god.
Scott: now a fight in a show is cool.
Rym: Everyone loves a good action scene in fact if a fights important enough.
Rym: I wouldn't mind if it spanned a couple episodes.
Scott: Yeah, but when you watch a show like rave master was a cute Happy show I was watching just because it was a cute happy show and then I realized that there was a fight that had lasted ten episodes or such Naruto.
Scott: the first few episodes are happy ninja school.
Scott: and then there's a fight that lasts ten episodes or such Dragon Ball.
Scott: every fight it lasts ten episodes or such.
Rym: well Dragon Ball Z. Dragon Ball was actually kind of funny.
Scott: Yeah, Dragon Ball is it when I'm talking about Dragon Ball Z and GT and GT is even worse, you know, it's okay If you have a plot, that's good.
Scott: If there's a fight that's important to the plot.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: If you drag out if the whole substance of your show is just making more episodes By having people come up with techniques and talk about how their technique will counter that technique and love it
Rym: If you do that with real-world things like at least initial D though I'm not saying initial D is highbrow anime at least when they come up with the.
Rym: oh, well, he blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: It's based on a real thing and the races only last two episodes in.
Rym: like Naruto.
Rym: They whenever they just make shit up like you can just like.
Rym: oh, well, I use the special flying puppy magic dagger Puppy puppy.
Scott: that's not substance.
Scott: It's just a waste of my time to watch that shit and the shows that so much potential.
Rym: I mean a lot of shows fall into this.
Rym: Yu Yu Hakusho was cute and funny and then it turned into crap.
Scott: Yeah, if I watched the first two episodes Yu Yu Hakusho and I was like, oh, that's why people say this show was good No one.
Scott: and then I found out the rest of the show is fighting bleach.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: Awesome characters Like.
Rym: I really really love the characters and I think the plot is cool.
Scott: I don't like the characters that much.
Scott: the plots Okay, but at the same time what really ruins the show is the fighting.
Rym: it's just they've everyone's fighting and that's all.
Scott: the show is Just shown in action.
Scott: like but it's not just shown in action.
Scott: Does there shows that are not in the shown in action genre that just have?
Scott: Useless substance list shallow fight equivalents.
Rym: Yep, or instead of a fight There's the monster a day or item of the day episodic format like Inuyasha Where oh we have to find the thingy.
Rym: Oh, there's the thingy.
Rym: Oh the thingy split into 10 billion pieces.
Rym: We must spend one episode each collecting them all.
Rym: great Cuz I actually like the story of Inuyasha.
Rym: I think it's a good story.
Rym: I like the characters.
Scott: man I like it so much.
Rym: the problem is for every one minute of character development and plot I get 29 minutes of bullshit.
Scott: yep, another thing a lot of animes do that's bad is Take two different genres and stick them together.
Scott: a good example of this is Full metal panic.
Scott: full metal panic could have been a really good show because the robot half of it with the Story about the war and whatnot was actually kind of good and I watched the whole first season just for that
Rym: and by the same Token, the other half the funny school military hijinks half was
Scott: pretty funny.
Scott: Yeah, the you know, there are a lot of school hijinks shows and they're good and bad.
Scott: But this one was you know, slightly above average sticking them together Subtracted from both of them.
Scott: I Think that that's really the point of full metal panic.
Scott: So it's kind of silly to say to take it out, but full metal panic would have been better is two separate shows.
Rym: I think it suffers from the fact that the military part was too serious and cool and the other part was just too silly.
Rym: So there's too much disparity.
Rym: You can't jump back and forth between emotions that quickly or it ruins the effect.
Scott: Yeah, I think plus earlier in the show There's a lot more school and later in the show those a lot more military which kind of helped it a little bit Which is how I was able to finish the show.
Scott: but yeah the school should have been a little less happy and the military should have been a little less serious because The military plot really wasn't deep enough to hold up to its seriousness.
Rym: Now here's a specific gripe about a specific show and series and franchise that frankly they should have let it die a long time ago.
Rym: Tenshi Muyo it the original Tenshi Muyo the TV and the OAV.
Scott: in the first movie I really like I kind of sort of invented the harem show.
Scott: Yeah, but harem shows are bad But at the same time at least inventing any genre.
Rym: and it did it.
Rym: Well, the show is funny and heartwarming.
Rym: I like the characters.
Rym: I really enjoy Tenshi.
Rym: Now for some reason.
Rym: well not for some reason.
Rym: it's obvious why they did it money.
Rym: But they made another movie and Alright, this movie is kind of a but it's not so bad.
Rym: It's short whatever.
Rym: and they made another movie Which was basically just doujinshi fan service porn.
Rym: Then they made Tenshi GXP, which is one of the worst travesties to everyone about Tokyo one.
Rym: And then and before the OAVs there were the first two.
Rym: the first OAV is awesome Except at the end when they pull this thing where they come out.
Rym: They're like the last episode.
Rym: They're like, here's a million million million million plot things that will never resolve, huh?
Rym: And then they decided to make another OAV and try to explain all that crap and that's not a good idea.
Rym: Tenshi in Tokyo was self-indulgent indulgent crap.
Rym: It just went nowhere and it was just a money grab.
Rym: It was also kind of poorly animated.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: The third movie is like terrible terrible.
Rym: terrible though It's worth watching because it has one funny thing.
Rym: That's not intentionally funny.
Rym: Mm-hmm when the grandpa I'll ruin the movie.
Rym: There's this tree and the grandpa's got to kill the tree because the tree is a thing An axe an axe that'll kill the tree.
Rym: No, he goes and gets his lightsaber a lightsaber to kill a tree.
Scott: when he's an axe Well, he has this.
Rym: don't get me started.
Rym: So he walks over to the tree and the tree's name is Haruna.
Scott: All right, I'm done with this and he'd like he knew the trees.
Rym: It's a long story.
Rym: It's kind of.
Rym: it would have been really cool if they'd done it differently.
Rym: He takes his little sword and he screams her name like harder to and he starts stabs into the tree.
Rym: All right, and then it cuts away and I'm like, oh we had to kill the tree.
Rym: Oh how poignant.
Rym: and the show keeps going for a while.
Rym: it cuts back to him.
Rym: He's still cutting through the tree and he's still screaming Haruna.
Rym: It cuts back to other action minutes later.
Rym: It cuts back to him again.
Rym: He's still cutting through the tree and he's still screaming Haruna.
Rym: Alrighty then it's just silly.
Scott: that sounds pretty silly to me.
Rym: plus the movie plays out as though someone wrote a doujinshi where They wrote themselves into the tenchi universe in order to have sex with tenchi.
Rym: Wow, the movie like the movie is painful to watch.
Scott: Okay, let's talk about tenchi GXP, which I saw the first four episodes of.
Rym: sadly first off This has nothing to do with tenchi.
Rym: They put the name on it and they put the characters in the background to try to make it popular kind of like Gundam see destiny.
Scott: Well, no Gundam see the gun as he does needs a different story actually.
Rym: Yeah, well, they start bringing the main characters back apparently more and more and having and then they become the main characters of the new Show, yeah GXP is like a show that has nothing to do with tenchi.
Rym: But then see that thing that just went by in the back.
Scott: What's the show that everyone knows?
Scott: I guess Naruto or everyone knows Naruto.
Scott: Imagine if I made Naruto XP and all the characters from the original Naruto were in it But they were never actually in the foreground.
Scott: You might see them in the background like just let you know like hiding around like if you're playing an RPG.
Scott: They would be the townsfolk that you can't actually talk to like.
Rym: you'll see Kakashi just like sitting in a chair as the characters walk by and they don't interact at all And then he's gone.
Scott: and you'll see Naruto like jump from one roof to another but you'll never talk to him and he'll never do Anything in the story.
Scott: and it's all about some other characters just who happen to be in the same world Where the characters that you used to know and love still exist But they have nothing to do with it.
Rym: now that alone wouldn't be so bad.
Rym: But the show itself is just ass.
Scott: Yeah, tenchi GXP is ass ass ass ass and all the characters in the original tenchi are in the background.
Rym: Now we didn't put this in the worst list.
Scott: Oh tenchi muyo GXP.
Rym: the reason it's not on the worst list is because the opening I was about to say Nobody's not on the worst list is that the opening song is cool.
Scott: The opening song is really cool and you have something.
Scott: If you have an opening song that's cool.
Scott: You're not the worst anime because they're anime.
Scott: they don't have cool opening songs and they're worser.
Scott: Yeah worser worser That's what they are worser.
Rym: Now harem shows are generally bad.
Rym: I don't like love Hina.
Rym: it's too close to pedophilia for me.
Scott: I actually watched way back in the day the whole first season of love Hina.
Scott: Oh my god You know why I watched it.
Rym: turtles.
Scott: I was waiting for the goddamn turtles to show up.
Rym: the turtles are awesome But that's all that show has.
Scott: all the show has.
Scott: it's why it's not worst.
Rym: It has a turtle like tenchi was a harem show, but it was also clever and funny.
Rym: Love Hina wasn't clever.
Scott: It was always the same thing and he accidentally being perverted getting hit Accidentally being perverted getting hit.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's the whole show.
Rym: get close to a different girl depending on which episode it is.
Rym: There's a different kind of girl for every kind of scary fanboy.
Scott: It's still the main girl that everyone loves and you get with her in the end.
Rym: Yeah, how do people watch this crap?
Scott: because they're perverted.
Scott: They're otaku who can't get any women.
Scott: so they need to fantasize about some anime woman.
Scott: and Since you can't have a different and it's cheaper to make one anime with a woman for every guy Than it is to make eight anime with one each one having the girl for each type of guy Now it is a equal opportunity.
Rym: I mean, it's not just for scary fanboys because there's the show out now mine liebe Which is just the same kind of harem show only for girls.
Rym: It's all these pretty boys.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep Yep.
Scott: Now notice how we haven't mentioned any actual hentai or actual, you know rated X Yeah, we or Yuri.
Rym: We haven't seen any of that crap.
Scott: Yeah, cuz we're not perverted.
Scott: We don't watch Porn anime.
Scott: I mean if I'm gonna look at porn I live real porn first of all and second of all I'm not gonna watch something that has the facade of a plot.
Rym: I Saw part of the blue girl at a con.
Scott: Yeah I think if you're if you're not perverted and you say the only hentai you've seen is the blue girl and you never watch anymore You okay, actually you can watch cutie, honey.
Scott: Also, but any more than that and that's no good.
Rym: now there are a lot.
Rym: I mean, there are some shows that aren't.
Rym: I watched elven bride.
Rym: Yeah, and it's actually kind of funny.
Scott: That's a cut.
Scott: it's an erotic comedy.
Scott: Yes, like sanctuary the manga is an erotic thriller.
Rym: Yeah build as such.
Scott: It's a political erotic thriller, but and it has some nakedness and some sex and stuff, but it's not a porno.
Scott: It's mostly about the plot.
Scott: It's just the plot.
Scott: has people having sex and when they do they show it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean how the bride is actually really kind of funny.
Rym: It's just a. it's a Sex comedy basically.
Scott: Yeah, imagine like dancing penises.
Rym: and happy What Dancing penises?
Rym: a?
Rym: no they are not in because well mostly because Japanese law and such they couldn't show genitalia.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what an anime with dancing penises.
Rym: be high Larry's You know, we could go to the city and see puppetry of the penis.
Scott: You don't want to actually see that.
Rym: I saw a video of much of it.
Scott: That's all you need to say.
Scott: It's actually really funny, but it is really funny, but it's you don't want to pay for it.
Scott: No one see it.
Scott: live that true unless you're you know into that sort of thing.
Rym: But actually the other thing about hentai is it's fun to mock.
Rym: We've never actually been to it.
Rym: But there's this like Dave and Buster's hint funny hentai dubbing the dick and Buster's David Buster's is an arcade slash restaurant.
Rym: Yeah dick and we never actually end up going to it because it's always either full or we have better things to do at cons.
Rym: But many people have told us it's hilarious.
Scott: I don't doubt them that it's hilarious.
Scott: You know, it seems like I Can't really tell what's going on in the anime community with all this hentai stuff because I can't tell if there are a large number of perverts who I should shun and throw out the window or Are there a large number of people who just really enjoy?
Scott: Using hentai as a tool for humor or is it a combination of the two and which side is more heavily favored?
Rym: It's a combination.
Rym: where mo?
Rym: I think many of the people who are very open about liking hentai Very much like it for ironic or comedic value.
Rym: But I think there are a lot of people who like who say they like it for that but actually like it because it arouses them.
Scott: I Think so, too.
Scott: I think the majority say it's 75% You know arousal perverts and 25% Probably with the just humor.
Rym: Yeah There's also the whole yaoi thing among young girls, which seems to be more of a cultural identity than an actual fetish or sexual proclivity.
Scott: Yeah, you don't see.
Scott: I mean at least I don't see You know girls actually getting off on yaoi.
Scott: Well, like in a in a porn sort of way.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: Where would you see that?
Rym: Where would you have the opportunity to see that?
Scott: I Don't know but I need to find out.
Rym: I Think we're about done here are we?
Rym: it's all right.
Rym: We got to play Mario.
Rym: I've the box I just the box is sitting right next to my microphone and I've been staring at it for the whole episode.
Rym: Good job thinking about what I'm going to do in the game.
Scott: No All right, let's see what else.
Scott: is there anything else that makes an anime really terrible beside Bad?
Scott: voice acting always makes it terrible Yeah, but you usually get around that by watching the subs or the dubs, you know, vice-versa.
Scott: Sometimes the Japanese voice acting is terrible.
Rym: Yeah, I this is not a popular opinion But I contend that the American voice acting in the original dub of erasera to beautiful dreamer Which is one of my favorite movies ever is better than the original Japanese voice acting.
Rym: Maybe that's just because you're used to the English But at the same time I've seen them both several times and I think they did a good job with the dub except for one Screwed up part, but that's like how Penn doesn't like Isaac Hayes words and shaft whatever.
Scott: Yeah, of course, you know animation glitches bad animation lack of animation.
Scott: I mean, I'm not a stickler for art but if if you're as bad as say the original transformer series with its glitches of animation or If you're like utana where you have lots and lots of still frames and you just pan across them with the camera.
Rym: Yeah, at least utana had an excuse.
Rym: They had no money and a lot of plot and the fact that the show is good Despite the fact that they had no money to animate it says a lot It does like.
Rym: that show probably would have been much more Popular.
Scott: it would much worse if they had more money because it would more like the movie.
Rym: No, not not because the movie was mostly kuhara's doing.
Scott: that's the point.
Rym: There was.
Scott: no there wasn't so much Chiyo Saito saying hey, you can't do that to my character.
Scott: Yeah, that's her name I remember.
Rym: Yeah, she's awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Hey, let me make this great manga.
Scott: Hey, the scary guy is sitting outside my house.
Scott: What does he want?
Scott: He wants to make an anime of my manga?
Scott: No, he's a scary guy who sits outside my house.
Scott: He's been there for a week fine.
Scott: You can make the goddamn anime But I'm gonna make sure you don't make anything.
Scott: perverted you sicko.
Rym: I think the two of them really worked.
Rym: Well because I the manga is mostly Chiyo Saito and The show is like a mix between the two and the movie is purely kuhara.
Rym: The movie is crazy Cornish crap because he kuhara is a scary dude.
Rym: The manga is good and cute, but it's a normal Jojo, it lacks a certain something you need.
Rym: like Ikuhara added the edge to the anime that made it Just one of my staples one of my favorite shows ever.
Scott: Yeah, the manga on its own might as well just be any other shoujo manga with somewhat magical girl whatnots.
Scott: But the TV show is something else.
Rym: once you add Ikuhara's whoa to it I guess it says you gotta have a little bit of that to make a show good a little bit of edge a little bit Of something a little bit of crazy guy.
Scott: Yeah, but that's what you need to be a good anime Not what you don't need to not be a bad one.
Rym: Don't do what Donnie don't does.
Scott: That's Right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think we're actually done.
Scott: All right, cool.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Tomorrow.
Rym: We'll be talking about the worst people Throughout history.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, we're not gonna.
Scott: we're gonna avoid people who everyone knows about like Hitler and Stalin and stick to the People you don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's not gonna be a comprehensive list because there are a lot of people out there who sucked.
Scott: Oh god, there are so many bad dudes.
Rym: It's mostly gonna be us talking about obscure guys You might not realize how bad they were and explaining why they're bad and why you should hate them.
Rym: One of them has a theme song that I'm going to play a little bit of.
Rym: Now we decided against doing the worst people we currently know or we've known in our lives.
Scott: That's more of a hate first of all, but we don't really hate.
Scott: I guess I don't know.
Rym: No, no, cuz some of these people I would submit are objectively bad.
Rym: Yeah, I'll note that We don't really know any of those people anymore.
Scott: No, we don't.
Rym: we just hear stories about used to know them.
Rym: Yeah, of course we wondered what do we do if those people listen to the show?
Rym: and then we remembered Oh, we won't care and we'll laugh.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I laugh at you and your miserable existence.
Rym: Your music's bad and you should fail bad.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So if anyone noticed, you know in worst week we did with the worst Hardware gadgets the worst game consoles and the video game consoles and the worst anime.
Scott: That means at some point in the future we can have worst weeks two and possibly even three where we do stuff like worst Softwares or yeah worst Worst comics worst comics worst manga or video game worst board games.
Rym: So god, there's only one Hellas.
Scott: Yeah, there are other ones.
Rym: Yeah, but we were smart enough to avoid Monopoly.
Scott: Yeah, Monopoly.
Scott: Okay Yeah, so This might not be the last worst week But this another worst week won't come for a very long time months, perhaps even a year.
Rym: I tried to come up with a joke about bratwurst, but it just didn't come.
Scott: The worst worst.
Rym: I Like worst a lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I think we're done.
Scott: You've said that like three times.
Rym: I know but we keep talking there.
Rym: Grandma baby born on Monday Hayes, I'm gonna leave you with that.
Scott: I'm gonna go play him some Mario.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1 5 3 7.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.