Rym: It's Thursday, January 12th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we begin our ongoing in-depth series on how to attend conventions.
Scott: Let's do this!
Scott: So, today at work, I spent about half my day working on our forums.
Rym: Yeah, people might have noticed because there was a lot of posting going on while you were fiddling with them.
Scott: And if you didn't notice, that's because you're not on our forums and you should be.
Rym: Yeah, the forums are really hopping.
Rym: I mean, we're not just saying that to try to get you to go.
Rym: There's actually a lot of people there posting about the show.
Scott: Yeah, and if you want to, you know, discuss the things we talk about with like-minded people, you should probably go to the forums.
Scott: It's a lot of fun, and the more people, the merrier.
Rym: Plus, we added, well, Scott added, avatars.
Scott: Avatars.
Scott: I think it's a lot better than the PHPBB avatars, which are like, they get really big and they stick out into the page.
Scott: I don't know, I always think that people use way too big ones, and they're not uniform, and they're all kind of ugly.
Scott: The worst?
Rym: Have you ever been on just those unmoderated forums that are out there in the cesspool of the internet?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: The ones that don't have restrictions on like, SIGs?
Rym: I've seen SIGs that were a full 640x480 like, flash animation.
Scott: Yeah, I can't take that stuff.
Scott: So, our avatars just use these cute little 32x32 pixel dealies.
Scott: Other things I added to the forum besides avatars are a few new themes.
Scott: There's a blue theme and a red theme that are new.
Rym: Yeah, we're thinking about putting the blue theme or some derivative of it on the main site.
Scott: Yeah, that way the forum will appear to be seamlessly integrated with the actual site, which could be kind of cool.
Scott: I made the blue theme the default because I think it looks better than the default default theme.
Scott: But if you really want the original default theme, it's still in there and you can switch it in your account settings or whatever.
Rym: Also, due to popular demand, meaning three people complained about this, there is now a link back to the site from the forum.
Scott: Yeah, it might not be obvious, but now in the big white title that says "Front Row Crew Forums" at the top of the page, if you click on that, it'll take you back to frontrowcrew.com, which you should be going to anyway, even if you, you know, get the podcast via some RSS somewhere.
Rym: Even though not that many do, compared to the people who just download the MP3.
Scott: Yeah, but everyone visit frontrowcrew.com and there's actual, like, posts in the blog and other information for you that you should check out.
Scott: And the forum.
Rym: Yep, and regarding that, I just have one quick question.
Rym: Whoever's using Winamp to listen to this, like, straight off the feed, I'm curious how you're doing it.
Rym: Because I look at all my feed statistics every couple days, and of all the different readers that it says, like, contact the RSS and download the files, one of them is Winamp.
Rym: One all alone, and it downloads every single episode.
Scott: Hmm, I wonder.
Rym: Yeah, I was just curious about that.
Scott: Because I don't think Winamp has a podcatcher in it.
Rym: Unless someone made a plugin that does it.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: I don't know, I haven't used Winamp since I switched to Linux.
Scott: I use it, but I only play MP3s in it, and that's it.
Scott: And not often, either.
Rym: I mean, I used to use it for Shoutcast, and I know if you give it a URL of an MP3, it'll just play it, so.
Scott: Another small change I made to the forum.
Scott: You'll notice on the top left, after you sign in, there's a little pull-down menu.
Scott: And you can change the categories in this little menu.
Scott: And that way, if you click on the technology category, then only the technology stories will appear.
Scott: And it's easier than clicking on the categories tab, and then clicking on the category you want.
Scott: You can just use the little pull-down menu.
Scott: It makes it a little easier to use.
Rym: You can see now that there's a lot of discussions going on in there.
Scott: Yeah, now that there's three pages of posts, it's a lot easier to filter out the categories using this pull-down on the side than...
Rym: Now, along with this, we're probably going to add some more categories at some point.
Rym: Because I noticed there aren't that many categories that are useful yet.
Scott: Yeah, we'll add more categories.
Scott: It shouldn't be a problem.
Rym: Yeah, if you have a really burning desire for us to add a specific one, let us know and we'll think about it.
Scott: Or maybe we'll just start a new thread, Category Request Thread.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: The last thing I added is Private Messaging.
Scott: But it's not private messaging like on PHPVB or whatever.
Rym: It's really cool.
Scott: It's much better than that.
Scott: I thought it's called Whispering, actually, which is very appropriate to how it works.
Scott: Basically, when you start a new discussion, you can type in someone's username on the forums.
Scott: And it'll auto-complete the usernames in case you forget them.
Scott: So just start typing a letter and the rest of it will appear.
Scott: You know, like Google Suggest or whatever.
Rym: So I swear to God, if anyone takes the name "Rym" with like a "D" at the end of it, I'll kill you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then, you know, set your subject and type your message and you can start your own private discussion with somebody.
Scott: And the only people who can see it are you and that other person.
Rym: Now, cooler, you can do that within another discussion.
Scott: Right, so let's say me, Rym, Joe Blow, and Joe Schmo are having a discussion about... Anime.
Scott: Anime.
Scott: And Joe Blow and Joe Schmo start having a fanboy rant, right?
Scott: In the middle of that discussion, I can send a whisper to Rym.
Scott: I type in "Rym" when I... I reply to it just like I would reply to any message.
Scott: But in the whisper box, I type "Rym" and I say, "Wow, these two guys are huge
Scott: fanboys.".
Scott: That'll put a message in that discussion, but only me and Rym will see it.
Scott: And those Joe Blow and Joe Schmo won't see it when they go and look at that discussion.
Rym: I guess the technical turn is side-channel communication.
Scott: Yeah, you're literally whispering to one other person in the discussion without anyone else seeing it.
Scott: It's way cool.
Rym: Yeah, play around with the forum.
Rym: And obviously, let us know if you find anything broken.
Rym: We'll fix it right away.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think anything's broken now.
Scott: I've pretty much fixed it all.
Scott: Alright, and since we pushed the forum a little bit too much, let me push the rest of our stuff.
Scott: You can email us feedback.
Scott: Email still works, and, you know, especially if you're not a forum-type person.
Scott: You just want to talk to us or something like that.
Rym: Yeah, because we used to get, you know, not really negative feedback, but constructive criticism.
Rym: And we seem to have addressed all the complaints because they stopped coming in.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, so send emails of any sort, audio feedbacks, you know, or anything like that to geekknights@gmail.com.
Rym: Call our phone number.
Rym: I mean, if you call it and you leave us a message that's even halfway crap, we'll probably play it and then respond to it in some way.
Scott: Yeah, the phone number is, I'm going to put it on the website eventually when I redo the blog part.
Rym: 508-677-0300.
Scott: 508-677-0300.
Rym: So, moving on with the news.
Rym: We talked a lot about the new Mac Intel PCs coming out.
Rym: And now there's a lot of questions as to whether or not they're actually going to be able to run Windows.
Rym: And the short answer is, no one knows.
Scott: The story is, is that right now, PCs with, you know, normal Intel AMD processors, whatever, have a BIOS in them.
Rym: Basic input/output system.
Rym: Right.
Rym: That's all that stuff.
Rym: you see when the computer boots before Windows or Linux starts.
Rym: You know, hit F1 and then there's all these options.
Rym: you don't understand.
Scott: That's all that stuff.
Scott: Basically, Apple doesn't use BIOS.
Scott: Apple uses Open Firmware, which is more advanced by far.
Scott: BIOS is really, really old and crappy.
Scott: It's just so standard and old that we keep using it instead of switching to something new.
Scott: There's something even newer called EFI, which is something Intel invented.
Rym: Extensible Firmware Interface.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They invented that for those Itanium chips, actually.
Rym: Which is, isn't that what's in the MacTiles?
Scott: That is what is in the MacBooks.
Scott: That, with the Intel Duo whatever chips.
Rym: Now this raises a big question because Windows Vista supposedly is going to support this just fine.
Rym: But Windows XP 2000, 98, 311, not a chance.
Scott: Nope, those do not support it.
Scott: However, Windows XP 64-bit edition supposedly does support EFI.
Rym: Of course, that ray of hope is shattered immediately by the fact that these aren't 64-bit processors.
Scott: Yeah, the Intel Core Duo is not a 64-bit processor.
Scott: So, the question is, will somebody, will, you know, Windows 2000 XP might just work.
Scott: We don't even know.
Scott: If they don't work, will somebody create some sort of patch or mod to make them work?
Scott: I say probably yes, definitely.
Scott: Will Linux work?
Scott: Almost certainly.
Scott: But it could be that you just can't run Windows 2000 XP and that you will need to have Windows Vista to run on these Apple Books.
Rym: And keep in mind that it's not 100% that Windows Vista will work.
Rym: Because Phil Schiller, the Apple guy who, the only one who responded to this so far, said that they don't sell or support Windows itself, but at the same time they're not preventing anyone specifically from using Windows.
Rym: So they're not trying to keep Windows off, but they're not trying to make Windows work.
Rym: They're just kind of ignoring it.
Scott: Yeah, so basically it might work, and it's a pretty good bet that it will, but I wouldn't actually put any money down.
Rym: See, I would kind of put money down because I point out two things.
Rym: One, EFI, at least in its raw form, but no one knows if they're going to implement this on these specific boxes, can fully emulate BIOS.
Scott: Oh, see I read something like that somewhere and I was a little confused.
Scott: So it can emulate BIOS.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: However, we don't know if these will do it or if that emulated BIOS will work 100%.
Rym: Because Windows relies on the BIOS more than you'd think.
Rym: Two, the reason I'll bet that any Windows is going to work is that one, Grub works just fine with EFI.
Rym: Two, Grub can boot Windows just fine.
Rym: Case closed.
Rym: Because once Windows boots, it's fine.
Rym: It just has to boot.
Scott: Really?
Scott: It doesn't use the BIOS after it boots?
Rym: Not to the point, basically once you get it booted, as long as the hardware abstraction layer is okay, it's going to work.
Rym: Now the question will be if the old versions of Windows include a hardware abstraction layer that can handle whatever proprietary bits might be in these MacTel boxes.
Scott: Yeah, see that's my question.
Scott: It's something no one seems to be addressing.
Scott: These Macbooks have things like the Express slot.
Scott: They have things like the built-in on-motherboard Wi-Fi and USB.
Scott: No, not USB, Bluetooth.
Scott: That's part of the MacBook.
Scott: They have all kinds of Mac stuff in them.
Scott: Windows has a lot of drivers, but does it have drivers for that stuff?
Scott: Will it work?
Rym: Now I could see Microsoft specifically going out of their way to add all that to Windows Vista.
Rym: Because, hey, they'll make money selling Windows to people who own Mac hardware.
Rym: It's a win for them.
Scott: No, because anyone who's using Windows on Mac hardware totally is not paying for a new copy of Windows.
Rym: I don't know, those people already dropped a couple Gs on a laptop.
Scott: Yeah, but you usually have to shell out $250 for Windows.
Rym: Maybe we'll see discounts or something.
Rym: You never know.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I just really don't think Microsoft wants to sell Apple hardware.
Scott: They want to sell hardware that has Windows on it already.
Rym: Yeah, but consider the markup they make when they actually sell Windows in a box.
Rym: I mean, Dell pays, I think, $30 or $40 for Windows, but it's $300 if you go to the store and buy it in a box.
Scott: I think the store makes most of that money.
Scott: I don't really think Microsoft is raking it in there.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know who buys those.
Rym: I mean, I bought a Windows 2000 box in the year 2000.
Scott: I can only see buying one of those in an absolute drop-dead emergency.
Scott: You absolutely need a valid Windows CD and CD key.
Scott: You can't get one any faster than going to Staples.
Scott: You don't know anyone who's got one.
Scott: You can't pirate one.
Scott: All the internets are real slow.
Rym: I mean, back in the day, when Windows 2000 came out, I built my computer like the week before that, and then I bought Windows 2000 at the store like the next day.
Scott: Oh, alright, yeah.
Rym: And back then, you couldn't pirate it.
Rym: Now you can pirate it.
Scott: I bought Windows 98 SE.
Scott: I had 95B from already, but I got a 98 SE CD just because 95 couldn't play some of the games I was buying.
Rym: You know, I never had any 95 after A.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: I used Windows 95 A, and then I had Windows 2000.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: I had 95B, then I had 98 SE, and then I got 2000 way later.
Scott: And then I got XP for free from school, legally.
Rym: In fact, I remember when you got Windows 2000, or when you first really used Windows 2000, and you, the staunch Microsoft hater, admitted that it was in fact a fairly decent product.
Scott: It was better than Windows 98, is what I said.
Scott: And it is.
Scott: That's about all I said.
Scott: Because Linux still just, I was using Linux, I've been using Linux for like seven years, or even more, I don't know, since high school.
Scott: But it was never good enough to be my 100% of the time operating system until like two or three years ago.
Rym: Yup, because I remember I tried, you gave me a copy of Mandrake, and I tried to install it on this extra computer I had, and it installed, and it was just kind of terrible.
Scott: You know, the thing was, is that like at the time, Mandrake didn't seem terrible because I had been using Red Hat.
Scott: And relative to Red Hat, it was great.
Scott: You know, and it's basically, it wasn't great enough for me to use it all the time, but I also got to think that in college I was playing a lot of PC games, a lot of Steam, a lot of Counter-Strike.
Scott: True.
Scott: So that had a strong effect on it.
Rym: I mean, we would literally come home from class like every day, and then just start playing Counter-Strike for like four hours.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I did use Linux in college for all of my work, and then my last two years I was pretty much using Gentoo only.
Rym: Yeah, I actually, it was weird, but despite the fact that I was in IT, we used Windows a lot more than we used Linux.
Rym: Because most of our labs were Windows like Active Directory, Windows Domain, crap, because all the Linux stuff was kind of easy, and they didn't spend much time on it.
Scott: I had a lab partner do all that, and I did all the Linux stuff.
Rym: See, I was the lab partner who did all the Windows stuff, and then the other guy did all the Linux stuff.
Rym: Of course, now I use Linux exclusively.
Scott: So for my Think of the Day, I got the video that disappeared from Google Video yesterday is back.
Scott: It's basically a video of three guys at a comedy festival singing a song that's kind of funny.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't as funny as I expected anything like that to be, but at least the topic hit close to home.
Scott: Very close.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Watch it.
Rym: So my thing, you know how whenever they bring games over from Japan to America, they always Romanize them or localize them?
Rym: Like, they'll change the cover, they'll change translation things, they'll take out the cultural jokes that Americans wouldn't get, they'll make the game easier, you know, that sort of thing.
Rym: Well, here's a site that shows the opposite, what they do to games that come from America to Japan.
Rym: And they do a lot of the same things.
Scott: Well, the biggest thing it shows is the changing of the cover art of the packaging.
Rym: Which was a lot more than you'd expect for some games.
Scott: The biggest one, I think, was this, uh, what was the name of the game, like, Seduki or something like that?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yo, some RPG.
Scott: Some RPG.
Scott: But the American cover had, like, this hot CG, obviously CG babe on it.
Scott: And the Japanese cover had this hand- well, looked like hand-drawn, anime-style RPG-looking character of the same babe.
Rym: Who I thought was a lot more attractive.
Scott: I thought it was very much a better looking cover.
Scott: Most of the Japanese covers, I think, were either equal but different to the American covers, or just better looking with brighter colors and they were happier.
Scott: I think the biggest example was the Ratchet and Clank ones.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because the American ones were these crappy CG, like you see on the front of every stupid third-party game for every system ever.
Rym: And in Japan, there were these funny, anime-type drawings.
Scott: Yeah, and in the American covers, there were, like, these angry guys.
Scott: It was an angry cat guy.
Scott: I don't know what he is, but he's an angry guy.
Scott: He's angry.
Rym: He's angry with a gun.
Scott: But on the Japanese cover, he's, like, smiling and he's like,
Scott: "Weeeee!".
Rym: Same game in Japan, happy soldiers chilling on a beach.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And even though it's the same exact game when you actually play it, except, of course, for the translation, you know, it's 99% the same game.
Scott: But they changed the cover so much because, you know, I guess what appeals to the different cultures and different sides of the ocean.
Scott: But the Japanese covers actually appeal more to me than the American ones do.
Rym: I find that interesting, but I note that our taste in games seems to vary greatly from that of most mainstream gamers in America.
Rym: We're like the old-school Nintendo-Japan types.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I do think, though, that they greatly underestimate how big those types of Japanese games would sell here, and they should really bring more of them over.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think they'd appeal to a wide audience, but I think the audience they do appeal to, namely people like us or people who listen to the show or people who go to, like, anime cons, you know, us types, I think we would more than make up for that.
Scott: We would definitely make up for it.
Scott: And, you know, you just don't have to print so many of them.
Scott: I keep saying this.
Scott: Katamari came over.
Scott: They only printed, like, a few copies per store.
Rym: And yet, I mean, you all know I've talked about my coworkers in my office periodically, and to say that they're fuddy-duddies, and I hate using that word, it's kind of an understatement.
Rym: They all know what Katamari is and love it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, all those other things that are like Katamari that you're keeping from us, Japan, send them on over ASAP.
Scott: Alright, so, yeah.
Rym: So, we decided to start another ongoing series.
Scott: Well, it might just be a two-parter, I'm betting.
Rym: At least a two-parter.
Rym: We could possibly stretch into three, because this is a subject we could rant on a lot for a number of reasons.
Rym: But basically, conventions.
Rym: Anime cons, gaming cons, trade conventions, Linux conventions, all sorts of conventions.
Scott: It's convention season starting about now, I think.
Scott: OhioCon just happened, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And it's not too long until KatsuCon.
Scott: So, we're gonna prep you all, especially those people who, if you haven't been to a convention, you're thinking about going.
Scott: If you haven't been to a convention not thinking about going, maybe you'll think about going, because you should.
Scott: Maybe you're a convention veteran, and, you know, it doesn't matter.
Rym: Now, I hope we don't sound like condescending, or like we're explaining this stupidly, but I guess, to put it lightly, we've been to a lot of conventions.
Scott: We're, what you could say, grandmasters of convention skills.
Rym: I mean, we're not the old man who has 40 Otakon badges.
Scott: That guy's scary, oh my god.
Rym: Yeah, that guy has like, he wears this armor of badges from all the cons.
Scott: I don't think he wears it anymore, but I recognize the guy, and I still see him there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But, the main reason that we want to do this is that we have a lot of friends, and like all of us go to conventions.
Rym: Like, we go to Otakon, you know, 22,000 geeks, and we run into a lot of people we know.
Rym: And it seems like almost every other group of people we run into has some sort of drama, or problems, or they had issues with the convention, and it made it a less fun experience overall for them.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much anyone I meet, even like just hearing complete strangers talk to each other, I just hear a lot of people with some sort of problem, or someone will complain about a convention sucking, and they might even recognize that it was their fault.
Scott: But it was still, they could have had a better time, but they didn't, because they didn't do something, or they didn't know something that I knew, and could do, and could have told them to do.
Rym: And, I mean, the main thing is, it started out, we start, we're like, we go to a convention, just a few of us in a room, and every year, some of the people who had drama would decide, hey, we want to stay with Rym and Scott, because their room is awesome, and they don't have trouble.
Rym: So, every year we've had more and more people stay with us, and for like this coming Otakon, I've already got three whole rooms booked in the Renaissance just for us.
Rym: And we've had people, like we had a group of people ask us after the last Otakon, hey, can we stay with you guys, because it sucked last year staying with these other people.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, I guess all I'm trying to say is we know what we're talking about when it comes to this.
Rym: We may not know about viruses, Pete and Lisa and all you people in the forums.
Scott: Yeah, we know about conventions.
Scott: We are convention experts.
Scott: So, the first thing you have to know about a convention is, should you go to it or not?
Rym: And, a lot of people really don't, like they say, oh, I want to go to a convention, but they don't really think about what they would actually do at it.
Scott: Yeah, the first thing I look at when I'm looking at a convention is location and guests.
Rym: Mostly location, because the number of hours it takes you to get to a con is really going to affect whether or not it's worth it to go.
Rym: I mean, driving an hour to a crappy con is not as bad as driving nine hours to a crappy con.
Scott: If this is a convention less than an hour away, it really doesn't matter how crappy it is, even if it's as bad as it could possibly be, it's probably worth going.
Scott: Just because, you know, you'll get something out of it.
Rym: Because when we lived in Rochester, I used to do a lot of work with the anime club where we'd go and like show anime at other cons in the area.
Rym: So, we'd go to these little gaming cons and sci-fi cons like Astronomicon and Unicon, and they weren't the greatest cons.
Rym: They were kind of small, but they were like 40 minutes away and it was a lot of fun.
Scott: But if those were like two hours away, not a chance.
Scott: But meanwhile, something like PAX almost has enough draw to get me to cross the entire country to go to it.
Rym: Yeah, if we had had money, we probably would have gone this year.
Scott: Yeah, we seriously considered going all the way to Seattle from New York.
Rym: Just to hang out with a bunch of nerds and geeks for a weekend.
Scott: Yeah, because their convention was going to be so amazing.
Scott: I mean, look at the concert they had lined up.
Scott: Damn, mini bosses, MC Frontline, holy crap.
Rym: Now, if you've never been to a con before, you really want to pay attention to what's going on at the con.
Rym: Because for someone who's never been to one before, you want to do all the stuff.
Rym: So what matters the most usually is what stuff there is to do.
Rym: But if you start going to them a lot, to the point that you've done all the stuff there is, you really don't care what the convention's doing.
Rym: You just go because it's an excuse to hang out with your friends in this unique setting and meet new people.
Scott: That's pretty much how it is.
Scott: I mean, once you've seen one cosplay, you've seen them all.
Scott: And once you've seen one music video contest, you've seen them all.
Scott: And once you, you know, had one Giant Land party, you played them all.
Scott: And sure, it might still be fun to do it again, but it's not, it's like once you, when you go to your first convention, all you want to do is do all these things you've never done before.
Scott: And then after a few cons, you're like, "I done all that," and you're looking for something new, but there won't be anything new.
Scott: The only way to get something new is to go to a different type of convention, but eventually you run out of those too.
Rym: So don't be the person who goes to, like, their ninth Otakon and sits in the room all alone complaining that there's nothing cool to do.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta, you know, you start out doing all the cool things, but then it's still cool.
Scott: Some people, a lot of people just stop going to them, they've noticed.
Scott: But we keep going because, you know, we make our own fun, you know?
Scott: I mean, Nintendo DS helped a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean, quite literally, we go to Otakon every year, and we do almost nothing at the con.
Rym: We barely, I mean, we don't go in any panels.
Scott: I think we went to one panel.
Rym: Yeah, and then I ran that one panel.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And we watch, like, we watch one closing ceremonies type thing.
Scott: I spent more time in the live-action Asian cinema room than any other single room.
Scott: Like, I might have spent equal time there and the dealer's room.
Rym: I spent most of my time just hanging out.
Scott: Oh yeah, I was hanging out, oh, most of the time total for the whole weekend, hanging out.
Scott: But most of the time at con events was, you know, dealer's room and that room.
Scott: You know, it's, and, but newbies, they go to every single freaky panel, and they go to every single, you know, all this, you know, wacky stuff.
Scott: That, I guess, gets old pretty quick.
Rym: So I guess just think about what you want out of the con, and then see if the con will provide it.
Rym: I mean, if you want to see the biggest gathering of geeks in all the world, go to Otakon.
Rym: Because Otakon, while it's an anime convention, is the closest thing to a pan-geek convention you'll ever find.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: If you want gaming, find a gaming convention, because it'll be nothing but playing games with cool people all night long.
Rym: I'm a big fan of UberCon.
Rym: I go to.
Rym: I used to go to Michicon, but I don't live in Michigan anymore.
Rym: I went to GenCon once, and if you can ever get to GenCon and you're a gamer, try it.
Rym: But if you're not really into games, GenCon's not worth it.
Scott: There's also a con I just discovered recently called Essen in Essen, Germany.
Scott: And that's the pinnacle of German board game.
Scott: amazingness that I will go to probably once in my life just to go.
Rym: Yeah, I'd love to hit that.
Scott: I think I'll just have a trip to, you know, Europe and just happen to have it while Essen is going on.
Scott: You know, it's not really worth it to go to Essen, from all this way across the world, but it is worth, you know, if you're on a trip from Europe, you know, why not?
Rym: Now, what we're talking about really applies to all cons, but almost all of our examples are going to come from anime conventions, just because those are what we go to the most.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I go to gaming conventions, Scott doesn't so much, but they're almost the same.
Rym: Trade conventions are a little different, but don't worry about that.
Scott: I've been to a lot of trade conventions, actually, in the food and technology related areas, and job related areas, so I can talk about those a little bit.
Scott: But they're sort of a different beast, because they're not about entertainment, they're about someone trying to sell you something.
Scott: So you're basically just walking around to booths looking at products and services and people advertising to you.
Rym: Yeah, you're not going to run into, like, a gaggle of cosplayers with DSs, like, running to a DDR tournament at a thing like that.
Scott: No, you're not.
Rym: And, actually, we went to one Linux convention, called Pinguacon, in Novi, Michigan, and I gotta say, that was fairly badass.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think any other--from what I can tell based on the website and who's been to these things and the kind of events they've had, I don't think that any other instance of Pinguacon has lived up to the one we went to, so I'm really glad we went when we did.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I don't know what it was with that one Pinguacon, but we hit solid gold.
Rym: Neil Gaiman was there and told us a story.
Rym: That I slept through.
Rym: Scott fell asleep while he was telling it.
Rym: Oh god.
Scott: It was a cool-- It was so sad.
Rym: It was a cool Detective Cthulhu story, too.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, he said, "Alright, I'm going to tell you a cool Detective Cthulhu story,".
Scott: and I'm like,
Scott: "Alright!".
Scott: And then he's like, "I tried to tell this story at another con, and I didn't finish.
Scott: We're going to see how many minutes it takes to tell this story.
Scott: I'm going to finish it no matter
Scott: what.".
Scott: So I'm like,
Scott: "Alright!".
Scott: Then I start hearing the beginning of the story, and I'm like,
Scott: And then I fell asleep.
Scott: And then when I woke up, and he's like, "Well, it takes exactly 40-something minutes to read that story," and I said,
Scott: "Fuck!".
Rym: "Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck,
Rym: fuck!".
Rym: Plus, it was just, it was weird, because also, Steve Jackson was there, and he wanted to play a board game with us.
Scott: Yeah, and I didn't even realize it was him.
Scott: Like, we were just playing Puerto Rico in the lobby, and this kind of scruffy guy walks up, and he's like, "Hey, I kind of want to play that,".
Scott: and I'm like, "Alright, maybe we'll hook up later,".
Scott: you know, whatever.
Scott: And then our friend-- Someone comes over like a minute later, they were like, "Dude, that was Steve Jackson,".
Scott: and I'm like, "No way.
Scott: What are you talking
Scott: about?".
Rym: And then we go to a panel, and there's Steve Jackson talking about Steve Jackson games.
Scott: I'm like, "Oh,
Scott: shite!".
Scott: But then for a geek fable, we'll tell later, because of that fable, we didn't actually play with him.
Rym: Yeah, we could've.
Rym: We were all set to do it, but something happened.
Scott: Well, that's a geek fable for another time.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Scott: So, once you decide if you're going to go to any particular convention, you have to decide who you're going to take with you.
Rym: This is probably the single most important decision you can make.
Rym: One bad person in your group of people going to a con can ruin it.
Scott: And, you know, there are things you can do.
Scott: if you happen to take a bad person, or, you know, someone might turn bad.
Scott: Like, someone who might be a good person, like, might get sick or something.
Scott: No matter how bad it makes you feel, you have to drop that person like a rock.
Rym: Yeah, not to sound cold-hearted, but if someone's dragging you down, cast them away.
Rym: Because there are some people who go to a convention and, for whatever reason, just can't handle it.
Rym: And they're probably not trying to make you have a bad time, but they're going to make you have a bad time.
Rym: There's nothing you can do about it except to leave them alone in the room.
Scott: Yeah, you're spending a lot of time and a lot of money to go to a convention, you know, no matter which one it is.
Scott: Even if it's, like, ten minutes away from your house and it costs five bucks to get in, if you're spending more than, like, a day there, you know, or even if you're only spending a day, you don't want that one day ruined, you know?
Rym: I mean, I went to--Scott missed this one, but I went to Anime Central with a bunch of my friends, and we always threw crazy parties there, because we had another friend who got the Presidential Suite.
Rym: And we had, like, it was expected that we had a crazy party.
Rym: And me and my friend Luke, we would, like, tend this non-alcoholic anime-themed bar, because the room had a frickin' bar in it.
Rym: So we made funny drinks like the Southern Belle Dandy, you know, stuff like that.
Rym: It was cool.
Rym: But we're getting ready to set up for the party, and there's a guy asleep in the little bar area.
Rym: And we try to move him, and he got all mad, and he was trying to explain that he needed sleep and he was tired and he was sick, and blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: So you guys can't have a party, 'cause I need to sleep.
Rym: Well, guess who slept in the hallway while the rest of us had a party?
Scott: Yeah, you know, not that, you know, I can't, I can understand where the guy's coming from, because if I was sleepy and sick, I would feel the same way and probably make the same blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: But at the same time, you know, Akan is the time of ultimate fun, and no one should have to suffer except for the person who is, you know, doing badly.
Rym: I mean, in terms of ultimate fun, basically the way we schedule Otakan, which is like the pinnacle of our year when it comes to the convention season, it's like there's all these little cons that lead up to Otakan.
Rym: Then we usually spend the entire week after it at one of our good friend's beach houses recovering from the freaking convention.
Rym: Like the day after the con, we pretty much just pass out for the whole day.
Scott: So, when deciding who to take with you to a convention, you wanna bring with you people who are reliable, they're going to pay, whatever, you know, the cost is, and they're not going to be an anchor that drags you down and makes things unfun for others.
Rym: Be especially wary of couples that are going through the throes of breakup.
Scott: Mmm, very dangerous.
Rym: Yes, generally unstable people, you know, people who just, like Scott said, unreliable people.
Scott: But, at the same time, bring as many people as possible.
Scott: The more you bring, the cheaper it will be, and at the same time, if you have a ton of quality people, that's how you get awesome, awesome parties and awesome craziness going on.
Rym: I mean, this year we brought, what, 15 people, 16 people with us?
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And across two rooms, we had like 16 people, and then we had like 20 other people scattered in other rooms.
Rym: We had like this giant posse of doom.
Rym: Mmm, giant posse.
Rym: Some people in the other peripheral groups had some drama, which we'll probably tell that story at some point, either today or next Thursday.
Scott: Mmm, oh, that story, okay.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of stories, because all our friends have drama, and we- This is why conventions are so great, because that's where you get all the stories from.
Rym: Yeah, I'd say more than half of our stories are from conventions.
Scott: And thinking about conventions, think about how much time we spend at conventions compared to time not at conventions.
Scott: The fact that there's more stories there than anywhere else, that just shows you why conventions are so awesome.
Rym: I mean, I guess if you've never been to a convention, the main thing about them is that, like, look at your normal life.
Rym: You probably know a bunch of geeks around you, but not that many.
Rym: And there's a lot of normal people in the way.
Rym: Imagine if you were in a small town for a weekend, and the only people there were geeks.
Rym: The only people there were cool people who are a lot like you and have similar interests, and you can just geek and yell and scream and dress up and do crazy things with no one caring.
Scott: Mmm, that's what it is.
Scott: That's what it is.
Scott: And that's why you can't let anyone drag you down.
Scott: And if you're someone trying to drag others down, just cut it out.
Scott: I mean, if you're not having a good time, you're upset.
Scott: If you're trying to bring other people down, you're the asshole, not the people saying "get away from me" and not being sympathetic.
Rym: Because we've had both types.
Rym: I mean, we had a friend once who came to a convention, she was having a really good time, but she actually got sick.
Scott: Actually.
Rym: And there was no fault of her own, she was sick.
Scott: And we did feel bad.
Rym: But she did the right thing.
Rym: There was nothing we could do to help her, so she stayed in the room and recuperated, and we brought her food occasionally and made sure she was doing okay.
Rym: But she went out of her way to make sure that while she was sick, she didn't hurt anyone else along the process.
Scott: And that's the way to do things at a con.
Rym: Yep, which brings back to bring quality people.
Rym: If your friends are quality, they won't screw you just because they're having a bad day.
Scott: Alright, the next thing you gotta worry about at a con is registration.
Rym: Yeah, now, basically it used to be the conventional wisdom, and this is like only three years ago, if that, where you didn't want to pre-register.
Rym: Because often the pre-registration line was slower and longer.
Rym: Now, at least for anime conventions, this is not the case.
Rym: And in fact, many of the big anime conventions sell out.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Otakon sold out this year.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I voted NekoCon.
Rym: KatsuCon, it almost sold out.
Rym: I don't know if it actually did sell out.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: A lot of cons are having caps on their registration because they're selling out.
Scott: So, pretty much if you don't pre-register, you're not, you're gonna have a very hard time getting in.
Scott: And a lot of them have things like Thursday registration, where if you pre-register, then you can get your badge on Thursday, which is a great idea, even though you have to pay one more night in a hotel.
Scott: You spend that many more hours having fun at the con.
Scott: It's totally worth it.
Scott: But you have to really, with registration, you have to consider two things.
Scott: Pre-registration usually gets you a discount.
Scott: You have to look at how big that discount is versus how much money you have.
Scott: You know, if it's really significant to get that pre-registration discount, go for it.
Scott: The second thing is how big the con is.
Scott: If the con is crazy huge, pre-registration's probably a good idea.
Scott: If the con is a little local con with, like, less than a thousand people or so, it doesn't really matter.
Scott: You just show up and you pay.
Scott: Who cares?
Scott: No one really does.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: And just make sure you do register.
Scott: A lot of people, if you screw up registration, you could end up taking a long trip to nowhere.
Scott: That's never good.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And in terms of registration, think about money, because this all costs money, and you're gonna have to, if you run out of money, it's bad.
Rym: Because we actually ran out of money at a convention once.
Scott: That's pretty much the worst thing that can happen.
Rym: Yeah, the first Otakon we went to, we didn't really know what to expect, because our first convention, our first anime convention, was OhioCon.
Rym: And while I've heard OhioCon is a lot better now and is fairly awesome, when we went, this was like the worst convention ever.
Scott: It was the first convention, anime convention I went to.
Rym: Yeah, it was the first anime con I'd ever gone to, too.
Rym: And we went with a bunch of people.
Scott: I think it was the second OhioCon ever.
Rym: It was.
Rym: And it's really hard to describe without going into excruciating, painful detail why it was so bad.
Scott: We'll talk about it later.
Rym: Yeah, we'll do a whole show on that OhioCon.
Scott: Yeah, but let's just say that it wasn't the greatest experience.
Rym: So when we decided to go to Otakon, we didn't know what to expect.
Rym: We didn't think that Otakon would be as insane as it was.
Rym: We had no idea.
Rym: And we show up, and I spent like, I had like $60 with me after the hotel, and I paid my $50 for a registration, and I had $10 with which to live the entire weekend and cover gas home.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We drove home without the air conditioning on to make sure we had enough gas.
Scott: Oh, is that the one where I got lost in the woods?
Rym: Yeah, I fell asleep in the back of the car and you were driving, and then I woke up and you guys were in like the middle of the woods with an empty tank of gas and no lights, no street signs.
Scott: That was great.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: See, what did I tell you?
Rym: We have so many stories just because of these conventions.
Scott: Anyway, the next thing is transportation to the con.
Scott: Transportation is real tricky.
Scott: If you live, I'd say more than five hours away, look into trains and planes.
Scott: If you can't afford trains and planes, you might want to reconsider going to this convention unless it's crazy huge and crazy awesome.
Rym: Yes, I mean people literally drive and fly and train from all over the world to Otakon.
Rym: They don't come from all over the world to like Michicon.
Rym: So if you're flying eight hours to Michicon to see like 200 other people, you probably made a mistake.
Scott: But just when you consider the distances, don't drive if it's too far because really no convention is worth the pain of that driving.
Rym: Well, honestly, the furthest I've ever driven for a convention is.
Rym: I drove from Rochester, New York to Chicago for Anime Central.
Scott: That's not so bad.
Rym: It took 12 hours because the car broke down on the way.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much the limit.
Scott: And the con has to be pretty big to get you to do that.
Rym: Yep, it was well worth it.
Rym: We're going to do a whole show on stories from cons because I just realized how many I have.
Scott: Yeah, I think we could probably do a whole bunch of shows on stories from cons.
Rym: Now, if you're going to take a train, and this really only applies to people in the Northeast Corridor and Amtrak, because in the rest of the country, as far as I'm concerned, Amtrak does not exist.
Scott: It does.
Scott: It's just slow and random.
Rym: It's not worth it unless you live in the Northeast, like pretty much anywhere around D.C.
Rym: or the New York area or Pennsylvania.
Rym: Amtrak's fine.
Rym: Anywhere else, no.
Scott: Well, you know, you might want to check it because sometimes you'll get lucky and there will happen to be a train that does exactly what you need, like Florida to, I don't know, somewhere.
Scott: You know, like North Carolina or something like that.
Scott: Because there are trains that do that.
Scott: But just check and if there isn't a train that's like perfect, don't even bother.
Rym: But the main thing with trains is to book, well one, look at the websites constantly and book like seriously six or seven months in advance.
Rym: Because the next time we went to ASEN, we decided driving is stupid.
Rym: We're going to take Amtrak.
Rym: And we took a 12 hour Amtrak.
Rym: But it was only like 60 bucks because we got some crazy deal.
Rym: If you don't get a crazy deal like that, you might be better off flying or driving.
Rym: Flying is always real tricky because for a convention, you usually bring a lot of stuff with you and bring even more stuff back with you.
Rym: And the conventions are never actually near an airport.
Scott: One thing to note is that Otakon kind of is okay to fly to because they have a post office at the con and you just mail things to yourself.
Scott: So instead of carrying them home on the plane, you just mail your stuff home and then get on the plane with whatever you want.
Scott: But that's very, very, very rare.
Scott: And Otakon is the only con I know of that has that.
Scott: So don't fly to a con with a bunch of crap if it's not really, really worth it.
Rym: Driving is your best bet because you really want to bring a lot of extra stuff to the con just in case.
Rym: Extra pillows, extra blankets, extra towels, which we'll get into when we talk about how to overstuff a hotel room.
Scott: Oh god.
Scott: I think that's next.
Rym: Yup, yup.
Rym: But transportation, most people drive to cons.
Rym: And there are a number of things to be aware of.
Rym: First of all, once again talking about reliable people, be real wary of who you're driving with and whether or not they're prepared to go.
Scott: You gotta make sure, number one, perfect directions.
Scott: If your directions aren't flawless, I wouldn't get in a car with someone who wasn't 100% sure they knew exactly where they were going.
Rym: I mean if you're going in a carpool, make one person the directions person.
Rym: And they give everyone the same directions and there's a cell phone in every car.
Scott: And make that person responsible.
Scott: So if anyone gets lost, make sure you know who to blame when things go wrong.
Scott: If the directions are bad, make sure you give that person what for.
Rym: Because when we plan conventions, I guess part of the reason we have such success and a lot of our friends have had trouble is that we actually sit down and plan.
Rym: Pen and paper specifically, duties are assigned and responsibilities and blames are laid.
Rym: Like we have a thing we always say, like Scott says he's going to do something.
Rym: I say, "Alright Scott, that's all
Rym: you.".
Rym: We're serious about that.
Rym: That means whatever consequences come of Scott's action, they are his to deal with and his to take blame for.
Scott: It's basically like, "Alright, you can try that crazy thing, but I don't have confidence in it so you're taking full responsibility if you want to go for
Scott: it.".
Scott: That's what all you means.
Scott: So when someone says all you, a lot of times you're just dissuaded from even doing it at all.
Scott: Of course it's great when you do it and it works and the other person does it.
Rym: Now regarding that, I highly recommend that you don't try to caravan a bunch of cars together.
Scott: That's a very, very bad idea.
Rym: Now there are a number of reasons for that.
Rym: One, I have an anecdote that is fairly detailed and gives you a good picture of exactly what can go wrong.
Scott: I think telling the anecdote actually just gives all the stuff we want to say.
Rym: Yeah, so basically we were going to Otakon.
Rym: It was the first Otakon we went to.
Rym: Yeah, it was the first one.
Rym: And this con, because the hotel screwed off, it was just a disaster from the start.
Rym: But we were going to drive on our own.
Rym: Everyone was going to meet us at the hotel room that we all had and we decided that, "Alright, we'll all go on our
Rym: own.".
Rym: But a bunch of our friends said, "No, we should carpool together.
Rym: It'll be fun.
Rym: We'll stop on the road and we'll hang out and blah blah
Rym: blah.".
Rym: So we agreed that, "Alright, fine.
Rym: We're going to leave at X time.
Rym: You can follow us if you want, but once again I'll note that I
Rym: speed.".
Rym: And when I say I speed, I speed.
Rym: I mean, I quite literally go about 100 miles an hour in the left lane as fast as I can go down the entirety of a freeway.
Scott: Now, a lot of people, whatever you want to say about speeding, we can talk about that in another podcast because we're going to put you down so fast.
Scott: The point is, is that every minute you're saving by speeding, going 100 miles an hour or more, is another minute at the con.
Scott: And the ticket is worth it.
Scott: Especially, you know, it doesn't matter.
Rym: I mean, it really adds up because I used to drive a lot between Detroit and Rochester and if I sped, I'd make it in about four hours.
Rym: If I drove the speed limit, it took about seven hours.
Scott: Three hours is worth a lot of my...
Rym: Yeah, especially when you're only going somewhere for a weekend.
Scott: Yeah, definitely.
Scott: So, whatever.
Rym: They say, "Alright,
Rym: fine.".
Rym: I said, "Alright, we're leaving at 6, 6
Rym: AM.".
Rym: And they're like, "Alright, meet us at our house and then we'll
Rym: go.".
Rym: So we show up at their house at 6 AM, ready to go.
Rym: We expect them to get in their car and come with us.
Rym: Not only are they not awake, but they have not packed.
Scott: Great.
Rym: That was awesome.
Rym: So, you know, being reasonable people, we waited and that was our first mistake.
Rym: We should have cut loose immediately.
Scott: We should have just said, "Oh, you're not ready.
Scott: We thought you'd be ready at 6 and you're not.
Scott: Well, see
Scott: ya.".
Scott: Boom.
Scott: That's what we should have done.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Just remember this.
Rym: Whenever there's a problem, unless you have a reason to help the person, like they're your good friend or you screwed up, like it's your fault that they're having a problem and not their own fault.
Rym: Yep, yep, yep.
Rym: But if it's their own fault and they're going to detract from the con, you really got to cut loose.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So we waited and they finally get all their stuff together and then one of them decides to lead us to the freeway.
Rym: Well, he didn't know how to get to the freeway and led us in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: Great.
Rym: So I passed all of them, flashed my Brights and my Flashers and followed me and I took everyone to the freeway and then we're going.
Rym: So we're on the freeway.
Rym: I get up to about 75 and one of them calls us.
Rym: Slow down.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We're probably not going to slow down.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So we slowed down a little, but we kept inching up and they eventually followed us around 75.
Rym: Even though I really wanted to be going about 100, but they wouldn't follow and whatever.
Rym: So then finally, we're about an hour and a half on the road and all of us have to pee.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So we decide to stop and pee.
Scott: Stopping and peeing is okay, but make it quick.
Scott: Stop at the rest stop, go and pee, get out.
Rym: So while we're stopped and peeing, people in the other cars decide they want to stop at this little diner there and eat breakfast.
Scott: It's not even like a diner that I would eat at ever.
Scott: It was like a trucker diner.
Scott: It was kind of scary.
Rym: Yeah, but two, it's real important to remember that you really shouldn't stop on your way to a convention.
Scott: Unless you absolutely have to.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean, don't stop and eat breakfast on the way because you're much better off getting to the con and then hanging out with a bunch of people and eating breakfast or lunch with them.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, if you're really, if you're going early in the morning, which is what you're probably going to do because you're going to take the day off work, you pack the night before, you wake up at the crack of dawn.
Scott: If you need food, eat a breakfast at home or go to a diner like right in your hometown, then get in the car, get on the highway and go and do not stop until you get there.
Scott: And then once you're there and you get into the hotel and all that nice stuff, then you can go eat and hang out with people.
Scott: You know, it's a lot more fun than eating with people on the road in some crummy place.
Rym: So the three cars are at this diner and they all say they want to eat.
Rym: So there are three of us in my car and we all agree that, all right, we're cutting the rope.
Rym: Goodbye.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: You have the directions.
Rym: We get back on the road.
Rym: They are all pissed at us.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: That's fine.
Scott: We ended up getting there.
Rym: Three hours before them.
Scott: Three hours.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Those were convention hours because it was a Friday, right?
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So we ended up getting three more hours of convention than they did.
Scott: They pretty much didn't get any convention whatsoever on Friday.
Rym: Because we got there at noon.
Rym: We checked into the hotel, which is a whole other story because the hotel was almost a disaster.
Scott: Yeah, we'll tell that story another time.
Rym: Yes, but we check into the hotel and then a bunch of our friends who are already in town call us and we all got together and got like breakfast, lunch at a bagel place and hung out and got our badges and had a good time for three hours.
Rym: And then they showed up three hours later, miserable and hungry and tired and they'd missed the con and they hadn't had their food yet and they didn't have their badges or anything.
Scott: And being illogical, they blamed it on us.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Don't blame your own failings on someone else.
Scott: I mean, you know, while we might feel sorry for you that, you know, yeah, you didn't have a fun time and that sucks.
Scott: It's not our fault that you didn't have a fun time.
Scott: It's your fault and we're not going to let you drag us down, you know.
Scott: Yeah, this dragging down thing, I think we've pretty much hammered it in.
Rym: Yeah, but we see it happen to so many people.
Rym: I mean, we've got some friends who when they hear this, they're probably going to call in and be like, oh, this happened to me, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: And they'll tell you a story that's even worse than the ones we've been telling.
Scott: Yeah, I've heard stories about people going to cons with like people from school or with different groups.
Rym: We're talking like fistfights in the rooms, molestations, money and food and jewelry being stolen, hotels not having the rooms because the person didn't actually get the reservations, people getting lost and actually not making it to the con.
Scott: Yeah, don't let anyone drag you down.
Scott: I think we've hammered it in.
Rym: That's pretty much the primary lesson here.
Scott: The next thing is your hotel.
Scott: Now, you're going to want to, depending on where the con is and how full it's going to be, you have to get the hotel well enough in advance to make sure you actually get a room.
Rym: Now, for Otakon, Katsu, not so much KatsuCon, but for Otakon, Anime Central and Anime Boston and NekoCon, I'm not kidding when I say that six months in advance is probably the latest.
Rym: you want to think about this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now, for a hotel, you're going to want to look at price.
Scott: You're going to want to look at proximity to the con.
Scott: If it's far away from the con, it's probably not the greatest idea because you won't be able to easily walk back and forth in case you really have stuff that you need to move around or you suddenly need to change clothes or maybe you're a big cosplayer, you want to change your costumes and stuff.
Rym: Well, it depends on what kind of con it is too because some cons run 24/7 and some cons don't.
Rym: And two, a lot of people use the logic of vacations where you pick the crappiest, cheapest hotel room because all you're going to do is sleep in it.
Rym: But honestly, at cons, despite how much fun you're having, you're going to go back to the room more often than you think to just chill with people.
Rym: And you really want the room to not be a cesspool.
Scott: The other thing is, hotels will always tell you this room has an occupancy of blah, alright?
Scott: Basically, while you can get in trouble for breaking that rule, lie to the hotel and tell them you have whatever the maximum occupancy is.
Scott: So if it's a four people room with a double bed, say you have four people.
Scott: Just tell them that.
Scott: But bring as many people as you can fit in there comfortably and divide the price among you.
Rym: Now, it really depends on the hotel.
Rym: Like, the Renaissance Hotel in Baltimore, where we usually stay, I'm not kidding when I say that their normal room can comfortably sleep eight.
Rym: And it can sleep ten if you're a little younger and a little spryer.
Rym: And one big trick is that if you've got a lot of people, instead of getting a suite, get two rooms and ask for them to be adjoining.
Rym: And you can open the little door between the two rooms.
Rym: You wouldn't believe how much more space that actually ends up giving you.
Scott: It's great.
Scott: You can even get, like, three rooms adjoining.
Rym: That's what we did for this coming Otakon.
Rym: We have three rooms adjoining.
Rym: It's gonna be nuts.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now, if it's a smaller con than Otakon, usually they're cons in hotels.
Scott: You're probably gonna want a room in that hotel because then you can keep going back to it all the time and you can do all sorts of crazy stuff.
Rym: But at the same time, you can cram more people into the room because a lot of people are probably gonna spend all night hanging out in the con.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And, you know, like at Otakon, you pretty much have to leave the con, go back to your hotel, and sleep at night.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: For the cons with the hotel room in the con, usually your hotel room turns into a party room at night.
Scott: There isn't a lot of sleeping going on.
Scott: It just turns into, like, a stuffed storage bin.
Scott: So you don't need to get as big a room when you have something like that.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Though if you actually want to throw a party in your room, like, not just people are hanging out, but we are having a party.
Scott: Public, you know, with public admittance.
Rym: We're gonna do a separate bid on that another day because we've done it many times and we can tell you exactly how to do it.
Rym: And let me just say that it is not for the faint of hearted.
Rym: It is not easy, it is not trivial, you will get screwed, but it might be fun anyway.
Scott: You have to get the biggest room you can.
Rym: Yeah, and you have to expect to spend money, and you have to be the kind of person who has no trouble lying through their teeth to a police officer.
Scott: Now, so, to get a hotel room, figure out the best hotel proximity and price.
Scott: Figure out how many rooms you're gonna need.
Scott: Make sure you call well enough in advance, you know, for the con, because the hotels will be sold out for big cons.
Rym: I mean, Otakon, three of the hotels are already sold out.
Scott: For what, August?
Rym: Yes, for this coming August.
Scott: That's eight months away.
Rym: In fact, two of the hotels sold out within two weeks of the con ending last summer.
Scott: So it was twelve months prior.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Rym: There were people calling hotels at the con for the next year.
Rym: I'm not kidding.
Scott: So, get them well enough in advance, make sure that you call the hotel, like, let's say you order the room four months in advance.
Scott: Call them two months later to make sure and confirm the rooms, then call them the week before the con and confirm the rooms.
Rym: Yes, and even then, when you get there, check in and confirm what you're getting.
Rym: Because remember when I said that when we showed up three hours before our friends and we checked in, the hotel was a disaster?
Rym: We checked in, and they gave us the key to our room.
Rym: Now, we had ordered a giant suite, because we had, like, twelve people come.
Scott: With an upstairs and a downstairs.
Rym: Yes, this hotel room has two stories inside of it, and it had, like, these utenna windows.
Rym: It was awesome.
Rym: So we go to our room, and we open it, and it's just a tiny little room.
Rym: What the hell?
Rym: So we go back to the front desk, and we're like, "Alright, bitches, we ordered a
Rym: suite.".
Rym: And they're all, "Yeah, suite, uh, sold out, uh, we're
Rym: dumb.".
Rym: And we're like,
Rym: "Great.".
Scott: They ended up giving us, uh...
Rym: They gave us the guest suite, like the presidential whatever suite, for a discount.
Rym: And they worked it out with us, because we were a large group of angry people who was going to raise hell.
Rym: But I'll warn you that if something like that screws up, the hotel is not obligated to serve you in any way.
Rym: Hotels are not obligated to keep your reservation.
Rym: So keep on them and make sure you've got it.
Scott: Yeah, basically be an ass to the hotel, and keep pushing them and pushing them to make sure that what you have is right.
Scott: And there should be someone in your group who's the designated hotel-doing person, which is probably the most responsible person.
Rym: Now, make sure, one, that that person has a credit card.
Rym: Because you have to secure the room.
Rym: And if you have multiple rooms, you have to secure them all separately.
Rym: And we actually have to split that between two of us, because I only had one credit card.
Rym: And because of various things on it, it could only secure one room at a time.
Rym: Because they reserve a lot of money on your card to reserve a room.
Rym: Because they're worried about breakage and such.
Rym: Now, as for paying for the room, basically, there are two ways to look at this.
Rym: We trust our close friends completely, so we don't make them pay right away at all, whatever.
Rym: We just trust that they'll give us the money, and they all give us the money.
Rym: If there is any shadow of a doubt whatsoever, and even if they're close friends, make them pay in advance.
Rym: Either before you book the room in cash, or make them pay before you let them into the room.
Rym: Because if someone's unreliable, and they don't pay you right away, they're never going to pay you.
Scott: And you'll just end up having to pay hundreds of dollars to this hotel room, and someone else stayed in it for free on your bill.
Scott: That's not good.
Rym: Be wary of people who just say they might come, and then they show up, and they want a place to crash.
Rym: Because that means they don't want to pay you anything, but they want to use your shower and bed.
Rym: Now, we've never actually had this happen, but a lot of our friends have.
Rym: So this is just kind of a warning to, even though you might all be friends, work out the money ahead of time.
Rym: Because it's real easy to lose friends over stupid things like money.
Scott: Yep, so, checking in, you get to the hotel, you go right to the desk, you say you want to check in, you get your keys, you go to your room, you put your stuff in it.
Scott: You make sure that, you know, you keep count of people in the room, you keep track of those keys.
Scott: Holy crap, you keep track of those keys.
Rym: Yes, if the wrong people have your keys, they'll disappear, and you can't get into the room, and you're fucked.
Scott: Make sure that whoever actually paid for the room, the hotel person, you know, whoever's the most responsible guy, he's got to have a key, whoever it is.
Scott: Two?
Rym: Usually, you might think, "Oh, I'll give the key to the two most responsible
Rym: people."
Rym: Or the two people who are, like, running the event.
Rym: That's always me and Scott.
Rym: So, it's kind of stupid for both of us to have keys, because we're both usually together at the con.
Rym: Great, so make sure you spread the keys out in a way that will inconvenience the key holders the least.
Rym: Like, if someone is a diabetic, or someone has asthma, or someone has a reason to go to the room often, they should have a key.
Scott: And, let's say there's, like, three people that are pretty much going to hang out with each other at the con, give one of those three people a key.
Scott: The most responsible of the three people a key.
Scott: You know, because, you know, they'll probably be going back to the room together, and, you know, if they're not going to split up, then why give them two keys?
Rym: Now, we used to have a lot of stuff to say about, like, radios, or how to keep in touch with people, or rendezvous points, but honestly, that's made completely moot by cell phones.
Scott: Cell phones and Nintendo DSes pretty much eliminate any need for that.
Rym: Yeah, everyone we knew had a cell phone, and we all just call each other.
Rym: Now, the one drawback of that is that, at least for us, pretty much, my phone rang about every fifteen minutes for the entire convention.
Rym: I just, like, I just set it to mute, and then I'd look, and, like, ten people have called me, trying to get into the room, or trying to find out when we're going to eat dinner, or telling me that they found something cool, or, yeah.
Rym: That's just my rant.
Rym: That's not actually anything useful.
Scott: I get just about as many calls at cons, just from other people at the con, all over the place, doing stuff.
Scott: "Where are you?
Scott: Let's meet up and eat.
Scott: Oh, my God, you have to come to this event.
Scott: You know, this is going on.
Scott: Do you want to do this?
Scott: Oh, I saw something
Scott: crazy.".
Scott: Well, I
Rym: guess the warning there is that, if you want to be the people like us, the ones who organize this for your group of friends, because someone has to do it, or you're going to have drama, be wary that your friends, while they're your friends, will become energy leeches, and will draw all of your energy, efforts, and attention for much of the con, managing them.
Scott: It's a good thing that, most of the time, the conventions are loud, and I can't hear my phone ring.
Scott: So I just, I don't pick it up, not because I don't want to, but because I just don't, I really don't hear it sometimes at the con, which I guess is good.
Scott: You know, because then I pick it up later, and I go, "Oh, someone called
Scott: whatever.".
Scott: You know, and usually it's not super important, and if it is, they'll call again and again.
Rym: Now, we went real long, so we're going to wrap this up for now, but we're going to start up, where this is going to be a series every Thursday until we finish this.
Scott: I think we might finish it next week, we're going to talk about what to do actually when you're at the con.
Rym: Yep, I'm also, next week, I want to talk about specifically how to cram a lot of people in a hotel room without getting kicked out, and without having a problem.
Rym: Because there's a lot of info there.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Alright, so stay tuned next week, tell us your funny con stories, we'll probably play them if they're funny enough.
Scott: And have fun if you're going to any convention soon.
Scott: I think the next con I'm going to is probably going to be the New York City Comic Con in the Javits Center in February.
Rym: Yep, and I'm going to be at Katsu Con, and I may or may not be on a panel, and if I'm not on a panel, I have a friend who's definitely going to be on a panel.
Scott: Alright, awesome.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds.feedburner.com/geeknights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: Also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion.
Scott: And whether you love or hate our podcast, we won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geeknights@gmail.com.