Scott: It's Tuesday August 29th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We discussed the board game.
Scott: I just purchased rah Let's do this Today.
Rym: for various reasons I had to meet with the CEO of my company.
Scott: You know the CEO of my company walks into my office in his pajamas and says hey, what's going on?
Rym: You know when I worked for IBM.
Rym: I never personally saw Paul Masano.
Rym: I never even was in the same room as him ever.
Scott: that company was Stupid big compared to the company I work at now.
Scott: the company you work at now can't be that much bigger than the one I Work at.
Rym: the company.
Rym: I work at now is many times bigger than the company you work at.
Scott: I know the company work.
Scott: It's pretty big.
Rym: how many people do you think work for your company?
Scott: They got an office in New York and I was in DC an office in Wisconsin and office in Louisiana.
Rym: So give or take how many people are in an office?
Scott: Hundreds couple hundred, I don't know.
Rym: all right a hundred yeah, I Think my company is kind of bigger all right.
Rym: Maybe it is yeah I can't really see.
Rym: I'm not a wall.
Rym: I didn't sign any ndas.
Rym: I kind of like where I'm working, so I'm not nearly as Forthwith in terms of giving up information about where I work.
Scott: I like I think also because the place you work Isn't a giant place like IBM.
Scott: No one really cares about what's going on there at all.
Rym: Yeah, well the thing is people would care because I do cool stuff, but they wouldn't care like NDA care.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: Well you can always talk about it without naming names and just to get generic office stories.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, cuz I know here's the one thing at least IBM.
Rym: I knew that many of my co-workers listen to GeekNights.
Rym: No one or I work now knows anything about this show, and I'd like to keep it that way.
Scott: Yeah, you think it's.
Scott: I think it's pretty weird like the people I work with are real internet savvy.
Scott: You know at least the three other people in the IT department yet None of them seem to have found my blog or GeekNights or anything like that.
Scott: either They're really good at not letting on and not caring or They just don't care to find or search for me or anything like that.
Rym: see if I were hiring people from my company I would just Google for their name.
Scott: That's what I would and all sorts of stuff, but a lot of it.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I guess my blog existed before they googled.
Scott: But maybe they just said oh he has a blog and don't care to read it.
Rym: Yeah, I'd read it.
Rym: I would totally read it, but then again I just don't think most of the people where I work are that tech savvy because I Just I I get that impression.
Rym: I mean the problems that people have with their computers that I overhear or The types of work that they do.
Rym: I just don't think they get it at all.
Rym: I don't think they know anything about Linux or open source or anything.
Scott: yeah I really can't understand like someone who has a job but like I mean They don't care about what they're doing.
Rym: I mean I don't care about what I mean.
Scott: I don't care about what specifically the tasks.
Scott: I have been assigned at this job, but I care about Computing in general, and I do computing.
Scott: you know it's like a dentist might not care about this particular filling He's giving to a person, but he cares about dentistry and dental hygiene.
Scott: You know he has something to say about it.
Scott: How could you be a dentist who has nothing to say about dentistry or an IT worker who has nothing to say about IT?
Rym: Well, I guess it's more that a lot of the people I work with aren't in really technical positions.
Rym: I mean I've kind of transcended the level of you know doing tech work like developing for something I do a lot more high-level which means I don't work with tech.
Rym: I work more with paperwork, and you know basic problem-solving.
Rym: It seems like the higher up you get in an organization the less real work you do.
Scott: yeah, it really makes no sense.
Rym: Yeah, I mean at IBM my choices were basically sit where I was doing the same thing forever Or try to get into management where I'd basically do less real work, but get more money.
Scott: But you had to stay there longer.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: all things considered I wouldn't terribly have minded staying at IBM because while I didn't make nearly as much money My commute was only like 10 minutes.
Rym: Yeah, because I'm not moving down to Yonkers.
Rym: good.
Rym: God.
Rym: I'm not living in Yonkers.
Rym: No no no I don't mind working there.
Rym: the tax thingy The tax thing is not even so bad even though the fact that I have to pay taxes to Yonkers even though I don't live in there bothers me on a level you cannot understand.
Rym: yeah, I Really really get angry every time I see that and Yonkers is justification for this tax is such horseshit But I can't vote in Yonkers.
Rym: I have no say over this tax or this money or anything.
Scott: oh It's taxation without Representation.
Scott: yeah, yeah time to have a pilot and bloody revolution.
Scott: Oh, yeah, like they did 200 plus years ago over the same exact issue.
Rym: I believe.
Rym: of course that was only a cover But that's not the point of my favorite t-shirt sets cuz I saw some punk guy wearing it actually down in the Bronx today.
Rym: It was a black shirt, and it had this.
Rym: you know those Propaganda style picture.
Rym: you know high contrast kind of images.
Rym: yep There was one and it showed Ben Franklin, and it said terrorist.
Rym: Then on the back is your George Washington, and it said terrorist.
Scott: It's the greatest.
Scott: I gotta get me one of those.
Scott: yeah Anything to the guy.
Rym: I didn't really have a chance.
Rym: I mean one.
Rym: the guy was you know just some guy walking on the street listening to his iPod.
Rym: I was on my way to a meeting.
Rym: you know you know soup.
Rym: Yeah, I generally don't talk to people on the street.
Rym: Yeah Unless they're the falafel guy.
Rym: the falafel guy the falafel guy is my best friend in all of Brooklyn or all of the Bronx.
Rym: I don't know why I said Brooklyn.
Rym: Yeah, I haven't been to Brooklyn in over a year, okay.
Scott: So before we do the news.
Rym: yeah, if you can't tell we were kind of padding out because we don't have so much for this Episode.
Scott: yeah before we do the news.
Scott: I got some geek back action.
Scott: Orderly the return of the geek back.
Scott: this geek back is from Colin from, California.
Scott: Cuz he went he to Worldcon.
Scott: He went to Worldcon and that's apparently some cool sci-fi con.
Rym: were you trying to make a fake thought bird?
Rym: Yes, were you thinking of ripping anime world order off poorly?
Scott: Yeah, that was fantastic because we didn't get our special thought bird replacement in.
Scott: yet, it's coming in the mail.
Rym: Oh, you mean?
Scott: No, no not that one.
Rym: How about born we won.
Rym: We to you all.
Scott: that's close, but not it my wife That's the one.
Scott: that's the one.
Rym: all right props to anyone who knows what all of those quotes were from.
Scott: yeah, so Colin went to Worldcon which is some sci-fi con in Anaheim, California, and he put out 1,200 GeekNights flyers.
Scott: cuz he is too awesome.
Rym: Yes, mad props.
Rym: you were on the list of people to eventually get schwag when schwag is forthcoming Mm-hmm.
Scott: and he said he even like went through the effort of counting like the remaining flyers Which I think is crazy.
Rym: Wow we didn't even do that at Otakon.
Rym: I didn't.
Scott: I wouldn't do that anywhere.
Scott: I mean even it was the tiniest con where I put out one stack of flyers.
Scott: I wouldn't count the ones remaining.
Scott: It's just not worth the effort, but he says that 250 were picked up, and that's cool Hopefully if you discovered this podcast by the flyer at Worldcon.
Scott: What's up?
Scott: How you doing?
Rym: Because they can obviously answer you through the interweb.
Scott: Yeah, that's exactly right.
Scott: They can go to our forums at front row.
Scott: crew comm slash forum all right.
Rym: That was too cheesy.
Rym: Let's do that again.
Rym: Good.
Rym: God good.
Rym: God that felt like we were trying to do some sort of promo.
Rym: Remember our promos.
Rym: They're still out there.
Scott: Yeah, yeah anyway Apparently Worldcon had 6,700 people and there was some cool science fiction fantasy and horror literature stuff going on there And he put some pictures.
Scott: The pictures he took.
Scott: there was an astro boy statue and a gigantor statue next to a Dalek Which is cool, and then he took pictures of the heek Knight's fliers in little stand to prove that he did it.
Rym: Yep, and he's not lying.
Rym: Yeah, we would have believed him anyway.
Rym: Yeah, I mean unless you said like yeah, I put a hundred thousand fliers at packs or something.
Rym: We'll believe you pretty much.
Scott: Yeah Speaking of PAX news number one packs was this most recent weekend the penny arcade expo.
Rym: now for anyone who doesn't know We use that phrase a lot, but I stress it here because I don't think there is anyone penny arcade Was a small webcomic about gaming video gaming in particular in particular The video game industry and recent news in the video game industry.
Rym: over time It grew to be by at least an order of magnitude the most widely read webcomic known to man.
Scott: Yeah, I really don't think there are any other strictly webcomic webcomics that are beating penny arcade.
Rym: Not even close like mega Tokyo.
Scott: not even a chance now.
Rym: Otakon has between 20 and 24 thousand people every year.
Rym: now Otakon has been going on for a long time.
Scott: packs had 20,000 people this yet packs and Otakon are basically equivalent in population.
Rym: as far as Essentially about now consider that for a minute.
Rym: Otakon is a con for all fans of anime manga Japanese film and culture anything Asian films kung fu.
Rym: Yeah, penny arcade expo is just a con for a webcomic.
Scott: Well, if you think about it, yes But in reality it is a gaming in terms of board gaming and you know Role-playing and tabletop gaming and also gaming as in video gaming.
Scott: It is all gaming.
Rym: Yeah Penny arcade has basically become one of the rallying points of a wide swatch swath of geeks.
Scott: Yeah, it's an edge any sort of game.
Scott: if you play games and you're a geek penny arcade They got you covered even if you don't play games.
Rym: It seems like PAX is going to be the biggest geek con in the country very quickly.
Scott: It's really sad that the biggest geeks in the country over here on the East Coast can't get there.
Rym: Yeah, but think of this if they have East Coast packs.
Rym: if there are two packs is a year Oh my god one in the east and one in the west each of which would probably be as big as if not bigger than Otakon.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we'd have to switch up our policy and make the week of awesome be after packs.
Scott: I think it would be Otakon week of awesome and then packs.
Rym: I don't know if my feeble brain could handle such awesome.
Scott: My brain is much less feeble.
Scott: Thus, I would take full advantage of the double powered quintuple.
Rym: No, you wouldn't?
Scott: you just have some sort of nerdgasm and pass out That's the same thing is what I was just saying You just translated.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, we don't have a lot of news for I mean there's news about packs.
Rym: There's lots of coverage.
Rym: if you want coverage of packs that is on the internet.
Rym: We're not going to give you all of that.
Scott: No, the highlights from packs are this Cool people played guitar hero 2 which is a game that is not out yet.
Scott: There was an omega-thon as is usual at packs and the prize it was a car.
Scott: Now a guy won the car.
Rym: Now what was the final game the final test of battling between the two greatest omega knots of the year?
Scott: Tetris Tetris Kremlin.
Rym: Tetris not Tetris -.
Rym: nope, not Tetris - not Tetris DS with teaspoons.
Scott: No, not Tetris DS straight up.
Scott: Tetris straight up.
Scott: There was a freaking Kremlin on the screen and then there were a falling blocks and I'm pretty sure it was car.
Scott: I koviniki, all right.
Scott: Yeah, I couldn't really hear it that well, it might have been some other song from a ghetto arcade machine, but whatever.
Scott: Yeah, the thing about you have the only real news about the Omega thon is the guy who won.
Scott: The way it works apparently is if you are a finalist in the Omega thon, right?
Scott: So you are in the final match and you lose.
Scott: You get the second place prize, which is usually a pretty good prize.
Scott: I think this year it was like an Xbox and a shit ton of games and money.
Scott: You get to come back next year and go into the Omega thon again.
Scott: Good God.
Scott: So the guy who came in second in the Omega thon last year came in first this year.
Rym: Wow that sets a precedent.
Scott: no, no.
Scott: So they were asking him like hey Did you lose in the final round on purpose last year?
Scott: because you knew the final prize this year would be better than the one last year and thus he would get a second place prize and then a better first place prize.
Rym: and he was like See the thing is I wouldn't be able to do something like that.
Rym: I mean that is definitely the kind of game theory cold-hearted thinking that would make a person succeed at life.
Rym: You know losing purposely in order to win later on more.
Scott: I had too much pride to lose purpose.
Rym: yeah, I mean we.
Rym: there have been times when I tried to hustle people like an air hockey or ping-pong or Board games and such and I can't do it because I refuse to lose.
Rym: I'll think to myself I'm not gonna lose to this asshole and then I win and then that's the end of the hustle.
Scott: That's exactly my problem.
Scott: So you can always trust us not to hustle you and to instead kick your ass.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if you've Scott if Scott's like let's have a Mega Man 2 competition and then he's trying to keep a straight face Where Brim says hey, I bet the bionic commando something and he doesn't start peeing his pants.
Rym: Yeah, so I can pretty much guarantee that we'll be covering packs next year in the very least East Coast packs if it happens.
Scott: if It happens and if you want to know more about what went down at PAX because many awesome things went down at PAX I mean this place.
Scott: Well, I saw I just just from watching the videos I get the feeling that it was the awesomest con ever.
Rym: I saw a quote from someone who said man if you didn't have a DS you were left out of most of this convention.
Scott: Yeah, apparently they imported mad beanbag Charage for DS action.
Rym: apparently the Best Buy that was adjacent to packs sold out of DS's like Friday.
Scott: who people came to pack?
Rym: actually Yes, actually one person on slashdot specifically said that everyone had DS's and he felt left out.
Rym: So he went to buy a DS and all but two had been already sold in the Best Buy.
Rym: He said the Best Buy was barren.
Rym: Wow Yes, apparently the nerd I don't want to say nerd the geeks at PAX cleaned out this Best Buy.
Scott: Did they even buy the refrigerators?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: To hold their Mountain Dew, of course Obviously.
Scott: Oh shit, baby.
Scott: Yeah Did they buy the dryers?
Scott: To clean theirs to dry their sweaty shirts.
Rym: Oh And the washers to wash their brand new penny arcade merch are the overextended metaphor the joke that's not funny anymore.
Rym: Oh Yeah now speaking of the DS Because it obviously went gangbusters at every con we have been to and every con we didn't go to this year.
Rym: Except I guess I don't know dentistry cons.
Rym: I don't think the DS is real big at those.
Scott: I don't know unless DS stands for dentistry something that was lame.
Rym: Yeah, now the you know that the DS has the Wi-Fi and while I haven't used it a lot lately It it was really good.
Rym: It was really well done.
Rym: And there are only what like eight games that use it so far still.
Scott: Yeah, there are more coming.
Rym: I think the mario 3r3 basketball might use it now Despite the fact that there are only eight games that one of which just came out recently that take advantage of the Wi-Fi.
Rym: At least two million unique DS DS's have gotten online and use the Wi-Fi and they have played more than 70 million games already.
Scott: Yeah I think there was a recent spike though because a lot of people bought DS lights who had DS's and then they played their Wi-Fi game on the DS light and That kind of adds to the numbers a whole bunch.
Rym: Yeah, probably did but even so the DS Wi-Fi for being a completely free service is doing very very well.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder how many people have used Xbox Live a lot.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is Xbox Live is also really smooth.
Rym: that just cost money.
Scott: Yep, of course I think it's a lot more feature-filled and possibly worth the money.
Rym: However, I'll note that the of the eight games that came out You can see a very definite progression in how well the Wi-Fi is utilized.
Rym: that is Mario Kart.
Rym: Mario Kart used it well enough for me But it was by no means a finished product.
Scott: Tetris was the one that really used a proper.
Rym: every game that's come out has used it better and better and better and the DS hasn't even begun its full potential lifecycle yet.
Scott: There's gonna be some hardcore Wi-Fi action in the future.
Rym: I Mean a lot of games have come for the DS already.
Rym: if the DS died now, I consider all the money I've spent on it.
Rym: Well worth it.
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: The DS is still on a rising tide.
Scott: Yes is nowhere near peaking and just so everyone knows it is very likely in the near future that black and Pinkish colored DS lights will be hitting the US.
Scott: Oh, man's I might get that black one.
Rym: I don't know I might get the black one.
Rym: I thought I was gonna say pink.
Scott: No.
Scott: No, I was pretty sure you're gonna say black.
Rym: Why?
Rym: cuz I have a pink towel.
Scott: I just want you figure you wanted to match your iPod nano.
Rym: Oh Yeah, I don't want to match my iPod nano and so do I.
Scott: I have also a black iPod nano.
Rym: Yeah, but unfortunately for you the DS light does not come in the color scratch to fuck.
Rym: I don't know how you did that to your dana.
Scott: my you know, it still works just fine.
Rym: So I don't give a shit what my nano has not a single scratch on the black.
Scott: yours came with that little sleeve.
Rym: now It's not just a sleeve.
Rym: you realize that the inside of it is a polishing cloth.
Rym: Polishes it every time I put it in you'll see I don't have that.
Rym: So the back is so unscratched.
Rym: I can use it as a mirror.
Scott: I can use the back of mine as a mirror.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to see scratches, no, you get it actually works pretty good.
Rym: You mean pretty well.
Scott: No, it does because deeds.
Rym: No, it doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't and besides we see myself.
Scott: That's a good you didn't?
Rym: you didn't use the verb.
Rym: do you use the verb work?
Rym: So it works good.
Rym: That would mean if you to use that sentence properly My face in it is doing work.
Scott: That's his job.
Rym: No work in that sense would have to mean working as an iron working as in.
Rym: you took good as your medium And you worked it somehow.
Rym: Alright, alright, we're getting kind of silly and off-topic today, but you know what.
Rym: every episode can't be a jam here.
Scott: No, I mean if you want us to make for a week And I don't think anyone is telling us not to make in fact you all told us to make more.
Scott: Yeah, so if you want us to keep doing this you're gonna have to settle with a few episodes being kind of kooky.
Rym: Now with that aside it is in fact time for things of the day.
Rym: So I think we're going to do the things of the day right now and try to stay a little bit on topic.
Scott: Well, my thing of the day is actually a thing of yesteryear and it's I'm not talking about You know the usual classic things of the day which were things that would have been things of the day Maybe five years ago.
Scott: I'm talking about something that was on TV in 1993.
Scott: Okay, this is OJ Simpson the juice Playing NBC's computer bowl 93 against Iron Mike Ditka.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: Is this being rebroadcast with implied oral consent but not express written consent?
Scott: This doesn't even have implied oral consent.
Scott: That is why this is so awesome.
Scott: All right, because they see This is like during the halftime show of an actual NFL football game, which means it is completely owned by the NFL.
Scott: yet Someone recorded it.
Scott: Someone kept that recording until today and then someone put it on YouTube.
Rym: Thank You Internet for providing endless entertainment.
Rym: Yes,
Scott: so this is not only awesome because it is OJ Simpson and Iron Mike Ditka playing a very old Sega Genesis football game against each other But it is also awesome Because you know, you're really really really really really not allowed to put any video footage that belongs to the NFL on the internet.
Scott: So it's a double whammy thing of the day.
Scott: Funny for two reasons.
Rym: That is utterly fantastic.
Scott: And OJ Simpson.
Rym: OJ Simpson.
Scott: Playing a Sega Genesis All right.
Rym: Anyway, my thing of the day Was actually on the forums.
Rym: So one mad props to glimpse seven for pointing this out to us.
Rym: I'll give him props because it's one of the few things that has hit the forums That was actually good enough to where.
Rym: yeah, this will be a thing of the day and we hadn't seen it yet.
Rym: So also if you don't visit the forums realize that you often will get a content ahead of everyone else.
Rym: I mean we've had what actually we just recently passed like a hundred thousand hits or something stupid to the forums.
Scott: I don't even pay attention to that shit.
Rym: Yeah, I was there because I googled for something and I was curious why we came up and I was looking around anyway.
Rym: This is one of those YouTube videos for someone somewhat surreptitiously film someone else and then edits it together for clarity.
Rym: Now this guy is a roommate or a friend or something who plays counter-strike a little too seriously and you know when you play it seems like a lot of other people get angry with you when you shoot them or They swear at you or obviously or in some way perturbed by how good you are.
Rym: This is what those guys look like and what they're doing behind their computer while you shoot them.
Rym: It is utterly hilarious.
Rym: And while I wanted a different thing of the day, but I can't find it anymore.
Rym: That is similar.
Rym: This is very much worth watching because it's not just clips of the guy swearing and yelling and screaming and freaking out Oh, it's so much more.
Rym: it is also Remixes of him yelling and screaming and all of this.
Scott: Yeah, like at one point the guy says bink bink and he like blinks his hands in the air kind of and then they you Know at a couple other times.
Scott: He's like, oh, yeah.
Scott: Oh, so the guy remixes it to be like, oh bink bink.
Scott: Yeah Oh bink bink.
Scott: Yeah, fuck fuck fuck fuck bink bibbing Exactly.
Rym: Now there was one that I'm not linking to because I don't know where it is.
Rym: I think I found it on file planet, but you know what fuck file planet.
Rym: That's the only place I can get it.
Rym: I'm not getting it exactly but way back.
Rym: I don't remember this was at RIT or if we just found it at RIT But it sounds like the kind of thing that would come out of RIT Where a guy had a neighbor or roommate who played Counter-Strike way Way too seriously.
Scott: Sounds like RIT to me.
Rym: So he would Record this guy yelling and playing Counter-Strike and then he made a techno song comprised mostly of loops of this guy's yelling And it was absolutely Hilarious if someone wants to find it and even other people.
Rym: and there were eight people gaga Inside Joe Kim.
Rym: Yeah, so the only inside joke that we can't reveal because we don't have the material Yeah Suffice to say someday there is going to be audio on GeekNights from what is perhaps one of the most Inside internet jokes in the world.
Rym: It is known only To the front row crew a few of our close friends and The people who played mega TF in the late 90s.
Scott: No, not just the people who played it the people who played it hardcore people who were in the clans the people who knew a guy Moog.
Rym: Yeah good.
Scott: Yeah, and of course moog himself.
Rym: Yes, if he's still alive.
Rym: Yep All right I should try to track him down.
Scott: find the moog find the move.
Scott: get the moog on the show.
Rym: interview the moog.
Rym: Be like.
Rym: do you remember this?
Rym: He's like, I'm a highly-played business professional.
Rym: What the hell is going on?
Rym: Yeah, so today we decided because Scott just bought it and we played it three times.
Scott: I think I played it four times four times four times.
Rym: We have a game called Ra now not a Mon Ray but Ra.
Scott: Yeah, just plain old Ra.
Scott: now on board game geek.
Scott: There are two Ra's.
Scott: There's a very old Ra and a very new Ra.
Scott: it is the newer of the two Ra Yep, and it is a game by Rainer Kenizia who is famed for being awesome.
Scott: He is makes the many many good games and also many many not as good games, but still kind of good games.
Scott: He is a great great game designer.
Rym: Now Ra is a bidding game But it's not like every other bidding game that the bidding is not needly.
Rym: It's not seven eight Eleven twelve fourteen fifteen.
Scott: Yeah It's here is the thing to bid on.
Scott: you have four sons and their sons are numbered one through.
Scott: it depends How many people are playing but if they're full set of people playing they're one through sixteen.
Scott: Yeah, one through sixteen and depending on the number of players you have three or four sons at your disposal and You pretty much get one chance to bid.
Scott: it goes around the table once and you either bid or pass and that's it.
Scott: So let's say the bidding starts at the Rym and he bids his he doesn't decides not to bid.
Scott: Then I bid my son that has the number five on it and then someone else bids the son that has the number seven.
Scott: Oh, I'm done.
Scott: I can't you know decide again to bring out my eight son or anything.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Yep Now that way the way the sons are balanced is that the way they're passed out and that this is determined by the rule book.
Rym: Everyone.
Rym: it's really balanced.
Rym: We're like one person will have one son that's higher than everyone else's Other.
Rym: three sons are kind of low and then like everyone can kind of trump everyone else Kinda and it seems really balanced and well put together in that regard.
Scott: Yeah, and the each son is unique like there aren't two of the same numbered son.
Scott: So there's no chance of a tie.
Rym: Yeah Now the other mechanic is that when you use a son you give it up it goes in the middle of the board and then You take back whatever son was currently in the middle of the board and put it back in front of you.
Rym: But face down you can't use it for the rest of the round Once.
Rym: but you basically anytime you use a son you get whatever son was out there.
Scott: if you win the bidding Yeah, so the game starts off with the number one, which is the lowest son out in the middle of the board.
Scott: So whoever is the first to you know bid and win?
Scott: Puts out whatever they bid with out to the middle of the board and gets the number one son.
Scott: And when you do that you get that you get the son from the middle of the board.
Scott: you put it face down Which means you can't use it again in this epoch.
Scott: and then there are three epochs in the game.
Scott: you basically play the game three times and you score, you know, you score some stuff each epoch and you score some stuff at the end of the game.
Scott: and You know each epoch you flip over your face down sons.
Scott: So if it's a three player game, you can only bid.
Scott: you can only win four bids and then you're all out of sons.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: You're done for the rest of the epoch.
Rym: Now the way the game plays is very very simple.
Rym: on your turn there's a god card.
Rym: forget about that.
Rym: you can either draw a random tile from the bag and stick it on the auction cart meaning that that tile goes up for auction.
Rym: or You can call rah, which means we have a bidding round immediately.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now there is also a chance that when you take a tile it's a raw tile, which means up we call rah.
Rym: Anyway now in addition the raw tiles.
Rym: every time one's drawn It goes on the top of the board and there's a number of slots and an epoch ends Immediately with no bidding when the last raw tile fills that top and there are a lot of raw tiles.
Scott: Yeah, so 30 raw tiles in the bag.
Rym: So basically it'll come down to you know.
Rym: Say there's two spaces left up there and people are drawing and then someone draws a raw.
Rym: Now if any other rahs are drawn the epoch is immediately over There is no more bidding and that's the end.
Rym: So people who still have face-up Suns are Really kind of screwed at that point because they either have to hope that a raw doesn't come up Bid real quick and win to get something before the epoch ends or you know not have put themselves in that situation.
Scott: Yeah, generally what you're bidding on are all these different tiles not gonna go into the different tiles But some of them stay around.
Scott: some of them disappear each epoch and some of them if you don't have enough of them you lose Points.
Scott: some of them only get you points at the end of the game.
Scott: You're just trying to get a lots of tiles and the more tiles you have generally the more points you get.
Scott: But you know certain tiles give more points to certain people.
Rym: Yeah, and I really that's pretty much the entire game other than you know, the specific rules and tiny little things about it.
Rym: There's really not much to it.
Rym: You make very few decisions during the game, but the game's still a lot of fun.
Scott: Yeah, the game was definitely like usually.
Scott: bidding games aren't way fun like Pizarro was literally.
Rym: Everyone bids on a finite set of things and then you count up your points.
Scott: Yeah, this was nothing.
Scott: that game What's?
Scott: what's?
Scott: another exam Tower of Babel was a bidding game.
Rym: God Tower of Babel.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm sorry Pete.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: You bought that game.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why you got to look games up on board game geek before you buy it.
Rym: seriously, yeah, but I mean, I guess the the thing that I thought was both cool and that I have a problem with with raw I mean, we haven't played it enough to be able to fully analyze.
Scott: I mean we played it four times.
Rym: I have not come close to figuring out everything there is to know about but I know that of the four games everyone pretty much went the same way and Your choices are basically take the most statistically likely chance to win.
Rym: I mean think of it like a horse race You can bet on the two to one horse where you're very likely to win But you won't get as many points like you'll win and just generically.
Rym: But you can also bet on the ten to one horse and you're less likely to win.
Rym: But if your boat comes in you super win.
Rym: Yeah And this game is like that in the center so far in the sense that there's the obvious safe Conservative strategy and there's the very risky.
Rym: But if the car the tiles come up right you'll win by so much that no one can even come close to you.
Scott: Yeah, that's it seemed to happen.
Scott: I mean the one person would you know really get on a roll and get lots of tiles And the other people would sort of not be able to stop the momentum, you know It's like that
Rym: might be a consequence of playing the three-player version -
Scott: I do I really do want to play this a lot more people like.
Scott: at first I thought the game wouldn't be so different when you change the number of players.
Scott: now I'm really seeing that the four and five players where it's at.
Rym: Yes I mean, I like the game and it's very fun.
Rym: But at least in the three-player version in the four games we've played it very much seems that once everyone knows what they're doing The game really just comes down to playing the odds.
Rym: it's really no different than playing roulette.
Scott: Yeah, it does sort of seem like You know, like I can see how luck is a big factor, you know But it doesn't quite feel like it's a total random game, you know It feels like there's something else going on.
Scott: that is you know skill and decision-based.
Rym: We had an argument like this before the show and I disagree with Scott very strongly and Alex disagrees to a Somewhat lesser extent than me but he still disagrees with Scott in the sense that the game really comes down to just an odds game and all you the only decisions you make are you look and you can say By doing this and following this basic strategy and going for these tiles and calling her out these times I will have a X percentage chance of getting Y points or I can have a lower Z percentage chance of getting a higher end points.
Rym: Hmm and that's really the only decision.
Rym: It's just do I go with the conservative strategy?
Rym: that'll win 60% of the time Unless anyone else goes for the non conservative one, or do I go for the non conservative one?
Rym: But then I'm totally leaving my victory up to what tiles come up.
Scott: See, I think that is sort of true unless you know.
Scott: It's sort of like blackjack where that it's true that you're playing odds unless you count the cards.
Scott: and it's not.
Rym: but everyone Counts the cards and everyone knows exactly what to do.
Rym: Everyone knows what's going on.
Rym: The game is the game is perfect information, you know everything.
Scott: no Unless you it's all of its play.
Scott: It's significant memory factor in remembering what tiles were out and got discarded face down in the box.
Rym: Yeah, except you realize counting cards in blackjack, you know how it actually works.
Scott: Yeah, you figure out the likelihood of the 10.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: No.
Rym: No, no, do you know the?
Rym: there's a system?
Rym: You know how counting cards means there's a count, you know how to do it.
Scott: Well generally like whenever you see certain cards the number goes up.
Scott: when you see other cards the number goes down.
Scott: Yeah, and that way, you know, if the number is high that means the likelihood of tens coming out.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: You don't need to remember all the cards You just need to remember trends and this game is the same way.
Rym: all the only cards you need to count in this game are the Roz and Then all that does is give you a percentage to where.
Rym: now, you know The exact odds of what you're whether or not your strategy is going to succeed.
Scott: I think the Roz are definitely the most important thing to count but it's also I think important to count other things like I was counting the Pharaohs in the game because I was short on Pharaohs and I need you know, I was wondering how many more of them would come out.
Scott: It didn't matter.
Scott: it did matter because if there weren't any more Pharaohs coming it would have been worth it.
Rym: No You know why it doesn't matter?
Rym: Because there are so many more tiles in the bag than will ever come into play in the game.
Rym: Yeah, therefore regardless of the odds the odds basically even out to where it doesn't matter and Unless there's a crazy run on one particular kind of tile That kind of count isn't?
Rym: it really isn't gonna matter.
Rym: The odds are that whatever you need isn't gonna come up anyway.
Scott: No, the odds are that it depending on what it is.
Rym: It may or may not come up But what happens when there's so many tiles is that the odds end up being effectively insignificant because the odds of one thing happening versus another thing are Virtually indistinguishable unless a crazy amount of one car has come up.
Scott: Not really Because I know how many Pharaohs start and I know how I see how many Pharaohs have already come.
Scott: and thus if I need Pharaohs I can say okay the odds of getting Pharaohs now or less or more Yeah, but that doesn't matter for your strategy because Pharaohs coming up is not really something you can control.
Scott: well, yeah, it is because if there's let's say there there's a chance to get one Pharaoh.
Scott: now and I only have one Sun left and You know, it's better to have one Pharaoh than zero.
Scott: But no if there's a lot of Pharaohs still in that bag Um, I might hold out wait to get two Pharaohs.
Rym: you you apply this to the most recent game we played right?
Rym: Yep, when you applied that because I remember you said it very specifically the fair you getting Pharaohs wouldn't have any effect on the game anyway.
Rym: Well, that's because I won by more even if I didn't get When you brought this up the Pharaohs wouldn't have mattered anyway because you needed so many more Pharaohs for it to affect you at all.
Scott: It would have helped and it did in the end, but not so much.
Scott: The point is I would have won even if I didn't have the Pharaohs ever.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it was still a way to get.
Rym: my main gripe was the game is that I make the same decisions when I win and when I lose and It really just seems to come down to how many rods come up and when.
Scott: oh see I made the first I won the first time he played and the most recent time he played and I made very similar decisions both of those Times and the second and third times he played.
Scott: I just kind of played casually, you know Just trying stuff out to see what worked, you know calling rod different times, you know.
Scott: and but you're really only in the most recent time did I have an idea of what I wanted to do and I was thinking About when to call Ra and yeah thinking I was doing it.
Rym: But here's the problem when you were thinking that Alex and I were thinking the exact same thing.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: we knew exactly what to do and but
Scott: obviously didn't work
Rym: because we knew exactly what to do for every player and Doing the optimal thing for you automatically because the turn order and the cards that were up at that time Prevented us from doing anything because the most optimal move we could make was draw a tile and hope it's a Ra.
Rym: Oh Yeah, I'm quite sure and Alex agrees with me.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see.
Scott: I don't think we're quite experts on this game.
Rym: Oh, no, I just definitely feel that there's a lot more randomness to this game that you seem to understand.
Scott: Oh, no, that is randomness.
Scott: You mean someone could just come up and you know draw exactly the tiles they want and you know If it happens, then they're gonna get a whole bajillion points.
Rym: It feels like the randomness really overshadows the strategy and that there is really isn't much strategy either.
Rym: It's just playing the odds and counting.
Scott: I don't think it overshadows the strategy because if you don't know what you're doing and you don't have the strategy down and you don't Play correctly no matter what tiles come up.
Scott: You're gonna lose to someone who knows that they're doing.
Rym: but then again It's just knowing the odds because then your your only strategic decisions are Do I take the safe lower payout or the more risky higher payout?
Rym: Those are the only decisions you make.
Scott: Mmm, I don't know.
Scott: I think this you can also.
Scott: you know as time it's.
Scott: It's not so direct, you know, it changes over time.
Rym: But it is because when the the things you were talking about, you know The things the factors you were considering and the things you were thinking about the things you were counting We were both counting the exact same things and we knew exactly what the optimal move was.
Rym: The problem is we also saw that you were in the position to make the optimal move.
Rym: that stops us every time.
Scott: I think there's maybe a move that it was not not.
Rym: as that case if you have your sons and You have Ra and then now that means Alex and I both have to draw a tile or call Ra.
Rym: Alex is not going to call Ra because there are no tiles out and neither one of us will bid and he'll be forced to Waste his son on nothing.
Rym: I Me calling Ra is most likely going to force me to bite that stupid tile for one of my sons.
Rym: You it gets to your turn now.
Rym: There are two sun two tiles out.
Rym: two tiles is the magic number especially when you have low-numbered sons.
Scott: Hmm, I guess.
Rym: but because remember the time I won I won mostly by go doing which exactly what you did.
Rym: I got to the point where I had a bunch of sons and I had Ra so I'd let it go around and I would Every single time it got to me because the two tiles we seemed especially optimal because people would either give me what I wanted or They'd give up their sons.
Scott: see but by that logic, you know, eventually someone drew a Ra tile or yeah Eventually, I would take a tile and put it out there.
Scott: How come when you didn't then at that point in the game because it didn't happen.
Scott: it happened many times.
Rym: No, because by the time it happened then it was a totally different strategic area and calling Ra was bad for another reason.
Scott: hmm, I Think there's just something that's being overlooked here.
Rym: No, I think there's just so much randomness in the game.
Rym: It might be mitigated by having more players I doubt.
Scott: yeah more players definitely help out.
Scott: because think about that You know one guy draws a tile the second guy draws a tile the third guy calls Ra.
Scott: You have these fourth and fifth guys sitting there going.
Scott: Uh, who didn't draw a tile or call Ra but can bid?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, that would definitely throw things off.
Rym: Plus just the fact that the Ra tiles have so much influence in the game and whatever your strategy is The end result is how effective it'll be almost always comes down to the Ra's.
Rym: because if you play conservatively and normally like the straight-up way we've seen Then if the Ra's come out too slowly or too quickly You're fucked and people who bet on the Ra's coming out slowly or quickly just win by crazy leaps and bounds.
Scott: Yeah It does seem like if you play if you don't bid and you keep your sons and the Ra's come out very slowly Then other people are kind of forced to bid and they will buy things and then run out of sons And then you win because now you can deal out a whole bunch of tiles and take them all for yourself.
Scott: But if the Ra's come out quickly Then you need to spend your sons quickly so you can get stuff before the Ra's finish.
Rym: So I guess just so far the game feels to me like a slot machine of Ra's and everything else is just incidental.
Rym: Mmm, that's the feeling I get I still like the game.
Scott: It feels a little different than that to me.
Scott: I mean, I'm not gonna say this game doesn't have mad luck factor.
Scott: It has a significant horrendous luck factor.
Scott: I just do not think the luck factor is the number one dominant factor.
Scott: I would say is the number two factor.
Rym: I think it's the number one factor when players are playing intelligently.
Scott: Maybe but I'm I would I would agree.
Scott: I would agree with that if I was confident that we Consider this way.
Rym: the odds are known.
Rym: Unless you have a shitty memory and you can't count the tiles that have come up the odds of anything happening are fully known to Everyone.
Rym: everyone knows the odds of anything coming up.
Rym: Everyone knows that the chances of any strategy has of succeeding Yeah, and everyone knows everyone else is bidding power.
Rym: So everyone is making the best decision they can make unless they are stupid.
Rym: Therefore what's the only other factor in the game?
Scott: See but I don't believe that everyone is making the best decision.
Scott: I Mean we have.
Scott: we've only played the game for time.
Scott: Yeah, we saw not gonna be convinced that we were making.
Rym: there might be times.
Rym: We are not making the optimal decisions right now However, the moment we have players that foot that understand the game well enough.
Rym: the game becomes completely random, which is true of many games.
Rym: I just feel like it's going to come much quicker in this game or This game is going to become nothing but a memory slash risk-taking game.
Scott: Maybe so maybe so.
Scott: Anyway, it is the seventh highest ranked game on board game geek.
Rym: Well, I can see why the game's really fun.
Rym: Yeah, I just I feel like I felt absolutely no satisfaction when I won and I felt absolutely no Apprehension when I lost like.
Rym: I didn't think ah, I could have done better.
Rym: I thought yeah, that's how it turned out.
Rym: and when I won I thought the exact same thing.
Rym: I don't feel any different when I win or lose.
Rym: I just enjoy playing the game.
Scott: See the first time when I won I was like, okay the game we'd ever played before I won.
Scott: That was random.
Scott: But the second and third the second time I was like, okay I lost by a little bit and I kind of was like, yeah Whatever.
Scott: the third time I was like when I got completely hosed that I had no points.
Scott: I was like you had three points three points, which is less than I started with and I was like, okay I did something stupid.
Scott: What did I do?
Rym: stupid now?
Scott: See and the most recent time when I just won by a landslide I really felt like I did some smart moves.
Rym: But in the game that you lost you didn't really do anything stupid.
Rym: from what I could remember so much as I did to you The exact thing that you did to me in the game.
Rym: We just played.
Scott: Yeah, but in the game we just played when I did it to you.
Scott: You didn't end up with three points.
Rym: Well, yeah, that's because I got really really lucky in the second epoch.
Rym: maybe it was because I didn't.
Rym: I was totally not doing well at all and I was losing by a lot.
Rym: and then in the second epoch Through pretty much randomness I happen to have the the position in place to get a whole bunch of points all of a sudden from a bunch of gold because there happened to be a tile out there that you weren't gonna take as it was gonna destroy your Civilizations and Alex wasn't gonna take because he had already spent too many of his sons.
Scott: Mmm, yeah those disasters do kind of throw things us.
Rym: It was a set of tiles that neither you nor Alex wanted and that happened to be Super super super points for me just because of the random money or the random stuff.
Rym: I happen to have not the monuments.
Rym: Yeah, I guess so I would have done really really terribly in the last game like more so than I did except for the random good luck I had in the second epoch.
Scott: Also, I think that From what I've been reading around about this game in the lower player games There seems to be a more significant factor of screw the other guy and when there's more players that becomes much less of a factor.
Rym: Yeah, I definitely want to play the game with more players.
Scott: Yeah, I mean in the three-player game you can basically see you know Let's say I'm ahead by a bunch and there's one Pharaoh left and I know that without a Pharaoh Rym We'll lose five points.
Scott: I could just buy that Pharaoh and not care to screw him.
Scott: and a five-player game.
Scott: that's like a really really bad idea because you only have three sons and not four sons and There's no way you're gonna get that kind of a lead in a five-player game.
Scott: I don't think even though I've never played a five-player game.
Scott: I've only played it three player.
Rym: I'm just making stuff up at this point Yep, so basically that just means that we're gonna do another episode on raw once we've played it I don't know 40 more times.
Scott: I think maybe we'll do like a half episode on raw and a half episode on something else as we get more experience with it.
Rym: It depends if if I'm right in that there's not much to raw once you figure it out We'll do a half episode if we discover the magic hidden awesome that I'm somewhat dubious of its existence.
Scott: Yeah, let me just I want to read the.
Scott: I just I've never actually looked at this recently.
Scott: the top 10 ranked board games and board game.
Scott: geek.
Rym: I'll know that doom was up there for a while.
Scott: No, these are like the ranked like all-time voting and all that stuff.
Scott: not just pop those.
Scott: that's like the popular list of what's hot now Ranking, right?
Scott: So Puerto Rico's number one best game ever.
Rym: Tigris and Euphrates second best game.
Scott: a list pretty much Yeah power grid, which you never played but it's sort of like web of power.
Rym: I like web.
Rym: I heard El Grande.
Scott: I have El Grande princes of Florence.
Rym: That's the first one on the list.
Rym: We haven't played.
Scott: Yeah, rah ageist eem Daimacher and number 10 is war the ring.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: So Yeah, a lot of those other games that are up there seem to be significant strategy games.
Scott: I mean El Grande yet not a hundred percent like the top three games.
Rym: Well, remember we never played the other variant of El Grande.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: That's all that's very true, which I have.
Scott: Yep But you know, this is a game raw that you know, we think is a significant luck game You know.
Scott: yet in a web site where strategy games are very popular Let me put it on a list where high strategy games are topping it.
Scott: It is made number seven.
Rym: put it this way one.
Scott: I think there's something we're one.
Rym: the box very clearly states that Fun is the biggest factor in the game and I'll say that even though I generally am so far Satisfied with the strategic elements of the game.
Rym: It is very fun to play.
Rym: Yeah, enjoy playing it.
Rym: It's true - it's not so much straight-up luck as it's just all you're doing is playing the odds.
Rym: Mmm, it just.
Rym: it feels that way.
Rym: I mean there are elements of that in a lot of the games we like.
Rym: it just seems like that is the primary strategic element is Understanding the odds playing the odds knowing what other players have and wants.
Scott: Hmm Alright, I think that's about all we got to say.
Rym: Yep tune in tomorrow when we'll probably be somewhat more on topic.
Scott: Yep Tomorrow, what are we gonna talk about again?
Rym: Uh, we'll keep it a secret because we haven't decided yet.
Scott: Oh, okay, cool.
Rym: Yeah, and once again, you know frapper map forums website review us in iTunes.
Rym: yada yada yada.
Scott: send us email.
Scott: send us odios.
Rym: Yeah, send us odios.
Rym: and for all of you who've sent us email We're probably gonna do a geek back episode at some point in the future.
Scott: Yeah, we might have to do that is we're basically now.
Rym: We're only gonna do a geek back in a show if it's particularly relevant or awesome.
Rym: And otherwise, we'll save them for feedback shows.
Scott: Yep Which means your email is less important, but still important enough to be read in an episode.
Rym: Well, we tend to respond to almost every email we get even though I gotta say if the trend of emails continues or increases That's probably not gonna happen anymore.
Rym: I'm sorry But I've had too many people emailing me asking For help with their podcast and while I love to help I'm basically writing essays to all of you.
Rym: I think I just need to make a little book and sell it.
Scott: I think that's a fantastic idea.
Scott: make like a little tiny handbook.
Rym: You're like this is how to make a podcast go away.
Scott: Well, no, I think we should go with that other idea.
Scott: We'll take a video of you know Rym screen when he does the Podcast post-production and all that jazz and that way you can all watch it and figure out what to do.
Scott: Yeah, we're actually and then we'll make a short YouTube of like what we have set up.
Rym: We're actually very much planning on doing that.
Rym: It's just a matter of one getting a better camera than the one we own.
Scott: Yeah, if anyone knows a good camcorders, we know absolutely nothing.
Rym: Why don't we just ask like Emily or Kate we will.
Scott: but in addition, you know We might have a listener who's like it knows a lot about it.
Rym: So the thing is the camera we have now cost four thousand five hundred dollars in 1980 something.
Scott: Yeah It's a VHS recording thing.
Scott: But no if anyone knows what's a really good camcorder something that will you know, we'll be able to make good youtubes We'll be able to make.
Rym: yeah, we're talking for less than like 600 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, you know something that can record video to some sort of.
Scott: get it into our computer.
Rym: basically You know either into the Mac and well Scott you realize that we could just do about 10 minutes worth of research.
Scott: Yeah, but you know if someone out there might already be smart.
Scott: We don't do any research.
Rym: Yeah Possibly so.
Scott: advice about camcorders.
Rym: Yeah, send it to us but we will definitely in the future have the episodes and videos and everything of how we do GeekNights because I Know a lot of people who ask us for advice Don't seem to know a lot about it.
Rym: Yep, or the people who do know a lot about it Don't realize that they can do the same thing for a lot less money.
Rym: Yep, and on that note we're out of here.
Rym: Hooray And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.