Scott: It's Thursday, December 21st.
Scott: I'm Scott, and I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we rummage through our forums and discuss random crap.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So in the spirit of the holidays, coupled with the fact that we kind of realized periodically that we've got some money here, we're finally gonna buy new microphones.
Scott: Are we?
Scott: When are we gonna do this?
Rym: We were thinking about doing it tonight.
Scott: Are we gonna do it tonight?
Rym: I don't know, maybe.
Scott: How many times have we said we're gonna do that and then not done it?
Rym: We're definitely gonna have these new microphones before Katsucon.
Scott: I'm betting you won't notice that much of a difference.
Rym: No, you guys probably won't.
Scott: Yeah, but we're probably gonna get those SM57s that everyone else gets.
Rym: Yeah, it is the microphone of bass drums and presidents.
Scott: Not bass drums, but other drums.
Scott: Bass drums get those big, other, those weird...
Rym: Well, actually a lot of people there, you can do something cool where you take what is effectively a subwoofer and use it as a microphone and stick it in front of a bass drum.
Rym: It works real well.
Scott: That could work real well.
Rym: It does work real well.
Rym: In fact, I saw some companies sell, apparently, they call them like bass microphones, but they're really just subwoofers.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: That's not so exciting.
Rym: Well, I mean we've been using... Now, I thought it was funny though that when we showed up at Sitacon way back, a lot of the other podcasters we met, I mean, they're cool people, but they had fairly expensive, a lot of mad condenser microphones.
Scott: Which are, I mean, sure, if you're doing something super fancy that's gonna, you know, sound better, I guess on some level, but when you turn during it into mp3 in the end, an mp3 that's mad, low quality, and shitty, that's a lot of extra money you're paying for not much more.
Rym: It wasn't just that because those microphones are okay.
Rym: It's more that condenser microphones used to be leaps and bounds better, but in recent years, dynamic microphones are pretty much just as good.
Rym: And in fact, in most applications you're better off using a high quality and cheaper dynamic microphone than you are using a condenser mic.
Scott: Yeah, I figured the SM57, they keep advertising the fact that the President of the United States, that's the microphone that's on the podium.
Scott: So, you know, and it is, and he sounds fine when he gives the State of the Union address.
Scott: So I think it's gonna be alright.
Scott: Well, not
Rym: only that, but we were looking around and pretty much numerous people have, when they, you know, if you run into them, people who know what they're talking about, always say, "Yeah, so what do you use, an
Rym: SM58?"
Rym: Which apparently is the industry standard, one of the most commonly used vocal microphones in the world.
Scott: Yeah, if you go to a concert and someone's singing, 90% chance it's an SM58.
Rym: It might be, they've just released very recently the newest, newest versions of the 57 and the 58.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: But they're quite a bit more money.
Scott: Yeah, forget it, it doesn't matter as far as we're concerned.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: We'll get the cheapest one.
Rym: Yeah, we'll probably get the 57.
Rym: I mean, the 58, from what I get, here's the thing- 57?
Scott: Oh, 58.
Scott: If I may, if you will, from what we can gather- Got made that very nice.
Rym: The difference between the two, and remember, this is subjective because no one really could give me a straight answer, is that the 57 is better for people talking and situations where you're not gonna, I don't know, throw the thing at a brick wall and then run it over with a car.
Scott: And drums.
Rym: Because the 58 is really, really durable.
Rym: There are stories of certain rock musicians swinging it around by the wire and banging it into things and then singing from it and it worked just fine.
Scott: Yeah, I think that seems to be the point of the 58, is for live vocals and beating the shit out of it and having it still work.
Scott: That seems to be the two things it's really good at.
Rym: So we should probably get those, you know, to fend people off at conventions.
Scott: Haha, lol.
Scott: Now, conventions, whenever I go to conventions, they seem to already have those there, already lined up, so.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Hey, whatcha gonna do?
Rym: Plus, it's not like, I mean, we're pretty much at any con now, we're gonna set up somewhere, all our equipment, and not move it.
Rym: And we're not gonna carry around some little crap recordy bit that someone we know may or may not break when we lend it to them to-
Scott: We should really invest, like, just, who cares about the price, it's worth it to get one of those high quality, you know-
Rym: Solid state recorders?
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Though for now, I mean, like, KatsuCon, there's a good chance we'll be just setting up in the, uh, video game room.
Scott: Yeah, that'll be fine.
Rym: But I mean, in the- Or like Otakon, we're just gonna set up at our table, I think, or in the hotel room or something.
Scott: But in the long run, it'll be worth it to spend, like, 400 bucks on one of those compact flash recorders with two XLR inputs and everything.
Rym: Oh, definitely.
Scott: I mean, especially after- Just bite the bullet and shell out the cash.
Rym: Yeah, though my primary concern now is updating the website.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Plus, those things are also useful for, you can record the show directly onto one of those, like, when we're sitting in this room.
Scott: And then we'll have a backup, you know, so if you delete it, you can just go and get it off the compact flash card.
Rym: Yep, like, I could just keep them, like, 'cause we could set up the mixer- We could even just record the show on it all the time.
Rym: Yeah, and some of them are fancy, and you just plug them also via USB or FireWire into a computer and just get the WAV files off.
Scott: Yeah, we can record the show without a computer and then just edit it on the computer.
Rym: Or we split it and record to both just in case the computer fucks up and- Yep, yep.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Yeah, expect a bunch of bit-by-bit upgrades because we- Upgrades that you won't notice, they're only for us, hahaha.
Rym: Yeah, 'cause, well, GeekNights is doing well enough to where we've definitely passed the point of pod-fading.
Rym: I don't know of a podcast other than the professional paid ones that have done more episodes than us.
Scott: Wait, wait, wait, let's see, um, I know that that MTV guy has done more episodes than us 'cause he did 'em five days a week for a long time.
Scott: You know, he missed 'em here and there, but whatever.
Scott: Um, I'm pretty sure Comic Geek Speak has done more episodes than us, but- Oh yeah, they could've.
Scott: In numbered episodes, we've done more, but they have a lot of episodes they don't put numbers on.
Scott: They're just, like, extra episodes.
Rym: Ahh.
Scott: They have, like, episodes for Book of the Month or for other stuff that they don't put numbers on.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, we put a number on everything just so we can serialize things for, you know, the DVD and such.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but, uh, yeah, I wonder, we might just become the podcast with the most episodes.
Scott: Yeah, I mean- Maybe Onion Radio News.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, hahaha.
Rym: Maybe we count hours of content per week.
Scott: Yeah, there might be, uh, like, some daily podcast with, like, five-minute shows.
Scott: They might beat us out.
Scott: We gotta go find this out.
Scott: What podcast has the most episodes?
Scott: Didn't we look into this before?
Rym: And we couldn't find anyone bigger than us.
Scott: No, someone in the forums pointed to a few podcasts who had the most episodes.
Rym: Well, maybe we'll find that in our, uh, dickings about during the main bit today.
Scott: Maybe we will.
Rym: But anyway, to get to the news.
Rym: Now, this news does not affect anyone in the world except for this one guy and all the people reading about it.
Rym: And I chose- I wasn't even gonna talk about this.
Rym: I was just reading this news to tell Scott about it because I found it funny.
Scott: It was gonna be a thing of the day.
Rym: Yeah, but then I read the actual article and there are some choice quotes here.
Rym: Now, the story is, and the story has been repeated around the world lately, a fat dude, he weighs over three bucks, you know, like 350 pounds, and he wanted to fly on an airplane out of France.
Rym: Now, he was French.
Scott: How tall was the guy?
Rym: I doesn't say.
Scott: Okay, because I'm trying to get an idea of how wide he was, because these guys who weigh 350 that are pretty tall and not so wide.
Scott: And there are guys who were like five foot six and they weigh 350, and they're like three plane seats wide.
Scott: So, you know, it's a tough call.
Rym: Well, the people involved, I mean, you know, the judge, it looks like the jury that may be sitting here, the lawyers, all seem to agree as to the stature of this man.
Rym: Now, you see, he tried to get on this plane and our friend said, "Oh, no, no, no.
Rym: You are too large.
Rym: You need to buy two
Rym: tickets.".
Scott: No ticket.
Rym: No ticket.
Rym: So this man gets obviously indignant and he buys the extra ticket.
Rym: Now, he's suing for the humiliation that he suffered for having to buy an extra ticket.
Rym: Now, never mind the fact that Air France warns its passengers on the website before they get there, all over the place, that if you're large and you require two seats, you'll be forced to buy one, you won't be allowed to board.
Rym: It's been their policy forever.
Rym: They enforce it uniformly.
Rym: There's no question that this is a set thing.
Scott: I have a feeling they're going to win this lawsuit.
Scott: I just had this feeling.
Rym: I don't know what it is.
Rym: Better call Randy.
Scott: I know.
Rym: So they get to court and Fernand Gomalt, who is the lawyer for the airline, in part of his opening statement said the following.
Rym: This is an exact quote I assume translated from French.
Rym: "Let's be objective.
Rym: This man is fat.
Rym: He barely fits on the courtroom chair.
Rym: How could he sit in an
Rym: airplane?".
Scott: "That has the best lawyer job in the world.
Scott: Make fun of fat guy.
Scott: Get lots of
Scott: money.".
Rym: Now the guy comes back to say that he feels humiliated, that he's been denounced as fat and enormous on quote unquote countless occasions during the hearing.
Scott: "Maybe you shouldn't have eaten so much food.
Scott: You did it to yourself, you fat
Scott: ass.".
Rym: I felt shocked and humiliated by what he said.
Rym: Now if he had called him say a fat fuck, or if he had said this man is a smelly fat obese person and he didn't actually smell, then he might have cause to be a little bit humiliated and shocked and angry.
Scott: I mean if he said the guy was a fag or something and the guy was, you know, then that's not cool.
Rym: But if I state an objective fact about a person I meet and that person becomes angry about it.
Scott: "Yeah, like Rym, you brown haired, brown long haired
Scott: person.".
Rym: "Scott, you
Rym: Jew.".
Scott: "Oh no, he said I was a Jew and I kinda
Scott: am.".
Scott: "Oh
Scott: lordy.".
Scott: "What am I going to
Scott: do?".
Rym: "You better stop
Rym: that.".
Scott: "All
Scott: right.".
Rym: "But if you see a fat man and you say, 'Excuse me, fat man, I would like to walk past you.
Rym: Could you kindly step
Rym: aside?'
Rym: That person really has no right to be indignant about the fact that you've called him
Rym: fat.".
Rym: But the fact that this lawyer, and this is what I love about other countries, if this happened in the U.S.
Rym: there would have been a shitstorm.
Rym: I don't see any shitstorm in France.
Rym: I don't see any reaction.
Scott: I think it's because there's less fat people in France.
Scott: I mean I don't know where France is on the list of having the most fatness, but I'm pretty sure it's U.S.
Scott: followed by Britain or vice versa.
Rym: Yeah, I think Britain is number one.
Scott: Britain followed by
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: People who speak English are fatter.
Rym: And Australia is catching up real quick, but no, France and Greece are really, really low.
Scott: Mediterranean people seem to eat good food and not be fat.
Rym: Because they drink nectar and they eat fruit.
Scott: Yeah, so they had really good fruits when I was in Israel.
Rym: I don't doubt it.
Scott: But no, so French people are less fat, so they have no problem making fun of fat people.
Rym: In America, the lawsuit, they probably would have still lost because the airlines win these lawsuits in America too.
Rym: But here in the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: the lawsuit would have gone along the lines of the fat man saying that he's being discriminated against and that he was being humiliated and blah blah blah.
Rym: And the airline would say, no, it is simply our policy.
Rym: But in France, they say, let's be objective.
Rym: This man is fat.
Rym: He barely fits in the courtroom chair.
Rym: How can he fit on an airplane?
Rym: I rest my case.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: And I imagine that the judge said, well, you sold me.
Scott: Yeah, the judges look at the guy and go, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Rym: Yes, that's how, let's see, we've already made fun of our Australian listeners and our our albionic listeners.
Scott: All right.
Rym: We've got to follow the anime world order thing and make fun of the Irish.
Rym: I would just like to ask, if we have any Irish listeners, give us a shout out.
Rym: We want to represent the Emerald Isle.
Scott: And I apologize.
Scott: Until recently, I was not able to tell you apart from the Scottish.
Rym: Luckily, Scott has learned.
Rym: We used to go through like wait years and years and years ago.
Rym: We do this thing where it's got to be like, so which one is winning?
Rym: I'd be like a Scottish.
Rym: You're like, which one is leprechaun?
Rym: That's the Irish.
Scott: I really didn't know.
Scott: I thought they were all the same.
Scott: I was like, yeah, I imagine like leprechauns playing golf by the Blarney Stone with some four leaf clovers in the Loch Ness Monster.
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: I thought they were all the same.
Rym: Much like one time, one of the places I worked at.
Rym: I mean, a lot of people, especially in the US, don't actually seem to realize that Asian nations are kind of different from each other.
Rym: So it's the same thing where a Korean was hired where I work and he was a cool guy.
Rym: But when they were interviewing him, they asked me if they wanted me to come in and talk to him a little bit.
Rym: And I was like, why?
Rym: What do I have to do with this guy?
Rym: And they're like, well, you like all that Japanese stuff.
Rym: And I'm like, yeah, Japanese, not Korean.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: What else I can say about that?
Scott: Not the same.
Rym: So then you have some sort of news.
Scott: I do.
Scott: There was a big rumor going around the Internet, like OMG, on Christmas, Nintendo is going to give people free virtual console games.
Rym: Is that rumor true?
Scott: No.
Scott: Nintendo is like, screw you guys.
Scott: Virtual console games cost money.
Rym: But if I were a Nintendo, I would put Super Mario Brothers one, the original game in the virtual console for free without saying a word on Christmas Day.
Scott: Well, that was part of the rumor.
Rym: No, I mean, that's what I would do if I were in charge of that division of Nintendo, because that wouldn't even preclude selling Mario one in the future.
Rym: You only you give it away for free and then later you sell the Super Mario pack or you sell Super Mario one plus.
Scott: Well, apparently Nintendo is not doing any of that.
Scott: All the virtual console games cost money.
Scott: But however, here is the list of what is going to be available on the virtual console Christmas morning.
Scott: Super Mario Brothers one for five hundred points.
Rym: You know, that's almost worth it.
Rym: That's such a good game.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: But I already have the game for Game Boy Color.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I have the game on numerous things.
Scott: Which is probably the best version of it, too.
Scott: Street Fighter two, the World Warrior, I assume is just going to be like a very good version of Street Fighter two for eight hundred points.
Rym: I'm not familiar with that version of Street Fighter two.
Scott: It's probably going to be a lot like Street Fighter two turbo because it's a Super NES game.
Rym: But if that's the case, I wouldn't be that averse to it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Super Castlevania, which I must say that if you're looking for the old school Castlevania, not the new school Symphony the Night Game Boy DS style where you get items and stuff, but the old school style where it's mostly whipping and platforming.
Scott: This is the best one as a game.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It introduced the dangly whip.
Scott: It did.
Scott: The dangly whip.
Rym: The dangly whip, which has survived to this day in the newest Castlevania for the DS.
Scott: In old Castlevania's, if you whipped, you basically the whip came out and the whip went away.
Scott: and that was it.
Scott: This is the first Castlevania where you could hold the whip out and just kind of jiggle it and swing it around and not stop swinging it around.
Scott: You could swing it in a circle.
Scott: You could kind of shake it back and forth.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Just kind of lower it over the edge of a rock and just kind of put it on the skeletons head below you and jiggle it back and forth and the skeleton would slowly die.
Rym: Granted, it's got nothing on Castlevania 2 where one of the items you could get if you did some crazy stuff was a giant diamond that you could throw.
Rym: It would just bounce all around the screen, killing everything.
Scott: But Super Castlevania is excellent.
Scott: Toe Jam and Earl.
Scott: Do you remember this?
Rym: I remember Toe Jam and Earl.
Scott: Toe Jam and Earl for the Sega Genesis is going to be out.
Scott: And R-Type for the TurboGrafx-16, which is perhaps that is the... I already have R-Type for the Game Boy Color also and R-Type too.
Scott: But R-Type for the TurboGrafx-16...
Rym: For the SNES.
Scott: It's exactly the same.
Scott: It's R-Type 1, not R-Type 3 or whatever it was.
Scott: R-Type 1 for the TurboGrafx-16 was pretty much the best incarnation of R-Type ever.
Scott: And that is a classic shooter.
Scott: So basically on Christmas Day, they're bringing out the big guns.
Scott: Not the biggest guns, but pretty big ones.
Scott: Then on New Year's Day, they're going to shaft us.
Scott: They're going to give us baseball and urban champion.
Rym: You know, as much as I like to talk about urban champions, it wasn't a good game.
Scott: No, urban champion is not a good game.
Scott: I mean, it's a nostalgic game.
Scott: It has that kind of value.
Scott: But to play it, maybe five minutes of entertainment.
Rym: Yeah, there aren't many games that old that hold any sort of non-nostalgic value.
Scott: Yeah, and baseball in its day was excellent.
Scott: But as soon as games like Bases Loaded existed...
Rym: Or Baseball Simulator.
Scott: Or Baseball Simulator that had actual fielding that wasn't crap, baseball was useless.
Scott: I mean, it also has some fun nostalgia to it, but...
Rym: Of the early sports games, other than that one football game and Ice Hockey.
Scott: 10 Yard Fight.
Rym: 10 Yard Fight and Ice Hockey.
Rym: None of them really have much longevity.
Scott: Well, the tennis game could have been good, but the controls are just so shitty.
Rym: Well, yeah, but I mean, plus.
Rym: then Mario Tennis for the N64 came out.
Rym: Thereby defining in my mind the genre of tennis.
Scott: Have you ever played Virtua Tennis?
Rym: Actually, yes I have.
Scott: Virtua Tennis is actually... Virtua Tennis is the real tennis game.
Rym: Yeah, but I prefer Mario Tennis.
Scott: I also prefer Mario Tennis, but Virtua Tennis.
Rym: Of course, I always will have the special place in my heart for Ice Hockey.
Rym: Namely because earlier today, I beat Scott 19 to 7.
Scott: Well, you know, you figured out something.
Scott: Because a few days ago, we were pretty much even.
Scott: And then suddenly, you learned something new.
Rym: Well, see, what happened was we got Ice Hockey in the Virtual Console.
Rym: We played it twice, when just the two of us were in the house.
Rym: And both times, Scott won by one point.
Rym: Then, Alex came over, who did not play Ice Hockey for the previous decade and a half of his life.
Rym: So, I jokingly, while I went to get my laundry, said, "Hey, why don't you two play Ice
Rym: Hockey?".
Rym: By the time I got back from picking up my laundry, it was halfway through the first period, and Scott was already up by like 12 or 13 to zero.
Scott: It was like, it was a lot.
Scott: I basically got the puck score, got the puck score.
Rym: So, I sit down, I just pick up Alex's guy, and I'm like, "All right, Alex, I'll show you how to do
Rym: it.".
Rym: And I proceed to thwomp Scott into the ground.
Rym: From that moment forward, I won every game by at least a couple of goals, if not a fiery hellstorm.
Scott: Yeah, I think you figured something out.
Scott: that's not good, and I got to figure out, I'll make a comeback soon enough.
Rym: Well, considering that during today's game, you discovered when I told you that while you're doing the face-off, you can use the D-pad to tell which guy to pass the puck to.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Scott: I had always just kind of pushed A and hoped to win the face-off, and sometimes, you know, the puck went, and sometimes didn't go.
Scott: So, I thought it was just sort of a random thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All righty then.
Scott: Things of the day!
Scott: Oh, wow, right, things of the day, shit.
Rym: Yeah, you almost forgot, didn't you?
Scott: Almost did forget, yep.
Rym: Right, so Star Wars, episode four, five, and six, I won't deign to credit episodes one, two, and three in this, are together a great set of films, but what could make them greater?
Rym: Perhaps if you made them silent films, in the old silent film style.
Scott: Yeah, some of the voice acting in them was pretty bad.
Rym: I prefer the sub.
Scott: Yeah, lol, okay.
Rym: All right, so very simply, someone took Star Wars, episodes four, five, and six, and did various magical video trickery to them to make them look exactly like those old silent films, and they did a really freaking good job.
Scott: Basically, they made it black and white, they put, you know, the old film grain on it, they put the funny, you know, you know how they had just the words, that is just the screen with text on it right before the video, and then they played some funny, old-timey, you know, silent film music, and they cut clips from the movie that match that music, it's pretty hilarious.
Rym: Not only that, but they even went so far as to give it that old-timey movie look where the film like sped up and slowed down a little bit while they were recording it, so all the action is quick and kind of jerky.
Scott: It's pretty awesome.
Rym: It's really, really well done.
Rym: And the thing is, if you've seen Star Wars, or pretty much if you listen to GeekNights, you pretty much will get the entire story of Star Wars from this thing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you'll even, if you've seen it enough, you'll know what words people are saying in certain parts, and you'll laugh.
Rym: It goes from, "Where is the
Rym: ambassador?"
Rym: to Ewoks dancing.
Scott: Not that shitty special edition music.
Rym: I can't believe, it's one thing to have something, I'm not gonna start on my right.
Scott: Not gonna start that, all right.
Scott: So, my thing today is pretty awesome.
Scott: There is a company that has existed for a very long time called Oriental Trading Incorporated.
Scott: This you might know because they might send a catalog to your house every once in a while.
Scott: They used to send one to my mom every once in a while.
Scott: Their catalog contains many, many things that are cheap, very, very cheap.
Scott: You ever go to an arcade, and there'll be all those prizes that are like one ticket or five tickets, like a plastic frog, or a bouncy ball, or shit like that.
Scott: Oriental Trading Company sells that shit in bulk.
Scott: Like for five bucks, they'll sell you like a sack of Superballs.
Scott: Huh.
Scott: Yeah, they sell a lot of random, cheap, little kids goodie bag shit.
Rym: I think we've figured out our swag.
Scott: Lol.
Scott: Okay, so one thing they were selling was a pinata.
Scott: Why not sell a pinata?
Rym: All right, all right.
Rym: I mean, nothing burns like an effigy, and pinatas are one of my favorite things in the world.
Scott: This pinata was filled with, you know, the cheap crap that they like to sell.
Scott: However, this pinata was a pinata shaped like a Humvee with little pictures of US soldiers.
Scott: So you- Oh.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Not so tasteful, but manufactured in the Orient.
Scott: Somewhere where people didn't like US soldiers, I guess.
Rym: Or maybe they didn't even think of that.
Scott: I guess they just- Someone made a cheap pinata, and they just put it in their little catalog.
Scott: But the product is no longer available.
Scott: You can no longer purchase the army vehicle pinata for $16 from Oriental Trading.
Rym: Uh, I'm kind of disappointed.
Rym: It's kind of like when Walmart was selling those neo-Nazi things, and everyone went out to buy them as a joke.
Scott: But you can still get assorted color plastic frogs for eight bucks.
Rym: How many do you get for eight bucks?
Rym: Uh,
Rym: 144. 144
Rym: frogs for eight bucks.
Rym: That's a pretty damn good deal.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it's not as good as 100 tacos for $100, but it's right up there.
Scott: If you want useless pieces of plastic, Oriental Trading is where it's at.
Scott: And if you want US soldiers in a Humvee pinatas, if you've got one, awesome.
Rym: You might want to look on eBay.
Scott: You might want to look on eBay.
Scott: It could be a collector's item.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So today, as a show, we realized that we haven't been doing a lot of GeekBacks lately.
Rym: And I'll tell you this.
Rym: There were actually two GeekBacks we were going to do this week that were topical and good.
Rym: Some emails people sent us.
Rym: Forgot to do them.
Rym: Gonna do them next week.
Rym: So to hold you over and also to promote our forums, because the GeekNights forums, the front row crew forums are pretty freaking rocking.
Rym: I mean, compared to all the other podcasts we know, GeekNights has one hell of a community behind it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Let's first say that if you listen to this show, which you must listen to the show, because you're hearing what I'm saying, you should know that we have a forum.
Scott: You go to a website and you can discuss things and threads and such.
Rym: And our listeners have had some interesting debates over the last 250 or so episodes of GeekNights.
Scott: There are many fun things being said and heard in our forums, and you can join them by going to frontrowcrew.com/forum and you apply for membership, then we approve your membership, and then you can post away.
Rym: And if you weren't aware, our forums are very special compared to the rest of the teeming masses of internet heathens.
Rym: You see, we only have one moderator now.
Rym: We're still slowly in the process of getting more moderators, but our wonderful moderator, Mr.
Rym: Period, his job is not only to moderate the forums, but to most importantly, correct the spelling and grammar of anyone who posts.
Rym: If you post in our forums with poor grammar or spelling, it will be corrected in red.
Rym: If you continue to do so, you will be banned.
Rym: As a result, there are no idiots in our forums.
Rym: There are no stupid kids in our forums.
Rym: There are only awesome people and punk kids.
Scott: Yep, that's about it.
Scott: And all of them know how to spell.
Scott: At least enough.
Rym: The few problems we've-- And we've only banned one person ever, and we've banned him twice.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So we thought to promote the forums a little bit, and to entertain all of you, and to take advantage of all the content that our listeners have generated for us over this year and a half, we're just going to go through the forums and respond or generally bring up everything that's come up in these forums.
Rym: Not everything.
Rym: Maybe five percent of the things that have come up.
Scott: Not even.
Rym: Five percent of the things that have come up that are not directly related to or already on the show, or in threads that are directly related to episodes of the show.
Scott: Yeah, we're not going to discuss any, because we have threads that are attached to shows, like this is a thread about this particular episode of GeekNights.
Rym: That's when people bring up such things as, "Wow, Raim, you were totally wrong about X," or "Wow, Scott, you were totally wrong about
Rym: X.".
Scott: Yeah, we're not going to discuss anything in those threads.
Scott: We're only discussing stuff in threads that have topics unrelated to shows that we've done.
Rym: Yes, and also we're not going to bother with some of the biggest and most awesome threads, but there have been some quite epic debates about copyright, religion, politics, religion, religion.
Rym: There are some really...
Scott: Video games.
Rym: Religion.
Rym: Xenosaga.
Scott: Xenosaga.
Rym: There are some really good... I mean, actual good debates.
Rym: If you don't think there's debate left on the internet, check out our forums and search for anything controversial.
Scott: Well, the good debate on the internet is oxymoron.
Scott: It's like honest lawyer, honest politician, et cetera, et cetera.
Rym: Good podcast.
Scott: Good podcast.
Rym: Right, so I guess you can start.
Rym: We both kind of picked out threads we wanted to bring up or bring some attention to.
Scott: Well, the first thread I want to bring attention to, because I wrote a giant freaking post in it, is the first person shooter's thread.
Scott: Basically, we were discussing how Halo is no good because it's just Goldeneye with better graphics and vehicles and how the only people who play Halo or people who didn't play real FPSs on the PC, like Counter-Strike, or people who are no good at those FPSs, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: And, you know, some guy... Water is Poison was like, "All right, what do you think were the groundbreaking FPSs and for what
Scott: reasons?".
Scott: So I made a list of every FPS that I thought was groundbreaking from Wolfenstein 3D up to Half-Life 2.
Rym: Now, while Scott was doing that, I was simultaneously writing my own rant.
Scott: Yeah, it took two posts.
Scott: That's how big this thing was that I wrote.
Scott: And I basically put down every single first person shooter I think was worth a shit and what I know about it and why.
Scott: And then it was pretty long, so you should all go read it.
Rym: Yeah, especially our dear friend Conrad out there, even though happy birthday, Conrad.
Rym: His birthday was recently.
Rym: But he tried to argue with us during one of the front row crew parties, actually the Macross party up in the Northern Geek House, that Halo was a pretty good game and that there's nothing special about using the keyboard and mouse to play an FPS.
Rym: And I highly recommend that he read that thread because it's not just us talking.
Rym: We actually cite some expert opinions there.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's definitely true that a lot of people say, "Oh, you're just not used to the
Scott: gamepad.".
Scott: Well, that's bullshit because I use gamepads for plenty of games.
Scott: I've been using gamepads longer than I've been using mouse and keyboards.
Rym: Our friend Scott Johnson, who I think one of the driving philosophies in his life is to get the maximum amount of entertainment out of video games and DVDs for the least amount of money.
Rym: And this man is a legend.
Rym: No matter what con we go to, no matter how good a deal I think I got on all the box sets I found for like a dollar from some homeless guy in the street, he'll
Scott: always come
Rym: back at the end of the day with three times as many DVDs as any of us for at least half the money.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: And he does the same thing with video games.
Rym: He has like every GameCube game.
Rym: But he plays all those console FPSs and even he seems to at least realize that computer FPSs with a keyboard and mouse are infinitely better.
Scott: Yes, I've never met anyone who argues in favor of the console FPS without a mouse and keyboard with a gamepad who has actually played significant PC FPSs with mice and keyboards.
Rym: Pretty much if you played at least a half of the list of games that we listed, you know, Doom, Quake 2 and all the mods, Half-Life mods, all those things, then you probably are able to make a judgment.
Scott: And you'll probably say mouse and keyboard on a PC.
Rym: Yeah, now of course we're not, I mean console FPSs do have their benefits in that you're all sitting in the same room and there's that LAN party camaraderie without the trouble of a LAN party.
Rym: But I've been to LAN parties and LAN parties, if you think you like FPSs, if you go to an actual LAN party and play FPSs there, it'll blow your goddamn mind.
Rym: Oh good God, the fun I've had at LAN parties back in high school.
Rym: Before I had a LAN.
Scott: I'm hoping that fun comes back as Portal and Team Fortress 2 come out.
Rym: Oh, Team Fortress 2.
Rym: I have such a hard-on for the game.
Rym: But anyway, there was a really cool thread a while ago, started by Scott Johnson, actually comes up again, or Kremlien in the forums, about your Dungeons & Dragons scores if you were a character in D&D.
Rym: But not in terms of taking one of those stupid quizzes online or anything, but he basically asked everyone to sit down, think about what those scores mean, and as objectively and rationally as you can, come up with and defend what your ability scores are in the real world.
Rym: And it was surprisingly, everyone who posted, posted a very well thought out, very, in most cases, humble, or at least realistic assessment of how smart and pretty and strong and fast they are.
Scott: Yeah, I think the only problem with that is, you know, in the D&D world, like, it's real tough to compare those numbers to the actual real world.
Rym: Not really, I mean, like, for strength, it's very clear how much can you lift over your head, and there's a direct correlation.
Scott: The problem is we are all not, we don't have any class levels in any PC class, so in the D&D world, we really should all just have 10s and 11s and stuff.
Rym: No, we have high ability scores, we just don't have class levels.
Rym: A peasant can have an 18 strength.
Scott: Not often, it's super rare.
Scott: And an 18 strength is like freaking Zangief.
Rym: Plus remember, because the basic ability scores range from three to 18, and the way probability rolls, they end up being effectively a bell curve.
Rym: So as a result, all you have to do is try to compare yourself and your ability in a given attribute to the average human being, and then try to figure out what percentile you're in, and from that you can come up with a very hard number as to your ability score.
Scott: If you assume the D&D scale is perfect.
Rym: Well no, it's not.
Rym: We use the D&D scale.
Scott: Yeah, the only other problem with the D&D scale is that basically two numbers are identical, like for all intents and purposes, 12 and 13 are the same.
Rym: Well, not if you ignore the ability bonuses and you go by second ed, or you go by the bell curve idea.
Scott: If we could have done second ed, it would actually have been a lot easier, because second ed has more information to determine those things.
Rym: Well, most of our friends don't have second ed books.
Scott: I know, neither do I.
Rym: See, it surprises me that I played second ed more.
Rym: I've still played more second ed D&D than I have played third ed D&D.
Scott: I played second ed D&D, just not much of it.
Rym: I played a lot of it.
Scott: Like two portions of two different campaigns.
Rym: Dude, I played regular D&D before I decided to switch to advanced Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: I never actually played regular D&D ever.
Rym: But I think the thread was pretty cool, and everyone did a really good job of within the constraints of this argument, assessing themselves.
Rym: I thought it was a neat thread.
Rym: I'm not going to go through and read everyone's ability scores, because that would take forever.
Scott: That's a good point.
Scott: All right, check this thread.
Scott: This thread was called Eggnog question mark, started by Rym.
Rym: Oh yes, I remember this thread.
Scott: So Rym says, "So does anyone out there actually like Eggnog?
Scott: Maybe I've just never had good nog, but I find this stuff vile, and it's made me queasy every time I've tried it, alcohol or
Scott: no.".
Scott: Well, personally, I've never had Eggnog, because I know that's no good.
Rym: Really?
Rym: You've never had Eggnog?
Scott: Well, I know it's no good.
Scott: Why should I even bother?
Rym: You know, actually, I'll say this.
Rym: Knowing your tastes, I mean, you can make non-alcoholic Eggnog.
Rym: I think you would like Eggnog.
Scott: Probably not, no.
Rym: I really think you would.
Rym: I know what kind of shit you like.
Scott: You're crazy.
Scott: You always think you know what shit I like, and then you don't know.
Rym: Well, it's pretty easy.
Rym: You don't like much shit.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Scott: You don't like shit.
Rym: You complain about that you can't drink anything carbonated, or with fructose corn syrup in it.
Scott: Is it water juice or milk?
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: So I'm not going to drink it.
Rym: Eggnog is mostly milk and egg.
Rym: Egg?
Rym: You'll eat egg.
Scott: But it's like raw egg.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Ew.
Scott: Raw eggs, great.
Scott: No, it's terrible.
Rym: I've eaten raw eggs.
Scott: When I eat eggs, I want them as non-liquid as possible.
Rym: God, when you eat eggs, you eat McDonald's egg.
Rym: I'm going to enlighten our listeners here.
Rym: I hate to make fun of Scott.
Rym: I know you all think that I'm mean to Scott.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with my eggs.
Rym: You all think I'm mean to Scott, but for anyone who is a member of the front row crew, they can tell you that, in fact, it is the opposite.
Scott: You suck.
Rym: I got to bring this up.
Rym: The way Scott cooks eggs is he takes a bunch of eggs and cracks them into some sort of container.
Rym: He then whips them, doesn't add water or salt or milk or anything to them.
Rym: He takes a hot pan.
Rym: He dumps the egg into the pan.
Rym: He waits until it's a solid mass.
Rym: He dumps it out.
Scott: I put salt on it and then I eat it.
Rym: Yeah, after you've cooked it.
Scott: Sometimes if I have some salami.
Rym: That's how McDonald's makes its eggs.
Scott: I'll put salami in the egg while it's in the pan to make salami and eggs.
Rym: You don't know how to make eggs.
Rym: Your eggs are disgusting.
Scott: You don't know how to make eggs.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Everyone who comes over when I make them eggs says, "Wow, Rym, those are really good
Rym: eggs.".
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: They just don't know what that is.
Rym: All right, tell you what.
Rym: At the New Year's party, you make a McDonald's egg.
Scott: It's not a McDonald's egg.
Rym: I'll make a real egg.
Rym: We'll blindfold some people and have them try both and we'll see what they say.
Scott: I like my egg.
Scott: I don't like eggs to be wet.
Scott: They got to be dry.
Rym: My eggs are wet.
Scott: Yeah, they are.
Rym: No, they're not.
Rym: They're not wet.
Rym: They're as wet as an egg is.
Scott: Eggs are really, really wet.
Scott: I like eggs to be solid and dry.
Rym: You like eggs to be a uniform dense mass of yellow matter.
Scott: That's what tastes good.
Scott: That's terrible.
Scott: It's awesome.
Rym: You don't even make scrambled eggs.
Rym: You just make a massive egg.
Scott: That's what I want is a massive egg.
Rym: All right, to continue with the threads here of Eggnog.
Rym: There was a thread about bathing and showering, which is kind of related to an episode we did, but there was an interesting comment from Ugly Fred, who has visited our house on several occasions.
Rym: I would contend that the shower in your house is one of those tap the top of the dial and get 10 degrees hotter showers.
Rym: Every time I come over, I have to spend like five minutes adjusting the fucking thing until it's just right because the threshold between uncomfortably cold and all caps burning your skin off hot is about an eighth of an inch of turning.
Scott: I don't really have a problem with that.
Rym: That's because we're used to it.
Scott: It could be because we're used to it, but I think it's also because burning your skin off hot is the temperature I set it in.
Rym: I will note that Scott takes showers so hot.
Scott: Is this just going to be the show of?
Scott: go through the forum and every single thread talk about how Scott thinks about it?
Rym: That was my plan.
Rym: Great.
Rym: This one's not really making fun of you though.
Rym: I wasn't going to make fun of you.
Rym: I was just going to note that Scott takes showers so hot that if I tried to take a shower after him, as opposed to before him, I can barely breathe from the level of steam that is condensed into that room.
Scott: We don't have a sauna, so why not?
Rym: Why don't we get a sauna?
Scott: Because we have a shower.
Scott: What do we need a sauna for?
Rym: Saunas are a lot nicer because you can sit in a sauna.
Rym: Actually, my grandpa had a sauna.
Rym: That was basically a thing that would boil the water and make steam and then a tent that you sat in and the tent went up and covered your whole body.
Rym: You could sit in a chair in.
Rym: it really comfy and it was a nice chair in there.
Rym: But the top had a hole for the neck that sealed around the neck.
Rym: So you could sit there and watch TV or do whatever you were doing or read a book or hang out, but you're in this sauna at the same time.
Scott: Okay, that's a little crazy.
Scott: And where the hell are we going to put that?
Scott: And it's against our lease.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: The only things against our lease are pools and hot tubs.
Rym: Saunas aren't bodies of water.
Rym: The only reason those things are against the lease is because they're too heavy.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I mean, we can't even play DDR in our living room.
Rym: We're not going to be able to put a hot tub in there.
Scott: No, no, we're not.
Rym: But a sauna, they're actually pretty cheap.
Rym: I've considered getting one.
Scott: It's all you.
Rym: To go with the bidet.
Rym: All right, you got a thread?
Scott: Uh, let me pick one here.
Scott: Oh, I got to mention this one.
Scott: There's a big thread by this guy named Kie.
Scott: K-I-E-Y.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: Kie.
Rym: Kie.
Scott: It's a thread about wiimote modding.
Scott: Apparently, this guy wants to put a cool design on his wiimote.
Scott: He's tired of the plain white wiimote.
Scott: And he put up some pictures of some pretty cool designs of what he wants to make his wiimote look like.
Scott: And they're pretty cool.
Scott: He's got some art skills going on there.
Scott: And thus, the thread continues to this day with the saga of what he has done to mod his wiimote.
Scott: All the different-- he's like, try different paints and different screwdrivers.
Scott: And also, now he's going to try some dye, some vinyl dye really soon.
Scott: And he's going to see what it takes to mod your wiimote to make it look cool and put designs on it.
Scott: So if you're interested in doing that or just seeing the results, be they horrible or awesome, you should check this thread out.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: And you get to see the inside of a wiimote, which you can see on a bunch of other websites, but whatever.
Rym: So a while ago, we were doing an episode, and I talked about how I left work when I was done with my time.
Rym: And even though that there was still work to be done, but it was beyond my hours.
Rym: It was time for me to leave, and I had to go.
Rym: I had plans, so I left.
Rym: And someone started a thread.
Rym: It was Thayed who started it about a work ethic.
Rym: And he basically makes the point that-- let's see.
Rym: "Doctor, this one's been difficult.
Rym: I know he's been open for eight hours, but it's going to take another six hours to save his life.
Rym: Nurse Rym, I'm not that kind of guy.
Rym: I'm out of
Rym: here.".
Rym: And he extrapolates through the whole thing, basically saying that-- and a lot of other people seem to go along with him that, wow, how could you just leave your work when the work is not done?
Rym: I would fire someone like you.
Rym: And I would just like to point out that at least it's been my experience and the experience of a lot of the people I have known in my life that have jobs.
Rym: Yeah, not just you, but a lot of people.
Rym: And not even just our geek friends, but older people, adults, people who are 20 or 30 years older than us, that most jobs, if you work the 40 hours a week and you're smart enough to do good work during that time, they're not going to fire you if you refuse to do unpaid overtime.
Rym: In fact, most companies seem like, in general, they'll just walk all over you.
Rym: And if you work unpaid overtime, they'll keep giving you unpaid overtime because they know that you won't fight it and you'll do it anyway.
Rym: And it seems that most of the people who work this unpaid overtime are people who don't have the balls to tell their employer, no, I'm not going to do that without compensation.
Rym: And I've also found that the people who refuse to do the overtime generally are actually the ones who get the promotions anyway.
Scott: Yeah, because the people who are smart enough and bold enough to not work overtime tend to be the people who have more skills and better things to do with their time than be at work.
Rym: Or they would finish all the work they were given in 10 hours anyway, and they're only staying the 40 hours to make it look like they're doing some work anyway.
Rym: So they're not going to stay an extra few hours because you failed to plan properly in allocating your resources as a company.
Scott: And the other thing is all the examples he gives of a doctor, a fireman, oh, sorry, I got to go.
Scott: My time's up.
Scott: Those aren't jobs where you're hired to work x hours.
Scott: We're in the IT industry.
Scott: They pay us x dollars to work x hours a day.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's not like we pay you to do this particular thing.
Scott: If I had a contract job, let's say I had a contract.
Scott: The contract would say, get this work done by this time on this date.
Scott: And it didn't matter how many hours I worked.
Scott: As long as I got that work done by that date, nothing else matters.
Scott: If you're a fireman, your job is when there's a fire, put it out.
Scott: It's all about job description and responsibilities.
Rym: And also how important the work is to you and to your company and all that and how much you care.
Scott: And how much your company cares about you.
Scott: I mean, my company, I don't do shit and they don't seem to notice or care or anything.
Rym: Or when I work at conventions, I mean, I was staffing at amazement and I had put in more than the time that I was required to put in.
Rym: I had done a lot of work and I was on my way to have a cocktail, wander back to the room and go to bed.
Rym: And I had my cocktail.
Rym: And then as I'm walking back to the room, exhausted, someone runs up and says, there's an emergency.
Rym: We need someone to cover the video game room until close.
Rym: And there was no one around.
Rym: So I said, all right, I'll do it.
Rym: And I stood there for another two and a half hours guarding the video game room until finally the click on ended for the night and I could go to bed.
Rym: I worked that unpaid overtime because that was important to me and I cared about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if my job was like GeekNights, I would just work on it all the time.
Rym: Whatever constant over time.
Rym: If I was my own boss.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: But when I work for a company, they're paying me for 40 hours worth of my time or well and or however much work they either how much work they can get out of me in 40 hours a week or however much work they expect out of me in 40 hours a week.
Scott: As long as their expectation is not unreasonable.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: If your work for a company that actually would fire you for refusing to do unpaid overtime, then you're working for the wrong company and you could probably easily get a job elsewhere unless you live in the middle of nowhere where there aren't jobs.
Rym: See, we live in downstate New York where the jobs compete for us and not the other way around.
Rym: I don't go to a job interview thinking.
Rym: I hope they give me this job.
Rym: I go to job interviews thinking, do I want this job as opposed to that other job?
Rym: Which job am I going to accept?
Scott: Yeah, that's what I go into interviews like.
Scott: I'm like, all right, is which is this job awesome?
Scott: I don't know if it's that.
Rym: when I interviewed for my current company and when I interviewed for IBM way back, I asked them more questions about their benefits and the pain, what they were going to do for me.
Rym: Then they asked me about my job skills.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So you got one?
Rym: No, let's do two more.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Two more quick ones.
Scott: Quick ones, you say?
Rym: Okay, all right.
Rym: Oh, because I got one.
Scott: This is actually an old thread from July, but it's been keeps coming back for the dead like a zombie.
Rym: Holy crap.
Scott: It's called the big headphones versus earbuds debate.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I can weigh in here.
Rym: I don't even care what people say in that thread.
Rym: Headphones and earbuds are two tools that have two different uses and two different situations where they are useful.
Rym: There's no debate.
Rym: You use whichever one suits whatever your task is at the time.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is, is that some people use like headphones when they should use earbuds and vice versa.
Scott: And that is a problem.
Scott: So I think people need to like, it's like people using hammers instead of screwdrivers and vice versa.
Scott: I don't know what they're thinking.
Rym: Well, if all you have is a hammer, everyone looks like Trotsky.
Scott: Yeah, here's what that was.
Rym: Nice pick.
Scott: Here's what it comes down to.
Scott: Headphones, the big kind that cover your whole ear are only useful if you're not on the go.
Scott: I know a lot of people take these things out in the street.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: You look like a doofus.
Scott: A doofus.
Rym: No.
Scott: Do not bring headphones, big ones outside of your house unless you are a DJ or some other such thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: If you're a professional DJ, if you derive 51% or more of your income from DJing and DJ related activities, you are perfectly justified in wearing the biggest headphones you can find as a public accessory.
Rym: Think of it as like a badge.
Scott: You can wear them around your neck, like on the subway, but you cannot put them on your ears and listen to anything unless you are currently engaging in the act of DJing.
Rym: Or I'd say if you are a professional DJ, it's okay to have mine.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: If I saw DJ Jin Ai in the street and he had headphones on, I wouldn't think, "Ah,
Rym: tacky.".
Rym: I'd think, "Yo,
Rym: DJ."
Rym: Whatever.
Scott: But also, why would you bring them around?
Scott: They're so big and clumsy.
Scott: Where the hell are you putting them?
Rym: Also, headphones are either big and really, really cheap, or big and expensive, but they're actually cheap, or they're big and expensive.
Rym: If they're big and expensive, don't carry them around because they're also fragile.
Rym: Good monitor headphones are very expensive.
Scott: I'm using the same- I mean, the really fancy ones, like you have to solder the things together yourself.
Scott: They come in pieces.
Rym: I mean, I'm using the same monitor headphones that I've had for over a decade.
Rym: I've repaired them numerous times because I don't feel like spending the crazy amount of money you would take to get another equivalent pair of monitor headphones.
Scott: Anyway, earbuds, like the classic iPod earbuds, are basically useless and you should never use them ever.
Rym: No, because they're actually dangerous for your hearing.
Scott: Well, see, they're not dangerous for the hearing on their own.
Rym: They're dangerous for your hearing if you ever use them in situations where there is significant ambient noise.
Scott: Well, no, they still won't hurt your hearing unless you put the volume up.
Rym: Yes, Scott, if you're in a situation with significant ambient noise, you have to put the volume up or you can't hear it.
Scott: That's right, but if you refrain from putting the volume up, even when there is ambient noise, you won't hurt your ears.
Rym: But usually the level at which it'll harm you is well below the level at which you can hear whatever you're trying to listen to.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So your choices are either hurt your hearing, only use earbuds in very quiet places, or suffer and not be able to hear what's coming out of them in situations where you would normally turn the volume up.
Rym: Yeah, we won't really go into all the details here, but just read that thread and buy isolation earbuds.
Rym: Get isolation earbuds.
Rym: Insertion, isolation, insertion, whatnot.
Scott: Because they make a suction cup in your ear and they keep the sound out, and thus they let you keep the volume low while still being able to hear and you don't have to carry big-ass headphones around.
Rym: So we've had a bunch of good debates about spelling and grammar and pronunciation.
Rym: And one of our listeners, Kalarni, often corrects us when we pronounce things incorrectly, or at least in his eyes incorrectly.
Rym: And I would just like to note that he, a while ago, called me out on pronouncing asbestos the way I do.
Rym: And over the last two months, by listening to various documentaries and news things and watching things, with one exception, everyone I have listened to says it exactly the way I say it, including two professional asbestos removers, one of whom is a person who removes it for the military, and one of them is a person who studies the effects of asbestos and all those diseases associated with asbestos, like lung cancer.
Rym: All the professionals and all the people in the BBC and all the people in NPR, without exception, say it the way I say it.
Rym: So, uh, big double-deuce.
Rym: Double-double-deuce.
Scott: Totally fun.
Rym: So yeah, we're all right.
Rym: And screw whatever that WAV file was that you posted.
Rym: We also there had a good argument about.
Rym: people tried to complain that the English language is somehow wasteful by using, you know, redundant letters and C and K are kind of the same and that sort of thing.
Rym: And I would like to point read a short post that I think defines that argument and defines both Scott and mine opinion on it very succinctly.
Rym: In English, the structure of our words provides a great deal of secondary data that our brains use to more quickly process what we read.
Rym: The extra letters give us clues as the origins, meanings, and histories of words.
Rym: They give otherwise similar words distinct symbol shapes that can be processed as a unit as opposed to the more purely phonetic languages that must be processed sound by sound.
Rym: They provide redundancy, which allows even garbled messages to be partially understood.
Rym: The complexity and redundancy of English spelling are some of the language's greatest strengths.
Rym: Pronunciation is a definite drawback, but the benefits seem to outweigh.
Scott: Yeah, I do think there are some words that don't follow the rules.
Rym: Like what?
Scott: I can't think of any right now.
Rym: Name one.
Rym: Besides, you've got to admit, it would bother you if people spelled knigget without the G and the K.
Scott: Of course, of course, but I'm saying there are just some words that-- Name a word.
Scott: I can't think of one right now.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I'll get back to you.
Rym: Yeah, get back with me.
Rym: We'll do a whole show on it.
Scott: All right.
Rym: We'll do a whole show on the English language.
Scott: You want to keep going?
Rym: We should probably stop.
Scott: Okay, let's stop.
Rym: I'll end it with this one, and I'm just going to read it.
Rym: I'm not going to follow up on it in any way, but Brian Shrimp posted a while ago on November 18th.
Rym: "I had a dream tonight that I was listening to GeekNights, and they linked us to this photo of a smashed up PS3 when someone had dropped it.
Rym: At least I think this was a dream.
Rym: Can anyone laugh or
Rym: verify?".
Rym: We did not, in fact, talk about a PS3 being dropped at any point.
Scott: No, but you might want to go to smashmyps3.com.
Rym: I think you better call Randy.
Scott: You might.
Rym: Actually, Kiwi Bird posted, "I was once laying in my bed listening to GeekNights.
Rym: The funny thing was my earbuds had fallen out and I was imagining the entire
Rym: thing.".
Scott: Okay.
Rym: A Merry Christmas, a Happy Hanukkah, a crazy Kwanzaa.
Rym: I can't think of any other holiday.
Scott: For the rest of us.
Rym: A glorious Festivus for the rest of us.
Rym: You can bet that we'll have our Festivus poll in the airing of Grievances.
Rym: Anyone who celebrates the solstice, I'm right there with you.
Scott: Noel, whatever.
Rym: Berna Yule Log.
Scott: Yule whatnot.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I'd say Happy New Year, but we got a whole week of shows next week and we'll probably have a New Year's special.
Scott: Uh-oh.
Scott: That's dangerous.
Rym: Before we end, as I did all week, I don't think anyone listens to the Thursday shows who doesn't listen to at least one other day, so this is probably redundant.
Rym: I'll be very succinct.
Rym: If you like GeekNights and you're a member of Digg, Digg.com, D-I-G-G.com, please, please, please, if you like GeekNights enough, go there and Digg us.
Rym: We are already beating out most of our friend podcasts in most categories that matter and we would like to keep it that way.
Scott: We mostly want it for humorous value, like, "Ha ha ha, you think you have more listeners than we do?
Scott: Look at how many Digg's we
Scott: have.".
Rym: The fact that we have five feeds makes it hilarious because Anime World Order finally beat us by a couple Digg's in the anime category, well, the anime search category.
Rym: However, our main GeekNights feed still beats them by a lot, so it's like, "GeekNights, Anime World
Rym: Order.".
Scott: It's like Anime World Order, which is a whole podcast just about anime, beat out the Wednesday shows of GeekNights by a few Digg's.
Rym: They're sandwiched between GeekNights and GeekNights.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And while you're at it, consider this a plug.
Rym: There is a podcast called Fast Karate for the Gentlemen and it is one of my favorite podcasts.
Rym: In fact, both us and Anime World Order steal quite a bit of our humor from them on a regular basis.
Scott: Hey, they just came out with a new episode while we were recording this one.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: I'm downloading it right now.
Rym: I'm going to listen to that on my drive to Rochester.
Scott: It's called Soronary.
Rym: So if you like Fast Karate or if you like Gentlemen, not only should you listen to Fast Karate for the Gentlemen, but while you're digging GeekNights with your massive botnet of shill accounts, I highly recommend that you also do the same for Fast Karate.
Rym: They currently have eight Digg's and they deserve at least 12 or 13.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.