Rym: It's Tuesday November 14th.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We review an old classic dig dug for the Atari 7800.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So I'm actually doing work find a new job, oh really it's kind of weird because every time Previously I've ever looked for a new job.
Scott: It's always been like oh, man.
Scott: I need a job.
Scott: I don't have one right now, but now I'm looking for a job.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I've got a job, so I'm just like ha ha You better offer me something good, or I'm not leaving.
Scott: I'm fine where I am.
Rym: See I'm doing something different for the first time too.
Rym: instead of looking for a new job right now I'm looking more to see if I can get a gigantic raise or a promotion at my current job.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: I've never actually you know tried to climb the corporate ladder in any way.
Scott: Well.
Rym: I just want more money.
Rym: I don't care about the corporate ladder.
Rym: I just I want more money, and I'm overqualified for my position.
Scott: Yeah, I applied for actually a bunch of jobs.
Scott: just one of them I happen to interview for today on the phone, but like I applied for some managerial position Which actually be pretty cool if I had that because you know imagine a job where all I do is talk to people and do Papers.
Rym: be so easy now because I've done stuff like that and it's kind of easy.
Rym: But at the same time you're managing people because usually those people don't know what to do on their own.
Scott: Yeah, but I imagine if I'm managing programmers We speak the same language, so I could definitely get them to do what I want.
Rym: We'll see we'll see.
Scott: I only applied for it.
Scott: I sent someone a resume.
Scott: It's basically nothing yeah, so I'm just pointing that out that I did that.
Scott: But yeah the guy on the phone He didn't really ask me the tough technical questions that have been asked in the past.
Scott: And I'm I'm sort of afraid with the job I interviewed for because it's like writing Linux kernel modules which I haven't done But I believe I am capable of learning.
Rym: well you're gonna buy that book.
Scott: yeah Decided it's real.
Scott: I looked at the book in the borders, and it's actually writing Linux kernel modules Isn't as tricky as I thought it was but it you know it's still tricky, and I'm actually real interested.
Scott: I'm probably gonna do it whether I get a job doing it or not.
Rym: so yeah Maybe we could write some drivers for these Sony recordy bits not without document.
Rym: do some reverse engineering.
Scott: Yes, that's the one thing.
Scott: I could probably write a driver for a piece of hardware if I had the documentation for it But without documentation.
Scott: I got nothing.
Scott: I'm basically hopeless.
Rym: yeah Yeah, so we only have one news really.
Rym: But that news has far-reaching ramifications for if you're not aware which means you know you're living under a rock Maybe you're blind and deaf.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe you've never heard of this internet thing, but the ps3 the PlayStation 3 was released in Japan three days ago And there's a lot of news about this and it's coming out in the u.s..
Scott: Three days from today.
Scott: well tonight and the Wii comes out five days from tonight and Since next week.
Scott: I'm gonna get the Wii on launch at the Nintendo store.
Scott: so next week All we're being able to talk about is we.
Scott: it's gonna be we we we we.
Scott: so it's gonna be we right now.
Scott: We're gonna cover all things ps3 to get it out of the way, so we don't have to talk about next week.
Rym: Well also, there's so much.
Scott: there is so much.
Scott: It's gonna take up the whole news.
Rym: remember way back when you know the Jack Thompson rule.
Rym: I won't talk about Jack Thompson or Sony unless they top themselves.
Scott: Well.
Scott: This isn't really a Sony story It's a PlayStation story.
Scott: It's like if I had a story about a specific like the Ford Taurus.
Scott: It's not a Ford.
Rym: so you know.
Scott: I would say this is a Sony story because Sony is pretty well Maybe parts of it or so no stories and parts of it or PlayStation.
Rym: Sony is pretty much putting their whole bank on the Ps3 and blu-ray.
Rym: if the ps3 doesn't do well Sony's in deep.
Rym: It's not gonna do so.
Scott: well Sony's already you know whatever.
Scott: why it's not what?
Scott: what do you mean?
Scott: What?
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: whatever?
Scott: well?
Scott: They're already not in like huge financial gains compared to what they were in the walk I actually from that.
Scott: not only are they not gains But they've been doing very poorly across the board and even so PlayStation isn't like a large portion of their business Businesses still selling TVs and shit.
Rym: actually they put more money into the PlayStation 3 than they've put into pretty much anything.
Rym: yeah, the PlayStation 3 and blu-ray are the future flagships of Sony and We'll see what happens with that.
Scott: And I wouldn't.
Scott: I don't think Sony is gonna be going like out of business or anything like that anytime soon.
Rym: I think Sony's gonna be in a lot of trouble in the next couple years.
Rym: I think there's gonna be some layoffs.
Rym: I don't think so, but anyway to start off They only sold eighty eight thousand four hundred ps3s over the course of two days.
Scott: But how many did they release?
Scott: a hundred thousand?
Rym: I think they said they released a hundred thousand But I haven't seen anything that directly confirms this.
Rym: that I would trust.
Rym: But from what all I've read a lot of the news sites are reporting that Almost all of the ps3s sold out which would lead me to believe that not all of them sold.
Scott: Hmm it's a tough call because if not all of them sold then either they didn't ship the hundred thousand they said and they did all sell or Why are people buying these things at such high prices in stores if not all of them sold?
Rym: Well, it could be that some of them just haven't been registered as sold yet.
Rym: It could be that the people who don't have one now are bidding on those auction sites because even though there's a few left They know they can't get one anyway.
Scott: Hmm or maybe Sony didn't actually ship a hundred thousand could be you know what whichever the answer is I have no idea But the numbers that are reported by websites say that a hundred thousand were supposed to be shipped and like in two days 88,000 sold.
Scott: you would expect you know any console would sell all hundred thousand in the first day.
Scott: Yeah, but it's Japan who knows craziness well.
Rym: more importantly I think this is the big news eight eight thousand four hundred ps3s were sold.
Scott: how many ps3 games were sold I don't know, but there weren't that great a launch games.
Scott: I mean what they have Ridge racers seven.
Scott: There was a Gundam game which actually look pretty cool And I don't know any of the other games.
Scott: really they didn't.
Scott: at least none were well known or cool.
Rym: Well the answer is that 62,000 one.
Rym: oh no no I'm looking at the wrong number nevermind.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: just under 80,000 games were sold.
Rym: the ps3 sold less games than Ps3s.
Rym: more people bought ps3s than bought ps3 games.
Scott: well what this tells me is a couple things.
Scott: number one Someone's buying this thing just as a blu-ray player Which if you're after a blu-ray player is not such a bad idea because a blu-ray player costs more money than a ps3.
Scott: Number two it's actually it's a computer.
Scott: You can install Linux on this thing and use it.
Rym: no one bought a ps3 for that purpose now.
Scott: So I think someone at least one guy bought it to use as a computer.
Rym: I doubt it.
Rym: It's especially in Japan.
Scott: Well yeah, but I mean for the power of the PlayStation power that you really can't access so readily.
Scott: you can install Linux on it You're just fine.
Rym: now cuz the cell processor is not that standard or well understood by most people and anyone trying to use The ps3 as a computer is gonna run into a lot of problems.
Scott: Yeah, but some awesome you think about the Linux hacker in Japan has got it already so he can you know?
Scott: Compile all these open source programs for cell and start shipping them out.
Rym: Yeah, whatever I don't see that being a factor as not many people, but this is one guy I don't think it's even any.
Rym: I don't think anyone who has the money and the care to buy a ps3 cares about Linux.
Scott: I think that there I think I don't think it's people that care about the ps3 care about Linux and these people Care about Linux have care now care about the ps3 because it runs Linux.
Rym: Well, I would furthermore say that anyone who does that it's not a useful endeavor.
Rym: the ps3 is not going to be a useful computer.
Rym: Computers themselves are going to far outpace the ps3 in short order anyway but it does.
Scott: if it it really depends on how useful as a computer will be because First of all getting a blu-ray drive in your computer is very expensive more expensive than buying a ps3.
Scott: Well that is true and someone might want a blu-ray drive in a computer and to well wait wait wait.
Rym: Someone might want a blu-ray drive.
Rym: There's such a small market for blu-ray or HD DVD at all in the first place.
Scott: Yeah, but also the PlayStation 3 has really good TV outputs.
Scott: So you know like how we have the Mac plugged into the TV?
Scott: And there's an obvious difference between plugging it into the computer screen.
Scott: if you have a PlayStation 3 with an HD Cable plugged into your HD TV.
Scott: That's a pretty good computer with TV output right there.
Rym: But you'd get a similar or if not better thing by plugging a regular computer into a regular computer monitor.
Scott: Yeah, but what if you want to get a computer that plugs into a TV?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: if you just what are you gonna use it for?
Rym: I mean if you're using it as a computer You're better off using a monitor.
Rym: if you're using it to watch stuff most stuff you watch from the internet is not HD Anyway, and it'll look just fine on a normal TV with a normal RCA connection.
Scott: I'm just saying that you know I know.
Rym: I'm just saying that I don't think anyone who is smart enough to think it through would buy the ps3 as a.
Scott: The final reason that they've sold less games than ps3s is obviously because a lot of people bought ps3s just to sell on eBay And that means you don't buy any games.
Rym: There are somewhat dubious reports that one gentleman through a small network of homeless people purchased about a hundred ps3s.
Scott: I don't know how much I believe that story, but it could be going to resell all of them.
Rym: But the news and this has been reported in several places Is that the majority of the ps3s according to shop owners were purchased by homeless people and Chinese nationals?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and most of them look like they were being purchased by these people for the express purpose of being shunted through some sort of Gray-market and resold at a profit.
Rym: someone was going around rounding up bums and paying them to buy ps3s.
Scott: So we're gonna go on Sunday.
Scott: We're gonna round up bums and get him to buy wheeze And we're gonna sell them all on a gray market somewhere.
Rym: Why don't we just do that with a ps3?
Scott: Because it's a lot more money to get it started up.
Scott: We need the money to buy enough ps3s.
Rym: We wouldn't we?
Rym: even if we bought one ps3 and sold it that but then we wouldn't need a bum to do it.
Rym: Yes, we would because I don't want to sit in line for two days Pay a bum, you know two bottles of MD 2020 and five bucks to buy a third bottle of MD 2020 At a later day, how do you know?
Scott: He just won't take your PlayStation 3 money and then buy a crate of MD 2020.
Rym: Well depends if you find a stupid bum you stick a collar on his arm and tell him it'll explode.
Rym: He doesn't come back.
Rym: Or or you simply say I will find you and kill you.
Rym: I have people watching you.
Rym: I will be in that.
Scott: Okay, you'd have to be a really stupid bum.
Rym: You know what if he's a hobo?
Rym: He's probably not that bright to begin with But regardless of all that at least the ps3 is out and people are starting are starting to use them though I have seen almost no reviews of actual Usage of the ps3.
Rym: all anyone talks about is either that they got one or that they tried to get one But no one's talking about the game.
Scott: I've seen if some talk about Comparisons between Ridge Racer 7 on the ps3 and Ridge Racer 6 on the 360 and basically what they're talking about is graphics Which I don't give a shit about but they they're showing these pictures of what the same Track with the same car looks like on both systems and in some ways the ps3 looks a lot better Like it's brighter and shinier and looks like higher resolution.
Scott: I don't think the resolutions actually higher.
Scott: I think it's both 720p but whatever.
Scott: but in other ways the PlayStation threes graphics aren't as good like this.
Scott: Models missing, you know that are in the 360 and there's different details on different things.
Scott: So it's tough to objectively say which one is graphically superior playing that this is almost the same game.
Scott: But a lot of people like oh man the ps3 sucks.
Scott: It doesn't look as good as the 360 and other people like oh man 360 looks just fine.
Scott: the ps3, you know, whatever.
Rym: But yeah The one problem that a lot of people have reported is that the backward compatibility with ps2 games isn't working.
Scott: So well That's a toughie because you know, there's not too many ps3 games out right now.
Scott: So someone who buys this to play games.
Scott: They're probably gonna be looking to play downloaded games and I don't think the download network is working yet.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know anything about that.
Scott: Yeah, and They're gonna want to play some ps2 games on it.
Scott: and whether they say almost 200 ps2 games don't work?
Rym: according to CNET Japan currently 196 ps2 titles have been reported as to not play at all.
Scott: Are people just?
Scott: it's like a hundred and people trying to play games and calling them in or did someone sit there with every ps2 Game trying to play them one by one.
Rym: I see a lot of reports and I think it's people calling in Wow cuz no one bought games for the ps3.
Rym: So what are they gonna use it for to play old Gran Turismo?
Scott: Yeah Kingdom Hearts 2.
Rym: Yeah, when I you could buy a hundred Slim ps2 Final Fantasy 12 to do all that.
Scott: Yeah, you could this.
Scott: you know, the PS the slim ps2 is pretty hot.
Scott: It's just 130 bucks.
Rym: And for that money, I get a DS lite, you know I'd buy a slim ps2 if the Wii weren't coming out right now.
Rym: Yeah, because I got some gaming.
Rym: it's weird.
Scott: the DS lite cost the same as the ps2 and the PSP cost the same as the Wii.
Scott: It's kind of crazy.
Rym: and also down at gizmodo They showed a picture about how the ps3 is.
Rym: they just took out of the box Was almost immediately and easily scratched to hell.
Rym: All right First of all, I want to say I'm tired of the people complaining like oh my god All the Mac users like yeah, there's a tiny scratch on the back of my iPod after I dropped it on the cement.
Scott: exactly It's like hello.
Scott: It's a piece of electronic equipment.
Scott: a scratch does not modify its functionality.
Scott: who gives a shit?
Scott: people aren't gonna look at.
Scott: You know, it's not like you have a big wart on your forehead or something nasty.
Scott: That's gonna make people go.
Scott: Oh, you're terrible person.
Rym: Well to me the issue is simply that a lot of companies now say well Sony lately and Apple has been doing this to agree to.
Rym: they'll make something that looks really really shiny and awesome Like it looks super super awesome.
Rym: But as a result, it's made so that if you look at it wrong, it scratches up real quick and suddenly looks like shit.
Rym: Why not just make it durable like I don't know Nintendo Nintendo products or even even earlier Sony products?
Scott: Yeah, frickin PlayStation 1 is frickin.
Scott: that thing could take a beating guy.
Rym: PlayStation Well, my ps1 Sega Genesis controllers.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: Those things kick around.
Rym: We're still using them.
Scott: We are yeah, but on the other hand, you know, I don't really care if shit gets scratched.
Scott: But on the other hand, it's like fine China.
Rym: How many hands do you have?
Scott: I got a lot of hands, but fine China.
Scott: right you go to the store you buy really expensive China.
Scott: All right, if you use the China properly if you wash it by hand in the sink and you eat dinner off of it And you know, it'll be fine.
Scott: It won't get scratched.
Scott: It'll be all good.
Scott: It only will scratch up if you drop it and break it.
Scott: China is a very fragile thing but in normal use it will hold up as long as you you know, don't try to put it in the dishwasher or Frickin use like a Brillo pad on it or anything stupid like that.
Scott: If you make a product any product in any category that is not some disposable product and it gets Marked up in normal use that is a problem.
Scott: if it's damaged in any way in normal everyday use That is not good.
Scott: No matter what the product is You know if your car get the paint job gets scratched driving around if you know I don't know the upholstery on your chair and your living room gets all roughed up just sitting in it.
Scott: That's not good That's a problem Even if I don't personally think it's a big deal.
Scott: if an iPod or a ps3 has scratches on it Like I wouldn't give a shit at all as long as it you know It doesn't hinder the use of the object But at the same time to have something that gets screwed up, but just not using it normally is not cool.
Scott: Not cool.
Rym: Yeah, well, I know that your iPod is pretty scratched to hell.
Scott: It is pretty scratched to hell, but it works just fine.
Scott: What do I care?
Scott: It's cool.
Scott: I can still see the screen just fine.
Scott: You don't even notice the scratches unless you you know looking at it like oh my god It's scratched up.
Rym: though back on the homefront here in the u.s.
Rym: GameStop had a I mean, they weren't entirely sure how many ps3s they were gonna get and they wanted to be cautious.
Rym: So they only offered a very limited number of pre-orders at their stores.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, what did they say?
Scott: 400,000 ps3s are coming to the u.s.
Scott: In three days.
Rym: I don't know if that's gonna happen now.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: well We don't even know if a hundred thousand They said we're gonna come out in Japan did.
Rym: I've seen people saying only 200,000 for the American release.
Scott: Well, we'll find out in three days.
Scott: But either way they say is four hundred thousand in the u.s.
Scott: So GameStop, you know went by those numbers and kind of estimated how many ps3s.
Rym: well It wasn't even that GameStop went beyond that and did a very limited one and they put out fewer Pre-orders than they even expected in a bad case scenario.
Scott: for for PlayStation 3 Yeah I was hearing that they gave like an average like nine PS3s per store.
Scott: of course stores in the middle of nowhere got maybe two ps3s or even one and stores in like a big city We get 20 30.
Rym: Well, it turns out that that wasn't enough.
Rym: There won't be enough ps3s to even fill those limited pre-orders and GameStop is now calling Their customers and telling them we know you gave us a hundred bucks But we can't give you a ps3 at least not right away.
Scott: the if you have a pre-order You're probably gonna get one when they get one for you know what you get.
Rym: You know you get if you get dicked over by this a free used game or DVD valued it under 1999.
Scott: Yeah When you eventually wind up purchasing the system So you can't even get it to like play in the time while you're waiting to get the ps3.
Rym: No, no You gotta wait till you actually buy the ps3.
Scott: you think they give you a nice used ps2 game to keep you from going crazy While you're waiting now because if that happened to me, I wouldn't go back to that GameStop to buy a ps3.
Rym: I'd be so angry that I would just freak out and make sure to that.
Rym: I'd never went to that store again.
Scott: Well, they don't.
Scott: when they get the pre-order they they don't promise that you'll get one at launch.
Scott: They say this is not a.
Rym: you know, what you know, what.
Rym: that's horseshit.
Scott: I know.
Scott: that's why when I went to the This guarantee me a unit at launch and they said yes It does
Rym: like that episode of Seinfeld where he goes, you know He's like a reservation for a rental car and he goes and they're like, sorry, we don't have any cars But I have a reservation.
Rym: Yeah, but we gave away all the cars and he went on this whole bit about.
Rym: so doesn't that make the reservation kind of useless?
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it's what it is Is they have the legalese on there and if you want to buy a pre-order, you know.
Scott: They tell you it's not a guarantee if you buy it.
Rym: Anyway, you knew yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I hate to say it but I wouldn't I would never pre-order something that wasn't.
Scott: I would never pre-order if it wasn't a guarantee either.
Scott: And that's why I asked.
Scott: I said does this guarantee me something at launch?
Scott: and if they say no It is not a guarantee.
Scott: I say I'm not buying it because I'm basically buying nothing.
Rym: at least It was really easy to get a we pre-order.
Scott: It was.
Scott: I went to the Nintendo store right as soon as you know, people were talking about wheeze.
Scott: I said can I have a we pre-order?
Scott: they said yes.
Scott: I said does it guarantee me a unit?
Scott: They said yes, and I'm pretty sure if I go to the Nintendo store on Sunday I'm gonna take the first train in the morning.
Scott: I'm gonna get away.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I got a point 9%.
Rym: I got to figure out if my first we experience is going to be with Scott here in the geek house or with the other Scott in the Pennsylvania geek house.
Scott: Hey don't care either way.
Scott: Ah, either way.
Scott: I'm gonna be.
Scott: we ended up on Sunday.
Scott: Oh, yeah clean in the bathroom.
Scott: on Saturday When I was playing Dragon
Rym: Quest 8,
Scott: I almost forced myself to go further because at
Rym: the very end I had the secret thing and I beat all the secret things except one where you have to fight the seven previous
Scott: bosses all at once with no rest in between.
Scott: and I looked it up on the internet and it's like yeah your prize for this is nothing.
Rym: You go right back on the shelf Goodbye, oh you simply have to level up to 65 38 but just find some metal king slides.
Rym: No problem.
Rym: Yeah, we better find them on my bookshelf.
Scott: That's the only place this game is gonna be for the next six.
Rym: Well Dave and Joel's best karate for the gentleman the anime podcast for people who don't like M or Podcasts find us online at www.daveandjoe.com.
Rym: So enough ps3.
Rym: it's time for things of the day.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: What's your thing of the day?
Scott: I know what your thing of the day is because someone sent us the link and it was hilarious.
Rym: Yes Well, some of it was hilarious.
Rym: Yeah, you see we all like Phoenix Wright, but I am now also a fan of Phoenix wrong.
Scott: That's so creative.
Scott: I never would have thought of that name for never in a million years.
Rym: God, but yeah, it's a bunch of little.
Rym: now The thing is these are a lot like Photoshop Fridays on something awful in that It'll be the same kind of jokes over and over and over and all the jokes are basically Animations from Phoenix Wright with funny audio put over them and these are done by some different people Varying levels of skill and funniness and at least 60% of them are absolutely hilarious.
Scott: Yeah I mean it seems like one guy started the trend of making Phoenix wrong videos and then a bunch of other people Sort of followed suit and some of them did a better job than the original guy and some of them did a worse job than The original.
Rym: yeah, like the last two on the site were pretty piss-poor.
Scott: ever just fan crap total fan crap.
Scott: but
Rym: like there's the one recurring theme that just really got me was there's this one thing von karma a guy near the end does Where he like bangs his fist on the ground and starts yelling and almost everyone used that and played some sort of air raid Siren or nuclear bomb exploding and it was always hilarious.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: these are worth watching Yeah Yeah, so my thing today is a random webcomic I found today it's actually one specific Comic yeah in the web.
Scott: I was trying to say issue or episode and I was like, no, it's not an issue It's not an episode.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Rym: It's a comic Sequential art.
Scott: Yep, one specific comic of this webcomic was particularly hilarious.
Scott: It had a nice Zelda to joke and I was laughing for about four minutes so I made it my thing of the day.
Scott: now the comic is digital unrest by Chris Simmons and digital unrest.
Scott: comic comm Updates every Monday with video game jokes in the style of penny arcade.
Rym: Have you ever actually read this comic?
Scott: No, but I read this single comic of the digital unrest.
Rym: You better watch out.
Rym: What if the rest of the comic isn't up to snuff for that one?
Scott: All right, you're ready.
Scott: You're ready.
Scott: I'm gonna go and read one other digital one other one.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Here we go.
Scott: You ready?
Rym: I'm ready I'm ready.
Scott: Okay, let's see.
Scott: Hold on Trouble.
Rym: just navigate the archive.
Rym: It can't be that hard.
Scott: the site's poorly designed.
Scott: Oh, here we go.
Scott: I got one I got one.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I read a few comics of Digital unrest and most of them are just sort of crude video game related jokes that aren't too funny But there were two or three gems that I discovered in my cursory glance at the archives and the comics about a year old.
Scott: So I wouldn't recommend Subscribing to this comic because I'm pretty picky about web web comics I subscribe to.
Scott: but the one that I linked to is Hilarious.
Scott: so go for it.
Rym: It's pretty funny mostly just because of the joke It makes not so much because of the way the joke was executed.
Scott: Yeah I mean the problem is is that if you look at the third panel before you read the first panel you the joke is already Spoiled.
Scott: they really should have made it one of those scroll down Instead of a horizontal one or they should have made the third panel less blaring, you know It's the same kind of joke.
Rym: Is that Final Fantasy 4 comic that we laughed about a while ago?
Rym: Yeah, we're where someone kills themselves in a heroic fashion.
Scott: Yeah, it is the same kind of comic, but whatever Laugh today, so I'll give it.
Scott: I'll give it a link.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean I'm the same way.
Rym: It's really hard for me to find a web comic I like and I've maybe read two web comics more than I used to read in the last several years.
Scott: Well, I really a drop web comics because either they sucked and I just was reading them by habit or they stopped making new comics.
Scott: It takes a lot takes a lot to pick one up.
Scott: like dr.
Scott: Mcninja I picked up in order to the stick that's about it and I picked up those a long time ago already.
Rym: Yeah, so with all this, you know new age console stuff that really doesn't matter at all We figured it'd be time to review a much more Important and much more fun game than a lot of things that have come out recently.
Scott: Yeah, I mean everyone knows classic games like pac-man space invaders.
Scott: Tetris I guess is kind of old, you know, but kind of old Tetris is fucking old.
Scott: Yeah Mario but one guy that's sort of like the second tier of classic video games is Dig-dug dig-dug.
Rym: See we I hadn't played dig-dug in Maybe five six seven years.
Rym: Oh god I hadn't played dig-dug in forever, but we got the Atari 7800 hooked up in the living room and sadly enough We've been playing the 7800 more than we've been playing any other electronic game we own by far.
Scott: Well that changed when I started playing Resident Evil 4 a few days ago But before that we were playing dig-dug all the time now because you haven't put as many hours into Resident Evil 4.
Scott: I put 10 hours into Resident Evil 4 so far.
Rym: Yeah, but we had the 7800 hooked up for a while.
Scott: We did but I don't think I played dig-dug for 10 hours.
Scott: You might have I don't know.
Rym: I don't think so and all those other games we were playing.
Scott: I think we played it 10 times 15 Though you're kind of obsessing over Resident Evil 4.
Rym: You won't let anyone.
Rym: you won't let me use the living room.
Scott: Basically Well, you can use living room.
Rym: I can't play video games or use the TV.
Scott: How are you supposed to play video games while I'm playing video games?
Rym: sink my iPod or use my 50% share of that TV.
Scott: Well, first of all, you don't have a 50% share of that TV because most of that TV was paid for with my Sony points Whatever like my money.
Scott: and second of all, I first come first serve.
Scott: I'm playing video games.
Scott: You can't stop me.
Scott: Yeah, when I'm done playing video games You can do it everyone.
Rym: when you play Resident Evil 4 most of what you do is sit there and bitch about the game while You play.
Rym: well, I got how much you hate it and how stupid it is.
Scott: You know the bitching for isn't?
Scott: evil 4 is relatively less than some other games because if the bitching was more I would have put It down and bitch.
Scott: I would not have played for 10 hours sitting in the room with you.
Rym: you bitch the same amount that you've bitch for every single Game you've played for as long as you've lived in this house.
Rym: No, when you were playing Megaman X you bitch the exact same Megaman X.
Scott: It depends on which Megaman X you're talking about.
Rym: I'm talking about the frequency of bitching's per unit.
Rym: time has remained constant.
Rym: If you're playing a video game in the room You will bitch about every five minutes about something in the game being stupid and how.
Rym: why would they make it that way?
Rym: It could have been better.
Rym: This is stupid.
Rym: Why do I have to do this?
Rym: Why did they do it this way?
Rym: This sucks, but you'll keep playing.
Scott: Yeah, keep playing.
Scott: keep playing.
Scott: press a press a.
Rym: okay Yeah, but of all the games for the 7800 which includes the entire 2600 library as well as the Atari equivalent of Tengen games No, God the ones we've been playing the most are miss pac-man Dig-dug dig-dug dig-dug miss pac-man super break out dig-dug pong.
Rym: Well video Olympics video Olympics, which is pretty much every possible type of game that involves pong controls.
Rym: Yep, it's kind of amazing.
Rym: It's got basketball Volleyball hockey soccer tennis.
Scott: I think the volleyball is my favorite racquetball.
Rym: The foosball oh yeah foosball soccer.
Rym: So it's just pong and the paddles are in different places.
Scott: All right, so dig-dug.
Rym: dig-dug is one of those amazing old pure video games The it's I mean I word like pure a lot of times law pure collect blah blah blah.
Rym: But games like this really are pure.
Rym: dig-dug is a game Where you dig into the ground and there are two kinds of monsters And you try to kill them in order to get as many points as you can Occasionally eating vegetables or galaxian flagships.
Scott: yep, so basically a big duck can kill bad guys in two different ways.
Scott: You can either dig directly under a rock.
Scott: if you dig directly under a rock And then you move the rock will fall down.
Scott: if a bad guy happens to be there when the rock falls He will get squished.
Scott: if dig-dug happens to be there when the rock falls.
Scott: He will get squished.
Rym: You know his name is not dig-dug right?
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: I forget it now, but in Japan he was given a name.
Rym: He's also known as the hero of the something incident.
Scott: his name is dig-dug and his name is not mr.. Driller Which you'll see a lot of.
Scott: mr..
Rym: Driller is has a name also.
Scott: Yeah, but mr.. Driller is related to dig-dug in a way.
Scott: You know they're like references that bind the two games together But anyway the other way dig-dug can be bad guys is by pumping them up full of air with his air pump.
Rym: Yeah He shoves a spike into their body with an air pump and pumps it up until they explode.
Scott: like imagine a bicycle pump With a big rope and a hook and he throws the hook into the bad guy, and then he pumps it up And you pump them four times and they explode.
Rym: now the monsters.
Rym: there are two kinds of monsters pookas and Phi guys.
Scott: Phi guards are awesome.
Rym: Yeah pookas are just little red things that eat you.
Rym: they have goggles that do nothing Yeah, the other ones are dragons that can breathe fire Horizontally and do so often.
Scott: yeah, they both suck.
Rym: now the cool thing is that both of them can also turn into a ghost form.
Rym: They call it something in Japan something like ghostly eyes.
Rym: I forget yeah, but they can kind of phase like like an x-man Through the dirt very slowly and then pop out in your tunnels and try to eat.
Scott: Yeah, you see at the beginning of any round of dig-dug any level you know dig-dug himself will dig.
Rym: his name's not dig-dug Whatever.
Scott: He'll dig from the top of the map straight down the middle into the middle of the board.
Scott: all the bad guys are in these Little dugouts, it looks sort of like an ant ant farm thingy that you buy.
Scott: And you know the bad guys are in the little dugouts, and they're just going back and forth.
Scott: But the bad guys can't dig in the dirt like dig-dug can.
Scott: so it's not easy for them to walk around on the dirt.
Scott: So they turn into eyeballs and float across the dirt to get to other areas where they can walk and thus kill dig-dug.
Scott: of course Turning into eyeballs they move through dirt a lot slower than they walk around.
Rym: But you move through dirt a lot slower when you're digging than when you're running through a pre-dug tunnel.
Rym: Mmm, and you know this is a pure old video game.
Rym: So you have two goals survive get points and the way they do points is cool.
Rym: You get more points if you kill a bad guy down under.
Rym: You get more points if you kill a fog are from the side because that way it's dangerous.
Rym: He can flame you.
Rym: You get more points if you crush guys with rocks instead of pumping them up.
Scott: you get a lot of points if you crush a Bunch of guys with one rock.
Rym: as soon as you drop two boulders no matter where they are or when or whatever they hit something or not a vegetable or Galaxian ship or fruit or pineapple will appear and then you got to go grab it and it's worth a whole ton of points.
Scott: You've got like 10 seconds to grab the vegetable, and you know in the beginning of the game.
Scott: What's the first vegetable?
Rym: It's like some crappy ass bean or whatever eventually turns into a galaxian ship.
Rym: and finally a pineapple.
Scott: Yeah, the pineapple.
Scott: once you get to level 18 1920 It's a pineapple and it stays a pineapple forever and a pineapple is worth some godly amount of points.
Rym: now by the way Digdog as Scott is calling him.
Rym: his actual name is Taizo Hori, okay What's his name?
Rym: in America, and he is the father of Susumu Hori who is the main character in mr.. Driller.
Rym: all right?
Scott: What's Digdugs name in English?
Rym: that is his name?
Rym: That's his name.
Rym: No.
Rym: I they didn't translator localized Digdug.
Rym: Okay, all they'd all.
Rym: the only part of that game.
Rym: They translated is press starts players one to Pineapple or teddy bear.
Rym: yeah, yeah There's some puns in the name or something whatever.
Rym: the the continuity of the Digdug universe is a little convoluted and It goes.
Scott: I can't believe there's a Digdug universe Not only but there's.
Rym: there's some trouble here because it's not all consistent.
Rym: Oh really, and there are people.
Scott: is it not consistent when the games contain No plot and therefore you could just make up the?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: They could have just made up a consistent plot with no game to interfere.
Rym: now we've been playing this game a lot and the conclusion is simply that I am Infinitely better than Scott.
Scott: you're not infinitely better.
Scott: I'm damn good at Digdug.
Scott: I just haven't been playing Digdug as much as you.
Scott: you know my wife And I played a lot more Digdug 2 when I was a kid.
Scott: then I played Digdug 1.
Rym: I could beat you Digdug 2 just as easily.
Scott: I don't think you beat me Digdug 2.
Rym: I played a lot of Digdug 2 as well.
Scott: see I actually had Digdug 2 for the NES and I played it a lot.
Scott: now Digdug 2 is a little different.
Scott: you got the same Digdug But he's got the same pump.
Scott: you got the Pookas and the Fygars right, but instead of digging under the earth.
Scott: you're on an island and the island has like cracks in it and You know what there's these spikes and he has a jackhammer instead of a digging tool instead of whatever an automatic shovel or whatever Digdug uses.
Scott: and If he goes to one of the spikes and uses the jackhammer he can put cracks in the island.
Scott: Now what happens?
Scott: if you put enough cracks in the island that break the island into different pieces like completely separate pieces The smaller piece will fall into the ocean like doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: ghostly eyes That's what they're called anyway.
Scott: Okay, so if there happened to be Pookas and Fygars on the piece that falls into the ocean Awesome.
Scott: if there aren't that sucks.
Scott: if Digdug is on the part that falls into the ocean that sucks.
Scott: So it's all about looking at the map and breaking up the island in a way that makes the bad guys fall off the edge And if you get in trouble you can always pump them up with the pump air thingy.
Rym: now I got to say I have a very special tender place in my heart for all of these old or even new just pure video games games that have a very simple very direct concept and they implement it as well as they can.
Rym: and The only factor here is how good are you at this specific pure game?
Rym: It is a direct contest of digging and dugging.
Scott: The best thing about these games is that there's so many nuances that aren't immediately obvious that you have to learn over time.
Scott: You know to the untrained eye.
Scott: you look at this game and you say what the hell is that shit?
Scott: There's nothing to this game.
Rym: Yeah Sit down with someone who knows what they're doing and watch them play on a difficult level and you'll see a situation Where there's like eight monsters going after you and you're in the corner and you think this guy's gonna die.
Rym: There's no way you can survive this and they'll do some kind of kung fu Like I'll make a little path go around back stun a bunch of guys run away catch a rock kill them all grab the mushroom And win.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you see people playing games like Soul Calibur and they pull off some awesome combo and you go Whoa, and you don't think that kind of thing is possible in some simple game like Dig Dug?
Scott: Well, it's very possible.
Scott: in a game like Dig Dug We pull off awesome moves all the time.
Scott: You know Like you'll be standing there with guys coming at you from all the directions.
Scott: you do some daring Digging and you you know, you're like pump up some guys a little bit But not not enough so that they die to keep them there to delay them just a little bit that the rock hits them Instead of them running away from the rock
Rym: course.
Rym: My favorite thing that you did was in one game in level one you walk to the right and were immediately killed.
Scott: What?
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna happen.
Rym: Sometimes that's like dying on the first goomba.
Scott: Yeah, you know if I play Mario 1 a hundred times maybe a thousand times one out of a thousand times I might hit that first goomba.
Rym: Well, you know, I got to make fun of you because you know according to the listeners I'm really too hard on you.
Rym: So I got to keep up this persona.
Scott: You've also died in level one of Dig Dug.
Rym: You know what though.
Rym: when I died in level one, I already had like 2,000 points.
Rym: you had 10.
Scott: What do you want?
Scott: The other thing is like a bunch of levels in Dig Dug.
Scott: I've done perfectly but I don't remember the.
Scott: it's a deterministic game.
Scott: So if you do the exact same input every time You know, I mean other games.
Scott: it's not easy to do the exact same input because the games are so complex.
Rym: In Dig Dug it is.
Rym: There are a lot of the levels.
Rym: I'll play in the exact same way every time.
Rym: I'll like wait two seconds walk to the right open into the monster's pit stun him once walk down walk Right, wait two more seconds go across the rock and kill three guys.
Scott: Yeah, you can't do that sort of thing in.
Scott: I don't know Mario 64.
Rym: No, but like Mario 1 you can.
Scott: Mario 1 you definitely can.
Rym: Mario 2 you can.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Mario 3 you can too.
Scott: Mostly mostly it's not.
Scott: it won't be a hundred percent the same as the last time you played it But in Dig Dug you can play a hundred percent the same every time and it'd be pretty cool.
Scott: now I just want to point out that I downloaded I got Maim, you know to play the arcade the original arcade version of Dig Dug.
Rym: Yeah, we've been playing the real Dig Dug.
Rym: We've been playing the 7800 version which actually is a very good port.
Scott: It's a very close to the original version.
Scott: the NES version However is basically nine, you know, I say the arcade version of course is a hundred percent identical to what Dig Dug is supposed to be.
Rym: Well, it's a hundred percent identical to itself.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: That's your argument.
Scott: Yes, the Atari 7800 version is about 90% identical to the arcade.
Rym: It's a little bit slower.
Scott: It's a little bit easier You know, there's less resolution and the bad guys are a little bit dumber even though I think they have the same AI.
Scott: Some of the pictures of the flowers are different stuff like that.
Scott: The NES version is ninety nine point nine nine nine percent similar to the arcade version.
Scott: So if you're gonna play this game by some emulation or something, it's probably easiest to get the NES version.
Scott: It's probably the nicest version.
Rym: Well, especially MAME is a little bit difficult sometimes for people who don't want to spend time fiddling with it to get to work.
Scott: Yeah, MAME is not is the easiest emulator to make because you're emulating all this different hardware.
Rym: It's not like an NES emulator where you're emulating the NES and maybe some MMCs and that's it.
Scott: Yeah, MAME isn't difficult just on its own.
Scott: It's just more difficult than something like ZSNES or What are those rock NES or any of those other NES emulators?
Scott: Which are very very very easy to use.
Rym: and We talked about Dig Dug today mostly because we were gonna review Resident Evil 4 but Scott Wouldn't put down the GameCube controller long enough for me to actually play the game.
Scott: Well, I found I'm almost done with the game.
Scott: Actually, I've only got like eight chapters to go.
Scott: So yeah, I should beat it pretty soon.
Rym: You know We missed the window because the Wii is gonna come out and then we're not gonna have a chance for me to play Resident Evil 4 for at least another three or four years.
Scott: But you'll play.
Rym: no no because look all the way on the Wii all these DS and Wii games are gonna be coming out at a pretty steady rate for a while and I already have a backlog of DS games to play let alone my other backlogs and We're playing D&D again.
Rym: Yeah, so I don't think I'm gonna get to Resident Evil 4 for a long time.
Rym: I'll be playing the Resident Evils on like the DS 365 years from now.
Scott: No, I'm gonna play this Saturday, you know because I'm going to get the Wii on Sunday.
Scott: So this Saturday if I don't beat Resident Evil 4 this Saturday, I don't think I'm ever gonna beat it Now maybe when you're an old man, maybe when I'm an old man I'll go back and there'll be a box set.
Scott: It'll be all of Resident Evil on a single Hollow foil and I'll play all ten Resident Evil games on the single hollow foil.
Rym: Honestly, I don't like any other Resident Evil games.
Scott: Yeah Well, I'll talk about it, but that'll save it for the Resident Evil episode.
Rym: Yeah, which in a few years We'll talk about Resident Evil.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four Different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.