Rym: It's Monday May 29th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: I have just returned from an amazement and as it is the holiday and in addition We are both very tired from the weekend today is somewhat of a cop-out episode though We do have a fairly interesting discussion on patents during the news bits.
Rym: For any and all of our new listeners who are coming here looking for actual coverage of an amazement It will be on Wednesday, which is our normal anime day.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I Am back from a crazy ass weekend.
Rym: I'm absolutely exhausted.
Rym: I flew in early afternoon on a little prop plane puddle jumper that took me back to Stewart Airport And then I slept until I heard Scott come home.
Scott: You know I came home well before you awoke and You were still sleeping.
Scott: so well I was awake, and then I went back to sleep now because I came in the house And you were.
Scott: you were completely knocked out And then you didn't make a noise until I opened the door to look at you.
Rym: Well actually I woke up, and I saw your.
Rym: I woke up, and I looked out the window.
Rym: I saw your car pulled in then I went back to sleep.
Scott: uh-huh yeah Cuz see I opened your door, and then I closed it and then you made a noise And then you didn't come out.
Rym: I spent the last five days getting not enough sleep and doing craziness.
Scott: I did a bunch of stuff while you weren't here.
Scott: I did more in like Friday night than you did all weekend man Yeah, but all you did was you went to an anime convention.
Scott: I did stuff.
Rym: Yeah, you did all right.
Rym: I didn't.
Scott: just it's like saying man.
Scott: I went on vacation.
Rym: I did so much yeah, except let me put it this way I will have my coverage of an amazement on Wednesday anime day though first I'd like to say an amazement was freaking amazing.
Rym: It was an amazing
Scott: Not funny,
Rym: but it was a really freaking awesome convention And I basically went from just being some schmuck going to being a panelist to being full-on staff over the course of maybe Six hours, and I ended up basically being crowd control and security for the entirety of the convention.
Scott: It's good to be awesome.
Rym: Yeah, and I was surprised they were Really impressed with the way I handled lines and crowd control and security and I you know the kinds of stuff We just kind of did back at RIT all the time.
Scott: Yep, you know some things come naturally to some people or you know how to do something in other people You know.
Scott: not so many people know how to do it.
Scott: So you come across someone who's never seen anyone do it properly.
Scott: see they don't know.
Scott: What's the real deal is you come around with what you consider to be basic skills?
Scott: And you know it's like this one village or everyone has a bow and arrow And they know how to use it and the other village No one's ever seen a bow and arrow in their lives.
Scott: So you go to the other village, and they think you're some kind of crazy.
Scott: God with your bow and arrow skills.
Scott: And yeah, it's a good analogy.
Rym: I think yeah, I mean they actually they do one thing really really well in terms of how they Actually set up lines and prevent people from standing in line that I'm gonna really try to push to make Otakon do Because holy shit did it save time.
Scott: Always good to save time.
Rym: Yeah, they have this system of how to get people lined up for the cosplay.
Rym: That's just fantastic.
Scott: Systems are good.
Scott: the problem is as you know if the system requires more work the more people you have the more breaks down Like trying.
Scott: it's like when you try to get people.
Scott: is another analogy ready.
Scott: It's analogy day.
Scott: When you go to a Sporting event the more people you try to get to chant something in unison the less complex that thing has to be.
Rym: But yet this system.
Rym: I'll talk about it in great depth on third on Wednesday, but basically it seems to scale I'll say it linearly With the number of people.
Rym: so for every you know a hundred people in line you directly over maybe 200 people in line.
Rym: You'll need one staffer to manage them.
Rym: Give or take.
Rym: that's my assessment, and I'm pretty sure it's a linear relationship.
Rym: That's good, so I'll we'll see I'll push for it.
Rym: But the the staff of an amazement was awesome, and I will go every year forever more.
Scott: I will have crazy coverage including all the interviews I did on Wednesday, so actually gonna do it or you cut up all that audio Or are you just gonna pretend that you're gonna do it?
Rym: Well, I did it last time for the other time at our con.
Scott: didn't it take you two weeks?
Rym: What?
Scott: no no no remembering incorrectly Katsucon was the one.
Rym: it was trouble because right I used Scott Johnson had a paper car.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I remember I was sitting there trying and we discovered that I don't have a single working tape player in this house.
Rym: That's right as I took apart every single one of them and found them all to be broken.
Scott: yep Yeah, I think we got it straight now.
Rym: I got some good interviews.
Rym: I don't want any one particularly interesting.
Rym: Actually I interviewed a gaggle of somewhat cute to incredibly cute fangirls and one fanboy.
Scott: That's not very good.
Rym: No.
Rym: It's actually a really good interview.
Rym: Everyone was very excited about being interviewed for anything so I tried to not do my standard.
Rym: You know ask them about the con itself, and I try to ask him more general questions about you know Why do you like anime?
Rym: Why do you go to conventions?
Rym: Why are you here?
Rym: Why are you dressed up as a cat boy?
Rym: And I got the same answer from everyone even people who didn't know each other And they gave the same answer that we always give because it geeks come together And this is the only place where geeks can just be geeks and meet other geeks and be within our own culture.
Rym: So yeah, I got some good interviews.
Rym: I met some interesting people and the con was freaking amazing.
Rym: now today's episode is going to be a little short partly because a Drawback of the con being amazing is that I didn't really sleep much for the last five days
Scott: and I've been doing all sorts of other shit like being on other people's podcasts and Playing board games
Rym: yeah
Scott: and driving to my house And yeah, so I don't have that much to go and we don't have a main bit planned.
Rym: Yeah, today's gonna be a little bit of a cop-out, but tomorrow.
Rym: We'll have a bunch of stuff Wednesday.
Rym: It's gonna be super long Thursday.
Scott: We'll probably have a bunch of stuff, so I'll probably just do news thing of the day and then Something else.
Rym: we'll talk until we run out of time.
Rym: yep To any of our new listeners out there because I know a lot of people.
Rym: I I printed out some flyers for GeekNights.
Rym: I forgot there.
Scott: already one person already joined the forum who saw your flyer really cuz.
Rym: I Forgot to bring my stuff with me to the convention like I left it here.
Rym: I had a flyer already.
Rym: I was gonna you know print at the hotel and pass out like a nice one now.
Rym: So I actually commissioned an artist who was sitting next to me in the artists alley while I was manning the artist alley stafftable for a while and I commissioned her for the price of one coffee to dry me up a Crick crick stick figure little figure
Scott: thing
Rym: and then I went to the hotel and actually got the business travelers Discount and made a bunch of copies and put them all over the event.
Scott: you should have commissioned a logo.
Scott: We still need logo.
Rym: I wasn't gonna condition anything big.
Rym: I was mostly busy doing other things.
Scott: Yeah, we're still.
Scott: you know we're getting some a couple more entries, but there's still nothing.
Scott: that's like aha.
Scott: That's the one.
Rym: yeah We've got one that we're real close to picking, but it really we want to see more.
Rym: Remember there's prizes involved and fame.
Scott: yes cash.
Scott: Well how come?
Scott: every other podcast in the world gets like original theme music right away and An original cool logo right away, and we don't have that.
Rym: we'd have plenty of original music.
Rym: the problem Is we want jazz music which I don't have the means to just create on my own.
Scott: But every other podcast in the universe got like a real slick logo real quick and easy.
Scott: How come we can't do this?
Rym: because we care a lot more about what our logo looks like and we're real.
Rym: But they have good logos too, and yeah, we're all picky and anal even when we like one.
Rym: We're like We're I mean like people were posting.
Rym: I look through the forum briefly after my five-day Absence and people seem to always talk about how we care a lot about production values and quality and professionalism.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: We're nuts for fastidious fastidious?
Rym: Yeah consider them fastidious From tomorrow until Thursday.
Rym: consider this to be our week's coverage of the Memorial Day weekend because we both had crazy weekends.
Rym: Yes, we did and once again like I was saying before we got sidetracked to all of our new listeners coming from an amazement.
Rym: I If you don't realize who I was at the convention I was the long-haired staffer guy who was pushing people into lines and sitting in the artists alley and many of you remember me as that tree guy or that elf guy in the tree because I was Quite literally sitting in a tree for much of the con.
Scott: And if you don't know who I am, I was the guy who wasn't there.
Rym: Yeah Though really you should come to an amazement next year.
Rym: That was a freaking awesome con.
Scott: I'm probably gonna go to all the cons next year.
Scott: Just not this year.
Rym: Well, see I'm laying the groundwork cuz we're probably gonna go to every con now as panelists staff or guests.
Rym: Mm-hmm I mean every time we've been to so far has invited us back except uber con, but they don't know that we were there Mm-hmm.
Rym: I never actually told them lol.
Rym: Doesn't matter.
Rym: I actually don't want to do stuff at uber con.
Rym: I want to play games at uber con.
Scott: Yeah, tell me about it.
Rym: If we did stuff at uber con we couldn't play games.
Rym: We'd be doing.
Scott: no I'm probably gonna run some German board games at uber con.
Rym: Yeah, if we get good enough by then We should try to run a burning wheel.
Scott: You really can't compete.
Scott: when the met with the master if he wasn't there I would do it.
Rym: No, even if he was there I have this feeling that if we tried to run a burning wheel and Luke Crane knew about that He he would probably help out or think it was awesome.
Scott: No, he'd come over and be like you guys doing it all wrong.
Scott: Okay, let me show you how it's done.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: Maybe like thanks.
Rym: Yeah All right, anyway like today's a cop-out as you said multiple times.
Rym: Yep, so we got some news though.
Scott: Okay, my news apparently DirectX 10 will be available only on Windows Vista.
Rym: Alright, I guess I won't ever be seeing DirectX 10 related things me either.
Scott: It's kind of weird since everything else that Windows Vista is bringing such as support for well like Internet Explorer 7 those Windows photo files all this other stuff that they're putting into Vista.
Scott: They're releasing packages so that you can install it on XP and it's like the new Windows Media Player I think is gonna be for XP, you know but They're not bringing DirectX 10 to XP.
Scott: this means that if when their games will eventually come out that require DirectX 10 and Those games won't work on Windows XP period.
Scott: Also, if you get a video card that say DirectX 10 features You won't be able to take advantage of those features without Windows Vista.
Scott: You'll basically be stuck in DirectX 9 land forever and you might as well just buy the best DirectX 9 video card in the universe and use that and Never get a better one unless you're gonna get Vista.
Rym: See I'm starting to think that for a long time people would use Windows and people use Linux and most people who use Linux Would use both and it wasn't that hard to do and that way you could get the best of both worlds.
Rym: And there were things you needed Windows for and there wasn't that much of a divergence.
Rym: like people who use Linux primarily Still used Windows fairly often for some things like games.
Rym: I think we're going to start seeing with Vista the beginning of a Actual schism where people use Linux don't have access to Windows at all Mm-hmm, and I wonder if that's going to segment the market or force maybe change on the behalf of Microsoft or developers.
Scott: Well, there are really only two things that tie people to Microsoft Windows anymore.
Scott: those two things are one PC games now the Xbox 360 is doing a lot to fix that problem and two are those proprietary applications you need at work such as my uncle with the dentist's office and the software that gets the pictures out of the x-ray.
Scott: or You work for the real estate agent.
Scott: You have these special real estate software that only works on Windows or all that.
Rym: Yeah, that tab work crap had to deal with them and those things are slowly and frequently being replaced with SQL.
Scott: You know databases with websites, you know lamp things.
Scott: I mean that's what my company does.
Scott: we have a lot of those things and they just keep replacing a lot of the shit with Lamp.
Scott: someone makes a database and web interface and it replaces that proprietary real estate Application or it replaces that x-ray application and as people do that more and more It doesn't matter what their client machines are and is more people get 360s and wheeze and whatnot.
Scott: it doesn't matter what their client computer is.
Scott: and As the same, you know more and more frequently we see no matter what computer you have Mac Windows Linux You're on Firefox no matter what computer you have using aim, you know, no matter what computer you have using Gmail.
Scott: so it matters a lot less what the OS is nowadays.
Scott: and Microsoft is really gonna have to rely on things like office Which is why they're scared to shit from the of the open document format cuz that'll be the end of office also.
Scott: Yep So yeah, I'm not gonna get Vista which means any game that requires DirectX 10 will only be played by me if it's Xbox 360 and I actually buy one of those things.
Rym: Yeah, which is very that we're considering it.
Scott: Well, cuz $400 seemed like so much until this ps3 came along.
Scott: it was actually up.
Scott: then there's actually a poll.
Scott: Not it wasn't a super scientific poll, but it was better than just a shit website poll.
Rym: It wasn't a slashdot poll.
Scott: No, was it?
Scott: No, and they asked people what system they planned on buying.
Scott: now I'm not sure what the sample was, but it was pretty big sample.
Scott: I think it was mostly gamers and 50% of people said they're gonna have an Xbox 360 and a we.
Scott: 25% of people said we only.
Scott: oh Yeah, that's looking good to me.
Rym: I'm feeling it.
Rym: No, actually, I'll note that the demographics, you know, there's been a lot of debate in our forums lately about PSP use versus DS use and the popularity they're in.
Rym: and I am there of Yeah, yeah, all right mister and and and yeah, you know, yeah like, you know, yeah.
Rym: Mm-hmm All right.
Rym: All right It's a lazy day, uh I saw about 10 DS's and two PSP's at an amazement Which is the highest ratio of PSP to DS I've ever seen at a con.
Scott: That's more than I ever seen.
Rym: and I guess I've noticed that yeah outside of the major Like large conventions urban centers in the Northeast and urban centers in the Midwest and you know, California the PSP does seem to be more more popular outside of those areas and less popular in those areas.
Scott: but when it comes down to straight numbers The other thing is the DS is popular where you have friends in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: You have no friends.
Rym: So a PSP, you know, that's where it has an advantage in the middle of no, honestly I did notice one thing interesting and every other kind I've gone to there'd always be like huge circles of people playing DS's together.
Rym: I Came across one such circle at amazement and I thought all right I'll sit down and you know play some games with these kids and then interview them.
Scott: little Tetris little Mario Kart.
Rym: They were all playing one with one exception.
Rym: They were all playing like one player games on their own and two of them.
Rym: I think they were Animal Crossing trading, huh?
Rym: However later to make up for that because I thought oh maybe people here aren't so much into the gaming.
Rym: While I was sitting in that tree watching the cosplay line There was this huge group of people all playing Bomberman.
Scott: All right Bomberman.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: I Do it in the same way that we are.
Scott: All right Yeah, I got I really don't for the crown or where they go in for the.
Rym: I think they were playing.
Rym: They were playing random meaning every round was different and they were screaming and walking around in line and it was good.
Scott: Oh good All right.
Scott: That's my news.
Scott: What's your news?
Rym: Oh, yeah news.
Rym: Mm-hmm All right.
Rym: Well, this is real quick and this is actually from Friday But there's been a lot of talk about.
Rym: I mean JPEG the image format.
Rym: that is pretty much the standard on the internet for many things.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you don't know that.
Scott: on Friday Thursday I talked to when you weren't here talked about the windows Media photo or the window.
Scott: There's a new.
Scott: Microsoft wants to make a new format to replace.
Rym: Yeah, I did.
Rym: No, I didn't listen to the episode, but I read your post.
Rym: Okay, and in addition to that I read an article about it.
Scott: Yeah, I talked about how?
Scott: JPEG puns?
Rym: good now, I don't have to talk about it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah JPEG puns.
Rym: Okay I It's not the greatest thing in the world, but in term I guess in terms of bang for your buck JPEG is pretty solid.
Scott: Yeah You know Windows Media, whatever it's gonna be called photo.
Scott: This is called Microsoft photo format Might be better technologically than JPEG.
Rym: You know what VQF was better technologically than mp3.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Haha Betamax And Yeah, but anyway the problem with JPEG which was also a problem with GIF back in the day.
Scott: You mean GIF.
Scott: it's GIF GIF and Ubuntu.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I've never met anyone who called him a GIF not ironically.
Scott: Well, GIF is actually the correct pronunciation if you search for it on the internet.
Rym: Oh, yeah, according to the that's like the people who say no, it's the new Linux That's the sits.
Rym: the same deal.
Rym: No one in the real world says GIF.
Scott: Yeah, but GIF is the technical correct pronunciation You know, it's.
Rym: I find it interesting that when it comes to GIF versus GIF.
Rym: It's been my experience that super super nerds not to disparage anyone out there and People who are not technological at all are the primary people who say GIF as opposed to GIF.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: GIF is a peanut butter brand.
Scott: That's what GIF is.
Rym: GIF is some popcorn, you know, jiffy puff.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: GIF doesn't mean anything except image format.
Rym: Therefore if they whoever I get very simple you realize that GIF stands for a graphical or graphics interchange format Ga graphic.
Rym: Yeah, it's a hard G. You don't alter the pronunciation of a letter in an acronym Woohoo.
Rym: Well, I am straight And while we're at it is garymandering you pig fuckers.
Scott: and here it comes everyone with their Counter-examples of where do we do it the wrong way?
Rym: Yeah, which is fine.
Scott: That's fine Nothing.
Scott: there's nothing wrong with being a hypocrite.
Scott: if you see if you accept it who booed - boo boo Do.
Rym: yeah from now on we're gonna call it GNU Linux every time.
Rym: No, sorry GNU Linux up yep, yep, because his name is Linus or I've heard I've heard him say it because I saw it.
Rym: It was like Linux once.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not sure we're gonna.
Scott: that's the thing.
Scott: is every interview with with Linus Torvalds I've ever heard I've never heard one.
Scott: I've always read one.
Scott: Yeah, I've never heard him talk ever.
Rym: I heard one once but I'm not sure if it was him or someone paraphrasing because it was a short bit.
Scott: We got to get some audio of him saying and whoever he says it is the correct way.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I might not accept it.
Scott: I might still say gif even though I know gif is correct But I just want to hear it to know.
Rym: Anyway, there's there were patent concerns because people own the rights to gift back then and there are people who have patents that cover stuff.
Rym: That's in JPEG One of the major one of those patents that this company looks like they're trying to use.
Rym: this to make people pay for the fact That they use JPEG was totally thrown out by the patent office.
Rym: Haha, so I believe the company's name was faux gents and they had a patent that covered JPEG.
Scott: Are they just one of those patent companies or that actually an image company?
Rym: Well, the reason.
Rym: I think this will answer that the reason it was thrown out is that prior art existed, which is fine and They might not have thrown it out right away or they might have allowed them to amend it or something.
Rym: But it was shown that they were fully aware of that prior art and chose not to disclose it to the patent office.
Rym: Yeah, there is no chance that they were not up to something.
Rym: shady.
Rym: See the patent office is good when someone like points out to them that a patent is bad and there's money involved because then they'll Deal with it.
Scott: The problem is is that there's so many things that are patented that there isn't a wide enough body of knowledge at The patent office to know about every single patent.
Scott: So when they get a patent about Image file formats.
Scott: There isn't an image file format expert at the patent office.
Scott: So they don't know.
Scott: Yeah, they just say yes.
Rym: Now they have a solution to this I talked about in the news a while ago But real briefly spent for anyone who didn't who didn't catch that episode.
Rym: They've got an idea to kind of have an open source.
Rym: they call it.
Rym: they call it this open something initiative.
Rym: I forget exactly the details, but they want to have pending patents and patents that exist available on the website and Have bounties for experts with free time like, you know us when we sit around bored to read over patents that are in our field of expertise and Just point out prior art problems or here's why this patent is stupid or here's why this patent should be invalidated.
Scott: See if they would have set that up when I was in college I would have spent my time going over there finding bogus patents and then eventually, you know They'd probably realize hey this guy like did this a thousand times.
Scott: Yeah, I'd be a patent clerk right now instead of Nothing.
Rym: Yeah Einstein was a patent clerk.
Scott: He was that he was very good playing.
Rym: I call this Johnson's theory of relativity Yeah, but in terms of patents, I mean I think you all know my opinions on the curtain patent system Especially considering that my former company is still trying to get a patent for me on something that I did for them.
Rym: That is basically 15 or 20 lines of bash scripting.
Scott: I got one thing to say about the patent system.
Scott: It's no worse than the copyright system.
Rym: You know what I would submit that the patent system as it is is more damaging to the economy and to the betterment and advancement of humankind than copyright is because Violating copyright has only actually hurt in terms of people who violate it get caught.
Rym: very few people mean when when property rights that are intellectual as opposed to real or involving something scientific are Violated the it's very hard to actually gauge how many losses there are.
Rym: I mean, how can you say how many copies of a CD would have sold if you couldn't get it free?
Rym: There's no way to know.
Rym: With patents people are prevented from taking a thing that is known how to make and making it better or manufacturing it or Advancing it in any way.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: I mean, they're not technically prevented, but you're allowed to advance it.
Scott: You're just not allowed to.
Rym: well, even if you advance it, you still have to pay license fees for the original thing.
Scott: Yeah Yeah As long as you don't utilize the original within a certain amount of time.
Scott: Good thing is though that patent.
Scott: the term of a patent is rather short relative to a copyright.
Scott: It doesn't take long for the patent to run out.
Scott: So everyone can make it for free.
Rym: It's still too long.
Scott: It is still too long.
Scott: It should be a year You know.
Scott: as technology progresses faster and faster the term should get shorter and shorter or if we had money to pay the patent office.
Rym: People properly make it an indeterminate sum with a minimum and a maximum and then the patent office decides how long the patent should be based on the merits of the invention and the Economic and scientific situation at the time.
Scott: Yeah, if you look at something like the washing machine The washing machine hasn't really changed technologically rather long time, you know, and it's pretty economically Important.
Scott: I mean there's a big business around washing machine making and you know, it's still the same business.
Scott: It was a bunch of years ago.
Scott: So that could be a rather long patent, but something like I don't know That's something that should be a long patent though by long.
Scott: I mean five years by long, I mean the limit they have now not 50 years or 100 years, but something like An image file format or Something that's gonna you know needs to change really quickly.
Scott: Let me like mp3 files.
Scott: that patent should last.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: week You know you get the idea.
Rym: Yeah, I mean in the very least if they were just if they could look at the patents and decide which ones are actually patentable as opposed to which ones aren't and really do that instead of just kind of rubber
Scott: and also you shouldn't be able to Patent something without physically having it.
Scott: none of this patenting.
Scott: You know perpetual motion machine business that everyone does.
Scott: if you can't produce it physically right now You can't patent it or at least that's what Scott says.
Rym: I say you could if you can show that it can be done.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: You don't actually have to do it.
Scott: It just has to be able to be done.
Scott: because let's say I invented a machine in you know mechanical desktop Which is a program kind of like CAD that lets you draw machines and actually make the machines work on the computer.
Scott: If I can make it in mechanical desktop and You know there exist Manufacturing processes to create the device.
Scott: I just don't have the five million dollars required to create the machine.
Scott: I should still be able to patent it.
Scott: It just has to be able to be made right now.
Scott: So let's say I make a machine on the computer, and I design it and it requires you know Some metal that we can't actually produce.
Scott: Then that doesn't count because we can't actually produce it no matter how much money we have.
Rym: But as soon as we I'm going to patent having an adamantium skeleton.
Scott: exactly.
Scott: you can't do that.
Scott: you can patent having an iron skeleton.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why you'd want to.
Rym: well the other really ass thing about the patent system Is that say Scott and I are both you know?
Rym: We're rivals and we're working on patents for I don't know magic light bulb thingy, and we're both like working on the invention Medicine.
Rym: now say I Finish like I come up with it, and I make it work But I don't know five minutes before Scott does.
Rym: Scott lives in California I live in New York and I mind works.
Rym: I'm done And I run out the door to the patent office and Scott finishes his five minutes later.
Rym: He runs out to the door to the patent office.
Rym: But I got to the patent office first.
Rym: I get the patent.
Rym: he gets nothing is absolutely no rights and in fact It is illegal for him to continue doing what he just did.
Scott: yep.
Rym: That is crap.
Scott: It is total crap.
Rym: In the very least there should be a system of if people discuss develop something independently Then they should be able to.
Scott: there needs to be a window.
Scott: So if someone comes up with something right and submits it to the patent office Because the way patents work is once a patent is is going they show it to everyone.
Scott: It's not like copyright where you keep it secret.
Scott: a patent is shown to the world You know.
Scott: so if I patent some machine you can go to the website and get the design for that machine.
Scott: You can go to the patent office and say hey Can I look at this patent and they'll show you the complete plans to my patented machine?
Scott: Let us show it to you.
Rym: It's the exact.
Rym: I mean the two ways to protect something in the corporate world are patents and trade secrets.
Rym: No patent is what Scott just said a trade secret.
Rym: you choose not to patent it meaning It's not protected in any way.
Rym: and if someone figures it out or steals it from you They can use it with just as much rights as you have, but you're keeping it secret.
Scott: And if anyone steals the secret with corporate espionage That's criminal.
Scott: So they have to come up with it on their own or they can steal it.
Rym: if they do it in certain ways I mean you know legal loopholes and all that stuff or they pay you for it.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but anyway What they should do is when you submit a patent it should stay secret for some period of time if anyone else is known To be working.
Scott: you know especially if anyone else is known to be working on similar things.
Scott: Or maybe you can tell the patent office Hey I'm working on something kind of like this and if a bunch of people say they're doing that and Then they get all the submissions within a certain window of time then you know you get a part of all the same patent.
Scott: They make a big one big patent and you all share it or something like that.
Rym: But I guess my main beef is that the Constitution and the way the patent system was originally set up Was that and copyright too was that is supposed to be to foster innovation and generally work toward the common good?
Scott: Mm-hmm it says that right in the Constitution and in fact under the powers of Congress enumerated.
Rym: I really don't care how the patent system is set up.
Rym: all I care about is that at least the people who?
Rym: Enacted or who run it or who decide how it is done if they would just think to themselves or at least Say that what they're doing they think it's for the common good or try to do things to for the common good as opposed to Just doing it for money or maintaining the status quo mm-hmm.
Rym: I give someone credit if they try and fail than if they never try.
Scott: Usually usually I think the argument that I've made before is that if This very day we completely eliminated patents and copyrights It wouldn't hinder the fostering of innovation.
Scott: really that much people are innovating of their own will without Copyrights or patents at all.
Rym: well.
Rym: It's like the people who don't understand how open-source software can exist.
Rym: I only bring it up because I came up over the weekend.
Scott: Oh really.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Tell me about that.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of relevant.
Rym: I'll talk about it, and I haven't had a. he works for some people and basically they.
Rym: he was explaining to someone Open-source free software, and how it's free and she didn't believe him.
Rym: She didn't believe that people would actually make Things without compensation simply be for the joy of it.
Scott: a lot of old people don't believe it.
Scott: They they like.
Scott: why would you do that?
Scott: We're like because we're not fucking evil fucks who care about only money in ourselves And we like to share just like you told us on Sesame Street.
Rym: No in fact you know what we are.
Rym: we're my thing of the day bitch.
Rym: So with my unsubtle segue you probably all remember, I'm the juggernaut comma bitch Which was my thing of the day a while ago?
Rym: I'm the juggernaut bitch you shoot with my pimp cane.
Rym: Yeah, well it's back, and I'm sure you might have seen this in the news, but if not I Went to see probably the worst movie.
Rym: I have ever sat through in a theater.
Rym: x-men 3 okay.
Scott: So it's not the worst movie ever seen it's just the worst you've sat all the way through in the theater.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I've walked out of movies before I've turned movies off that I sat all the way through Clifford But that wasn't in a theater.
Rym: that was in my house Mm-hmm.
Rym: this movie was asked for reasons that I won't get into.
Rym: maybe we'll do a show on Comic book movies someday, maybe.
Scott: yeah be pretty good in fact.
Scott: I will.
Scott: I haven't seen many of them I've seen.
Scott: I saw the first x-men and didn't know why everyone else liked it a lot more than I did.
Scott: I saw hellboy, which is kind of normal ish.
Rym: We saw V.
Scott: V was a. it was probably the best one.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: well I'll put in the Netflix queue, and I'll put him to the top.
Rym: all the comic book movies We haven't seen.
Scott: you have to see some of the old Superman movies.
Rym: I've seen some of them.
Scott: Yeah You didn't see enough of them.
Rym: No.
Rym: I haven't.
Rym: yeah I'll put all those.
Rym: I haven't seen enough of them either, and then we'll do a show on that.
Scott: If anyone out there really all said to see our isn't the second spider-man movie supposed to be good?
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: the first one was good.
Scott: I didn't see the second one.
Scott: is there a third one?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm out of the movie loop, but x-men 3 is terrible.
Rym: Don't go see it.
Scott: They too late they already went to see it.
Rym: Well if you didn't go to see it yet I'm going to spoil it right now.
Rym: spoiler spoiler spoiler spoiler spoiler.
Rym: I was gonna loan gunman it But I decided not to because we do have some new listeners who don't realize how.
Rym: I don't know assholes we are sometimes Okay.
Rym: Jean Grey is killed by Wolverine but she tries to have sex with him and they kill Scott Summers in the very beginning of the movie and just for no reason.
Rym: and They kill Professor X and they take away Magneto's powers and the movies just dumb yeah.
Scott: But anyway, I just want to say anyone out there if you have never read x-men comics So you haven't read x-men comics contain?
Scott: You know old ones containing the real x-men stories because modern x-men comics aren't the real deal.
Scott: Go to like borders and they have these big black books And they say essential x-men on the side of them.
Scott: not essential uncanny x-men.
Scott: not essential x-men classic Just essential x-men.
Scott: the second volume of that is 10 bucks Just 10 bucks possibly even less than 10 bucks.
Scott: It's huge.
Scott: It's got like a hajillion comics in it And it contains the real x-men stories that you need to read.
Scott: once you read those Go back and watch these movies a little bit You know what.
Rym: if you want to see the best x-men that's in my opinion ever really been done.
Rym: check out the Fox cartoon Fox Cartoon rules.
Rym: that was x-men as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: as far as I'm concerned Because yeah the x-men that I read it was the x-men of the early 90s Which a lot of people consider to be the worst x-men, but that was when I was a kid.
Scott: So that's what I you know think is the real deal.
Rym: but anyway Obviously while it is Monday, and it is science and tech day.
Rym: We were just kind of rambling.
Scott: yay rambling Oh my thing of the day.
Rym: I didn't even do my thing of the day.
Rym: Oh, I didn't say anything yet I just said okay.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: We'll finish it up.
Rym: so in this movie.
Rym: the juggernaut is in it and You've all seen my on the juggernaut bitch video.
Rym: In the movie the juggernaut says the line.
Rym: don't you know who I am I'm the juggernaut bitch.
Rym: Awesome, I'm reasonably certain that the scene where the juggernaut says this was Added into the movie because of the on the juggernaut bitch movie that has been out on the internet.
Rym: I'm very certain that it was not the other way around because the people who made that video There's no way they could have known that that line was in the movie.
Scott: I don't think there was a way they knew either unless the video was made by someone who works on the movie.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just because the whole the x-men movie was really there were so many things they threw in that were just for super nerds Like those are the Morlocks aren't they?
Rym: yeah, but they don't even say anything about that.
Rym: They're just there.
Scott: it seems like a lot of the comic book movies.
Scott: They want to bring in the mass populace, but they don't want to alienate the nerds.
Scott: So they take all the nerdy stuff and they put it in the background Where the nerds go ooh and ah and get crazy over it and in the foreground is just the normal stuff that the normal people Can get and without being alienated and scared away by scary nerdy things,
Rym: but yeah I linked to the clip from the x-men movie of the juggernaut saying his line
Scott: Awesome,
Rym: that's pretty much the only now.
Rym: the best part was we're in the theater you know me Evan and Nury and we're watching this after the con.
Rym: so we're all exhausted and The movie was asked.
Rym: we're just sitting there periodically looking at each other when something stupid happens like what?
Rym: But then when the juggernaut said that line We exploded laughing and laughing and laughing and laughing and laughing anyone else.
Rym: no awesome the entire theater.
Rym: Everyone turned around.
Rym: they were looking at us with this.
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: What have not been on to Internet?
Rym: I don't think I think we were the only three people in the theater at any idea why that was funny.
Scott: That's awesome.
Scott: Okay, so I Always go for the Nintendo commercials and whenever I can and here is yet another one, but this isn't advertising Nintendo.
Scott: Well, I guess it kinda is indirectly.
Scott: This is an advertisement.
Scott: so for some furikake.
Scott: Furikake is some sort of rice topping.
Scott: you put it on rice.
Scott: No, it's furikake anyway.
Scott: This is a food ad for some brand of furikake in Japan and the ad features animated Mario And it's a pretty funny advertisement because apparently it's not mushrooms, but furikake that makes Mario grow big And the guy.
Scott: it's funny when the Japanese guy says super Mario brothers furikake.
Scott: It's hilarious.
Rym: I gotta keep resisting.
Rym: I keep like wanting to talk about the convention, but I'm gonna try to save that for my actual coverage on Wednesday.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, we don't have a tech topic today.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: You know what we kind of did.
Rym: We talked about patents enough All right.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: So I'll say that the show was about patents.
Scott: cool.
Scott: No, so, you know we didn't.
Scott: We don't have a real tech topic for today, so Straight to bed.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna say this stuff.
Scott: We have to say and put this episode up.
Scott: The first thing I have to say is that Friday I was on one of our listeners podcasts Called the Friday night party line.
Scott: The guy's name is Thade.
Scott: I think I think I pronounced it right.
Rym: Sorry Okay, a preachy.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's his real name.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Scott: I'm sure now he's going to listen to this and tell me that's right.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, if you want to hear me in my terrible logitech headset audio quality Of course, his audio quality is great.
Scott: Just my voice is terrible because I'm using logic headset.
Scott: if you want to hear me on someone else's podcast Discussing the stuff they wanted to talk about go to thae D dot libsyn.com And episode 9 contains me in it.
Scott: perhaps in the future Me and or Rym will be on his podcast or some other podcasts, you know as guests and such for awesome.
Scott: Yep, I mean you always let you know.
Rym: now that I have gone to an amazement I actually have some free weekends until you know Otakon and everything in August.
Rym: So we might actually be doing a lot more fun stuff with the podcast now that I have freaking free time Huzzah.
Scott: Yeah, of course the Sun will also be out.
Rym: So yeah, I mean it's great.
Rym: You know, I flew down to South Carolina North Carolina God and the weather was beautiful and hot.
Rym: it was like 90 The South Carolina scary.
Scott: don't go there.
Rym: But I came back here and it was just as hot though when I had left here was actually kind of chilly.
Scott: Yep, pretty much as soon as you left this insane heat and humidity set in right behind you.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I came home and I walked into the house and I said wow and I immediately put my air conditioner in the window.
Scott: Did you notice that mine was in the window?
Scott: I did indeed Before you put yours in or after.
Rym: nope, cuz I walked into my room I put mine in and then I noticed that the screen for your window.
Rym: Just as I noticed that my screen I had to pull it out of the window again, and there was a bug stuck to it.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, my screen was is downstairs in the under the stairs room.
Rym: I noticed it when I was looking for the foamy bit to stick in my window Haha, which I couldn't find.
Rym: so I have a towel stuck in there now.
Scott: I got my foamy bit still.
Rym: Yeah, I have mine.
Rym: I just got to find it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So air conditioners.
Scott: you everyone should have an air conditioner.
Scott: unless you live somewhere awesome We're.
Scott: no wait somewhere sucky cuz it's cold.
Rym: Honestly, I don't really like to use air conditioners much.
Rym: I'd rather get the.
Rym: you know, the nice smells outside of the nice breeze at night.
Rym: I really only use an air conditioner if it's hot and humid and I'm trying to sleep.
Rym: I Don't mind just hot humid.
Rym: I don't even use the air conditioner.
Rym: my car broke and I could have fixed it.
Rym: It would have been cheap.
Scott: I just never bothered because I don't care to be honest I put the air conditioner in my room this weekend more for the computers than for me.
Rym: Yeah, your room is basically our data center right now.
Scott: I mean I was a little bit hot but I wasn't too, you know A fan would have done just fine at one point.
Scott: It got a little cooler outside.
Scott: I opened the window I was just fine, but the computer was getting pissed off Really pissed off.
Scott: So I'm like fine.
Scott: I'll put the damn air conditioner in.
Rym: you know what?
Rym: Yeah, just think about when we started the podcast so long ago.
Rym: that wasn't during the heat.
Rym: So the listeners have never heard the alarm on my computer that goes off when it starts overheating.
Scott: Oh You know if that alarm goes off, the only thing we can do is restart your computer and wait.
Rym: so don't know I already fixed that.
Rym: I set the threshold significantly higher.
Rym: All right, and the alarm stopped going off.
Rym: That's right Just like I solved the loud case fan problem by unplugging the case fan.
Rym: Luckily my computer's so old and slow it hasn't complained much and it's really not overheating.
Scott: Well, I don't think it's gonna be a problem since you have the side of the case open and the air conditioning on.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, though.
Scott: I mean many a time I'd be playing counter-strike at RIT where we didn't have air conditioning and suddenly It's really when you try to use the video card, but remember your GeForce 2 isn't in there anymore.
Rym: Yeah, because it exploded.
Rym: now I got.
Scott: that's gonna help out a lot with the heat problem.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I've noticed I only ever had heat problems when I played games and the CPU and the video card were both maxed out.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now you have a shitty TNT - and there that doesn't make heat.
Rym: Yeah, your TNT - actually which was one hell of a piece of equipment back in the day.
Scott: Oh, man Was that thing?
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: It's still awesome.
Scott: I can play.
Scott: you can play half-life 1 and lesser games with it.
Rym: Yep, I currently can't get the 3d to work in Linux, but that's partly because I didn't try.
Rym: And there's something funky with the Nvidia driver.
Rym: I'm using currently Yeah, because I had to use a special Nvidia driver to make my GeForce 2 GTS work.
Scott: So my parents have the onboard video card in their computer and it has a little problem I think because these green dots all over the screen and it doesn't matter what monitor you use.
Scott: There's still green dots So I think I'm gonna buy them an AGP card to go in the slot.
Rym: I am the GeForce 4 that we got downstairs.
Scott: that thing has some GeForce 4s for 25 bucks.
Scott: I'm thinking about buying two or three of them.
Scott: What do you think?
Rym: Yeah, I'll probably go in on that.
Rym: It's good to have a couple video cards laying around.
Scott: Yeah, they're $25 AGP video cards.
Scott: I think we should buy a couple.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: We got to buy more network cable - yeah, I'll get on that at some point.
Rym: Yeah, so anyway, we're gonna wrap it up today.
Rym: Normally, the show is a little more structured, but we at least once or twice a month have a cop-out day.
Scott: Yeah, you try doing a podcast four nights a week and never copping out.
Scott: and yeah Try to you.
Scott: even every webcomic does some sketch day even penny arcade and they only do three nights You know with the penny arcade comics.
Scott: So imagine doing four once in a while.
Scott: You got to just not do a real episode.
Scott: You're glad.
Scott: you should be glad we do anything.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we debated early on like we considered dropping back early on to three shows a week instead of four.
Scott: Yeah, it's Memorial Day.
Rym: Yeah, we don't stop for anything.
Rym: 117 times about an hour worth of original internet content Plus all the extra episodes that you'll never hear.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of those five day a week podcasts They don't actually do full hours of podcasting.
Scott: They do crap.
Scott: They do like a minute show or something.
Rym: Yeah, we're mainly show rationalizing the fact that we do all this work for all of you.
Rym: Yeah, it's fun We like it.
Rym: We wouldn't be doing if we didn't like it and see what else.
Rym: we're also padding out this episode a little bit So we're kind of just drawing on anything we can think of.
Scott: Yep on Saturday.
Scott: I played board games all day.
Scott: I could talk about that on Tuesday.
Scott: Yep, Wednesday.
Scott: I will talk about an amazement on Sunday and today I was at my parents house and I ate food hung out Set someone up with DSL on Thursday.
Rym: I'd like to talk about the airline industry.
Scott: Do you want to talk about airlines?
Rym: Yes, I want to talk about airlines because I didn't talk about it today.
Rym: and God damn as I have I never in my life flown anywhere without complications.
Scott: God damn if I never had a complication while flying.
Rym: cuz you fly jet blue.
Rym: Yep Yeah, you know what.
Rym: jet blue doesn't go to half the places.
Rym: I want to go.
Scott: I don't go to those places.
Scott: I Just go wherever jet blue takes me.
Rym: Oh, you know if you want to go to all these cons with me next year You're gonna be flying on some not jet blue Airlines.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what?
Scott: I'm not gonna be flying on the broken flight.
Scott: It's gonna be perfect.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see about that.
Scott: yeah, we will see.
Scott: you'll see how I do it.
Rym: We're flying out of Stewart for everything first off.
Rym: Just screw JFK.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Screw that.
Scott: I'm going to JFK.
Rym: What?
Scott: All right, fine That way I won't have the shitty as delayed broken flights.
Rym: Actually the delays had nothing to do with Stewart.
Rym: The delays were just us air.
Scott: No There's your mistake right there.
Rym: us air as the cheapest flights and they're the only ones who fly to the places I wanted to go with the times I wanted to go for I'm willing to pay a little bit more to have a flight that doesn't have a problem.
Rym: No, you realize you don't get to pick if it has a problem or not.
Rym: Yeah, I do and it's not a little bit more.
Rym: the the difference between flying us versus flying someone else was like $200 more.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: maybe we'll have a little competition where we both fly from.
Scott: you know Wherever we want to the same destination and see who gets there first leaving this house at the same time.
Rym: That doesn't work because I take flights based on price not on when they leave.
Rym: hence I went to an amazement Thursday morning and I came back today.
Rym: Yeah, well is that that saved me another couple?
Rym: it would have been to get the exact perfect flight.
Rym: the flight that went there Thursday night and came back Monday morning and Was a direct flight and everything would have cost me about six hundred dollars round trip.
Rym: Instead I paid about two hundred dollars round trip Mm-hmm, and all I had to do was get delayed for an hour in Philly and then get delayed for an hour in Philly.
Rym: I got delayed going in got delayed coming back.
Rym: Both delays were exactly one hour.
Scott: Yeah You got a DS.
Scott: It's all good.
Rym: Yeah I also got free drinks on the flight back to Stewart as a Consolation for the fact I was in an episode on new Mario Brothers have wing now.
Rym: But we'll probably do that later because I'm sure we'll have enough gaming to talk about tomorrow as it is.
Rym: Because remember I'm gonna cover the video gaming at an amazement tomorrow as I those video gaming there.
Rym: Oh, yeah My last bit about an amazement because I it's all trying to just spew out of my mouth and I'm trying to hold it in.
Rym: Plus I want to go over my notes to make sure I didn't forget anything.
Rym: An amazement is a small con.
Rym: Remember we did our series on anime conventions and we kind of broke it up into.
Rym: there's three levels of convention Like the small con the mid-sized con and then the gargantuan con.
Rym: like Early, Ohio con it is the lower one may anime central is the mid one and like Otakana anime Expo or the third ones.
Rym: Mm-hmm An amazement is.
Rym: the is as big and awesome as a small con can be.
Rym: it's like the Absolute top of a one hotel.
Rym: small con.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: They have you know about 3,000 Change.
Rym: people show up that they really can't expand without becoming the next level of convention.
Scott: I guess they might have to step it up.
Rym: The thing is because they're that big yet.
Rym: There's still a small con.
Rym: They have all the benefits of a big con, you know the full-on gaming room the the of the good cosplay the I Don't want to say good but as good as they're going to be given how good and these are today and the contest.
Rym: And they're actually some clever ways of funny.
Rym: Actually the best music video at all of the con and I'll leave you all with this was to char from Original Gundam.
Rym: great and it was just some polka song The Gundam polka I Got I could offer to a two-hour show on Wednesday.
Scott: Well good, then we'll have to talk so much and then I can come back next week with some big something's.
Rym: Yep Once again, welcome all of our new listeners.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: If you're a new listener, make sure you go to front row crew calm Yes and join the forum which actually is very lively.
Scott: Yeah more people keep joining constantly.
Scott: It's getting out of control now.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we started the forum way way back when we started GeekNights and we told all our friends to join and
Scott: It's slowly Kind of didn't do anything because
Rym: our friend
Scott: is like a false start
Rym: because our friends all talk We all just talk to each other.
Rym: We don't need a forum Yeah, and then we started getting listeners and after a couple of weeks all these people we didn't know join the forums.
Rym: And now the forums are self-sustaining.
Rym: like I come back after five days and there's all these posts and they're opposed.
Rym: It's great.
Scott: I check it every day just cuz I have nothing to do at work.
Rym: Yeah, I got stuff to do at work now.
Rym: Yep, plus I haven't even followed up on the news from the weekend.
Rym: I didn't even check my email until I got back.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I saw there's a bunch of emails from fans and listeners.
Rym: Did Scott did you take care of those?
Rym: Did you answer him or anything?
Scott: Some of them.
Scott: Yeah, all right the ones that were important.
Scott: I Actually went.
Scott: Oh, I actually read a bunch of fan emails on Thursday.
Rym: Alright cuz I saw a bunch there and I wondered if we because we tried it We really try to be good and if someone talks to us at least remember that if you send us an email We do read them all.
Rym: Mm-hmm, like.
Rym: it may take a while, but we read them all.
Rym: we may not respond because we don't have time to do that But we read them.
Scott: Yeah, the only the only ones we got lately were like hey check out this cool thing and that sort of email.
Rym: Yeah, well, I got a couple shells again.
Scott: I see did we get some shells?
Scott: Maybe they're in my spam folder.
Rym: Yeah, I got some shills in a foreign language about some music.
Scott: No, really, but they want.
Rym: I saw the word podcast in there.
Rym: So they know we're a podcast but they want they want us to show some music from Spain.
Scott: I think we're not gonna show Spanish music.
Scott: Sorry.
Rym: No, we're not gonna show that book either.
Scott: We should you know, the thing is I would anti shill things say don't buy this.
Rym: No, remember what happened with kagehime.
Rym: Yeah, we said don't watch kagehime.
Rym: It's a terrible disturbing anime.
Rym: all our listeners watched it and then they posted.
Rym: Wow, that was horrible.
Rym: Well, I shouldn't have watched.
Scott: so when someone comes to us and says hey do you you know?
Scott: We have a product.
Scott: tell your listeners, you know to buy it We're gonna.
Scott: you know, if we tell our listeners not to buy it some of them are gonna buy it.
Scott: So we have to just not say anything at all Unless we actually want to shill it out.
Rym: and if we shill it out, we'll let you know Yep, so I guess last and least for all of you who came looking for an amazement coverage the format of our show is generally That Mondays are science and technology days Tuesdays are gaming in general Wednesdays anime.
Rym: so Wednesday I'm going to have my full press coverage of the convention including all my interviews all my stories the traffic jam the cosplay everything And a Thursday we do whatever the hell we want.
Rym: Yeah Which apparently is probably going to be airlines unless something happens until any time before Thursday.
Scott: and of course email us.
Scott: GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Rym: Yep, or GeekNights at gmail.com.
Rym: I guess that's still where they go to the same bin.
Rym: It doesn't matter all my email accounts filter into one account.
Scott: It's the same email GeekNights at whatever.
Rym: Or if you do if you want to complain about Scott Rym at front row crew calm.
Scott: Yeah, you can complain about Rym at to.
Scott: well a PR e CH e at front row crew calm.
Rym: Yeah, it's funny.
Rym: How my I guess stage name is also my real name.
Rym: So I'm Rym everywhere online Except for places where I don't run people to know who I am.
Scott: I'm a PR e CH e everywhere online Absolutely everywhere.
Scott: I'm online.
Scott: That's my name.
Rym: No one else has that name except here on GeekNights where you are Scott.
Scott: Well, that's my real name.
Scott: Yeah, that's the name I use in flesh.
Rym: So I use the same name everywhere except work.
Rym: work is where my name is my real name.
Rym: No, not my real name my given name my legal name my name Lombre.
Rym: Alright the cop-out episode has finished.
Scott: Oh wait number.
Scott: It's it's yamo.
Scott: Whatever I Forget Spanish good game High school.
Rym: Yeah And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.front row.
Scott: crew calm if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.