Rym: It's Monday July 17th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We move towards science fiction.
Rym: for a bit when Scott talks about the first of the lens man boats while I talk a bit about the difference engine Let's do this.
Rym: if you notice a strange noise in the background today It's because we've left the air conditioning on due to the fact that despite the Sun having gone down.
Rym: It is still a 100 billion degree night Warm today.
Scott: warm yesterday even warmer today.
Rym: Yeah In fact, it's so hot that I was at work today And I was listening to a bunch of podcasts which I'll get to because I got a lot to say about the pot.
Scott: oh sphere Oh great.
Rym: Yeah, I got a little manifesto here But I was at work, and I'm listening to my iPod and I'm typing and I'm drinking something and suddenly my computer turns off and I think Is my computer broken?
Rym: did the power go out, but my brain says you're hearing music the power is not out.
Scott: Were you listening to on your iPod or your computer iPod?
Rym: Now of course.
Rym: then I look to my left and my telephone Which is super digital is still on and working, but is it a vo IP or no?
Rym: no?
Scott: But it's just an internal digital phone network.
Scott: Yeah, like log lines out.
Rym: Yeah, it's like yeah Voice over IP.
Scott: yeah, I know what you're doing.
Rym: Yeah, so then I look back and I look up and I realized hey all the lights went out.
Rym: And yeah, the power was out woot Blackout.
Scott: yeah, it was actually one of the sticks at my work when I was there.
Scott: is they'd be like he's gonna black out black out.
Scott: They had a joke about blackouts.
Rym: the funniest thing was it went out.
Rym: and what I realized?
Rym: the power is out almost immediately.
Rym: Someone like two cubes over goes son of uh.
Rym: and then someone else like save his work.
Rym: And then someone else says fuck it.
Rym: I'm going home.
Scott: Yeah, good thing.
Scott: We bought UPS is just the other day.
Scott: Yeah, now we're gonna go buy some more.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna buy like four UPS's and stick them on everything.
Scott: Yeah, that's cool because then they'll be less excuse to not do GeekNights.
Scott: Yep, because we at the at the worst if we can keep the networking equipment on.
Scott: no if we get we'll just turn the networking equipment off.
Scott: well To record the podcast on my laptop, hopefully the battery on it won't die.
Scott: and Then we'll plug the networking equipment in power it up on the battery Connect with the wireless or wire with the laptop.
Rym: Yeah Upload it and then turn everything back off when because five minute you it would have to be one fuck of a power outage For us to not be able to use our cable modem.
Scott: It really would yeah, especially, you know I mean for the cable company would have to die when.
Rym: yeah, the thing is it was weird It was a power distribution problem.
Rym: because for all of you who don't live in downstate, New York like we do We're on the edge of remember in California had those rolling blackouts and all those problems.
Rym: New York State is getting real close to that.
Scott: like maybe we should build a power plant.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but instead we have people protesting the power plant we have right here.
Scott: But wait.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what if we gave them what they wanted and we got rid of that power plant?
Scott: What would we'd have?
Rym: Well, we'd have fucking chaos.
Rym: that's what we'd have because the power would stop.
Scott: Oh Geniuses those people are.
Rym: yeah, but seriously downstate New York is pretty much at capacity for electricity.
Rym: So power outages are becoming more and more common and there if anything happens to any of the power plants around here GeekNights might be in trouble for a week or two.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean think about it man Just a few rods of some metal in a big box basic a big cement box.
Scott: With me up the power is now perfect.
Scott: Yeah, all we need is a freaking metal in a box and we're fine with some water flowing it through it.
Rym: All right anyway, now the reason I was listening to music is because well, I was listening to my iPod at least because I finally Decided to listen to a bunch of podcasts.
Scott: now that we have the Mac all set up finally and Rym finally learned the lessons that I learned when the iPod nano came out and I first discovered podcast.
Rym: Yeah, so I found like 20 podcasts that looked good and I subscribed to all of them and I looked good Based on their text describe.
Scott: They didn't sound good.
Scott: I bet.
Rym: now one thing is I found that all the educational ones I subscribed to so far are really good.
Rym: In fact, I want to plug the 12 Byzantine Empire or Emperor's podcast Which is just discussions of 12 different emperors of the Byzantine aka the Eastern Roman Empire.
Rym: All right, it's so far fascinating.
Rym: however All the other podcasts I subscribe to were varying levels of ass.
Scott: How much is?
Rym: I'm not gonna name names because a couple of them I listen to or kind of big names but I subscribe to a bunch of anime and Video game podcast.
Rym: the video game ones were all unmitigated Asshole, they were just quiet nerdy nerds Barely talking about video games that they don't even know much about.
Rym: Like one guy was talking about Grand Theft Auto and he didn't even know who made it.
Rym: Maybe like he was mentioning like publishers of games.
Rym: But then he'd like he said the wrong publisher and he didn't know who made Grand Theft Auto.
Scott: It's developed by rockstar, but it's published by take to interactive Yeah, and it was just kind of.
Scott: I know that and I haven't played Grand Theft Auto since Grand Theft Auto one.
Rym: Well, London expansion pack, but even so listening to these podcasts was like watching the first 15 minutes of Napoleon Dynamite.
Rym: It's just painful
Scott: Yeah as basically the thing I got from podcasts I mean, you know, I felt bad because you know podcasting feels like blogging like it's this big amateur medium full of all sorts of interesting non-professional Big media people making good stuff, but in the end after you know, most amateur shit 99% of it is ass.
Rym: Yeah, well webcomics are the same way.
Rym: I mean, there's the big names and then there's all the good comics and then for every good comic there are a hundred bad ones.
Scott: Let's see how many podcasts do I actually still subscribe to one two, three, four five six seven eight nine Ten eleven twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen and one of those is like a temporary.
Scott: I'm checking it out.
Rym: So fourteen Two of the ones I subscribe to have already pod faded.
Scott: Yeah, let's see how many of these are professional one two three four five six four five Six.
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure everyone wants to hear you counting.
Scott: Okay, so half the podcasts I listen to are not amateur and half of them are yep.
Rym: Now the anime ones didn't fare much better so far.
Rym: The only anime related podcast I can at all stand to listen to are GeekNights.
Rym: Oh, I do listen to a portion of every episode now just to make sure that every audio is okay and everything's going fine.
Rym: and
Scott: I listen to a few episodes and They kind of entertain me even though I know
Rym: Surprisingly when I listen it actually is kind of cool because one I'll forget things that I said or Scott said a bunch of stuff that that
Scott: would be the best if I could somehow forget GeekNights Yeah, anything I said and then listen to all of it
Rym: or like Scott will say stuff to me during on the show.
Rym: But I'm not actually listening because I'm busy like writing or getting ready for the next bit or something.
Rym: And then I listen.
Rym: it was like, oh Scott says something really cool.
Scott: Yeah, I say things all the time.
Rym: Yes, don't pay attention as most of them are kind of man.
Scott: He's a Mr.
Scott: May.
Rym: but then anime world order which is the only other anime podcast.
Rym: I found that doesn't suck.
Rym: so far.
Scott: I have one video anime podcast besides anime world order that I subscribe to which is anime podcast net aka.
Scott: Hey Yeah, that's that's as close as I can get to pronouncing it.
Rym: I don't know I can't deal with video podcast because I don't have time to sit and watch.
Scott: that's the thing is the video podcast I do are all short.
Scott: It's got to be like less than five minutes.
Scott: So it's the equivalent to watching something on YouTube, you know, yeah It's like it's basically someone who I know is gonna keep posting the same kind of thing and it's gonna be short.
Scott: if it's like An actual show forget it.
Rym: It's too much Yeah, but anyway to move on a bit because we're trying to rein in the episode length back to what it originally was Yeah Cuz.
Scott: we've been getting episodes out of like an hour and a half a little over an hour and we really need to bring it Back to 45 minutes because we have the maximum libsyn account and we got dangerously close to filling it.
Rym: Yeah, also the fact that I think if we go long just out of course We'll end up doing kind of a haphazard treatment of topics that would better be served by doing multiple episodes.
Scott: Yes, and also, you know, we have you know, there's a bin of stuff to talk about and a bin of stuff That's talked about.
Rym: Yeah, we talk every weeknight.
Scott: So if we have the bin that's you know, one item in the bin is pretty big.
Scott: It's better to chop it up and use it for two weeks instead of just making one big long episode one week.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: Cuz that way the bin doesn't run out as quickly because
Rym: it hit us once way back when we were reviewing anime for a while you know before con season and then we reviewed like two or three shows in an episode and then we Ran out of new shows to talk about Because we didn't space it out and we probably could have covered all those shows in better depth by breaking it up more.
Scott: Yep, so that's what we're gonna do whether you like it or not.
Rym: also, we're really gonna try to cut back on the news section because GeekNights is basically turned into.
Rym: the first half is just twit with Rym and Scott and then the second half is the show.
Scott: Yeah, so with the new edition of the geek back segment, which is gonna come in like 10 seconds We are going to just reduce to one news and two things the day six five.
Rym: Well, I guess we're doing it early then.
Scott: Yes, we are.
Scott: All right geek back ahead of schedule.
Scott: The geek back for today is from Robert who is the awesome guy in the army and he says hello again random Rym and Scott.
Scott: to begin I would like to say I'm still loving your shows, but I still wish you talked more about comics.
Scott: Well, I guess that's a good thing because you know I always seem to think that people might be like listening to our show and then getting tired of it and stop listening.
Scott: But if he's still loving our shows, that's cool.
Rym: Also this Thursday, we're going to talk about a comic.
Scott: Yeah Wednesday.
Rym: Oh, yeah Wednesday Yeah, I always it's because anime Club was on Thursday back at I know I know but Wednesday night Wednesday episode we can.
Scott: I see we're going to talk about a comic we already recorded.
Scott: Now y'all where now?
Scott: y'all were talking on Monday night's episode about Firefox works and all the websites.
Scott: This is mostly true.
Scott: However, I have found that government related websites.
Rym: I can't use while I use Firefox you're totally right and we didn't even think to say anything about that.
Rym: because Actually, I run into that a lot in New York State because there are a bunch of websites.
Rym: We can look at New York State laws and submit forms and none of them work at all in Firefox.
Scott: I forget if we discuss this on the show or in the forum or somewhere about you know how why open document formats were important.
Scott: because you know If you don't have an open document format, then it's basically government forcing you to choose You know a particular piece of software in order to get things that should be free because your tax money paid for them.
Scott: You know, it's kind of like if the government for you know uses this then that means you have to use this software.
Scott: It would be the same as if the government made a road that only a Ford car could drive on so a government making a website that only an Internet Explorer can work on is equally bad.
Scott: and I would submit that if I had more money and a lawyer if I encountered a government website that did not function in every Single web browser that exists and follows these standards for websites that I would sue and say hey You're you know,
Rym: the thing is I think he's talking probably more about Internal government or military, you know internet kind of sites where I mean if they give you the computer and they give you IE They can really kind of do that.
Scott: But that is true.
Rym: The one thing I'll say about that is that the military when it comes to technology is relatively smart.
Scott: at least Yeah to me, but I don't know I've not.
Rym: I mean it seems that from what I can gather because I have a lot of friends in the military Actually, they're ones that Scott doesn't know.
Rym: They're my the other crew I hang out with but at you know Conventions and from what I can the military seems to move very slowly in adopting widely technology at least Technology that we would care about.
Rym: there are other kinds of technology.
Rym: They seem to adopt rather quickly maybe hastily even but it seems like Very slowly.
Rym: they will lumber toward whatever is the most efficient thing and I wouldn't doubt for a second that Eventually the military will lumber toward open source.
Scott: Yeah, it seems to be slowly going that way.
Scott: You know the military You know in their search to you know, find whatever gives them some sort of combat advantage.
Scott: I guess at least that's what it seems like they want.
Scott: They're pretty much willing to try anything, you know, and they actually seriously check out what works the best for them.
Rym: yeah, I mean like look at back during the not prohibition but integration and Segregation the military is one of the first organizations to say.
Rym: All right, whatever We're mixing you all together because it's stupid to separate you.
Rym: and yeah now go kill.
Scott: Exactly, you know the when they're looking for some armor, you know.
Scott: Then they go to all the companies that make armor and say hey, what do you got?
Scott: And of course, it's probably some bribing and corruption in there.
Scott: But if you take that out of the equation, yeah, and you can't I mean that's everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, they seriously try to figure out what's the best, you know for the money and you know, they check shit out.
Scott: So also let me finish his email.
Scott: It's kind of short.
Scott: This really ticks me off because I hate the times I have to use Internet Explorer while on government computers So when I have to use it on my own on my personal computer I hate it so much more.
Scott: I'm with y'all on your feelings about Firefox versus Internet Explorer.
Rym: Sincerely Robert from the army Well fight the good fight and hang on.
Rym: maybe someday in the next 20 years or so.
Rym: They'll move toward Firefox.
Scott: Yeah, maybe you know, I mean, I don't know much about the you know detailed organization of the US Army.
Scott: But is there like a division that deals with IT stuff that you know, or is it contracted out?
Scott: You know, there's got to be someone you can talk to or something.
Scott: Yeah I actually I should ask some even even if you're not trying to convince them or you know Or switch them over you get at least like discuss it with them be like hey question them out.
Scott: Yeah, that'd be cool.
Scott: What is the government IT guy think about Firefox?
Scott: Does he even know it exists?
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, thanks for email.
Rym: I mean now that we're doing this geek back We're gonna actually probably read a lot of the feedback we get.
Rym: so if you have anything to say to us send it in.
Scott: We just got one.
Scott: I think it's good for tomorrow, even though it's kind of long.
Rym: I don't know I got one for tomorrow.
Scott: Okay, then maybe it'll be delayed a week anyway.
Rym: Yeah, all right, so we also have some news and it's Monday so I don't feel bad doing a tech to it.
Rym: news.
Scott: Yeah Okay, what's the news?
Rym: you want to do it?
Rym: Cuz this is the one you wanted.
Scott: I've had the webpage open.
Scott: neither Do I go.
Rym: awesome great?
Rym: All right.
Rym: All right The long story short is this the individual story doesn't matter because the the base of this the crux of this is something that happens all the time a major company has a problem or Maybe is starting to lose market share to open source things.
Rym: So the first thing they do is Blame open source for their trouble or they run negative ad campaigns.
Rym: They spread some fud bud fud fud fud about open source.
Rym: I'm sure you all know what FUD stands for.
Scott: It's fear.
Scott: and so I found the story.
Rym: All right fear uncertainty and doubt.
Rym: I actually did a speech about FUD at RIT when I took in a Communications class where I was public speaking and all that.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So I think the first paragraph of this thing pretty much sums it up McAfee or McAfee or yeah McAfee Yeah, I've always heard McAfee.
Scott: Yeah, they Hackers have borrowed the same open source development techniques used to build Firefox Apache and Linux as they collaborate on malware projects.
Scott: a security company's researchers claim Monday.
Rym: Alright McAfee, you know what?
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I want everyone to go to our forum and see the thing I wrote to classic brai about the history of Software development and the original hackers.
Scott: people don't seem to realize all programming all computer programming was open source until The 70s, you know from the early days at MIT Up until the 70s all software was open source.
Scott: in fact not open source was like a crazy idea.
Rym: Yeah, like I remember watching in my history of computing classes a lot of documentaries We read a lot of articles written by you know early computer hackers and early computer programmers Without exception.
Rym: like one of them wrote about something like how one of his friends or someone in the computer club at MIT Had the idea like he was trying to sell a program and all of his friends Just kind of laughed at him like he was an idiot.
Scott: Yeah, the word hacker comes from the MIT Railroad Club, I think it's the.
Scott: I forget the exact name of it But what?
Scott: because people would you know, they would be in their little room working on their little model trains all day Hacking away on you know, because you're sitting under this big table hacking away on the train tracks.
Scott: That's why they called him hackers But those were the guys who also did a bunch of computer stuff and they would take their source code and post it up on the wall for people to see and to share and to learn from.
Scott: Hackers and people like that have been doing this as long as computers have existed.
Rym: Yep, and I mean hacking doesn't just apply to computers I mean people hack things all the time if you're in an alley.
Scott: Yeah, and that I don't want to talk about like, you know, the semantic definition of hacking.
Scott: Well, yeah Hacking cracking white hat.
Scott: Yeah, that's a whole separate discuss head.
Scott: The point is is that the open source development techniques have been around far longer than Firefox Apache or Linux.
Scott: They've been around longer than the closed source development techniques.
Rym: Also to extend their analogy and thus destroy their argument by means of what is almost a straw man They blame, you know, they say oh these botnet people use the same techniques that were used to make Firefox blah blah.
Rym: You know what the US military uses many of the same techniques that were used by the Nazis in World War two.
Scott: Oh God went alert.
Scott: God win.
Scott: incoming God win.
Scott: watch out We need a. we need a special God win alert sound effect.
Rym: I was thinking about that as you were making those noises.
Scott: Yeah, that's definitely Minds think alike, you know, yeah.
Rym: Well real soon.
Rym: I'm gonna start fiddling with the Mac like Hitler and Goebbels.
Rym: Maybe I'll take some clips from the mr.
Rym: Hilda sketch (Laughter).
Rym: Things of the day Dinghy, all right.
Rym: Now this might seem like a strange thing of the day So I'm gonna give you the background story as to how this came about and then I will reveal my thing of the day.
Rym: So Scott and I last weekend this previous weekend.
Rym: There was the first weekend We've had in almost all summer where we were free.
Rym: We had absolutely no obligations responsibilities or plans.
Scott: There was an end convention.
Scott: There was no one coming to our house.
Scott: We weren't going to anyone's house.
Scott: We didn't have any family obligations.
Scott: There was no holiday.
Scott: There was nothing so we didn't have any errands to run that were urgent.
Rym: Yep Thus we made a list and we drove up the road Into all the other towns went to every store we needed to do did everything.
Rym: on the way back I stopped at a liquor store because I needed to replenish my supply of liquor Great, which I don't drink.
Rym: Yeah, not so much replenish as add to because I was missing a lot of key components like vermouth.
Rym: I didn't have any vermouth, but that's beside the point.
Rym: So we go into the liquor store, which is a massive high-class nice store.
Rym: I mean, I like the place a lot and while I'm in the port section picking up a wine Scott asks where the mad train wine is.
Scott: Yeah, you know mad train as in mad dog or night train or Thunderbird the stuff that winos buy in large quantity.
Scott: that's mostly sugar.
Scott: and Yeah, yeah, I wanted to see what it looked like.
Scott: cuz you never really see that shit.
Rym: He actually wanted to ask the guy at the store.
Rym: Where's the stuff the winos by?
Rym: Yeah I mean a big box of cheap one Yeah, but I mean the place doesn't even carry stuff like that, but we call it mad train wine.
Rym: That's our catch-all because in Kingdom of Loathing a game.
Rym: We don't play anymore, but was really fun while about a week Alcohol was a big part of that game.
Rym: It was a kind of an MMO text adventure thing and The cheapest primary alcohol was mad train wine.
Rym: I'll play on mad dog and night train.
Rym: We assume Yeah, I'm reasonably certain now.
Rym: Then you know.
Rym: then on the way home We were talking about you know all those wino type wines and making fun of it And we decided the next time we drove past the seedy liquor store We're gonna go in and get some just to laugh at it.
Scott: I think we might actually just get a bottle of Thunderbird wine.
Scott: Yeah So there it is Thunderbird wine.
Rym: So yeah, so then I don't think we'd ever drink it.
Rym: that stuff can't be.
Scott: I might take like a spoonful of it Just to say yeah, I wouldn't drink it though.
Rym: Well, I remember we both took a spoonful of that pushers rum and it tasted like unmitigated poison.
Scott: I think it needs to be converted into grog.
Rym: Yeah, we'll make some grog at some point.
Rym: I won't be drinking that got to take a tot of it at least.
Rym: then you can say you're a sailing man.
Scott: I'm not a sailing man.
Scott: In fact, I've never sailed.
Rym: You're a software pirate.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well you were.
Scott: yeah I was there now.
Scott: I'm all open source in a fire.
Rym: Anyway, so we had a long discussion about why no wine.
Rym: Then we get home.
Rym: I come up to my room and what's the top story on FARC?
Rym: How to make cheap wine and in the.
Rym: the article was pretty good But the first link posted in the FARC thread which I'm already laughing about the fact that our lives are topical to FARC is How to make prison wine quite literally how to make sangria in the turn.
Scott: Hey, you're making sangria in a toilet course.
Rym: It's shanker B shanks and apparently in Prison the way people make wine they don't do it in the in the toilet so much But what they do is they'll take a trash bag.
Rym: they fill it with all the fruit juices they can get their hands on all the sugar they can get their hands on and socks filled with moldy bread.
Rym: and these guys from this link on the internet did it and tasted it and It's like pretending to be in prison.
Rym: Yeah, only without all the you know.
Rym: fun prison rape exactly.
Rym: yes Follow this FARC thread and the story and the first link in the FARC thread.
Rym: if you want to learn a lot about things You should never ever drink.
Scott: Yeah, if there's anything ever that you should not try at home.
Scott: This is it.
Rym: Yeah, prison wine is pretty much the bottom right?
Scott: Oh, but but continuing our theme of you shouldn't do this is my thing of the day.
Rym: I think you should do this cuz I was a punk kid like that once.
Scott: oh indeed indeed.
Scott: But I also only suggest doing it if you were very good in the skills.
Rym: These guys weren't so skilled.
Scott: They were moderately skilled.
Rym: They were but they fell all over their asses.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, so Apparently there was this water park that was abandoned.
Scott: It looks a lot like action park to me But it's not action park because I found some abandoned pictures of action park on the internet.
Scott: And this is not it because there was one slide that both parks have.
Scott: But the slide at this park was blue and yellow an action park.
Scott: It was red and yellow, so it's not action park.
Scott: this is a bunch of punk kids who sneak into this abandoned water park and They rollerblade on the dried up water slide.
Rym: It's pretty badass.
Scott: While it's crazy dangerous Crazy stupid it's crazy awesome.
Rym: Also when I watched it It was really awesome And it really brought me back to my days as a punk rollerblading kid even though I could do like two tricks.
Rym: Yeah, I just mostly rollerbladed around for fun and every time I tried to do tricks I'd hurt myself, and then I'd give up immediately.
Scott: yeah these guys seem to have you know a moderate average level of trick skills.
Scott: You know they grind on the side of the slides.
Scott: They can jump from one slide to the other which is probably the coolest part of the video.
Rym: But actually the music in the video is way cool.
Scott: if anyone knows What song they're playing in this video?
Scott: I want to know because it's a good song.
Rym: yeah Cuz I really don't feel like doing research to find it But it was a song that I'd never heard before and I never heard anything quite like it before.
Rym: Yep, I mean it's similar to some of those hip-hop type remixes where they take an old song and they sample it And they remix it to hell and make it awesome, but I don't know I like it.
Scott: I like it, and I want to know what it is.
Scott: so someone tell me and also these kids are Good kids.
Scott: yeah, I want to see more and there's no belly man coming to beat them up.
Rym: He was on his way.
Rym: Just took him a while.
Rym: You know that belly.
Rym: You know I know right Yep, so anyway today is Monday, which is science technology gadgetry Linux computers and Science fiction.
Rym: yes, we have decided to add science fiction to Monday Mostly because the only other place it could fit is Wednesday or Thursday.
Rym: both days We already have far more content than we'll ever get to.
Scott: yeah, and you know it it really only fits in on Monday.
Scott: and I mean you think I think we did a Thursday on Star Wars a long time ago.
Scott: Yeah, but if we start really doing more sci-fi stuff I mean there's still this room on Monday to put that there isn't room on Thursday.
Rym: Yeah, and Wednesday is our fullest day.
Scott: and also you know for us being super do-everything geeky geeks that we are We're not so much sci-fi.
Rym: Well it I I am more than Scott.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I mean I loved Firefly.
Rym: I think Battlestar Galactica the original and the new one are both awesome.
Rym: I absolutely loved the next generation and the original Star Trek.
Scott: yeah See I don't like.
Scott: it's pretty much almost no science fiction television shows that I like.
Scott: like the stuff That is essentially you know just stories that happen to be in space or stories that happen to involve crazy technology or the future.
Rym: I'm generally not always a fan of What if they made a TV series or a movie based on like stranger in a strange land?
Rym: Yeah, and it was well done.
Scott: So that's the thing is stuff.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: I really only like.
Scott: you know the quote hard Sci-fi like you know Twilight Zone.
Scott: some of it is hard sci-fi.
Scott: You know stuff like that.
Scott: you know stranger in a strange land is a real hard science fiction foundation.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: and I also like the classic sci-fi which you know.
Scott: foundation.
Scott: yeah This stuff you know Star Trek.
Scott: I really don't like Star Trek.
Rym: Yeah, or just like stuff.
Scott: It just doesn't do anything for me at all.
Rym: Yeah, we both very much like things by.
Rym: you know William Gibson Neil.
Scott: So those are cyberpunk, which is like a sub-genre, but yeah But it's it's there.
Scott: the point is is that we're not the hugest super sci-fi nerds like some people and therefore There's plenty of room on Monday to put a little bit of science fiction that we have Especially since we're reading a lot more now that at least in terms of the podcast.
Rym: It doesn't take us any Extraordinary effort to do the episode.
Scott: yeah most of the sci-fi that will do will be novels that we have read.
Rym: yeah So so today we decided we do it.
Rym: We'll probably talk about both of these again after we both read the other one, but Scott is currently reading something.
Scott: Well, I finished it.
Rym: Well that you finished the first one of the series about that Yep, and I recently finished a book.
Rym: They're both very good science fiction, and we'll both just kind of talk about them.
Rym: all right, so you want to go first.
Scott: Okay, I read it's like a little.
Scott: it's the GeekNights book club that we talked about.
Scott: I just finished reading Galactic Patrol by EE doc Smith.
Scott: doc is one of those you know nicknames and quotes in the middle there and This is the first book in the lens min series.
Rym: now you may or may not have heard of lens min from the anime Pretend.
Rym: it doesn't exist for now.
Scott: Yes in the future.
Scott: We will probably do a giant all lens min episode with all the books and the anime and the whole thing But not right now.
Scott: That'll be for another time.
Rym: Yes, perhaps.
Rym: You will do it with anime world order.
Scott: Now what can I say about this book?
Scott: Well, it's pretty short.
Scott: So you know if even if you're the kind of person who can't handle like a giant book or lots of really hard Writing this is not that this is very you know.
Scott: it's moderately easy to read for any literate Adult.
Scott: it doesn't take long.
Scott: it reads pretty quickly.
Scott: if you don't you know mull over it Which you probably shouldn't have to and it's enjoyable.
Scott: It's lacking in Like you know depth and hardcore and I say you know I expected more of a hard science fiction book and that's not really what you get.
Scott: you get more of a space adventure of awesome.
Scott: it reminds me a lot actually of a a lot of those manga that we read like the political ones like Sanctuary and Eagle.
Scott: not because it's political because it really isn't very political at all.
Scott: but Lensman is about you know a guy who's just badass and awesome and does the smart thing.
Rym: Yeah, it seems very rare that characters in things we watch or read will do the obvious smart thing or the thing that we would do or Something smarter than we would have even thought to do.
Rym: It's usually ah you dumbass.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like.
Scott: there are certain things like you know.
Scott: normally if you watch a sitcom on TV or any drama it all.
Scott: I have a theory that Scott's hypothesis of the drama stupidity the drama stupidity Hypothesis and where there cannot be drama it without stupidity because if everyone is smart there won't be anything Happening to cause drama.
Rym: well I can think of one exception.
Rym: Let's say we've got two nations fighting over resources.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Scott: They're both smart you get but you get.
Rym: my point is yeah Yeah, when you know what drama in the OMG drama sense as opposed to drama.
Rym: Yes, exactly You know it's oh my god, so and so ban me from her live journal because so and so thinks the so-and-so's cheating on so And so after I read.
Scott: okay, that's enough of that.
Scott: When you know you watch sitcoms and things on TV and it most movies Hollywood movies you know you see characters do things that are stupid, and it pisses you off cuz like why didn't you do this?
Rym: Oh, it was so obvious What god like in Nana that we just watched an episode of where a character did something real dumb exactly?
Scott: Lensman is actually about a guy who can't be stupid.
Scott: you see it starts out.
Scott: Well, let me let me give you a picture of this universe you ready.
Scott: It's a space universe.
Scott: people can.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: Actually the way they fly through space faster than light is they remove inertia like the spaceships.
Scott: they take inertia out of the spaceships, and then they go away and They're constantly talking about how they're gonna.
Scott: You know landing free or you know going inert and the people can go inert and un-inert with.
Scott: you know They have devices to help them do this.
Scott: It's not just a magic powers.
Scott: So they're always talking about like oh, you know You know if you start running then you take away your inertia And then you put it back on you'll still be going forward because the inertia was still from before.
Scott: So like you take your spaceship off then you go You know you remove the inertia then landing is always tricky And it's pretty cool when they they deal with that in a somewhat.
Scott: I guess realistic way yeah, but no it's a universe.
Scott: or people can fly around real fast from planet to planet.
Scott: and And There is one civilization called the Galactic Patrol, and it's a relatively new civilization.
Scott: and there is another civilization called Boscone or Boscone, I can't really tell because it's a book.
Scott: Boscone yeah, B O S K O N E and Basically, they're quote space pirates, but really they're not space pirates They're you know like in the classic sense even though they do a lot of space pirating.
Scott: They're sort of an evil galactic civilization.
Rym: Yeah, too late.
Rym: I realize me children are me only treasure.
Scott: Yeah, that Boscone is an old and powerful Galactic civilization that is much much more powerful than the Galactic Patrol.
Scott: who are the good guys?
Scott: now?
Scott: the story follows Kimball Kennison who is a guy who goes to the Galactic Patrol Academy and he eventually becomes a lensman which is the absolute ultimate Policeman of the Galactic Patrol you can possibly be.
Scott: and You know.
Scott: the very first chapter is where the guy says you know You can't fake being a lensman because you get this lens from these aliens or whatever and you'll find out all about that.
Scott: That would be a spoiler if I told you anymore.
Scott: So you have a. it's a lensman are guys who are perfect in every way.
Scott: They will not be corrupt.
Scott: Guaranteed.
Scott: you can trust them.
Scott: guaranteed you do what they say no matter what?
Scott: They will always make the best decision.
Scott: They're always awesome.
Scott: You know, they're better than all other people in every way.
Scott: They can act as judge jury and executioner and you can trust that that will be better than any other Judge jury and executioner that you can find guaranteed.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: and you know, there's no drama in the book.
Scott: Like where a lensman is gone bad.
Scott: No lensman.
Scott: Don't go bad Period.
Scott: they are good guys.
Scott: the end end of story You know.
Scott: and the because the in.
Scott: they explain like the selection process for lensman.
Scott: they weed out any possible bad guy.
Scott: You know, they're like amazing amazing dudes with the slightest fallibility.
Scott: Oh, sorry.
Scott: I can't be a lensman.
Scott: So yeah, you have this guy Kimball kindnessing as a brand new lensman and they send him on what's essentially a suicide mission.
Scott: You see I told you before that the they can't beat the aliens who are much much more powerful than they are.
Scott: well, they give him a Spaceship.
Scott: that is sort of crazy.
Scott: Like it has a very different combat strategy from the standard combat strategy But the chances of him actually succeeding in destroying or capturing an alien vessel and stealing alien technology is somewhat slim But it kind of puts him on the fast track.
Scott: It's like if you pull this off you're gonna go way up in the lensman, but if you don't you're dead.
Scott: So, of course being a lensman He goes off on this mission and I don't want to tell you the rest of the plot because there's no point in reading the Book.
Rym: Yeah, we're definitely not reviewing our things.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of giving them the once-over.
Scott: Yeah, and you know, I don't want to talk too long.
Scott: I'm gonna end this up pretty quick.
Scott: But the rest of the book is Kimball Kennison being awesome as he goes from thing to thing Doing the awesomest thing possible always pulling off the incredibly amazing thing.
Scott: and you know, the reason you want to keep reading is To find out.
Scott: All right, how the hell is he gonna do that?
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Well, how the hell is he gonna do?
Rym: Oh my god, I get the what's he gonna do next.
Rym: holy crap See, I didn't read it at all yet But I get the impression that it'll feel a lot like the Horatio books in me.
Scott: That's the impression that I get not having actually read a Horatio book.
Rym: Yeah, I've read all of them.
Rym: I've read almost everything CS foresters written.
Scott: Mm-hmm It even has the the guy who's sort of it, you know Haines who's sort of like the the boss But he's not really the boss, but you'll that's doesn't matter.
Scott: It's sort of like tell you you know, you always.
Scott: He always takes care of Kimball, you know, he gives him what he needs.
Scott: He tells him what he needs to be told etcetera, etcetera.
Scott: It's way cool.
Scott: Yeah way cool.
Scott: I'll be reading it soon and then I can see why all those people were inspired to like make lensman anime and lensman Comic books.
Rym: if only they hadn't been if only they died.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I'm not gonna talk about the lensman anime, but good fucking God.
Scott: Yeah, so yeah lensman book is definitely, you know The books.
Scott: make sure you go to Wikipedia before you read them to find out the correct reading order.
Scott: Yes, if you look at the books themselves if you can find them, they're pretty cheap and use bookstores They will tell you to read them.
Scott: They'll tell you to first read triplanetary and then read first lensman and then read galactic patrol.
Scott: That's sort of not correct.
Scott: See Triplanetary and first lensman were prequels that were made and published later.
Scott: So that's sort of like you get spoilers.
Rym: if you read those first It's like I think you get a lot more out of Star Wars watching four five six one two three then watching one two three four five six Exactly, or even Horatio.
Rym: the order they were written and the order you're supposed to read them is way out of chronological order Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, the lensman books are numbered for you to read them in chronological story order But really you should read them in Publication order which is galactic patrol gray lensman.
Scott: I forget but Wikipedia has it listed.
Scott: Go to Wikipedia for lensman and read it and make sure you read the books in the right order.
Rym: Yep So as I've mentioned a bunch of times I was reading the difference engine by William Gibson.
Rym: Yeah, and oh god, I forget the other author's name or the book handy, but it's co-written by him and someone else.
Scott: Oh, I'll look it up.
Rym: Yeah, but It's hard science fiction, but you know, there are basically two ways to tell hard science fiction.
Rym: There are the stories that like have the omniscient narrator and they're like there was this civilization and then this happened.
Rym: or you know follow the broad strokes of the leaders of these countries of the leaders of these civilizations and you know Very epic wide scale wide lens.
Rym: and then there's the science fiction where you set up the world the science fiction world You want to explore.
Rym: and then you explore it by following a character or a few characters through that world on a semi Unrelated plot Bruce Sterling.
Rym: Yeah, Bruce Sterling.
Rym: There you go author of a holy fire I believe but it you have a plot that isn't like the plot itself in.
Rym: the difference engine is kind of me.
Rym: It's just this kind of you know Skullduggery and adventure.
Rym: it follows one character for a while Then it kills.
Rym: that storyline follows a different character for a while kills.
Rym: that storyline follows a third character until it ends.
Rym: But that's really beside the point.
Rym: the book itself really explores an interesting idea now Babbage and numerous other people throughout history had come up with Mechanical means of doing what computers today do just on a much slower massive scale.
Rym: But they came up with you know difference engines machines that could calculate add and subtract multiply and divide.
Rym: There were just were never really the resources to build any of these machines.
Rym: and Even if they had been built the theory behind building them, they would have been very difficult.
Rym: It would have been very engineering intensive.
Rym: It's still not known if it would be even possible to make an engine large enough to do anything useful Yet still able to function.
Rym: but regardless of all that the idea here is what if Babbage had gotten the funding and the money he needed to build a difference engine?
Rym: And what if it had worked?
Rym: and what if the information revolution had happened during the Industrial Revolution?
Rym: instead of you know in the 1960s 70s 80s 90s and it's really just a fascinating look at how Vastly different and yet in a lot of ways how the same history would have been.
Rym: I mean it puts forth a lot of the ideas that if these things existed They were so massive and would have taken so many resources that Only the old world powers like Britain and France and Japan and China could have possibly built them Which means that all of these nations would have remained powerful through the Industrial Revolution and beyond Instead of what we saw happening where new upstart countries that didn't have a lot of knowledge and technology But had a lot of resources and people eventually overshadowed them.
Rym: I mean, it's it's set in a world where the Civil War kind of ended in a truce and For Britain and France and all these countries because they had the technology and the information really worked to make sure countries like America and Germany never unified and never became threats.
Rym: and it really goes into a lot of theory of computation Turing machines and it goes a lot into how different our history would be if meritocracy and science were lauded as opposed to religion and emotionalism and reactionism and all those sorts of things.
Rym: I mean they.
Rym: it gets to the point where they talk about how the noble classes were kind of abolished and people were given nobility based on their achievements and they weren't hereditary and little asides.
Rym: a whole bunch of little things where they'll mention you know, like remember the potato famine in Ireland and how Britain and France shipped all those tinned foods over made by machines and save the day Little things like that.
Rym: It's a really fascinating read.
Rym: I blew through it.
Rym: It was just.
Rym: I loved it.
Rym: I've been very vague on a lot of the details of the book mostly because like Scott I don't want to ruin it for anyone because there are Quite a number of twists and the story itself is pulpy like very pulpy But it's very fun.
Rym: and in addition to that the fun story really guides you through this world and really shows you all of the Amazing things that humans could have accomplished if we'd had the information revolution sooner.
Rym: and it also really paints a semi optimistic picture of Now that we're in full swing and the information revolution has been happening for so long.
Rym: Just the heights we can take it to now that I mean the machines we've got are billions and billions of times more powerful than what is posited in this book.
Rym: and Yet look at what people could have done with machines at even that week.
Scott: and that Unpowerful It's only powerful.
Rym: Yeah I'm running out of English here because I'm really trying to not ruin anything about this book because I really recommend anyone who enjoys science fiction or computing or Victorian pulp crap action.
Rym: all of these are in this book and it's very much worth reading.
Scott: Yeah, lens min is pretty much like the same thing.
Scott: just you know It constantly just gets bigger and bigger and crazier and crazier.
Scott: just a guy flying around in space You know pulling off amazing things to fight against the evil space pirates.
Rym: I noticed they both definitely have this idea of meritocracy.
Rym: I mean the lens min are infallible.
Rym: you take the people who are awesome and you put them in charge.
Scott: Well, the lens min aren't really like governing it's sort of but you put them in like people.
Rym: you see a lens min You go I'll listen to that guy.
Scott: Yeah, it seems to me like the in lens min The.
Scott: it's pretty obvious that the Galactic Patrol the good Civilization there is never any in fighting in the Galactic Patrol.
Scott: everyone in the Galactic Patrol Even if they're not lens min awesome, they're good.
Scott: They never do anything bad.
Scott: They don't turn coat They they always do their job really really well.
Scott: They're all awesome Good guys all working on the same team and united hurrah.
Scott: and the bad guys are the ones that have in fighting and all sorts of other stuff, but you know, it's just so many Things that you see today, you know in all sorts of entertainment, you know If there's a team of good guys, even if it's just two good guys, there's always conflict within between everything.
Scott: they always set up a conflict between every possible character imaginable and it's just really enjoyable to see like this giant team of awesome Perfectly marching forward towards goodness without anything wrong with them.
Scott: Just doing the greatest.
Rym: yeah, the most of the conflict in the difference engine is generally very silly and over-the-top and well over the top in a Subdued way.
Rym: It's really hard to explain but it's kind of Oh Tally Ho.
Rym: Let's go off on the adventure and aha We won't die.
Rym: We're the main characters.
Scott: Yeah, the the conflict in lens min is actually while it's sort of fantastic in its Spaceness, you know with aliens and lasers and spaceships and shit But it's not really like Tally Ho.
Rym: it's like, oh, yeah See the real conflict in difference engine is much more subtle and not we're comparing two books.
Scott: They've done to do with each other.
Rym: Yes apples and oranges for the win but the conflict the real conflict which is very subtle and kind of you figure out going on that it's really Luddites and reactionaries versus science and technology religion versus technology Idiots versus not idiots.
Rym: I mean the one of the major pivotal points is that the communists have a Very very big advantage in a world like this because information is so much more free and available that it's much more easy for communists and socialist sympathizers to mobilize especially back in the turn of the century in the Industrial Revolution when There was a lot of communist sympathy and a lot of people especially for the working conditions at the time Really probably would have joined any communist revolution if they'd known that one existed.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot to the difference engine and actually my favorite part of the whole thing is there are the equiv the not the Industrial Revolution equivalent of data centers.
Rym: and it's just.
Rym: it's really funny because there's the guys sitting in there and they talk about.
Rym: It goes into kind of great detail about all the steam and the tubes and the and the little widgets and pipes and the people wearing the.
Rym: you know they don't let people smoke in there anymore because they realize the smoke in the air interfered with the gears.
Rym: and It's just really really cool.
Rym: Like they talk about gear yards like my computer has 100 gear yards and there's a funny scene where one guy who thought he knew about computers was like Yeah, how many gear yards you have here at you know?
Rym: He's at like the government center for computing and the government center guy says gear yards.
Rym: We measure them in gear miles now boy There's a lot of little bits like that.
Scott: It's a pretty good one.
Rym: Yeah, I liked it a lot.
Scott: Yeah, so but what does difference engine say about Hitler?
Scott: God went alert.
Rym: Why don't we just play the monkey Tuesday theme Hitler?
Rym: Don't even start with it All Right in the spirit of keeping our episodes somewhat under control.
Rym: I think we'll stop now.
Rym: As for the semi new show format my last little bit here any thoughts any feedback?
Rym: What do you think you really want?
Rym: the two news's for us to yell about?
Rym: Do you want to keep the GeekNights or the geek back?
Scott: Yeah, you know we're pretty much doing as we please With our show format, but the show isn't for us.
Scott: It's for whoever you are listening.
Scott: So however you want our format to be you need to tell us by email or forum.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if all of you say you want.
Rym: I don't know all yaoi all the time Then GeekNights is over.
Rym: Thank you And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com, and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.