Rym: It's Monday August 14th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight after an almost two-week hiatus.
Rym: We bring you our live podcasting panel from Otakon.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well after almost two weeks of hiatus GeekNights is back.
Rym: Beware we live we hunger Run coward run run run see.
Rym: I thought about putting the actual wav files in but that was so much more fun.
Rym: Yeah, I guess you can put them in near the end of the episode for funnies or randomly throughout.
Rym: ooh also funnies But anyway for anyone who isn't aware Meaning mostly people who may be new listeners since we seem to have a lot of you.
Rym: We were at Otakon and Wildwood and Atlantic City and Beacon for the last two weeks pretty much collecting content for podcasting.
Rym: We have enough content to do the next three weeks handily.
Rym: at this point I'd say we have enough content to the next three months.
Rym: Now instead of doing one or two massive massive episodes are going really long all week.
Rym: The
Rym: plan is that we are just going to use all of these stories from Otakon and the week of awesome Throughout the next several weeks as we
Rym: see fit
Rym: Which means you are in store for many many entertaining episodes of GeekNights instead of one incredibly stupid long one
Rym: Now for all of you who are looking for our Otakon coverage or all of that business We are going to have our main Otakon con report this Wednesday on anime manga comics day.
Rym: Tomorrow we're gonna talk about just the gaming that
Scott: we did over the past two weeks
Rym: I think right
Rym: which was mostly the gaming room at the con that we did check out and play a bunch of games in and Then playing DDR for pretty much three days non-stop in Wildwood.
Rym: We also played some D&D for a bit.
Rym: sure we did a bit, but we fell asleep.
Rym: It's right about halfway through the one shot.
Rym: yeah right after we fought and failed to kill that dragon.
Rym: good job.
Rym: Thursday We will reveal the new motto of the front row crew.
Rym: yes We will have to give mad props to the two people who are somewhat together responsible for the new motto the front row crew.
Rym: But suffice to say we enacted the motto to its fullest.
Rym: we have done not one not one, but two Um Dumb things that are going to be all over the internet.
Rym: I guarantee it.
Rym: Hopefully we can use the Incredible internet popularity of the dumb things we have done to bring in new listeners.
Rym: I mean honestly we did these things.
Rym: just they're the kind of things we would do anyway.
Rym: We found them hilarious, but then afterward we realized that they're exactly the things we always see on Boing.
Rym: Boing Yeah I mean the other day I was going around the internet, and I saw a link to a blog story about leet license plates.
Rym: hello I have a leet license plate.
Rym: you have the most basic leet license And why wasn't I on there?
Rym: what the hell you're also in one of the most populous states.
Rym: Yeah, the fact that no one got that before you I guess.
Rym: oh well I was neglected.
Rym: But we will generate two awesomes to counteract my lack of leet license plate.
Rym: knowing Now if you notice that I particularly sound a lot different than usual one We completely lost our voices at Otakon as in Scott, and I could not talk at all.
Rym: Now you're going today.
Rym: what we have for you is actually a recording of our Otakon panel Which was Sunday morning.
Rym: now we lost our voices sometime around the middle of Saturday.
Rym: Yes We drugged ourselves with the halls and menthol in order to actually do the show and it was painful as in the moment the panel Was over I couldn't talk at all anymore.
Rym: Yes, so thanks to the halls of medicine We did our panel and thus destroyed our throats and vocal cords Which is part of the reason why the panel is going to sound bad now?
Rym: Additionally we'll talk about the rest of the problems with the panel recording when we actually play it.
Rym: yeah Yeah, additionally you might notice that I sound different because my pop filter Which I brought to Otakon to show to all of the other podcasts is nice homemade Embroidery loop.
Rym: yes the one that was featured on the creative mom podcast the same.
Rym: it has been lost somewhere.
Rym: Therefore I'm currently angling the microphone oddly in order to minimize the popping that I normally make.
Rym: Good job.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm gonna have to stop somewhere and buy a new pop filter sometime soon.
Rym: Yeah, we'll probably buy those new microphones that the audio guy at Otakon told us to get and then we'll buy pop filters for them Yes, or buy more embroidery loops.
Rym: also the fact that the audio guy at Otakon laughed at our mixer.
Rym: We're going to upgrade the mixer.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, especially since there's nothing really wrong with the mixer itself except It doesn't have enough holes.
Rym: we used all of them at Otakon.
Rym: yep in fact We recorded a whole bunch of awesome interviews that are going to be played all week.
Rym: We also survived an assassination attempt Which will be.
Rym: we actually have audio of that which will be played at some point in the next two weeks.
Rym: Yeah, probably a week from Wednesday.
Rym: I'm guessing Fucking clown pistols.
Rym: Oh my god All right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway to not go too on about all of our crazy stuff.
Rym: That'll come during the week.
Rym: We have the news as usual.
Rym: Wow, there was a lot of news in the past two weeks that we didn't talk about at all.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I didn't even bother to go back on dig to see every news story of the past two weeks.
Rym: Yeah, I basically just picked out the one that kind of stood out in my head.
Rym: and yeah This is.
Rym: this is the time when podcasts like twit come in handy, you know, cuz they're weekly They just summarize the whole week.
Rym: So listening to two twits today I was completely caught up even though that's what all of you seem to want us to turn GeekNights into.
Rym: yeah It's like what.
Rym: if you want to listen to it, seriously, just listen it to it.
Rym: I do note that most of the people who suggest that said that they like us more than they like to it.
Rym: Some of the people yeah, but how come twit has a whole jillion listeners and we don't ah, we'll get on that.
Rym: Yeah, all right.
Rym: So mine's real simple because I don't think I need to do much commentary on this.
Rym: This is pretty Obvious now self-explanatory.
Rym: Sony Kinda sucks and blu-ray has pretty much been a train wreck from the start.
Rym: now recently the blu-ray drives the first of the blu-ray drives have come out and Alright cool.
Rym: It came to the attention of the internet that these drives cannot actually play commercially released blu-ray discs due to problems with the copyright and DRM stuff and as well due to problems with the software and The fact that HDCP does not really work on computers.
Rym: yet.
Rym: Basically the way it is you buy a blu-ray drive for your computer because you want to burn blu-ray discs play Blu-ray movies on your computer something whatever you want to do store data on them because they're marginally larger.
Rym: Maybe you have a blu-ray disc and you want to play.
Rym: you want to get data off of it.
Rym: It's a data blu-ray disc and put it on your computer except no one has those.
Rym: yet The only blu-ray discs are commercially released movies that don't work.
Rym: on the only drives that exist right now.
Rym: The drive can play the movies But what it does is it requires that you have this DRM called HDCP which is high definition content protection in your video card and I think even in your monitor, right?
Rym: Yes now to the best of my knowledge unless something's changed or I haven't googled around too closely There don't appear to be any video cards that have HDCP support.
Rym: There were many that said they had HDCP support over HDCP ready, but none of them actually were.
Rym: Yeah, so if you want a blu-ray drive don't buy one they don't work.
Rym: Well, you can buy one as long as you know that in the future You're going to have to buy a new video card that has this DRM in it and a new monitor that has this DRM in it.
Rym: If that even comes to pass or if they don't change HDCP or if they don't just completely redo the format or all the other possible problems.
Rym: Yeah it's like you need to have a video card that has DRM a monitor that has DRM a special cable and then This blu-ray drive and some of those things exist and some of those things don't or at least they're not all commercially available.
Rym: therefore it Effectively the D hit the blu-ray drive for your computer cannot play blu-ray movies.
Rym: So I hate to be the Deadpool dead horse, and I'm not gonna go.
Rym: I'm really not gonna talk about blu-ray again because there's.
Rym: It's kind of like Jack Thompson.
Rym: Yeah, I only talk about blu-ray or Jack Thompson if they top themselves somehow.
Rym: And so a lot of Jack Thompson lately, but it's nothing out of the ordinary.
Rym: It's nothing new.
Rym: He's just been in the news more.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I mean he would have to pretty much kill a baby For me to talk about him, didn't he?
Rym: Yeah, but I I'm very much.
Rym: I'm pretty much 90% certain that blu-ray as a format is going to fail and That I was about 80% certain until this news came out.
Rym: So we'll see if anything can make that percentage ever go down again.
Rym: We'll see All right.
Rym: So also in the news What was my news again?
Rym: Good job.
Rym: Good.
Rym: You finally get back after two weeks.
Rym: I just reminded myself like two minutes ago of what it was.
Rym: Oh Right the RAA.
Rym: Oh they exist.
Rym: Yeah, they're still around doing stupid shit and they're suing people as always.
Rym: So they sued this guy and while they were suing this guy he died.
Rym: He suddenly died of an aneurysm.
Rym: Yep, so they said ah shit How are we gonna sue a dead man?
Rym: You know what they're going to sue a dead man.
Rym: They're continuing with the lawsuit and they're forcing the family He bereaved family including the man's children to submit deposition so that they can that they can then prosecute and then Extract money from his estate.
Rym: Yep, so they basically said alright the guy died.
Rym: We'll give you 60 days to mourn on the 61st day.
Rym: We want you to come in and give deposition so that we can take his money.
Rym: um, I don't know what to say to that.
Rym: that's That's the worst PR move in the world.
Rym: I mean they've already sued old ladies young kids single moms College students and now they're suing a dead man and they're making his children testify against it.
Rym: Well, I mean think about this.
Rym: Let's say you had a legitimate lawsuit against someone like a really legitimate one.
Rym: say, I don't know What's something you would see.
Rym: you stole a million dollars from me straight up by violating a contract and then you died.
Rym: There you go.
Rym: I should be able to get that money back.
Rym: You should but sometimes, you know, if it's not a big deal Even though you have a legitimate case, you'll let it go because the guy died.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the RIAA obviously is not suing people to get money.
Rym: getting money is just a byproduct.
Rym: They're suing people in order to scare people into not downloading things which isn't working at all - they've never actually won a lawsuit.
Rym: They just get people to settle and everyone who's ever fought them has won.
Rym: and Three they're not going to scare any more people by continuing to sue this dead daddy.
Rym: All they're going to do is piss more people off.
Rym: all I can hope is that because of the attention brought to this case of Where the guy died that some of those lawyers who won cases for other people will go help.
Rym: these people Prevent the RIAA from taking money from the estate.
Rym: Because I'm thinking what the RIAA is thinking is that hey look there's an estate and no one to defend it.
Rym: Maybe we can loot it and they won't feel bad because they're looting a dead man who isn't there to care.
Rym: I don't think they're thinking that at all.
Rym: I think very simply they'll just sue anyone They have a case against I don't know and then if the person fights back They'll probably just immediately drop the suit as they tend to do Whatever.
Rym: They're evil.
Rym: They're more evil every day.
Rym: They haven't let up, you know.
Rym: Wow, so the news today was Sony is incompetent and the RIAA is evil.
Rym: Seems like nothing much changed while we were away for two weeks.
Rym: Fantastic.
Rym: Things of the past two weeks.
Rym: Things of the day Alright for all of our new listeners.
Rym: We're not gonna annoy all of our current listeners as we have in the past when we get a bunch of new listeners by explaining The entire show every day for an entire week, but I think it warrants explanation that what we're about to do is something we do.
Rym: it's a bit on every show where we Show you and then talk about whatever thing we found on the internet in the last 24 hours.
Rym: That was awesome enough to share with anyone on the internet.
Rym: It's probably something you've already seen.
Rym: if you're the type of person who reads lots of websites like dig and slash
Rym: Many of our listeners do not do these things and they're often new and sometimes our listeners send us things that we have not seen
Rym: Very rarely
Rym: maybe once or twice ever though actually
Rym: over
Rym: the week of awesome Which actually we'll talk about in great detail on Thursday because that's where all the hijinks took place Our friend showed us a good number of things that we had missed over the course of the internet that we are now going to Share.
Rym: yep, and you know sometimes, you know I think the real point of the thing of the day is that We're gonna tell you about cool things on the internet that you'll probably find out about in a couple weeks.
Rym: But since you find out about them now you kind of keep pace with us a little bit plus You know you get all of our witty commentary.
Rym: Yeah, it's really all about the witty commentary.
Rym: So this video I forget who exactly showed it to us.
Rym: It was either Jess or Yuko, I believe I don't actually remember because I walked into the room and it was playing.
Rym: it's called dad's home And it is this cute awesome animation kind of reminds me of the Perry Bible Fellowship.
Rym: yeah, and it's just a father comes home and Goes on a destructive rampage, and then he saves the day by rocking out hard.
Rym: I can't describe it any other way other than that.
Rym: It is exactly my kind of humor.
Rym: Wow that was some witty commentary.
Rym: It's so worth listening to this show Because they couldn't figure that out just by watching it.
Rym: well the thing is it's it's that humor That's kind of offbeat and hard to follow like the guy's head catches on fire randomly and then self referentially and then he gets isolated laser eyes for no reason.
Rym: So one if you're a fan of the Perry Bible Fellowship watch this video.
Rym: If you're not a fan of Perry Bible Fellowship go read it.
Rym: if you like this video go read the Perry Bible Fellowship.
Rym: Go read the Perry Bible Fellowship No matter what if you can read the English language even if you can't read the English language.
Rym: Though on a completely side note that I'll talk about again whenever we do playback the our webcomic roundtable that we did at Otakon I might have added a new webcomic to my list of webcomics.
Rym: Oh Yeah, cuz I've known.
Rym: you know I've met Michael Mookie.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: actually I'd never known his last name until just now when I'm looking at the book in front of me, but Dominic Deegan Oracle for Hire I'd never read.
Rym: I just kind of knew the guy who wrote it.
Rym: as in I ran into my cons all the time And you go gave me the book of the first I guess season of his webcomic, and I think for the first time since dr.
Rym: McNinja.
Rym: I'm going to read a new webcomic.
Rym: Only thought of that because of Perry Bible Fellowship.
Rym: I think it's a good enough time to say mad props to the dr.
Rym: McNinja cosplayer at Otakon.
Rym: Oh, yes I think I was the only one who recognized his costume because I walked out to him like are you dr.
Rym: McNinja, and he was like oh, yeah, and we shook hands, and he was all good time.
Rym: He reacted exactly the way he should have.
Rym: there was a picture of him in my flicker So you go check that out.
Rym: definitely good in fact.
Rym: go check out the flicker And you might be able to surmise Some of the things that have gone on that we were going to be talking about over the next two weeks.
Rym: You'll probably be able to surmise more from our friends flickers than from ours because I don't take very many pictures.
Rym: Yeah though all of you who are savvy to the forums will probably easily find the other flicker that has the pictures of us doing the Dumb things we did last week.
Rym: Yeah, the things we will talk about Thursday All right my thing of the day is I'm sure everyone has seen this by now because it's at the top of YouTube.
Rym: It's an old man on YouTube like a 79 year old man, and he's from Britain Which is awesome because that means he talks in a cool way.
Rym: is he actually 79 Or did you?
Rym: he really is like 79 years old.
Rym: you keep saying like is he or is he not 79 79 years old, okay?
Rym: And because you said like 79 lies in he's like 80 or he's like 90, but the fact that you used 79 specifically 79 years old okay I think what the deal was is YouTube profile says 78, but in one of the videos He says 79. so he must have joined YouTube before his birthday.
Rym: damn you internet.
Rym: Yeah Anyway this old guy apparently he used to be a biker but not he doesn't have tattoos or anything and he used to be pretty hardcore.
Rym: and now he's an old man in Britain and he likes blues music which is awesome because I like blues music and he likes YouTube and he's one of the few old people who actually knows enough to Go on YouTube and look at stuff, and he thinks it's really cool that all the cool videos that young people are making.
Rym: So he decided that he would try to make a YouTube video and he pretty much set up a webcam and he played some blues music and He talked about being an old cranky guy And he figures he'll impart some of his old man wisdom onto the YouTube kids out there.
Rym: I have so much respect for this man, and he succeeds in becoming the most popular thing on YouTube.
Rym: I mean 79. think about how old that is.
Rym: think about how different the world was when he was a punk kid and Now he's managed to get on YouTube and become stupid pop.
Rym: I mean, I know a lot of people my age who couldn't get on YouTube.
Scott: yep
Rym: So I've linked you to his first video Which is called first try and there's a lot of comments and a lot of there even videos people have put up in response To this video, but he also if you go to the guy's YouTube page Which I can't seem to find because I don't know how to use YouTube There is you can see all the videos.
Rym: He's made.
Rym: He's got like episodes going on.
Rym: It's sort of like a. It's more like a vlog.
Rym: you know a vlog.
Rym: I like that.
Rym: It's a vlog.
Rym: That's a terrible word that should never be you I know, but that's the most accurate word for what this old man is making.
Rym: you know what you're allowed to say vlog because I've Said blog o sphere more than once
Rym: all right,
Rym: and I said pot is fear once -
Scott: yeah
Rym: I normally wouldn't say vlog for something like ask a ninja or whatever But this is a vlog an awesome old man vlog that is deservedly at the top of YouTube.
Rym: All right now before we go into the podcasting panel at Otakon first off a bunch of meta bits.
Rym: Stay tuned once again all this week for all of our Otakon and Wildwood and Atlantic City coverage.
Rym: We have so many funny stories to tell.
Rym: you have no idea Not a single idea.
Rym: unless you were with us, then you already know all these stories.
Rym: We did some dangerous things.
Rym: we gambled and won a decent sum of money.
Rym: Don't give it away.
Rym: Yeah, that wasn't giving anything away.
Rym: I was giving something away.
Rym: It was giving a tiny bit away.
Rym: someone ate something Not someone else.
Rym: the kind of stuff you got to give away.
Rym: someone had something made.
Rym: People bought things.
Rym: yes people bought things.
Rym: indeed People did not buy things.
Rym: um some things that were bought involved eyeballs and robots.
Rym: People engaged in activities and said things which were humorous.
Rym: There is a thing that exists.
Rym: it is called a clown pistol, and it is weighed heavily on my mind all right, okay?
Rym: Now the panel.
Rym: we were asked to do a poll actually we asked to do and then Otakon said this is a great idea.
Rym: Please do it a panel on podcasting as in how to listen to podcast what they are how to do them And all that sort of thing at Otakon this year,
Rym: and it was scheduled for Sunday morning, which means Everyone is checking out at their hotels and isn't going to come to your panel.
Rym: But regardless of that like a good number of people showed up.
Rym: Yeah, it was also Interestingly enough scheduled.
Rym: I mean there are four panel rooms at Otakon this year two of which are the standard panel rooms one of which is like the tiny panel room.
Rym: they give to unpopular things and They put us in the panel room.
Rym: that was pretty much massive.
Rym: I would use the word ginormous.
Rym: Yes this year They've destroyed main events They what used to be main events which is this tremendous ballroom on the top floor of the Convention Center.
Rym: They removed that entirely because the only reason they had main events was for the cosplay and they didn't really Anything else they used it for did not use even half the space of main events now.
Rym: This may not happen next year.
Rym: Yeah, we don't know.
Rym: next year.
Rym: We will have much to say about.
Rym: Yes And on Wednesday we give our general con report.
Rym: so because they move main events to the arena down the street They split.
Rym: they split up.
Rym: They moved the cosplay to the arena down the street.
Rym: Main events was split up and they cut it in half and one half of it was theater is now theater one Which is a showing theater for movies and stuff.
Rym: The other half was split in half yet again.
Rym: One of those quarters I think was a video room.
Rym: Yeah, it was like video seven or something or video six I don't remember.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: but the other quarter so a former quarter of main events became panel four.
Rym: Now us.
Rym: there was a massive sound system in there to the point.
Rym: now some of its cut out But you can still hear the echo.
Rym: We were on stage with the microphones and it was so loud and echoey that it sounded fine in the place for the audience.
Rym: But because we were on stage we could not actually hear what anyone in the audience was saying to us.
Rym: Yep, so eventually at some point in the podcast we get off the stage and then we can hear people.
Rym: Yes, now there is a feedback.
Rym: at one point I forget who walked in front of the speaker, but he walked in front of the speaker.
Rym: whoever they are They are a fan boy or girl.
Rym: if I listen to it.
Rym: I could probably figure out who it was.
Rym: I don't remember now.
Rym: The other part of this is that the audio equipment was very expensive and fancy.
Rym: It was also old and broken.
Rym: So as a result the raw recording of the panel, which sounded really good Otherwise because they used really good microphones and everything was top-notch has this.
Rym: Yeah, basically what happened is there was already existing awesome audio equipment in the panel more than we will ever need for GeekNights and we asked the guy the audio engineer in charge of the room if we could have a cable that would you know we could plug into our Mac and our mixer and record from it and he did.
Rym: he gave us a cable but the cable went And there's really nothing to do about it and it was pretty low and it was pretty consistent.
Rym: So whatever we decided to record anyway.
Rym: Now the choices in terms of playing this panel back for you were either one leave that noise in which was not what you want.
Rym: No, I tried to listen to it with that noise and it is painful wicked painful.
Rym: Now the other option was to do a simple noise gate wherein I cut out these Whenever no one's talking, but that means that you hear it whenever we talk and it made me sound weird Not good.
Rym: the third option which we went with was to basically use the audacity noise reduction thing because while I could have done It manually Scott did not want to sit there for an hour or more while I did it.
Rym: Yep plus I've never done that on such a terrible source of noise before and I removed all of the frequencies that the Was on.
Rym: as a result, we sound slightly like robots and we're slightly echoey.
Rym: Well, the echoes were there.
Rym: I know it's doubly echoey.
Rym: Yes, and so it's it sounds a lot better than some podcasts.
Rym: I've listened to it.
Rym: So you can't complain to me about this.
Rym: Yes, your only other option besides a slightly robotic sounding Podcasting panel was to have no Podcasting panel and we would now be talking about something else unprepared.
Rym: now as a result We are going to have next week on Monday a discussion on the difficulties of doing live shows as opposed to recorded shows in our studio.
Rym: There's a big difference between performing live and not performing live And there's also a big difference between performing live with your own equipment and performing live with other people's equipment.
Rym: Also, there's a big difference between being well-rested and being hungover with a sore throat a broken voice and a bloodshot eye Two bloodshot eyes here.
Rym: Yeah, but no hangover.
Rym: So I'll warn you now we sound weird because our voices are completely gone and we've taken drugs in order to be able to speak.
Rym: We are so tired and broken because we had to get up at 6 in the morning to prepare for this and to get out Of our hotel room.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We had slept exactly 3.5 hours in the 48 hours prior to this panel.
Rym: Yeah Yes now as it despite all that I think it was a pretty good panel.
Rym: It was definitely not our best work.
Rym: I was much happier with the podcasting panel.
Rym: We did at Tora con last year.
Rym: Mm-hmm Yeah, that was definitely.
Rym: it was more fun at least.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, this is fun But I think if they had given us a better time like maybe like Friday late later Friday or earlier Saturday Also, if I hadn't been hungover that would have really helped.
Rym: Yeah Then we could have had more people in there and then it would more exciting.
Rym: now also the one thing that would be nice Is I think instead of doing an informative panel, even though everyone seemed to really like I mean We got a lot of really good questions and a lot of people tried to bother us after the show to ask us more questions Which?
Rym: because at that point we couldn't talk anymore.
Rym: We were unable to answer all of your questions.
Rym: if you have questions Send us email send us an audio Audio also.
Rym: Yeah, Odeo is awesome But I think next year we're going to try to do a more less informative more fun panel as in Rym and Scott talk about something unrelated to podcasting loudly for an hour on Friday night.
Rym: Ah Something possibly making fun of hentai And I don't want to do one of those.
Rym: not as in we watch hentai and make fun of it But we get people to come and we make fun of them for liking hentai.
Rym: Mmm, I can think of something better than that.
Rym: It's given a given a year.
Rym: I'm guaranteed to come up with something non anti-relate.
Rym: It's got to be something that'll fit into the over 18 late-night crowd at Otakon as opposed to the hungover Sunday morning crowd.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And Also the final bit before we play this the other things that we recorded Otakon are a whole bunch of interviews that we're going to Play all throughout the week whenever they're relevant.
Rym: We did a webcomics roundtable with a whole bunch of webcomic artists and it turned out really well.
Rym: all I have to do is do stuff to it and then we'll play it probably next week.
Rym: and We recorded a short roundtable with the folks at anime world order and the folks at ninja consultant and who else was there?
Rym: Fast karate for the gentle.
Rym: Yes, we will be playing that probably next Wednesday.
Rym: Yes, if you visit all of those podcasts the anime world order the ninja consultant and the fast karate for the gentleman Those are like the primary podcasters.
Rym: We were down with at the con so their latest Episodes have stuff possibly relating to us that you might be interested in.
Rym: Yes, and during the next week We will have stuff related to all of them Mm-hmm.
Rym: So thus without further ado and once again, I apologize This is as good as I could make this sound the Monday after the week of awesome the podcasting and internet radio panel from Otakon 2006.
Scott: whoo.
Rym: Well, we've got a stellar crowd here.
Rym: So I suppose we will just begin.
Rym: My name is Rym, I'm Scott and we are the hosts of GeekNights the late-night podcast for geeks.
Rym: now This is a panel not about GeekNights our podcast.
Rym: what about Podcasting in general?
Rym: how to listen if anyone's interested how to make a podcast What this whole thing's about and then we'll probably just descend in general chaos as the panel goes on.
Scott: So thank you all for coming.
Scott: I know it's not easy to wake up.
Scott: It's Sunday at 10 in the morning after Yeah after a raucous Saturday night, so thank you.
Rym: All right, so how many of you listen to podcasts?
Rym: All right, how many of you have never heard of a podcast?
Rym: you just wandered into this room whoo All right.
Rym: Do any of you actually do a podcast?
Rym: Really?
Rym: All right, we will do some shoutouts at the end to get you to pick your podcast since we got to represent here No to con.
Rym: But for all of you who have no idea about podcasting or how to listen We'd like to go through kind of what podcasting really is and the fact that you don't need an iPod to be a part of podcasting.
Scott: Well, technically a podcast is an RSS feed with enclosures pointing to multimedia coded files.
Scott: But what that means?
Rym: that means in English if you have an mp3 player and any kind of pod catching software.
Rym: There are millions of applications out there that all do it.
Rym: iTunes iTunes.
Rym: Pardon me is the one most people know.
Scott: There's a juice receiver.
Rym: you subscribe to a radio show online So you go to their website and subscribe and then every time they make a new episode.
Rym: It's automatically downloaded the next time you plug in your mp3 player.
Rym: It's automatically put on the mp3 player and then you listen to it.
Rym: It's like a radio show plus a TiVo on the internet.
Scott: Yeah, but you don't even need an mp3 player.
Scott: I mean most people just listen on their computers with whatever Windows Media Player iTunes or whatever music player they have, you know And you don't even need.
Scott: all you need is a computer and an internet connection.
Scott: if you listen to us with dial-up I don't know what's up with that.
Rym: people listen to us with dial-up in foreign countries.
Rym: I don't know how they manage that.
Scott: Yeah, and a podcast isn't necessarily just audio even though it's usually audio.
Scott: There are plenty of video podcasts out there and Yeah, we don't make those because they're very difficult and time-consuming and bandwidth intensive.
Rym: Yeah, though one of them.
Rym: I mean ask a ninja is a very popular video podcasts.
Rym: one person recognized.
Rym: ask a ninja All right.
Rym: I know it's Sunday morning.
Rym: wake up.
Rym: Give me a Leroy Jenkins.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I've never had such a stellar crowd before Mm-hmm.
Rym: I will take some questions in a minute But is anyone everyone kind of clear on how to like what podcasts are how to listen to them?
Rym: It's just internet radio At all.
Scott: Yeah, that's exactly what it uses.
Scott: In fact, it's not a podcast if it doesn't use real simple syndication, you know I'll repeat because he wanted to know if the subscribing to podcast is using RSS real simple really simple syndication, which yes that's the only way.
Scott: and Basically someone makes you know an RSS feed and in each item in the feed They put what's called an enclosure which is just a URL to an mp3 or a video file.
Scott: and then if you use a piece of software like iTunes or juice receiver or iPod or or any of those things it recognizes the enclosure and When there's a new item in the feed and the enclosures there it automatically will get the episode for you And you can listen to it whenever you want.
Rym: And also what a lot of people do is if they don't want to install anything on their computer or they don't have an mp3 player you can go to like Odeo or Yahoo podcasts and they have players or things built into the web browser Or you just go to a website and you can just stream the audio directly from there.
Scott: I mean half our listeners don't even use the RSS feed or you know any of the podcasting features at all.
Scott: They just visit our website four days a week Click on a link and download an mp3 and then play in their player without using anything fancy Though more than half of our listeners use Firefox.
Scott: Yeah, if you use Firefox, it's pretty easy.
Scott: You can subscribe to podcasts with the live bookmarks.
Scott: It works pretty well.
Rym: now Podcasting really I mean webcomics.
Rym: now webcomics started out kind of this obscure thing and then they kind of ballooned and then one day they Exploded and suddenly mega Tokyo and penny arcade and all this is just huge.
Rym: Podcasting hasn't quite reached that point yet.
Rym: There are probably more people reading a popular webcomic.
Rym: then listen to all the podcasts combined.
Scott: There's some crazy popular podcasts, but they're usually Associated with big media.
Scott: I mean you don't see big media going into the web comics industry so much.
Scott: But there are podcasts of like major league baseball official podcasts ABC NBC CBS NPR.
Scott: All have official podcasts, you know, and those have a whole mess of listeners.
Scott: But those people, you know, they're only listening usually to that specific thing.
Scott: They're not into the podcasting scene.
Rym: But among the non huge podcast the best thing I mean you're all here at an anime concert Obviously some stretch of either nerd or geek, which is awesome.
Rym: Those are not bad words anymore.
Rym: There are more geekly podcast I think than there are anything else out there.
Rym: I mean how many video game podcasts are there?
Scott: too many and none of them are good.
Scott: Yet generally what happened is because early in the podcasting days The only people who knew how to use RSS and all this stuff were geeks.
Scott: So the podcast that became the most popular and got the most attention early on were the podcast targeted towards the geek demographic podcasts like twit, I got it, you know, like a hajillion listeners and You know all the podcasts that are sort of there.
Scott: I mean there are crazy podcasts out there.
Scott: There's one that's like about Australian real estate market and stuff.
Scott: It gets kind of crazy.
Rym: But you think you just made up that weird example.
Rym: That's a big podcast.
Scott: It is a pretty happening.
Scott: this is a podcast about like financial aid for colleges, that's all they talk about like every week.
Scott: It's crazy.
Rym: And of course, I know the question burning on everyone's mind Are there anime podcasts?
Rym: and the answer is there's an infinite number of them.
Rym: I Actually, they're here and they're supposed to be at this panel with us.
Rym: We don't know where they went but anime world order.
Rym: You might have seen their flyers.
Rym: They're here.
Rym: Are they here?
Rym: I Didn't see them.
Rym: I still don't see.
Rym: Okay There's some work on.
Rym: they were in our room last night and despite their assassination attempt.
Rym: We were still here today.
Scott: That's right a clown.
Scott: We are immune to clown pistol.
Rym: Yeah I was shot in the face with a clown pistol after Daryl Surratt screamed six-center tyrannous last night.
Rym: Yeah, I Got a little bruise still.
Scott: Yeah, the anime podcast pretty much fall into two categories.
Scott: There's the ones that's one fanboy going.
Scott: Yeah, my favorite anime is this and it was so great and you don't listen to those worst anime ever.
Scott: and then there's like The three or four ones that are actually intelligent like ours.
Rym: Ours really goes beyond an anime podcast.
Rym: We're kind of well, we'll get it up.
Rym: you guys actually are you interested in how to like how we do this?
Rym: How people make podcast how this all works?
Rym: All right, I don't know if they picked it up but everyone yelled.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll get right into that.
Rym: We do a show called GeekNights.
Rym: now We do it four nights a week for about an hour every night, which is crazy by most people's standards.
Scott: I mean, they're like, how do you do it?
Scott: And we're like we sit down and talk for an hour every night.
Rym: See the thing is I mean, we're really not trying to diss anyone or anything.
Rym: But in terms of podcasting it seems like a lot of the podcast has started early on Or I'm people who really knew a lot about what they wanted to talk about Not so much about the audio or the tech or all that stuff.
Rym: so a lot of podcasts have a lot of good content, but they're hard to listen to either because of audio problems or Their website is difficult to use if the RSS feeds are broken.
Rym: a lot of good podcasts don't show up in iTunes Just because people don't know how to do all the stuff to make it show up in iTunes.
Scott: Yeah, there's some podcasts that I honestly want to listen to but they don't even have it a feed with enclosures.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: I would have to go to their website every once in a while to Maybe find a new episode if I'm lucky and it's just not worth the effort no matter how good their show is The effort of constantly checking a website all the time for a new episode.
Rym: Yeah, I mean some people listen to one or two podcasts.
Rym: Yeah, they'll just go to the website every day and download the episode But if the episode gets uploaded an hour later Then they'll miss it till the next day.
Rym: or if you listen to 20 podcasts and they update every day Why not just have it all automatic?
Rym: So if one podcast isn't automatic they really lose out on listenership just because a lot of like most people who listen to the podcasts They don't even know that you can listen to them outside of iTunes.
Rym: So it doesn't show up in iTunes as far as they're concerned.
Rym: It doesn't even exist.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty sad that you know it.
Scott: It was a big mistake when they came up with the word podcast It's like.
Scott: at first they thought all right That's the perfect word, and then they're like oh wait now We have to tell everyone a thousand times that you don't need an iPod You don't need iTunes.
Rym: and yeah, how many times when we tell someone one of our old friends?
Rym: Hey, we do a radio show now a podcast.
Rym: Oh, I don't have an iPod You don't need one.
Scott: if you can play an mp3 and download an mp3 you can listen to podcasts.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Yep now in terms of actually Recording or doing this it seems There's a lot of bad information out there on the internet.
Rym: if you just think like oh I'm gonna do a podcast and Google around or look at what other people have said they've done I hate to say it But most of the guides out there Really give terrible advice as to how to make your audio sound good or how to use the applications properly or actually This is kind of an aside, but the worst thing is that Apple seems to really push a lot of their solutions like buy a Mac.
Rym: It's really easy to podcast and We found by doing it four nights a week that Macs are really not a good solution for podcasting at all.
Rym: and GarageBand Which is really promoted as this podcasting tool.
Rym: if you go beyond the most amateur level in the world like if you try to go Anywhere beyond that it's pretty much unusable.
Rym: It just it doesn't have the functionality It doesn't have the features it has arbitrary limits in it Like you can't even record an episode as long as you want because it'll arbitrarily say oh that was too long.
Rym: I'm stopping you.
Scott: The worst thing about if you use GarageBand to make a podcast and you don't know what you're doing if you just follow the instructions That Apple gives you you will accidentally make a podcast that really does need an iPod or iTunes to listen to and that's really Really bad.
Scott: you're basically saying oh those millions of people with windows and whatever they can't listen to my show Screw them.
Scott: only Apple people can listen to my show which is not very good.
Rym: Yeah, one of our listeners wants asked us.
Rym: Why don't you do the Apple enhanced podcast?
Rym: I think it would be really cool.
Rym: We had to explain to him that that would alienate at least half of our listeners who don't have Apple don't have iPods And they still want to listen.
Scott: Yeah, also the.
Scott: if you could we could do some people put an enhanced podcast and a normal mp3 podcast up together But that doubles the amount of bandwidth and storage we need and it really really sucks.
Rym: Now what we use to actually record the show.
Rym: we'll take a whole bunch of questions in a little bit.
Rym: We've got a lovely assistant here Nury.
Rym: We'll be going around with a microphone at some point because we are recording this and it's all going to go up on our show After we get back from the Jersey Shore at some point.
Rym: But we've got a Linux box actually running Gentoo and on that we run a program called resound Which is if anyone has ever heard of it?
Scott: It's like an old program called cool edit Pro or cool edit 2000 Which yeah, if you can get cool edit Pro or cool edit 2000 Those are the ultimate wave editing programs ever created and you can make awesome podcasts with that.
Scott: But it's they don't make it anymore.
Scott: What happened was Adobe bought it and then they removed a bunch of good stuff from it and added a bunch of other Crap that you don't care about to it.
Scott: and they called it audition and they doubled the price.
Rym: So I mean cool edit really was the industry standard for a lot of radio stations like professional ones for the longest time.
Rym: But resound is an open source program that it mimics almost all the functionality of cool edit.
Rym: And it's actually got to the point now where there are many cases where it goes beyond what cool edit can even do in the first Place.
Scott: Yeah, but if you're loaded you can buy audition.
Scott: if you're poor you can install Linux and get resound for free.
Rym: Now what most people use who do podcasts actually is a program called audacity, which is also open source.
Rym: But you can run it on Windows Linux.
Rym: you can even run it on Macs if you want and it's really easy to use.
Rym: It's got.
Rym: basic functionality is there to where you could put a pretty good podcast with it even not knowing a lot about audio.
Scott: Yeah, but if you get really if you get more advanced audacity will eventually not have the features you're looking for and you know Some of the filters in it, you might want to do something different and it just doesn't have.
Scott: you know The controls that you want and you know, so if you keep it simple and audacity is probably all you're ever gonna need.
Scott: But if you want to do fancy stuff, you're gonna need something else like resound.
Rym: I mean really in terms of what you use to do a podcast you have to decide Are you doing this just for fun?
Rym: Do you really want to learn about how to do this the professional way?
Rym: How deeply do you want to get into this?
Rym: because the scale of money you can spend is from five bucks to?
Rym: Tens of thousands of dollars on fancy equipment like a certain podcast.
Rym: We know that still doesn't sound so good.
Scott: Yeah, I mean look at all this equipment those guys have over there.
Scott: if we had that stuff We could make some crazy freaking podcast.
Rym: The AV guy who sets up this room was actually laughing at our tiny little mixer we have here?
Scott: Yeah, instead we have like a hundred dollars worth of junk on the floor, which is more than most people have.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, we'll go through all the hardware in a minute and we try to show it to you But it's all plugged in but after the panel we can totally just show you like everything we've got.
Rym: now It's plugged in but in terms of actually doing the podcast and you know how deeply you want to get into it There's.
Rym: you have to learn a lot about audio and if you use like resound or audacity and you get Audio textbooks and you actually try to learn how to do it better as opposed to using an apple Which will make it sound pretty good to start, but you really can't go anywhere from there You'll learn a lot about audio.
Rym: You'll learn a lot of valuable skills that maybe you could use in a job someday.
Rym: I mean you can put audio engineer on your resume there.
Rym: You've already gained something from podcasting even if your podcast pod fades as they like to call it.
Scott: Yeah, and I mean even if you.
Scott: there's also this web hosting side of it.
Scott: You know, there's a lot of.
Scott: you need to manage blog software.
Scott: you need to manage the RSS feed You need to manage all those podcast directories.
Scott: So in addition to getting audio engineering skills, you're getting a lot of webmastering skills.
Scott: If you don't have the webmastering skills, your podcast isn't going to work.
Rym: Yeah, like most podcasters they either use something like libsyn which has a good service for doing podcasts or They'll use wordpress.com and then feed burner to run the feed.
Rym: We'll talk about all that stuff in detail, but we actually because we're technologists I mean, we're both computer professionals.
Rym: We have our own hosting as in we have our own Linux box in the sky that we run our own Everything on our own web server our own forums our own jabber server.
Scott: Yeah, it's a lot of fun to actually manage everything on the low level that way.
Scott: if something goes wrong I know it's my fault and I know I can fix it instead of having to wait for some guy Who might be on vacation to come and do something to some computer somewhere?
Rym: But at the same time it takes a lot more work.
Rym: I mean if you're just using like libsyn and libsyn goes down all you do is email libsyn and say hey my podcast disappeared WTF and maybe it'll come back up at some point.
Rym: we if it goes down.
Rym: we have to sit there and try to fix it.
Rym: But at the same time by dealing with all that you'll learn a lot and your podcast will get better and better and better.
Rym: it'll sound better it'll look more professional and You'll learn a lot.
Rym: What can I say?
Scott: Yeah, so if you actually want to make a podcast, you know, you get the software we just described to you.
Scott: You plug a microphone into the computer and you push record.
Scott: It's really that easy.
Rym: Microphones are a big source of confusion for a lot of people because most people you buy a computer.
Rym: It either has a microphone built into it or it comes with like that tiny little white stick microphone that comes with most sound cards.
Rym: You really me you really can't use that.
Rym: I mean it's cheap, but your podcast will sound terrible like if anyone listened to the first penny arcade podcast.
Rym: They basically use something like that sitting on one side of the room and it just it was almost unlistenable.
Rym: But that doesn't mean you have to spend a lot of money.
Rym: We have $20 RadioShack microphones and our broadcast sounds pretty good.
Rym: I think I could say yeah, I think we need to buy some of these things though We got to upgrade at this point.
Scott: Yeah, since we have this giant crowd here, obviously Please don't spend more money than your skill allows.
Scott: I mean a lot of people will you know, they get in, you know They get into something and then they buy fancy equipment like guys will get into golf and then they'll buy a fancy set of golf Clubs thinking it'll make them better at golf.
Scott: The same thing is true with podcasting.
Scott: a lot of people get into podcasting.
Scott: They spend thousands of dollars Like I get a fancy microphone at a big mixer and they don't know really how to use it.
Scott: that well So it doesn't help their audio quality that much.
Scott: We've done the opposite where we spend the minimum Possible and we use our knowledge to bring the quality up above a lot of the people who spend more money than we do.
Rym: Because really I mean podcasting is fun and great and you can just do it in your spare time.
Rym: But it will take a lot of time and a lot of effort at least initially as you Learn how to edit audio and you learn what sounds good and what doesn't.
Rym: I mean When we started doing the show it would take me about three hours after every episode to Do all the stuff to it to make it sound good to you guys, you know post-production editing out, you know Scott coughing or Scott burping or Scott dropping the microphone
Scott: Rym hacking up a loogie.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, or when we forget something or you forget what we're talking about or we forget the mics aren't actually on and we talk for An hour or you accidentally delete the whole episode.
Rym: that only happened two or three times.
Rym: Yeah okay, and As it goes on it's gotten to the point now where it takes us literally maybe two minutes worth of Editing to make the show ready to go yet.
Scott: What really takes the longest now is the actual computer processing.
Scott: I mean Rym's.
Scott: computer is a half on one gigahertz.
Scott: It takes you know, he clicks make mp3 and we wait ten minutes.
Scott: It's it's really kind of painful.
Rym: Hey, I built that computer for $4,000 in like 1999.
Rym: It's time to buy a new box Now.
Rym: I suppose I mean we could ramble on a lot about all the specific details of what we use for hosting what we use Equipment wise but I guess at this point we could send our lovely assistant.
Rym: And if you guys have specific questions since it's kind of a small crowd I guess we can really address all of you almost individual.
Rym: if you really want.
Scott: Yeah, we'll get all nice.
Rym: and yes, that was indeed your cue.
Rym: Oh lovely assistant This is Mary.
Rym: by the way, who does a podcast called artists alley?
Scott: Don't turn it on in front of the speakers or we'll all die.
Rym: Yes walk it Walk across then turn it on.
Rym: See it's amazing.
Rym: I do just doing this for so long.
Rym: You'll learn so much about how to deal with all this audio stuff or like how to hold a microphone properly.
Rym: We've Scott still kind of struggling with from time to time.
Scott: What can I say?
Scott: Hello You were mentioned.
Scott: you were talking earlier about Enhanced podcast Apple enhanced podcast.
Scott: What's the difference between an enhanced podcast?
Scott: I think okay our podcast is an mp3 file.
Scott: You can play it on anything that plays an mp3.
Scott: an enhanced podcast is an Apple.
Scott: It's a special Apple thing.
Scott: That's Apple only.
Scott: so you need iTunes or an iPod and what they do is first It's an AAC file and not an mp3.
Scott: So you need some software that can play an AAC in order to hear the audio.
Rym: now a lot of modern even not iPods But mp3 players will play AAC But not everything and there are people who actually couldn't listen to now.
Scott: in addition what it does for you is if you have this Normal AAC is which are just audio and that's not a big deal.
Scott: But an enhanced AAC does.
Scott: it does three things for you.
Scott: number one?
Scott: You can put like these markers within your podcast.
Scott: So for example our podcast starts out with the news and the thing of the day than the main bit.
Scott: We can put little markers at the beginning of each segment that allow people using the enhanced Podcast to skip around to different segments, so it's like chapter markers on exactly.
Scott: it Also allows you to put different images album covers for different parts of the podcast.
Scott: so if you're talking about a race car in the first part of the episode you can have a picture of a race car as The album art.
Scott: and then later on you're talking about the or really owl and you have a picture of an owl is the album Art.
Scott: and the third thing it does is it allows you.
Scott: It allows you to put a link to a website in the album art.
Scott: so if someone's listening with iTunes, and you start talking about Otakon then there'll be a picture of the Otakon logo down there with a link to Otakon.com right there.
Scott: So if someone's listening and they go oh, that's pretty interesting they look over in the corner They see a link.
Scott: they click on it.
Scott: it opens up in their browser.
Scott: It's actually pretty cool, but you're alienating so many listeners by doing it that it's kind of not worth it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we're not saying don't do it at all.
Rym: We're just saying we don't do it because of our.
Rym: we really kind of have a broad appeal.
Rym: But in terms of there are a lot of podcasts that make very good use of that like podcasts that tried to teach you Japanese which there are a lot of.
Rym: they'll show the Kana or they'll show kanji while they talk about him And it's a great method of learning all the kanji.
Rym: you know if you see the kanji there in your iPod and it's telling you about the kanji and then the next one back and forth or Technology podcast they'll show the schematic diagram of whatever thing they're talking about while they're talking about it Which
Scott: yeah, I find it's really good for music podcast because you you know as you listen to different songs throughout the podcast You'll see the cover of the album that they're playing and you'll have a link to the band's website And all that kind of cool stuff.
Scott: But yeah If you have a lot of money and a lot of bandwidth.
Scott: you can do a normal mp3 and an enhanced podcast for the people Who want the enhanced podcast, but if you can't afford you know double?
Scott: Bandwidth and double the storage for all your podcasting needs, then you probably should just make an mp3.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we already spend over a thousand dollars a year just on bandwidth and hosting at this point.
Rym: Yeah, we'd add in two feeds.
Rym: We'd have double that.
Scott: yeah All right question Dylan time.
Scott: Actually sort of a direct question.
Scott: I've just started listening to your podcast, so I haven't caught up yet.
Scott: By now has somebody told you what the duty of grand Fenwick is The touchy of grand Fenwick.
Rym: we had a couple people answer the question which made me very happy.
Rym: good Yeah, our podcast has actually gotten a somewhat interesting community around it to the point that our forums are basically a whole Text-based show I mean unto themselves.
Scott: Yeah All right, I have a Convention well a meeting and we want to podcast those two people who were not able to attend that and we have Some background hiss from our audio equipment Because again we couldn't afford to bring big stuff.
Scott: Is there software to take out that?
Scott: yes before we actually broadcast it and what?
Scott: how difficult is that to do?
Rym: There I could go into excruciating detail into how to Like how to take the hiss out how to get rid of noise all that stuff And I'll try to keep it as informative and yet light as I can.
Rym: but basically there are a couple of ways to deal with Noise, I mean you know most of you've ever tried to record something on your computer.
Rym: There's that hissing noise in the background or a low hum sometimes or your voice is just really scratchy I hope sounds like those.
Scott: Or you breathe into the microphone you know because you hold it next to your face all the time like that.
Scott: Yeah, or the speaker.
Scott: some of them are nailing the mic Microphone.
Rym: discipline is a very important part of podcasting.
Rym: How annoying is this right now?
Rym: Would you listen to a podcast that did this for an hour?
Rym: There are so many to do and I hate it because I like the podcast But I just can't listen to him because they keep going like this.
Rym: I have no idea what they're actually talking about.
Rym: But in terms of like hisses and noise If you the hardware solution is something called a noise gate which in its simplest form is a tiny little thing that says whenever the Audio level is below a certain threshold it gets rid of all the audio there at all.
Rym: So if there's a low hiss whenever you're not talking that low hiss disappears.
Rym: And then when you amplify the whole podcast it doesn't amplify that hissing.
Rym: you make it a louder hiss.
Rym: More advanced ways to get rid of noise.
Rym: if you use audacity It has a nice function where you highlight an empty part of your podcast like while you're recording you record 10 seconds of silence.
Rym: You highlight it And then you kick a. they call it a noise signature And it'll try to figure out what frequencies all the noise are in.
Rym: and then you can remove that from the rest of the show Which works with varying degrees of success.
Rym: you really have to experiment with it.
Rym: Generally the more noise you remove the more you sound like a robot on the show.
Scott: I can't tell you how many robot podcasts I've listened to it.
Rym: The hardware in general.
Rym: in terms of this sort of thing a hardware solution is always better than a software solution in terms of quality And ease of use.
Rym: but a software solution is usually free.
Rym: That is key.
Rym: I mean a noise gate.
Rym: You know twenty thirty dollars But it all adds up as you buy noise gates compressors for every audio problem you have there's a piece of hardware That'll make it go away.
Scott: But that's one more chunk of money you have to spend and even when there is a piece of hardware that can make your problem You're gonna have to spend some time learning to use that piece of hardware.
Scott: I mean a noise gates.
Scott: pretty simple I could set one of those up But a compressor is a lot more difficult.
Scott: if you don't know about audio engineering you're gonna have to read some books.
Scott: Yeah Actually when we did record this we had it compressed and that was part of the problem because it was a little bit of a noisy Mixer.
Scott: so it did bring the floor up and that brought the noise up.
Rym: Actually if you have a big problem with noise There's a hardware thing or actually you can do this in software in a lot of programs called an expander Which obviously opposite of a compressor.
Rym: now actually I'll talk about this now.
Rym: It's a nice segue because this is really an important part of podcasting that very few podcasts.
Rym: You know how to do properly.
Rym: There there are two ways to deal with noise and two ways to deal with audio levels But generally you want everything in a podcast to be about the same volume.
Rym: It's not music or there's a quiet part in a loud part.
Rym: You don't want one guy in a podcast to be really loud and one guy to be really quiet because that's annoying.
Rym: and a compressor what it does is It'll once the audio gets above a certain loudness.
Rym: It'll start Decreasing the amplitude or reducing the gain on that audio further.
Rym: So the louder I talk the more it turns the volume down on me.
Rym: So in the end no matter how much I yell the podcast it still sounds pretty much the same.
Rym: it doesn't get that much louder.
Rym: and The problem with this is that you're making the whole thing quieter as a result because all they can do is take away audio.
Rym: Now you have noise like the hissing the hum and all that and that's really low.
Rym: That's like this low level like you look at a picture of a wave, you know, the actual audio.
Rym: There's this low-level warbling going on when no one's talking and If you compress the highest vocal points the highest Amplitude of the wave the points where you're talking the loudest are far away from that noise.
Rym: That way the noise is overpowered by your voice.
Rym: when you compress you make that How I'm trying to do this in such non-technical terms.
Scott: If you fail miserably, you're bringing those peaks down.
Rym: you're bringing your audio level down Which means my voice is now closer to that noise.
Rym: So you've brought the noise floor up.
Rym: The floor below which the noise is is higher and as a result, there's more noise in your podcast.
Scott: it makes a lot more sense when you look at some of the waves from when you talk and then you can see ah Someone shows you a picture of.
Scott: this is what a good wave should look like and this is what you have recorded.
Scott: You're like, oh my god.
Scott: It's so bad.
Rym: Oh Just basically it if Scott yells it turns the volume down on him automatically.
Rym: Now an expander is what you need.
Rym: It does the exact opposite it.
Rym: the louder something is the louder it makes it.
Rym: so it Expands the audio and it amplifies everything except the noise.
Rym: it amplifies everything that's above a certain threshold.
Rym: so the noise or the hiss which is below that won't get picked up and That would probably deal with the problem.
Rym: you have at least to some degree All right more questions.
Rym: I swear to God if we get feedback in this room, I'll scream.
Scott: hi Um, yeah, my question is that say like that a couple of my friends of mine want to do a pocket but we want for example interview somebody but they're not in the same room.
Scott: as I say like.
Scott: they're like Oh Just like in another state or something.
Scott: What's for PC users?
Scott: What's the best software you recommend for that?
Scott: to do a conference and report a podcast before you're interviewing someone?
Rym: Well, there's a story here.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: There are many many ways and as always a lot of money will make it really easy.
Rym: Well, did we tell the funny story first about how we failed at this?
Scott: All right, tell the story.
Rym: It's Otakon related.
Rym: So about two months ago We did what.
Rym: we did a bunch of stuff on Otakon The artist alley fiasco.
Rym: that happened when there was the misunderstanding and as a result we ended up talking to Jim bottles a bunch the con chair of Otakon this year and He expressed interest in having us interview him on the show and we thought this is gonna be fantastic.
Rym: The con chair of Otakon.
Rym: we get to talk to him.
Rym: We're gonna ask him so much stuff off the record.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: So we get him on and he doesn't want to use Skype because for various reasons Skype is good But it's also bad and he had a Mac and we had.
Rym: we didn't.
Rym: we had a Mac eventually.
Rym: So we decided to try to use I chat which supposedly integrates with garage band.
Scott: Yes Theoretically if you have I chat your garage band And so it is the other person you can.
Scott: I chat with each other and garage band will record your conversation.
Scott: That will fail if they have a really really old version of I chat like Jim bowels does.
Scott: Now some other solutions are you can get.
Scott: I forget what the name of it is but this is telephone bridge where you can actually use an actual telephone and plug the telephone cable into something.
Scott: that then goes into your Computer and you can record it as if it was a microphone.
Scott: But it's a telephone and then you just call them on the phone and start talking.
Rym: Now the audio that way is usually pretty bad.
Scott: I think you have to know a lot about audio to make that work properly and even then just telephones in general a very Low audio quality.
Rym: I mean we did some interviews over cell phones and it was listenable, but it sounded pretty bad.
Rym: overall.
Rym: I'd say the best solution if you don't have a lot of equipment You have a lot of PCs is something called gizmo phone Which is a lot like Skype voice over IP, but it has recording built into it So you can just record the whole conversation without having to do anything special.
Rym: Skype has no built-in way to record what you're talking about and There are no really easy ways to get around that that.
Scott: your choices for recording Skype are pretty much there's like a couple programs called like hot recorder or turbo recorder or something like that and They have ads and you have to pay their shareware and they will record Skype.
Scott: They you know.
Scott: You just open Skype start talking push the button in the recorder and it will record.
Rym: what some people do is they'll.
Rym: They'll do the Skype where one person records what comes out of their speakers the other person records that comes out of their speakers and then they mix it together and that is the most tedious and Terrible way you could possibly do it But a lot of podcasts do it that way.
Scott: now the correct way to record Skype is Actually somewhat difficult to set up.
Scott: audio wise I mean if you don't have you need a mixer you need a bunch of cables you need two Computers
Rym: on your end
Scott: and what you do is you have a computer that records the audio you have a computer that only does Skype and you treat the output of the computer.
Scott: that does Skype as You know a person with a microphone and you plug them into your mixer.
Scott: The thing is you then have to send back what you say to the Skype computer So the person can hear you talking without sending them back what they say.
Scott: because then you know If they talk it comes into your computer then goes back out to them.
Scott: They hear everything they say and it really screws it up.
Scott: So you need a mixer.
Scott: I need to fiddle with the auxilary settings and it's.
Rym: there's no way I can explain easily Without showing you how to do it.
Rym: But after the panel anyone wants to see come on up and I'll show you exactly How we do that and where the cables go and how it all works.
Scott: There is an episode.
Scott: There is a TV show I think I'm revision 3.com or whatever.
Scott: the URL is called system Systm and they have.
Scott: there was an episode where they went to this guy Leo Laporte who's a big-time Podcasting guy.
Scott: they went to his house and he showed everyone like the ISDN box He had and this giant mixer and how he set up Skype and that's how we figured out how to do it.
Scott: We saw exactly what he did.
Scott: my question is When it comes to Group environments where you have multiple people talking in a room at the same time You have a group discussion and you can't get individuals up to the microphone one at a time Do you have an arrangement for that a solution for that?
Scott: Well, there are two ways.
Rym: Well, actually we had a lot of experience with that last night and Generally, I mean we do the show together.
Rym: We also live together in college for a long time A lot of listeners seem to think that we are gay which was kind of Larry's.
Scott: we're not gay We're just.
Rym: well, what was the term from clerks?
Rym: I don't know But we've been friends for so long and actually all these people that we know too when we record a show We just we have these cues and even for all in the room together talking It's really no big deal in terms of cutting people off.
Rym: There's just kind of this vibe and flow and especially us.
Rym: when we get a third person on our show as a guest They can't get a word in edgewise.
Rym: we have to force ourselves to shut up and let them talk.
Scott: Yes, some people like invited us onto their podcasts and you know inviting one of us is okay But if they invite both of us, it basically becomes an episode of our show.
Rym: Yeah What we were with them is the guess we appeared on what geek speak and it was just us talking to each other for an Hour and him kind of like.
Scott: yeah Yeah, if you want to record a group There's two ways you could do it.
Scott: number one you get a mixer and a whole bunch of microphones one for everybody.
Rym: again money can Every problem.
Scott: number two you can get I haven't actually found one yet up for sale But you can get them.
Scott: there are these omni directional mics that you can put in the middle of a table that you know They use them for like teleconferencing and offices and things and if you get one of those it might call.
Scott: I don't know how much they cost.
Scott: They're probably a lot of money.
Scott: 60 70 bucks Yes But if they if you get one of those you put it in the middle of table and you Everyone's voice will come through.
Scott: the quality won't be amazing, but it'll be decent enough to share with everyone.
Rym: It'll be pretty bad Over all things considered.
Scott: It'll sound like an office teleconference.
Rym: I mean generally what we did.
Rym: I think the best will just what we did last night.
Rym: We had a whole bunch of people trying to be on our show and we only had three.
Rym: see there are two kinds of microphones Basically, they're omni directional and uni directional.
Rym: now an omni directional mic records the same Volume from any direction.
Rym: so you stick it in the middle of four people and they can just all kind of talk at it.
Rym: Or you hand it to someone and if they don't know how to hold a microphone It doesn't matter how they're holding it.
Rym: They'll still sound the same.
Rym: The problem is it picks up all the noise in the room.
Rym: so if someone's you know fiddling with something in the corner, it'll pick that up too.
Rym: and Unidirectional mics really only pick up sound from essentially one direction.
Rym: So you have to point it very specifically at yourself in a certain way And it won't pick up any noise.
Rym: Like if I had a unidirectional mic and Scott's talking to me Scott wouldn't even get picked up on the mic, but I would be picked up perfectly.
Scott: These are unidirectional.
Scott: So if I But if it was omni directional you'd still be able to hear me if I was like this side of it.
Rym: So what we did is we had the three unidirectional mics and we gave those two I guess the three people we thought were the coolest or whoever had the best voices and then everyone else.
Rym: We just stuck one omni directional mic and we recorded that on a separate track Because it was so noisy.
Rym: and then what I can do in post-production now is the three people on the good mics.
Rym: I just throw them in and then I only bring in the track from the other omni directional mic When people on that track are talking and otherwise I quash it out.
Rym: so no the noise comes through In terms of dealing with a bunch of people as in terms of who talks when You just have to designate someone as the moderator.
Rym: I mean we had I basically did the whole first roundtable.
Rym: we did Scott wasn't in the room so much.
Rym: So I moderated the whole thing, you know, I asked people questions.
Rym: I would cut people off if they were talking too long.
Rym: then when we did the thing where you know, the assassination attempt occurred.
Rym: We Scott we were tired.
Rym: So Scott and I just kind of did it and there's really no true moderator and it kind of descended into chaos until we got shot.
Rym: But in general it if you ever want to have a whole bunch of people recorded.
Rym: Someone needs to be the moderator someone you everyone needs to agree that they will take that person's direction No matter what they say until the recording stops.
Scott: Yeah, I mean some podcasts, you know Don't have a moderator and everyone's polite and they know each other.
Scott: So they know, you know only talk at once.
Scott: if people are interrupting each other or talking over each other It becomes unlistenable because you know one person just keep talking over each other.
Scott: Yeah Well one person is this loud and another person is exactly as loud.
Scott: if they both talk at the same time It gets double loud and not good.
Rym: I can't believe.
Rym: that's all the questions.
Rym: No.
Scott: No, I've got the mic.
Rym: Ah Understand that hosting and the RSS feed is basically an art form.
Scott: Constantly developing sounds like two of you are having far more fun than should be allowed.
Scott: Did you share with us some of your experiences with that?
Scott: Okay, what I do is we have hosting from a company called line ode which is not for the faint of heart If you cannot administer a Linux system on your own do not get a line ode.
Scott: But I have a line ode because I can do that and what I did is install the patchy the web server PHP, you know the programming language system and WordPress WordPress.
Scott: if you make a blog post in WordPress and you link to an mp3 It will automatically make the RSS feed and the enclosure and do everything for you.
Scott: If you don't want to you can go to wordpress.com and get your own WordPress blog But your URL is going to be something dot wordpress.com.
Scott: Then what we did is you need special things in your feed for iTunes to recognize it because iTunes is screwed up And they like to do their own thing.
Scott: so if you want iTunes and Apple to recognize You know all the information about your podcast and you want them to put your podcast in their directory properly You need to add all this stuff to your feed Which there's two ways you can do it.
Scott: if you're using WordPress number one you can get a WordPress plug-in that allows you to do it.
Scott: or You can use feed burner.
Scott: What feed burner does?
Scott: is they provide a service where you give them an RSS feed.
Scott: then they?
Scott: Tidy up your RSS feed into something perfect And then you share the feed burner feed with everyone because you know that one always works Just fine, and that's that's what we do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: They're very good.
Rym: I mean, I'd say I'm not quite the majority of podcasts now Or it's moving to feed burner just because it's so easy.
Rym: I mean like we're Linux admins and all that and dealing with email is such a pain that we just use Gmail And it's kind of the same deal.
Rym: It's a pain to deal with RSS.
Rym: So if you just use feed burner they take over everything for you, and you don't have to worry about all that.
Scott: There are a lot of people out there who are scarily Manually editing their RSS feeds.
Scott: if you're manually editing your RSS feed you are doing something wrong.
Scott: You should have a piece of software that is doing that for you automatically Or else I don't know why you're wasting your time.
Rym: Yeah I mean the RSS exists to make podcasting or anything like this easier to do not harder to do.
Scott: And as for the hosting there are a lot more companies now used to be just Libsyn really But now there's a whole bunch of competitors.
Scott: I think that pod show company has something and there's a few others and The way they seem to work for podcasts is you can upload so many megabytes of podcasts per month and then infinity downloads Which is which is good because you know if you get a hundred million listeners all of a sudden You don't want to be screwed.
Rym: Yep, and they keep your archives as long as you keep paying them.
Rym: so everything stays up forever.
Rym: and All told we spend about a hundred and twenty dollars a month on all of our hosting.
Scott: Yeah, I think our Libsyn is 40 bucks and the line out hosting is 80 bucks But in terms of anyone else out there I mean one.
Rym: we do four shows a week, and they're all about an hour long - we record pretty high quality and we use 96 kilobits per second.
Rym: for various reasons and For anyone else out there who isn't insane like we are If you do like a weekly or a monthly podcast you could easily get away with spending ten or fifteen dollars a month and be Perfectly fine and ready to go in case you get slashed on it or parked or something.
Scott: Yeah, Libsyn actually provides a total podcasting solution.
Scott: So if you're not doing a whole lot of podcasting you can just pay them and everything will work.
Scott: You won't need any other hosts.
Scott: You won't need anything else.
Scott: You'll probably need a domain name from someone, but that's about it.
Rym: I don't personally terribly recommend using Libsyn for that because their technological service is very good.
Rym: Their customer support is kind of lacking and if you don't know about the technology and you need help Libsyn generally can't provide it very easily or very well.
Scott: It's sort of like using GarageBand.
Scott: You know it works.
Scott: It's everything in one, but at the same time you can't really do anything with it.
Scott: You're trapped inside the noobs world the low end.
Rym: I generally recommend using WordPress in some form either on whatever hosting you already have or WordPress.com.
Rym: it's easy to use you'll learn a lot And it's really the best solution.
Rym: as far as I can see.
Scott: there are other blog softwares that are just as good like movable Type or type.
Scott: I don't know what they're called.
Scott: I don't use them, but they're out there.
Scott: Hey guys.
Scott: Hey, what's up um?
Scott: By podcast we use Skype and Audacity.
Scott: simply because one of our new one of our hosts is in England and The other programs don't work so well over there We're running into a problem rather severe problem where two of us there are four of us total.
Scott: two of us sound great The other two sound awful, and if we put it into a car they become unhearable There.
Rym: it's always twos with us apparently, but there are two things that cause that.
Rym: Early on we record everything where we can coded everything to 64 kilobit per second mp3s which is pretty much as low as you would ever want to go for voice.
Rym: and Because of the way our levels are we didn't realize that you know listening to our masters everything that I mean.
Rym: it sounded pretty good to us, but then one of our listeners told us one day that in the car we sound like two robots killing each other and Those are basically the artifacts from encoding something to an mp3 or in skype's case What skype uses to compress the audio to send it across.
Rym: the best solution?
Rym: I mean in terms of encoding you can't do much about Skype because Skype changes how it encodes depend on your bandwidth.
Rym: So there's nothing you can do about that except buy more bandwidth.
Rym: in Terms of dealing with the fact that they sound bad the best thing you can really do is have them on two separate tracks and Then do a separate set of filters to the bad sounding one to try to smooth it out a little.
Scott: Yeah, also two guys sound bad and two guys sound fine.
Scott: There's probably something wrong with their end.
Scott: Maybe they have a sound card with a lot of noise on it.
Scott: Maybe they didn't set their levels properly.
Rym: I think it sounds like his problem is very specifically an encoding issue.
Rym: Yeah, because that kind of noise really only comes up when you're compressing something.
Scott: all right MP3 before you upload.
Scott: you should probably upload all the waves and combine them and make an MP.
Rym: You never want to transcode anything.
Rym: I mean real.
Rym: briefly in case anyone isn't fully aware of this There are two ways always two.
Rym: you can encode audio losslessly like in flack or essentially a wave file where it's perfect or an mp3 where it's small because it's lossy.
Rym: information is Destroyed.
Rym: if you encode something to mp3 some information is lost.
Rym: if you encode that to an mp3 again More is lost.
Rym: so if you encode to mp3 upload it And then he makes an mp3 from that.
Rym: that is probably where almost all of your problems are coming from Especially if he's using a bitrate less than 96 It's just like if you ever use Photoshop.
Scott: you want to do everything in what the PSD format.
Scott: that is completely lossless Until the very last minute you make your JPEG or your paying or your gift.
Scott: It's the same thing.
Scott: you want to keep everything as a wave file, or if you're using an Apple they have those lossless Files.
Scott: yeah, whatever they're called you want to make everything you know lossless until the very last minute you make your mp3 or your AAC.
Scott: Anyone else?
Rym: we're almost out of time, so I have a question about the new video Podcasts.
Rym: I know you guys aren't too involved, but I'm guessing that you know more than most.
Rym: We've been debating doing it and the only limiting factor is money.
Rym: at this point The only video podcast I watch is ask a ninja.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Think of it.
Scott: I'm listening to the audio podcast because while I work I'm a computer programmer so I could sit in work and listen at the same time.
Scott: It was a video podcast.
Scott: you know I'd have to stop work.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I work in the Bronx, and I live an hour north of it So I drive to work an hour one way every day.
Rym: I can listen to podcasts in the car just fine.
Rym: I can't watch a movie in the car.
Rym: Well.
Rym: I can but it's fine.
Rym: I have a good idea But in turn I mean it.
Rym: video podcasting is really I don't think going to take off soon because It's really just the barrier to entry and the amount of effort.
Rym: I mean think you've got blogging podcasts video casts and Blogging.
Rym: the barrier to entry is really small.
Rym: I mean blogs are free.
Rym: all you have to do is type whenever it takes almost no effort.
Rym: Just type whatever you want audio now.
Rym: You know this equipment.
Rym: You need to learn about audio.
Rym: you need to actually sit down and record the audio Usually late at night when I need to go to bed because I've worked in the morning And Pardon me now, and you have to worry about the noise in the room and all that video.
Rym: now You also have to worry about lighting about bandwidth about makeup about all these other things, and it's just it becomes an Exponentially increasing amount of effort.
Scott: yeah, I mean with audio You know the mp3 is gonna work on everyone's computer pretty much if you use video.
Scott: you got to worry about the mpeg 4s What's it called the h.264?
Scott: And the iPod formats.
Scott: at the PSP formats the Divix the expid There's so many different video formats the QuickTime the windows media.
Scott: It's really just a pain in the butt I think.
Rym: maybe give it three or four years.
Rym: video Podcasting is bandwidth increases as long as you know the internet isn't made up of a series of tubes.
Scott: Yeah as digital cameras get cheaper and as Google turns on more dark fiber you're gonna see a lot more video podcasting.
Scott: All right, I think we're out of time anyway, so we're not on time just yet.
Rym: We got to wind down.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think we have any more questions.
Rym: I guess at this point everyone who does a podcast come on up here And we'll well yell and scream and be if someone will take a picture.
Scott: Make a line.
Rym: come on up as long as you actually do a podcast.
Rym: I'll know if you're lying.
Rym: I'll know.
Rym: And there are no freaking clown pistols allowed up here.
Scott: good God Oh We should pimp ourselves first.
Rym: Oh, yeah once again.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights Front row crew.
Rym: calm we got fires for everyone.
Scott: Yeah, we do it.
Scott: We have a flyer.
Scott: so if you want to actually listen to our show if you thought we were at all entertaining We'll give you a flyer.
Scott: just come up and see us after the show.
Rym: Yeah, and we would talk in depth about our show, but that's not really what this panel is about at least this year.
Scott: Yeah, we do four shows a week is a Technology then games then anime and then every other geeky thing in the world.
Scott: so no matter What kind of geek you are you know at least one day a week?
Rym: You'll like our show now fully the first other podcast we ever met was right here our friends at anime world order who?
Rym: Interviewed me at Katsucon last year.
Scott: Hey, I'm Darryl Surratt.
Scott: I'm the one who assassinated Rym and Scott boo.
Rym: Yeah We're the people who don't know anything about audio engineering or web hosting or anything, but we do know about anime.
Scott: So if we can do this any of you idiots can.
Scott: oh did I say idiots whatever.
Scott: This is my co-host Gerald say hello Hi All right, then But yeah, you might have seen us obnoxiously carpet bombing this place with flyers Or not?
Scott: yeah check the show out and then check out these other people as well.
Scott: I'll move you like this way.
Scott: It's closer down that way first.
Rym: Hi, I'm Erin, and this is Noah, and we're the ninja consultant podcast.
Rym: we've been around for about a year.
Rym: so after a year We finally figured out how to use like microphones and mixers and stuff.
Rym: so now it sounds pretty good.
Rym: So if you haven't listened in a long time you check it out and some guy offered to build this web page.
Rym: So the web page also looks pretty good.
Rym: I really recommend the anime world order podcast.
Scott: They're pretty awesome.
Scott: They came out like last December or something.
Scott: Most of our listeners are fifth graders, so They're either like fifth graders and junior high kids or parents.
Scott: So if you are a fifth grader or no fifth graders, I understand that fifth graders like our podcast.
Scott: I'm Joel white from fast karate for the gentleman.
Scott: Yeah, I'm Dave Riley.
Scott: you can find us at Dave and Joel.
Scott: It's the podcast all about kung fu asking and cartoons.
Scott: How's everyone doing?
Scott: I'm Alan.
Scott: my podcast is a taco generation and We've been doing for about a year and Darryl contributes a lot so that they hear his voice quite a bit.
Scott: And we're we're pretty old-school.
Scott: I'm the only one represented out of the 10 of us 10 15 of us that Normally do our podcast every week.
Scott: and because they're all lame They have something else like you know life to do or something like that.
Scott: actually I think it's Otakon has burned them out completely.
Scott: so And since we're old school.
Scott: We're all old guys So you know they can't get out of their rocker chairs that come to them to con stuff.
Scott: I'm Marcus noble I host.
Scott: You were the loser.
Scott: you you totally ruined our perfect streak of no feedback.
Rym: See I didn't really warn him But you learn a lot about audio and the first thing you'll learn when you start doing live shows anywhere Is that you never walk in front of those big things because they'll hurt you.
Rym: I Marcus noble I host the skunk smells podcast.
Rym: basically I spend about a half hour my Saturday playing with some of the pot safe music that I like and ranting about stuff that annoys Me about life.
Rym: if you're interested feel free to check it out.
Scott: skunk smells dot Libsyn.
Scott: calm All right cool.
Scott: We'll go down this side.
Rym: use your microphone this time.
Rym: Okay, okay our lovely assistant Mary, okay?
Scott: This one yes, it is hi.
Rym: I'm Nury hi.
Scott: I'm Michelle and we do a podcast called artist Ali For artists and commissioners, so if you're either one come up to us later.
Scott: We'll interview you right here at the convention.
Scott: Listen to him and Scott's show.
Scott: they're awesome we.
Scott: My name is Devin.
Scott: I'm also known as um maveron line.
Scott: I host TGP servers org which is a free team speak hosting for gamers.
Scott: I need a team speak and stuff like that.
Scott: pretty much, we just get online and make fun of people and each other and We've only come out with one episode, but we are trying to get into the video podcast.
Scott: Hey, I'm Spada.
Scott: I'm a host of the TF wire podcast.
Scott: We're the one and only transformers podcast online.
Scott: We've been going on for about a year right now.
Scott: We're in a three-week hiatus, so we can actually Regain our sanity.
Scott: But we're at TF wire comm.
Scott: give us a listen.
Scott: Just don't listen to us in the car.
Scott: Yeah, that's something else.
Scott: I guess you should point out is it there?
Scott: There aren't.
Scott: there are a lot of podcasts covering weird things like I said Australian real estate But there are a lot of things that there isn't a podcast for them like.
Scott: I don't think you know.
Scott: There's no podcast about like lens men there.
Rym: If you know something if there's something you're an expert at there's something you're passionate about You could do a podcast so easily and anyone else.
Rym: It's a great way to meet people who are interested in the same weird things you're interested in.
Rym: I mean my favorite podcast other than GeekNights right now that I listen to is called 12 Byzantine emperors And it's just this guy talking about 12 emperors from the ancient empire of Byzantine and Byzantium and all that is actually Rome Which I just learned.
Rym: And I just like to say that it's really Podcasting is really seems to be starting to take off.
Rym: I mean last year at Otakon there was practically no podcasting.
Rym: now We've got all these podcasts here and even though it's 10 a.m.. On Sunday next year.
Rym: There's probably gonna be twice as many.
Rym: There's probably going to be a podcasting party that I'm sure all of us will have something to do with and I'm sure there will Be some sort of trouble occurring.
Rym: Clown pistol related the fact that he yelled six semper tyrannous before he shot me.
Scott: All right, I think we're running out of time so if anyone wants to say anything to us or anyone else up here We'll be hanging out after the panel.
Rym: Yes most if anyone wants to see our equipment we can explain in great detail in ways that I didn't want to bore the rest of You with exactly how we do all that stuff, okay?
Scott: All right Yes And you can also pick up flyers to all of our podcasts to you know.
Scott: get our URLs because I know you're gonna forget by The time you get home and sleep overnight and all that good stuff, so thank you for coming.
Scott: everyone here is awesome.
Scott: Everyone not here is not awesome.
Rym: And I just would like to plug.
Rym: if you have nothing to do today And you've never been to them before go to the closing ceremonies, and if you can the feedback session.
Rym: They're very good at Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, the feedback session is now.
Rym: Yeah, and the closing ceremonies?
Rym: They usually show all the winning AMVs.
Rym: in case you miss the AMV contest Ray well the winner is you All right, thank you.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Rym: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Rym: if you like our podcasts you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Rym: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows It's actually recorded at night.