Rym: It's Thursday November 2nd.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight with the upcoming US midterm elections We talk a little bit about politics.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Today I actually had some work to do.
Scott: Oh my god, cuz I didn't have work to do and I left work early to go buy.
Scott: Shit, we desperately needed and did not have an opportunity to go buy.
Rym: Though by having work to do I ended up being in Mount Vernon today and I ended up being in an area that is Predominantly Hispanic.
Rym: Now the interesting thing is I needed some food.
Rym: So I just wander out.
Rym: I'm looking for a deli or something.
Rym: I see a deli.
Rym: I just walk in stand in line get to the front I go to order.
Rym: then I realize that I'm the only one in this place who speaks English.
Scott: Oh my god, everything's in Spanish.
Rym: the menus in Spanish on the wall the Owners and employees.
Rym: none of them speak English at all.
Scott: You know, I haven't, you know taken a Spanish class since high school.
Scott: high school I took two years of Spanish.
Scott: middle school.
Scott: I took three years and since then not so much but I still find I can kind of read a Spanish newspaper I guess like a Spanish elementary school kid maybe and I probably could order food in a Spanish restaurant.
Scott: But yeah, that's that's pretty interesting there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it was.
Rym: it was interesting that no one spoke English at all Which is something I've never actually run into in this country before Where I went to a place of business and tried to conduct business and I was unable to Because the people owning the business did not speak my language.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they guys speak English.
Scott: I mean, I've never encountered some.
Scott: I've encountered people who can't speak English at all but they're usually people directly from foreign countries like vacationing someone or You know someone from an older generation.
Rym: Well, I have another little.
Rym: I have a beef though before I get into what actually happened.
Rym: Alright the the sign outside said it was a deli.
Rym: I went in because I wanted to sub.
Rym: it wasn't a deli.
Rym: They only had like tacos and burritos awesome, so and I didn't want to walk out because that was awkward even though it's awkward enough that everyone's just kind of staring at Me and I'm obviously this guy.
Rym: It doesn't speak the language and I didn't want to leave because I thought that would be rude.
Rym: so eventually it turns out one of the other customers spoke enough English to Translate to the patron or the proprietor that I wanted a chicken burrito Which in the end was really really good and really really big and it was only like three bucks.
Scott: I imagine it would be.
Scott: it was.
Rym: it wasn't as good as the cafe Maya, but it was three bucks.
Rym: I pay more than that for a slice of pizza and sometimes Great.
Rym: All right, but then more much more interestingly I I work.
Rym: I go to these two big hospitals to do a whole bunch of work and that you need diseases.
Rym: I hope not.
Rym: But though at one point I dropped a pen on the floor in one of these data Closets and the guy was like I go to reach it.
Rym: the guy says don't pick anything up off the floor.
Rym: Here's the new pen Mm-hmm.
Rym: He's like don't touch the floor here.
Rym: You'll get sick Wasn't the best hospital I was in?
Rym: Okay, well at least the first hospital one was better.
Rym: But the cool thing is while I was that I've never been in a not nice Hospital like.
Scott: I went to a hospital once that looked not nice on the outside like outside the hospital.
Scott: I was like, huh?
Scott: This looks like a shady hospital, but inside it was nice hospital.
Scott: I mean it was gone.
Rym: It wasn't any dirtier than any other hospital that I've worked in.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: no one had ever specifically warned me against touching the floor before and I've been in operating rooms.
Rym: Maybe
Scott: that was just a scared, dude You know the kind of people are afraid of germs all the time or
Rym: you might just been making a joke
Scott: or maybe he's making A joke, but
Rym: the point is while I was working I met a cool guy who you know I'm just making small talk while I'm doing my business and he's showing me around and Unlocking all these places I have to get into to do my business.
Rym: And we're talking a bit about hobbies.
Rym: and I mentioned yeah, blah blah blah Convention.
Rym: whenever I talk about my hobbies most people in the world.
Rym: I interact with in my job Do not understand geekery at all.
Rym: So when I say like normally if I meet someone I'm cool, I'll be like, yeah I was just at an anime con or yeah, I do a podcast but to normal muggles I say things like yeah I speak at Japanese muggles.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I said muggles.
Rym: I speak it.
Rym: nor I speak at a Japanese cultural or Japanese film Conventions or Japanese film and animation things and I do an internet radio show or something like that.
Rym: but I mentioned blah blah blah Japanese blah and the guys like Like Katsu Kanon Otakon ride and all that and we start talking.
Rym: He's kind of an anime fan and he wants to start a podcast.
Scott: What kind of other hobbies did he have?
Rym: We talked a bit.
Rym: He's into computers.
Rym: No, he's an IT guy.
Rym: He knows a lot.
Rym: He doesn't isn't so big in Linux, but he wants to be.
Scott: Where does it live?
Rym: somewhere in the city?
Rym: I'm not gonna tell this guy's life story on the show.
Rym: I just thought it was cool that perhaps the for the first time in many years of employment I met another geek in the course of my work No a geek who seemed to know what he was talking about about technology.
Rym: because most of the people I end up Meeting in my work don't really know much about what the job is.
Rym: They're supposed to be doing.
Scott: That's just what it is.
Scott: Like as these old people go out, you know, then we're just we're on the edge.
Scott: We're the young people coming in who know what we're talking about.
Scott: And we just got a more of us got to get in there.
Scott: because yeah, many of us are Knowing but not getting jobs.
Scott: They're just being bums.
Scott: I know a lot of people being bummed.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, we do.
Scott: we could call them out by name Yeah Go get jobs so that we can infiltrate the workforce faster and get rid of the old.
Rym: more Importantly to all of you out there who are friends of mine who are good at technology particularly computers I Get a pile of money if you work for my company and you also get a pile of money and by a pile I mean multiple thousands, so I want that money.
Scott: That's all I got to say Rym not yet wealthy enough to say himself.
Rym: No, no, the thing is I get almost everything I want out of life.
Rym: I don't need much more money to live a perfect life.
Rym: And if I didn't have my school debt, which is rapidly going away I'd be living in luxury as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: Well, the thing is I could always do with more money But the thing is to improve my life I would need so much more money.
Scott: like it used to be I needed a house in a car.
Scott: Well now I have a house in a car.
Scott: So how much money more would it take to significantly improve my life?
Scott: Yeah, the probably it would take like five hundred thousand dollars to buy a wicked house.
Scott: I mean it said I don't get five hundred thousand dollars.
Scott: I'm basically it doesn't change my life at all.
Rym: The sad truth is that the next step to make us more happy in terms of you know money and physical Possessions and lifestyle would to be it to be to be independently wealthy.
Scott: Yeah, I got to remove the debt or remove the job somehow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So we can't be happier physically Unless we have independent wealth or like Ferraris and mansions and shit.
Scott: But even then that doesn't make me that much happier compared to how much money it got.
Rym: You know, what made me the most happy is being independently wealthy and having all that free time.
Scott: Yeah, I think the only real thing I could buy would be like vacations constantly just traveling around the world crazily Yeah, but I can't afford that with a job.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, no I can afford it.
Rym: I can't afford the time.
Scott: Yeah that too.
Rym: I mean we could Scott and I could right now just like go to the airport and fly to Greece and Then we can get back to.
Scott: yeah, that's about it.
Scott: It's like a thousand-something dollar plane ticket.
Rym: Yeah, we can live there for a while too and we could pay off that debt pretty handily with Greek money.
Rym: I'm not saying move to Greece.
Rym: I'm saying fly there stay there.
Rym: We fly back.
Scott: Okay Work in Greece to pay off our American debt.
Rym: We just go on a two-week vacation in Greece.
Rym: on like my credit card.
Scott: Did they use euros in Greece or something else?
Rym: They're part of the EU.
Scott: I think I gotta go check on that.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta admit I haven't been paying attention to modern European politics, it's so weird.
Scott: It's like I know all about old Greece relatively.
Scott: I know a lot.
Rym: Yeah, shall we have quiz time with Rym and Scott?
Scott: No, because I just read I know more about old Greece and I know nothing about new Greece.
Scott: I know nothing about what Greece is like right now at all.
Rym: Where did Alexander the Great come from?
Scott: Greece no.
Rym: No, he came from a Greek ish nation to the north of Greece.
Rym: Whatever who is his dad?
Rym: Rym the grim the not-so-great Anyway was Archimedes Greek.
Scott: He had a principal.
Rym: Okay, I I just.
Rym: it's funny because yesterday I read a long Wikipedia on something in Greece and now Greece is coming up a lot in our lives.
Scott: Oh better get some some more sandwiches Sandwiches not Greek fire of the gyro nature.
Rym: You could have said Greek fire, but you said sandwich Damascus steel.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I'm down with that.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway, that was a crazy tangent.
Scott: I got some great news.
Rym: I got some interesting news.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well our favorite professional sport Is ice hockey.
Scott: and well ice hockey is not doing so well.
Scott: I mean, it's not as popular as any other professional sport in the country.
Scott: I mean pretty much.
Scott: you got football at the top Then you got your basketballs and your baseballs and all that stuff.
Rym: granted baseball seems to be dropping like a rock.
Scott: Yeah, that's you got your NASCAR's doing pretty well, but you know of all of them NHL not doing so.
Scott: Well, you know, the only thing is doing worse than the NHL are like, you know We golf is doing better than the NHL.
Rym: Well, but I mean think about it in these terms.
Rym: This is what I really think Differentiates hockey from many other professional sports in the US and Canada.
Rym: is that in every other sport?
Rym: it seems many of the players do it more for the money than for the love of the game and hockey players.
Rym: when there's no Hockey or something happens or they can't play their hockey.
Rym: They just go play hockey somewhere else Even if they don't get paid.
Scott: that's something I always liked about hockey.
Scott: is I asked my dad once you know.
Scott: Hey, wait a minute those NHL guys, you know when there was that strike.
Scott: All right Why did they go and play in Europe?
Scott: It's like they're hockey players.
Scott: They just want to play hockey and then when the hockey players are in the Olympics You know, there's the Olympic break and they go play in the Olympics and I'm like, why would you try hard in the Olympics?
Scott: Wouldn't you just get tired out and then not be able to play in the Stanley Cup?
Scott: He's like, they're crazy hockey players.
Scott: They just want to play hockey.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean while hockey isn't doing well in terms of making a lot of profit It's doing well in that it supports itself and all the people who like hockey can get their hockey.
Scott: Yep Anyway, because NHL obviously knows it's having problems, you know outside of the big teams that are really popular A lot of the other teams Not too many people care about at all.
Scott: And they're just basically fodder for the real teams.
Scott: quote real teams.
Scott: So what have they done?
Scott: something that is pure genius that I've been begging.
Scott: Every single sport that exists to do and I think Formula One the sport that should do it The most is gonna be the last one to do it.
Scott: but regardless if you go to video Google dot-com slash NHL dot HTML you can watch Hockey for free.
Scott: now NHL pretty much said all the hockey videos on Google video are awesome.
Scott: You can watch the Rangers game from two or three days ago on Google video just right off MSG.
Rym: now I the only reason I don't watch a lot of hockey is that I really don't like television and it's not worth the money To have it even if it were just a hockey machine.
Scott: I mean think about it.
Scott: We could get cable television, right?
Scott: What would we watch on cable television?
Scott: hockey?
Scott: We would watch hockey I might watch an f1 race and I might watch like I don't even know if I'd watch the Super Bowl if my Might what I might watch like Battlestar Galactica.
Rym: The problem is wouldn't while I would watch all that stuff I would totally TiVo it and watch it.
Scott: Most of those things like Simpsons South Park Futurama all that shit.
Scott: We Netflix that we don't need a TV for that.
Scott: Netflix is way cheaper.
Scott: Yeah, because he would be paying that was it like 40 bucks a month more than that.
Scott: Yeah Just to watch hockey game, which wouldn't be that bad Except that also I don't have that much time and I don't really have time for it and not all the rituals.
Scott: Yeah, and hockey games are only once every three days.
Rym: So now I can just go to Google pick the hockey game I wanted to watch and watch it.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: This is I don't do work at work.
Scott: whenever there's a new Rangers game I'll just watch yesterday's hockey game.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: It's free.
Scott: This is awesome And I think what they have to do now, this is the great.
Scott: This is a huge step for the NHL because now it's not popular but all internet people might get into it.
Scott: Yeah, watch these videos for free.
Scott: What they've got to do is they got to take it to the next level.
Scott: They have to really not let up and keep pushing.
Scott: You know the fact that this webpage exists and that you can watch this stuff for free.
Scott: to get people to watch it.
Scott: Here's what I would do if I were them.
Scott: Watch hockey for free.
Scott: Go go go.
Rym: I would one make forever Hockey games more than I'd say, I don't know.
Rym: 24 hours 48 hours older hockey games.
Scott: Oh, you could.
Scott: there's older hockey games on here newer games.
Rym: No, no, no, I'm saying what I would do.
Rym: I'd make all the non live hockey free to watch and it'd be awesome.
Rym: I'd have a service where you could pay to see the games live.
Scott: I would pay five bucks a year.
Rym: Like you just pay, no you just pay per, I'd even make it.
Rym: you just pay per game Or get a lifetime thing or yearly thing, whatever.
Rym: The numbers don't matter.
Rym: The point is you always make the old ones free because those are nothing but promotion.
Rym: People who actually get into hockey Will probably want to see the games live and they'd probably willing to pay a small amount.
Rym: Couple that with advertising Targeted at geeks and nerds.
Rym: because I got to say a lot of geeks and nerds are into hockey in Proportion to geeks and nerds who are into other sports.
Scott: Yeah I don't know.
Scott: I think that if they if they try really hard because other sports are pretty much neglecting the internet.
Scott: You know, it's if you want to watch baseball in the internet, you got to pay a fuck ton of money.
Scott: It's not worthy.
Scott: football basically non-existent on the internet.
Scott: You can't watch football in the internet.
Rym: You can't watch head footballs.
Scott: Yeah, you know basketball not on the internet.
Scott: hockey now is all on the internet.
Scott: You can watch all the games After they're done being played on Google video for free legally, you know sponsored by you know They gotta add a fight video.
Scott: The thing is the NHL.
Scott: if they ever, you know say, you know promote their fighting That doesn't work because then they get this huge backlash.
Scott: You know what the backlash is only from non hockey I know but they just they can't do it even though they want to real bad.
Rym: Yeah, they could because then it creates the sort of you know All the people who complain about the fighting just make the people who are interested more interested.
Scott: I know I know but that's how it goes.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, the NHL just keeps pushing it.
Scott: They can I think they definitely become popular again and awesome.
Scott: And even if they don't I can watch hockey now if I have bored and I got nothing to do hockey game.
Rym: So a while ago there was a study.
Rym: Well a poll that was going around and a lot of people were quoting it on the internet.
Rym: It's kind of an old poll and it's been done a few times and it basically said that 90% of Americans believe in God and a lot of people were trying to use this as Evidence in various arguments and debates all over the internet most notably on FARC.
Scott: So do we know how this poll worked or anything?
Rym: Oh, well The poll wasn't that good.
Rym: Recently a real Harris poll that went much more in depth came out and very similar if you don't know Harris is a really really Reliable and well done polling company.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, and there have been other studies and what they discovered is that actually 42% of Americans are not certain that there is a God they believe kind of but they will not commit to being absolutely Certain that there is a God.
Rym: Mm-hmm, which is significantly different than saying that 90% of Americans believe in God.
Rym: now I'm not really going anywhere this other than that.
Rym: There are a lot of interesting correlations.
Scott: Read the part that you know, I want you to read All right.
Rym: One thing is that very many Jews or people who claim to be Jews do not actually believe in God.
Scott: Yep What was the percentage?
Rym: let's see only 76% of Protestants 64% of Catholics and 30% of Jews are certain that there is a God.
Scott: now I want to point out that Jewish culture, especially, you know, the United States mostly but Jewish Culture and the way Jewish people are mostly Jewish families Jewish mothers.
Scott: They really stress education a lot.
Scott: Well a lot funny.
Rym: you mentioned that because apparently there is a direct and clear negative correlation between level of education And belief in God and that is why a lot of Jews like I identify myself as Jewish.
Scott: Ish, I guess Jewish ish kinda.
Rym: did you call yourself an open-source juggle a while ago?
Scott: Yeah, you could call it.
Scott: whatever the hell you want The point is Jewish don't believe in God.
Scott: A lot of rabbis don't even believe in God.
Scott: It's kind of crazy.
Rym: Yeah, well, it's more of a culture that we get into that but that's not the point.
Scott: I want to know a lot about it.
Scott: You can read Douglas Rushkoff's book.
Scott: Nothing sacred anyway.
Rym: There's just a lot of interesting things.
Rym: Women are slightly more likely than men to believe in God.
Rym: blacks are super more likely than whites to believe in God.
Rym: So are Hispanics but not as much as blacks.
Rym: Republicans are more likely to believe in God than Democrats.
Rym: The education thing and then they ask a whole bunch of other interesting questions Like do you believe that all religious people worship the same God or does God actually control events on earth and all sorts of things?
Rym: Now here's an interesting only 29% of people believe that God has an effect on the earth only 29%.
Scott: you say yeah.
Scott: well to the see the thing is.
Scott: Gotta ask people if they allow their belief or disbelief in God to affect their decisions.
Rym: See a question like that's not good for a poll.
Rym: Yeah internal subjective question.
Rym: They're asking very direct questions like is God male or female?
Scott: What do people say to that?
Rym: well 36 percent.
Scott: there was a big controversy actually because I went to this.
Scott: it's 50/50.
Rym: It's 50/50 between God is male and God is neither male nor female.
Rym: Ten percent say God is both and one percent say God is a woman.
Scott: Only one percent say God's a woman.
Rym: Well, remember most people in this country if they have a religion have a monotheistic Religion.
Rym: that is probably not believing in some sort of earth spirit.
Rym: Yeah, except for you know Wiccans and all then but They weren't heavily represented.
Rym: or if they were they didn't say that God was female.
Scott: Yeah, see one of the key tenants of Judaism is iconoclasm.
Scott: You're not supposed to like, you know Iconify anything.
Scott: Yeah, so there was one temple I went to once where they said this They said this song or whatever you want to call it and in the song It's.
Scott: there are some words that were like, you know, God is black hair and he's a man, you know It was like one sentence and it was a big controversy.
Scott: So, okay, it just reminded me of that.
Scott: well the only other talking about Jewish the only other interesting thing you're talking about Jewishness.
Rym: I was going on a different tack and well Jewishness.
Scott: I'm Jewish.
Scott: That's all I could talk about.
Scott: Okay Not really.
Rym: the the interesting thing they talk about at the end is they're trying to figure out whether or not belief in God is actually declining or not.
Rym: and the reason it's a difficult question to answer is Because in the past a lot of these polls were conducted over the phone and now many polls like this are conducted over the internet.
Rym: and it turns out that a lot of studies have shown that when given a poll that is by mail or over the internet people are much more likely to tell the truth when they are asked about Something that may be socially undesirable.
Rym: So if you call someone and ask them if they believe in God Even if they don't they're much more likely to say yes because they're afraid of stigma from saying no Because they're talking to an actual person.
Rym: But if they're responding to a machine they're much more likely to tell the truth about their actual beliefs.
Scott: But isn't there also a problem of when you're calling people on the phone You're only polling the subset of people who have home phones Which is not us and when you're doing the internet you're doing the subset of people who have internet connections and take polls on the internet.
Rym: Well the way us the way Harris does it they have a very strict methodology that basically Comes up with very statistically significant results.
Scott: Yeah, I know that but I'm just pointing that out.
Rym: Oh, yeah Telephone polls are largely becoming irrelevant because the only people who have telephones and are willing to do polls Tend to be busybodies.
Scott: Yeah Busybodies do they believe in God?
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: I've got a very relevant thing of the day My thing.
Scott: it is not relevant.
Scott: So I'll go first, but mine's very relevant.
Rym: I want to do it.
Scott: That's why you do it.
Scott: second.
Rym: No, cuz it's not actually relevant.
Rym: You know, what my thing of the day is.
Rym: That's why there's a joke.
Scott: Okay, we'll go for it.
Rym: Then someone just put up this video of a banana spider who has found a grub in his in his web And he goes over and he eats it and I just thought it was really cool.
Scott: Yeah, I was.
Scott: I was watching the video and I saw the grub in the web and I was like, where is the spider?
Scott: Where is the spider?
Scott: and then the spider comes and it's like aha.
Rym: There is the spider There is the spider there's the spider.
Scott: Alright, alright, is that it?
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Just watch this video.
Rym: It's kind of cool.
Scott: Okay, I guess you're not getting enough Discovery Channel.
Rym: You can watch rooms if you want to watch a really big spider eat a really little yellow grub.
Scott: So my Google video is titled almost terrible workday and in the video They say like this guy's the luckiest store clerk ever.
Scott: I don't think he's a lucky store clerk because he was lucky.
Rym: this wouldn't happen to him Because that was an awesome story.
Scott: if it is an awesome story, but you're not the luckiest.
Rym: no, the luckiest would be if right after it happened a lottery ticket fell out of it and landed in his pocket and then I don't know Jesus and Moses and yeah Hanukkah, Harry came down and gave him a present the Jewish today.
Scott: No more Jew talk.
Rym: You're the one who started it.
Scott: I know I'm gonna stop it, too.
Rym: I'll start saying random Yiddish words if you don't say you're watching this video.
Scott: It's very obviously a music store.
Scott: you can see some amps going you could see a keyboard and there's a rack of sheet music And on the right side there's a guy sitting behind the counter and he's I think he's browsing the web on that computer there You know, he's doing something.
Scott: So you're watching and the guy's sitting there.
Scott: He's typing.
Scott: He's doing something All of a sudden like out of nowhere Frickin, you know, he picks his head up because he hears a noise and he looks to the back of the store.
Scott: But you think oh he's looking to the back of the store because there's a guy in the back of the store He's looking at.
Scott: then I don't know if a car hits the store or maybe just the wall Collapses for no reason or they.
Scott: maybe they hung too much shit on the wall, but the wall behind him just Smashes right in on him.
Scott: And I think he was the reason.
Scott: they say he's real lucky is it totally misses him.
Rym: Yeah, the whole area is completely crushed except for this tiny area right around where he's sitting.
Scott: Yeah basically it's like a man.
Scott: the guys like those looney tunes are like there's a hole in the wall and the wall falls down and Bugs Bunny ends up standing where the hole was.
Rym: after it happens.
Scott: The guy's just like what the fuck.
Scott: He freaks out and he gets up and he starts running around doing whatever You know that you would do if the entire wall of your store fell in on you.
Scott: But yeah the one spot sitting at the desk is where he didn't get hurt.
Scott: if he was like not browsing the web He would have been totally crushed by the wall Probably had to go to the hospital with some serious injuries.
Rym: Alright, so we were inspired to do today's show.
Rym: well tonight's show mostly due to the fact that back in the day a lot of newspapers and a lot of publications would around election times Come straight out and not only have opinions that were actually the opinion of the newspaper But they would officially endorse candidates in elections.
Scott: Yeah nowadays all the newspapers and TV stations They say the opinions Dated here are solely those of the people on the show and are not the opinion of the network at all.
Rym: I like the idea of a newspaper saying you know what we're back in so-and-so because blah and you can suck it.
Rym: This is our opinion.
Rym: If you don't like it, well suck it.
Scott: Yeah, nowadays you get newspapers.
Scott: the editor-in-chief will write an article saying, you know This guy is great and some other people write op-eds about.
Scott: so-and-so is great and someone will write a letter to the editor saying So-and-so is great But it's only in this op-ed section and the rest of the newspaper while it might obviously be slanted you know, I mean everyone knows the New York Post is totally right-wing and everyone knows the New York Times is slightly left-wing if not a lot more than that.
Scott: and everyone knows that those newspapers with just the Red-ink and the black ink totally socialist the socialist worker the communist worker the yeah I know at least know what it is.
Scott: at least those newspapers had the balls to say they're socialist.
Rym: the Piece of paper with a bunch of red ink that some hippie guy with dreadlocks tries to show newspaper.
Scott: that's in New York the epoch whatever the one for the.
Rym: I just remember the one day at RIT Where I was walking to class and I was dressed up real nice because I was doing something that day.
Rym: And one of these hippies with the socialist club on campus, which was probably the smallest status club on the campus Even though it's pretty vocal.
Rym: Yeah, they were real loud, but there weren't many of them.
Scott: Nope
Rym: and he's in the middle of the quarter mile yelling and screaming and handing out the socialist worker and he's like The war in Iraq blah blah blah because this is before the war in Iraq happened, you know back before everything went to shit and I was against the war.
Rym: I was against the war from the start.
Rym: but When this guy comes up to me and he's like the wars about oil blah blah blah blah blah I was just like I'm for the war.
Rym: He's like what blah blah I'm like cuz it'll probably make oil prices go down and the guy just exploded.
Rym: and then he every point he made I just made the stupidest Simplest counterpoint I could even when it was something I totally disagreed with and he couldn't deal with it.
Rym: He's just yelling and yelling and yelling and yelling and getting red at the face.
Rym: I just laughed and walked away.
Rym: It was the best thing ever.
Scott: I would have been like, you know, I'm for the war just because I'm against you.
Scott: No, I was against the war But because you're also against the war and I really don't want to end up a dirty hippie like you.
Rym: At one point I was like my dad works in the arms industry.
Rym: I'm gonna get a lot of money if this war happens.
Scott: Oh, that's great.
Rym: This our war is paying for my college.
Scott: awesome.
Rym: He was so mad.
Rym: It was great every day and a couple times I'd see him on campus and he'd see me and he'd narrow his eyes and that Newman here remembered you Like how to stand out?
Scott: Yeah a little bit a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, those guys are fun though.
Rym: Yeah, so Inspired by that GeekNights is going to officially endorse some candidates However, not many because we don't like most of the people running in the United States elections.
Scott: No, no, and we're only pretty much the elections.
Scott: this what's a week from its next Tuesday.
Scott: Yeah It it's only New York State people we have to vote for and you know our local representatives and we have I think one Person in the Federal House of Representatives to vote for.
Rym: and now to to all of our non US listeners.
Rym: I promise we'll keep this interesting and not go into boring detail.
Scott: Yeah I mean even people in the US.
Scott: if you don't live in New York and don't have the same candidates as we do It's not gonna be interesting to you at all.
Scott: What do you care?
Scott: who our governor is?
Scott: They have they're not governing you.
Scott: if you're living, California You have the govern ater.
Scott: whatever I like the govern ater he's alright But I'm you know, it's not as bad as some people make him out to be at least no, not at all.
Rym: I'm a supporter of the govern ater because he while I do disagree with him on points.
Rym: He is very much a Republican like the old Newt Gingrich days which while not great or a lot better than the current Republican day I don't know enough about him to say anymore.
Scott: But yeah, anyway, alright, so we're gonna talk about New York candidates But we're still gonna try to make it entertaining.
Rym: Yeah real quick Let's just get the names out of people.
Rym: We officially want to endorse as I guess journalists.
Rym: Alright, you know what?
Rym: I'll start cuz I got the easiest one.
Rym: This is probably the only candidate.
Rym: I'm actually behind.
Rym: Mm-hmm Elliot Spitzer and David Paterson are running for office governor and lieutenant governor.
Rym: Respectively and not only am I endorsing them but they are running.
Rym: they have been nominated by more than one party.
Rym: They're running as Democrats, but they're also running as the Independence Party Which is a party that I am pretty much.
Rym: It's the.
Rym: it's the political party in America founded by a guy who gave a lot of money to RIT Among other things.
Scott: I guess he got his money's worth.
Rym: he convinced us the party is the closest thing to my beliefs as to how government should be run if Any party in the United States far and away?
Rym: I mean, I'm very Libertarian party not at all because they do not agree.
Rym: I do not agree with them on many points Many points and I get this party is the closest thing to what I believe politically of anything.
Rym: not to say that I agree with them a hundred percent because I certainly don't.
Rym: but that's the closest thing and Because Elliot Spitzer and David Patterson are running in America.
Rym: You can be nominated by as many parties as Parties will not like.
Scott: let's say me and Rym started the GeekNights' political party, right?
Scott: Since we were a really small political party, we might not have a person in every disc.
Scott: Let's say we're only in New York political party, right?
Scott: New York has I don't know how many districts a whole lot of districts of voting.
Scott: let's say we don't have a Candidate for every single district of New York.
Scott: well in those districts, you know, we can either have a blank spot on the ballot or We can endorse say the Republican candidate.
Scott: then people have a choice They can vote for the candidate on the Republican line or they can vote for the candidate on the GeekNights' party line.
Rym: Yeah Now the benefit of this is in America.
Rym: if you get a certain percentage of the vote Then you are eligible for money from the government in the next set of elections.
Rym: Yeah, so let's say also basically get recognized as a real political party.
Scott: Yeah, so let's say Joe Blow is running for governor and we don't have a candidate for governor in our shitty little party.
Scott: So we endorse Joe Blow and Joe Blow wins because enough people vote for him But 25% of the people who voted for Joe Blow voted for him as a GeekNights' party member and not as a Republican.
Scott: We get mad moneys.
Scott: Yo, it's awesome.
Rym: Yeah, so Elliot Spitzer and David Patterson are running on the Democratic Party and the Independence Party.
Rym: So I officially endorse voting for these two men on the Independence Party.
Rym: line State is column C on the ballot.
Scott: I just want to talk about Elliot Spitzer for like a minute.
Scott: All right Is that basically Elliot Spitzer was until recent?
Scott: Well, he still is the Attorney General of New York State and as Attorney General he has done many things that are awesome.
Scott: He basically goes after all the people I think are assholes and tries to sue them as the state.
Scott: He sued a bunch of evil insurance guys.
Scott: He sued spammers.
Scott: He sued spyware guys all sorts of awesomeness and it you know, that's how I found out about him and he's way cool for it.
Scott: and I look at what he stands for and most of it's awesome.
Scott: and You know a lot of people say, uh, he's just doing that kind of stuff to get people to like him.
Rym: You know what if someone does good things because they want to be liked and then they keep doing good things because they keep wanting To be liked.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm saying is it doesn't matter his intent.
Scott: He's doing what I want and he's probably going to continue to do what I want.
Scott: I don't care if his intent is because the result will be pleasing to me.
Scott: and The only thing I disagree with Elliot Spitzer on is he is anti, you know, violent video game.
Scott: and While I don't want to vote for someone who's anti violent video game I think it'll be enough to just write him a letter because I if I agree with him on almost everything else I can let one thing slide.
Scott: Yeah This will be banned.
Rym: that's not gonna happen.
Scott: It's not like the other if the other candidate isn't exactly pro violent video game.
Rym: So we really need a pro violent video game candidate.
Scott: Yeah, dude The candidate goes up and he's like.
Scott: I think video games need to be gorier and bloodier with more sex and more guts.
Scott: This I got the name of the party already the not enough Gibbs.
Scott: Yeah Oh, I gotta say this right now.
Scott: I'm looking at the list of parties in New York State.
Rym: Now what I just wanted.
Rym: I'll I know what Scott's gonna say But I want to jump in real quick and point out that in America the name of your political party usually has Absolutely.
Rym: Fuck all to do with what your party stands for.
Scott: for example, the Constitution Party.
Rym: Oh God Don't God.
Scott: the Constitution Party has nothing to do with the Constitution.
Rym: the Constitution Party wants quote To their conservative blah blah blah.
Rym: They want to bring the quote biblical foundations of American jurisprudence.
Scott: Yeah, they should be the Bible Party, but no they are the Constitution Party.
Scott: why they call themselves that I don't know.
Scott: But anyway You know looking at the list of New York State parties this Republican Democratic Independence working families working families make sense.
Scott: libertarian green socialist workers socialist equality.
Scott: alright, alright, alright.
Scott: hit this one party that catches my eye.
Scott: and The abbreviation for the party is our th And it says here on the right side.
Scott: What does our th stand for?
Scott: it stands for rent is too high.
Scott: Ha if you think rent is too high you can vote for Jimmy McMillan for a New York State governor.
Scott: I don't think he's gonna win because you know what my rent isn't too high.
Rym: Maybe I'll vote for him Maybe I don't know.
Scott: No, I think that spitzer is better.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I would love to have lower rent But I'm not gonna vote for a guy whose only political stance is rent is too high.
Rym: Now the sad truth is I hate to say it but there's other than maybe kinky Friedman in Texas just because he's hilarious.
Rym: There's no one I support Anywhere, there's no one else I could endorse.
Rym: I could anti endorse a bunch of people but that list is long.
Scott: Yeah, there's only one person I want to specifically anti endorse and this is our person who is the representative of.
Scott: you Know us in New York where we live in New York State in the federal House of Representatives and that is Sue Kelly.
Scott: I looked back in the day when I moved to Beacon at you know, the voting record of all my congress people and senators and Sue Kelly everything she voted on like Every single thing.
Scott: I went looking at all the bills in the House of Representatives at the federal government in the United States.
Scott: She voted the opposite of what I would have voted on every single bill Every single one.
Scott: I would look at it and I would say yes, Sue Kelly voted.
Scott: No No, Sue Kelly voted.
Scott: Yes, every last one.
Scott: Now the Independence Party is supporting her and so is the Conservative Party in the Republican Party.
Scott: But god damn there's no way I'm voting for someone who votes the opposite of the way I do.
Scott: Yeah, the Democrat running is John Hall and I'll probably end up voting for him because he's the only other choice.
Scott: but even if I disagree with him on a lot of things which I'm sure I do I Know that he'll vote differently from the Republican Sue Kelly.
Scott: Well, I mean even he votes differently.
Scott: just once I'll agree with him more than I agree with Sue Kelly.
Rym: I spoke with John Hall very briefly a while ago really as he was around and I ran.
Rym: actually I Ran into a whole bunch of candidates over the past month just around New York City and in various places doing things Mm-hmm, and I ran into John Hall up here when he was doing something one day and he seems like an unassuming guy.
Rym: Yeah, he's one of his platform seems to be I was something to the effect of make the Bush administration accountable for what it's done, which is Definitely vague and not actually going to happen.
Rym: But yeah, this is definitely a lesser of two evils situation.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know about John Hall.
Scott: Slowly on her vote.
Rym: John Hall votes for one thing Differently from the way Sue Kelly would if I consider it a victory.
Scott: That's what I'm saying is is suke, you know, he Every single thing?
Scott: she voted the way.
Scott: I disagree with every last one.
Rym: So for all of you foreign listeners American elections are really kind of silly.
Rym: Yeah, we don't have but we don't have or anything good We don't have.
Rym: it's just a winner.
Scott: take the big elections aren't so silly because they get a lot of attention But everything that's not big in the public eye The big elections is all really silly and kind of fun.
Scott: and that's where the democratic process actually works.
Rym: Yeah, except that no one votes.
Scott: I know if more people voted it would work but but no cuz no one cares.
Scott: Oh, there's 29 districts in New York.
Scott: That's interesting.
Rym: That is interesting.
Rym: Yeah, I mean in general we could talk a bit about our actual political leanings I guess or we could just go to bed and start fresh next week.
Rym: cuz once again, we got a crazy weekend coming up.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know who I'm gonna vote for for our senator though You know what I had to say it.
Rym: but I'm pretty much not going to vote at all on Many of the positions that I can vote on because I simply don't agree with any of the candidates or can't find enough actual Information about him or I really don't care because none of them stand for me at all.
Rym: So it doesn't matter which one gets elected.
Rym: I'm not gonna endorse one with a vote.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not going to lend legitimacy.
Scott: I think there's like three positions where I'm just not gonna vote.
Rym: cuz here's the cool thing.
Rym: One of the things that a lot of members of the Independence Party are really pushing is that they want there to be very literally a none-of-the-above option where if you go and vote you can say I Do not want any of these people and if that wins then you have to do something to the election
Scott: But you to make a new election where none of the existing candidates can run again.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: That would be the way.
Rym: I mean you'd have to think out all the details of that.
Rym: But in general a lot of people say, you know You should vote no matter what but I say if you really don't agree with any of the candidates Don't vote for the lesser of two evils.
Rym: Just don't vote because not voting does say something.
Rym: It says you either don't care or aren't represented and the less people vote the less Legitimacy there is around the voting process which might force some people to take action.
Scott: Yes That's what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go in and the people I want I'm gonna vote for and when there's no one To choose from I just won't vote in that column for any of those people.
Scott: and then you know They'll see that though They'll freakin see that.
Scott: you know there was someone who went in and specifically voted for X Y & Z but didn't vote for any of the people for the position of Comptroller because they all suck unless we use d-bold machines.
Scott: Oh Pund yeah.
Scott: The other thing is that in the United States when you go into vote at the top of the voting machine on the ballot There are questions you can vote for.
Rym: well referendum reference got a little while ago was like we should talk about the questions.
Rym: I was like what the fuck are you talking about?
Scott: They phrase them as questions.
Scott: It's like, you know, do you want you know this to go into effect?
Scott: or do you think that you know?
Scott: This is right.
Scott: Yes or no?
Scott: And they're all yes or no.
Rym: the problem it varies state by state and city by city.
Rym: how these things work is in a lot Of places referendums are non-binding.
Rym: They're basically just a poll.
Scott: Yeah, but I always even if there's no one on the ballot I want to vote for I will go always go in and answer the questions Because you know if you get there's a little piece of paper you can pick up that gives you the full details of what you're Exactly doing with the questions and I will always have an opinion yes or no.
Scott: and that's where I can vote directly representing myself without Between.
Rym: I'm generally in more in favor of a more representative government and I generally dislike the idea of referendum.
Rym: Don't move to Oregon except on issue.
Rym: I know about Oregon Yeah, except on issues where it really matters or it really should be that way which aren't many.
Rym: I mean I'm of the mind that people should work with their state legislature for local issues or their local government and Vote and however in that and the local government represents them.
Rym: They elect Representatives to the United States federal House of Representatives, which represent them.
Rym: the people to the federal government the House of Representatives The door the state legislature or someone should then choose a senator though It could be okay if states have people choose them like they do now.
Rym: But the senators should be the representatives of the state to the federal government.
Rym: The senator should not be accountable to the people of the state.
Rym: They should be accountable to the state legislature like they used to be.
Scott: Yeah, it is a little bit that way.
Scott: I mean if you send a letter to your senator, you're almost always gonna get some crap form letter back.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is you send a letter to your representative.
Scott: It's a good chance.
Scott: They'll actually reply to you kind of.
Rym: Well, the thing is senators are a little more high-profile.
Rym: So as a result, there's a slightly lower incumbency rate there.
Rym: So as a result, you have a lot of senators who do things in their home states that don't need to be done Just to generate awareness to get votes when they should be working on actual real government business that doesn't involve their home state so much.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I mean my view is actually a lot more complicated than that But I would need a whole show just to lay the basics of what I believe.
Scott: Anyway, that's who GeekNights is voting for if you live where we live.
Scott: We hope you vote the same way.
Rym: Elliot spitzer is my man.
Rym: That's all I can say.
Scott: Yeah, but vote however you want.
Rym: We're not gonna tell you No, I'm telling you straight up vote for Elliot spitzer.
Scott: I'm telling you I would like it if you voted for Elliot spitzer Elliot.
Scott: I'm not going to hate you if you don't.
Rym: Oh No, okay.
Scott: I would just think you're stupid.
Rym: Well This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.