Rym: It's Wednesday May 10th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about free comic book day.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Apparently talking about all of e3 in one episode was more than Rym could handle.
Rym: Yeah, we also had technical limitations.
Rym: not really lipson doesn't like you uploading more than 50 megabyte file.
Scott: It wouldn't have been 50 megabyte.
Rym: It was 45 as it was all right.
Scott: all right anyway.
Scott: The Point is that Tomorrow we're going to complete our we coverage by I mean our e3 coverage by talking about the we and the Xbox and the other stuff.
Scott: Microsoft had to say yeah
Rym: Pretty much just the rest of Nintendo and Microsoft
Scott: And I guess that's a good thing actually because a lot of stuff happened with the Wii and Microsoft today Information that was available on the show floor that was not available at the press conferences But Sony not.
Scott: so much new news of the show floor.
Rym: the best news that came out since Sony did their thing is That someone said that the controller They demoed wasn't as shitty as other people had said.
Scott: it was well because people said it was shitty based on what they saw at The press conference, but upon actual use the accelerometers in the PlayStation 3 controller actually worked pretty well.
Rym: I still think it's a terrible idea, but that's beside the point.
Rym: It's a terrible idea.
Scott: That's well executed Yep, but that's the only News from Sony so we don't have to go back and update that but we are going to complete the e3 coverage tomorrow.
Scott: Today we're gonna talk about all the comics.
Scott: We got our free comic book day.
Rym: Yeah, well they were mostly terrible But we'll get to that we will.
Scott: that's the main bit.
Rym: All right, let's get.
Rym: some news is out of the way.
Scott: some news is Well all those anime people will be disappointed, but I do have some anime news.
Scott: So if you came to listen about anime and are disappointed because this comic books He's here one great in it of interesting information.
Scott: Samu Tezuka is the god of manga.
Scott: you know the Astro Boy guy who writes all the best manga ever.
Scott: of course He's dead, but well.
Rym: He didn't write Death Note.
Scott: No he didn't write death Unless he came back from the dead as a zombie, and he's actually the secret writer of Death Note.
Rym: You know I would put that as a non-zero probability except for the fact that Misa Misa exists.
Scott: Yeah, he definitely would not write a Misa Misa.
Rym: Oh he would but she would be different.
Scott: Yeah, anyway Apparently there were five of his manga not like full manga, but just you know comic works.
Scott: They weren't very long that were Recently discovered as in they were lost, but no one realized they were missing, but now they're like oh Here are some.
Scott: What happened was there was a US censorship unit from World War two and that censorship unit had gathered some?
Scott: ossamu tezuka mangas and Apparently every other copy of these mangas in the world was destroyed if there were any other copies at all.
Scott: and Someone who is looking through the Gordon W Prang collection at the University of Maryland Found some ossamu tezuka works and was like oh Newly discovered manga super awesome, and it is super awesome.
Rym: Are there scans of it available, or is it gonna be published?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think right now your best bet would be to go to the University of Maryland and go to the collection and check them out.
Rym: You know that's not that far away.
Scott: No, it's not really that we can.
Scott: we can stop by there on our way to Otakon.
Scott: Maybe we'll call them ahead of time or something you know.
Scott: it's in Baltimore or near its north of Baltimore?
Scott: Very it's like barely north of Baltimore.
Rym: doesn't matter if I drove all that way to Baltimore I'm not gonna be against driving another.
Rym: you know 20 minutes.
Scott: Yeah, let's see there was a six-frame strip called Tamishi girl in which a Subordinate uses his wits to fend off his Lord's violence way to spoil it.
Scott: there was a four-frame strip titled Yari Kirimasen Which it translates to I can't take it features a mannequin that gets embarrassed when someone peeks up the skirt.
Scott: Yeah, a 16 page manga called Hans to kin.
Scott: no common, okay?
Scott: And it doesn't say anything about that other than that translates to Hans and golden hair.
Scott: Yeah, and I don't know what the other ones are a link to the article.
Scott: you can read it yourself.
Rym: But if that's way cool, uh-huh I decided the non anime news.
Rym: It's a little old too, but there wasn't any interesting news other than e3 news today And I really want to save all of that like the revelation that pit is going to be in Smash Brothers.
Rym: Oh my god I've been waiting for that forever, but Alright, so someone made a fan video to battlefield 2. now This is a common thing.
Rym: people make all these sorts of music videos or stories to various games.
Rym: I remember seeing a particularly creepy one to cat girls from Final Fantasy 11.
Rym: God yeah, but I mean it's a cool thing.
Scott: things you see on YouTube every day.
Rym: Yeah, I mean people make them all the time, and they're not anything new.
Rym: the internet knows about them.
Rym: They're a done deal.
Rym: Someone made one.
Scott: you know about them.
Scott: Yeah, they've been things of the day.
Rym: often someone made one and It was somewhat anti-us.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: now the United States government and our wonderful intelligence agencies got a hold of this and thought hey It looks like the terrorists and al-qaeda and whatnot are making propaganda videos and distributing them to American youths via video games and the internet and To anyone on the internet who has half a clue.
Scott: It's obvious that no some guy just made this video because he has a battlefield 2 playing, dude Made a funny video using footage from battlefield 2.
Rym: in fact his name is Sonic jihad.
Scott: That's a good screen name right there.
Rym: now I just it amazes me that our government spends so much money on intelligence and Despite this they need to spend all this time and money tracking down propaganda.
Rym: That was actually just something some kid made in his spare time for fun.
Rym: That was obvious to everyone in the world except them I'm telling you.
Scott: This is what it is.
Scott: these people are so out of touch.
Scott: That's why they have a crazy spy network because we know everything.
Scott: there's nothing you don't know.
Scott: You don't have to do anything to know it.
Scott: But they are so out of touch that they can't know what we know because they don't know how to freakin use a computer And they know nothing about computers.
Rym: I'll know that there are things.
Rym: We don't know not much.
Rym: Okay, sorry Scott What sites exactly do say the AIDS virus bind to when they're trying to replicate?
Scott: I can go look that up on the internet.
Rym: all right Why do we get cancer?
Scott: I can go look that up on the internet - we don't know.
Rym: No one knows.
Scott: I can go look up some good answers.
Scott: Yeah, but you don't know I'll give you the same answer Some bio teacher gives.
Scott: I'll email them and get his answer.
Rym: Yeah, the answer will be mostly we don't know.
Scott: that's fine That's the answer.
Scott: I'll get from the internet.
Scott: Then the point is that that's why these people need a spy network.
Scott: for what's normal for us.
Scott: They need a spy network for that's how incompetent.
Scott: They are well.
Rym: It's like the gaming industry.
Rym: I mean the engage.
Rym: when it was announced by and large the internet said that's going to fail.
Rym: I'm a hundred percent sure that that product is going to fail.
Rym: It is obvious to me, and I will not even consider it further.
Rym: side talking then Nokia seemed to be completely unaware of this and went forward all the way and then it failed and they couldn't imagine why and they lost millions.
Scott: I got four words that are gonna end this discussion right now.
Scott: that shows people being clueless about how the internet works.
Scott: snakes on a plane.
Rym: See at first I thought snakes on a plane was gonna be there like a clue.
Rym: Maybe it was a clever marketing scheme, but I really think they were clueless, and they don't really don't know why it's popular.
Scott: They're really clueless.
Rym: I just it amazes me that people in power can be so clueless and yet still be in power.
Rym: Why don't they hire me to tell them?
Rym: What's up?
Scott: Yeah, you could replace the entire NSA just all on your own.
Rym: No, I need at least five or six guys to sit in various cities and tell me if anything weird is going on.
Scott: well They already have those guys.
Rym: Yeah, but they pay those guys a lot more than they need to pay me.
Rym: oh Well those guys don't know the internet like I do.
Scott: Well no they have a bunch of this room at the NSA.
Scott: somewhere where all these people sit on computers is listening to Terrorist chatter.
Rym: yeah, they probably listen to he talking to Emily in Japan on Skype.
Rym: Yeah Though actually I did see that the government is demanded to be able to wiretap Skype Whatever.
Rym: well they can go you can't encrypt on Skype.
Scott: Yeah, I'll use something else.
Rym: yeah I'm really waiting for someone to make a really ubiquitous good easy to use in PGP encrypted voice talk thing.
Scott: We'll make it.
Rym: someone made it a long time ago.
Rym: It's called called PGP phone.
Rym: It's just slow old and hard to find.
Scott: Yep, it also doesn't work, so well well We'll just add some PGP to gizmo or something and we'll be all set all right.
Rym: that was quick Which is good because my thing of the day has been trying to jump out of my mouth for the past 10 minutes.
Scott: Well it's a crazy thing of the day now.
Rym: anyone who follows my delicious priority saw it And it may be linked to from various places because it's it's quite hilarious.
Scott: But I really didn't expect what it was when I first saw it, and then I was like whoa.
Rym: It's a video That some roommates took where they snuck into a guy's bedroom and caught him Masturbating.
Scott: oh, that's no big deal to World of Warcraft.
Rym: whoa.
Rym: Some Dancer girl is dancing on the screen and he's typing something furiously while he's doing something else furiously and the camera guy slips in real quiet and Ahead of time like if you see on the camera like people like he's in there.
Rym: He's doing it right now.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: And then they slip in and you can tell the guy with the camera is just like on the verge of exploding.
Rym: And then the guy is Masturbating and he turns around because he hears the guy walk.
Scott: well No first the camera guy zooms in on the screen, and you see this dancing girl.
Rym: Yeah, you got to see the dancing girl Yeah, and then the guy turns around and just the look on his face followed by the what the fuck what the fuck?
Rym: And then the camera guy just starts laughing and it's hilarious.
Scott: There's really not much more to say.
Scott: don't worry you don't see any penises or anything but It's completely safe for work.
Rym: actually one if any of you out there if ever masturbated World of Warcraft because I Wouldn't be surprised if this was a not entirely uncommon phenomena.
Scott: Oh, I don't I'm not surprised at all.
Rym: um oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, something's fucking wrong with you If you're masturbating to World of Warcraft.
Scott: that could be who knows what on the other end.
Rym: now to his credit There's a slight chance that he has a wonderful girlfriend or boyfriend somewhere And they were merely engaging in some cyber play and World of Warcraft.
Scott: be a girlfriend.
Scott: He was looking at a dancing girl.
Rym: I never know you never know.
Scott: He's gay, and he wants his gay partner The dancing girl.
Rym: the dancing girl could have just been there.
Rym: it could have been all in the text.
Scott: it could have been.
Rym: However, I'll note that when you see the guy's reaction, and you see what the guy looks like one He looks like the kind of guy you'd catch doing this sort of thing.
Rym: mm-hmm We've known people like that mmm And - I don't think he has a girlfriend or a boyfriend.
Scott: I don't think so either.
Rym: so if you needed any other reason to not play World of Warcraft this video is it Because people like that are playing it with you.
Scott: Do you really want to play with them?
Scott: Or you might be thought of as one of those people in fact.
Scott: I probably think of you as one of those people.
Scott: So that's if you care what I think about you, which you shouldn't Because you shouldn't care what anyone thinks about you.
Rym: well you really shouldn't care what Scott thinks about you because he probably hates you.
Scott: I hate it Really hate people.
Scott: I just think they suck.
Rym: Yeah, you're not like Dave who hates people.
Scott: Yeah, I just think people suck.
Rym: Yeah, we got this friend Dave who hates everyone, but it's real straightforward about it.
Scott: Yeah I feel like I hate you.
Rym: Yeah like hey Rym.
Rym: I hate you.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, whatever these people think I hate them But really I just think they suck.
Rym: That's not much better.
Scott: It's a whole lot better.
Rym: It's so much.
Scott: Yeah, it's plenty better.
Rym: So can you top an ugly dude masturbating to World of Warcraft?
Rym: I can come close masturbating Sexually pleasuring himself in a furious way.
Rym: I mean he is going at it furiously.
Scott: I can get some furious Dancing.
Rym: yeah, it's got things pretty badass.
Rym: I watched it just now.
Scott: so this guy who's apparently a stand-up comedian I'm not sure what his name is He's obviously pretty good at stand-up comedy and He's good at dancing too.
Scott: I'm real good at dancing.
Scott: I mean he's not like a professional Broadway perfect dancer But he can dance better.
Scott: You know he can go to a club and dance and you wouldn't be like oh that guy can't dance.
Scott: He'd be like oh he can dance.
Rym: No.
Rym: I can decide know what most people who can dance don't know they can.
Rym: yeah I was at a dance or hanging out at Katsu counter their friend Bruce and heat We're dancing you know with all these people around and he turns to me.
Rym: He's like hey Rym Do I look okay am I like dancing okay?
Rym: And I look and he'd look.
Rym: he was dancing fine, but he like.
Rym: he actually was dancing pretty well But he was so worried that he looked stupid.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know how people worry about looking stupid dancing.
Scott: You just let it flow with the music.
Rym: God I should find you look stupid.
Scott: as long as it feels good everyone else gets the double deuce.
Rym: I should find some of those pictures of some of the dance parties We used to have at RIT because you feel all cool You know in the dark room, but you look like a dumbass especially when someone takes a picture with the flash.
Rym: Oh god Yeah, yeah outside of the darkness that guy with the glow sticks not so much.
Scott: That's the thing about dancing.
Scott: is that any still frame of the dance looks completely stupid, but the video is alright.
Scott: Yeah, dance is all about motion.
Scott: anyway It's a video.
Scott: this stand-up comedian dancing and what he does?
Scott: he does dances through history.
Scott: he starts with Elvis in the 50s and Moves to the twist and he gets into some disco action, you know, he does a whole bunch of you know hit songs Threw out from the 50s to today and he does the dances to them.
Scott: I think the best ones.
Rym: Let's see to me the Michael Jackson.
Scott: Michael Jackson was good.
Scott: The MC Hammer was real good.
Scott: Yeah, he did that thing the thing that hammer does.
Scott: Yeah The the Roboto followed by the breakdancing was good, man I can't do the robot at all.
Scott: I can kind of do the robot, but I can't do the breakdance Worm thing that he did.
Rym: I know a guy he works at IBM who got drunk and tried to do that almost broke his nose.
Rym: Oh, basically, he just he stood there.
Rym: He's like, hey, I'm gonna do the worm.
Rym: What?
Scott: He did do the get knocked down and some of the dances he does aren't really dances.
Scott: They're just stupid jokes.
Rym: Yeah, he makes fun of the Macarena.
Scott: Yeah Like when he cuz I knew as soon as this started and I realized what it was I was like is he gonna do the Macarena?
Scott: and then it came to the Macarena and he just gave the finger to the cat To the audience.
Rym: There's a tidbit when I was in middle school, right?
Rym: It was a long fuck time ago.
Rym: God, I feel old and We'd have we do science Olympiad and that's a really nerdy activity.
Rym: and then we'd have the big You know regional tournament and it was a huge region in our state where we did this.
Rym: so there would be like five or six hundred kids and they put us in a big gym and they'd have a dance before the award ceremony and It was all nerds who can't dance at all.
Rym: So it was mostly kids milling around talking about computers while music played.
Scott: I noticed wait I want is what the guy left out the electric slide.
Scott: I was disappointed.
Rym: Ah, I didn't even notice The electric slide But I remember they started trying to get everywhere together.
Rym: they teach us dances like this is the hustle?
Rym: this is you know whatever?
Rym: and Then they decided to teach everyone the Spanish hustle.
Rym: they called it and it was the Macarena Before it was popular and they just had this song and we learned this thing and it was kind of stupid.
Rym: And then years later this Macarena thing appeared.
Rym: I was like, that's just the Spanish hustle.
Rym: I've never heard anyone call it the Spanish hustle hustle anywhere except that stupid nerdy science.
Rym: Olympia dance when I was a little kid.
Rym: Yeah, so I've done that dance.
Rym: it's electric.
Scott: Yeah back when you know me and all my relatives and friends were being all the bar mitzvahed.
Scott: cuz we're all Jews.
Scott: The Macarena was big in those days.
Scott: So we were doing Macarena's.
Rym: now is so dry here.
Rym: Yeah He's polyps in the back of my hand.
Rym: Sorry, we just watched a bunch of South Park with Jew jokes.
Scott: Yeah Jews anyway It's electric All right, so today tell them that mp3.
Rym: That's a good idea.
Rym: Yeah, I might have it.
Rym: Whoo We'll have to look after.
Rym: we do the show people but before that we have to talk about free comic book day.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let's list all the comics that we got on a free comic book day.
Rym: Yeah, I'll know we're doing this partly because we haven't talked about comics in a while.
Scott: That's mostly because I can talk about a whole lot of comics that I've bought and Rym doesn't buy or read so many.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I thought I'd be commuting on the train doesn't look like I will be.
Rym: so I'm still reading my manga and my you Know books.
Scott: Yeah, I read my comic books and then my books.
Rym: Yeah, I got a lot of good books.
Rym: I just finished I doru which was actually awesome.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: We should talk about sci-fi books someday.
Scott: Alright so the we should probably talk them all about separately one book at a time.
Scott: Okay, the first comic that we got for free was from Dark Horse.
Scott: It's half Star Wars half Conan.
Rym: Yeah, well, we got all the like gold sponsor whatever is except I think one.
Scott: Yeah, we got all.
Scott: if you go to free comic book day calm and you click on the comics.
Scott: You'll notice that there are Gold sponsors and like silver sponsors there are people who paid more to diamond distributors and people who paid less.
Scott: Anyone who paid more.
Scott: we got their book except for Tokyo pop.
Rym: We didn't get Tokyo pop Yeah, mostly because the comic shop we went to was kind of scary.
Scott: Yeah, but it's pretty good.
Scott: They gave us a whole big fat thing.
Scott: Usually they let you take like four.
Rym: Yeah The thing is they look kind of pissed.
Rym: when we walked in we looked at every single piece of merchandise They had didn't buy anything.
Scott: took the free comics and left.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: It's free comic book day.
Scott: Screw you Yeah, you didn't pay for these comics.
Scott: They just gave them to you.
Rym: Well, all they had was crappy comics.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Anyway, and the only thing we got this top 100 trade paperbacks of all time But I think it's kind of crummy and it wasn't one of the gold sponsors.
Scott: I'm not gonna talk about it.
Rym: Yeah, though it does list.
Rym: watchman is number two.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the first comic is from Dark Horse.
Scott: It's half Star Wars half Conan.
Rym: then we got DC Justice League unlimited.
Scott: Then there's something from devil's do press who's a really good publisher, but it's GI Joe sigma six, which isn't God Donald Duck, which is kind of cool from gemstone.
Scott: Yeah, that's cool.
Scott: a Simpsons comic from Bongo Yep a Future Shock thing from image which contains like a whole bunch of different comics that are all somewhat related to future Stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I'll say right now.
Rym: They're all ass, but we'll get to that.
Scott: from IDW.
Scott: There's two transformers comics one regular one and one Beast Wars one.
Scott: And of course the cut the transformers comic that I'm interested in transformers evolutions.
Scott: They only have like a little preview of it in here Marvel x-men runaways, which is the x-men and the runaways together.
Scott: and there's some other stuff in here, too Which we'll talk about.
Rym: and of course Archie.
Scott: I've never read an Archie comic in my life.
Rym: Neither have I. this was the first one I ever ever ever ever ever read.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right, so The Star Wars from Dark Horse, it was pretty stereotypical predictable.
Rym: It was a lot like the Clone Wars cartoon.
Scott: I was gonna say it's almost exactly like the Clone Wars cartoons where you know The stormtroopers.
Scott: they don't say anything.
Scott: They just is quiet.
Scott: Star Wars action?
Rym: No, no dialogue lots of shooting and blasters and explosions and it's really I got to say I mean this stuff's all cool, but it's like it's just fan service for the Clone Wars.
Rym: There's nothing.
Rym: there's nothing to it.
Rym: It's not Star Wars.
Rym: It's just guys shooting robots.
Scott: Yeah, the thing about this is I guess it's mildly if you have ten seconds where you're not entertained You can spend your time reading this.
Scott: it'll.
Scott: it's a good filler, but Since it's not animated you really lose a lot because it's the exact same thing as the Clone Wars cartoon without the movement But it's all action.
Scott: So a lot is left up to the imagination, which is which is okay if you have a good imagination But at the same time it there's nothing really to make you Imagine.
Rym: it's drawn in style and I've seen other comics where they draw it like this where it's like It's based on something that has real people like it's based on something that has real actors in it.
Rym: So they draw the characters who are from whatever they're basing it on Really really accurately.
Rym: so you don't think like wait a minute.
Rym: That's not what obi-wan looks like But as a result, they seem to draw them just kind of a.
Scott: I Think the some of the drawings of like the stormtroopers and the equipment.
Rym: Oh, that's fine Yeah, they look pretty good.
Scott: And that's most of the comic.
Rym: So yeah, but look at the last page That's one panel is as a crappy obi-wan face in it and then a crappy Jango Fett.
Rym: Yeah Well, I just thought of it because the Firefly comic did the same thing.
Rym: good comic, but they really drew it Just kind of yeah, whatever.
Rym: as long as it looks like the characters doesn't matter how we actually draw it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right It's like about the Conan comic in the other half.
Rym: I actually kind of like the Conan.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what it was, but it seemed it was really generic the story but at the same time it wasn't too bad.
Scott: Yeah, the only thing that bothered me was all right.
Scott: if the wizard needed the spear Why the hell did he leave it downstairs all that time and go get it at the last minute?
Scott: Yeah that it was fine.
Rym: I mean slayers the anime.
Rym: to handle that the best in the first season where the evil guy has the thing he needs to finish His ritual and the what does he do?
Rym: He immediately fucking runs away and does his thing as soon as he can.
Scott: Yep, this didn't have that.
Rym: Plus it was kind of intellectually Void.
Rym: there's not much to Conan.
Rym: Well, he's not much to this Conan But I can see a nice subtle.
Rym: I mean look the the guy Who the Conan killed was so self-important and sure that he was right and sure that nothing could stop him that that was his downfall.
Rym: Yeah, so yeah, there's a little bit there but a little bit not much.
Scott: Yeah, all I can really say about this Conan is It wasn't painful to read.
Rym: You know It's really sad To say that about free comic book day that the best we can say about something so far is.
Rym: it wasn't painful to read.
Scott: Yeah, the art was actually pretty good as his nice sort of D&D look.
Scott: Yeah, which I don't mind.
Scott: It looks like the Monster Manual art only a little simpler.
Rym: Yeah, the new Monster Manual art, not the third edition third edition.
Scott: Yeah, and you know if I saw Conan, but I used to completely ignore Conan.
Scott: What did I care?
Scott: but now I guess if I see a Conan book in the comic shop I might pick it up and flip through it to see if it's interesting or more of the same.
Rym: All right, Justice League.
Rym: Now when I read it, it went from all right.
Rym: This is actually kind of good to.
Rym: this is complete shit over the course of one page worth of plot Alright, so this is Justice League Unlimited.
Scott: So it's not the real Justice League.
Scott: It's based on the cartoon show that you know, it looks just like the cartoon show.
Scott: So on the first page you got you know Like oh my god, crazy things are happening, but I don't even know who half the characters on this page are first off.
Scott: I mean it puts their names at the bottom of the page, but I Don't know.
Rym: Well, I know what their powers are.
Rym: I know who Batman, Wonder Woman, Superman and The Flash were.
Scott: That's all I knew.
Scott: I don't know who that white guy.
Scott: it says here He's Captain Adam and then it says Zatanna and Hawkgirl which are pretty easy to figure out which one was which I had seen Hawkgirl Before.
Scott: all right, but I didn't know what their powers were or anything.
Scott: It didn't explain it to me.
Scott: But oh god looks like a kid's comic.
Scott: So maybe the kids know.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: a lot of kids don't read comics and I guess if a kid watched the show they Would know it had the bolding The bolding of the words not as bad as some other comics have had it.
Rym: I consider the bolding to be a kind of cancer or a plague.
Scott: Well, I'm looking at some of the bolding on page two and it's not so bad.
Rym: That's like.
Scott: it makes a little bit of sense.
Rym: It makes more than page three.
Scott: It makes a little bit less sense.
Rym: It makes more sense than the bolding in any comic I've ever read ever.
Scott: All right But yeah The plot starts out where you're kind of wondering exactly what's going on like.
Scott: there's a nice setup and a little mystery You know, it's like alright what's going on here?
Rym: Yeah I mean, I hate superhero comics and it was enough for me to really want to know how this was gonna end Yep, and then at the end it was just silly.
Scott: Yeah, it was just the explanation was crap.
Rym: It was just deus ex machina crap.
Rym: Like the whole thing is we tested and we couldn't find the problem and then suddenly the villains appear and say ah Here is our plan and intricate text detail for everyone who couldn't figure it out.
Rym: Oh, there's a mystic thing that you couldn't detect
Scott: The thing that I really didn't like about it the thing that made it subpar was the fact that It didn't really matter what you could have replaced in all these characters with just like a stick figure of a different color like There was no personality to anyone.
Scott: Everyone was just a hero with the same personality.
Scott: only Batman had a slightly different Personality to him because he was the one who figured things out.
Scott: cuz he's Batman he figures things out.
Scott: He always figures out that the only difference between the characters other than that was their powers.
Scott: They didn't have a different personality.
Rym: They all had the same dialogue, but other than the magic girl, they didn't even use their powers.
Rym: They were just kind of there.
Scott: Yeah, there were these generic, you know when you have a story you have to be like, okay He's the angry guy and he's the sad guy.
Scott: and he you know The different personalities and different characters.
Scott: all the characters are the same personality.
Scott: We're heroes and we're gonna beat the bad guy.
Scott: that was all they had to him.
Rym: and Yeah, except for Batman Yeah, the only thing I got out of this and I got to say if I get my scanner to work or if I find An image online there's no page numbers But there's a Scooby-doo ad and the page before the Scooby-doo ad.
Rym: if I replace the text bubbles with different words I can make a very funny sexual joke.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it shows Superman standing in front of hot girl and then Wonder Woman appears and puts her hand on hot girl shoulder.
Scott: then hot girl turns around and looks at Wonder Woman like ooh, and then both Superman and Wonder Woman put their arms Hands on hot girl shoulder and in the fourth panel Batman gets this smirk.
Scott: I don't see him there.
Rym: He's got this little smirk his smile not even in the panel.
Scott: Yeah is where I don't see him.
Rym: Superman.
Scott: Oh, you said Batman.
Rym: I did I meant Superman.
Rym: Okay, Superman gets this little smirk.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: No, yeah Batman Oh, I do it in the last panel.
Scott: It totally looks like Wonder Woman has her hand on hot girls boob.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so yeah, that's Justice League.
Rym: That's what I got out of that.
Scott: All right GI Joe's Sigma six is crap.
Scott: see our.
Scott: Actually, this one had an advantage over the other comics and that the entire comic book was pretty much one story with very few ads.
Scott: That's the advantage.
Scott: The art looked like a TV show a kids cartoon.
Scott: the plot went like a kids cartoon and I think this thing is just here to sell toys.
Rym: Yeah, the worst thing is it fell in that stupid trap of all.
Rym: right We're gonna make all the bad guys robots.
Rym: that way we can kill them in cool ways But we don't get in trouble for killing people in a kid's thing.
Scott: I didn't even know that didn't bother me.
Scott: the things that bothered me were a the Sharks.
Scott: Yeah B This one guy.
Scott: He's not his name isn't GI?
Scott: Joe?
Scott: And he makes jokes about these little paper umbrellas like three times which aren't funny.
Scott: The bad guy.
Scott: there's only one Cobra bad guy Destro.
Scott: Yeah, and he's totally lame like Like.
Scott: until the last page he wasn't super lame.
Scott: But at the end he has like this funny face and he's like I need a vacation.
Scott: That's not something a villain says.
Rym: what the hell was he control?
Rym: He has like a PSP to control the robot shark things And it has a silly.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, Joe has this wicked awesome Sigma suit and Destro has a PSP to control some sharks.
Rym: It just wasn't good.
Scott: No, I guess this is just for kids who like the modern GI Joe toys selling TV show.
Rym: I didn't even like the old GI Joe.
Scott: The only GI Joe that's good is the movie GI Joe that I like is the one that has a million GI Joe guys like sergeant slaughter mostly and Cobra has a million guys like the guy with the gold head and Cobra commander and whatnot.
Rym: Don't forget the frickin movie.
Scott: Yeah, we should watch that Million blue lasers and a million green lasers shooting back and forth, but no one actually gets hit and dies.
Rym: Yeah, I never liked it.
Scott: things explode.
Rym: I never liked it when they had the ones where it's like here.
Rym: these three GI Joe's are gonna go on a crazy mission together All right now getting to probably one of the best comics in the lot Donald Duck, it's real old-school and real clever.
Scott: Yeah, it has three different Donald Duck stories in it.
Scott: They're mostly Huey Dewey and Louie stories, which is even better than Donald Duck stories Yep.
Rym: Now they're really really old-school.
Rym: That's the only way I can describe it.
Scott: Yeah The first one is Huey Dewey and Louie skip school and crazy stuff happens and they almost get caught by Donald like ten times And it's it goes like a Looney Tune or an old Donald Duck cartoon.
Rym: The only weird thing about it is that the writing it's Very I guess good in terms of the fact that they talk like normal human beings Which doesn't seem to happen in most comics.
Scott: Yeah, I think the the duck voices are.
Scott: they don't even have to put the duck voice in the writing like you have it in Your head because you see who's talking.
Rym: It's just it's old-school.
Rym: again is the only way I can describe this.
Scott: the art looks just like a duck tales cartoon, you know, even though I think the Donald's little sailor suit is the old-school one at the new school one.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, it's just generally Typical and humorous and I mean I laughed and I'm not a little kid.
Rym: I enjoyed it.
Rym: I like the cartoons more I guess but I grew up.
Scott: The thing is this isn't the best Donald Duck ever now, but it's still pretty good It's at least compared to this other stuff we got in this pile.
Rym: Yeah, though I got this hankering suddenly to watch all the old Donald Ducks.
Scott: Yeah, I really like the last story with the caveman who was like uncle Scrooge.
Scott: Yeah, that was good Especially when it's like oh look they made a funny about uncle Scrooge.
Scott: All right Bongo the Simpsons, yeah, I don't know why they called it.
Scott: I guess the publisher is Bongo, but they said Bongo comics free-for-all.
Rym: now I have somewhere like all the original Simpsons comics from when the first one was released.
Rym: Mm-hmm and They pretty much as far as I can tell never changed in quality at all.
Rym: They're the exact same level of humor and quality now that they were way back.
Rym: If you're really really really like the Simpsons then yeah, all this taught us is that The Simpsons I mean the writing.
Rym: if you close your eyes you read this comic and then you pretend you can't see it and you Imagine it being acted out in your head.
Rym: It's kind of funny.
Rym: It's like current Simpsons season.
Scott: funny Yeah, I mean the first story is obviously with comic book guy and he becomes a strong dude and instead of a weak-ass lame comic book guy and you know Nelson beat someone up and says haha.
Rym: and But without comic book Joe without the animation and the comedic timing and the voices It's just.
Rym: it's not that funny.
Rym: It's just kind of lame.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of the jokes are timing related Although I did laugh when I saw the Springfield tire yard on fire next to the Opera House.
Scott: That was good.
Rym: The only part I really laughed was when they have it early on when they have that long bit that basically just makes fun of comic nerds.
Scott: But that's what comic book guy does and I'm giving out a free comic book on comic book day.
Scott: The way to appeal to the people reading it is to make comic jokes that they'll laugh at more.
Scott: It's like penny arcade you give it to video game people and they laugh.
Scott: So you make a comic joke and you give it to comic people and they laugh and that way maybe they'll buy Simpsons comics.
Rym: I guess this just reminded me a lot of like the old Beavis and Butthead comic and just those generally not great Comics that are based on TV or cartoons.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah in the middle There was a bit with Bender.
Scott: that was kind of funny because I like Bender a lot.
Scott: if it hadn't been It seemed like a forced bender.
Scott: that was the problem.
Scott: if it wasn't the true Benderness you can't force bender.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they drew Bender and they forced Benderness out of him to make him, you know, and it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't natural.
Scott: And then let's see if the last story was about Homer was a superhero named pie man.
Rym: No, the last one was with nuclear power man and iron foot.
Scott: Oh Well, there's Homer being the pie man Which I guess it was.
Rym: it wasn't really funny.
Rym: Not at all.
Scott: It was just a Simpsons story with no humor whatsoever.
Rym: The last story was even less funny.
Scott: Well the last story I think I liked.
Scott: how discos do is the bad guy?
Rym: Yeah, that's all it's got going.
Scott: they made a village people joke And that was that.
Scott: Alright, whatever Future shock I wouldn't buy Simpsons comics if I were.
Rym: you know We should go through each of the comics and we should go through.
Scott: each of the comics is one of them I think is better than the others.
Rym: All right Fear agent.
Rym: I have no idea what's going on.
Scott: I have no idea what the hell's going on either.
Rym: Don't ask me It's really generically drawn.
Rym: There's something about a giant brain and the future.
Rym: They throw you into the middle of the story and then they take you out before the end.
Scott: it's like you get.
Scott: let's see one two three four pages of Where you get like this hint of what could possibly be going on, I don't know what this comics about.
Scott: It just forget.
Rym: the last line is you you're from the future one in which you murder me.
Scott: oh, that's right.
Scott: this guy's like arguing with an evil brain alien and The.
Scott: the brain alien figures out that this guy is a time traveler or no.
Scott: It figures out that this guy is going to kill the brain in the future.
Scott: Whatever it's just a crazy plot and you don't get enough of it to know whether you like it or not, but it's just crazy.
Rym: Now godland.
Scott: All right before even knowing what the story is in godland.
Scott: Look at this craziness.
Scott: He had like these really weird creatures fighting very superhero style fighting.
Scott: Yeah, but they're the weirdest creatures.
Scott: I can't know what the hell they are.
Scott: They're supposed to be gods.
Scott: Is that the story?
Rym: why it's called godland, but then it turns into a completely different comic about this girl.
Rym: Yeah, who's in a spaceship that is hurtling out of control or something?
Rym: And then it does the.
Rym: I want.
Rym: I don't want to use the pretentious word I hate that word to describe things like this.
Rym: But it goes into one of those comic book Crapfests where they have a lot of descriptive text that's supposed to sound literate and meaningful and cool, but it's just dumb.
Scott: But in her mind's eye the unique awareness of her soul.
Scott: She sees everything.
Rym: Yeah the fucking bowling Okay, the steel beast she rides constructed by the sweat-soaked hands of Earth.
Rym: men lurches once arcs wide and finally The next one.
Scott: Yeah, no, the next one is invincible, which I think is I guess the better than the other things in here.
Rym: It looks like it's supposed to be silly.
Scott: Yeah, it looks sort of like Hitchhiker's guide.
Rym: Maybe yeah, but it also has this hint of Dragon Ball.
Scott: It does have a hint of Dragon Ball, but I don't see any fighting in it.
Rym: yet They keep talking about like power levels.
Scott: Well, I think they're just saying you know how strong this guy is because they made him super strong.
Scott: I think it's a story about you know aliens and people from different races and how there's one guy and he's named Invincible and maybe he's an alien or something and he's really strong and he's a superhero.
Scott: I Don't know but there's a Cyclops alien.
Scott: That's kind of silly.
Rym: Yeah, the guy takes his beard off - yeah, I don't know why because I am a vulture might and he takes the beard off Like that's supposed to mean something to me.
Scott: Yeah, I Guess it means something if you read the whole comic.
Scott: But if you don't know what a vulture might is and you don't know why taking your beard off I don't know how they're supposed to make you want to read this comic with something like that.
Rym: All right noble causes.
Rym: I got nothing to say about.
Rym: it's just so generic.
Scott: Yeah, I Completely agree.
Rym: generic superheroes.
Scott: It's there's a guy.
Scott: He's a superhero.
Scott: There's a military.
Scott: They're fighting.
Scott: they call in the bad guys to stop the good superhero from doing bad.
Scott: But really, you know in the end the good superhero is really doing good.
Scott: The government just thinks he's doing bad and it's just obvious and cliche.
Scott: All right, Savage Dragon, this is like an old comic that a lot of people like.
Scott: I've never read it any of it before and from these four pages I'm probably never gonna read any of it anymore.
Rym: Anyway, I'm not really sure what it's about.
Scott: It's about this green guy who's the Savage Dragon.
Rym: apparently has this girlfriend who doesn't trust it.
Scott: He seems like a lone Ninja Turtle.
Scott: Yeah, that's what he is.
Scott: He's a Ninja Turtle solo.
Rym: Well, he's got that little thingy like Dr.
Rym: Zoidberg.
Rym: does you mean a thin now, but they call it a thingy.
Rym: Okay, that's fine in fear trauma at least.
Scott: yeah, it seems like a comic about you know, a guy who's a green dragon creature and he's kind of silly and he has some plot behind him and Stuff happens to him, I guess.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway Shadowhawk Actually, I don't know Wasn't what I might have.
Scott: Shadowhawk number one?
Scott: I'm not sure.
Rym: wasn't the joke in Shadowhawk a similar joke to something that happened in gravity?
Scott: Yeah, it's the exact joke that happened in gravity actually.
Rym: so what the hell?
Scott: yeah?
Scott: Did this guy read gravity and steal the joke?
Scott: basically the novice superhero gets tricked into carjacking For someone else.
Scott: it happened in the gravity comic where it was funny because I'd seen it before.
Scott: it wasn't funny.
Scott: It's just a novice superhero sucks.
Scott: He looks pretty cool.
Scott: I got to say that with a shiny helmet.
Scott: If I was super hero I wouldn't mind that costume.
Rym: yeah, but I I don't know what to think of this I.
Scott: It's such a generic.
Scott: Very it's like a short skit.
Scott: You can't really tell what Shadowhawk is about or anything based on this.
Scott: All you can tell is it's a superhero comic about a novice superhero and that's what he looks like.
Scott: That's all you can tell.
Scott: you don't really know what his powers are except for maybe acrobatics, I guess.
Rym: Spawn.
Scott: Yeah, you know I never read a spawn comic ever until now.
Rym: It's really just kind of boring and trite I Don't know.
Scott: It's like spawn is there.
Scott: He's a scary dude spawn.
Scott: You know that you know the spawns a scary dude.
Rym: But then they have this.
Rym: you know this thing about granny and this little kid and oh spawn is an angel and obviously Some sort of metaphor symbolism that probably makes more sense if you know what the hell's going on.
Scott: Yeah, I think all this four pages tells me is that spawn is a scary.
Scott: scary.
Scott: scary, dude, but really he's good But he's really scary, but he's good not bad.
Rym: Yeah, once it wasn't really enough to say anything about spawn.
Scott: nope other than he's a scary dude who's actually good?
Rym: Now the last one which played never actually read any of it, but I know what it is.
Rym: in fact I made fun of it in the forum a little while ago Because I've seen it the covers of it and all these comic shops, and it's I lump it in with lady death.
Rym: It's a comic that on the cover There's a mostly naked woman with large breasts and tiny bits of something covering her naughty bits.
Scott: I knew nothing about which blade but apparently the witch blade is this weapon thing that kind of Attaches to your body or something and this girl had it, but then she lost it to this other girl.
Rym: And that's that the cover of every one of them is just a mostly naked woman wearing this thing.
Scott: Yep, so And not not much really happens here other than you find out that there's a girl And she had a thing called the witch blade which was a dangerous weapon and now someone else has it.
Scott: dumb dumb dumb.
Scott: That's all you find out.
Rym: Yeah, there really wasn't anything worth reading in that whole thing.
Scott: We only spent a lot of time talking about this because it had freaking a whole bunch of four-page stories in it.
Rym: All right Transformers we can talk a little bit about that.
Rym: I mean here.
Rym: We got what bumblebee?
Scott: Alright first of all and the inside of the the opening cover.
Scott: There's a picture from Transformers generations.
Scott: They're just.
Scott: that's what I want to read.
Scott: That's real transformers.
Scott: look at that.
Scott: see that giant sound wave.
Rym: Yeah, but they put this text on it.
Rym: that isn't from it.
Rym: Yeah, it's like hey read Transformers comics.
Scott: If the Transformers comics looks like that I'm gonna buy those ones transformers generations.
Rym: I can remember generations Yeah, but no we don't get that.
Scott: we don't get transformers generation.
Rym: We get infiltration infiltration Which it's drawn.
Rym: it looks like it's in that style that like every new comic is in.
Scott: it looks like shiny transformers to me.
Scott: Yeah, it's got this orange haze over a lot of it, but that's because they're in the yellow transformership.
Rym: I think it's hard to tell what's going on.
Rym: There's a lot of talking.
Scott: it seems that the transfer the Autobots are having an argument over whether someone was supposed to do something and it's it's.
Scott: it's looks like It could be just any generic argument between military guys over.
Scott: you shouldn't have done that.
Scott: you should have done this.
Scott: you're not following the Military rules whatnot?
Rym: yeah like it has nothing to do with transformers.
Scott: That's the thing that bothered me.
Scott: if you're gonna make a Transformers comic you need to have Transforming and flying and fighting Decepticons.
Scott: this has none of those things.
Scott: this could have been any military dudes.
Scott: They just put transformers in their place.
Scott: They don't even transform what the hell and then they give you a nice what the fuck at the end and then at the end They're like here the Decepticons doing evil.
Scott: That's a duh.
Rym: Now it just gets better because the other half of this is Beast Wars.
Rym: Great Beast Wars has the worst bolding I've ever seen.
Rym: it's got a terminal case of bolding.
Rym: really it bolds freaking every other word.
Rym: Randomly here's.
Rym: here's a text bubble where every word in it is bold except one.
Scott: Between optimus primals maximals and Megatron's Predacons.
Scott: More and more Predacon avatars arise to swell Megatron's ranks their former allegiance forgotten.
Rym: There are so many escalates there are so many made-up words and just crap.
Scott: in Beast Wars Here's the worst one his mission isolate and contain the renegade.
Rym: Oh and don't forget the crap We remain cronally displaced by one or two nano clicks.
Scott: Yeah You know I didn't like Beast Wars when I saw one episode of the TV show back in the day And this makes me dislike Beast Wars even more.
Scott: It's like Seems.
Scott: the only reason they ever made Beast Wars is some kids don't like cars and planes.
Scott: They might like animals.
Scott: so they made transforming animals for so they can sell to those other kids.
Rym: Yeah, all right, so we got this X-Men runaways.
Rym: well.
Scott: No in the middle of this comic though.
Scott: I want to.
Rym: oh There's something in there.
Scott: Oh there were actually two other transformers.
Scott: things in here.
Rym: There's I tossed this one away.
Scott: Oh this transformers storm bringer in the middle here Which actually looks like more of a real transformer store you got like a group of Autobots going to Cybertron Which has been long abandoned.
Scott: so this seems like a continuation like actually in the Transformers storyline but far in the future from any transformers that I've ever seen.
Scott: and Yes, what's his name?
Scott: What's the guy's name Sunfire?
Scott: I think I don't fire.
Scott: Yeah, jet fire the giant Valkyrie guy.
Scott: He's there which is a plus for Scott and then he couldn't even remember his name.
Scott: Yeah, I know what he looks like.
Scott: and then there are two pages of a preview of Transformers evolutions, which I don't know how good a comic it's gonna be but it has steampunk style transformers That's worth buying.
Scott: one issue right there.
Rym: Yep, basically anything that has steampunk air pirates or pirates in it We'll probably give it a chance got bumblebee, and it looks like he transformed.
Scott: It looks like Transformers plus kitchen core.
Scott: that's exactly what this is in visual Visual styling.
Scott: so I might get one issue with that.
Scott: I got one issue of the infiltration.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Scott: maybe I have an issue of some transformers by these guys.
Scott: I don't know which one it is, but I didn't have.
Scott: is he didn't buy any more?
Rym: All right x-men runaways.
Scott: Well, I read runaways and I read x-men when I was a kid, but not recently.
Scott: But I read runaways.
Scott: at least the first five trade paperbacks and runaways is really really good.
Scott: You should read it now.
Rym: I hadn't read it.
Rym: All I read was this and from this it looked like runaways is crap.
Scott: Well, it's this is written by the same guy who wrote runaways, but it's sort of like this 10 page Short story meant to introduce you into I don't know it didn't introduce you media anything.
Rym: it introduced all these normal dudes Who were actually mutants.
Rym: and then the x-men came and then they fought and only one of them's a mutant.
Rym: But they all had powers or some their powers.
Scott: Yeah, but they only one of those a mutant whatever.
Rym: they all had powers.
Scott: There was nothing to it as they actually what some of them don't have so many powers.
Rym: They still held the x-men off.
Scott: Yeah, they did.
Scott: they they sure did.
Rym: and the one thing that bothered me is the way it was drawn Wolverine.
Rym: Whenever you see him, his mouth is wide open with these big teeth and he's snowed.
Rym: Oh, yeah It totally bugs the hell out of me like there's two panels where there are two different panels on the same page Where he has the exact same expression on his face, even though his body is in a different position.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: and it's like why does kitty pride have a dragon?
Scott: and why all right?
Rym: I was about to say the only saving grace of this was that one kitty pride is in it because I kitty pride is awesome Yeah, and two kitty pride has a frickin dragon and that's awesome.
Rym: I don't know why she has a dragon I don't know, but I like the dragon.
Rym: He's cute.
Scott: Yeah, I think this is just written because it's so short.
Scott: The guy just kind of wrote it really quick.
Rym: Like yeah, it's good enough It has a dinosaur in it.
Scott: The dinosaur is actually part of runaways and it's why it's not that stupid Alright.
Rym: Yeah, they drew the Beast a lot like a monkey.
Scott: Yeah, the Beast looks sort of like a monkey.
Rym: seriously the only I Runaways, it better be damn good because runaways is damn good.
Scott: This is nothing like runaways.
Rym: So why is this called run away?
Scott: because it has those characters.
Rym: those characters are a runaways.
Rym: Tell me they're different.
Scott: Those are the runaways.
Rym: Tell me they they have different personalities or something.
Scott: Well here they don't seem to have personalities And runaways they do.
Rym: they just each one of them whips off a one-liner.
Scott: Yeah, that's about it.
Rym: But once again two pluses kitty pride.
Rym: and kitty pride has a dragon All right on her shoulder.
Scott: after it comes Franklin Richards, which actually is pretty good.
Rym: It was alright I wasn't really.
Scott: I thought it was really funny.
Rym: I Really didn't know now wasn't anything special or new or interesting.
Scott: I thought it was funny and cute like a little.
Scott: you know that You know a little comic where you see the little kid and you imagine stuff.
Rym: and then yeah It just didn't make me chuckle at all.
Scott: yeah, it wasn't chuckle like haha, that's hilarious like simply good Simpsons.
Rym: I didn't even crack a smile.
Rym: I just read it and then I kept going.
Rym: yeah, I don't know I just didn't like it.
Scott: I think it's cute.
Scott: Especially since it's like.
Scott: you know they draw a guy and obviously dr.
Scott: Doom, but it's not.
Scott: It's like haha.
Scott: We're making fun of ourselves.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I don't even notice that I don't read comics.
Scott: I don't know any of those people come on you look on like the last page of it And it's like okay.
Scott: There's the Hulk and this Captain America, and there's a guy who looks like Batman, and this is generic girl.
Rym: Yeah, dr.
Scott: Doom is all tied up.
Scott: Whatever, did you read the Marvel adventures Avengers?
Rym: Civil War?
Scott: No, no, no just turn go to Freddy.
Scott: Oh, that's the SN ad.
Scott: turn the page.
Rym: yeah I did that.
Rym: that was all right for a second Because I don't know what's going on.
Scott: Civil War is an ad.
Rym: I was sky I was skimming this and The first thing I thought on the second page of all the third page of it is why is spider-man a tiny little dude?
Rym: Did he get transformed?
Rym: and then I read the text is like oh, that's a giant okay?
Scott: Yeah, giant girl I don't know about giant girl.
Scott: Don't ask me.
Scott: But yeah Marvel adventures comics.
Scott: whenever you go to the comic store if you go to the comic store And you see something like spider-man adventures or cats in America adventures Those aren't read those aren't quote.
Scott: real Comics that are.
Scott: you know in the real story that all the comics are in.
Rym: so they're not canon.
Scott: yeah They're like separate.
Scott: You know story kids comics type things and often They're actually a lot better than the real comics because they're just telling good stories or Attempting to just tell good stories with the characters and not make some giant continuity laden crap.
Rym: the only good thing about this is that spider-man and the giant girl talk about pirates and Spider-man has a pirate sword that he's made out of his webs that he's carrying.
Scott: Oh, I didn't even notice that.
Rym: oh my god That's the only thing I got out of this.
Scott: That's awesome.
Rym: It's right there.
Rym: He's holding it.
Rym: He's like a vast matey no cannons blah blah blah.
Scott: That's why I kind of like spider-man comics more than other superheroes because while most of the comic is the same as any other Superhero comic spider-man is constantly making wisecracks and jokes and all that kind of shit.
Scott: Deadpool is the same way Deadpool.
Scott: You know he just constantly saying assholish things and whatnot.
Rym: No, I actually the ultimate spider-man saga thing was kind of interesting.
Scott: Oh, did you read it?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: I read it.
Scott: all it does is summarize everything that's happened in ultimate spider-man So that if you decide you want to read ultimate spider-man you're now caught up so you can buy the latest issue.
Rym: I don't know how good the comic is but the summary made it sound kind of good I guess.
Scott: well because the ultimate comics from Marvel.
Scott: what they did is they said all right a lot of people don't know what the Hell's going on in the real Marvel comics.
Scott: We're gonna create a whole separate You know universe with its own separate continuity, and we're just gonna call the ultimate universe.
Scott: And they started over you know basically from scratch and just called everything ultimate And you'll notice if you know the real original spider-man story that this one is crook slightly different.
Scott: Yeah, like in the original spider-man.
Scott: It's mostly this is more like what happened in the movie and less like what happened originally.
Rym: You know I do note that once again kitty pride.
Scott: Yeah, really where all right?
Scott: Yeah, that was kind of weird cuz I like kitty pride.
Scott: Let me go Let you go, but the thing is is that the original spider-man story is spider-man goes out with Gwen Stacy.
Scott: He fails to save her she dies spider-man goes out with Mary Jane.
Scott: the end.
Scott: This one seems to be like spider-man and Mary Jane.
Rym: then Gwen Stacy shows up later And then there's conflict and then she gets axed and then spider-man dumps Mary Jane, and yeah now he's with kitty pride.
Scott: Yeah, I guess that's what happens in the ultimate universe.
Rym: I'm fine with that whatever.
Scott: Yeah The other thing is in the real Marvel comic spider-man's old now, so here's a chance to read spider-man when he's young again.
Scott: I guess all right.
Rym: last and least Archie is the most bland comic I've ever seen.
Scott: well at least Archie wasn't painful Like the other comics.
Scott: it was just so bland and plain and all like unoffensive.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's a perfect word for this is the most it's like.
Scott: leave it to Beaver the comic.
Rym: I Don't know who could read this and actually be amused by it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know who would pay money and like be a fan of these and want to read them.
Rym: I'm pretty sure by reading what I just read I've gotten every possible joke I could get out of Archie except I either wasn't a joke about Jughead eating hamburgers.
Scott: Oh wait Yes, there was the thing that really bothered me about this is how like they trick you out with bullshit.
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: They have this like?
Rym: Oh?
Rym: There's a big change.
Rym: Archie's leaving town.
Scott: Oh, no, no, no.
Rym: then at the end They're like never mind.
Scott: in the middle like Archie runs into Sabrina the Teenage Witch.
Scott: But really it's just a two-page ad for their Archie comics.
Scott: Archie comics is a publisher And they happen to print Archie comics among other comics.
Scott: So they also publish a Sabrina the Teenage Witch comic which is drawn in a manga style.
Scott: so in the middle of this Archie story Archie runs into Sabrina the Teenage Witch and acts like She's his friend and is like hey and then it's an ad for the Sabrina comic and then the next page is an ad for the Josie and the pussycats comic and Then a few pages in you've got an ad for some other comic And Betty and Veronica, which is a separate comic.
Scott: I guess It's like they just run through all their cut you know Yeah, and I gotta say then there's the actual ad for Sabrina.
Rym: Wow like they must have hired someone and told them try to rip off manga, but do it shittily.
Scott: I think they just the cat's cute.
Rym: Yeah, the cat is cute, but it's cute in a very like forced way.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they hired probably some like college or high school person who could draw manga.
Scott: and No, they drew some Sabrina the Teenage Witch comics that look like manga.
Scott: That's not what.
Scott: that's not what sells manga.
Scott: They're stupid.
Scott: They still don't get it.
Rym: Yeah, you know what sells manga having stories like Death Note.
Scott: Yeah, that's what sells them.
Rym: I can't wait to hear what those comic geeks have to say about death.
Scott: one of them is already like woohoo Man.
Rym: you got to post in their forums.
Rym: man.
Rym: now you got to read sanctuary.
Scott: Yeah, thanks is.
Scott: the problem is not everyone can get sanctuary, so it's hard to get people to read it.
Scott: It's much easier to say hey read something like monster read you know and Akira is too expensive.
Scott: so it's hard to get people to read that and Phoenix isn't easily available even though it's in print so it's hard to give people to read that.
Scott: yeah you know it's like all the great manga because they print the shoujo manga like nothing but The older really good manga they don't print so much of so it's really hard to get more people to read it.
Scott: The other thing is manga is starting to even out where they're really good.
Scott: Manga is selling more and more titles and the crap manga is selling less and less type.
Rym: You know copies Yeah, we'll see how much Cantarella sells.
Scott: Yeah So a manga.
Scott: it's getting to the point where manga like FMA and Death Note our chart and fruits basket are starting to sell Way more copies than they used to.
Scott: like bestseller list copy yeah But Tokyo pop random shoujo is selling fewer copies, so it's becoming less worth it to do that.
Scott: So now people are probably gonna be start getting more discriminative about what manga they license and publish Trying to only sell you know publish manga that are really good not just any old crap because it's gonna sell enough.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I know Tokyo pop does a lot of market research because they they seem to see what is popular at conventions and go With that.
Scott: yep, but Viz seems to be really pooning everyone.
Scott: I mean you know I looked at it for a while, and it was like in the original days.
Scott: It was Viz and then Tokyo pop came and blew everyone away.
Rym: Well it seems like whenever the Tokyo pop people are doing something at a con The only people who are reacting to what they're doing are they screechy?
Rym: Fan girls mm-hmm, so that's I wonder if it's like this cycle where the people they talk to her fangirls And then the research they get back from them is fangirl stuff And then they make fangirl stuff, and it just it's a feedback loop.
Scott: I guess I don't know.
Rym: I Maybe why don't we ask him we could yeah, Oh believe me when Otakon comes.
Rym: They'll be interviews.
Scott: Yeah, like Tokyo pop should really I Mean?
Scott: they need to go out and figure.
Scott: I could tell them what the popular manga is.
Scott: they should bring over What.
Scott: what's the the best anime right now?
Scott: Right now is there an ergo proxy manga.
Scott: I have no idea they can get the mushishi manga that would freakin sell.
Scott: yeah I know that's been licensed or not.
Scott: whether manga could they go grab that would sell big.
Rym: I really don't know.
Rym: that's the problem.
Rym: I can tell you I know anime left and right I don't know manga anymore because all the manga that I thought oh that manga is awesome I've got or read or I'm planning to read already.
Rym: Yeah, or I can't get it Like the end of Death Note.
Scott: Yeah, yeah It's coming out fast enough.
Scott: the real problem with manga is that you know the the American publisher eventually catches up with a Japanese Publisher and then you're stuck waiting forever to get the next volume.
Scott: It's sort of annoying.
Rym: Yeah, unless you just wait and then read the American releases Read just enough of the scans lations to know what to know that you're gonna like it and then just hold out for the real One.
Scott: no, that's what I'm saying.
Scott: is that with the real one like Death Note We're gonna get like in rapid succession.
Scott: the first like I think there's ten.
Scott: Well, that's no bonds now.
Rym: That's no it's not gonna go that much longer.
Scott: So yeah, but I mean Excel saga is a good example.
Scott: They put out a billion volumes of Excel saga and now the people who bought all those volumes Cell saga is not done.
Scott: They're gonna have to wait months and months and months and months for the next volume.
Rym: Maybe they should I don't know stagger the releases a little more because then people say hey so much of this is out.
Scott: Why don't you hurry up and give me what's already out, you know?
Rym: But then if they put it all out people say hey there hasn't been one for X months and now we're pissed.
Rym: Yeah, you can't win with these people.
Scott: No No You can't.
Scott: what you need to do is need to just take shown and jump and all those other magazines and just directly Translate them maybe with a weak delay or a two-week delay Maybe in a month delay and just bring them over here.
Scott: direct.
Scott: replace the ads.
Rym: Yeah, I just wonder how much of a mass market there is currently.
Scott: the trick with that is you have to put it on magazine Racks everywhere.
Scott: You can't do this wussy thing where you barely publish it.
Scott: You need to get a pile of money.
Rym: You've said this on the show a bunch of time have I?
Rym: and we've gone long.
Rym: so we'll do a whole episode on that.
Scott: All right, you advertise the fuck out of it.
Scott: So you keep saying everywhere.
Rym: Yeah Cuz we've already gone long have we?
Scott: yeah.
Rym: All right Yeah, and in the end free comic book day was kind of a bust.
Scott: at least they're free.
Rym: Yeah, they're free.
Rym: pretty good for free if they're if the goal of free comic book day is to get new people to read comics I think they failed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean look at the Simpsons comic targeting comic people.
Scott: Hello if you want to get new people to read comics first of all Give the free comics out somewhere besides a comic book store.
Rym: Yeah The only people who go to a comic book store are people who buy comics.
Scott: any only people know about free comic book day are People who buy comics anyway.
Rym: I don't think any of the people in the city of Newburgh even know that comic book store is there except comic book nerds.
Rym: They probably just see that door and never even think that there's something behind.
Scott: but there's a sign above it.
Rym: But they brought even see the side.
Scott: if I just ignore it.
Rym: They don't care cuz the store is pretty scary and dark and grimy inside.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to get new people to read comics have free comic book day.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: It's great.
Scott: Put the free comics in the fucking grocery store.
Rym: Oh and have good comics.
Scott: Yeah, even these comics would have done.
Scott: Okay in the grocery store better than the comic store.
Rym: Well, look free comic book day.
Rym: It happens once a year right and every publisher puts out one crap little normal comic.
Rym: Tokyo pop Constantly constantly constantly puts out giant-ass manga full of previews high quality.
Rym: Mm-hmm Just free.
Scott: they give them away everywhere like conventions and all kinds of stuff.
Rym: Yeah I mean I remember when we had there were a bunch left over at a con or something and they gave us a frickin crate of those Sneak things.
Rym: they said oh just give them away or whatever you want to do with them.
Rym: Yep Why don't the comic?
Rym: why don't the comic people just pay more and do something good like that?
Scott: Tokyo pop has that free magazine - oh, yeah, Takuhai Yeah, that's it.
Scott: You you sign up for it and they send you what's basically a little magazine every once in a while.
Scott: I think it's me for a year I'm not sure and it's got a whole bunch of manga in it And of course a whole bunch of Tokyo pop ads.
Rym: the only reason I didn't sign up for it was that they really Aggressively marketed it and pushed it and the more people market things the less I am willing to do them.
Rym: if especially since then They'll probably just spam me.
Scott: Yeah, it really felt like it was a spam deal.
Scott: I mean the thing itself they get.
Scott: they had free ones at Otakon.
Scott: I picked one up and It seemed like it was a span ad, you know, it didn't have a whole bunch of manga in it.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I'm just resentful of that sort of thing because I get enough junk mail as it is Mm-hmm.
Scott: So if you're looking to read some comics Don't read these comics.
Scott: Yeah the ones that I'll tell you to read later.
Scott: I wish we could have gotten the silver whatever's because those is those I wanted to read the Scott Pilgrim and the owly.
Rym: You know all the independent comics and I'll know that people in our forums have the same sentiment.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, someone hook us up with those and we'll talk about them on the show and we'll thank you for giving them to us.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'll give you all the gold comic books.
Rym: I got it on the other day.
Rym: I'll just mail them to you in exchange.
Scott: Yeah, I'll send anyone all of these in exchange for the owly.
Scott: Yeah just the owly just the owly and The comic meant for nursery school kids and it's better than these which are meant for elementary school and middle school kids.
Scott: What does that say?
Scott: that's another thing.
Scott: all these comics are meant for like kids and most comics in the comic store are not meant for kids and Kids don't really go to the comic store or read comics.
Rym: these kids don't read comics.
Rym: kids play with their DS's.
Rym: Yeah, and they're wheeze All right It's with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.