Rym: It's Monday March 20th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk about how to put a computer in your living room attached to your television.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So I've been getting a lot of emails and messages of various sorts of people saying I heard this separate feeds for each day.
Scott: How do I how do I you listen to just one day of GeekNights instead of all four days?
Rym: Now people on iTunes have already seemed to have found these on their own Because they're listed and there's about 20 subscribers to each already.
Scott: Yeah, if you go to iTunes or Yahoo podcast you can see there will be the.
Scott: there'll be like five different entries.
Rym: If you search for GeekNights actually scratch Yahoo podcasts, they've got issues.
Scott: Yeah, but it's the feeds are still there.
Rym: You know, they disappeared again randomly.
Rym: what Yahoo podcasts has problems with GeekNights, and I don't know why.
Rym: Sometimes it'll show us normally, you know It says we have 30 Yahoo subscribers and we have you know 70-whatever episodes and we have one feed or five feeds or four feeds.
Rym: Sometimes it says we have like three subscribers and like 12 episodes.
Scott: Oh, yeah Look, there's only one feed there now with eight subscribers and yeah Yeah, Yahoo doesn't understand us or Yahoo's weird.
Rym: I don't know I've given up.
Rym: I made that thread away back when I was trying to figure it out.
Rym: I gave up.
Rym: Yahoo podcast is just kind of broken.
Scott: Yeah yesterday I saw all four feeds there.
Scott: whatever.
Rym: it's not just us either It's it's a lot of podcasts.
Rym: just move up and down and left and right and the tags changed.
Rym: I just don't think Yahoo knows what they're doing.
Rym: Obviously not because I don't think they monitor it.
Rym: I think they just let computers do it.
Scott: I think the computer is coded poorly.
Scott: Anyway, if you go to iTunes You'll see if you search for GeekNights in the podcast section of the store You'll see like four or five different GeekNights choices.
Scott: One of them is normal GeekNights in which you will get every single episode.
Rym: We're not gonna call that GeekNights full or anything because that should be the default.
Scott: It's total GeekNights.
Rym: Just like Well, that means there's an ultra GeekNights out there somewhere.
Rym: you get an episode on Friday.
Scott: Ooh It's just Rym farting into the microphone.
Rym: actually, you know what?
Rym: Yeah, you can get ultra GeekNights right now for a hundred dollars a year.
Rym: You will get access to ultra GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, we have this fifth episodes that we've been making every Friday and keeping secret and yeah.
Scott: So no one had access to them.
Rym: one dude has been getting access.
Scott: one dude one dude, who's that one, dude I don't know.
Rym: I couldn't think of any funny name to say in the interim.
Rym: Okay, see He's totally unscripted.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, if you want to get if you're the kind of guy who wants to listen to you as Monday just Tuesday Just Wednesday just Thursday You can go now to front row crew calm and I made a giant blog post and on the right side in the feed section There are now six feeds.
Scott: There's the raw blog feed which isn't actually a podcast feed even though I guess you could use it as one even though you probably Don't want to know.
Rym: you don't.
Rym: the enclosures aren't there or anything.
Scott: Well, yeah, they are actually are.
Scott: yeah, but it's not formatted for Like quality with the titles and everything.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so it won't have any of the feed burner stuff in it.
Scott: Yeah, but It'll.
Scott: you'll get every single post to front row crew calm whether it's a podcast or not.
Scott: So if you want to like keep track of when we put news items there That's probably a good feed.
Scott: you want to throw in your Firefox or something?
Scott: The rest of the feeds are all podcast feeds.
Scott: The first one is every episode then it's just Monday just Tuesday just Wednesday and just Thursday.
Scott: So if you're using podcasting stuff You have to change what feed you want.
Scott: and I'm gonna say this Probably every day this week because in case someone is listening to just one day Yeah, because there's a surprising number of people found these feeds before we really advertise them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So if you're one of those people who found GeekNights and you think it's awesome and you wish it was more than one day A week today is your lucky day.
Scott: and if you're someone who?
Scott: Listen to GeekNights four days a week, but would really only want to listen to one day a week.
Scott: Well, you can do that too now.
Rym: Well, I will recommend not for any self-serving interest because I don't care how many people listen to Thursdays But GeekNights Thursdays are actually usually fairly interesting and we always get the most feedback from those days
Scott: Though really at
Rym: least the feedback from the people who I am me all the time.
Scott: Yeah Which is like the same two or three people over and over again?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but no one else has anything.
Scott: That means they're perfectly.
Scott: Oh, all right.
Scott: Let me while I'm remembering we have a forum.
Scott: It's happened.
Rym: Yeah, it's hopping in a way that pleases me to no end.
Scott: Yes, so go to front row crew calm and Join the forum and say stuff there.
Scott: Don't just like poke around and look.
Scott: I can tell you lurkers are out there.
Rym: Yeah, we can see everything all of you do.
Scott: Aha No, I don't do that, oh and there's a frapper map.
Scott: it's on the right side.
Scott: there's a link in the Scott's link.
Rym: Yeah, you might have remembered it.
Rym: I think it was two weeks ago.
Rym: We rediscovered the frapper map that we had made and forgotten about and there were a bunch of people in it.
Scott: It's just a little map and you put a pushpin where you are.
Scott: So that way anyone can look at the map and say oh look where the GeekNights listeners are around the world.
Scott: There's one.
Scott: there's one.
Rym: I'll tell you one thing for all of you out there if you zoom way out You'll notice that there's pins in many other countries by many.
Rym: I mean three.
Scott: Do you have any Canadians yet?
Rym: Actually, I don't remember.
Scott: I haven't looked at it in a while me either but people go there and put your pushpins in and I think we should say This stuff.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna keep reminding people all week.
Scott: It's a reminders week here on GeekNights.
Rym: That's a great week.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: So, you know, they have those little Robot car rover things on Mars, right?
Rym: No, I was completely unaware of these scientific advancements of the previous several years.
Scott: Anyway, these guys are like, you know, it's like kind of a flat remote control guy Who's got like three or four wheels on each side and a bunch of scoops and cameras and all that sort of thing.
Scott: Yeah, all kinds of little scientific lab equipments for testing soil and a camera.
Scott: Yeah, the top is all solar panels to fill the battery up.
Rym: Well, it hasn't been in the mainstream news much lately because you know people seem to immediately stop caring about space Like the second after anything is announced about it.
Scott: Well because the only part of space people like is the giant rockets and then once the Rockets put a satellite in space No one cares about the satellite going around space anymore.
Scott: Who cares?
Scott: Anyway One of the they were supposed to last.
Scott: what like six months or something like that?
Rym: not too long and they're still going.
Scott: because well, they're freaking crazy and it's been like the most bang for the buck of any space mission ever probably.
Scott: and What happened recently?
Scott: is it?
Scott: Almost was the end.
Scott: like if it was the end it would have been crazy like when that jeopardy guy finally lost.
Scott: That's what it would have been like, you know.
Scott: But actually what happened was one of the wheels broke.
Scott: So you have this thing that had like eight wheels and now it has seven But it still has enough power.
Scott: So what they're doing is they're having it drive up this little hill or kind of a big hill I don't even know I didn't see a picture.
Scott: and it's gonna drag this dead wheel along And recharge the solar cell at the top of the hill and keep going.
Scott: It's just unbelievable.
Rym: I think it's really cool.
Rym: Just the ingenuity here It's like, you know, if any of you aren't familiar with the space program if you ever seen I don't know Apollo 13 Kind of or read anything about the Russian space program Well the Russians yeah.
Rym: Just the things that they'll do Because it's not like there's a procedure for everything that goes wrong.
Rym: almost every problem The space program has ever run into was a new problem like new to humanity
Scott: Because they think about most of the problems that have like quadruple redundant, you know backups so that those problems never happen You know,
Rym: so when there is a problem They have engineers who have to figure out how to fix it based on what's up They're like right now.
Scott: because if there's a problem that means it's obviously something you didn't think of beforehand.
Rym: Yeah, I went to space camp when I was a kid.
Scott: So yeah, that's pretty much the job of space.
Scott: People is think of stuff beforehand.
Rym: Unless you are that that kid who was appointed to the head of NASA by Bush then your job is suppress research.
Scott: Ah That's that's a much less pleasant job Probably but at least lives aren't on the line in that job.
Scott: No, not so much so you wouldn't feel guilty if you failed to find a way to.
Scott: you know duct tape the space helmet or something.
Rym: Now in other tech news much more computer tech Delicious, which we all know and love and use, you know, the web 2.0 is bookmark II thing online.
Rym: If you don't know what delicious is there's a link anyway.
Rym: They have now added private bookmarking meaning you can add a site to your delicious and flag it so no one else can see it.
Scott: This is something that I you know thought of quite a while ago and a lot of other people are clamoring for it But the only real use that I can see for it is number one.
Scott: I could bookmark like my bank or like my credit card and no one else can see it Which is which is good.
Scott: Now the other thing is I could keep track of all sorts of porn links in there and no one else Would see that I was hoarding porn links.
Rym: now both of those are very good and valid.
Rym: But there's one other thing that I don't think Scott even thought of and when I realized this because it's a problem I've always had with delicious.
Rym: if you work at a company Where you have a large company where you have an internal intranet like IBM where I work currently we have our own internet all on our own with our own web servers and everything inside and It's completely inaccessible to the outside and the links are useless and broken if you try to access them from the outside world.
Rym: having those private in my delicious is very useful because There's basically an internal equivalent of Google that I have to use to find things and I have hundreds and hundreds of internal bookmarks that I need to access on a regular basis.
Rym: So using delicious I can still as long as I can get to the outside world internet.
Rym: I can use delicious to find those things in IBM And I mean a lot of other companies have similar infrastructure.
Scott: So isn't it great that you're not gonna be at IBM so much longer?
Rym: Yeah, we'll see how that goes.
Scott: like my company We have some internal web servers But I write the web things that are on most of them and I only use like two of them.
Scott: Yeah, well, I want that I'm making and the one that I just made.
Rym: so yeah, I wish I could talk more.
Rym: There's a lot of other IBM news today actually, but it's not stuff that's been released yet.
Rym: All I can say is that god damn it.
Scott: Mm-hmm Big blue evil.
Rym: no, no, no, not evil definitely not evil, but I will say this IBM is doing fine compared to Sony.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: I'm doing fine compared to Sony profitable despite debt
Rym: alright, so I got one more news here because we might go a little short on the tail end of the show, but Microsoft supposedly this seems to be more rumor than truth currently is Going to make an iPod killer.
Rym: Now they didn't just say iPod in this rumor.
Rym: It's what was.
Rym: it was an iPod DS PSP Camera blood killer.
Rym: It'll kill every small consumer electronics product that's out there.
Scott: Now I have two feelings on this number.
Rym: one lie blatant lie.
Scott: Well, no if you look right I realized recently I've been looking for a phone Replacement.
Scott: right and I want to get right.
Scott: now I have a blackberry and a phone and I want to combine them into one device.
Scott: The blackberry is a phone but there's a long story.
Scott: I can't actually get phone service on it and whatever.
Scott: so the really the only good option these days at least in America is HTC wizard HTC Apache HTC whatever.
Scott: These are all Windows mobile devices.
Scott: Microsoft doesn't make them.
Scott: Microsoft just develop the technology and licenses it to other people.
Scott: So basically, I think Microsoft is doing is they're gonna develop some sort of technology that Will like an OS or something that will be iPod PSP whatever killer.
Scott: But it'll be up to other companies to pay Microsoft to license it and then attempt to profit off of it.
Scott: Microsoft profits no matter what.
Scott: if at least one person tries to use it Microsoft profits.
Rym: Microsoft seems to do that often.
Rym: It's definitely the strategy of develop something.
Rym: make money off it no matter what.
Rym: let everyone else take the risk.
Scott: Yeah, exactly It's like hey, we can you know develop a risky new in you know kind of technology.
Scott: That's never been done before and then if it fails, it doesn't matter.
Scott: We still make out now.
Rym: I've seen some other ideas as to what this could be.
Rym: some people seem to be suggesting that Microsoft Leaked this rumor on purpose in order to convince the market that they're competing in a market that they're not actually competing it.
Rym: Okay, maybe if they're gonna release a handheld device a year from now They start making the buzz now and then they announce it, you know a year from now Who knows?
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: Is it SanDisk?
Scott: SanDisk?
Scott: the people who make like the little flash chips for your cameras and stuff?
Scott: Yeah, that's probably the only product you buy with their name on it.
Scott: They're actually competing pretty well in the mp3 player market Because they have all that flash storage production capability.
Scott: I think they actually make like the cheapest like space per dollar Flash player on the market, huh?
Scott: and they say that they're gonna start eating away at Apple's market share and everyone's kind of like.
Scott: I think you're.
Scott: you know, it seems like they're saying they're doing a lot better than they are like they're lying.
Scott: But at the same time who know?
Scott: it's kind of weird.
Rym: now the other Observation I have and this is more me than what other people have been saying but I'll just note that an mp3 player uses processing power and thus uses batteries a Camera uses batteries independently of that and all these other little bits use battery power.
Rym: Having a device that does everything will require a monster battery.
Scott: Not really because it only does any one thing at one time Yeah, but even then think about it.
Rym: most people listen mp3 is pretty much constantly and then they still expect to be able to make A call and play games.
Rym: a lot of people I know at least would listen to an iPod while they play their DS.
Rym: I just don't think the device that Microsoft wants to make is feasible in a way.
Rym: That would be affordable?
Scott: No, no, no, it could be done.
Rym: If you spend a million bucks, you could make a perfect little piece of technology.
Scott: No one says it'll be cheap.
Scott: They didn't say we're gonna make it cheap, but if it's GSP SP It's cheap.
Rym: It's not a killer because it doesn't compete with that product Just how the PSP doesn't compete with the DS anymore.
Scott: Well, the PSP doesn't have games.
Scott: That could be why it doesn't Do it the price.
Rym: so my thing of the day I Chose it and something I found a long time ago and I had meant to make it a thing of the day.
Rym: I just never did for various reasons.
Rym: I mean better things kept coming up, but it's basically I'm throwing it as a bone.
Rym: To all the people arguing about religion in the forums and one I just like to say that I'm very pleased that everyone is arguing About religion in the forums.
Scott: Everyone loves a good religion argument.
Rym: I've been not just an argument a flame war.
Rym: I was hoping for some sort of epic flame war to kind of break the forums in and we finally have a topic where enough People are strongly opinionated enough on to where you guys are arguing.
Rym: I'm real happy.
Scott: Let's start some more flame wars in that forum.
Scott: All right more people new people though.
Rym: Here's some fodder for the flame war.
Rym: this is a list of almost every comic book character anyone's ever heard of and their religious affiliations.
Rym: It's got the golem here.
Rym: He was a Jewish obviously.
Rym: Superman was a Methodist apparently.
Scott: I Don't know what's up with that.
Scott: He's an alien.
Rym: Yeah, my favorite one is there's a superhero called the atheist and It lists his religion as atheist.
Scott: Okay, at least it makes sense.
Scott: Yeah This doesn't like the atheist secretly.
Scott: Scientologists.
Rym: now there are any Scientologists, uh, let me look.
Rym: Let me look Actually, there's one Triathlon is a triune understanding which is based on Scientology.
Scott: Oh Okay, so he's a culty.
Rym: Yeah, basically.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway, I thought this was interesting and I hope to see some arguments along the lines of Superman belief in God.
Rym: Why don't you?
Rym: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: So my thing of the day is this way cool video I found this morning.
Scott: Actually, I'm pretty sure this entire website is funny because it seems to have a lot of links to other videos.
Scott: some of them are just Family Guy clips and whatever but Whatever.
Scott: It's I think it's pimp.
Scott: Panther.
Scott: comm is the name of their site.
Scott: the funny video that I'm specifically going to link to now is A few guys are playing a video game Up, I started playing it by accident In the video game, they're controlling this giant kind of army dude.
Scott: Who's like the main character, I guess and You know in a video game where you can't die.
Scott: It's always fun to do silly things like, you know Jump off a building and get up Shoot yourself run into a wall repeatedly.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I remember like in double golden I used to do all kinds of stuff for like the invincible code you'd like jump off of stuff and Shoot thing like stand in the middle of giant explosions of fire and get burnt without dying anyway, they keep doing that sort of thing and then Well, you'll have to see for yourself.
Rym: It's yeah, we can't ruin this one.
Scott: It's got high production values and it's awesome.
Rym: All I want to say is the sheer ferocity of the beating and beatdown that ensue is classic more than classic I would say.
Scott: What's older than classic?
Rym: Uh timeless.
Scott: There you go perhaps even more so.
Rym: antiquities All right, wasn't that an expansion for magic?
Rym: Those antiquities close enough.
Rym: Anyway, today is Monday and we're not doing a themed week but it is science and tech day and we have a lot of ideas for shows that we didn't feel like doing any research for.
Rym: and we realize that there's one topic that We've actually just embroiled ourselves in yet again Awesome.
Rym: it is hooking a computer up to your living room TV.
Scott: Ah the living room The place where a computer must go in fact is Quickly becoming the most important place to have a computer much more useful than on the desk.
Rym: I mean, honestly, we didn't really have a computer hooked up to our TV until we moved into this big house.
Rym: So all through college whenever we wanted to watch something we all huddle around my computer because I had the biggest monitor.
Scott: Or we would like burn a VCD.
Rym: Yeah, those are the highest of quality items.
Scott: then later we would burn a DVD.
Rym: by the time we were burning DVDs We were almost moved out.
Scott: Anyway, you're definitely almost moved out by that point.
Rym: So at one point when we moved here We were talking about building a nice micro ATX little PC to hook up to the TV.
Scott: But it turned out we had enough parts to just make extra computers.
Rym: We have several extra computers many.
Rym: if you're a geek You'll eventually accumulate several extra computers.
Scott: if you're not accumulating several extra computers as a geek Either a you're getting rid of your computers.
Scott: bad move.
Scott: Well now again, you're not biting enough new computers If you only have one computer in your house.
Scott: buy two more is better.
Rym: now, we're not going to talk about myth TV Because while myth TV is awesome.
Rym: We have not yet set it up for reason.
Rym: We'll get into.
Scott: yeah We're gonna have a whole nother episode about myth TV and perhaps some things from that episode will become entwined.
Scott: and yet a third episode relating to a different topic.
Scott: and Yeah, I want to figure actually get myth TV working before I talk about it, but actually let's talk about what myth TV is though.
Rym: All right.
Rym: It's basically a you know TiVo Or whatever.
Rym: all the other PVRs are out there.
Rym: I forget what they're all called.
Rym: Anyway, myth TV is just an open source implementation of something very much like that.
Scott: in other words instead of buying a TiVo and paying TiVo every month you take a computer and you plug it into your television and you install myth TV on it Which is absolutely free.
Scott: it runs on Linux, which is absolutely free.
Rym: freeze in both speech and beer.
Scott: Yeah, so you pay nothing except for the cost of the computer obviously, which is obviously.
Scott: you already have one lying around Obviously and it does the same thing.
Scott: a TiVo does in fact better.
Rym: Well almost the one thing you don't get is the directory that you pay TiVo for but there is a free directory You can connect to online Yep, and it's mostly as good.
Rym: as far as I can tell.
Rym: we don't know.
Rym: we don't actually have any sort of television service whatsoever.
Scott: But yeah I mean if we're you if we're gonna use myth TV The reason we want to use it is not to watch television or record TV shows, which is its primary function.
Rym: Yeah, though we might get an antenna to record.
Rym: I don't know Simpsons Yeah, who knows.
Scott: but it is also just a very good interface for using a computer attached to a television.
Rym: Yes, especially emulation and Well emulation.
Scott: Yeah, it gets really hard to use a computer when you just plug it into your TV and try to use the Mouse and keyboard especially at a high resolution.
Rym: You can't see shit, especially if you don't have an HD TV.
Rym: Yeah, like we don't yeah, we could have had one.
Rym: It just wasn't worth the money.
Scott: No, it's not worth it.
Scott: So You know myth TV Let's use like a remote control.
Scott: if you set it up right and it just has big text and nice easy to scroll through menus and You know, you can set it up to check the weather check the news read RSS feeds run emulators from nice You know and all it does is put nice easy menus on all this stuff To play video files that are just stored on your computer that you downloaded with bit torrent all that good stuff.
Scott: I think it even has bit torrent.
Scott: I'm not sharing web browser for has a web browser.
Scott: So if it gets really hard to use gnome or KDE or whatever your choice of desktop You know system is on Linux.
Scott: You can just run like a crap desktop environment like flux box or flux box.
Scott: people are gonna yell at me now But fuck.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: All right fine.
Scott: I still um, no one will defend that maybe not all right, you can you run rat poison and then Run myth TV and you'll never have to look at rat poison or use it and it'll be really easy to use your computer plug.
Rym: All right.
Rym: for any of you who don't know what rat poison is I'll put it very briefly in that once I went to the website to read about rat poison and There is no screenshot section.
Rym: instead there was text explaining that if you need a screenshot rat poison is not for you exactly.
Rym: But instead of talking about myth TV We're gonna talk about just the basic.
Rym: What if you want to have a TV in the living room with a computer attached to it?
Rym: all the things you've got to consider Because we recently went through all this and we've learned our lessons.
Scott: Step one you're going to want a computer.
Scott: You don't need so much RAM.
Scott: That's the first thing you only need.
Scott: about 256 might even get you by but RAM is so cheap.
Scott: Yeah 512 is more than enough way more than enough.
Scott: You're not gonna need a whole lot of RAM.
Scott: You need only enough RAM to like hold a video file in memory and not even that, you know, it's just nothing.
Scott: So don't spend don't get a gig of RAM.
Scott: That's silly.
Rym: Yeah, basically the key factors I would consider.
Rym: I guess it depends on whether or not you're scavenging an old computer or buying a new computer for the purpose.
Rym: Yep, but Quiet you want it to be quiet.
Scott: get big fans and not so many of them.
Rym: Yeah, and keep in mind that it's not gonna be a gaming machine It's not gonna heat up that much the video cards not gonna be doing 3d whatever.
Rym: so you can get away with less powerful Cooling.
Rym: if you can try to get away with passive cooling wherever you can put it in.
Scott: Yep Number two, you're gonna want a CPU.
Scott: That's you don't want to get one.
Scott: that's crazy stupid fast because you don't need that.
Scott: But you have to make sure you don't skip too much or else you have like videos that skip and that's no good.
Rym: a broad broad broad Idea, and I hate using a number like this, especially a number like megahertz, but more than 1.2 gigahertz You're probably gonna want maybe like two or one and a half.
Rym: We've got what we got a duron 900 down there.
Scott: Yeah, duron 900 is not enough.
Rym: That's like that's just below the line.
Scott: My desktop computer currently is a 1.8 gigahertz Athlon XP.
Scott: if you get a high-end sempron or a low-end AMD 64 or pretty much any Pentium 4 you'll be fine.
Scott: Yeah, or anything better than a Pentium 4 is more than fine.
Rym: And I'll just say it because I have to if you even consider overclocking a rig like this just kill yourself right now.
Rym: Yeah, there's there's no reason no reason at all.
Rym: In fact, if anything you'd want to underclock it that way it'll be quieter and less hot.
Scott: Mm-hmm The third thing you're gonna want is just buy like a $20 something that plays DVDs.
Scott: You don't need to burn DVDs next to your living room TV You just need to play them.
Rym: or in the very least when someone comes over with a DVD full of crap You can put it on there and watch it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So you want to get something that's a DVD reader.
Scott: now these days You can get a DVD burner reader/rewriter thing for like 20 bucks.
Scott: So just get the cheap one off Newegg.
Rym: Yeah, I mean having a DVD burner there would probably be real handy especially a CD burner for you know Your friends are over burn a CD for the car or whatever, but don't spend money if you don't have to.
Rym: We'll talk at the end about if you're gonna spend money what you want to do.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Third thing the most important thing is a video card.
Scott: you're probably gonna want from my experience an Nvidia video card only because Especially with Linux but also with Windows the Nvidia video cards are the best at supporting TV out Regardless of operating system.
Scott: Yes Like we had an ATI card and we plugged it into the TV with s video and we just couldn't.
Scott: no matter what we did.
Scott: Could we get any video to come out of that s video hole now?
Rym: There's nothing wrong with ATIs hardware.
Rym: I mean ATI and Nvidia.
Rym: I'd say their hardware is equal just their beaches.
Rym: each has itself pros and cons.
Rym: The problem is Nvidia's drivers are incredibly well-written and awesome.
Scott: ATIs drivers are crap.
Scott: ATIs drivers are a travesty unto man But this doesn't even have to do with drivers.
Scott: if you have an Nvidia video card Right and your computer has no hard drive and no operating system and you plug in the s video cable to the television It'll work.
Scott: You will see the BIOS going by on the television.
Rym: It might it might not take up the whole screen or something, but it'll be there.
Rym: No, it'll.
Scott: it'll actually be Unless your TV is wicked old.
Rym: Yeah, assuming you're I don't want to make an assurance here that we can't back up in the.
Rym: Yeah, but if you're using an s video cable or better your then it's able to detect your television settings unless that s video cable is then converted to RCA and then run through an RC are an RF modulator and then into an old TV through.
Rym: and yeah, we're talking.
Scott: we're talking.
Scott: that's one thing you had to be sure of.
Scott: you're gonna want to plug your computer Directly into your television.
Rym: There's a lot of reasons for that.
Scott: You're gonna need a television.
Scott: That's somewhat modern.
Scott: It's sad.
Rym: Now.
Rym: The other thing here is, you know talking about the TV.
Rym: We're not talking about HDTV because you're gonna.
Rym: it's almost impossible to take advantage of HDTV via a computer.
Scott: No, it's incredibly easy to take.
Scott: It's the easiest way to do it.
Rym: Here's the problem with it.
Rym: Oh, here's the thing.
Rym: you can get it to work on TVs, but the HDTV standard changes so much.
Scott: You realize every single HDTV that you can buy has a DVI hole HTM whatever.
Scott: no a DVI hole.
Scott: as in you take a DVI cable and connect your video card directly to the television Really?
Rym: There's got my work who's like super into movies and he has multiple computers hooked up to his TV And he said that that didn't work Really?
Scott: Yeah My dad has a Sony Sony.
Scott: That's like the worst you could possibly get HDTV.
Scott: it's just.
Scott: it's a CRT, you know WG a one of those and I took a computer with a DVI cable and plugged it right into the TV and it worked perfect really bad.
Scott: I had no effort whatsoever.
Scott: So well if you're willing to spend an extra 500 bucks We know the rule is if you buy an HDTV make sure it has a DVI hole and not just an HD.
Scott: Whatever HDMI, I think any one of those DRM tolls or a component, you know component holes You can't really get component out as video works just as well.
Scott: though.
Rym: Now if you want a PVR with HDTV or anything like that There's basically one option.
Rym: you got to get a somewhat expensive special card.
Scott: Well, it's a hundred and seventy dollars.
Scott: it's readily available and it's called the HD 3000. you can go to PC HD TV comm and buy this thing now.
Scott: There are probably other things you can buy but this is the one that is a guaranteed to work with Linux 100%.
Rym: Yep, just now Scott was reading off the feature list of it and it's pretty robust.
Scott: It's basically a TiVo on a card that goes into PCI slot and it's even compatible with the HD 2000 card.
Scott: is the previous version?
Scott: that wasn't HD?
Scott: Well, I guess it was kind of HD But it wasn't as awesome and like if you have an Nvidia card to go with it.
Scott: they kind of work in tandem and you can get a whole bunch of these cards if you need multiple tuners if you're not Like that and it supports pretty much Linux perfectly and HD perfectly.
Rym: Ooh, wait a minute tandem with my Nvidia card.
Rym: Does it use those cool?
Rym: On Labeled special connectors on my video card or anything.
Rym: No every Nvidia card I've ever had has multiple connectors internally for ribbon cables.
Rym: That don't go anywhere.
Scott: All it will do is use the power of the Nvidia GPU in order to play the HD TV smoothly.
Scott: Oh, that's all it means.
Rym: that's understandable because HD is a lot of data.
Rym: Yeah All right, though at least in terms of what we're gonna talk about.
Rym: We don't have any HD whatsoever in this house.
Scott: Nope, but I know all about it or enough about it more than most people.
Scott: Yeah, most people who have HD don't even set it up, right?
Rym: Yeah the only there's one guy I know and he's at my work and basically his whole life has become movies and He has a hell of a setup from what I can gather and he know as far as I can tell he knows everything about it.
Rym: He's got like multiple computers hooked up to his TV.
Rym: He's got like multiple cable providers in HD and Netflix and he's gonna get blu-ray right away.
Scott: Whoa, I didn't think anyone was gonna get blue right away.
Rym: I mean like when it's 400 bucks not right away the first one when there's no blu-ray DVDs out yet.
Scott: Yeah, actually they're gonna be if the private blu-ray and HD DVDs before their players.
Rym: Actually, oh there was just an article on it recently where they were talking about that and they delayed blu-ray partly because that way There would be DVDs out for it first.
Scott: I think who knows who cares?
Rym: All I know is the list of blu-ray.
Rym: DVDs are not movies that will take advantage of blu-ray at all.
Scott: Anyway back to computers plugged into the television.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We use as video.
Scott: Yeah as video is simple.
Rym: It works It's not a problem and honestly for I mean most things you download off the internet are not the highest of quality because they're compressed somewhat.
Scott: the thing is the thing what you're gonna do with your computer if it's like a video watching type of thing.
Scott: even if you download an HD quality video the s video can probably more than handle it and For other things you do with your computer your computer is probably gonna be at a higher resolution than your TV can ever handle.
Scott: I mean, you know your computer can beat the TV HD resolution by like a million miles.
Rym: Yeah, so be ready when you're setting up your desktop.
Rym: if you don't use myth TV or anything to make all the fonts big keyboard shortcuts and or a wireless keyboard Yeah, make sure you have a wireless keyboard and mouse of some sort.
Scott: We just bought a little logitech one for 40 bucks because we were suffering with the wired ones.
Rym: Yeah, we had a wireless one that had a range of about one inch.
Rym: now We've got one that can actually reach across the room, which is yeah It's a good feeling to sit on your couch with a mouse on your lap and a keyboard sitting next to it Picking a movie that you downloaded off bit torrent.
Scott: It's actually a pretty light nice and keyboard - I expected it to be crappier But it was pretty cool.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to if you want to splurge Logitech makes the de novo media controller keyboard and mouse setup.
Scott: I would not pay money for that thing 200 something bucks, but damn it has all the buttons you need to control shit.
Rym: If someone gave me one.
Rym: I wouldn't complain.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's pretty cool.
Scott: It's definitely the thing you buy if you're rich.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: now hardware wise the last real thing is if you're gonna buy a new computer at least for this or even if you have One around think about what kind of case you have it in.
Scott: Smaller the better and quieter the better.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I could put my computer down next to the TV.
Rym: My computer is a giant hulking monstrosity.
Scott: Yeah, I can't think we can stress enough that you need a living room computer to be quiet more than anything else because if you're watching a movie and the whole time this is That's no good.
Rym: Also the fact that you're gonna want to leave it on all the time because booting the computer every time you want to watch Something's just a pain in the ass.
Scott: Yeah until we have computers that have like solid-state hard drives and they boot up instantly You're gonna want to be leaving this thing on all the time Which means once again you want it quiet and you're gonna want it not to be so power hungry.
Scott: So don't put a whole bunch of drives in it.
Scott: Just you know Ideally, you would have all your videos and things stored somewhere else on your local network either on your computer Or if you have you know out server somewhere on a server.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to fill your living room computer up with hard drives because then you have to listen to them in your living Room, but if you must, you know put them in there.
Rym: In fact, honestly, especially if you're putting an older computer down there And it's not serial ATA but a 5400 rpm drive in there those things are actually really quiet.
Scott: Yeah, just put like a like a 20 gig old drive in there.
Scott: It doesn't have to be fast or anything is you're barely gonna be using it.
Rym: Yeah, the drive we threw on ours actually has a broken spot in it.
Scott: Yeah, we store a few videos on there, but that's just because we don't have a storage array set up yet.
Rym: Yep Yeah, we're working on that.
Rym: Yeah And as for the case if you're building a new one at least go micro ATX because that way it's a tiny little motherboard and There are computer cases that are basically the size and shape of a DVD player Mm-hmm, and you can just put it there and it'll just be like another thing on your rec sitting above your DVD player and under Your xbox.
Scott: Well, you won't even need a DVD player.
Rym: I prefer watching DVDs on a DVD player.
Scott: I Don't see it if your computer plays DVDs just fine.
Scott: What's the difference?
Rym: Well, yeah, if it does but it's just the usability and the ease of the fact that the DVD player just works automatically No matter what all the time.
Scott: Oh, that's why myth TV is one of the things that handles that.
Rym: Yeah, but we don't have myth TV going yet.
Scott: So of course and if you are smart and you use Linux properly It's not difficult.
Scott: If you buy a DVD ROM from the store right to go in a computer It's set to region free by default.
Scott: as soon as you put a DVD into it Let's say I put a region one DVD into it and I you know, I play it in Windows It will automatically set the DVD player to region one.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of them have a grace period of like five DVDs and then it'll stop changing things like that.
Scott: Yeah, then let's say I put a region two DVD into it.
Scott: It'll ask me in Windows if I want to change my region to region two.
Scott: And if I say yes that there's a physical thing in the drive that breaks and there are maybe five of those things that can Break.
Rym: Yeah, there's all sorts of different methods.
Rym: Don't try to open your drive and figure it out.
Scott: No, you can't figure you can't do it.
Rym: Sometimes it's physical.
Rym: Sometimes it's an unflashable firmware for all for all purposes.
Scott: It's undoable.
Scott: once it's broken you're done.
Scott: So you'll have like five chances to change your region and then once you've changed it five times You're left with the last region or maybe your drive will even stop working.
Rym: So you see that dialogue.
Rym: Don't think you've broken the horrible encryption and you can just change regions.
Rym: Your time is numbered.
Scott: Yeah, so what you want to do is if you use Linux and never use Windows Linux won't automatically change your region.
Scott: It'll just leave it at region zero.
Scott: if you never.
Scott: you know If you never had Windows and the drives region was never changed it's a brand new drive.
Scott: You'll be able to keep it region free forever.
Scott: Of course, there is a program for Linux I think called region set or DVD region set that you can get and it very reliably at least in my experience Allows you to change to whatever region you want Of course, but of course it will break the things because it has to.
Scott: so if you accidentally say buy a drive Boot Windows watch a bunch of region 1 DVDs you decide you want to go to Linux and never go back to Windows ever again.
Scott: you can go to Linux change your drive to region free and then Never go back to Windows again because it'll set your region back to who knows now sound cards you.
Rym: it basically depends on what kind Of setup you've got.
Rym: if you don't have surround sound or receiver It doesn't matter.
Rym: any sound card in the world that fits in your computer will work just fine.
Scott: yep, what you're gonna want to do in that case is Take a Cable that on one end is a headphone plug just like the kind you have on your earbud headphones you put into your iPod.
Rym: We're being simple here.
Rym: if you know what they're actually called whatever this is for people who don't know you know, You're not listening to this
Scott: and on the other end of the cable will be a red and a white plug and you're gonna want to take the headphone plug and put it into the sound card on the computer and you're going to take the red and the white plugs and put them on to the Audio input on the television next to the video input from the that comes out of the computer.
Rym: Now generally just adjust all the volume on the computer to whatever set level sounds good and never touch it again and always change The volume via the TV.
Scott: Yeah That's the general idea with sound is that you want to all.
Scott: the sound comes from somewhere and eventually ends up Close to at some central point really close to the speakers.
Scott: So if you're using your television speakers, the closest point to those speakers is the TV volume.
Scott: So adjust every other volume to something and leave it and never touch it and then only use the TV volume Just like podcasting.
Rym: here Scott and I are set to two different volumes and then the final volume the mix.
Rym: the knob that I'm poking At all the time while we talk is just one knob at the end right before it goes to the computer.
Rym: Yep So I mean it's real simple.
Rym: if you don't have surround sound or if you have a receiver But you don't care about it do the same thing and just plug it into the receiver on whatever input Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now if you want to do surround sound it it's trickier.
Scott: I am like an expert on this because I spent maybe five years figuring out how surround sound and Linux work.
Scott: Yeah, he really did and all the different things about it and all this crazy batshit surround sound crap.
Rym: All I've learned from listening to him complain about this is that it's a pain in the ass.
Scott: Alright, um, let me tell you a couple things.
Scott: number one If you're gonna use Windows because if you're not if you're not gonna use Linux on your you know computer living room PC You can use that Windows Media Center But it's actually honestly really good.
Rym: if you don't care about paying for it and you don't care that it's Windows Yeah, if you don't care about paying for it, you don't care that it's Windows.
Scott: You don't care that it is DRM and you don't care that you'll only play like region 1 DVDs.
Scott: go use it Why not?
Scott: It's really easy.
Scott: You don't have to spend a bunch of time Like don't think we're being condescending here really.
Rym: it's that easy.
Rym: and if you don't care go for it.
Scott: Yeah, but I gotta warn you one thing.
Scott: It will require a better computer than a Linux setup.
Rym: Well, yes You'll probably end up buying a new computer.
Rym: Anyway, if you do that, yep They're actually.
Scott: they sell computers in the store.
Scott: Windows Media Center computers.
Scott: buy one and if you have money go for it.
Scott: They work.
Scott: people seem to like them and that's so bad.
Scott: You know, it's like a TiVo alternative.
Rym: Yep, because there's a guy at work who kept saying he wanted to do something like that.
Rym: So I kept telling him use not myth.
Rym: it makes making myth TV easy.
Rym: Well, yeah, we'll go we'll get into that.
Scott: Yeah, we'll get into that today.
Rym: I remember he came back to me.
Rym: Well, I'll tell the whole story another day, but suffice to say he ended up buying one of those Windows Media Center things.
Scott: Yeah, they work all good.
Scott: Anyway surround sound in Windows surround sound will work.
Scott: If you buy a sound card that supports surround sound and plug the speakers into it properly It'll work.
Scott: The thing is if you want to Route audio from say your DVD player your VCR, etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: into the computer and then out of the sound card of the computer to the speakers and a little trouble there You're better off routing everything to a receiver.
Scott: Yeah You need to if you buy a receiver to do your surround sound.
Scott: Well now your computer doesn't really need a surround sound video card.
Scott: It just needs a video car sound.
Scott: car sound card.
Scott: It doesn't need a surround sound sound card.
Scott: It just needs a sound card with digital out preferably optical out but SPDIF out also works.
Rym: Yep I mean, we're not gonna get into the details of how surround sound works, but consider that the word logic appears in doubly pro logic.
Rym: yeah, there is logic there that can determine what the surround sound should be and Data is put to that in various ways.
Scott: The only thing I can say is if you want surround sound number one Anything more than five point one surround sound is stupid because you're never gonna find DVD that has six point one or seven point one surround.
Scott: It's just silly.
Scott: 5.1 surround is the only surround.
Rym: Yeah We're not even kidding all these extra surround sound.
Rym: things are just scams for Best Buy to sell you.
Scott: they're mostly scams to sell extra Speakers to gamers.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right number two What you want to if you're gonna go for surround sound you get the speakers are the most important thing.
Scott: So buy the best speakers you can Afford, you know as long as they're not crazy Randy audiophile silliness, you know You'll be able to tell because they'll advertise a bunch of things that don't sound right.
Rym: Yeah, I'd say as a general baseline if you don't know what you need don't spend more than three or four hundred dollars.
Scott: Yeah, I spent two hundred dollars on my Logitech Z 5500 and that those are a good choice for any not incredibly large room.
Scott: They're perfect.
Scott: home theater desk Surround it's.
Scott: it's perfect surround.
Rym: So yeah, I will note that his subwoofer is bigger than my monitor.
Scott: Yeah, it was bigger than I thought it was gonna be.
Rym: Well, no, yeah, it's slightly bigger than my monitor.
Rym: I think volume wise who knows my monitor is fucking huge though.
Scott: Maybe it's equal to your monitor Bigger who knows?
Rym: Yeah, we'll measure.
Scott: Yeah, we will.
Rym: But now one if you're if you're cheap.
Rym: I know a lot of people listen to GeekNights are in college and when we were in college We were poor and we have poor.
Rym: it's not even surround sound.
Rym: It's the poor man's receiver.
Rym: Go to Kmart or Target whatever and you know those crap.
Rym: Oh stereos.
Rym: They sell mm-hmm that come with like two speakers and they're always big and rice looking.
Rym: Yep buy one of those.
Rym: They're like 80 bucks at most usually a lot less.
Scott: make sure it has RCA in.
Rym: yeah The little red and a little white thing on the back.
Rym: Yeah the one I talked about before Yep, and just plug all of your stuff into that Mm-hmm, and you know what?
Rym: It's not the greatest sound but for watching a TV It's usually a hell of a lot better than what's on the TV itself.
Scott: speaker wise Yeah I mean cheap TVs usually have one little speaker.
Scott: slightly better TVs have Two speakers and they're usually not the greatest speakers in the world.
Rym: if your TV has good speakers on it That TV cost more money than my computer.
Scott: Yeah and usually the really good TVs don't have speakers like the really good computer monitors don't have speakers and only crap computer monitors have speakers on Them.
Scott: it's like that.
Scott: But yeah, if you're gonna do surround sound what you're gonna do is you're gonna If you really want it you're gonna pay for equipment that has either an optical input or an SPDIF input.
Scott: then you're gonna get a sound card that has optical output or SPDIF output and Take the wire from the sound card to the speaker or receiver and it'll probably just work normally.
Rym: But if you want all the surround to work, you're gonna have to listen to another episode.
Rym: We do well Scott will explain all that in Linux or read like the near book size Guide.
Scott: I'm in the middle of writing.
Scott: that's taking a long time.
Scott: Yeah, yeah I'm writing a whole giant guide about PC audio specifically with Linux and specifically with surround sound So that everyone can learn from my five or six years of journeying to get stupid speakers to work in Linux.
Rym: Yeah, I gave up pretty much right away and I've always just dumped with a subwoofer and left and right.
Scott: I solved my problem with money.
Scott: It's a good thing.
Scott: I got plenty of it.
Rym: but anyway, you'll get the sound set up somehow and After that just get stuff and watch it.
Scott: Yeah, load up your bit torrents download your TV shows and Run M player.
Rym: and I mean, I remember we set this up and at first we didn't use it that much.
Rym: It was just this computer that was sitting there.
Rym: It was always on.
Scott: well, that's because we couldn't really get it to work.
Scott: We were switching out video cards and stuff.
Rym: Yeah, well because of ATI and then we didn't have a network drop to it for the longest time and we originally just wanted to Use it to play DDR.
Rym: Yep, until we discovered that the floor in our living room is not the most structurally sound item.
Rym: Mm-hmm I mean, it'll hold us up.
Rym: It won't hold us up if we're jumping around like monkeys.
Scott: No, no.
Rym: So we couldn't play DDR and the box sat there for a while every now that we had played emulated games on it.
Scott: Yeah for emulated games.
Scott: I recommend you buy a USB hub, which we didn't buy but that's okay And that's you know, like one with four ports.
Scott: so you can bring four USB ports right out to the front Where people are sitting and then just get USB game pads and plug them in.
Rym: I highly recommend though you'll have trouble getting to work in Linux.
Rym: Sometimes like saying makes things where you can.
Rym: you can connect an old Super Nintendo controller to a USB.
Scott: Yeah, there are all sorts of things you can buy to plug in actual NES SNES PlayStation controllers directly or you know convert them to USB and then plug them into the computer.
Rym: now We'd really like to say buy the Xbox 360 PC controller But we haven't actually found one.
Scott: Well, there is one in Circuit City that no one's bought but I'm afraid to buy that particular one because it's too much money.
Rym: Yeah, but it looks like it'll be a good thing if it ever comes down in price.
Scott: There is there is.
Scott: for anyone who doesn't know you can buy an Xbox 360 controller that is designed to work with a computer as opposed to working with an Xbox 360.
Scott: You can probably buy them online pretty easily buying them in a store.
Scott: They're hard to find they.
Scott: they come in a similar package to an Xbox 360 controller only instead of the green and white cardboard this red Microsoft Windows e cardboard and it has USB plug and I've read that people have definitely gotten it to work a hundred percent in Linux by doing You know adding the things in the kernel and such and it's not credibly difficult But not easy for people don't know what they're doing in Linux.
Rym: Now if any of you have this controller or know someone who does let us know we're really curious about it.
Scott: Yeah, I'm definitely looking to buy one because the problem is a lot of PC game pads are just crappy.
Rym: Yeah I mean I the.
Rym: the standard right now seems to be the gamepad Pro the gravis gamepad Pro USB.
Scott: Now the gravis gamepad period has been the PC standard for a long time.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I submit that it is terrible.
Scott: It's not great.
Rym: The reason is and it really seems to only affect old-school Nintendo games That if you hit right you very often hit down and right a little bit instead Which will destroy you because then Mario ducks instead of running.
Scott: Yeah, it's very it's it works And it works easily like it's guaranteed to just work period.
Scott: the problem is it's not so precise and it's controlling.
Scott: So if you're playing any game, especially old emulated games that requires precision handling you are going to die.
Rym: Now also we mentioned DDR.
Rym: if you want to play DDR with step mania on this computer one Make sure you don't have neighbors downstairs.
Scott: Make sure the basement is a good place.
Scott: If you have a furnished basement, you can't do better than that.
Rym: Yeah, we're actually thinking this summer We'll just tilt the TV a bit and play on our deck because we have a big sliding door there and then a deck That's big might maybe work.
Rym: Yeah, I think it will but anyway You're gonna need to connect their DDR pads to the computer somehow and this is a problem that has vexed me for ages.
Rym: It is not.
Rym: basically you'll see things in the store that claim to do it.
Rym: They lie.
Rym: They almost all lie.
Rym: if you want a thing that works go to the step mania forums or the DDR DR freak forums and look and see what those people recommend.
Scott: Yeah for converting PlayStation to USB.
Scott: There are plenty of things that work.
Scott: The problem is they do not support hitting two arrows at the same time because you know who hits two arrows at the same time.
Scott: Well DDR people hit two arrows at the same time And even then a lot of them.
Rym: you have to put them in a special mode to make them work with dance pads.
Scott: Yeah, there's a special like code you have to press in.
Rym: usually It's like hold left and right at the same time or hold X and over at the same time for like three seconds And then hit start like that.
Scott: I recommend you buy a dance pad that has USB on it automatically.
Rym: Yes, the the new red octane ignition pad has USB on it and it's good.
Rym: It works.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I have it It works just fine.
Rym: I bought my ignition pad a year and a half before Scott did and that would did not exist.
Rym: yet.
Rym: So mine does not have USB.
Scott: No, it does not.
Rym: It has Xbox which should be USB, but it doesn't output the same signal.
Rym: No, well the same signal.
Rym: It doesn't output the same key presses.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's.
Scott: it's generally a bad idea to try to get older PS, you know PlayStation dance pads to work on a computer.
Rym: Just buy a dance pad that has USB.
Rym: Now surprisingly the dance pads that plug into parallel ports work fairly Well, the problem is you will never find one of those again.
Scott: Nope, they don't exist anymore.
Rym: Unless if you see one for sale don't buy it.
Rym: It's probably either used or has been moldering in a warehouse for the past Thousand years.
Scott: if you're big into DDR and you're really gonna play it You should probably just buy a dance pad.
Scott: Anyway, if you don't already have one if you already have one Hey crackhead, if you're such a crackhead, how come you don't own a crack pipe?
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: Well, maybe they're just getting into DDR.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta link to the party though when we got into DDR We basically had those crap Oh thin rubbery plastic dance mats duct tape to the floor in our apartment semi-permanently.
Scott: I think we've told the story before.
Rym: Yeah, we'll tell it again.
Scott: All right But anyway, other than that, that's all you need for a living room computer.
Rym: I mean don't don't let the feature creep creep in.
Rym: don't try to use it for other stuff because it's just gonna be a pain.
Rym: Think about what you want this computer for and then do whatever you want.
Rym: If you want to watch movies set up to watch movies.
Rym: if you want to play games set up to play games Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean you could try to be all cool and maybe like Have a laptop and have a docking station next to the TV and you put the laptop in the docking station and the laptop Doubles as the you know living room computer and it's also your laptop.
Scott: But you're just gonna clutter up your laptop with a bunch of living room stuff.
Rym: Also, don't expect to surf the web on this thing often.
Rym: It's great for Google video.
Rym: One of our favorite pastimes is typing words like explosion in and just sitting around having a grand old time.
Rym: But as for surfing the web with all of its texts not so good.
Scott: Yeah, I mean one thing you're gonna want to learn.
Scott: if you don't know it already if you're using Firefox or a lot of other programs Control plus and control minus well control equals.
Scott: technically.
Scott: if you press those buttons You can make the font bigger and smaller now even better.
Rym: if you use opera opera does it one step better and actually zooms in And out including the images.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I actually really recommend opera if you're gonna have a PC hooked up to the computer and you expect to use a web browser at.
Scott: Opera seems to actually be the best browser for anything except a desktop computer.
Scott: Yeah Well, I think they're putting it on the DS opera on the DS opera on the palm pilot.
Scott: Opera on the TV is the way to go but on a normal computer.
Rym: It's all Firefox I guess I'm glad that I mean, I like opera.
Rym: I don't use it, but I like it and I'm glad that they seem to have found their niche Like.
Rym: this is the thing that opera is good at.
Rym: that makes it different from Firefox.
Scott: Mm-hmm Speaking of Firefox.
Scott: Firefox 2 alpha came out today.
Rym: Yeah, I think we're gonna have to try it out and talk about it next.
Scott: I tried it out a little bit.
Scott: I'll talk about it.
Scott: Later.
Rym: All right.
Scott: All right I think that's it for our living room PC discussion.
Rym: for those of you who listen to all four days of GeekNights Tune in tomorrow when we're going to resume our trend of review some games and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.