Rym: It's Thursday May 4th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We tell tales of injury and disease.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So everyone who knows me knows that I have this stupid bucket hat that I wear every now and then.
Rym: Yeah, whenever I need a hat to put on whenever I don't feel like combing my hair.
Rym: I put on this green bucket hat.
Rym: I've had it for a long long time.
Scott: It's messages.
Scott: It's like a useless piece of just cloth.
Rym: I like it now.
Rym: In fact, it's my second stupid hat.
Rym: I replaced the previous stupid hat that I'd worn all through high school and then someone stole from me during orientation at RIT.
Rym: Yeah, someone actually stole it.
Scott: I wore many different hats Over the years.
Scott: I mean in elementary school I had like a hat with some basketball team on it and then in middle school I had some.
Scott: I didn't think I had a hat in middle school because they didn't allow you to wear a hat in middle school But then oh they didn't let us either but I wore him outside of school all the time.
Scott: Yeah, then in high school I got the the Mets hat and then I kept that to college and then around freshman year just stopped wearing it.
Rym: See, I don't like wearing hats with stuff on them and for the longest time I eventually found a black baseball cap with no logo or anything on it.
Rym: It's just a black baseball cap with a gray brim.
Scott: Mmm, see was all about.
Scott: I used to wear the hats that had the Adjustable size in the back and then I discovered the fitted hat and that's when I was able to wear it for extended periods of Time because the one of the adjustable size is not comfortable at all.
Rym: Well, it depends if you get the crappy one with those plastic nubs that fit into the other plastic holes.
Rym: That's crap.
Scott: That's the crap what I'm talking about.
Rym: No, no, see my head is adjustable But it's nice because instead of that it has a leather strap in the back that you can adjust to any size.
Scott: Yeah, it's a little better, but it's still not as good as the hat.
Scott: That is your size.
Rym: That's really comfortable and I can adjust it depending on my hair.
Rym: The size of my hair determines how big my head is in any given day.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, my hair is always the same size.
Rym: Anyway, I've had this hat for a long time.
Rym: It is a very fairly iconic hat of Rym.
Rym: I'm often wearing it, you know at the beach or when I'm a bum.
Rym: The other day I was running along the railroad tracks and I was hot.
Rym: I was wearing my hat so I took it off and I put in my pocket and I kept running Somewhere along a span of at least four miles.
Rym: it fell out of my pocket and I don't know where Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm rather miffed at this.
Rym: In fact, I ran back along the railroad tracks today to try and find it and It wasn't there at least in the span that I ran in.
Rym: So if there's a decent chance that someone took my stupid hat off the railroad tracks on the ground and did something with it Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't think an animal took it.
Rym: There's no trains.
Scott: I Don't know why I don't want your stupid hat.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of raggedy and old.
Scott: It's not even a hat.
Scott: you if I leave you saw it lying there you'd say hey There's some tattered piece of material wasn't that tattered?
Scott: wasn't tattered but it just kind of flumpy.
Rym: Oh, well, at least I'll just buy a new one.
Scott: Yeah, I Don't know where you're gonna find such a useless hat.
Rym: They sell them all over the place.
Rym: I bought that for like eight dollars at Kmart when I was in high school.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Kmart.
Scott: Kmart doesn't really exist that much anymore.
Rym: I mean there's one over there, but That's about it, yeah, but out in the Midwest there's still a lot of them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Well, we're not going to the Midwest.
Scott: Are we?
Scott: Yeah, when's the last time you're in the Midwest?
Rym: Uh, I think it was.
Rym: they said which was when while ago.
Scott: Yeah long time ago.
Rym: Maybe I'll fly out there when I visit my dad and I'll buy a hat.
Rym: Yeah, I need a goddamn head.
Scott: I'm fine in Detroit cuz I need to buy me a hat.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I'll go to that leather shop to buy new boots.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Rym: Yeah, actually my boots are fine.
Rym: I just have to take care of them.
Rym: If you can't tell we're stalling cuz we don't have so much good news.
Scott: There's not much to talk about.
Scott: We're bored.
Scott: We're tired.
Rym: You're tired.
Rym: I'm fine.
Rym: I don't know what's wrong with you.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: what's wrong with me?
Scott: How many times are you all tired?
Scott: And I'm like, what's wrong with you?
Rym: Never.
Scott: Many times.
Scott: When?
Scott: Many many times.
Rym: Name one time.
Scott: Last week.
Rym: When?
Rym: What day?
Scott: Some day.
Rym: Nah, that's not good time.
Scott: Just cuz I can't name a specific day doesn't mean it didn't happen.
Rym: I got a specific one right now with Scott You suck.
Rym: Anyway, in the news Alright blu-ray DVD.
Rym: Well god blu-ray.
Rym: Here's my prediction that blu-ray is going to fail solely because even just now not intentionally I said blu-ray DVD instead of just blu-ray.
Rym: Yeah, the name is blu-ray.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Not blu-ray disc.
Rym: Not blu-ray just blu-ray.
Rym: But DVD is one of those words like mp3.
Rym: This just seems it seems to have infiltrated the consciousness of even non geeks.
Rym: I mean how many people when they want, you know music on their computer?
Rym: They say mp3.
Rym: They don't know that mp3 is a format of a file.
Rym: They think mp3 means sound on a computer.
Scott: Yeah, they might be getting AACs and WMAs.
Scott: They don't know.
Scott: Yeah or a tracks.
Rym: But anyway blu-ray DVD was delayed again.
Rym: Wow, and now it's going to come out in the end of middle end of June.
Rym: And it wasn't delayed for any technical reason as far as I can tell.
Rym: it was delayed because the players aren't coming out until June and Sony entertainment wanted to release their discs the blu-ray discs the blu-ray DVDs in May Which is just fantastic, you know have discs for sale that there's no player in the world that can play them.
Scott: well, I think the idea of that is you put the discs on store shelves and People can either a buy the discs in anticipation of buying the player or B get comfortable with the fact that okay, these discs are available.
Scott: and then you know get the player.
Scott: You don't go buying a DVD player when there's no DVDs in the store.
Scott: You have to have the DVDs in the store first, then people will buy the player.
Rym: All right.
Rym: point to point the first the 12 or so movies that are being released on blu-ray first are Either of their one of two categories Unmitigated crap or Movies that in no way will benefit from being on an HD format
Scott: Naha
Rym: movies that really didn't benefit much from being on DVD.
Scott: Well, if the movies weren't made in HD really then it doesn't really.
Rym: I don't think there are many people out there Who can really tell the difference between a DVD and an HD blu-ray DVD?
Scott: I can tell the difference on the same television as As long as you know, it's a good.
Rym: it has to be a power a good HD television.
Rym: Yeah, I mean our TV.
Rym: There's no way to tell because our TV is just not that good.
Scott: Our TV is not HD at all.
Rym: However, HD TVs are very very expensive.
Rym: compared to normal TVs.
Scott: You can get some smaller ones now, but it still is America.
Rym: You expect someone to buy a small TV.
Rym: Relatively how many people do you see they have?
Scott: you can get a 36 inch HD TV nowadays?
Rym: Yeah for quite a bit of money.
Scott: compared to what we pay a couple hundred dollars more than a non HD equivalent.
Rym: That's quite a bit of money for very little actual difference.
Scott: Yeah, but that's 720p.
Rym: if you can get something to go to 1080p then then it's a lot more money for still not that much Of a difference.
Scott: It's a pretty big difference if it's utilized.
Scott: It's.
Scott: the problem is not too many things utilize the HD to the fullest because it's hard to utilize No kidding, and it's also expensive to utilize and in many cases.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it doesn't really add anything.
Scott: A lot of times it takes away things.
Rym: Yep I mean unless you've got an Xbox 360 and even then most of the games aren't actually HD.
Rym: They're just up sampled.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But anyway, the reason they really delayed it was that all the retailers and the people and the other studios said hey You can't release those discs so soon.
Rym: We don't want to have these stuck with these things on our shelves with a month of no one buying them release them later and Sony said crap.
Rym: and they had these negotiations and the good negotiations broke down, and then Sony said all right fine We'll delay everything.
Rym: God Mm-hmm once again.
Rym: I predict that blu-ray is going to be a miserable failure.
Scott: HD DVD also even.
Rym: oh yeah I'm not even going to be started on HD DVD But I think it has a slight edge in that it has the letters DVD in it.
Scott: well everyone knew it had that edge from The beginning.
Rym: that's the only edge.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know well the blu-ray was really banking on.
Rym: You know people buying ps3s that who I want the game system, but it's also a blu-ray player whoo.
Rym: But ps3 is not looking so hot right now either.
Scott: I have a feeling they're both going to become another mini disk whatever.
Scott: yeah, unless the computer drives can drop in price quick enough to make HD DVDs or blu-rays useful for data or Unless porn studios can start putting out HD porn in high quality studios.
Rym: Don't want HD porn?
Rym: Yeah, you realize most porn is shot with a soft focus because if you have really good clarity it just looks disgusting.
Rym: Yeah, yeah porn is very little.
Rym: the porn industry has very little interest in HD formats at this time.
Rym: There have actually been a couple articles on FARC about that recently.
Rym: awesome.
Scott: That means it's gonna fail.
Scott: You don't have porn your technology can't win.
Rym: yeah for anyone out there who doesn't know and we're not kidding We're not just saying this that you can verify this from respected sources.
Rym: The primary driving force in consumer home entertainment technology and theater technology for the past 50 years has been pornography.
Scott: if your technology Doesn't have pornography in some way.
Scott: It's going to fail.
Rym: We're not even kidding.
Scott: look Atari Custer's revenge any yes had those strip poker games DOS their porn games for DOS.
Rym: the first applications of VHS were mostly pornography.
Scott: It's all porn.
Scott: porn drives Information technology.
Rym: now the number two drive is actually military research.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: There's really almost nothing after that.
Rym: No one cares about the market.
Rym: the market comes after the porn.
Scott: if your technology does not have any violence or sex It's not gonna make it.
Scott: HD DVD doesn't have in blu-ray don't have violence or sex.
Scott: I think the screwed.
Rym: the main thing about blu-ray and all that that I'm thinking about more and more is that DVD was such a huge leap over VHS and At that time computer technology was nowhere near the capability of playing those kinds of movies Just on a computer without any sort of physical media.
Rym: It's true now.
Rym: We're beyond that.
Rym: We're getting to the point where you could give people just data files It doesn't matter what the format is and they could play them on a computer or some intelligent device.
Rym: By locking into a format like blu-ray or HD DVD You're just locking yourself into something that's gonna be obsolete and crappy within a few years Mm-hmm.
Scott: That's the idea is that they want to make money by selling you the same movie Ten or fifteen times out of the course of your life as you switch from one media to the next.
Rym: Yeah, you know what the best movie that's gonna be released on blu-ray is.
Rym: Fifth fucking element really of the list.
Rym: That was the only movie that.
Rym: those are just the launch titles.
Rym: Yeah, but the fifth element doesn't need HD.
Rym: You're not gonna get anything.
Scott: It wasn't filmed really in HD.
Rym: She's not gonna say multi-pass better Multipass.
Rym: it's one of my favorite movies ever.
Scott: It's alright Great, so that oblivion game that everyone's playing that I'm not really interested in at all.
Rym: I'd be interested in it if it were better, but I like the idea of games like that.
Scott: Yeah actually When I found out the game wasn't like Baldur's gate where you have to click all the time and it's more like a first-person Thing.
Scott: I was more interested in it.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it still has you know, the same tedium sort of Me the I.
Rym: I like games like that, but I don't want him play him in a sandbox Single-player games of that magnitude.
Rym: I just I feel like I'm wasting my life playing them.
Rym: Yeah, an MMO would be cool if it was like that.
Rym: just freeform Crazy complex no balance whatsoever.
Rym: Deal with it kind of world Mmm.
Rym: anyway, that's a whole other conversation.
Scott: Yeah, so the game had a rating of T for team.
Scott: I'd have never played the game.
Scott: So I don't know if that's an accurate rating.
Rym: Uh, mostly because when you hit someone they scream and bleed.
Scott: so it's realistic.
Rym: It's pretty realistic.
Rym: It's as realistic as you'll get from a game like that.
Scott: All right, the gay ESRB changed the rating to M.
Rym: Now why?
Rym: oh, why did they do this?
Scott: Apparently they found some violence and such that they didn't know about before The violence wasn't really the main drive.
Scott: Yeah, actually most of it was the violence.
Rym: the topper was the Topless model.
Scott: there wasn't really top.
Scott: There isn't any toplessness in the game.
Scott: They just have a model.
Scott: but when the model appears in the game It's covered by underwears and on the Xbox 360 version.
Scott: You can't possibly mod it.
Rym: This is the same as that hot coffee issue.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: it's slightly different Now because it is something that's in the game that you're not supposed to be able to access so it effectively isn't there.
Scott: Yeah, but they're also changing the rating on the Xbox 360 version where you can't access it no matter what.
Rym: Yeah, well because it's one game.
Rym: I don't know if they like the idea of having the same game have two different ratings.
Scott: I don't know but The company that makes it Was like oh, we don't care do whatever you want change them change the stupid rating.
Scott: We're not changing our game.
Scott: Fuck you.
Rym: Yeah, if the ratings are really meaningless at this point parents ignore them or don't understand them.
Rym: kids don't care.
Rym: stores don't care.
Rym: I mean if the one EB won't sell the game do because it's rated M to a kid the game stop next door will.
Scott: Well, actually it nowadays.
Scott: I think I heard 70% or so of stores are actually selling by the ratings.
Rym: Are they really though?
Rym: I mean remember most stores like that are staffed by one or two dudes who are younger than us just hanging out.
Rym: They don't care.
Rym: Yeah If I were working in a game stop, I probably even think about the ratings Unless my manager was standing there.
Scott: I definitely don't look at the ratings of games when I go to the store at all.
Scott: You know when you go to the moon I don't even look at movie ratings anymore.
Scott: used to when I was a kid and it kind of mattered but nowadays No, see the nice thing when I was a kid.
Rym: It didn't matter.
Rym: the theater near us didn't care.
Rym: Yeah, I just want to see our rated movies.
Scott: all the time Our theater acted like they cared but they really didn't.
Rym: our theater was like we don't care.
Rym: They were pretty open about it.
Rym: Awesome I'll bet that's changed.
Scott: The problem I see here is that the ESRB is getting bashed like really bashed because by all the evil Fucktards in the government.
Scott: and If they go around changing the ratings on games, that's sort of like saying yeah, we suck They should have just let it slide and no one would have made made a big deal about it And no one would have found out or continued to bash them.
Scott: So it's like they're covering their ass Because they you know on an issue that they didn't really need to cover and thus Exposing that there was an issue to cover which no one knew about.
Scott: You know, it's like if I had a gaping Hole in my armor and then I patch it up.
Scott: someone goes.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know you had a hole in your armor.
Scott: Oh, look at that.
Scott: He had a hole in his.
Scott: they make shitty armor.
Scott: That's what I thought You know.
Scott: if you just let it slide no one would have noticed there was a hole.
Rym: you'd be alright Alright, so my thing of the day.
Rym: I gotta give some props to laws on the forums for pointing this out to me.
Scott: I think laws stands for Legend of Zelda.
Scott: am I wrong?
Rym: Ah, that would make sense.
Scott: Yes, and I thought it stood for laws seems particularly cool and geeky.
Rym: but laws pointed out to us that there is this video online and It is definitely think of the day worthy and once I watched it It had to be.
Rym: I have to share this with the world.
Rym: So anyone who doesn't go to the forums isn't gonna know what this is until I actually say it Holy crap kind of an incentive to hit the forums.
Rym: you get the scoop.
Scott: Well, you get the scoop sometimes Yeah, most of the time you try to scoop us and you fail.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but anyway this thing is a. it's a video about Mario kicking some goombas butts and doing the whole flag thing.
Scott: Great.
Scott: We haven't seen that video a thousand times.
Rym: However It's done in this very Soviet style propaganda.
Rym: awesome.
Rym: It even has Soviet music playing in the background from the Russian to the red of Russian choir.
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: I mean it ends with like Mario with his giant hammer Standing there and there's the flag and it's really cool.
Scott: Yeah, it is really cool.
Rym: The only gripe I have about it all is that in terms of the audio?
Scott: They should have one used higher quality sound effects Mmm, they didn't use Mario sound effects, you know, like the sound effects they use were kind of annoying and loud.
Rym: And you know The only reason they were annoying is because they were low quality the audio.
Rym: if they had used those sound effects higher quality would have Been better.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And if the sound effects have been a lot quieter and the music had been a lot louder They really didn't set up their Not to get an audio crap, but they didn't really set up their soundscape properly.
Rym: So the sound effects was overpowering but you kept wanting to turn it up to hear the music.
Rym: Yeah had to be the other way around but ignoring that it's awesome.
Scott: It seems like it's something that's really old like I seen it before But I can't actually say aha that I did did see it before because I don't remember it and it was still awesome when I watched It.
Rym: I think that's partly your desire to not have been scooped on something that cool.
Scott: No, no It seems like you know, I can't tell when it was made, but I feel like I've seen something similar in the past.
Rym: Uh-huh, maybe in a past life Dude, just let it go.
Rym: You got scooped.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: So I found this other Mario thing.
Scott: cuz what the hell.
Rym: wait, is this the thing I told you about?
Rym: maybe that's fine The bullet bill thing.
Rym: It's a bullet bill game.
Scott: Yeah, it's a game where you're bullet bill and you have to smash Goombas and bricks and stuff But you can't hit the mushrooms in the ground or else you die And then you get shot out of the cannon again, and you have to do it again.
Rym: now This is the fun unique kind of game I like.
Rym: I like games that put you in a cool situation like that Like I like.
Rym: I'd like to see a flash game where you play all the bad guys against Zelda.
Scott: That'd be a good game.
Rym: Yeah, we go to multiplayer game.
Rym: Yeah We should make that or someone out there should make it so I can play it.
Scott: Yeah, just make a mega man game, but you're a flash man or your metal man.
Rym: Or make a mega man game where it's two-player and one guy controls each of the bad guys as it comes down and then controls the boss.
Scott: Yeah, it's alright.
Rym: or make it like in Northversus south where you're walking your mega man and the other guy can has like a Limited number of enemies that they can drop down and control on you.
Scott: That was a good one.
Scott: north versa.
Scott: if you haven't played north versus south for the for the NES you're missing out.
Scott: That's a great two-player game.
Rym: Oh my god It's fairly terrible, but it's terrible in that awesome kind of terrible.
Scott: It's fantastic.
Rym: It's got its issues.
Scott: Basically, the only issue with it is once you build up the skills You're golden now.
Rym: now the issue with it is that in the combat?
Scott: Oh the war Combat with the cannons and the horses.
Scott: in the
Rym: combat if you're if you play from a fully enlightened game theory Position where you make the ultimate move It'll often come down to the fact where it's a perfect stalemate and someone has to force themselves Someone basically has to quit and lose their army and there's no way for either team to actually kill the other team.
Rym: The gates a perfect stalemate and whoever makes the first move loses.
Rym: So you have no incentive to ever act and the game ends.
Scott: Well, you do have an incentive back to move your guys around.
Scott: so don't get canoned if the other guy has good cannon skills.
Rym: No, because the cannon runs out after six shots.
Scott: Oh Yeah, but then you can have multiple cannons.
Rym: No, yeah up to three and then they all run out.
Rym: Hmm then what now?
Rym: you've got that little bridge and you both got six dudes on either side and whoever walks Forward the other guy's gonna shoot and then win.
Scott: Well, it depends.
Rym: No, it doesn't depend.
Rym: I played this game hundreds and hundreds.
Scott: you send out your horsey guys all some of my gun guys and vice versa.
Rym: Yeah, the horsey guys will probably just die.
Scott: Well, the horsey guys can win if they rush.
Rym: No, they can't win if the player plays optimally on the other side.
Rym: No, he just sits there with his gun guys.
Rym: There's no reason for you to ever advance.
Rym: if the horsies come you shoot them.
Scott: You can fake the other guy.
Scott: you said your horsey guys to make him move his guys.
Scott: And then you said you're out that you stop them and you move the other guys down.
Rym: You can't stop them.
Rym: They keep going they go right into the water and die.
Scott: You can stop them?
Scott: No, you can.
Rym: you cannot stop them once they go.
Rym: They whatever we're not.
Scott: we're not talking about earth We're talking about bullet bill.
Rym: Yeah, but don't don't talk about something.
Scott: You don't know I know about it.
Scott: I played this game many times.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: and you know what if You play the game and
Scott: the problem in the combat is that you have a lot of guys to control and you can only control One at a time and the cannons are really hard to control So if anyone is the cannon skill, it doesn't matter how big your army is you'll get owned.
Rym: No, the cannon skill is useless because even if you play the cannon perfectly There's no way you'll hit anyone's stuff.
Rym: If they're they have even half a shit worth of skill.
Scott: if I get my cannon into middle your horsey guys guys You can't move the cannon forward.
Scott: I can I can change the distance the cannon shoots and then I just move out of the way.
Rym: the cannon ball takes a Long time to get to the other side of the screen.
Rym: You can never ever ever lose any troop to a cannon.
Rym: unless you're an idiot.
Scott: You can lose a troop to a cannon.
Rym: No, you can't.
Rym: you can only if you suck.
Scott: No.
Rym: All right We'll play the game after this.
Scott: All right, where are we gonna get this game?
Rym: We've got it on the emulator All right.
Scott: Well, let's go try to play it.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: play right after this.
Scott: It's still.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's a hard game to play.
Rym: I Mastered that game.
Scott: No, you didn't.
Scott: Yeah, I did.
Scott: Not at all.
Rym: I played with my little brother constantly Whatever.
Rym: all right, we'll see we'll see.
Scott: we'll post anyways about bullet bill.
Scott: bullet bills awesome.
Scott: They should make more games where you're a different character besides the main character.
Rym: Yeah, the game does something really well and that if you die, it just immediately starts you over and you can try again.
Scott: Yeah, and every time you beat a level you get a password.
Scott: because and that's a good thing because it's really really hard Like I. I don't know if maybe I just suck at this kind of game But I couldn't.
Scott: I still beat level two.
Scott: Well one - - I can't beat it.
Rym: Yeah, the game is really hard.
Rym: It's the controls are really really really fickle.
Scott: I think what the game needs is to be a little slower in the Scrolling so that you can see far or wider so I can see farther ahead.
Rym: It feels like it's going at about the speed that a bullet bill would have been going in Mario 1.
Scott: No bullet bills went slower than that.
Rym: Not too much slower.
Scott: Yeah, they went pretty slow.
Scott: This is going like a double or triple speed bullet bill.
Rym: It's really just a memorization game.
Rym: Once you memorize a level you win.
Scott: Yeah, but sometimes it's also a reflex game like I'll remember I have to go up but if I start pushing up too late It's over.
Scott: It would be a good game to have an analog control for It's definitely a much better game where if you can watch someone play who knew what they were doing You get everything you need to get out of it pretty quickly and then you don't need it anymore.
Scott: The game's done.
Scott: Of course I really just want to beat one world because supposedly when you get to a - for level marin Luigi you're there and you try To hit them.
Scott: So that's why I'm still playing just to see that once I see that I'll probably have no more reason to play.
Rym: if I made the game one I mean, it's gonna make it incredibly difficult like that did to actually get to the world x4 where you fight Mario - I'd set the game up with some sort of logic so that Mario would always dodge you no matter what
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: That would be the most cruel horrible thing that could be done to a man.
Scott: Or I'd make it a little more easy and more fun because the point of the game isn't to me.
Rym: I'd make it impossible because you know Because you know that instinct when you're playing a game and you get real close to beating it But you just can't beat it.
Rym: You just keep playing it over and over and it's hard to stop until you win.
Rym: Sometimes you could you could get people to sit there.
Rym: I almost got Mario.
Rym: Oh, I almost got him again.
Rym: Oh, oh so close.
Rym: I'll stop as soon as I hit Mario, but you can't hit Mario because the logic of the game won't let you.
Scott: That's just dumb because then people would find out and post it on a forum somewhere and then no one would play.
Rym: no They wouldn't because they would not.
Rym: many people would even get that far.
Scott: Anyway, the game also has really good music and sounds and such that it does.
Scott: Yep Play bullet bill until you get driven insane by it then don't play it anymore.
Rym: Or just watch the Mario communist video over and over again a couple times is enough.
Rym: Yeah, it'll get you real pumped up for communism.
Scott: Just so we need more damn commies.
Scott: Communist bullet bills.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So today's main bit was Scott's idea so you can introduce it.
Scott: Oh So it's really hard to come up with ideas for it to talk about on Thursday.
Rym: Well now we have a lot of ideas.
Rym: We just they're ones that require research or an interview or stuff that we haven't got prepared, right?
Scott: So today we're gonna do a geek fable, but there's gonna be multiple fables, but they all the same.
Scott: moral so doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, mostly this idea came from the fact that we get a lot of feedback that people really just like to hear us tell stories Yep.
Scott: So today is geek fables of illness and Injury, we've got plenty.
Scott: any fable having to do with illness or injury will be told today.
Rym: So I'd like to start by saying that other than one pinky toe.
Rym: I've never broken a bone in my body.
Scott: I have only broken one bone in my body ever which one my collarbone.
Scott: Ah, I was Sitting on a swing set on a part where you're not really supposed to sit and then I fell off and I landed on my back on the ground and I said ow.
Scott: and Then I went to the emergency room and I looked in the x-ray and they were like, oh, yeah collarbones broken.
Scott: I'm like, well, what do I do?
Scott: Like you don't do anything?
Scott: It'll just be better soon.
Scott: Yeah, and then they gave me like a little sling for my arm and they're like here scare your mom with this.
Scott: And then that was it.
Rym: Oh, so it was just like a hairline fracture.
Rym: It wasn't broken.
Scott: No, I don't even know what it was, but it doesn't.
Scott: now I can reach really far around my back.
Rym: So it's great because when I was a kid what at least when we lived in New Baltimore We moved out of Detroit into the suburbs.
Rym: There was a place.
Rym: we were kids and there was this street.
Rym: that didn't have a name yet but it was part of a develop a future development and Had this big mound of dirt that over the years kids had sculpted into mini little BMX course.
Rym: We called it dirt Hill Road dirt Hill Road and the BMX thing was called dirt Hill.
Rym: All right Yeah, we were creative little kids.
Rym: Yeah Well a friend of mine did a really awesome jump like he did a. this thing goes up on his bike He jumps really high falls back where he lands on dirt Hill.
Rym: He broke his collarbone.
Rym: He had to wear this giant like hold him in a certain position thing for months.
Scott: Wow, that sucks.
Rym: Yeah, you didn't break your collarbone.
Rym: You got a little hairline fracture that healed itself.
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: it's so young It's not.
Rym: even you didn't have a giant metal thing holding your shoulders at a specific angle.
Rym: Never Yeah, you didn't break your collarbone.
Scott: Yeah, but now I can reach really far on my back.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I can touch every part of my back.
Rym: So can I know?
Rym: That's not the only people who can't touch their whole back or either really fat or really inflexible.
Scott: Yeah, we should have a survey who can touch every part of their back.
Rym: You know what we will Post in the forums.
Rym: Can you touch every part of your own back?
Scott: Yeah, the best way to need a or Dina's sponge on a stick or a towel on a stick.
Rym: I wash myself with a rag on a stick.
Scott: Yeah, you do a All right Let's see.
Scott: When was the next time I was injured or I will do injuries first.
Rym: I've had some horrific bike accidents, but I'll save those.
Scott: Oh, that's a good one.
Scott: Yeah Here's one.
Scott: So I was I don't know how old I was maybe 10.
Rym: I don't remember you were sentient at least.
Scott: Yeah, it must.
Scott: it might have been 10 because I think I was in fifth grade and like my dad had come home from a Business trip.
Scott: so I went over to the door.
Scott: I don't know if I was running full-out, but I was sort of running and At the bottom of the stairs in my house is sort of like this big stare, you know, I'm talking about It's like a landing.
Rym: Oh, yeah Yeah so if you.
Scott: so the stairs are in between living room and the Den and so to cross from the den to the living room you go up a little bit and then down.
Scott: You know, it's like one stair and then to the left is the actual stairs.
Rym: Yeah, it's the landing.
Scott: Yeah the landing.
Scott: so I tripped over the landing and the right side of my face landed on the floor Like just flat on the floor the right side of my head just way Great, your dad opens the door like I'm home.
Scott: Crap.
Scott: Wham.
Scott: and then I had braces at the time.
Scott: Ah So the brace unlike my bottom.
Scott: Like, you know the pointy tooth right the the what's a nine.
Scott: the canine tooth like my right bottom right canine tooth The tooth to the left of that.
Scott: so the rightmost front bottom tooth The brace on that went into my lip just into it.
Rym: I have many braces and lip stories because they're like the Trump.
Scott: This is all the way in like.
Rym: did it come out the front?
Scott: No, not so bad But you know, so then I'm gushing blood all over the place.
Scott: Just bleeding bleeding bleeding bleeding bleeding.
Rym: if I was your dad, I don't know if I could help laughing I don't know.
Scott: So I'm bleeding bleeding bleeding bleeding bleeding.
Scott: We had like a whitewash cloth and I got it all wet and I put it up there to apply some pressure.
Scott: Red washcloth.
Scott: bleeding bleeding bleeding bleeding.
Scott: and I'm a little kid.
Scott: So I'm like am I gonna bleed to death?
Scott: What am I gonna do?
Scott: I'm just standing there bleeding all over the place, you know, then eventually they're like, all right We'll go to the stupid hospital Went to the stupid hospital and I had to get stitches in my lip.
Scott: So, you know stitches in your lip sucks ass God damn I can imagine.
Scott: and now I have this bump on my lip.
Scott: That's permanent.
Scott: It's still there.
Scott: Oh, you can feel it if you want.
Rym: No, no, I got my little stitch scarf.
Scott: It's like this whole lump of scar tissue in my lip like um, that's fantastic.
Scott: Yeah It's not pleasant.
Rym: I had a similar falling down the stairs incident.
Rym: This is probably the most serious injury I ever had.
Scott: No, what about the bike spoke?
Rym: Yeah, the bike spoke wasn't that serious.
Scott: It's on the most serious to me.
Scott: It wasn't serious.
Rym: It wasn't life-threatening like the falling down the stairs.
Rym: All right.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Now everyone's get wondering what's the bike spoke?
Rym: That doesn't sound good.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Rym: you know what?
Rym: it isn't good?
Rym: No, I still got a mark on my leg.
Scott: It's really not good.
Rym: Yeah, but then I was a little kid because we had the same kind of stairway that Scott has, you know Except the landing was at the top.
Rym: So you go like it was actually two landings.
Rym: Like you come out the hallway and you go down a few steps And then there's a landing and a door to this tiny little deck Like a tiny little deck that was like to a story up and it was really kind of useless.
Rym: My parents never let us play on it.
Scott: I wouldn't let you play on it dangerous They wouldn't like.
Rym: we never even opened the door and it was like a normal steel door like the kind of Security door you'd have in your front door.
Rym: Yeah, but it had a skeleton key.
Rym: It was kind of cool.
Rym: Mmm Marietta dream once where there's something there.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah, like I opened the door and there's something there and it was cool.
Rym: Anyway, then it goes down to another landing and then 90 degrees back.
Rym: There's the long stairway down and I remember very specifically.
Rym: I was eating snacks.
Rym: I was eating cheese nips which were the same as cheese It's and I was eating Chex mix.
Rym: and then I went upstairs and I was eating alphabets.
Rym: Like I had three bowls of each and I was eating them all.
Scott: three bowls of each nine bowls.
Rym: Well, I had one bowl of each a total of three balls.
Scott: I'm like, what the hell.
Rym: and for some reason I was eating all of them.
Rym: All right, these three separate bowls.
Rym: I ran upstairs to do something and I was walking back downstairs and I missed a step and I rolled all the way down the stairs to the bottom.
Rym: like but I'm put up but I'm put up whomp and I just laid there.
Rym: I don't know if I was knocked unconscious or what I was really young.
Rym: Mm-hmm The next thing I know.
Rym: there's paramedics standing around me and they're like, can you move your feet?
Rym: and I was like no And they freaked out.
Rym: they're like, oh my god, my parents are freaking out everyone's freaking out and I'm like, oh wait, yeah I don't remember much else other than that.
Rym: I'd wear a neck brace.
Scott: Oh wait.
Scott: Yeah That's classic, can you move your feet?
Scott: No.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Oh wait.
Rym: Yeah, I Think I was still a little delirious from the fact that I was knocked out.
Scott: I think so, too, but that's all that's great.
Rym: And partly I was scared to move it.
Rym: cuz my I remember my mom yelling like don't move your neck It might be broken.
Rym: and I was like what happens if it's bro.
Rym: He's like paralyzed something.
Rym: I didn't understand what was going on But yeah, I was fine.
Rym: I just had to wear a neck brace for a long time At least a long time for a kid.
Scott: Did he get all itchy and whatnot?
Rym: I had a couple other I'd changed it and I could take it off at night and it was.
Rym: it was a pain.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but I didn't die obviously Or did you don't?
Scott: don't?
Rym: uh god there was a threat on far flame war today about that.
Rym: Don't get me started Really?
Rym: Some guy was like, you know We every time you think you almost died, but you made it, you know Like a car almost hit you.
Rym: You really did die and as far as everyone else is concerned you're dead and you just split off into a different universe.
Rym: Everyone lives to old age.
Scott: You're a nutcase yeah.
Scott: and the flame war started because he wasn't kidding and he yeah Well, hey, if that guy's out there listening come over to my house.
Scott: I got a knife with your name on it.
Rym: No, he's fine Cuz as far as he's concerned you missed and then you went to jail and he keeps leading his life.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure.
Scott: yeah I'm sure.
Rym: Anyway, yeah now I'm gonna hold off on.
Rym: the bike spoke cuz you know Anticipation and all that.
Rym: So yeah, what do you got?
Rym: any more injuries?
Scott: There was the RIT leg injury.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that was classic.
Rym: that involves the fight club.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Rym: Oh the fight club.
Scott: So at RIT at some point I hurt my leg.
Scott: Don't ask me how I hurt my leg I hurt my leg.
Rym: It might have been in some sort of roughhousing event with Pete?
Rym: We're not.
Rym: I'd have been some roughhousing cuz there was some roughhousing with Pete previously was there?
Scott: Yeah, I don't remember.
Rym: There was some minor amount of roughhousing.
Scott: Anyway, so the roughhousing or whatever it was resulted in like this horrible bruise like a giant bruise on my leg like huge.
Scott: yes so much so that like like it didn't wasn't?
Scott: it must not have been immediate cuz like You know, it didn't like.
Scott: I woke up one day and it hurt.
Scott: it wasn't like, you know, someone hit me and then it hurt Immediately.
Scott: It was like, you know, someone must have hit me and then it over time got shitty.
Scott: and then one morning I woke up and it hurt to walk on a leg and I was like fuck Yeah, and he keeps saying to me like my leg really hurts.
Rym: It hurts.
Rym: Yeah, it hurts more and I was like go to the doctor.
Rym: I don't need to go to a doctor.
Rym: It's just a bruise.
Scott: Yeah, I looked at it looked like a bruise.
Scott: I'm walking around and it hurts to walk and kind of limping and shit.
Scott: So then I'm like, alright, whatever.
Scott: So then it gets a little better.
Scott: I'm like, oh it's getting better.
Scott: Hooray It's just a bruise.
Rym: I'm alright.
Scott: No, and then it got worse.
Scott: So I'm like, okay when something gets worse, I'm gonna go to the doctor.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I went to the school doctor and he's like Um You actually saw that they never actually put me into the school doctor.
Rym: I always got the nurses See.
Scott: at first it was nurses But apparently the only male doctor at RIT's health center at the time was a. what's the name of the doctor?
Scott: orthopedic?
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: Yeah, the one who deals with muscles and sports injuries and that sort of shit.
Scott: Orthopedics, I think right?
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, I So he like looks at it and I'm like, yeah So it was a bruise and then it hurt less and then it hurt more and now it's hard to walk really hard to walk.
Scott: and he's like, um And eventually after enough humming, he's like, alright, there might be a blood clot in your leg, which means bad stuff.
Rym: Yeah, you could die.
Scott: Yeah, so he's like so I'm gonna send you to the hospital so they can look at it.
Scott: I'm like great.
Scott: I go to the hospital and they ultrasound it and It's fine.
Scott: and I waited at the hospital for a long time because a bunch of more injured people were there in front of me as Is with hospitals, of course.
Scott: Yep so now it's late at night in the hospital and I need to get home.
Scott: so I call a cab and There's a cab that will take that.
Scott: if you're an RIT student, they'll just charge your RIT student account.
Rym: Yeah, they don't help you out.
Rym: If you're hurt at RIT.
Rym: They just make it easy for you to pay.
Scott: Yeah here Here's a free ride to the hospital in the RIT ambulance when you don't really need an ambulance.
Scott: now get home on your own.
Rym: Bitch god, remember that drive Alex back from that hospital in the blizzard.
Rym: Yeah, I'll tell that story.
Scott: That's a good one But yeah, it's someone else's injury.
Scott: We'll go with that route anyway.
Scott: So I call a cab and this one cab service where if you get in their cab and you're an RIT student It's okay because they can charge your student account.
Scott: I called that cab company, but apparently some other cab company came and I got in their cab.
Scott: I don't know by accident.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I think they work some sort of scam.
Scott: I don't know what it was But it was some sort of mix-up and I got in the wrong cab and they was like no you pay me cash now.
Scott: And I was like fuck luckily.
Scott: I had enough cash, but I left my cell phone in his car And then I got home and I still was you know hurt to walk still but I need it still needed my cell phone back.
Scott: So Rym drove me to the cab company's office and I got my phone back And they went home and it just sucked all around.
Scott: I didn't even get crutches.
Scott: I had to go back to the health center like the next day to get stupid crutches so I could fucking walk.
Rym: now the injury There.
Rym: that's not the best part of this.
Scott: What was the best part?
Scott: Oh, right, right.
Rym: You can't forget the fucking.
Scott: Oh, yeah So the injury was just so.
Scott: you know.
Scott: The injury was like a pulled muscle that you know.
Scott: It was really pulled a lot and it just got re pulled at some point because I was walking on it and maybe it was caused by your Sedentary lifestyle.
Scott: No Anyway, anyway Later what happened?
Scott: because I went to the campus health center Campus safety the security for the school came and knocked on my door and they're like were you injured recently?
Scott: and I was like, oh, yeah What what do you think?
Scott: someone beat me up?
Scott: You want me to turn them in when I don't even know how I get injured.
Scott: They're like, oh are you in some sort of fight club?
Scott: Literally literally they're like are you in a fight club?
Scott: And I almost was like, yeah me and everyone in this building we have a huge fight club.
Scott: I was gonna make up a whole big sarcastic story, but I was just like.
Scott: no This is gonna be hilarious when I tell everyone what you asked me.
Scott: And now I'm making more out of that humor, yep
Rym: so the best part is that later we wandered and we started googling, you know, like RIT fight club and we found two videos of Guys Beating the lever living shit out of it
Scott: upstairs deaf guys who wrestled with each other.
Rym: Oh, not even that.
Rym: remember that video RIT fight club.
Rym: Yeah, it was just about two country guys fighting with each other in a dorm at RIT.
Scott: I Guess there are actually, you know not fight clubs like the movie But I guess people got together to fight in sort of friendly fights of some sort because they're stupid.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: well There was that time we were all behind Gracie's fighting with sticks and then well if a safety kendo is a little different than just stupid fighting.
Scott: Yeah It's like if a guy goes to karate class, it's not the same as if he goes to fight club.
Rym: Yeah, but that wasn't kendo class.
Rym: That was all of us trying to beat katsu to death with sticks and bailing at it.
Scott: Yeah, I remember that time because I didn't really believe that anyone had magic ninja powers.
Scott: I'm like I can hit you with a fucking stick.
Rym: who couldn't hit him with a stick?
Rym: None of us could.
Scott: even we had even once we couldn't hit him with a steak.
Scott: I was like, come on.
Scott: I can hit you with a stick.
Scott: Especially we all go at you at once and no no we couldn't hit him.
Rym: He was just whirling around and he'd like poke us all with his stick.
Rym: Like I could have killed you all.
Rym: I could have killed you all again.
Rym: I could have killed you all again and we're flailing at him as hard as we can.
Rym: We couldn't do anything to him.
Scott: No, not a thing.
Scott: but I learned a lesson.
Scott: alright, so Injuries and illnesses.
Rym: Yeah, I can't hold the bicycle spoke any longer.
Scott: All right, go for it.
Rym: So I'm biking as I like to do.
Rym: I used to mountain bike heavily I'm I still I bike constantly.
Rym: I love biking.
Rym: I've had the same bike for God 12 years now It looks like the most ragged falling apart.
Rym: piece of crap, but it still works.
Rym: Now one at one time I was riding and it wasn't.
Rym: it was a cliff, but it wasn't a deep cliff.
Rym: It was like a trail through the woods and there's like a 15 or so foot drop off to the left of it And it's kind of a whiny trail.
Rym: I'm going and there's a stick kind of stuck in my front brake.
Rym: So I lean forward while I'm riding, you know not really thinking and I grab this stick and I'm gonna rip it out of my brake so I can just keep going.
Rym: and Then I hit a rock or log or something and it pushed my hand into my spokes.
Rym: Oh Now instead of my wrist breaking though I still have a mark on my wrist for my hand went into the spoke.
Rym: It just broke the spokes and flipped me over my handlebars and then I proceeded to fall down that 15 or so foot drop.
Rym: Great and I landed in this bog area.
Rym: great now the spoke had broken.
Rym: instead of my wrist Somehow I ended up with the spoke having been pushed mostly through my leg.
Rym: Okay, I was laying there.
Rym: I'm thinking I feel fine.
Rym: My wrist hurts a little but it's not broken.
Rym: So that's not so bad.
Rym: and my leg really hurts and I look and I'm like nothing's wrong with it.
Rym: Wait a minute, and there's a spoke sticking out of it.
Rym: I pulled the spoke out and there comes the blood And I thought well should I put the spoke back?
Rym: Now the thing was I was in the woods really nowhere near my house.
Rym: I didn't have a cell phone or anything.
Rym: This is high school.
Rym: I mean what we had a family cell phone back then But my parents weren't gonna.
Rym: let me take that with me biking.
Rym: It was like it was huge.
Rym: I'd lose it and expensive Yeah, so I ride my bike home and all the while I'm bleeding and my socks turning red and there's blood everywhere and I get home and I go into my house.
Rym: I'm like mom.
Rym: I had a bike accident And she comes around.
Rym: she's like well let me oh my god You're going to the hospital like what it's just it's not.
Rym: it doesn't even hurt that much.
Rym: like you're going to the hospital and I go to the doctor and I don't think it's so bad and I'm looking just a tiny little hole and Then he's like, well how deep is I'm like, I don't know.
Rym: He's like hmm and he takes a q-tip and he's poking at it and I can't see because I'm laying on my stomach And he's like, how deep do you think that is?
Rym: and I thought probably healed.
Rym: it's probably only like a centimeter or two deep.
Rym: He's like turn around and look at it and I look and you see his hand there.
Rym: Then he pulls the q-tip all the way back out of my leg And he's like you're getting a stitch.
Rym: I'm like one stitch.
Rym: He's like, yeah, we're just one.
Rym: It's all you need and I got one stitch And I got this tiny little scar on my leg where there was one stitch.
Scott: Of course, there's a giant gaping hole behind it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, they put goop Cut you there and then we'll poke his q-tip down and say I'm sure it healed by now.
Rym: Well, they will say Yeah, you put goop in there so I wouldn't get infected.
Rym: Yeah, I think I had to get a tetanus shot.
Scott: Yeah, you need one of those.
Rym: Yeah, I got a tetanus shot before when I stepped on a rusty nail in the woods.
Scott: This is one time I had tetanus, right?
Rym: No, no Yeah, I had the bubonic AIDS.
Rym: I Did have Lyme disease.
Scott: you did have Lyme disease.
Rym: Yeah Though I will preface that by saying that I spent my early years in Michigan in an area that is known as a hotbed of Lyme disease.
Rym: Lyme disease isn't that common, but there are a few areas in the world where it is very concentrated.
Scott: That's because there's a lot of fucking ticks.
Rym: I've lived in two of the top three tick infested areas.
Scott: Ticks are nasty fuckers.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No normal takes are fine.
Rym: I mean they bite you and they burrow in but you just set them on fire and rip them out.
Rym: No big deal Yep, the ticks they give you Lyme disease are so small.
Rym: You won't see it.
Rym: Well, they're dear to ya little bastard deer ticks.
Rym: They're tiny.
Rym: They're like the size of a period at the end of a sentence.
Rym: They look like a mole.
Rym: You won't even notice them.
Rym: They don't hurt or anything.
Scott: Yeah, you can't even tell that they're there unless you like.
Scott: look for them on purpose.
Scott: a magnifying glass is good for that Yep.
Rym: So, I mean whenever I go into the woods I always have to take a shower and I stand there naked for about five minutes with a mirror Looking at all my bits making sure there's no ticks on them.
Rym: It's a good idea because the worst thing is I didn't even know this until I got Lyme disease and I learned more about it.
Rym: Those little bastards will get on your leg.
Rym: They won't just bite your leg They'll crawl up your leg in your pants and then crawl over to your crotch.
Rym: There's a lot of hair to hide in there.
Rym: where they you won't get you won't catch him.
Rym: Oh, then they'll bite you.
Scott: man I would never find a tick that got into my nut hair.
Scott: He'd be totally lost.
Scott: Be like, where do you?
Scott: I didn't know he was there.
Scott: there's no way I could have known he's hiding behind him Frickin forest of black and he's got a goddamn afro down there.
Scott: Yeah, I do.
Rym: I got a goddamn Pube bro, I keep myself nicely trimmed, but that's a conversation for another day.
Scott: It is a conversation for another day.
Rym: So I got this headache and whatever.
Rym: I've had headaches before.
Rym: I got sinus problems.
Rym: The headache stayed for about a week and a half and it didn't get worse.
Rym: that didn't get better.
Rym: Imagine just a constant headache.
Scott: Uh, I don't really have headaches so often.
Scott: So that's really yeah.
Rym: Like it wasn't like I was thinking.
Rym: All right, this is weird.
Rym: Am I sick?
Rym: Then I got a little fever.
Rym: So I have a little fever and a headache.
Rym: It's now been about two and a half weeks.
Rym: Yeah, so I go to the doctor and the doctor's like you might have a brain tumor or something.
Rym: We're gonna do a whole bunch of scans.
Rym: Great, and I was like, okay and they do MRIs and all the cat scan.
Rym: They did a full-on cat scan.
Rym: my insurance paid out the ass for this.
Scott: It was doctors are so smart.
Rym: They know these tests.
Rym: he finds nothing and then after like five hours in the hospital He says take some aspirin get some rest.
Rym: You'll be fine.
Rym: call back in two weeks if it doesn't get better.
Rym: Well, then I went to Wildwood, New Jersey and I was but the headache was so bad I couldn't even go like water skiing and all the fun tubing whatever on the boat that everyone else did.
Rym: Instead I laid and that was a fun time.
Scott: You missed out.
Rym: I know I did.
Rym: Instead I laid in the beach house going fuck.
Rym: So then I go back home and I go back to the hospital.
Rym: I say I still got the headache Basted yeah, and he didn't know he had no ideas.
Rym: and then later I'm sitting there in this nurses examining me and she's like you don't happen to live near your vaster farm.
Rym: Do you?
Rym: And I said I run there almost every day to which she said alright, take off your shirt, and then she looked and sure enough in my Sub bender or no my anti bender got to keep the term straight here in the middle of my anti benders a little bull's-eye shaped kind of rash To which she said you have Lyme disease.
Scott: And I said great I'm glad you didn't bite me during that Wildwood trip.
Rym: You can't get Lyme disease from biting.
Rym: good You can only get it from dare ticks.
Scott: Well, they bite.
Scott: that's how they give it to you.
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't work that way no
Scott: but if you bit me the way a deer tick bites
Rym: if I bit your arm and Held my mouth there for about a week slowly sinking my face deeper and deeper into you without you noticing eventually dying inside of your flesh then yeah
Scott: Awesome, that would be great
Rym: now.
Rym: So I learned a lot about Lyme disease from all that and I learned that one.
Rym: it's a horrible disease that fucks you permanently Unless you catch it.
Rym: if you catch it within, you know several months of getting it.
Rym: You just take antibiotics for a couple of hours and it goes away and you're fine forever.
Rym: Yep Now some people get screwed because there's really no test for Lyme disease.
Rym: So if you don't get that little bull's-eye rash There's really most doctors have no idea They won't catch it.
Rym: and there's a guy about.
Scott: if I ever have a headache for two weeks and I've recently been in the woods I'm gonna be like I might have Lyme disease.
Scott: Can you check?
Rym: Yep I mean the worst case is they'll just make you take a horrible antibiotics for two months Which they'll make you kind of sick.
Rym: but better that than what Lyme disease does.
Rym: Oh god Yeah, because there's a guy at work who had Lyme disease for like I don't know how many years.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and then they finally found out cuz Lyme disease is kind of a new phenomena.
Scott: It was discovered recently and it's still not it's only decades old like in terms of humans knowing about it scientifically.
Rym: Yeah, it's named after that town.
Rym: Lyme is.
Rym: I think it's in Connecticut.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I think it is.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, that's like the center of Lyme disease.
Scott: Yeah, obviously Connect we were big on Lyme disease in Connecticut.
Scott: Everyone always talked about it like check for ticks.
Scott: Yeah line disease.
Rym: For when I was very young I was deathly afraid to walk into tall grass.
Rym: cuz I was like I'll get Lyme disease and I'll die Mmm, but yeah, it's fine Unless you get.
Rym: if you catch it is fine catch it as in catch the fact that you caught it.
Rym: But this is not good.
Rym: Yeah But this guy had it for years and years and then they finally figured out what it was by then it was too late.
Rym: He's got permanent arthritis and like other troubles.
Scott: Yeah, at least it's not like rabies or something.
Rym: Yeah, just death.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I was very happy.
Rym: I just took some antibiotic.
Scott: You're happy that you had Lyme disease.
Rym: I was happy that I had no long-lasting ill effects from it.
Scott: Yeah, maybe you do and just you don't realize.
Rym: now cuz I went in for the follow-up and they were like, yeah It's gone.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: All right, plus I took horrible antibiotics for two months Mmm plus a penicillin shot.
Rym: Wow, if you've ever had a penicillin shot It's syrupy and thick and it's a big-ass needle and they put it in your butt and it sucks ass.
Rym: It sucks.
Scott: It really sucks.
Scott: Yes, like most shots really don't suck like a TV test shot.
Scott: Nothing MMR nothing tetanus shot really sucks because it makes your shoulder feel like it's inflating shoulder.
Rym: I had it stuck into my leg.
Scott: Oh, I get the tetanus shots in the shoulder.
Scott: Wow, and it makes you feel like your arm is inflating like a balloon.
Scott: It sucks see.
Rym: they told me I could get have the shot wherever I wanted and they but they explained to me that it Tetanus shot.
Rym: at least if you get it in your leg.
Rym: The thing that will make a tetanus shot feel Less bad is to cut to flex the muscle a lot and work the muscle that it got injected into Mm-hmm.
Rym: So if you put it in your thigh that muscle gets worked a lot because you're walking on it all the time.
Rym: So it'll end up not hurting as much.
Scott: Yeah, maybe I don't know.
Rym: That's what the doc.
Scott: I've had a tetanus shot in a while.
Scott: Maybe I should go get another one.
Rym: You got to get one every 10 years You know, otherwise, you're not protected.
Scott: I'm not worried.
Rym: We got those freaking rusty tack things sticking up out of the carpet by the bag door.
Rym: Yeah, I step on those like every day.
Scott: Yeah, I don't step on them, but I don't know.
Scott: I don't have tetanus obviously.
Rym: Yeah, you just like to bite things.
Scott: Yeah Well, that would be rabies if I like to bite things.
Rym: so should we tell the story of the hockey puck.
Scott: Yeah, it's someone else's story, but they're not here now this one where it's better than any stories.
Scott: I've got left because I'm relatively free of illness and injury.
Rym: Yeah Though I will say preface this one story by.
Rym: we do have a moral.
Rym: the moral is if you're at a hockey game Watch out for hockey pucks.
Scott: god damn watch out for hockey pucks.
Rym: Cuz Scott and I. actually this hockey puck would have just as easily hit either Scott or me.
Scott: Okay So right at RIT college hockey game right back when they were someone hits the puck and it goes up the glass and it goes Over the glass and somehow the way he hit it.
Scott: It was basically coming across the seats Horizontally, so I'm sitting there on the side of on the long side of a hockey rink looking at the ice.
Scott: I turned to the right and as a puck where if I didn't move would have hit me right in the face Like it was coming from the side.
Scott: It was insane.
Scott: so I Duck put my head between my legs and cover the back of my head with my hands and I go fuck.
Rym: Meanwhile, I'm turning to the right and I see Scott duck and suddenly there's this black thing and it's right in front of my face and I went like I made this girly kind of scream and I put my arm up like ah and it didn't hit my arm because if it hit my arm I would have been in a bad way.
Scott: Oh You would have been in a very bad way and it.
Rym: but it was deflected slightly by my arm like it Just kind of touched my arm and I had a little mark.
Rym: and then our friend I hear crack.
Rym: We look and Alex is sitting there and we asked him did it hit you?
Rym: and he says did what hit me?
Scott: Or he said he wasn't very clear because it hit him.
Rym: We're like he like he was gone.
Rym: There was nothing there.
Scott: Yeah the puck like hit him in the in the glasses and the glasses went into his head a little bit and he was bleeding and He was just like Hawaii totally dazed.
Rym: And we're like, um, I don't remember if he actually had a concussion but he was gone.
Scott: He was totally gone and they always have ambulance guys there in case hockey players get injured.
Scott: So we're like, hey take him away.
Rym: Yeah, they right now the funny thing is whenever a puck goes into the crowd There's always this chain give it to a kid give it to a kid and everyone will keep chanting it until you give the puck To a kid.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you're not supposed to keep the puck you feel like a college.
Rym: So we're all standing up around Alex and he's sitting there.
Rym: He has no idea what's going on because he's he's.
Rym: he's hitting the head with something and the whole crowd.
Rym: Shannon give it to a kid give it to a kid and we're like he got hit and then the whole crowd stops.
Scott: They're like, oh They're like, all right, you can keep it if you got hit.
Rym: So I. they took him away and they gave me because I was the only one who had a car at the time.
Rym: They were like they.
Rym: I gave them my phone number and they said we'll call you with something and then they took him away.
Rym: So the hockey game continues.
Scott: The hockey game continued.
Scott: we were cheering.
Scott: we forgot all.
Scott: we didn't forget all about it.
Scott: But we you know, we're like woo hockey.
Rym: We kept the puck for him.
Scott: Yeah, we kept the puck.
Scott: We watched our hockey game.
Rym: we get home we get home and I get a phone call.
Rym: now keep in mind at this point a blizzard Started great.
Rym: I get a phone call.
Rym: Yeah, it's me Alex.
Rym: They let me out of the hospital.
Rym: Can you come pick me up?
Rym: I was like, alright I'll be at strong in like 15 minutes.
Rym: He says I'm not at strong strong.
Scott: If you don't know is the closest hospital to RIT.
Scott: It's an it's an okay hospital.
Rym: I say, all right, what happened?
Rym: He says well strong was full.
Rym: So the ambulance was diverted hospital was full.
Rym: There were a lot of injuries that night.
Rym: So that's they were diverted somewhere else and I asked all right Where are you?
Rym: and he says the name of a town and I've never heard that town before.
Rym: I had no idea what he said.
Rym: Great, and he didn't know where it was.
Rym: I didn't know where it was and it ended up taking me almost an hour to find the place in the blizzard.
Rym: Awesome, it was great Yeah, so if you go to a hockey game watch for pucks.
Scott: if you go to any sporting event and except for maybe basketball or Football those are pretty safe.
Rym: Yeah, how many times have you seen a basketball player like charge and miss and just hit all those people in that front row?
Scott: Maybe but mostly at baseball Hockey and I guess those are the big ones.
Scott: lacrosse could possibly hurt you soccer.
Rym: You gotta watch out for the fans Yeah But mostly baseball and hockey.
Scott: when you're at those sporting events watch the fuck out for the ball and the puck.
Scott: Oh my god pay the fuck attention.
Scott: It's not like a movie where you can just like doze off or whatever.
Scott: You gotta watch every single play to make sure the ball doesn't come and nail you.
Rym: Though in this case to Alex's credit that puck came out of nowhere.
Rym: it sure did guys We were sitting kind of low.
Scott: I didn't even realize it was out of the glass.
Scott: I just I could have been in some serious trouble if like things were different by like a half a second Yeah, even less like tenths of a second because that thing was pretty much right on track to hit you square in the forehead.
Scott: Oh god I would have done well if I wouldn't have turned to the right.
Scott: it would hit me in the side of the head like Right in the temple.
Rym: just that would have been worse.
Rym: that could have killed you.
Scott: I could have killed me.
Scott: I turned to the right.
Scott: now I would have hit me square in the forehead or right in the middle of the face.
Scott: Oh broken my nose.
Scott: God knows Yeah, and then I ducked in a. my glad I ducked.
Scott: Ooh, just makes me cringe thinking about what happened if it hit me.
Rym: All right, we've gone long so we're not gonna tell all the rest of our stories.
Scott: Oh, we have more tales of injury and illness.
Rym: I guess we'll have to save this for another.
Scott: I've already told that story of you know Food poisoning on the floor in the bathroom.
Rym: Yeah And I think I told my story of vomiting diary of food poisoning in New York City while poor Emily is sitting there holding the bucket.
Scott: Did you tell that story?
Rym: I think I did.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: That's the story needs to be told.
Rym: All right, we'll end on this story.
Rym: and the moral of this story is Don't get food poisoning because it sucks.
Scott: I think the more we'll end with the moral, but that's all right.
Rym: Yeah, but I like I don't.
Rym: I don't get sick that often Allergies which come a lot, but I don't get sick often.
Scott: I really don't get sick.
Scott: The only time I ever get sick is if I eat too much.
Scott: if I eat too much food I get like diarrhea.
Scott: and if I really eat too much food, I'll vomit.
Scott: but I haven't vomited in years.
Rym: He's like Jerry Seinfeld.
Rym: He's got the streak.
Scott: I got the street going.
Scott: no vomits.
Rym: I gotta get me some Ipecac.
Rym: put a stop to this.
Scott: No, you're not gonna put a start to it.
Scott: I'm keeping the streak alive baby.
Scott: No vomits.
Rym: I like how the closest you got to losing the streak was when I was vomiting and it almost made you feel sick.
Scott: Look is the smell of bomb.
Rym: It's really nasty yeah, so I was in New York City with Emily and I'd like our state.
Rym: we like I. basically I never really been to New York City in any capacity for walk forever.
Rym: so I went there and you know tours and hanging out and doing all sorts of things and exploring the city.
Rym: and Exploring the city meant exploring food in the city and I had a sandwich at this deli down and like down downtown.
Rym: I Got food poisoning.
Rym: I woke up the next morning and I felt kind of a and she would.
Rym: she had some homework and studying to do so.
Rym: she Was kind of give me the hint and go leave me alone go wander around Manhattan and I was very uncooperative.
Rym: I'd rather just lay here in bed.
Rym: Then I vomited.
Rym: Great I thought all right, no big deal I must have something must have been bad that I ate whatever and I think she left at this point.
Rym: So I'm alone in her like in the dorm apartment thing.
Rym: Then about an hour later I vomited again.
Scott: Fantastic.
Rym: then about 45 minutes later.
Rym: I vomited again.
Rym: Three vomits at this point.
Rym: I took some Pepto Bismol.
Scott: good job I would have done that after the first vomit, but I guess late.
Scott: better late than never.
Rym: she came back And she got me the Pepto Bismol.
Rym: Okay, then I vomited about a half hour later.
Rym: Okay, and then I vomited about 20 minutes later.
Rym: now at this point I'm not eating or drinking anything.
Rym: My body is making things for me to vomit.
Scott: great because you're already cleaned out all the way Yeah, but no diarrhea at all.
Rym: I'm getting to that.
Rym: Okay, those stuff kept coming out of my stomach.
Rym: Then one time I was vomiting and then I felt this pain and then I turned around and I sat on the toilet and then I Diarrheated and then I turned around and I vomited And it was.
Rym: the smell was so disgusting that I vomited again.
Scott: So you vomited because you were sick and then you vomited because of the sickness.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm trying to keep as much like tepid ginger ale and water down as I can.
Scott: That's a good way to go.
Rym: Meanwhile, she's got like finals and work to study for like she doesn't have time to deal with my crap.
Rym: So I'm trying to play it tough.
Rym: Like don't worry.
Scott: I just called the ambulance and let them take me away it much easier.
Rym: Well, here's the problem.
Rym: I was starting to get dehydrated.
Rym: Yeah, when you get dehydrated You get a little delirious.
Rym: So I was not in my right mind by the time.
Rym: by the time I was at the point where I needed to go To the doctor if I vomit more than twice in rapid succession.
Scott: I'm already calling the ambulance.
Scott: It's the end.
Rym: Well when I've had flus before I would vomit like that.
Rym: That was nothing new.
Scott: Yeah, I noticed.
Rym: Well that other that time you saw me vomiting was also food poisoning.
Scott: Yeah, that doesn't matter fucking lasagna.
Scott: Got them.
Rym: So by the time I got to the point where I was delirious and at which point she says I'm taking you to the Hospital good move.
Rym: So we're hobbling down the street toward the hospital with a bucket.
Rym: I don't think you need to.
Rym: I don't explain why we had the bucket.
Rym: I felt bad that.
Scott: what if you had the diarrhea in the street?
Rym: I held that in.
Rym: Oh god I barely got.
Rym: now.
Rym: from this point on I barely remember anything.
Rym: I remember walking down the street with the bucket.
Rym: I remember sitting in the cab with the bucket.
Rym: I remember the cab driver really looking at me like what's that bucket for?
Rym: He found out We get to the hospital.
Rym: the hospital doesn't take emergency room patients.
Rym: We have to go to a different hospital.
Scott: That's why I would have called the ambulance instead of doing the hospital.
Rym: Well one is New York City.
Rym: It would probably faster to go the way we did.
Scott: Yeah, the ambulances can be pretty quick depending on what's going on.
Rym: But plus it wasn't life-threatening or anything.
Rym: It just sucked.
Scott: It was almost life-threatening.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I'm sitting in the waiting room and I at this point I'm gone.
Rym: the next thing I remember is I'm laying in a hospital bed and They they're about to put an IV in me and they put an IV in me.
Rym: and that IV felt fucking great Because it was a. it was a drip of like nutrients and electrolytes and all this fun stuff.
Rym: Also an anti-nausea medication.
Scott: Ah, that's a good one.
Scott: So I don't make you feel real good.
Rym: I don't know if it was psychological or what but I could feel the good feeling coming into my arm from that thing.
Rym: Then the doctor comes over and he asks me you need anything?
Rym: and I said my back really hurts.
Scott: Did your back hurt?
Rym: Yeah, my back hurt.
Rym: I'm maybe from from being hunched over the toilet.
Rym: Yes He gave me some Percadine.
Rym: Whoo, and everything was fantastic for the next hour.
Rym: alright now the worst part is after the IV finished and They'd done all the things they could do and I was basically cured.
Rym: at this point My stomach was a little dodgy, but I was okay.
Rym: I was no longer food poisoned.
Rym: I no longer had gastroenteritis.
Rym: So she's worried because I obviously I was admitted to the hospital.
Rym: I walk out of the hospital whistling feeling great and I'm like, let's go get some dinner.
Rym: She about killed me.
Rym: Yeah, the moral is don't get food poisoning don't eat dodgy food.
Rym: Yeah, the food wasn't dodgy.
Rym: it was this nice-looking deli in downtown Manhattan and it was a good sandwich then Alright, so the moral of tonight's episode is we love morality.
Rym: turn turn turn.
Rym: Tell us the lesson that we should learn Avoid injury and illness at all cost.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: If you get food poisoning and you're vomiting a lot go to the doctor before I did You just do.
Scott: don't get injured and don't get sick.
Scott: do whatever you can to prevent it.
Scott: It's the worst thing ever Like when you're a kid, it's great because you don't really get sick when you're a kid.
Scott: You just feel kind of and you don't go to school When you're an adult.
Scott: getting sick is like the worst thing ever.
Rym: actually when I was a little kid I caught a dangerous dangerous freaking flu.
Scott: I Got like pneumonia once but then like all that did is I felt sick for one day and then I stayed home for a whole Week taking these pills, baby.
Scott: I didn't feel sick after the first day and I just watched The Price is Right and played video games All week.
Rym: I was hospitalized for the flu twice when I was a little kid.
Scott: Awesome I think I had the flu once and I was a little kid and I drank too much grape juice and I had purple vomit Coming out my mouth and nose.
Rym: One time when I had the flu when I was a kid I ate a whole bunch of green jello and Then I vomited the green jello and my little brother because he was really young at the time.
Rym: I remember him recounting the story later and he was like Brandon's mouth opened as wide as it could and a stream of green as big as his mouth just flew out.
Rym: It was all in one go.
Rym: it was like whoo.
Scott: Yeah, yeah so Do let other people near you get ill and injured because it can provide hilarity.
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure it was hilarious.
Rym: when you're laying in your bed trying to sleep and every 30 minutes you hear me go Bargo Bargo Bargo Bargo, it would have been hilarious if I wasn't trying to sleep and it wasn't so loud.
Scott: It was keeping me up.
Scott: If I could have just stood there going ha ha ha you're vomiting and I'm fine.
Rym: It was during the day that have been the greatest, you know, if you'd done that I probably would have just turned and vomited on you.
Scott: Yeah, have you vomited on me?
Scott: I would just kick you right in the nuts and then you would have vomited again on you.
Scott: It doesn't matter You'd have a kicked in nut or two or three.
Rym: Actually, I Got into a fight with a kid when I was in elementary school.
Scott: I got a lot of fights and not so many of them.
Rym: It was a normal like.
Rym: it was gonna be a normal fight.
Rym: We're standing there and we're about to.
Rym: we were like literally like second grade.
Rym: I think all right, and we're about to punch each other.
Rym: then the bastard punches me in the balls And it it pushed one of my testicles up, yeah, that's happened.
Rym: like it read.
Rym: it read undescended my testicle.
Scott: Yeah, that's happened.
Rym: Yeah, you had the same thing happen.
Scott: It's a trick is if one of your nuts I learned the trick cuz I went to the doctor you jump up and down on the heels of your feet Just and then eventually your nut will come back out.
Rym: Wait, how often does this happen to you that you need a trick?
Scott: Well, I had I'd use the trick once but I've taught the trick to other people nearby when it's happened to that.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't know the trick.
Rym: So I was fine after he punched me.
Rym: I was like you fucker.
Rym: Well, I didn't say fucker I was a little kid.
Rym: I was like you Dick.
Rym: I said dick when I was a kid for some reason I'd fuck was out of bounds, but I could say dickhead all right, and Then about for a couple hours later was like there's a pain and it's getting worse.
Rym: and it's getting worse.
Rym: and oh god I went to the doctor and they're like, I'm gonna make you not fall back down And he made my nut fall back down.
Rym: Yeah, then he taught me how to make it fall down.
Rym: if that ever happened again Just jump up and down stand on the heels of your feet only and jump up and down now also Don't like be careful with it because if it's your leg can kind of crush it in there.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, you know what go.
Scott: you'll know because you'll feel you're like crushing it in there.
Rym: Yeah, it's a sensitive thing.
Scott: But I mean like you happen to me once and I learned the trick from someone and then it happened to someone in gym class.
Rym: So I told him the trick and you know, yeah tomorrow there if someone punches you in the balls It fall down because that's all you can do.
Rym: Yeah, but as soon as you get back up I don't care how good a friend they are punch them right in the ball.
Scott: No kick them.
Scott: You got to get your shin right across the whole groin just straight up.
Scott: just wham That's the best way.
Rym: no, no, cuz the punch is better you stand up and you're like you asshole But you act like you're like that was funny though, ha ha ha.
Rym: and then you're like, alright, whatever.
Rym: And then as soon as he moves to like shake hands or anything, then you punch him in the balls.
Rym: His name was Ricky and I never got back at it.
Scott: Oh, maybe we meet him one day.
Scott: You can just kick him right in the frickin.
Rym: just I don't even know his last name.
Rym: I barely knew my last name.
Rym: I still remember in like preschool or whatever.
Rym: We'd ever name tags, and I didn't know my last name, but it was there.
Rym: Mmm, I knew my first name and I was always mad because kids with shorter first names could finish their homework quicker.
Scott: All right, this episode got real long so I guess you picked an okay topic then.
Rym: yeah Yay Tell us all your funny or horrible injury stories in the forums.
Rym: Well, I'll have a good laugh.
Scott: Yep and Come up with ideas for Thursday shows.
Scott: pretty much anything is okay as long as it doesn't involve science technology Video games board games role-playing games anime manga or comics.
Rym: Yeah, and we've got a lot that were already suggested and we're going to do those at some point.
Scott: Yeah, all the but the problem is a lot of the things that aren't just talking about a geekery require lots of effort.
Scott: So come up with something that also doesn't require effort.
Rym: Yeah, tell us what you want to hear.
Rym: We've got stuff We want to say.
Rym: tell us what you want to hear because the basic feedback we always get is we love it.
Rym: Would you just tell stories?
Scott: Well, we're running out of stories.
Scott: Not really.
Rym: Not really, but it's you know We're running out of stories that we can tell with some sort of pretext like blah blah blah video games.
Rym: Oh, well when I was little video game story.
Rym: Yeah, most of our stories are gonna be alright.
Rym: I'm gonna tell a completely unrelated story.
Rym: go Yeah, we're trying to avoid that.
Rym: I With Rym and Scott special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1 5 3 7.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.