Scott: It's Tuesday February 7th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We talk about fear and Through the desert.
Scott: let's do this.
Scott: so today was yet another.
Scott: go to work and do not so much day I don't know.
Rym: I had a good day.
Scott: I went and I actually took a wrong turn and I went around in a circle a little bit and then I got to work, and they didn't do much, and okay, okay?
Rym: So if you didn't do anything then why you bother and telling everyone out there that you didn't do anything?
Scott: I did some stuff.
Rym: Yeah You said you didn't.
Rym: you said today was just a boring crap day.
Rym: Why even bring it up?
Rym: Why not just get right into the news?
Scott: Because that's what you're saying before we started.
Rym: now before we started I said let's get into the news since you obviously don't have any.
Rym: yeah Mmm.
Scott: You said let's get in the news, and I didn't want it cuz we never do that.
Rym: Yeah, but you didn't have anything to say before the news.
Scott: I was gonna talk about how boring it was.
Scott: Okay It was real boring.
Rym: Yeah great anyway.
Scott: So um While I was being bored at work Apple decided to release the awaited and rumored Nano that only has one gigabyte of space.
Rym: great, so they released a crappier Nano.
Scott: Well the thing is is only 150 bucks, so if you're poor wait a minute.
Scott: 150 bucks for a one gigabyte Nano.
Rym: Yep, how much is it for the bigger one?
Scott: the 2 gig is 200 and the 4 gig is 250.
Rym: All right, I mean I I love music and I like little mp3 players But I just really don't see any of those being worth that much money.
Scott: Well the 1 gig shuffle was a hundred But now the 1 gig shuffle has been discounted because the 1 gig Nano exists.
Scott: So if you really wanted a 1 gig shuffle now's the time.
Scott: yeah, I don't really see the point of the shuffle.
Scott: I mean you don't know what you're gonna listen to.
Rym: I guess the point of it was that it's cheap.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean if you're a podcast listener that doesn't really help because you can't select episodes or anything.
Scott: I guess it's good.
Scott: If you have just a lot of music that you want to put on shuffle Then I guess the shuffle works.
Scott: or if you're exercising it doesn't weigh anything.
Scott: You don't care if you drop it, so I guess it's good for that, too.
Rym: Yeah, they usually when I exercise I watch TV like an anime or something.
Scott: well What if you're like you know running around the hills and if I'm running I don't want to have music with me.
Rym: I want to enjoy where I am Whatever.
Scott: a lot of people run around with music on.
Rym: yeah, I just find that kind of plus.
Rym: if you get all sweaty I mean you can't really wear normal headphones.
Rym: They're big and heavy.
Rym: if you wear earplugs.
Rym: They'll just get all sweaty and nasty.
Rym: There's really no easy way.
Scott: I don't know the ones I have be alright.
Rym: Yeah, let's see you wear those and work up a good sweat.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: All right, try it someday.
Scott: Well, what do you think will happen?
Rym: it gets all yeah as those sweat pools around the outside of the plug and start seeping in.
Scott: I don't know about you my ears.
Rym: Don't collect sweat in them, and you've never had a good workout.
Scott: I Think you just got some problems with your ears sweat glands.
Rym: If I go out for an hour run by the time I come back I pretty much look like I've been running in a rainstorm.
Scott: Anyway, so there's one gig nano.
Scott: um I guess it does everything my nano does and you know I actually I checked and I don't really have more than a gig of stuff on my four gig nano.
Rym: But Yeah, if I can get a nano for less than a hundred bucks That's when I'm gonna jump ship and buy an iPod.
Scott: I don't think that's gonna happen.
Rym: I don't think I'm gonna buy an iPod and don't get one.
Scott: You can get one of those other Brands that make things that aren't as good.
Rym: see the thing is honestly as much as I listen to music I really have no need for a small portable music player Mmm.
Rym: I mean I listen to music in my car.
Rym: I listen to music in my computer room, and I listen to music in the house.
Rym: and when I'm out I'm really only out doing things.
Rym: I really never.
Rym: I mean I can't listen to music so much at work since I'm doing a lot of tech support or walking around The line talking to people.
Scott: no I listen to music at work.
Rym: Yeah, you're a coder.
Rym: You just sit there and code.
Scott: listen to music in the car.
Scott: I listen to music between work in the car.
Scott: Listen to music on the train.
Rym: when you listen to music between you don't ride the train anymore.
Scott: No when I did Yeah, but you don't anymore listen to music.
Scott: You know whenever.
Rym: if I had a train ride I guess whenever and if I had a train ride or something I'd probably definitely have an iPod.
Scott: you think that I could use the iPod in your car with your broken CD player.
Scott: I'll just play CDs In your broken CD player now.
Rym: I fixed it.
Scott: Yeah, that's not what happened last time.
Scott: We were in the car.
Rym: I worked just fine.
Rym: The only thing is that doesn't work when it's really humid out.
Rym: the iPod works in all weathers, and you know it was really humid.
Rym: Honestly, I'll just listen to NPR cuz that's free.
Scott: Yeah, I mostly download NPR so I don't to listen all the stupid ads Except for the see.
Rym: when there's ads I switch to the other NPR station.
Rym: That's on a different schedule.
Scott: Yeah, I had two MPRs in the same place.
Rym: Yeah, well.
Rym: It's weird this area.
Rym: We live in an area.
Rym: There's a lot of mountains so radio stations come and go crazily And I actually lose an NPR station on my way to work and have to switch to another one anyway.
Rym: Yeah Wow, it's good even though.
Rym: I honestly I drive five minutes to work.
Rym: I live right there.
Scott: Yeah, but see that's what iPods are all about.
Scott: is you just download it listen to it.
Scott: You don't have to worry about fiddling with stations or anything.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it's just not worth the money to me.
Rym: I'm kind of a cheapskate that I just I'm not that Interested in a lot of these expensive gadgets.
Rym: I mean I like them and if I had them for free I'd use them left and right, but I've been.
Scott: you change your mind every day.
Scott: one day You're like yeah I'm getting an anno as soon as I get this money.
Scott: see I saw that and then and then you're like I'm not getting one.
Scott: It's too expensive.
Scott: They don't like I'm totally getting one real soon.
Rym: Yeah, I point out that I've stayed constant and that oftentimes I think oh I'd really like one.
Rym: But then when it comes down to like a go to the site and I go to buy it and then I like oh yeah Cost that much money for that much money.
Rym: I can go to another con, and then I go to the con instead.
Scott: Why don't you go to the con and?
Rym: Get the Nana which is what I do because instead of spending my extra income on gadgets I'm dumping it all into my student loans, and they're going away real quick.
Scott: I could do that, too.
Rym: You know you make less money than me plus.
Rym: You don't really go to so many cons.
Rym: I guess I have more expenses of that regard and it's not that much money.
Rym: Set me back over 300 bucks at least as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: anything less than $500 at this point is just blue.
Rym: Then give me four hundred ninety nine dollars now.
Scott: Yeah, I just I just make a lot of money now, and it seems that you know at the beginning I was being all frugal like a college guy was you know?
Scott: and I had piles and piles of money Just piling up, and I was like you know what I can buy stuff, and I even though I buy stuff I still manage to pay everything and still have money left over.
Rym: see I don't buy stuff so much But I spend a lot of money on Travels and eating out and events and various lots of money on travels and eating out.
Rym: no I really you don't.
Scott: yeah, I do.
Rym: I mean I'll point out that when I was living out here alone before you moved out Pretty much every weekend.
Rym: I drove many hours to various places I spent.
Rym: I spend more money on conventions and food than I do and I think anything else in my life except all my student loans.
Scott: I spent just as much money on outside food as you do if not more.
Rym: I Highly doubt that.
Scott: and then you only go to like two or three conventions.
Scott: I don't go to.
Rym: Yeah, you know let's see Katsu cons gonna.
Rym: Send me back about 300 bucks.
Rym: so 300 all right.
Rym: Oh, and amazement is gonna.
Rym: Send me back at least 500 cuz I got a fly there.
Rym: all right all right That's already a lot of money right there 800 bucks.
Scott: It's not even a thousand dollars.
Scott: Yeah, it's not even thousands and thousands of extra money.
Rym: bad ass computer.
Scott: I have.
Scott: I have thousands upon thousands of extra dollars I'm not using.
Rym: yeah, I'm also at a car.
Scott: I went to those cons.
Scott: I would still have thousands of dollars left.
Rym: all right fine, and then be happy in your money bags.
Scott: richness I am.
Rym: I mean I make more money than you, but I also spend more money than you.
Scott: I don't know what the hell you're spending it on.
Scott: that's that's the real just amazing thing.
Rym: mostly I spend it on my loans.
Scott: I spend money on my loans, too.
Rym: I put almost a thousand dollars every month into my various student loans.
Scott: I could do that, and I'd still be okay.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I'm doing that now, and then all my extra money.
Rym: I spent on other stuff.
Scott: Why the hell you're buying.
Scott: you must be getting ripped off by someone or maybe you have a secret mafia payment You're making.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: it must be.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: What else happened today?
Scott: Well?
Rym: I'm also subsidizing your ass in the rent for the past seven months.
Scott: It's like chump change 200 bucks.
Scott: whatever it adds up It doesn't add up very quickly.
Rym: you owe me almost a thousand dollars if I wanted that back.
Scott: It's like nothing.
Rym: all right think of me a thousand dollars not a chance, but you just said it was nothing.
Scott: Yeah, I'm still not gonna.
Scott: Give it to you.
Rym: Why not.
Scott: It's nothing you don't care because if you're cheap bastard I'm gonna be one, too.
Rym: It's just that I really often don't see the benefit At least for the money like I'd love a laptop But it's not worth the money would take to get a laptop that I would like.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: a lot of times though you you know you don't see the benefit of things And then you get him and then you're like oh my god.
Scott: This is the greatest thing ever.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if I get something.
Rym: I mean if I just had a laptop now.
Rym: It'd be awesome.
Rym: I use it forever, but it's not worth the money to get one.
Rym: I mean, I really want a MacBook and I was almost thinking about buying one.
Rym: But I decided against that because I'd rather go places and do a bunch of stuff with that money, or you can do both.
Rym: No, not really because I want to pay off my debt.
Rym: I'm not gonna put less money into my student loans.
Rym: I want those gone as soon as possible.
Scott: You can do all three.
Rym: see about all right.
Rym: No.
Rym: I really can't.
Scott: What the hell is your money going?
Scott: Oh my god, okay?
Scott: I can pay for this car.
Scott: Oh, I just don't get it To check your accounting sometime.
Scott: Money's going.
Rym: see keep in mind that I have many different student loans.
Rym: You just have that one.
Scott: Yeah, it's a big one.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I have that one, but I Think it's like bigger than my car loan.
Scott: It's twice as long.
Rym: I mean let's say I put like 800 bucks a month into my student loans.
Rym: I put 250 month into my car payment.
Rym: I put about a hundred and fifty a month into car insurance.
Rym: I Put about 600 a month into rent.
Rym: The money adds up.
Rym: plus I pay more taxes because I've been working here for a long time.
Rym: So I mean these last two years I've paid the full taxes as though I made all that money and since I'm not a student anymore I paid over 10 grand in taxes this year, and I'm not gonna get much of it back.
Scott: Oh, maybe I paid almost 10 grand in taxes And I'm not gonna get my stupid New York State taxes back those bastards, but I think I'm gonna get my like many 5g's I think of federal taxes back Which should be nice because that cancels my car down payment, which is why I made a $5,000 down payment on the car.
Scott: That was my logic right there.
Scott: Yeah, just get it right back.
Scott: I should do those taxes All right.
Rym: um Yeah, so to get off that tangent Nintendo.
Rym: There's a nice little interview here on Forbes with Perrin Kaplan.
Scott: she's probably the VP of something At the end of something.
Rym: Perrin Kaplan the vice president of marketing and corporate affairs for Nintendo Nintendo
Scott: Europe Nintendo Japan Nintendo
Rym: America
Scott: The
Rym: only one that really matters here for us at least
Scott: yeah,
Rym: and they're just talking about Nintendo's blue ocean strategy, and how a lot of analysts say they're gonna blow Microsoft and Sony out of the water.
Scott: yeah Well, it's just basically.
Rym: you know the it seems to be having every market these days But you see forward claim that they were a blue ocean Company and they kind of fucked themselves.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't get it blue ocean means it's sort of like an analogy pertaining to pioneering and exploring in that It's currently an ocean where all the customers are and people are fighting in that ocean to Over which customers go to who and that's the red ocean because it's filled with the blood of battle.
Rym: Well, it's.
Rym: the blue ocean is a finite resource.
Rym: There's a finite number of people in it and a finite number of resources to spend.
Scott: Yeah, the idea of blue ocean is that there's a bunch of people who aren't in any one's you know customer And you would go over and say I'm not fighting with you guys anymore over this red ocean.
Scott: I'm gonna go sail into this brand new blue ocean over there.
Scott: That's now.
Rym: Specifically is that Nintendo.
Rym: I mean currently there's a market of gamers and gamers as defined by Microsoft and Sony and there's a limited number of them and You can only get so many of them from the pie and so many is just pretty much winning that.
Rym: but war.
Scott: it is a demographic primarily consisting of teenage boys who like FPS's and Grand Theft Auto's and racing games and sports games.
Rym: So Nintendo is trying to go into different waters and get people who aren't currently in that market into the market and into the Market under Nintendo's name.
Scott: Yeah, which basically says alright, we obviously can't make games to Get all those guys to buy Nintendo games instead of Sony games.
Scott: Let's get all these other people mommies and kids and dads and grandpas and casual
Rym: gamers
Scott: everyone else in the world to buy Nintendo games and that way the only customers that Sony and Microsoft will have will be teenage boys and Like
Rym: and it seems to be working really well.
Rym: They talk here about how the DS is basically kick the PSP's ass.
Scott: Yeah, the DS is just You know beating the shit.
Scott: the DS is so crazy in Japan that they're re importing them from the u.s.
Rym: They sold 13 million DS units last year and all of Nintendo's portals combined have 82% of the portable Software sales market.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty nuts.
Rym: Yeah, 82% of game consoles out there that are portable are Nintendo Mm-hmm.
Scott: It's mostly GBA which is like 50 plus percent.
Rym: Yeah, though the DS is coming in strong Yes is coming in very strong And also the PSP even though it has sold fairly well in the u.s.
Rym: None of the games forward have sold at all Really?
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's it's being purchased and they count it in terms of market share in terms of who has the most, you know Video game portable hardware is out there and you look at the numbers and there's a bunch of PSP's out there.
Scott: But they're not really being used to play games.
Scott: They're being used to play ROMs and to UMD movies and downloaded movies and that sort of thing.
Rym: Yeah, how's that?
Rym: Most people buy a DS and play Nintendo games.
Rym: Everyone else buys a PSP to play Nintendo games.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty hilarious.
Rym: The other thing is that Nintendo.
Rym: this is kind of an interesting distinction But it's kind of like the difference between how Otakon reports its attendance and how anime Expo reports its attendance.
Rym: But Sony reports every unit that is sold or shipped to a distributor or to a retail outlet.
Rym: Nintendo counts things that are sold to a customer.
Scott: Well, that's just old, you know company Accounting numbering talk.
Scott: Yeah, you know if you're winning you always report, you know The most impressive number that you can report, you know that makes it still look like you're winning.
Scott: and if you're losing you Report the most impressive number that you can report to make it look like you're not losing by that much.
Rym: true though Nintendo has always made a point of reporting that number at least even when they were losing with the Like the GameCube when they were in second place.
Rym: by far They didn't try to pretend they were doing better than they were.
Scott: well because the number that they were showing was still you know It was accurate enough.
Scott: If that number I guarantee you if the number of GameCube sold was like one and the number of GameCube sold to stores was A million they wouldn't be saying we've sold one GameCube.
Rym: I don't know if they seem to stand by that that practice of only reporting direct sales.
Scott: They would be like a million GameCube shipped.
Scott: That's what they would be doing.
Rym: Anyway, but Sony very specifically just kind of backs off this and doesn't say where their numbers come from.
Scott: Companies keep a lot of secrets that are all weird for no reason.
Scott: I mean if you try to ask anyone from Gillette how long the razor blades should go before there's changed They'll never tell you.
Rym: Oh, I know the answer about two shaves.
Rym: Those things are such pieces of crap.
Scott: Oh my god, actually a lot of people are.
Scott: there's a big Conspiracy going around the net.
Scott: people like you never have to change them.
Scott: You can buy a Mach 3 and use it for a year.
Rym: What?
Scott: no you can't I know I don't know what these people.
Scott: they must be shaving themselves with like just flat pieces of metal.
Scott: I don't know what the hell.
Rym: I mean, these are probably the same people who say if you put acetone in your gas tank You'll get better gas mileage.
Scott: Yeah and explode your gas tank.
Rym: Actually, no, it probably won't cause any damage other than maybe to your catalytic converter.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to mess that up though.
Scott: You can get in trouble Only if you're in a state that has emissions testing, you know My car actually has this emissions equipment because New York has evil testing Every all the exhaust goes through my catalytic converter two times before it leaves the car.
Scott: It's crazy.
Rym: That's probably a good thing because the county we live in has been trying to have Admissions testing as part of its inspection for a long time and I'm kind of for it because it'll really screw all those frickin rice Boys with their giant loud fart pipes.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but I always seem to drive by our house late at night If you have a fart pipe or and thank you You should totally be busted but I mean running it through twice.
Scott: It's like alright, what is that?
Scott: How much does it really buy you?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, how much does it hurt you?
Rym: There's what six horsepower something like that.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Rym: It's probably worth it.
Rym: Safety I see the thing is six or seven horsepower.
Rym: unless you took the car on a track and did many many laps You do there's no way you can even begin to notice that.
Scott: no, I don't really notice anything.
Scott: the car goes fine But you know, the emissions doesn't really benefit me in any way whatsoever.
Rym: Does you know environment pollution etc?
Scott: All the things I don't care about.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so things of the day.
Rym: Well when I was in high school for any of you who don't know me I was real big into marching bands and drum cores and there was a time when I considered pursuing it professionally instead of going into IT Bando.
Rym: Yeah, what do you want?
Rym: I mean the band I marched in.
Rym: we put over 200 people on the field and we were fairly well Renowned.
Rym: we used to travel all over the country competing.
Rym: It was a lot of fun.
Scott: Yeah, you know bragging about your high school marching band is something that most people look down upon.
Rym: Hey, it was fun.
Rym: I would say that the band I was in in high school was pretty much the all I cared about from high school Everything.
Rym: I got out of high school.
Rym: I got out of that band.
Scott: Just keep on insulting yourself.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: I had a good time.
Scott: It's a sad.
Scott: the band in my high school was the greatest.
Scott: Oh my god It's like you see a guy doing that and you're like roll in your eyes Whatever.
Rym: I had a good time.
Rym: band camp was fun.
Scott: Yeah, and no matter what it was for you.
Rym: Everyone else looks at it like My school was kind of weird and that honestly people really didn't care about the football team or anything and They'd come and watch the halftime show and then everyone would leave and then the football team would lose.
Scott: Yeah, our school had a band too and there are plenty of people who were into it and everyone else was like Oh those freaking bandos.
Scott: They're all freaking me.
Rym: Yeah It was fun.
Rym: I had to go March in the Citrus Bowl and all that crap.
Scott: But anyway, they all did really into it.
Rym: I used to go watch marching band competitions like the actual drum cores and My thing of the day is a nice Google video compilation of some of the cooler.
Rym: I guess sets that people have done over the years Mm-hmm.
Rym: So if you've never seen marching bands like real marching bands Not like a high school marching band But like a professional marching band doing its thing.
Rym: at least give these videos a look because it's really interesting.
Scott: I think it's a neat sport and it really it's not a sport.
Rym: first of all, actually It's very much a physical competitive sport and there are competitions all over the country.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: I don't consider it.
Rym: It's a competition.
Scott: It is a competition.
Rym: It's a sport.
Rym: in so in as far as say figure skating is a sport Yeah That's how I'm gonna say.
Scott: is it's more like figure skating and less like football because it's more like a subjective thing with the scoring It's not so much a points getting thing.
Rym: Yeah, but I still say it's a sport.
Scott: I don't even think figure skating is a sport.
Scott: for me Sports are games has to be a game where if there is also an athletic component That's what a sport is to me.
Scott: Anyway, that's that's my because you know Everyone likes to have arguments over.
Scott: that's a sport and that's not.
Scott: and that is and that isn't you know, and all that bullshit Wait a minute.
Rym: So, uh Nanofictionary.
Rym: it say there's a game where the only Determining factor and who wins is a subjective judgment by external people.
Scott: It's not a game.
Rym: So nanofictionary isn't a game?
Scott: Not really, oh, okay.
Scott: It's not a game.
Scott: See, that's the thing in.
Scott: in the dictionary There are multiple definitions for the word game as there are for many words, you know There's game one game two game three.
Scott: when I say game in this context.
Scott: Anyway, I mean the game Definition that talks about like, you know competition winning and losing and all that.
Scott: There's another definition for game.
Scott: That's pretty much just means fun thing you do, you know, it's like.
Scott: oh a fun pastime.
Scott: an activity of enjoyment You know is a game.
Scott: and in terms of activity of enjoyment sure nanofictionary is a game.
Scott: but in terms of like, you know a serious competition of Luck skill or ability or whatever nanofictionary is not Alright, well, I disagree, but I definitely prescribed to a broader definition of game.
Rym: But anyway, if you've never seen a marching band like a real one check out this video.
Rym: it's cool.
Rym: if you have seen them then check these guys out because there's some of the best in the world and That's all I got to say about that.
Scott: Yeah, so I like Merchandise like especially merchandise.
Scott: You can't get consumer haul.
Scott: Well, it's really.
Scott: I don't know if I like it because I can't get it or because I didn't wasn't able to get it I don't know.
Scott: But the point is is there a lot of cool things out there that you can't buy in stores Because they're from Japan and they usually involve Nintendo?
Scott: and I already got one of them and it was a little diorama.
Scott: When like I didn't realize and I got the diorama.
Scott: But Mario is like a magnet and you can move them around with this magnet and it's really really cool.
Scott: But the latest trend is these things called dots.
Scott: Did you ever play with like light bright or anything?
Rym: I Had a light bright.
Rym: I liked it a little bit and then I got tired of it.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much how light bright goes.
Scott: But imagine if you had a light bright that didn't light up so it was crummier, but at the same time it came with.
Scott: It was horrible.
Scott: it came with Dot, all right.
Rym: Wow, basically, these are just little Nintendo things where you can put pixels from various pallets to make various Nintendo sprites.
Rym: It's awesome to put it very succinctly since Scott was gonna go off on something.
Scott: Yeah, so the newest one there's one where you can make Mario and a goomba and stuff.
Scott: But the newest one you can make blue ring link and give dough and the ghost from the graveyard and you don't know the ghost Name, I forget the ghost name.
Scott: I'd remember it if you said it like.
Scott: you said a bunch of things and said which one of those is the name of the Ghost in the graveyard.
Scott: I'd say that one.
Scott: But I don't remember The blue.
Scott: he's not a tech tight a lever the guys come out of the ground or levers a Goria a blue Goria.
Rym: I remember a long time ago.
Rym: We had an argument It was a fierce one about what the name of the first sword in Zelda 1 was.
Rym: Oh guys Remember there's the white sword and the master sword.
Scott: Yeah, you can make the white sword and the magic shield with this set.
Scott: No, dude Oh, you can also make the normal shield.
Rym: But anyway, but there's the original sword and I had always called it the red sword because it was red.
Scott: I had always called it the wooden sword because I remember seeing the words wooden sword somewhere and it was brown.
Scott: What other sword is brown?
Scott: It's not made of metal unless it's a rusted.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So we argued about this for quite some time and then I remembered that I actually had the original Instruction book and I dug it out and I opened it and you know, it was called sword Thus or it wasn't even called the sword.
Scott: It was just called sword.
Rym: So yeah, that's that anecdote.
Scott: You know you want to do?
Scott: you want to get four freaking heart containers before even beating any levels and go get the white sword.
Scott: That's useful because the sword sucks unless you're one of those awesome guys who beats the game with sword.
Rym: Well, anyway, since today is a video game board game and etc.
Rym: day Yeah, well first of all, like we said yesterday we were in Rochester over the weekend and between the two of us We bought a hundred and eighty dollars worth of board game a lot of board games And you know what?
Scott: We're going to uber con this weekend.
Scott: We're gonna get more games from.
Rym: Yeah We're gonna get more games and then play all the games we bought.
Scott: so Expect at least one or two German board games a week for the next few weeks on Tuesdays.
Rym: now today We're gonna talk about through the desert which is a fun little pastel camel game.
Scott: We've played it a long time ago, but we recently got it again.
Rym: Yeah, because kind of cheap but also Scott I didn't get to play it.
Rym: My computer's slow and I don't have windows but Scott played the fear demo that we had talked about a while ago.
Scott: Yeah, it was that new PC game.
Scott: fear Fears pretty much.
Scott: I installed it.
Scott: It was 600 megs.
Scott: I got the single-player demo because I didn't really want to play any multiplayer business and it was an FPS.
Scott: and the first thing I got to say about it is I had to sit through about five to ten minutes of cinematic.
Scott: I can't control anything stuff before I could play what?
Scott: Yeah, I mean What is up with games trying to be movies these days?
Rym: You know, it's not a new trend at all.
Scott: I know it's not a new trend but when games started doing that I stopped playing the games.
Scott: that did it.
Scott: so You know, I don't know.
Scott: I just really don't like not being able to control stuff.
Scott: I remember the first time I saw Final Fantasy 9 the first like 20 minutes.
Scott: You really didn't do anything.
Scott: You just watch plot happen and I was just like goddamn If I'm not doing stuff, why am I playing a game?
Scott: Just make a movie.
Scott: That's the first thing about fear.
Scott: the second thing is Let's talk about the FPS ness of it.
Scott: It's a pretty standard FPS.
Scott: you walk.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Shoot you reload You can use any weapon as melee so you can like hit people with any gun.
Scott: That was pretty nice.
Scott: Uh-huh, you can lean left and right which soldier of fortune had a long time ago.
Scott: So it's not a big deal.
Rym: I never really liked games that had that.
Rym: it never seemed very realistic feeling to do it.
Scott: It doesn't seem realistic feeling but When you do it, it's pretty much like I can hide behind this and then you know Shoot and then hide again without going up.
Scott: You can do it to the left to the right.
Scott: so You know how like when you're aiming at a guy behind a crate and you're just aiming above above the crate because you know He's gonna pop up if you have this mechanic You you don't know if you have to aim to the left right or above the crate because the guy can pop out on any side.
Scott: That's what that's about.
Scott: But anyway, it doesn't have really anything special.
Scott: I got to use about four or five different guns during the demo and all of them were pretty boring.
Scott: I mean the pistol shot the submachine gun shot a lot of things really fast and all over the place, too.
Scott: I couldn't control the accuracy for crap.
Scott: There was some sort of assault rifle, which is also kind of crummy, you know, I guess it killed guys pretty well But I don't know there was a shotgun that didn't really feel like a shotgun and I don't know I didn't like any of the guns.
Rym: So what was the game?
Rym: just an FPS?
Scott: Well, I can see the reason that people are making a big deal out of this.
Scott: It's because it was an FPS sort of combined with a Resident Evil kind of scariness.
Rym: Wait a minute So you'll be walking around and then something will jump through a window in front of you.
Scott: Sometimes yeah That.
Scott: the other thing is the bad guys do all sorts of acrobatic things Like I went to this right through a grenade into a room and the bad guy Jumped out the wind through the glass of the room out on to like the catwalk and then tried to shoot
Rym: on the catwalk.
Scott: yeah, and I can see how people think that's cool.
Scott: and You know in that one part of the demo it was pretty cool.
Scott: It's like oh look they gave the AI the ability to do some stuff.
Scott: But later the bad guys were like running around jumping and doing acrobatics.
Scott: that didn't really help them strategically and I just killed them.
Rym: Great so it's not like they're freaking ninjas in half-life that just flew around and killed you and you could barely see him.
Scott: Yeah, this is like the bad guys are normal bad guys, but they try to do.
Scott: you know They try to give them cinematic action movie abilities, but they don't actually use it strategically They just use it for show.
Scott: It's very cinematic.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Now.
Scott: The one thing the game has is has this slow motion Which I figured would be all cool like matrixness because the part of the plot is that you're you have advanced reflexes So you push a button for slow motion and the game slows down which gives you the opportunity to like shoot a bunch of guys.
Scott: Or you know, I don't know.
Scott: the problem with this was is it slowed me down?
Scott: Also, so that made it pretty much completely useless in every way I can imagine.
Rym: I don't know really.
Scott: I could see how that would give you more time to react to something I Guess but what I really wanted was slow down time and I go around killing everyone and then time stops being slowed down Because I'm also slowed down.
Scott: sure I can get a perfect headshot and every guy shoot, but I move so slow I can't really get enough shots off and I can't really move very fast.
Scott: So like you want to use the slow motion when you're in a dangerous situation like guys are shooting at you But if you turn it on now, you're going so slow.
Scott: You can't really run away So you're just taking the damage in slow motion.
Rym: Well, maybe the slow-mo should be used in different situations.
Scott: Maybe it wasn't intended the way you're trying to use it Maybe but they told you when you're in a tight spot use the slow motion to you know Make out.
Scott: so I don't know.
Scott: Uh-huh I couldn't figure out any use for it.
Scott: but maybe if you had really bad FPS skills and really bad aim and Maybe because the guns are really wildly inaccurate You would turn the slow-motion on and then pick guys off with a pistol to conserve ammo just shooting him in the head.
Scott: perfectly you know, but if you can probably only get two shots off in the time the slow-motion lasts and The game gave you all sorts of med kits that you could like save for later.
Scott: So you never died anyway.
Scott: Then the last thing that happened in the demo was the scary part.
Scott: Whoo Where they're like?
Scott: this ghost is like jumps out at you And of course the ghost is some little girl who you can't see your face.
Rym: Okay, typical scary Japanese thing.
Scott: Yeah, what the hell is up with using little tiny girls to be the scariest thing?
Rym: Well the first time someone did that it was really scary because it's just this incongruous kind of strange thing.
Rym: But it seems like everything's doing it lately.
Rym: So if I see a little girl, I immediately think wow, she's the horrible evil.
Scott: Yeah It's like occasionally like they would jump out at me like I opened a door and all of a sudden the room was upside down and the girl was standing on the ceiling and blood was dripping from the walls and they couldn't open the door.
Scott: and well and I as soon as it happened, I was like ooh something happened.
Scott: But then while it was happening, I was like, oh whatever It's just stupid scary crap.
Scott: And then as soon as I was about to fight something big and with this nice rockety type But it wasn't really a rocket launcher is pretty much a thing that shot had held very few ammo and shot big powerful shots.
Scott: The demo ended.
Scott: Great I guess I can't really, you know, make that a complaint against the game itself.
Scott: It's just a complaint against the demo which of course they do that on purpose to make you want to buy the game.
Rym: I guess it doesn't sound terribly intriguing.
Scott: No, it's just an FPS with some fancy graphics stuff and some I guess quote Horror, I mean to admit we're pretty jaded about FPS is yeah I mean, I mean we grew up through the.
Rym: you know Doom 2, oh my god is the greatest thing ever.
Rym: Quake 2, it's the most moddable thing ever.
Rym: Counter-Strike It's the best game ever.
Rym: Quake 3, wow It's not as good as Quake 2.
Scott: This game really didn't have anything that Soldier of Fortune 1 Didn't have.
Scott: and Soldier of Fortune 1 I think was one of the best single-player FPS's there is and this really doesn't.
Rym: Honestly, I want to put big props in to Duke Nukem 3D.
Scott: Duke Nukem 3D is great But have you played Soldier of Fortune 1?
Rym: Actually, yeah, and I do really like it.
Scott: Yeah, it's a really that's one of the best single-players except for like Half-Life 1 and 2.
Scott: Yeah, but this really It just didn't offer me anything new and it wasn't particularly exciting.
Scott: Maybe if it had come out before Soldier of Fortune 1 I would have been like, oh And treated it just like it was Soldier of Fortune 1, but as far as I'm concerned It's that game with new graphics and some scariness.
Rym: Well, there you have it.
Rym: Yep And I guess moving on to the German board game tonight, Through the Desert It's one of the Rainer Knizia tile laying trilogy, even though they're not all really tile laying.
Scott: I guess it's tile laying because you just replace the camels with tiles and there you go.
Rym: Yeah I read somewhere that people talked about how tile laying trilogy was just a mistranslation of something you said once and then it kind of Stuck.
Scott: Yeah Well, you know you release three games in a row that are sort of tile laying.
Scott: ish and that's what people are gonna say.
Rym: But it's a Rainer Knizia game where it's very very very simple.
Rym: you have little camels.
Rym: well, you have four guys on four different color camels.
Rym: four or five five guys, I think five guys and There are a whole bunch of piles of little camels.
Rym: Every turn you draw any two camels you want and place them on the board in a Tron type style.
Rym: Try to surround things and touch things.
Rym: You can't run through other people's lines.
Scott: It's sort of like nibbles plus Tron.
Rym: Basically, you want to touch oases with your little trees you want to surround or touch little watering hole holes And you want to prevent your opponent from doing the same.
Scott: Well, you want to surround pretty much anything because that's what you get.
Scott: a ton of points is by surrounding.
Rym: It's incredibly simple, but there is very much a depth of not many kind of strategy But a lot of tactics of oh, he's going this way then I'll go this way to block him off.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like you got to know.
Scott: like if you devote camels to blocking another guy that means you're not devoting camels to getting points for you and It's tricky like that.
Rym: You can't really make big sweeping moves because you can only place two camels at a time and You're pretty much telegraphed.
Rym: what you're gonna do every time you play camels?
Rym: Oh, look Ryms trying to make a line across that area of the desert here.
Scott: I come yeah, or oh He's making a line across that area desert.
Scott: there's nothing I can do about it.
Scott: Let me go over here and try to make a line across the desert.
Rym: Oh, no, I have to go stop that other line, but now he has time to stop my line.
Rym: Now that's the two-player version playing with the full allotment of four or five people.
Rym: the game is very different.
Rym: Yeah, I Mean every time your turn comes around you just play two camels and then four other people each play two camels before it gets to you again.
Scott: It can get really painful in the four and five players.
Scott: You're pretty much just Scrounging for points as they get cleaned up almost immediately.
Scott: Yeah, and your chances of surrounding something are almost nil Because there's always someone in the way.
Rym: I used to always have success.
Rym: I'll point out that in the two games of this we played since we bought it.
Rym: I won both times.
Scott: Yeah, it's because I always got stuck in like.
Scott: I didn't want to devote resources to stopping you because I thought that I could do Better by just collecting points for me, but no no no Hamels in your way ahead of time ready for you to try anything.
Rym: yeah, I Tried to do that, but not so well I Mean, I guess why we'd love to say more about it, but it's a very simple game, and it's very enjoyable And it's pretty cheap, so I highly recommend Rainier Knizia's through the desert.
Scott: Yeah, it's really good.
Scott: Especially if you Aren't super hardcore.
Rym: It's definitely a quick.
Rym: you can just pick it up plop it down play a game straight through in about five minutes and the past I'll camels are pretty.
Rym: yeah It's got very high production values other than the board.
Rym: the board itself when you open it is real Wobbly and you have to kind of break its back a little bit on the bindings to make it flat.
Rym: They got a real carefully you'll break the board entirely and then you'll cry.
Scott: Maybe that was just our copy?
Rym: I don't know because I remember when way back Luke and Dave bought it And that's where we first played it and they had the same issue.
Scott: I hate it when people make game boards that don't come out flat right away.
Scott: It's so annoying.
Rym: It's alright because at least Endecker had a really nice solid board with it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that was huge and flat.
Rym: yeah We'll talk about Endecker another day But it's one of the old-school German games and that there's more randomness in it and more importantly it was overproduced as in There are pieces that are unnecessary that are there solely to provide atmosphere.
Scott: You know what I love the huts.
Rym: Yeah, whatever you and your huts safety huts You know there's a lot of controversy about the huts.
Scott: Yeah, you know what I'm on the side of the huts Really?
Scott: Yeah, cuz I like the huts even though I recognize that they make the game less awesome in German.
Scott: I Recognize that huts are awesome.
Rym: Well actually apparently if you use because Endecker there are a couple expansions.
Rym: if you use a certain expansion the huts are still there But they're not so random anymore, and it makes the game a lot more like a new style German game.
Scott: really Maybe we should go over that expansion.
Rym: Yeah, but we'll talk about that when we talk.
Scott: maybe we should try to play old style Endecker with no huts.
Rym: We'll try to play all the different styles.
Scott: Yeah, I think we might have to do a whole show on it Even though I know another podcast has already done a whole show on it.
Rym: Yeah, but we might as well.
Rym: Yeah No, I mean that's all we got for board games, but we will say that this weekend Saturday We're going to be at uber con in a lot metal ends.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's in Secaucus.
Rym: no no I mean the name of the Convention Center hotel.
Scott: It's at oh, I think it's at the something sweets.
Rym: Yeah, but it got renamed recently.
Rym: I saw a tidbit.
Rym: It's like the something metal and some god whatever.
Rym: It's uber con.
Rym: It's in Jersey North Jersey.
Rym: Yep, it is a gaming convention.
Rym: I went last year And it was hella awesome And we're going to be returning.
Rym: so anyone who lives in the North Jersey, New York area come on down look for us.
Rym: We're not hard to spot.
Rym: We're looking for some board games to play.
Scott: Definitely we will play board games with you if you find us.
Rym: Also, we're gonna be demoing hopefully again the Burning wheel role-playing game system, which some people in the forums were talking about and I've played a demo of once.
Rym: I want to show it to Scott because We're really thinking about using this system possibly and we want to know more about it.
Scott: It's the prime sweets.
Scott: prime is in all capital letters.
Scott: Uh-huh in I think Secaucus, New Jersey.
Scott: I can't find the actual.
Rym: well You know what.
Rym: if you google for uber con you'll find the website and all the information.
Scott: I think it's uber con.
Scott: calm you be.
Scott: e RC o n calm.
Scott: Secaucus, New Jersey.
Scott: Outstanding 350 route 3 West.
Rym: yeah, it's in the same places last year.
Rym: all I know is the hotel changed names.
Scott: apparently It's it's the prime sweets.
Scott: Oh It's.
Scott: it's apparently 20 minutes away from Newark Airport.
Rym: Oh Fantastic I've taken a cab there from here before yep.
Scott: It's two minutes away from giant Stadium So it's definitely right near the metal lands.
Rym: I know exactly where this is and That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 2 0 6 3 3 3 1 5 3 7.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.