Scott: It's Tuesday October 10th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We will discuss many old and varied Atari game.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so today at my job I came to a Conclusion that has somewhat disheartened me.
Scott: This is not new information.
Scott: You knew this before.
Scott: what did?
Rym: No, no, I think the difference.
Rym: I knew the fact that I've discovered today.
Rym: I knew that it was true.
Rym: I did not realize the absolute magnitude of the fact or the situation I am in.
Rym: you see I Have discovered that I am a little bit overqualified For the position I hold at my company meaning I could train a monkey to do my job And people who are in the exact same position of me as me know less about computers than my mom.
Rym: Aha Take a long story short Guy, I got to do a project real quick thing got to do something to some PCs.
Rym: So a guy at my office who has the same position as me who apparently knows about this is supposed to.
Rym: You know take me down to the lab show me what needs to be done and I can go off and do it.
Rym: All right so it's a terminal emulator kind of like telnet hyper terminal and You've got to make a new icon that points to a different IP address.
Rym: No big deal.
Rym: So he shows me an excruciating somewhat incorrect detail how to do this and the way he shows me is Copying the shortcut and renaming it and then going into the shortcut that he just made which points to the same place as the one He just made a copy of changing the settings saving it and then running it to which I said but won't that change the settings on the program because the shortcuts both point at the same place where the Configuration data is that you changed?
Rym: and his response was you know, we had a problem with that before.
Rym: you think that'll solve it And I about beat my head against the desk.
Scott: God,
Rym: I could go into great detail exactly why this was done, but It's weird how I went from a position where I was basically the head sysadmin of like 300 Linux Machines and I was a cosas admin on a whole bunch of critical servers and I helped manage a data center and a raised floor to Basically doing more on work yet.
Rym: I get paid more money and have better benefits doing it.
Scott: We really need to make a company that goes around to other companies and make sure this kind of stupidity doesn't happen.
Rym: I don't know what to what to think or do.
Rym: I don't know either.
Rym: This just isn't cool.
Scott: I mean in other professions, I mean if you're a plumber, right?
Scott: You don't go to other plumbers and say wow that guy doesn't know how to plumb.
Scott: what's he doing plumbing?
Scott: you know if you're on if you work for a company in which does a bunch of copy machine repairmen You know it I can't imagine that one guy actually knows how to repair copiers and the other guys that don't know.
Scott: You know all of those guys there know how to repair copiers and you call for your copy to copier to be repaired.
Scott: a guy Shows up.
Scott: It's always a different guy.
Scott: They always know what the hell they're doing.
Scott: You know, they do the job.
Scott: Why is it in the IT industry that we know what the hell we're doing and most people don't have a clue?
Rym: I mean I complained a lot about IBM but I got to say most of my complaints were with the company as a whole and The employees I ended up interacting with outside of my own department because the people in my department Pretty much knew what they were doing and we're pretty cool.
Rym: I mean a lot of them had a lot of skills that really aren't so common anymore and by and large They were interesting people.
Rym: They they were interested in the weird stuff.
Rym: I did and when they asked me a technical question They not only expected a technical answer, but they took my advice into consideration.
Rym: Like if they wanted something Linux, they'd come to me and be like, hey, is this feasible?
Rym: or hey?
Rym: What do you know about this?
Rym: and they'd listen this company's like Linux was the fuck.
Rym: Now there are smart people at this company.
Rym: I gave a guy Ubuntu and he is all about this.
Rym: now It's just uh, I don't know what to say.
Rym: I could I should just quit and get a better job.
Rym: I could probably make twice as much money as I make now.
Scott: So my job right on do anything and I could also probably making twice as much money somewhere else.
Scott: I got an email today.
Scott: Holy crap, did they fire you now?
Rym: Did they give you work?
Scott: No kind of not really.
Scott: Well, I've had work.
Scott: I just haven't been doing it because no one cares if I do it or not.
Scott: No one got attention.
Rym: I'll trade you you realize every day for the last two weeks.
Rym: I've asked my boss directly and straight up Is there any work for me to do?
Rym: I'll do something.
Rym: Give me something to do and I'll do it.
Rym: You're paying me.
Scott: Yeah, I have a few projects to be working on but they don't have deadlines and no one pays attention or cares.
Rym: No one talks to see everyone acts like they're so busy at my company.
Rym: But then they offer my services and not to sound big-headed, but I'm a badass.
Rym: I can do anything they asked me to do and they just don't take advantage of me at all.
Rym: But yet they complain constantly that they're under deadlines.
Rym: They can't finish anything.
Scott: Anyway, the email I got today was concerning a project that did.
Scott: I worked at the most recent work that I actually did.
Scott: I actually did something, you know about a month ago I and I made this new website, but I didn't do any CSS because they hired some designers or anything.
Scott: So it's good.
Rym: I don't like just.
Scott: it's just crappy ass plain HTML.
Scott: it looks like it looks really bad because it's just a form that's completely Unstyled or anything.
Scott: It's just you know form input input input input slash form and it's a bunch of forms and links and that's it.
Scott: So they're like, yeah, we're putting there's a new server coming this week.
Scott: We're putting that thing up on it by the end of the week and it was a CC to me.
Scott: It was actually to someone else because they were having to set up.
Rym: This happened to you where someone will email someone else with a bunch of important stuff That you that you haven't heard of before and they CC you but they don't mention you.
Rym: So you have the sense of all.
Rym: right was ICC because they want me to do something.
Scott: So I sent an email.
Scott: I'm like.
Scott: You guys know that that thing isn't CSS, right and you know that You know some.
Scott: you know, I designed this thing.
Scott: basically I offered to make this thing because I was kind of interested in making it and They said okay go to it.
Scott: So I did but I did it without any input from the people who are using it.
Scott: So I'm like, yeah, and maybe you know We should have someone who's actually gonna end up using this thing look at it to make sure it's what they want.
Scott: And I was like is this server a production server or whatever?
Scott: They're like, oh, yeah The new company websites going up Saturday night blah blah blah blah.
Scott: I'm like, ah I'm like, can you maybe keep me in the loop on things?
Scott: maybe?
Scott: so now they today I Started getting kept in the loop on things and it's just a bunch of useless emails.
Rym: good job.
Scott: So it's like they were giving me out of the loop and how I'm in it and I thought it's nothing.
Rym: There's really no loop.
Scott: It's I I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, so so
Scott: this week I think I'm gonna do a little bit of work on that thing and just make my own decisions and say ha ha and you
Rym: Think I'm gonna set up some hamachi and then I'm just gonna start building a lamp server and writing stupid web Applications to learn we already
Scott: have a lamp server in the other room.
Rym: No I'm gonna make my own on this box sitting here and I'm gonna futz with it and break it in.
Scott: What is the one we already got?
Rym: because I plan to break it and fix it over and over again.
Scott: I break that one and fix it all the time.
Rym: Yeah anyway Yeah, I'm just gonna start doing like I did at IBM whenever was bored at IBM.
Rym: I'd like build a Linux server and install Samba on it or something.
Scott: Yeah, Ubuntu is a good Distribution to run lamp on because it the it works really nice.
Scott: Not only that but they're the configuration files are organized in an intelligent manner.
Rym: their instructions online.
Rym: They're like do this.
Scott: then this then this left app get install Apache - yeah.
Scott: Yeah get install my.
Rym: anyway It's not that day.
Rym: We don't want to talk about that.
Scott: No, we don't.
Rym: it's game day Yeah, but before that game on now that was late.
Rym: We're not that kind of pod.
Rym: you got game First off.
Rym: we're back from sitcom.
Rym: We're gonna be talking about sitcom tomorrow though.
Rym: Once again, I'd like to note that Entertainment system is a badass.
Rym: video game metal band myspace comm slash entertainment system.
Rym: We want to give them mad props because we've seen them in concert twice and they're doing a huge concert in at Penn State College, Pennsylvania October 28th.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: We're gonna plug it a lot because they're badasses and they deserve recognition.
Rym: Indeed - we saw the video game pianist and hung out with him and he's an awesome, dude Even though it's really modest.
Scott: video game penis calm.
Rym: Yeah, it sounded like you said video game penis.
Scott: I know that's why I did.
Rym: Yeah, yeah All I got to say is that not only is this guy awesome But he is way more modest than he needs to be dude.
Rym: It is okay for you to say that you were cool Yeah, and he was like Looking for some ladies.
Scott: You know if he wasn't so modest.
Scott: he could probably get mad.
Rym: ladies I could anyways.
Rym: problem is he plays at video game cons instead of anime cons.
Scott: Yeah There was.
Scott: there was recently that thing with the with the hot girl with the violin playing the halo theme.
Scott: He should ask her out.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: We suggested to him that he should do some kind of duet Concert with her.
Rym: Yeah, cuz that would be really freaking cool.
Scott: That would be too awesome.
Rym: So yeah video game pianist if you guys didn't go to sitcom you missed out on a Real up close and personal concert with this kid because it was basically this giant.
Scott: It was a convention that was put on as if there was a thousand people there and only like less than 200 people showed up.
Scott: So it's like there's this big con and you were all.
Scott: it's like being alone in the amusement park.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: It was fantastic.
Scott: Who's awesome?
Rym: Sitacon was said to come could have handled like a thousand people easily.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they did they they the staff worked as if there were a thousand people there yet there weren't.
Scott: so everything was awesome.
Scott: Yeah, we'll talk about it more tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, we got a lot to say about that kind.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, my news is quick and non video game related because I saw this on dig and again, remember I talked about old news coming back because a dig and people who aren't hip to the internet a Lot of men when they turn 18 are noticing that they receive a Gillette Mach 3 razor or
Scott: whatever Gillette's newest fangled.
Rym: No, they still send out the Mach 3.
Scott: really awesome.
Rym: Yeah, so and one blade.
Rym: now, we're not gonna talk about this.
Rym: We've talked about it on the show many times, but the mind is shaving episode.
Scott: It's real old.
Rym: Yeah, in fact Emily's on that episode.
Rym: Yeah, but the Gillette Mach 3 is shite shite shite shite.
Rym: It costs more than video games.
Scott: It costs more than video.
Rym: God Gillette is a terrible company and their razors are terrible.
Rym: But anyway they send every man in the United States who is a citizen for the most part that they know about a razor when they turn 18 or in some places 21 usually 18.
Rym: Mm-hmm and This has been going on since I was 18.
Scott: I got one.
Rym: Yeah, this is 24 now.
Rym: Well, I turned 18 before you.
Rym: Yeah, so your be you turning 18 and get one is old news.
Rym: Dude I'll bet our friend Colin got one probably got Johnson for I got one.
Rym: Yeah, that old man is like a hundred.
Scott: my dad Probably go.
Scott: Yeah He's like 40 something.
Rym: Yeah, the point is something who knows all these people are talking about like.
Rym: this is news.
Rym: How is Gillette finding this information out?
Rym: blah blah.
Rym: This is the oldest freaking news.
Rym: This has been going on forever.
Rym: They get the information from all sorts of places.
Rym: It's not a big deal when they send you the razor use it once because you might as well then throw it away.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: Anyway real news video games.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So today was the day of pre-ordering ps3s.
Rym: Holy crap And they all went immediately.
Scott: Yep, pretty much every GameStop.
Scott: I think the the official GameStop corporate line is that they have 3600 stores.
Scott: Each store had but had at least eight ps3s.
Scott: Some of them had up to 16.
Scott: At most two of them per store could be pre-ordered by the staff and the rest had to go to actual people.
Rym: I point out that one of the first things I read about this was a guy from an EB talking about how Four of theirs went to the staff and another guy.
Scott: This is the GameStop party line.
Scott: GameStop is one big company now.
Scott: However, EB and GameStop are still run sort of separately kind of like YouTube and Google video But not.
Rym: and I saw another Where the guy was like, yeah, the employees in our store got all of them and they're all on eBay.
Scott: Well, cuz what'll happen is, you know to the two of them officially if you're at a GameStop two of them Officially go to the staff.
Scott: So those are the guys working in the store.
Scott: Alright, so if you got any other six employees are waiting outside at the front of the line.
Rym: If you've got a store with three employees Yeah, yeah, but here's the interesting thing.
Rym: There were like 15 pre-orders for sale on eBay like this morning.
Scott: The thing and different stores have different policies on these pre-orders, you know Some of them say you pre-order you got one.
Scott: some of them say you pre-order you'll get one as soon as we can.
Scott: Some of them say you pre-order that means you have a spot in line.
Scott: So if you come here on launch day and there's a line of which there will be you have your pre-order slip.
Scott: So you get in the front of the you, you know, you go Behind all the people who showed up before you with pre-order slips, but before the people who don't have pre-order slips.
Scott: so if the store opens at 8 a.m.
Scott: And you get there at 805 with your pre-order.
Scott: slip your Sol because some guy without one is in line ahead of you.
Rym: I got to say one thing I want to see.
Rym: I want to keep track of how many of these things go up on eBay as a Percentage of the total pre-orders because that will be one of the biggest tellings as to how popular the ps3 really is.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is a lot of the news I've heard.
Scott: I'm not it's not a hundred percent.
Scott: real news Is that like 80% of the ps3s are going to EB GameStops?
Scott: And the rest of the like 20% are going to Best Buy circuit cities.
Scott: Toys R Us is type places.
Rym: I think the real stat here is that 90% are going to eBay.
Rym: Now to say something that I said a whole bunch of times today.
Rym: It's been my thing today.
Rym: I mean I get into little bits and I've been saying this over and over All right Totally got interrupted but uh by it by a ricer who just drove by and perhaps the stupidest rice car I've ever seen or heard the stupidest rice car I've ever seen.
Rym: It's the stupidest rice car I've ever heard.
Rym: I mean, I've never heard a rice car that sounded stupider than that and I've heard some stupid glass packs before but For what?
Rym: I was about to say before I get interrupted I would have said the exact same thing to that ricer all day today.
Rym: I've been saying whatever dude
Scott: Whatever dude
Rym: and that's what I got to say to the people who are gonna stand in line to get the pre-order So that they can then stand in line and possibly get a PlayStation 3 on launch for $600 plus tax plus two controllers plus a game.
Scott: Yeah, I Mean.
Rym: I'm not gonna say the ps3 is a shit system because it's a pretty powerful thing, but Getting one at launch is pretty much a losing proposition.
Scott: No matter how you look at it Unless you're real lucky and you score big on eBay Yeah, I don't then go for it by all means.
Scott: or if you're wicked rich like if you're loaded uncle money bags.
Rym: Yeah, if you're loaded and you're bored, there's no reason not to get a ps3.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a great way to spend your money, but seriously buy an Xbox.
Rym: Well think there's one Two years from now when it's a lot cheaper and the good games come out.
Scott: This one interesting thing.
Scott: Is that a gamestop spokesman said that while the sellout wasn't confirmed until 2 p.m They said that it was a matter of minutes at most stores, which was a faster sellout rate than the 360.
Scott: But that might be because there are more 360s but sellout rate.
Scott: He's not very specific.
Rym: Yeah, well it also might be that anyone who wants a ps3 and there's probably more than two million people who want a ps3 Regardless of whether or not they can afford it.
Rym: They probably knew that they wouldn't get one unless they acted crazily.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's just that It for the 360.
Scott: It's sort of just like a general gamer.
Scott: good feelings, you know.
Scott: And for the Wii there's some craziness and also some gamer good feelings.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the ps3.
Scott: it's pretty much either.
Scott: Wow, this is stupid.
Scott: screw that shit.
Scott: if because if you're a general gamer, you're not gonna have good feelings for the ps3 So it's only crazies.
Scott: It's own.
Scott: It's mostly ps3.
Scott: crazy.
Rym: Yeah, cuz pretty much any reasonable person because I wouldn't mind getting a ps3.
Rym: I wouldn't mind having one.
Scott: I mean if it weren't that much money if you put one if you came up to the door and said here's a ps3 I'd be like, thank you, sir.
Rym: And if the ps3 say it were like, you know, three or four hundred bucks I might I mean it would have been on the list of possibilities if I had money line or if I had an HDTV be higher on the list, but Goddamn got them.
Scott: Right?
Rym: All I want is I want it.
Rym: I'm not gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna reserve all my judgment until the Wii pre-orders really come.
Rym: cuz that's soon.
Scott: I Printed out this we countdown calendar today.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you already have a Wii pre-order - I do.
Rym: Yeah I mean gig nights ahead of the game.
Rym: We got a Wii pre-order a while ago at the Nintendo World Store.
Rym: Yeah, the most confirmed.
Rym: we are so guaranteed to get a Wii.
Rym: It's pretty much like me.
Scott: Oh, no Not only am I getting a Wii there's a good chance like Reggie will personally hand me my Wii.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I can you imagine what it's gonna go down at the Nintendo store?
Scott: It's gonna be some craziness full reports from GeekNights in 40 days.
Rym: Yeah, 40 days a day 40 days and 40 nights.
Rym: Yep But I really can't wait until the Wii pre-orders come out and then the actual launch days.
Rym: Cuz I'll bet that the ps3 and the Wii will both sell out Maybe and that means a very different thing to Sony as it does to Nintendo.
Scott: It doesn't be All right.
Rym: Anyway things of the day dinner dinner.
Rym: You think I should sit down with a bunch of effects and make a radio kind of you know Things of the day with a lot of reverb and echo and lasers in the background and shit.
Scott: We should do that eventually.
Rym: What do you guys think?
Rym: is that a good idea or not?
Scott: I think it's an awesome idea.
Scott: It's much better than hearing you say things of the day than hearing me go doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: Yep We have this dynamic here.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right thing of the day here.
Rym: so I was playing bionic commando as I've been talking about and I was real good at that game as a kid and I got better at it.
Rym: and on the way to CityCon I beat it and killed Hitler twice in the car.
Scott: You can't kill two Hitler.
Rym: We can't kill two Hitler's.
Rym: I then killed Hitler like four more times at the con.
Scott: kill six Hitler's.
Rym: and Not only did I find a couple speed runs of bionic commando But I learned a way to beat the game a lot quicker that I didn't realize.
Scott: you can't beat bionic commando ten minutes.
Rym: So I'm linking to two speed runs.
Rym: The first speedrun is not machine assisted is a straight-up guy playing the game all the way through American version speedrun and It is pretty much a video of almost exactly how I play bionic commando.
Rym: I mean I was following along watching it with my fingers and it's pretty much straight up how I play the game.
Rym: Except there's a couple of places where he did things I didn't think to do and there's a couple of places where he fucks up and I could have done it better.
Scott: That's pretty typical yeah, but I mean what about the other speed run?
Rym: you go All right, the other speed runs of the Japanese version of the game, which is easier and harder.
Rym: Oh, yeah gonna be easier and hard in one level like I see him going.
Rym: and there's these platforms that weren't there before.
Rym: they make it a Fuck shit ton easy.
Scott: Are you sure there aren't platforms of death?
Rym: Yes, I'm sure.
Rym: But yet then there's this like wall of spikes that comes out of nowhere and all these extra guys And there's changes to the game that I don't even know why they bothered because they like they took stuff out of the game.
Rym: There's nothing to do with anything.
Rym: No It's weird, but all right, that's a fucking speedrun.
Rym: I can't play the game like the second speedrun, but I'm gonna try Okay, because I think I'll be able to do that someday Mmm, so my thing of the day is yet another funny video from College Humor.
Scott: You like.
Rym: this is fucking a Larry.
Scott: College Humor is coming out with the funny videos lately.
Scott: way to go guys.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there that Street Fighter 2 thing.
Scott: We just talked about and yeah, so now they've got this Rejected Wii games.
Scott: it says the upcoming Nintendo Wii.
Scott: we use a revolutionary new controller which won't be used for any of the following and it's basically a video of a bunch of people with a normal remote control that they're pretending as a Wii controller and They're acting as if they're playing Wii games that don't exist.
Scott: Like the first guy is flipping burgers at McDonald's.
Rym: It's called five dollars an hour.
Scott: Yeah, and he's.
Scott: he acts like he's working at McDonald's.
Rym: now The video is hilarious Spoilers cuz whatever but my favorite one.
Rym: it's called hot hands.
Rym: No hot hands is good.
Rym: You remember hot hands?
Rym: It's hard to describe as the slap.
Scott: It's the game where you try to slap the other guys hands the game that no one ever really played so much.
Rym: It was just kind of like in movies.
Rym: It was there a lot.
Scott: Oh, I play that game.
Rym: It's always just like a big kid picking on a little something.
Scott: gotta make mercy.
Rym: We mercy.
Scott: we gotta make mercy for the way.
Rym: Why don't they make like schoolyard games for the Wii and have a million stupid games like that?
Scott: It'll be a backyard baseball.
Scott: I'm sure will eventually come out.
Scott: Yes a popular one.
Rym: It's like Nazi something.
Rym: So it's just like you hear all this Hitler stuff like Hitler giving a speech and then when the crowd goes they Kyle the kid Holds the Wii controller like zig heil zig heil And then it's like thing.
Scott: Perfect.
Scott: Yeah, the other one is The one the guy does hara-kiri with the.
Rym: yeah, it's like seppuku and that would be a cool game.
Scott: kind of Make sure you kill yourself properly with this Wii controller.
Rym: I have anything I would make a samurai game where there is a seppuku minigame.
Rym: Haha, or maybe Or if you just lose you got to commit seppuku and you can get a but like you get a bunch of points for committing Seppuku properly.
Scott: so at the end of the game should have a game where you yuck as a boss and you chop fingers off.
Rym: Let that finger fly.
Rym: But imagine this you're playing this yacht this like samurai game and you can just get killed.
Rym: But the best way to win is get as far as you can and then instead of dying you commit seppuku Before someone kills you.
Rym: but you got to do it right and you get a crazy bonus if you do it properly.
Scott: Should we let people in on the let that finger fly joke?
Rym: All right I don't remember how to say it in Japanese, but I learned it once because I thought it was really funny.
Rym: but apparently and this is an all old Yakuza manga and Gekiga and Yakuza anime if You piss off the Yakuza Lord, you know a lot of movies They show like Yakuza guys have fingers missing.
Rym: Yeah, now a lot of people thought that that was just like Oh Yakuza guys have a finger missing.
Rym: No, if your finger got cut off that means that you did something stupid and they punished you.
Scott: Usually, you know in Yakuza movies.
Scott: It'll be you did something stupid and You would cut off your finger and then offer it to the Yakuza boss like I'm sorry finger.
Rym: or sometimes the Yakuza boss turns to you and basically says let that finger fly which means Goddamnit, yep, so he'd either order you to cut it off or apparently nowadays They'll just say it and it's it.
Rym: they don't actually want you to cut your finger off.
Rym: It's more of a wow, you did something stupid.
Scott: Yeah So if you're a Yakuza and you screw up someone to be like let that finger fly now.
Rym: I might be totally wrong here But from what we've gathered it seems that the origin of the Yakuza finger thing comes from way back feudal Japan.
Rym: where?
Rym: For various reasons a swordsman's pinky finger would be cut off thus making him a much less effective swordsman.
Rym: I'm sure our friend Katsu can tell us whether or not the pinky finger is critical to wielding a sword.
Scott: I'm think it would be don't you?
Rym: I think so.
Rym: Well, that's why I want to ask Katsu cuz I mean he kicked that guy's ass at Otakon Yeah, and he's really good at Kendo.
Rym: So I'm sure he knows anyway.
Scott: funny Wii game video.
Scott: It's really funny.
Scott: You want to watch this, you know and from the in the future just go to College Humor and watch their videos cuz they're funny.
Rym: Yeah, we're not gonna use those as things today anymore unless they're crazy.
Scott: Yeah, we'll stick with the ever popular You goog or goog tube.
Rym: I like goo - goo - goo - goo - All right.
Rym: So today well actually two days ago.
Rym: We were talking about what to do the show on and we decided let's just pick any old game and do it like some old game we both play.
Rym: and Then today on a whim I whipped out the Atari 7800 and my giant shoebox full of games and the four new games you just bought.
Rym: Yeah, we bought a bunch of games for the Atari original cartridges recently at a video game store Uh-huh.
Rym: So we bought a ice hockey because I didn't own it warlord because my copy didn't.
Rym: my copy didn't work anymore Yars revenge because I never actually played it and God that game is stupid.
Rym: Anyway These games and we started playing it.
Scott: I thought we'd review a whole bunch of Atari games because and describe some of them and how they work because a lot of people Don't understand a lot of.
Rym: I mean in a lot of ways Video gaming hasn't come that far And in other ways it's come a million million miles.
Rym: Yeah But like compare there are Atari games that are better like hands-down Objectively better games than a lot of the Super Nintendo games that came out the like mountain bike whatever it's like whatever god I'd rather play the yards revenge daily.
Rym: Yeah, I know ever have to play that fucker again.
Rym: The other thing I'd like to point out is that Scott's going to make a whole bunch of stink about this But god damn it does.
Rym: he suck at Atari you suck.
Scott: What are you telling me?
Rym: All right Do we have to list all?
Scott: because I'm using the Atari 7800 has the shit joysticks that no other game system has had the like of ever and They're really.
Scott: the only reason that you can use those things is because you use them when you were a kid and you've been using them For years.
Scott: nobody else who's never used them before can manage them.
Scott: I'm gonna go get a Sega Genesis controller and then you'll see that I don't suck at these games.
Scott: I just suck with the shitty 7800 controllers.
Rym: Yeah We'll see cuz you were it.
Rym: I mean you were making tactical mistakes in a lot of these games not just what ever Like the maze game.
Rym: You just don't know what your way around mazes.
Scott: Oh, well screw that stupid maze game.
Rym: All right It's a sign of intelligence.
Rym: You just can't follow a man.
Scott: I could I just kept going on the wrong way because I could have followed the maze.
Scott: I just kept going though cuz the stupid joystick I would make a right turn and the guy would keep going straight into the dead end.
Scott: I had to turn around then he go too far and I had to turn around again.
Rym: You have no manual dexterity.
Scott: I have plenty of manual dexterity Just is mostly in my thumbs and not for a shit Joystick that I mean.
Scott: I could use a joystick.
Scott: if you give me a Street Fighter 2 joystick I'm all good, but you keep saying that the Atari 2600s joystick is superior.
Scott: It is superior I don't.
Rym: I think.
Rym: if you use it again, you'll realize that they're pretty much the same.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Scott: It's a. it's not purpose.
Scott: Regardless.
Scott: It doesn't matter I'm getting a Genesis controller next time I go to my house.
Rym: So the first game we played was a game I hadn't played.
Scott: cuz if you didn't know you can use a Genesis controller on an Atari.
Rym: Yes, they're the same connector and everything.
Rym: Yep, even though most the buttons don't work.
Scott: I only need one button.
Rym: Uh at 7800 games you need two buttons.
Scott: a Genesis controller has three buttons.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, you'll have to figure out which button is what a and B. All right.
Rym: So we're gonna review a whole bunch of Atari 2600 and 7800 games starting with.
Rym: we'll go pretty much in the order.
Rym: We played them.
Scott: ice hockey You know, it wasn't so bad.
Scott: It was from Activision by the way.
Rym: Yeah, this game is not as good as the Nintendo version of ice hockey Which I consider to be the best hockey game ever made.
Rym: I agree, but it was actually pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, you think you figure an ice hockey game for the Atari be kind of crummy, but it really isn't so bad.
Scott: The only thing that's really bad about it is that you have two guys on the ice.
Scott: you know one guy is sort of at the top and one guy sort of at the bottom and Moving the stick moves the guy who is closest to the puck.
Scott: So if the puck is up at the top of the ice then the guy on the top you can move and the guy In the bottom, you can't control it all.
Scott: So, you know, I kept wanting to move the guy at the bottom of the ice closer to the goal But I couldn't because I could only move the guy at the top and that was annoying.
Scott: But other than that the ice hockey game was pretty good.
Scott: You know your guy gets the puck you skate around you shoot.
Scott: it's pretty much.
Scott: all you can do is shoot with in a direction Yeah, or you can knock the other guy down.
Scott: Yeah, you can.
Scott: you can push the button a whole lot to mess with the other guy when you're on defense.
Rym: Yep, Scott ended up beating me.
Rym: I think ten to six.
Rym: Whoo.
Rym: It was a pretty stunning victory on Scott's.
Scott: I'm good at them.
Scott: ice hockey games.
Rym: Let me tell you Yeah Even though I beat you the last time we played NES ice hockey and this is with the shitty 7800 controller I could still play ice hockey because there wasn't much to this game.
Rym: It moved real slow.
Rym: We were playing on the fast advanced setting.
Scott: Yeah, it was still pretty fun.
Scott: Like I would play it some more.
Rym: Yeah, well the other thing is ice hockey is one of the earlier Atari games because the Atari like every other system Progress quite a bit as it went on and older games were not as good as games that came out late in the Atari's Lifecycle were much more.
Scott: It's like Mario 3 compared to Mario 1 Yeah, or like urban champions urban champions compared to Zelda 2.
Rym: Yeah star tropics Exactly.
Rym: All right, so then we played warlords, which is pretty much the iconic Multiplayer Atari game.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's a great game.
Scott: I think it's unique for the Atari and that is a fast-paced smooth paddle controlled Four-player directly versus game.
Rym: Yeah straight up four player.
Rym: it's basically four player breakout where each person in the corner has a castle and Knights that moves around the outside and a dragon breathes a fireball and the fire.
Scott: the Knights bounce the fireball against each other and Hit each other's castles and then if the fireball gets into your castle you die.
Rym: we played two-player.
Rym: I beat Scott the first time.
Rym: he beat me the second time.
Scott: I'm actually good at warlords and I can use any paddle games I can.
Scott: I can do so.
Rym: then we tried to play with Alex And we learned that my Atari which is old as fucker Can't the second port can't support the multiplayer paddles anymore so we can only play two-player games.
Scott: Or maybe we need to flick some switches or who knows what.
Scott: but yeah, it just didn't work.
Scott: it was unhappy.
Rym: Yeah game has issues.
Rym: Mmm warlord is a good game.
Rym: I mean it has issues just for the fact that it's an old Atari game But that is one of the earliest four-player games.
Rym: That wasn't just as.
Scott: if you want to play a new good version of warlords I don't want to recommend this game, but the retro Atari compilation for the DS It's not really that great.
Scott: It's more like some guy Practice DS coding by making implementing a bunch of it.
Rym: don't buy it unless you see it for five bucks or less.
Scott: Yeah, I spent like 15 no a 10 on it I think.
Scott: but yeah, it has warlords so you can try warlords out with that and it's an okay version of warlords.
Rym: So then we played slot racer, which is a game.
Rym: I used to love as a kid even though it's real hard.
Scott: It's real hard and complicated and obtuse.
Rym: yeah, once you figure out what's going on see slot racers the game where you have these vehicles that move around and The controls are intuitive, but they're not obvious.
Rym: like once you figure it out you're like, oh and then you have a lot of control over the game and it's really just a Game of being able to.
Rym: I mean Atari games are simple.
Rym: They're blocks.
Rym: It's usually blocks moving around.
Rym: The controls are real.
Rym: simply got one button in an eight-way joystick.
Rym: So the skills involved tend to come down to straight up.
Rym: I hand coordination pattern recognition movement prediction better joysticks.
Rym: so in terms of this game the game is basically trying to predict where the other person will go and Creating a path for your projectile that will hit him while avoiding his projectile.
Rym: And you like basically you program.
Rym: it sounds like a lot.
Rym: it's a lot of guitar games were really complex even though you had such Simple controls.
Rym: you're driving around controlling your vehicle simultaneously.
Rym: You shoot projectiles and Effectively program them with simple logic to move around and you try to get them to hit the opponent.
Rym: Scott couldn't play the game at all.
Rym: I beat him handily a bunch of times, but I never played the game.
Rym: I can't blame you because the game is real difficult to be good at it's really.
Scott: I couldn't see many people liking this game.
Rym: I love that game me my brother and my dad and all my friends played it constantly and I'm real good at it.
Rym: And so we're all of them.
Scott: I think if you tried to make a game like that today people would be like fuck this shit and throw it out.
Rym: Yeah, you kids have no patience for actual difficult game.
Scott: It's not worth it because it's not that fun.
Rym: even once they're good at it Alright, so then we played maze craze, which is actually one of my favorite Atari games.
Rym: It has a lot of different kinds of levels and basically you got a blue guy and a red guy.
Rym: it's two player always and a maze and whoever gets the end of the maze first wins and Scott couldn't deal with the fact that it would be like one two three go with the maze appears and I immediately am running directly For the exit as fast as possible.
Scott: I think you've memorized all the mazes, but they're actually random Scott.
Scott: Yeah, whatever Whatever.
Scott: no, they really my main problem is that like, you know I would start off pick a direction and go for it and then I would look to see if I was going the right way.
Rym: That's what I did, but you always went the wrong way.
Scott: Well, and then the other problem was that I would you know I'd be like turn left and my guy would go straight a little bit too far.
Scott: then I have to turn around.
Scott: I go too far You know, it was really hard to.
Scott: I don't know why you have so much ice with the joys.
Rym: I don't know why you have so much trouble with this joystick.
Rym: I find it to be incredibly precise.
Rym: The thing is it's not a joystick and don't treat it as such.
Rym: treat it as a d-pad with a stick coming out of it.
Scott: That's no good cuz.
Rym: I don't move it like a joystick.
Rym: I tap it left and right it up and down.
Scott: I can't do that.
Scott: I got a if it's a joystick.
Scott: I gotta hold it in one.
Rym: I gotta hold it now I got maze.
Rym: craze is a game that it was probably my favorite favorite favorite game.
Rym: as a kid I played it constantly with my brother.
Rym: It was like a battle of wits because it's not just a maze.
Rym: I mean you can play where part of the maze is invisible.
Rym: all of the maze is invisible.
Rym: You can play one version where while you're running you can hit the button and Create a secret door where it looks like there's no path, but there is a path that confuse the other person Mm-hmm, and there are some modes where you have to collect three things that are moving around and then escape.
Rym: There are modes where there are things moving around that kill you so you have to get out without being killed.
Rym: The game is really really good and really really taxing on the brain.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's brain was a little overtaxed.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: I beat him like ten times.
Rym: then he just turned the game.
Scott: I wasn't my brain that was over.
Scott: text is my hand.
Rym: Yeah, your manual dexterity though There were a couple times you just went the wrong way and then like because you were going fine And you you had this like you thought you're gonna win and then you stopped.
Rym: you said Shit, you were in a dead end all by yourself.
Scott: Yeah No good.
Rym: It's a good game.
Rym: I like it a lot.
Scott: Yeah It would do.
Scott: I would do better at it if it like.
Scott: they showed you the maze and then they counted down from five And then you went instead of you go as soon as the maze appears.
Rym: Yeah, well, it's a different kind of game.
Rym: Yeah, it's more of a quick reactions game than a.
Scott: I just want to look at the maze for even one second before I have to start moving.
Rym: see well the game.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: if you wait and look then if I go the wrong way Automatically then you win.
Scott: as long as then if you went the right way, I'm screwed I have.
Scott: the only way to do it is to do it the way you do it Where you go the right way right?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Well, yeah Well, the game is the game of how quickly can you parse a very simple maze?
Rym: Well, it's not that simple.
Scott: actually They're pretty complex.
Scott: You can even make them even more complex in the higher levels.
Rym: yeah, the one trick is that it's like all mazes there tends to be a Direction you want to go in and you can kind of get a feel for it.
Rym: But it's definitely a game of how quickly can you parse a pattern and then implement it?
Scott: The thing is like I don't even try to parse the maze because I have to start moving right away Arse and move at the same time and
Rym: I'll often go the wrong way when Scott's real close to me on Purpose and then immediately duck out because he'll follow me and then run off into the dead end
Scott: It's because I can't control my guy.
Rym: Hey, yeah, it's also just it's a good game.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, then we played some 7800 games, which is the next iteration of the Atari.
Rym: Yeah, the 800 was backward compatible.
Scott: Yeah, you got the Atari 7800 is a system that can play Atari 2600 games But it can also play Atari 7800 games, which are almost as good as a Nintendo game.
Rym: In fact Atari's well, they're almost as good as low-end Atari 7800 games have the capability to be on par almost straight up with non MMC meaning early NES games.
Scott: Yeah Donkey Kong for the Atari 7800 is Basically 90% identical to Donkey Kong for the NES.
Rym: Yep, and we played Donkey Kong.
Scott: Don't care for the NES is still better, but I kicked Scott's ass.
Scott: Well, I Frickin I don't know what the hell was going on there.
Scott: But like I'm usually the master of Donkey Kong Well, not the grand master But I can usually beat like a few I can get Donkey Kong dead a few times before it's game over.
Rym: Right now I'd give you the controller thing because you have trouble with the controller.
Rym: I respect that.
Rym: It's not that big a deal, but you made serious tactical errors.
Scott: It's like you played level one and I watched you and I was like, yep That's exactly what I do.
Scott: and I was watching it and that was how my brain processed.
Scott: level of Donkey.
Scott: Yeah, but then you and then I did it and like these are these barrels coming at me from other places I'm like, what the fuck?
Rym: Well, the thing is like you went up ladders.
Rym: that is dangerous to go up and then the barrel would come down and get you.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what was going on.
Scott: There was no good.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I played through it for a while But I didn't make it past the second level because I did the Rama Sharma.
Rym: I tried to do too much with you tried to do too much.
Rym: I tried to get that stupid purse and that was the enemy.
Scott: never go for the stupid person level in - - It's always stupid to go for that.
Scott: You just go kill Donkey Kong get your points.
Scott: So then we played Donkey Kong jr Which is a game that I played in the arcade maybe two times ever.
Scott: Yeah All I remember is the one where Donkey Kong jr.
Scott: Tries to save Donkey Kong from Mario and he goes on vines.
Rym: Yep, it's actually a really good game.
Rym: I mean, it's I'd say it's on par with Donkey Kong.
Rym: No, not really I think it is.
Scott: No, it's been dying.
Rym: Kong 3 God Yeah, but this I kick Scott.
Rym: I'm not gonna keep hammering this but Scott was like he watched me play and I like bust through the game like crazy and I can't.
Rym: I save doggy on a bunch Of time I finally die and I even did crazy stunts Like I jumped on things you can't jump on to and glitch the game to get even further Mmm, and then Scott starts.
Rym: he dies like immediately like he climbs up the first vine And then he falls to his death and then he climbs up the first line to the exact same spot.
Rym: It falls to his death in the exact same way.
Scott: It's it wasn't fun.
Rym: No, it was.
Scott: it's not a good game.
Scott: It's a pretty good game.
Rym: No, it's not gonna cuz you're not good at it.
Scott: No, it's really just not a good game.
Rym: Well when I was a kid, actually I sucked ass at that game and I hated it.
Rym: Now that I'm a better gamer and I'm older.
Rym: I like it a lot more.
Rym: Mm-hmm Got.
Rym: after that we play.
Rym: Oh, we can skip some of these games.
Scott: Yeah, just talk about whichever games, you know you bring up the game and I'll talk about it.
Scott: All right, of course Outlaw Outlaw is actually one of my favorite Atari games.
Scott: You got to understand the awesomeness of this game.
Rym: It's two stick figure cowboys shooting at each other with pixel guns.
Rym: Yeehaw Like a cactus in the middle or stagecoaches going by and the game is so simple.
Rym: it is straight up just a competition of bluffing and It's really just bluffing once everyone's good at it.
Rym: bluffing and I hand coordination and calculating angles.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can really only shoot bullets at 45 degree angles or zero degree angles And you got a cowboy on the left and a cowboy on the right and one guy shoots to the right and the other guy shoots to the left and in between You can choose to either have a cactus which is invincible.
Scott: You can choose to have a stagecoach.
Rym: Well, no, no You can have a cactus that's invincible with unlimited ammo a cactus that cactus that's invincible with limited ammo a cactus That's not invincible with unlimited ammo.
Rym: Okay, every variation has limited and unlimited ammo.
Rym: Yeah stagecoach.
Rym: That's invincible That isn't.
Rym: that's moving and invincible.
Rym: That's moving and not invincible.
Rym: a wall a wall that's moving a wall that's moving.
Scott: and Yeah, there's a whole bunch of different combinations in case you get bored of the invincible cactus mode.
Scott: But now, of course you get the bouncing bullets the non bouncing bullets.
Scott: You know, it's all good.
Rym: I beat Scott every time.
Scott: No, you didn't get it.
Scott: I beat you many times infinite Am?
Scott: I beat you?
Scott: I beat Once.
Rym: you beat me.
Scott: I beat you a couple times.
Rym: No, you killed me a couple times.
Scott: I think I beat you twice.
Rym: No, you beat me one.
Scott: I've ever beaten you twice and one of those stagecoaches I think I didn't.
Scott: I beat you on the bouncing cactus.
Rym: You beat me on the second round we played which was unlimited ammo bouncing cactus Whatever and you beat me pretty thoroughly there, but I beat you everywhere else.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: I'm good at outlaw.
Rym: No, you're not All right.
Rym: combat Combat is a great game.
Rym: It's the same thing as outlaw almost only with little tanks little tanks and airplanes and you move around and it has modes like you Can only beat the guy if you hit him with a reflected shot and stuff like that.
Rym: My favorite mode is invisible mode where it's just a blank screen.
Rym: There's two tanks and you're both invisible and when you shoot you appear for a second.
Rym: and I got to admit it was funny.
Rym: Cuz we're both invisible and Scott's like how am I supposed to do this?
Scott: And I shot it cuz I used to be able to do invisible tank when I was a kid But now I can't freaking do that.
Rym: Oh, where the fuck?
Rym: how'd you?
Rym: and I shot him again and I shot him again And I shot him again when I was invisible.
Scott: He shot me.
Scott: Yeah, like Scott I mean, I don't even know where I am, but somehow he's shooting me.
Rym: See I had an Atari and I played it a lot.
Scott: In fact, I played my see I had an Atari but when I was three it broke.
Scott: So I only really played Pac Man a bunch of times and broke breakout and then that was it.
Rym: even after I got a Super Nintendo I played my Atari regularly.
Scott: Yeah, our Atari was gone by then so I didn't play it that long and I you know I played all those games but mostly at other people's houses and in the arcade and stuff like that.
Rym: All right, Crystal Castle sucks ass.
Scott: It was kind of sucky.
Scott: I'm good at it wasn't the worst thing ever though.
Rym: well, it's a. as a kid the game scared the hell out of me because it was all these monsters and They were all kind of scary and they'd come out.
Rym: They weren't pretty scary and the game is just kind of hard.
Rym: and so you're a teddy bear.
Rym: Yeah, you're a teddy bear and these like giant skeletons are coming to kill you.
Scott: The skeleton was awesome though He was.
Rym: you didn't get to see the ghosts.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: I want to see the ghost.
Rym: Yeah, like bees come and sting you to death.
Scott: It's sort of like Qbert in a way that you're trying to touch the whole board without getting killed by monsters.
Rym: It's like a cross between Qbert and pac-man.
Rym: Yeah, that sounds kind of weird.
Scott: and there's also honey and Hats.
Rym: Yeah magic hats magic hats.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: now the next game we played.
Rym: Scott can't blame the controller.
Rym: cuz cuz.
Scott: I'm actually really good at this game.
Rym: Plus it's it's pitfall.
Rym: Alright fucking pitfall no matter what controls you're using Unless your controller is physically broken.
Rym: The skill of pitfall is purely the skill of playing pitfall.
Scott: It's just right left and pushing a button now.
Rym: Scott talked a big game.
Scott: Scott and I came out with a big game.
Rym: Scott talked a big game and I did real good.
Scott: I got two freaking treasures, man.
Rym: I Got three past a fourth one and could have kept going but killed myself on purpose.
Scott: Yeah, that's only cuz you went.
Scott: second if you would have let you didn't then you turn the game off and if you gave If I had another try I would have gotten five treasures.
Rym: I doubt it.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna beat pitfall.
Rym: you watch The point out that Scott talked a really big game.
Rym: I mean, I can't make fun of him for losing it like kaboom because I'm Tommy at kaboom.
Scott: I did pretty good at kaboom for not being Tommy.
Rym: Yeah, he did really good.
Rym: But me well well That's a paddle game.
Rym: I can play that I can't make funny for the other games.
Rym: But you've talked a big fucking game for pitfall and I came out with a big game.
Scott: But it was the first try.
Scott: and how many years you knew you'd only let me try it once one try.
Scott: That was pretty good.
Rym: It had been equally many years for me.
Scott: Yeah, but you got to watch me play first.
Scott: you got to see which boards are where I didn't matter.
Rym: It's the same every time.
Rym: I have that game practically memorized.
Scott: see that's that's not fair because I don't have it memorized.
Scott: I just memorize how to do each kind of board, but uh It's the same game everywhere.
Scott: No, it's it.
Rym: I don't memorize pitfall you I memorized it in terms of I know where all the treasures Are.
Scott: I don't know where the treasures are.
Scott: I just keep going and trying to get until I get them all.
Rym: Yeah, you talk a big game and then I don't have a big game at pitfall.
Rym: I'm great at it didn't even break 10,000. that's cuz.
Scott: it was the first time I played in years first time I played in years But you knew the game still.
Rym: so why would you talk a big game?
Rym: if I know the game and I'm good at it You're not good because I am good at it, but you sucked at.
Scott: I just don't have memorized.
Scott: and I did really well Not really.
Scott: Yeah, really getting three treasures is nothing It's nothing.
Scott: yeah next time I'll beat it.
Scott: you watch you'll see I could be pitfall.
Rym: I'm just ragging on Scott because he's good.
Rym: I mean, he's really good at video games.
Rym: Just not at Atari.
Scott: I'm good at Atari games Super controller and I can't Frickin be expected to be amazing and kicking ass at a game that I haven't played that much in my life that I'm kind of Good at in one try the first try in years.
Rym: I'm fine I'll give you all that but you have to admit that I'm better than you at Atari games.
Scott: You're only better than me.
Scott: Hey at Certain games in the Atari 1700 because you played them for years of your life You can actually use that controller.
Rym: but uh, I suck at.
Rym: you know, Mega Man 2 and the only reason you're good at it You played it a whole bunch.
Scott: No, even if you played Mega Man 2 a whole bunch you wouldn't be as good as I am.
Rym: I probably would no fine you.
Rym: Which let's see who will win first.
Rym: you beat bionic commando or I beat Mega Man 2.
Rym: Does that have to be the competition?
Scott: Mega Man 2 is an easier game?
Rym: Bionic commando is really easy.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I never really tried to get past the first level.
Rym: You can borrow that Capcom mini-mix.
Rym: I bought.
Scott: I'll try.
Scott: Yeah, I never actually tried to beat bionic commando at all.
Scott: I kind of played it for a few minutes and then be like, okay Wow, yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So yards revenge is just terrible.
Scott: Yeah, it's I don't know Atari guys are like, yeah yards revenge is like the awesome amazing Atari thing.
Rym: It's To quote what was used to see because I listened to like 10 of their episodes in the last week and one they're really cool.
Rym: they're good podcast about movies.
Rym: a little plug here, but They you know They're British and they use British isms and they always say like when something's shitty like Americans say, oh, that's shitty.
Rym: They always say well, it's a bit shit It's a bit shit And it's grown on me.
Rym: I like saying that it's a bit shit.
Rym: this game's a bit shit.
Rym: See cuz I love they were making fun of American accents one day and I love hearing Non-americans do American accents.
Rym: So it's I love.
Scott: I also love hearing non-americans do American accent.
Rym: So I hope you all enjoy hearing your accents done poorly even though like I know we have a lot of Australian listeners in there.
Rym: I can't do anything on a Crikey.
Rym: Oh I'm sorry to Australia.
Rym: You guys are awesome.
Rym: In fact, I was talking to my grandpa today cuz he loves Australia and he spent like a month there, but I digress.
Rym: I don't think we're gonna talk about any more Atari games because I don't want to go long on an episode.
Rym: We're just laughing at Scott about a target Happen at rain cuz.
Scott: he played too many shitty Atari games.
Scott: Only some of them are awesome.
Scott: Most of them are shit.
Scott: They're a bit shit shit a bit.
Scott: It's a bit You can't be a bit shit time Stan.
Rym: that was lame Whatever.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think we're descending into silliness.
Rym: I'll end this by saying that if you can find an emulator and you're in any way a video game fan It behooves you to play all of the Atari games you can find.
Rym: I mean don't play them a lot don't get good at.
Scott: Yeah, just at least turn each ROM on and try to play it for a little bit and then you know Some of them will actually be fun.
Scott: Keep playing those like pitfall and some of them won't be fun like the shitty version of pac-man for the 2600.
Scott: God, don't play.
Rym: that was like the worst game ever made.
Scott: Yeah, just don't play those.
Rym: I mean it really.
Rym: Video games have come a long way But a lot of modern video games seem to miss the point that the point of a video game is that it's fun.
Rym: And there are games that don't look fun.
Rym: And even the people who are fans of the games When they play them, they don't look like they're having fun.
Scott: It's like they're playing them like it's a chore or they're you know, they're playing it to like unlock a story bit or something.
Rym: Plus, I mean you'll see games that you know, the game is a bit shit.
Rym: But you'll play it and then you'll play a modern game and realize that the modern game is Essentially the same game that was on the Atari just polished a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, someone should make a frickin modern Yars revenge then it wouldn't suck.
Rym: Someone should remake every Atari game modern.
Rym: And they've done it quite a bit in a flash with good great No straight-up port just with good graphics like Xbox 360 graphics, but it's just like Yars revenge This exact same game with the same controls.
Scott: It's been done many times.
Rym: Yeah All right, so I'll leave you with that and tomorrow we will have our coverage of Citicon 2006.
Rym: I hope there will be a Citicon 2007 and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com.
Scott: And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.