Rym: It's Wednesday April 26th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We bring you our coverage of ToraCon 2006.
Scott: Let's do this Today work.
Scott: I was setting up all the you know stuff on my fresh work windows crap Laptop thing I send.
Rym: sometimes I like doing that because it means my computer is going to be not bogged down by all the crap that I'm about to put On it, but at the same time.
Rym: I hate doing that.
Scott: yeah Surprisingly I had to reboot only like four or five times to do all the windows updates Oh, and I had to add two or three times to do the office updates.
Scott: Anyway, one of the things I had to do is update iTunes now.
Scott: I originally thought hey look at this You know all I really do with iTunes is podcast.
Scott: I'll save my opml and It's okay.
Scott: if I delete all the mp3s off my hard drive because they're on my iPod - they all get redown loaded.
Scott: No no no, so I'm like all right.
Scott: You know and then when I Import my opml and then get my podcast list back It'll just get all the mp3s from my iPod and reload the whole thing.
Scott: Okay, I didn't quite work that way.
Rym: What happened?
Scott: well first of all it didn't let me import the opml like I couldn't.
Scott: I went to import.
Scott: I chose the opml file.
Scott: I clicked ok nothing happened.
Rym: Did you try getting some other opml and importing it just to make sure it wasn't yours?
Scott: This is opml that I had exported from iTunes.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but just in case I mean I would have taken someone else's and just ride.
Scott: I don't even think about that, but no it wasn't importing opml, so I Manually added all the.
Scott: well that's the other part of the story, but I manually added podcast to the feed And then I plugged in the iPod.
Scott: What did it do?
Scott: It didn't take the You know mp3s off my iPod and match them to the feeds to which I was subscribed.
Scott: No, it took the feeds to which I was subscribed and overwrote everything on my on my podcast on my iPod.
Scott: So I lost a whole bunch of stuff.
Scott: I could go redown load it, but anyway Yeah, iTunes isn't so great.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's it's not really straight like in in its goal to be really simple.
Scott: It makes it really difficult to do.
Scott: To get it to do exactly what you want it to do You know because it's really only designed to work if you use it in one specific way.
Scott: So if you try to make it do anything else it just fucks you.
Rym: well I'm sure I'll be running a follow of all that since now that it really looks like I'm gonna pick one of these jobs I've been offered for the past month and At that point.
Rym: I'm just gonna buy it on a spending spring by an iPod gonna buy an i-trip Maybe a motorcycle yeah, I think we should just have one Apple computer to manage all this shit.
Rym: That'd be kind of nice.
Scott: I gotta say yeah We should have one Apple computer one Windows computer and all the other computers can be Linux.
Rym: I'm thinking to turn in my current computer when I get the new one into our Windows computer.
Rym: Maybe I mean or you could turn your computer, which is significantly faster than mine into that.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: Anyway, the point is is that because I had to manually read all these podcasts.
Scott: I ended up dropping a whole bunch You know because they just weren't worth adding again, or like there are a couple of them like that's harsh I mean how bad you have to be to where you were only listening out of habit.
Scott: and now that it's no no no like I wasn't even listening like NPR story of the day.
Scott: right NPR stories of the day range from like five minutes to like 20 minutes.
Scott: Right yeah.
Scott: So I just kind of collected them and I would listen to them if I ran out of everything else that I had.
Scott: But I ended up not listening to them and just downloading like a bajillion episode.
Scott: So I just didn't read that.
Scott: it just wasn't worth my time.
Rym: You think you'd get to all that with an hour drive each way home to and from work.
Scott: Yeah, the other one That's pretty sad is is IT conversations, which has all the recordings of people speaking at different Conferences around the world and all that stuff.
Scott: and you know that's a feed where you really don't want to download anything in there Automatically.
Scott: you just want to look through and see what comes and download very specific Episodes.
Scott: and I had about like 20 of those things that I hadn't had time to listen to yet that are kind of wanted to.
Scott: but Again, it just wasn't worth it to read that feed and go through it.
Scott: So I tried to add like Like.
Scott: they have separate feeds on IT conversations or different categories.
Scott: So I was like, okay, I'll just add the programming one.
Scott: The programming one hasn't had a new item in it in like a year.
Scott: Great it was totally not useful at all.
Rym: I'm really looking forward to dealing with all that.
Scott: Yeah, but In addition, I added a whole bunch of new podcasts and what's kind of scary is like.
Scott: I have one anime podcast Which anime world order I added like three gaming podcasts to make up for the loss of gamers with jobs and we'll see which of them survive past, you know one episode and And You know, I have one.
Scott: I have pretty much one podcast for every geekery.
Scott: I have a board game podcast a comic book podcast, whatever right see.
Rym: now wouldn't it be nice to consolidate all those into one?
Scott: You know and listen to GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah You've already done that but I have GeekNights on everyone.
Rym: I need to listen to that for You know surprisingly we've been doing this so often and so long that it's got to the point to where after about a week I'll remember the topics I talk about.
Rym: but when I listen to myself, I don't remember saying half the things.
Scott: I say no I'm not gonna remember saying this but the What scares me a lot is that I have three sports podcasts after what I did today Three three I have I have every day.
Scott: I really actually discovered two of them today Because if I had television right like which I don't the things I would watch would be like f1 races Cartoons.
Rym: I'd watch The Daily Show probably The Daily Show maybe Sports Center, maybe I'd watch occasional hockey games.
Rym: Yeah hockey only important hockey games cuz unless I'm at a hockey arena hockey's not that fun unless it's really a big game.
Scott: See if I had HD TV I'd watch a lot more hockey than that cuz.
Scott: hockey like the enjoyment of hockey and HD is like doubled.
Rym: Yeah, if HD had anything going for it other than sports.
Scott: But and I'd probably watch that show on ESPN with the two guys arguing right which is like the best sports news show.
Scott: There is that.
Scott: the thing is I just got a podcast of the ESPN show with the two guys arguing Wait, isn't that the show that we originally considered using as the basis?
Scott: that was that was my idea.
Scott: Yeah that we can make a show and be like those two guys only do geek topics instead of sports topics Of course, that didn't work out, but whatever.
Rym: Yeah Well, we never really tried it because we settled into the format we're using now pretty quickly.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we could do a Thursday like that once or twice.
Scott: maybe it's you need a whole bunch of news items.
Scott: You need to do them really quickly and we always need to be on opposing viewpoints and all of them.
Rym: Um, that's not that hard with us.
Rym: Let's go down far and we need it.
Scott: We need to use the sand timers.
Scott: We got sand timers I know yeah, but then I got that there was a Sports Center podcast, which is like 10 minutes a day.
Scott: You get Sports Center, which is like whoo, of course I probably might unsubscribe from that pretty quickly because the best part about Sports Center is like.
Scott: you don't watch every sport.
Scott: You maybe watch like your one team But especially during baseball season you watch Sports Center and you see like the amazing plays from every sport.
Rym: Yeah, because I mean baseball is to me a really boring sport to watch.
Rym: However, occasionally awesome things happen.
Scott: It's not just baseball is there even basketball which I really don't.
Rym: I don't like basketball
Scott: But you watch Sports Center like for an hour in the morning before you go to school or work or whatever on TV And that was the best because you would just see Amazing plays from every single sport of the previous day in the United States.
Rym: What works pretty well is just Searching on Google video.
Rym: Yeah hockey fight Soccer goalie.
Scott: Yeah, but eventually you run out of those, you know, this is like, you know The best of the best of yesterday and it's always pretty good, you know Like it's some guy in the Kansas City Royals makes like an amazing dive throw thing.
Scott: You're not gonna freaking know about it without no one watches the Kansas City Royals that people in Kansas City don't know.
Rym: There's two pairs two pairs two pairs.
Scott: Yeah, but if there's an amazing play Sports Center, you know, you get that It's pretty good entertainment.
Scott: I don't think there's a better morning TV show in this country.
Rym: See to me that could definitely be the future of television.
Rym: if good shows like that We're just video casts that I could watch at my leisure with no ads and no money.
Scott: Yeah if like I won't pay 40 bucks a month to get cable to watch Sports Center every morning and have to wake up at a certain time to watch it But if I can download every Sports Center
Rym: I don't know how easy it would be to do that show if it weren't for the copyright restrictions.
Rym: All you'd have to do is be a sports geek watch all the sports on TV Maybe have a table them all and then go to it pull out all the plays put them on a thing at the end and talk about sports every day or
Scott: even better just have one guy and what.
Scott: he has a bunch of Agents around the country so he gets a fan of every single team and they're gonna watch the game.
Scott: Anyway, yeah They edit out all the best plays and send it to this guy and then he pays them all together and then he talks over It.
Scott: and there you have it Something that's not quite as quality as Sports Center but provides the same entertainment in the same content.
Rym: Yeah, and anyone who would say that no one would do that for free Look at all the podcasts.
Rym: We're all doing it.
Scott: We'll do it for free.
Scott: The problem is that stupid Major League Baseball spy satellite with their expressed written consent instead of the implied verbal consent.
Rym: We just need some focus in.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right Let's actually get to the news.
Scott: All right.
Rym: now since it's anime day and we've got our coverage of torque on 2006 coming up I would like to say that Otakon has released a minor little press thing.
Rym: That's kind of a warning that Considering the nature of it I think it's a good idea to tell all of you about it since I've realized that most people who go to Otakon have never Actually seen the Otakon website and don't bother following the forums.
Scott: How else can you find out about Otakon?
Scott: There's no other way.
Rym: Yeah But people word of mouth people just hear about it and then decide to go with a friend.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people apparently don't go to the Otakon website or at least don't go regularly.
Rym: They go like once to see what the dates are.
Scott: if you're listening to this and we have somehow convinced you to Otakon or if You have a plan to go to Otakon.
Scott: You've never been before.
Scott: maybe you have been before.
Scott: it doesn't matter You need.
Scott: if you're going to Otakon you must visit its website.
Scott: if you don't have a computer I don't know how the hell you listen to this.
Scott: but go to the library.
Scott: Go to the library and visit the Otakon website.
Scott: It is mandatory to visit.
Rym: You know what you go.
Rym: No No, it's not mandatory anymore since they finally implemented the RSS feed.
Scott: Yeah, but it's still pretty mandatory.
Rym: Well, at least follow the RSS because there is a announcement on it that apparently some fairly unscrupulous travel agency Types have been offering magic Otakon packages that may or may not include privileges at the con membership badges preference in lines and Otakon has come out to say that they haven't sponsored anything.
Rym: and no one no one No one has the right to offer Otakon badges or any Otakon privileges or use the name Otakon in any way Except Otakon.
Rym: Yeah, so if anyone says offers you like hey for a hundred bucks We'll get you a badge at a hotel room and blah.
Rym: They're lying Scammers Ahoy.
Rym: now at the same time there are a lot of fan groups that put together like chartered bus it buses from certain cities.
Rym: I know there's one leaving New York City.
Rym: Whoo, and Some people get together like hotel collectives where they get a bunch of people Strangers in and all sorts of fun things like that and that's cool.
Rym: And some travel agencies are offering like Otakon travel packages But the moment they say that they're doing anything involving Otakon itself.
Rym: They're lying.
Scott: Yeah kind of makes you wonder about some of those package deals for other places like.
Scott: I know this you the down is always down At Disney World as a bunch of packages you can buy but most some of those are legitimate at least most of them.
Rym: Yeah, well even the ones that are legitimate they're usually not in any way affiliated with Disney World.
Rym: Yeah, and that's the same thing.
Rym: There is no such thing as any affiliated package for Otakon.
Rym: Mm-hmm There are packages for Otakon but Otakon has nothing to do with them.
Rym: They don't endorse them.
Rym: They don't promote them.
Rym: They have nothing to do at all.
Scott: You know, this really makes me wonder like I never really understood the point of the travel agent.
Scott: I mean if I want to go somewhere in a trip, right if it's somewhere in this hemisphere The only person I need to help me is triple-a and even then I could probably do without.
Rym: in the very least.
Rym: Orbits plus map quest equals gold.
Scott: I know right And maybe just maybe I'll have to go get one of those books From the bookstore that tells you about the place and what you should not miss when you go there.
Rym: Yeah, that only be for a big trip.
Rym: Like if we were going out to like the west coast for a week.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: But if you're going to like a foreign country, right?
Scott: I need the book But I don't need a travel agent.
Scott: all I really need is Maybe like a tour guide or a translator or something like that, you know.
Rym: Well, it seems that most travel agencies offer deals Like they'll get a bulk rate for something and then they try to sell all the spots on the bulk rate.
Rym: So if you go with one of their spots, you couldn't negotiate that bulk rate on your own.
Rym: But they could because they have a lot of clients.
Rym: Yeah, but then you're stuck in a bulk rate thing.
Scott: Yes That's the thing I'm talking about is like why would you ever want to go on a trip that like someone else?
Rym: Set up for you now at the same time some good travel agents I've seen because I was looking around I mean we're because we're thinking you know Both of us going somewhere weird next summer.
Rym: I'm like a vacation somewhere awesome.
Rym: Well, there are a lot of travel agents that work locally in an area like say you want to go to France.
Rym: I'll just use France as an example.
Rym: You can go through a normal travel agent or just call a hotel and stay at a Marriott and eat dinner it.
Rym: you know Hard-rock cafe and all the stuff that's here.
Scott: We can.
Scott: I'm sure that on our own we could find a better hotel in France.
Rym: Oh, yeah hotel but and eat at a better place.
Rym: you could find a travel agent or at least someone out there who will help you who could Get you in touch with say the youth hostel or the chateau that lets like Tourists or boarders stay with them for a week or the cool ways to get around
Scott: a bale of hay.
Rym: Charlie Brown, is that what you're thinking about The Simpsons?
Scott: Oh Yeah season what one two one yeah episode like two or three.
Rym: That's way back.
Rym: I barely remember that it was real early.
Rym: I was thinking about the Charlie Brown where he went to France and he was mistreated and left in the barn Just like The Simpsons where Bart went to France and he was mistreated and left in a barn Yeah, and forced to drink antifreeze.
Rym: Charlie Brown was he didn't drink the antifreeze.
Rym: Yeah, they tried to make him drink it.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, Charlie Brown didn't have to drink any antifreeze.
Scott: Yeah, that's what you get for wearing a zigzag II shirt.
Scott: That made no sense.
Rym: All right.
Rym: All right, what's your news?
Rym: Oh, so Katsuhiro Otomo who is perhaps the second or third Partially, well, you don't want to get yelled at by animal world order.
Rym: Do you know?
Scott: okay, Miyazaki is like the king of anime especially anime movies and Tezuka the astro boy guy.
Scott: he's the king of manga.
Scott: Otomo is like Next in line after those guys cuz he's kind of manga and anime both.
Rym: Well, I'm really curious what anime world order is gonna have to say about that.
Scott: He made freaking Akira.
Rym: Oh, yeah I don't disagree at all.
Scott: steam boy and memories Come on.
Scott: All right anyway Cup noodle Freedom.
Scott: yeah cup noodle and Freedom this.
Scott: this could have been a thing of the day, but I think it's news cuz it's anime day.
Rym: I just this is something I really don't get.
Scott: So cup noodle needed a commercial to sell cup noodle to Japanese people.
Scott: They got Otomo one of the greatest anime makers of all time to make the commercial for them and their Campaign.
Scott: their their marketing campaign slogan is freedom.
Scott: What does cup noodle have to do with freedom?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: ask a ramenite but What that?
Scott: okay, they pay this guy a lot of money and they got Utada Hikaru to sing a song Over the commercial.
Scott: what the hell?
Rym: I don't get it.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I don't even like cup noodle.
Scott: I don't like cup noodle either.
Rym: I get I gotta go with a bowl noodle or at least the Sapporo Ichiban.
Rym: Yeah, or the.
Rym: I personally like the kitsune with a bean curd.
Rym: That's my favorite ramen.
Scott: But still what's up with the Really expensive commercial of a freaking noodles that are more American than Japanese cup noodle.
Scott: Yeah Japanese people get better noodles than that and like any street corner And you make yeah, all right.
Rym: Yeah, I don't get but watch the commercial.
Scott: it's it's entertaining because it's made by a master of anime.
Scott: Oh Do we have some good things of the day today?
Rym: Yeah, we didn't even have to try this time.
Scott: You might have seen some of them though, but that's okay.
Rym: All right, so we've talked up V for Vendetta.
Rym: It's a fantastic movie.
Rym: It's a fantastic comic.
Rym: I was very impressed with it.
Rym: I have found a trailer to a movie that you might like even more.
Rym: C for cookie.
Scott: C is so cookie is good enough for me.
Rym: It's someone made this.
Rym: it kind of doesn't sync up with the audio.
Rym: I thought it was my player but it really doesn't because they just took clips from Sesame Street and put them in to V for Vendetta.
Rym: yeah, and then they put voices over it, but the voices are top-notch and I think the best part is when the count is like two last chances.
Scott: Yeah, the count voice was in fact the worst voice though.
Scott: It didn't sound like the count so much Yeah, but it had the spirit of the count.
Scott: Yeah, it's what counts.
Rym: That was not intentional, all right, here's a nice question for all of you out there.
Rym: One watch this trailer.
Rym: It's really well done and cool.
Scott: It's a already trailers.
Rym: In fact it's probably better than Titanic to the surface.
Scott: Yeah, that one wasn't that impressive.
Rym: well That's because you haven't seen Titanic.
Scott: don't really care about Titanic.
Scott: I'm never gonna see it.
Rym: if someone out there can find us a video of The batty bat the batty bat batty bat batty batty batty batty batty batty one two three count.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Yeah, I know Betty bet well.
Rym: We actually will give some sort of prize because we can't find it.
Scott: Yeah, I tried to search on YouTube and Google video for a video of The batty bat the original Sesame Street batty bat, and I couldn't find it at home.
Scott: I actually have a VHS tape that like this my sisters and my brothers, and they were little.
Scott: It's like a Sesame Street dance tape or something and it shows you how to dance the batty bat using.
Scott: So I could get that and dance the batty bat.
Scott: But I don't think I don't have the original batty bat.
Scott: with the bats that are hanging from the ceiling accounts little room with his organ.
Scott: You know moving the little wing-a-lings back and forth and spinning around and you know singing.
Rym: Yeah, I want that video All right, yeah now really We'll give you something.
Rym: because I know a lot of times we say oh if you give us something and we trail off no We'll give you something.
Rym: I don't know what it'll be one day.
Scott: what we're gonna Do?
Rym: you know it will be like all those webcomic artists?
Rym: We'll give them a sketch.
Scott: Yeah, I'll give you a sketch.
Scott: Ready here's the dirty Vika skin.
Scott: Oh Tits go go.
Scott: No, what we'll probably do is one day when we have a logo and such We'll buy a lot of merch and we'll get like merch.
Scott: that costs money like t-shirts And then we'll get free shit merch like stickers.
Scott: and whenever we say we'll give you something.
Scott: It'll just be a sticker Yeah, or something else cheap like a keychain.
Rym: And I remember just now that someone did answer one of our previous questions in the forum and I forget who it was.
Scott: But the next time I remember it I'll say something on the air cuz tomorrow I'll go through our emails in the forum finding all the people who are on the list and I'll make a list.
Scott: And then what we'll do is when the time comes and we get merch I'll send everyone.
Scott: I'll send an email to everyone a list or a forum message to everyone on the list and then I'll send you a sticker.
Scott: Or if I see you in person, I'll give you something.
Rym: Yeah, come to Otakon and you'll see us.
Scott: Yep All right, so my thing of the day you might have seen this already because it's pretty popular It's a secret Wars reenactment video.
Scott: It's it's basically parodying two things.
Scott: Well three things It's parodying stupid comic fans all things all things.
Scott: It's Monty Python day.
Scott: It's parodying three things nerdy comic fans.
Scott: So Marvel secret wars and those people who reenact the Civil War.
Rym: those people are cool But they're also scary like SCA people.
Scott: cool yet.
Scott: Scary.
Rym: I watched a reenactment of a battle from the Civil War once Mm-hmm.
Rym: It looked really realistic and well done and it was kind of cool But at the same time they got a little too into it.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's what bothers me is, you know people get into it.
Scott: Anyway, if you don't know let me explain secret wars really quickly because I had never even read it.
Scott: I ordered the books though.
Scott: She should be here in like two months.
Scott: But secret wars is like the second time ever that comic books had like this giant event Right that had a bunch of million characters in it.
Scott: And what basically happened is like I think it was the cosmic cube.
Scott: I'm not sure but there was something in Central Park and all the Marvel superheroes went into it and it took them to some other Dimension where crazy shit happened.
Rym: See this is why I don't like comics.
Scott: Yeah And basically spider-man with the galactic sewing machine or whatever the fuck it was Made the black and white spider-man costume that eventually became venom, you know.
Rym: That's why I also don't like comics.
Scott: and the thing Was able to switch between being the big rock guy and a human self.
Scott: So he stayed there and everyone else went back and they fought a bunch of villains.
Scott: and that was it.
Scott: It was a secret war cuz no one knew about it because it took place in this other dimension.
Scott: That's why it's called secret wars.
Rym: so a sewing machine.
Scott: It's kind of a sewing machine kind of not but it's essential.
Scott: They don't use the word sewing machine, but it's essentially a galactic sewing machine.
Rym: Great, right?
Scott: So What these guys are reenacting is all the battles that went on in secret wars.
Rym: So now this is obviously not real.
Rym: This is obviously some kids making a funny thing like a fear of girls.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: That's what it is.
Scott: But it's also hilarious, especially, you know There are a few jokes like even they're actually some obscure characters and they're like Kang.
Scott: Kang is like one of the best dudes in Marvel Comics and no one even knows about Kang You know and it's the one guys dressed up as Kang and I think someone says to him something to him and he's like Kang doesn't blah blah blah.
Scott: It's pretty hilarious.
Scott: and the little kid with the Wolverine is pretty funny, too.
Scott: Yeah, I want the guy trying to pick up the frisbee with the thing or Hulk hands the Hulk hands.
Scott: Yeah, that was good, too The mr.
Scott: Fantastic guys kind of weird.
Scott: and then there's like the spider-man guy who doesn't know what he's doing.
Rym: Yeah, yeah the Doc Ock trying to wiggle his hips to hit the guy with his Doc Ock things.
Scott: Yeah, just just watch it.
Scott: It's pretty funny.
Rym: Yeah, it's definitely not as good as fear of girls, but it's up there.
Scott: Yep It's just another one of those things like that.
Scott: And it's appropriate cuz it's comic day.
Rym: people should not be afraid of cookie.
Rym: cookie should be afraid of people.
Scott: Cookie should be afraid of stomach acid.
Rym: Yeah, all right, so we went to target.
Scott: wait a minute.
Scott: You know like there are people who believe that you know some magical God created them and they pray to that God.
Scott: Do cookies pray to grandma for baking them?
Rym: So we went to target.
Rym: We went to Torah con this year this past weekend.
Rym: for those of you who only listen to anime day I suggest that you listen to the Monday episode this week Because we played on that episode our live panel from Torah con 2006 because that panel was largely about Podcasting and not about anime.
Scott: We played it on Monday, even though we did it at an anime convention.
Rym: Now Torah con is not a terribly widely known convention because this was its 2.5 one.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: Yeah, basically way way back when I was president of the RIT anime club.
Rym: I Tried to Fiat threw a spring cosplay and it went All right, not that many people showed up But actually we had a really good promotional thing and there was a good event.
Rym: It was fun.
Rym: The next year after I graduated the next president of the anime club decided that they would go one step further and turn this into an actual one-day convention.
Rym: hooray now Everyone in our crew the entire front row crew with the exception of Scott Drove out to torque on 2005 last year and had a ride his time.
Rym: Yeah, now the funny thing is none of us expected torque on to be big or anything.
Rym: We expected basically the same kind of events.
Rym: The club has always thrown just a little thing.
Rym: We got there and there were.
Rym: there was a huge crazy crowd and a line out the door and it was fantastic.
Rym: For the first year of a con it was just amazing.
Rym: So we came back this year this time as both of us guests and did a panel.
Scott: Hooray Let's do a little crap.
Scott: so driving up there was Somewhat unpleasant with the rain.
Rym: Yeah, basically Rochester it rains there always.
Scott: Well, no, the sky is always gray there.
Scott: It just happened to be that when we were entering with as we got closer to Rochester It rained more and then when we finally left Rochester the rains started to subside.
Rym: Yeah, plus we drove up real late Because you know people.
Rym: yeah, yeah, but we got there and it was weird.
Rym: this was the first time where we visited Rochester place.
Rym: we lived for some four or five years going to school and Instead of crashing on someone's floor or doing the thing.
Scott: We always do we stayed in a hotel room Which is good because I could freakin sleep on a bed not on a floor.
Rym: Yeah Shower is key.
Rym: I mean no offense to our friends in college and Especially since our shower is just as bad but no one in Rochester at least at RIT has a shower that I can deal with anymore.
Scott: No, no, no, damn.
Scott: I Mean either they have low pressure or it's dirty.
Rym: Dirty is the primary.
Rym: this stuff in there one of our friends their bathroom in their in their apartment And RIT is so bad with mildew and mold that I if I walk in my eyes start watering.
Rym: Wow, I pee in there with my eyes closed.
Rym: Oh my god All right Yeah, but anyway, we you know stay in the hotel room crazy time and then in the morning we woke up and we went to Torricon.
Rym: It wasn't much bigger than last year, but that doesn't really mean anything bad because that means it was still really big.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't seem very crowded, you know, yeah
Rym: But that also could be due to the fact that it used more rooms this year,
Scott: uh-huh
Rym: Now I will say that the primary thing we did at Torricon was actually sit in a big circle in various rooms throughout the con Playing DS games
Scott: mostly Tetris.
Rym: Yeah Tetris is great.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna call this Tetris con Instead of Torricon, it would have been just as accurate But I got to say it's.
Rym: I realized that I'm kind of addicted to going to conventions as a guest.
Rym: Like it's different from going to a convention normally.
Rym: I'm not used to going to a con and here's my money.
Rym: Give me a badge because for so long it's been.
Rym: hey I'm Rym and oh, it's Rym.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Here's your special magic badge that says something slightly different.
Rym: that makes you 1% cooler than nobody.
Rym: All right, so it was real nice to get in as a guest.
Scott: It just meant I didn't have to pay though.
Scott: It was a 12 bucks.
Rym: Yeah, it was a decent bit of money quite a bit more than last year.
Scott: Yeah the 12 bucks I think you know.
Scott: while in the grand scheme 12 bucks is like nothing like if any con charge 12 bucks They're like sure 12 bucks is less than what we paid each for our dinner at Torricon.
Scott: Yeah, but at the same time considering the Torricon is so small and you're not really, you know I don't think you really get 12 bucks worth.
Scott: Get like 10 bucks worth maybe eight, you know, so while 12 isn't like exorbitantly overpriced It's it's like a tiny bit much and it some a lot of poor otaku types felt a little uncomfortable and I could see why.
Rym: Yeah, well part of that was due to confusion at RIT.
Scott: Oh, yeah, some people thought it was 20 because some the SG listed it is 20 when it wasn't.
Scott: yeah, that was a mess-up.
Scott: Yeah, that's not cool.
Scott: 20 would have been outrageous.
Scott: But you know 12 is.
Scott: it was, you know near the limit Yeah, but I think it was fair considering that they had pine am do a concert Yeah, but then they charge you two bucks extra if you wanted a pine am ticket.
Rym: I heard that that was because they got pine am at the last minute after they'd already set the prices.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I don't know for sure since I'm not on their board or anything.
Scott: as a matter two bucks is basically nothing Yeah, and they didn't charge for anything else besides that.
Rym: Yeah Well, I think they'd like if you did the metal works panel you had to pay a little bit for your stuff.
Scott: Well, no, I think what happened because we were the metal works panel was right before ours and I heard them talking.
Rym: Well, it was listed as $3.
Scott: it was listed as three dollars, but it seemed like the metal works guys are the ones collecting that money because It was only paying for their materials and such.
Scott: Yeah, and Those guys really didn't seem to care if the people didn't pay they just thought it was nice if you paid.
Rym: Yeah, they really didn't seem to want to get out of our panel room and it was time for us to record our show.
Scott: Yeah, and I heard a story later just to hearsay that they didn't want to get out of the their the room later when they Had a panel again because they had two panels, but whatever what workshops technically.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway I mean, it's not a big con but it's a one-day thing and it's it's very fun.
Rym: I think it's fairly well-run.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I mean basically, you know, we got there and we saw all of our old friends again.
Rym: It was a huge get-together.
Rym: We couldn't walk five feet without.
Rym: Hey, it's Rym and Scott in the front row crew.
Scott: Oh There's a person I haven't seen.
Scott: Oh, there's a person I haven't seen you.
Scott: There's a prison.
Scott: I've been seen.
Rym: Yeah, we saw some people with people I have seen.
Rym: yeah, basically everyone was there with a few exceptions, but they all had good excuses Mm-hmm, except Ian.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah his story is.
Scott: I don't think you listen to this So you should tell him to listen to this one, I think I did once.
Scott: I don't know What he's doing.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean they had a panel on web comics Which was funny because one we knew all the webcomic people on the panel and two None of them.
Rym: really well I was one except they don't really update their comics so much anymore.
Scott: Yeah, I'm kind of.
Scott: Their panel was actually a pretty good panel like and it was mildly entertaining all things considered.
Scott: But at the same time I'm kind of phased, you know, every con has a freaking web comics panel.
Scott: I just don't see the point of it anymore.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it'd be like if we still do a podcasting panel two years from now.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you're gonna have a panel at a con.
Scott: sure you can make pretty much any panel.
Scott: I could make a panel.
Scott: you can pick a random topic and I can make it entertaining, you know That's not the point.
Scott: The point is if you have a panel at a con there should be a purpose to that.
Scott: I feel there should be a purpose.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well to me I see two basic kinds of panels Informative and entertaining.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And as long as you're one of the two, I don't really care what the panel is about.
Rym: I mean with what the panel went to at Otakon last year.
Rym: Mike Pfeffer's thing on Politics and anime.
Scott: that was informative.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: It was also entertaining.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, that's cuz he's so cool Yep.
Rym: Now we did a panel at Tora con that was very informative.
Rym: It was here is Podcasting and how it works.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now if we do this again, we'll probably be a lot less informative and a lot more entertaining.
Rym: and the webcomic panel.
Rym: It was very entertaining but there's really nothing left to be said about web comics.
Rym: every web comics panel Everyone asked the same questions.
Rym: How do you do it?
Rym: How long does it take to do it?
Rym: Why did you start?
Rym: What comics do you read?
Scott: Yeah, it's like I don't you know, that's the part of it that I don't see the point of anymore.
Scott: you might as well just have a You know don't call it a web comics panel because it's kind of dumb to have web comics panels ever call it like You know.
Scott: panel.
Scott: meet webcomic artists you know.
Scott: or webcomic artists chat or call it something different and you know.
Scott: bill it as an Entertaining talk with webcomic artists and not as the web comics panel where everyone talks about webcomics Yep, which luckily that's what the three webcomic artists did in their panel here at Otakon at Tora Con.
Scott: Well, that's the other thing is that even if you bill a web comics panel as talking about web comics Webcomic artists have talked about that stuff so much on panels a thousand times and there's nothing left to be said.
Scott: So they end up just having to do what I said They should do anyway, which is just be entertaining and have a fun time.
Rym: Yep, which to me is the best kind of panel?
Scott: Yeah, I mean the worst kind of panels the ones where guys just sit there go Yeah Nothing hat or even they don't do anything and they don't show up.
Rym: or hey people not showing up for a panel is great.
Rym: That's how I got my start in this whole panel business.
Scott: Yeah But there's also industry panels which I don't go to but they have a purpose to like.
Scott: those are quote real panels.
Scott: Yeah, you know where they have like announcements to make Guests to like question and announce things and that sort of shit.
Scott: That's a real panel.
Rym: But overall that panel is really fun.
Rym: The panel we ran actually was very fun, too.
Rym: We had a decent crowd and they seem to like us.
Rym: Yeah, you heard that on Monday, yep, you can hear him cheering in the background.
Scott: The dealing at the con was done mostly in the main lobby and There really wasn't anything for me to buy at all.
Scott: I think the best thing I saw was like a bank that was shaped like a question block.
Rym: Yeah I mean, I guess for me, I'm just jaded to dealers rooms.
Rym: I buy almost nothing at cons anymore.
Scott: Yeah, well the thing with dealers rooms is like originally.
Scott: it was like that There was stuff there that you'd never seen before but you really wanted you like.
Scott: Oh my god amazing imported goods from Japan.
Scott: I must have them all.
Rym: yep capsule toys capsule toys.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, but once you get them all or you get enough of them, it's like, okay.
Scott: What do you have?
Scott: That's new.
Scott: Do you have you know this new Mario diorama thing?
Scott: Do you have this new plushie from this brand new anime that everyone's into?
Scott: and if you don't have anything new It's like.
Scott: I've seen all this stuff before.
Scott: I already know I don't want it.
Rym: Yeah, I've gotten to the point where I go to a dealers room and I want like one or two specific things and I just Walk around looking for those things.
Scott: Yeah, the first two Otakons I went to where the dealers room is tremendous.
Scott: You know, you see everything and you've already know your brain has already said I don't want that and I do want this.
Scott: It's like if you go to a video game store and then you go to the same video game store the next day.
Scott: You already know the parts of the store that have stuff and what's generally there and that you don't want it and you go right to the place that has the stuff that you might want the new releases or whatever.
Scott: and That's what dealers rooms turned into.
Scott: is you gloss over everything you've seen and you go right for the new stuff and then you're done.
Scott: Yeah, but at least the unique stuff that I may not be new, but I didn't realize existed Yeah, that's another thing is like I don't want to spend too much time in the dealer room because it could be a waste of Time.
Scott: it's a risk.
Scott: but at the same time you can tell the interesting dealers when they start to have like Weird things that don't look conventional
Rym: like first
Scott: I get down and I start rooting through all of it to find you know Like the rare hot piece
Rym: like you see the dealer that has DVDs at basically retail prices.
Rym: ignore him.
Rym: You see the other dealer with the exact same setup.
Rym: You see the dealer that has all the $40 Japanese CDs and $100 art books.
Rym: you ignore him and then you find the one that has like the cool weird bin of crap or discount manga for a dollar or Crazy imported weird thing that you've never seen in the US before.
Rym: look at this thing
Scott: You can always tell like there was a one dealer at Otakon last year where the the booth was set up weird with like these White racks and like there were things hanging from overhead and everything like that and it was real crowded to walk around.
Scott: the booth.
Scott: Wasn't the best booth design in terms of crowd control?
Rym: Well, it might have been due to the fact that I don't think he expected to quite the crowd at his booth.
Scott: yeah, but everything in that booth was like You know, it was mostly imported mangas and art books and things that you'd never seen before because you know the major importers like Kino Kuni.
Scott: you don't get that stuff because not stuff you get in bulk and It wasn't stuff that was ever translated here.
Scott: See then you start looking around.
Scott: you find all this weird stuff.
Scott: It's not really, you know outlandish, but it's stuff you've never seen before in your life didn't know it existed.
Scott: So then you start to look through every single item the guy has and every single weird, you know He doesn't have things organized so well with everything in the same place.
Scott: So I'll have like a pin like hanging up on the side of a little white rack and you like oh, you know And those are the.
Scott: that's the dealers you spend time in.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's actually how I got my.
Rym: it's one of my favorite little bits.
Rym: It's a con badge holder.
Rym: It exists solely to hold convention badges as far as I can tell and it's a really cool little piece of I guess jewelry.
Rym: And I just found it by itself hanging from actually the ceiling of one Guys booth at Katsucon last year.
Rym: Hmm.
Scott: It's all about the nooks and crannies, you know.
Scott: So when you have a little dealers room like the one at Tora con There really aren't so many nooks and crannies and you see pretty much everything.
Scott: They've got from 10 feet away and you don't need to.
Scott: you know deal a lot.
Rym: But at the same time they seem to be doing brisk business.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I think you know a lot of people.
Scott: they're probably never been to a con or you know Their first Tora con at least and the dealers didn't seem like they were super used to dealing You know at many big conventions, so no, what do you expect?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I mean it is a small convention.
Rym: still though I do think it's gonna grow in time.
Scott: Hmm So, let's see the head of video game room, which I didn't spend more than also five minutes in Yeah, but it was definitely spacious which is key.
Scott: Yeah It was good that it was spacious and give give people a lot of room to move around and breathe and all that spectate but at the same time it didn't seem like they had too many games going on and They're you know, they had the shitty small TVs.
Rym: well for chairs the fact because I mean I used to do all this if the fact that they had so few TVs leads me To believe that the TVs were allocated elsewhere by RIT and they had fewer TVs than they wanted I'm pretty sure that's the case.
Rym: But you know though to me the only failing of the video game room is that they should have Encouraged and set up something to do with a Nintendo DS.
Rym: Yeah, every con I've been to since the DS came out has been just a flood of DS's and you'll see whole groups of people Just sitting down all over the place playing DS games wirelessly.
Scott: I didn't see too many DS's other than ours though.
Rym: It's weird Yeah, but I mean I've been to RIT during anime club meetings recently and yeah 30 or 40 DS's all whipped out.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: So yeah, maybe because people there I mean, it's RIT It's a campus.
Rym: Everyone's playing DS games all the time.
Rym: So when they go to a con they want to do con stuff.
Scott: Yeah, plus there were with three tournaments and none of them were really exciting.
Scott: They should have had at least one fun tournament like a Mario Tennis or something.
Rym: Well, I guess I don't think they had.
Rym: I don't know why but they didn't run any big tournaments.
Scott: Yeah Oh, well, the artist's alley was pretty good.
Scott: The only thing that you know, it could have been bigger, but I think they had it just right for the room They put it in.
Rym: Yep, because there aren't so many rooms they can use in the building that they have the con in.
Rym: So that was pretty much the only room they could put that in unless it got really really big.
Rym: Yeah But I mean the art there was typical of artist's alleys.
Rym: It was good.
Rym: We had some friends in there who have awesome art.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: There were some people in there with not so awesome art, but that's how artist's alleys go.
Scott: You know, not everyone's super amazing.
Scott: Oh my god art, you know, if everyone is super amazing.
Scott: Oh my god art There wouldn't be any crap art and then the super amazing wouldn't be super amazing and etc.
Rym: Now, of course true to its roots the main thing about ToraCon I mean basically up until the cosplay.
Rym: ToraCon is basically just getting people to hang out long enough for the cosplay to start.
Rym: Toric I mean start.
Rym: there was a. it started as a cosplay and then it became a con But it was centered around the cosplay and now it's becoming a real con bit by bit like a big con But it's definitely still.
Rym: the cosplay is like.
Rym: this is the main event.
Scott: Well, it seems like a lot of conventions the cosplay is the main event, you know Even when you go to Otakon you can totally ignore the cosplay and get a crazy con.
Scott: They oh the cosplay is still crazy huge.
Scott: Yep, even when they have a main event like a concert with a real band The cosplay is like perhaps bigger or if not equal.
Rym: Yep, though.
Rym: Definitely ToraCon.
Rym: Nothing was scheduled opposite the cosplay.
Rym: So, I mean there were things going on during the day, but pretty much it was after the cosplay started.
Rym: it was cosplay and the concert and The dance and nothing overlapped anything.
Rym: from that point on Cool seem to work fairly.
Rym: Well, there was definitely time to get dinner which was good.
Scott: Yeah the cosplay itself.
Scott: I went to some of the skits.
Scott: I think there were two skits that were real funny and good Yeah, the Legend of Zelda skit.
Scott: that one was actually really good Yeah, and some of there were a few really good costumes there too like surprisingly But at the same time it didn't have a whole.
Scott: the quantity wasn't there, you know It was.
Rym: it was over pretty quickly like, you know what that made me very happy.
Rym: I I like watching cosplays because a lot of times it'll you'll see the diamond in the rough the awesome sketch or that the awesome Costume, but I can't waste two hours of my time at Otakon.
Scott: Yeah at Otakon We've made a habit of just kind of moseying into the you know spillover.
Scott: Yeah the spillover room.
Scott: They always have a spillover room even though they you know Even if the regular cosplay room doesn't fill up.
Scott: They always have the cosplay like Video casted in another room live and it's always so much better to go there cuz not crowded and you can see better and It's just great.
Scott: Yep, and they usually in that same room show the really good movies late on Saturday night.
Rym: Yeah, yep But I mean the cosplay toricon was short and it was pretty good and I really enjoyed it and the fact that it was short Was very key and me enjoying it.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one thing that's wrong about.
Scott: You know bigger cons is that the cause any cosplay is 90% crap 10% awesome.
Scott: So the shorter it is the less time you spend crap and you still get the same amount of awesome.
Rym: Though the one main thing about the cosplay at toricon that I like is that last year I was actually cosplay judge and this year I was not but I did other things instead.
Rym: The cosplay was actually run very professionally and very well by the people who were in charge of it.
Rym: They had a sort of crisis where the person who was in charge of the cosplay was for various reasons He left the board and was no longer in charge of the cosplay right before the con.
Rym: So someone else was forced to take his place and run the whole cosplay basically on almost no notice.
Rym: Yeah, and considering that they did a pretty good job even not considering that that was an extremely well-run cosplay.
Rym: Yeah I mean even Otakon.
Rym: they have a lot of trouble running the cosplay smoothly.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, they're always like oh who's on next who's right, you know.
Scott: The only time they messed up I think at this one was they had.
Scott: They seemed like they had a piece of paper for every skit and cosplayer.
Scott: Yeah, that's how you do it Yeah, and I think they lost one of the pieces of paper and that was the worst thing that happened.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it was really well done.
Rym: Like I was actually really impressed.
Scott: Yeah had the shit together all good.
Rym: now after that We got dinner and then there was the concert pine.
Scott: and yeah I had heard of pine am like I knew it was the name of a Japanese band of girls who made music And then I knew they were no Otakon and I didn't see them.
Scott: I think I saw them from far away, but didn't actually listen to the music or anything.
Rym: Yeah, I'd been told of their music, but I hadn't actually heard it and it was.
Rym: it was described to me by someone as Almost electric electro pop but almost techno but not really Yeah, and with cute Japanese girls and that didn't really explain anything to me.
Scott: No, I didn't so considering you know, that was like The biggest thing going on at Tora con.
Scott: we paid our two bucks and we went to see it and it was pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, I there there.
Rym: two of the three band members were there.
Rym: They put on I'd say a really good set in an actual real auditorium.
Rym: Mm-hmm He the crowd was a little sedated first, which might have surprised them but then a bunch of people ran up to the front and then I ran up to the front and then everyone ran up to The front ever started dancing and screaming.
Scott: Yeah, I would have run up to the front to like I wanted to but I food.
Scott: Well, there was the Thai food and the the hours and hours of driving and I was like, you know what?
Scott: I haven't sat down all day.
Scott: I can see it.
Rym: Yeah, I ran straight up to the front.
Rym: I was literally about three feet away from the the singers.
Rym: Yep It was a. it was a really good concert and they seemed to really get into it.
Rym: in fact after the concert They set up a little table right outside and they signed pretty much as many autographs as people were there who wanted them.
Scott: It doesn't seem like they're that crazy popular in Japan or the US.
Scott: so You know, they're sort of like.
Scott: they're not an independent, you know garage band, but they're like one step above that.
Rym: They definitely don't make enough money however to keep themselves going.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's for sure.
Scott: I mean if you have any success at all.
Scott: It's like with a record company with being a musical artist.
Scott: if you're in it with a record company There's like this line and when once you're below the line you're in trouble, but as soon as you cross the line, it's great.
Scott: Especially, you know, if you're actually musically talented you do all sorts of other things besides just your band, you know You do all sorts of other musical things to make money also Yep, and I got to say I do really like their music now that I've heard it.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't the worst music It wasn't the best music, but it was decent.
Scott: It wasn't painful to listen to.
Scott: you know, I was pretty much just Groovin, I wouldn't download it and listen to it my car But I wouldn't mind listening to it if someone else popped it into a CD player, whatever.
Rym: Yeah I'll probably acquire an album at some point.
Rym: Yeah, but that's I mean the two singers were actually really cool.
Scott: Yeah, it seemed like they were much Like the people themselves were much cooler than at least my opinion of their music.
Scott: It's like someone is so cool and then they make decent music.
Scott: That's not as cool as they are.
Rym: But okay No, the crowd seemed to love them and I don't know.
Rym: Maybe they'll be back next year.
Rym: I don't know what'll happen to next Tora con.
Scott: Yeah, they'll have to do something.
Rym: Who knows I mean this was the torque on first musical guest.
Rym: I think it was a really good pick because it was like it was a good band.
Rym: It was a good show and It's actually really it's kind of rare for a small con to get a not up.
Rym: not it's not definitely not a big name But a sizable good band for as little money and resources as they had.
Scott: Usually if you have a tiny con like this, you're lucky to get.
Rym: you're lucky to get like industry person.
Rym: You're lucky to get like the one guy in town who kind of knows how to play a Final Fantasy song on his guitar.
Scott: You're lucky if you get piano squall.
Scott: Or you're lucky if you get like one guy from a TV to show up.
Rym: anyone can get piano squall You just have to pay.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, he doesn't Oda Khan doesn't pay him.
Scott: Yeah But he does that one for free.
Scott: That's his advertising.
Scott: But the point is The fact that you get like a real band at a little tiny con.
Scott: It's just huge.
Rym: Yeah, like I'm really props to them for doing that plus the.
Rym: they took it.
Rym: I don't know if they took the suggestion from us.
Rym: I think it's just the natural progression of things in a con.
Rym: but this year they had a dance slash rave after the concert.
Scott: You kind of need one of those in any con nowadays.
Rym: Well last year when we went after the cosplay and impromptu dance slash rave Started all on its own in the cosplay room afterwards.
Scott: How did you just get a boombox?
Rym: Well, we're in the.
Rym: they were in the web auditorium and someone just put a CD on and everyone just stuck around and danced until We basically got kicked out.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: So this year they actually got a real DJ who was mixing vinyl out there.
Rym: And while I'm not the hugest fan of you know, straight-up house mixing with vinyl I just I'm not that interested in that kind of music.
Rym: The guy was really good like the DJ.
Rym: I forget his name, but he was really good at what he did and I think he put on a good show.
Scott: Yeah, like.
Scott: I'm not really a fan of like being in the dance club while they're playing the dumb dumb dumb Technos, but I actually kind of like listening to good Electronic music just listening.
Rym: Yeah, you know, I like dancing to it But I don't like.
Rym: I don't usually like dancing to the stuff that people in clubs tend to play.
Rym: Yeah, because the people in clubs in the US don't tend to play the type of techno I like.
Scott: but listening to this guy You know through the walls because you can hear it from anywhere nearby.
Scott: Some of the at least the parts that I was listening to in his music were like, yeah, it's a good techno All right.
Rym: Yeah, and people were for the most part actually dancing.
Rym: Yeah I mean I was a little disappointed that he didn't play more anime related stuff But I mean, that's me and that's the kind of dance music I like.
Rym: but the fact that despite that he played music That was good enough for me to go dance to it was good.
Scott: Yeah, if I would have if I would have been in the mood to get up to the front at the pine am concert I probably would have spent some time in the rave instead of just poking my head in and not poking it.
Rym: Yeah, again, though while I poked my head in I'll say that the sound system was good.
Rym: The music was you know, like if we said good there was very little funk which made me very happy.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't think there was really funk anywhere in the con so much Like I didn't have a bad smell at all.
Scott: and when we were at the little tiny video game con there was smell.
Scott: Yeah, that one Oh God aiming for hope how to smell and not toricon not at all.
Rym: Yeah, especially considering it was kind of humid and kind of hot all weekend.
Scott: Did you there wasn't any DDR?
Scott: toricon was there?
Rym: I wouldn't be surprised if that was a conscious decision.
Scott: Maybe I think was there a guitar hero.
Scott: I didn't see that either.
Rym: No, actually now that I think about it No, they didn't have any of that as far as I could tell but last year the video gaming was all in the fireside lounge Which is this huge huge huge room this year.
Rym: They didn't have that room for the whole con.
Rym: I think that threw a kink in all their plans.
Scott: Yeah someone else was using that room for part of the time.
Rym: they were pissed those other people because there's a giant dance party and all These crazy anime people running around and they're having some sort of like award ceremony thing.
Scott: It's sort of banquet pageant thing.
Scott: Yeah, it was great.
Scott: But before they took that room over I think the They used it for the music video showing.
Rym: Yep, which we did I forgot to talk about but it was actually.
Rym: I mean, it wasn't great.
Rym: We played Tetris during it Yeah, but we stood up and watched, you know bits of all the videos to get a feel for it.
Rym: Most cons these days have really crappy anime music video contests.
Rym: I'm not even gonna lie.
Rym: most cons just the AMV is that are coming.
Scott: Well, there's nothing to do with the cons has to do with the fact that people making music video these days are just terrible.
Scott: Yeah back in the day It was hard to do so.
Scott: people wouldn't do it unless they were gonna put in a whole lot of effort to make something really good.
Scott: and it sort of went on this curve of.
Scott: Okay, some people put in a lot of effort to make something really great.
Scott: The technology got better.
Scott: people kept as a technology made it easier.
Scott: people kept doing a better and better job and making better and better Music videos.
Scott: then the technology made it too easy.
Scott: So now people don't make as good music videos.
Scott: It's so easy to make them.
Rym: now some people still do but they're just harder to find or harder to sift out through all the crap.
Scott: Yeah, or they just keep it to themselves.
Scott: a lot of them.
Scott: They're kind of scary.
Rym: So bearing that in mind that our opinion is we're fairly elitist when it comes to AMVs and we were very kind of.
Scott: well It's all relative.
Scott: Like if I'd never seen an AMV before and I had seen the ones shown at ToraCon I would have been like holy crap.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But seeing is that your music video has to compete with all the anime music videos I've seen in the past.
Scott: Yeah, you got you're up against a tough bunch.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the mama Leo hit me baby one more time.
Scott: It's sort of unfair because when you think about it, you look at something like sports.
Scott: Right, the Mets team playing right now in baseball doesn't have to compete with Previous baseball teams.
Scott: They only have to compete with the ones that exist right now.
Scott: But you know seeing is that music videos aren't sports.
Scott: you make something now You have to compete with everything that ever existed.
Scott: It's really hard to win.
Rym: Like you might have the best idea for an Evangelion music video ever like.
Rym: seriously your idea is awesome And you were an awesome person, but there are so many Ava music videos.
Rym: Don't even bother because there's no way anyone will even notice it.
Scott: I mean look at the f1 race.
Scott: He just watched, you know Alonzo is doing really really well.
Scott: He didn't win the most recent race But if anyone had to compete with not Michael Schumacher now But Michael Schumacher of five years ago in his better car you couldn't win It.
Scott: just that's how it is.
Rym: Yeah, so bear all that in mind.
Rym: I mean I can't say the AMVs were great because a very few AMVs are great to me anymore.
Rym: The AMVs were typical of big good conventions.
Rym: Like it was the kind of AMV contest I'd expect from an Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, I think there were two sappy one two or three sappy ones I wasn't interested in.
Rym: there were the typical whole bunch of fighting scene ones.
Scott: Yeah, the ones with a whole bunch of fighting scenes.
Scott: There was one that could have been a little better Where the action scenes didn't really match the music.
Scott: because if you're gonna do the action Music video, you know, what you have to do is you have to match the beats of the music to the action.
Scott: That's what makes those things cool to watch.
Scott: Yeah, like if you don't get it right on it's like, uh, you know what?
Rym: Let's do a whole show on AMVs Because we could actually go point-for-point examples like this.
Scott: This is one of the categories and this is how to make a good video in those categories.
Rym: Yeah, I think cuz we're really kind of like connoisseur slash snobs when it comes to the sort of thing kind of Comes to a lot of things.
Scott: Yeah, we are.
Scott: That's the point of this.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So while I said the AMV is a torque on weren't great take that with the grain of.
Rym: we are elitist bastard salt Because it was a really good AMV contest.
Rym: Like I really given props for pulling that off.
Scott: There was that one video that was actually like five as among Adil videos attached to that was.
Rym: that was cheating in my opinion.
Scott: I also counted as cheating.
Scott: But if you separate it into five separate videos, like it should have been the first one was a was really good.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Scott: Yeah, that's about it.
Rym: Yep And I mean overall torque on was a great time and anyone who lives anywhere near the Rochester area I highly recommend you check it out.
Rym: It's super cheap.
Rym: It's only one day.
Rym: if you need a hotel hotels in Rochester cost nothing.
Scott: Yeah, it seemed like a lot of the hotels really close were either expensive or full But we found one a short ways away for nothing.
Rym: I think the reason most of the hotels I looked at were sold out was due to the fact that I waited until three days Before we left to get the hotel room.
Scott: Yeah with Otakon you have to get a year in advance.
Scott: with Tora Khan I think a couple months in advance is it would be okay, but not three days.
Scott: three days.
Scott: This isn't okay for anywhere at any time.
Scott: Yeah, except for like on the highway where you get off and you stop at any hotel you want.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean really if you live anywhere near Rochester definitely check out Tora Khan.
Rym: It's really fun and it's growing.
Rym: Uh, I don't want to commit to anything, but I would wager within four or five more years It's gonna be one of the not be like huge cons not a mega con like an Otakon But I think it'll be one of the bigger cons.
Scott: Maybe we'll see.
Rym: Yeah, I could see it even moving into Rochester and out of RIT.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Rym: Yep Now I guess we'll wrap up this episode With.
Rym: I didn't do a lot of interviews at the con for various reasons Mostly because I was busy doing other things and I wasn't too worried about Interviewing people since we recorded a whole hour of us doing a panel
Scott: and we didn't really have a lot of interesting things to ask People.
Rym: yeah, I mean when we go to Otakon, I'm gonna one we're gonna interview people about Otakon But two I'm gonna interview people about anime and have a whole separate set of interviews for like another show sometime.
Scott: Yeah, we actually you know cuz just going in with a little thing in a record II bit doesn't really work.
Scott: I think we had to take a cue from the anime world order guy who actually had a plan for what he was gonna ask People in his search for the truth.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, my plan for toricon was very specifically.
Rym: I just want to get a cross-section of what people at the con thought of the con.
Rym: Mm-hmm So I didn't really ask any particularly the hard-hitting questions.
Rym: Yeah, maybe none of that.
Rym: None of that.
Rym: Why are you dressed up as a blah-blah-blah?
Scott: Yeah, maybe an Otakon we should do like a search for the lies.
Scott: Oh speaking of anime world order I don't want to forget to say this for yet another week.
Scott: We did an episode a while ago about Lupin the third.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I forgot about that.
Rym: Yeah, we did this show on Lupin the third mostly because we were tired and it's easy to talk about Lupin because we love it And they sent us an email that was very informative and awesome.
Scott: Oh Yes, after we did our Lupin the third episode the anime world order people who knows so much more about anime than we do Sent us a little email with all the mistakes we made in that episode.
Scott: I'm not gonna read the whole thing because it's not worth my time or yours But let me just tell you the interesting tidbits of things we messed up about Lupin.
Rym: Yeah, at least we were dead on about Zenigata.
Scott: We were dead on about Zenigata.
Scott: So forget about him.
Scott: Apparently we said something like the first series of Lupin like that was all you you said.
Scott: yeah Because I did.
Scott: I watched like the first episode of the original Lupin series and it was really kind of 70s and corny and kitschy and all that sort of thing And the second series wasn't just kind of corny and silly.
Scott: it was silly in the Lupin that I know that's my Lupin.
Scott: Yeah, but The first series got canceled after 23 episodes.
Scott: And of course, actually I just downloaded all those 23 episodes today.
Scott: Some of those episodes are by Miyazaki Which is interesting.
Rym: Yeah, so Scott got booed.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm gonna have to go watch those and we'll we'll get back to you on that one.
Scott: Apparently jigen his name.
Scott: That's not his real name.
Scott: He's not actually a Japanese, dude.
Rym: Yeah, I remember hearing that he was like half Japanese or something.
Scott: No, he's like, uh, he's like a Chicago mafia dude who ran away Or something like that, they don't no one actually really knows.
Rym: yeah, I mean the Lupin movie the live-action.
Rym: one Supposes or puts forth a history, but I don't know if that movie is actually canon.
Scott: Mm-hmm Goa Mon was actually not in the manga for a long time.
Scott: Like he wasn't even in Lupin at all and He started out in the manga as an assassin that someone hired to kill Lupin and then he just kind of stuck around.
Rym: I'm very happy about that.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I know I was really curious as to why going on wanted to kill Lupin early on.
Scott: So there's more here, but it's not that important.
Rym: Yeah, we just wanted to throw that out mostly because really we're plugging.
Rym: We're not plugging them because they told us to but if you want to learn about anime anime world order is pretty cool.
Rym: Yep, they definitely catch us on all over because we're very fast and loose when it comes to.
Rym: I don't know everything Everything.
Scott: I mean if you can pick two words to describe us it would be loose fast and fast loose.
Rym: So anyway without further ado here is a collection of the short interviews.
Rym: I conducted at Tora con 2006 And there's nothing after that.
Rym: So I'm here outside of the Tora con cosplay with Nathan King and he has the most villainous voice I've ever heard in person.
Rym: Do you give us some sort of evil shout out?
Rym: Dare you How do you do that like?
Rym: does that hurt?
Rym: or what?
Rym: I used to watch a lot of anime?
Rym: yeah, that would do it.
Rym: So is this your first Tora con?
Scott: Yes, it is.
Rym: All right I do live in the area you ever been to RIT or the RIT anime club before.
Rym: Yeah, we visited a couple times.
Rym: We're part of the anime club over at rush MCC And that's this stormtrooper is the president.
Rym: So, okay.
Rym: We've got a stormtrooper here.
Rym: probably can't speak into the microphone But she's dancing in a very sexy provocative way.
Rym: I'll be in my bunk.
Rym: Thank you all.
Rym: So I'm here with the winners of Tora cons cosplay.
Rym: Well, at least three of the lovely ladies of the winners Um, what are your names?
Rym: My name is Brittany Cassie Christy, and you were dressed up as Princess Zelda man and Saria.
Rym: So have you been to Tora con before here?
Rym: Yeah, I was here last year.
Rym: No, first timer really.
Rym: so what do you think of it?
Rym: I mean you guys won the cosplay not the biggest cosplay, but it seems always to be a lot of fun.
Rym: I love it.
Rym: I have a lot of fun doing it.
Rym: I like getting attention.
Scott: So I Had a lot of fun.
Rym: here was definitely a lot more than I expected.
Rym: Alright great, and I just like to say your costumes are awesome.
Rym: I'm here with two anime fans outside of the pine am concert at Tora con 2006.
Rym: What are your names?
Rym: What did you think of the concert?
Rym: I'm Louie and that was awesome.
Rym: It was just crazy.
Rym: I'm Alex and I think the concert had a lot of energy.
Rym: It was amazing.
Rym: All right, great.
Rym: So you guys go to a lot of anime cons around?
Rym: Come see comes.
Scott: I've been to a couple mostly a con the big one in, Texas.
Rym: Yeah, I really like it.
Rym: cuz like.
Rym: a lot of people don't like that kind of music, but I Think it's just cool how they like mix in that synth stuff with the rock and I think it's just good Alright, so so the kind in general what you guys think about it?
Rym: I thought it was very good.
Scott: the the artist Sally was a lot busier than last year I think uh-huh.
Rym: They had the same vendors again awesome vendors, and I love the fact that they've added not only pine Am but there is a dance tonight.
Rym: All right, so I'm here with some fans who just got out of the pine am concert at Tora con 2006.
Rym: What's your name Dan?
Rym: So what do you think of high name?
Rym: They are they awesome?
Rym: Yeah, they're awesome Mr.. First or con.
Rym: Yep, would you come back?
Rym: Yeah, probably if you had one thing you'd like to say to our listeners out there about Tora con or pine am what would It be?
Rym: I love pine am All right, so I'm here.
Rym: outside of the pine am concert.
Rym: There's a big crowd.
Rym: everyone's really excited and worn out from the dancing there with Kate.
Rym: What do you have to say to pine am or about pine.
Rym: am I never heard them before?
Rym: But I'm totally gonna buy their album.
Rym: They're really fun in concert and that's great because if you sound good in concert you sound good on the album.
Rym: Have a good time at the dance itself.
Scott: I would dance all night if I could.
Rym: I believe I could see you in the front dancing your butt off, and it's a big, but - baby.
Rym: Thank you, Kate.
Rym: You're welcome.
Rym: I'm here with a parent outside of the dance at Tora con 2006, so what do you think of all this?
Scott: It's a lot of fun.
Scott: Everybody's really nice and very happy.
Rym: everybody's extremely happy which makes it really nice for us.
Rym: So simply a good thing for kids to get into.
Scott: it's definitely a good thing.
Scott: very positive.
Scott: the vibes are very positive very positive.
Scott: Energy.
Scott: right right Phil.
Scott: not not no crazies or weirdos or anything.
Rym: well crazies and weirdos, but they're different kind of crazy.
Rym: So do you actually watch the anime with her?
Rym: sometimes I've seen some things.
Rym: I usually fall asleep.
Rym: Well, do you have a show that's your favorite or show you really liked?
Rym: spirited away?
Rym: spirited away is beautiful like that.
Rym: So are you gonna go join the dance party in there?
Rym: No?
Rym: Did you catch the pine am concert?
Scott: we went and watched.
Scott: it was very cool.
Scott: What do you think of my name?
Rym: They were cute very cute.
Rym: I'm here at Tora con following around one of the staffers who looks very busy with two rolls of duct tape.
Rym: Conrad what are you doing?
Rym: I'm I'm just getting done taping up some windows for the rave.
Rym: so uh after taping up the windows I mean, that's a really big responsibility Up to the task.
Rym: I'm still wiping the sweat off my brow man.
Rym: I worked really hard to tape up those windows And I just don't want to say how proud am I I am of myself and how much I got to thank Pete and Jackie Here.
Rym: they made all this possible seriously.
Scott: without their without their diligent efforts I never would have got those windows taped all right.
Rym: keep up the good work, man.
Rym: Thank you, you too, man fight the good fight, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at Www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at two oh six three three three one five three seven GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.