Scott: It's Tuesday August 15th, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight We bring you our coverage of gaming at Otakon and the following week of awesome.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, we're back and yet again I do not have a pop filter since no one seems to sell the things I need to make them other than craft stores Which I hate But he hate craft stores.
Scott: craft stores are awesome.
Rym: craft stores sell mostly smelly things now or things that I have no interest in.
Scott: It really depends on the craft store.
Scott: I mean the.
Scott: Joanne mostly specializes in fabrics and all sorts of tailoring kind of stuff and Like Michaels sells all mostly arty stuff the kind of stuff that like art students need and AC Moore sells like crafty stuff.
Rym: Well, my beeps are that one.
Rym: every craft store just smells really really bad.
Scott: They know that's because they have the the fake flower shit and they have the.
Rym: yeah, you know what?
Rym: That's it.
Rym: that alone is enough for me to hate craft stores, I don't like things that smell bad.
Rym: Yeah, he's close.
Scott: I don't like that either.
Scott: But you know, they sell important things, but they also sell annoying thing.
Rym: Well for me, they only sell one thing in the world I need and that is embroidery loops.
Rym: I think I'm going to buy a thousand of them.
Scott: I don't think you need a thousand.
Rym: They're three cents each.
Rym: I can buy all of them.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't think you need a thousand.
Scott: I think ten would suffice.
Rym: I think I'll go for a hundred.
Scott: I think that's too many.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You know what I'll do.
Rym: I'll just buy all the embroidery loops.
Rym: They have.
Scott: that way I can always make pop filters But what are you gonna do with all the ones that you're not using?
Rym: I'll dump them in that box where I dump everything else I don't use.
Rym: it's full of cables from old computers a bunch of my old DS games.
Rym: I don't lie.
Scott: I think we're gonna have to make something out of like a hundred embroidery a hundred pop filters.
Scott: Yeah I don't think we need a hundred pop filters.
Rym: I could make a condom slingshot.
Scott: That would work.
Scott: I think we're gonna end up like having disposable pop filters.
Scott: like we use one we throw it out kind of like razor blade.
Rym: You know, it's kind of a good idea because many pop filters start to smell like.
Rym: you know those.
Rym: We talk about these often in person.
Rym: I don't think we've mentioned them on the show, but things called tonsilloliths.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Eventually, well very briefly if you've ever had a pickling picking sensation in the back of your throat and eventually you coughed up a tiny Little white nodule that smelled like the worst thing you've ever smelled in your life.
Scott: That's what that is.
Scott: It doesn't smell like the worst thing.
Scott: It's the second worst thing.
Scott: The worst thing would be like a rotting corpse or something like that.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: a rotting corpse might be somewhat pleasant compared to a tonsillolith.
Scott: Remember when the trash had that chicken in it.
Scott: that smells worse than a tonsillolith.
Rym: True true, you know Yeah, but tonsilloliths are real bad mainly because your body makes them.
Scott: Yep basically, what happens is shit gets in the back of your throat and your body the tonsils grab it and
Rym: Actually to be a little more specific there are like deep holes in your tonsils called I think they're called Crips at least that's what I've read them to be called
Scott: the Crip
Rym: the Crip keeper.
Rym: Yes and Infections and dead bacteria end up building up in there and then they're expelled in little white nodules.
Rym: The point is they smell bad and pop filters over time start to smell like that just because you're constantly talking into them Yep, and the fact that they're made out of things other than metal my microphone which is made of metal doesn't smell bad?
Rym: Nope, of course yours did that one time.
Rym: Yeah that one time.
Rym: Yep Anyway, we got a bit of news today.
Rym: I guess Scott can go first.
Rym: It is video game day.
Scott: Check out this crazy shit.
Scott: We're always complaining that You know, we want it.
Scott: if you want to make a PC game, you can make a PC game.
Scott: You can make a Mac game.
Scott: You can make a Linux game.
Scott: No one can stop you.
Scott: and if you want to make a game for an older console The only reason that no one can stop you is because those computers are.
Scott: those consoles are so old and their technology is so well-known That you can do it.
Scott: You know there we have perfect NES emulators.
Scott: So if you want to make an NES game, you're good to go.
Scott: If you want to make a TI calculator game, you're good to go.
Rym: In fact, a lot of people are making NES games and Atari games because it's fun to do.
Scott: Yep, someone recently released for sale a Sega Genesis game.
Scott: I think we talked about it.
Scott: Maybe I don't remember.
Scott: The point is is that you still can't make a GameCube game or a PlayStation 2 game.
Scott: I think you can make a PlayStation 2 game.
Scott: I'm not sure you can't make an Xbox game.
Rym: Really that he said you really can't make Nintendo games.
Scott: You really can't make GameCube games, you know.
Scott: and In the newest round of consoles, you know mean even people with dev kits can't make ps3 games.
Scott: No one can make a Wii game even though they said they're gonna make the dev kits for Wii and DS a lot cheaper.
Scott: They did but they still not giving them out to average people, you know I can't go and get one.
Rym: even if I could afford one we could get one of those bootleg ones But then we really couldn't ever release our game.
Scott: Yeah, but Microsoft has finally done something smart way to go.
Scott: They're having this XNA program.
Scott: The deal is just about anyone will be able to make games for the Xbox 360 and the PC for Little to no money.
Scott: I think you know.
Scott: I read in a couple places that it'd be free and I read in a couple other places to be like $100 a year, which is essentially Oh, whatever nothing.
Rym: And yeah, how much was it?
Rym: when we asked Nintendo if we could get a DS dev kit?
Rym: It was like 10 grand or something stupid.
Scott: $10,000 and $10,000.
Rym: that's my sign.
Scott: non-disclosure agreements.
Rym: I can buy a. pretty good you have to be a company.
Scott: the Microsoft is gonna be giving this thing out.
Scott: It's like college students.
Rym: I could live off a 10 grand for a year.
Scott: Yeah, you see and it's really cool because Because an Xbox is basically a computer with Windows and DirectX and a computer runs Windows and has DirectX.
Scott: So if you make a game for one, it doesn't take much to make a game for the other.
Scott: That's the exact same game.
Scott: So this XNA development kit that Microsoft is going to be just handing out to people like willy-nilly Will allow any doofus on the street who knows how to write code to make a game once and that game will run on the Xbox 360 and The PC and that's freaking awesome.
Rym: I gotta say As much as I generally dislike Microsoft as much as I really don't particularly like the original Xbox I'm getting more and more excited about the Xbox 360 as time goes on.
Rym: Microsoft really seems to have turned itself around at least gaming wise.
Scott: Yeah, I mean as far as games go on the 360.
Scott: I mean I was thinking about it for that Oblivion game which I don't know if I'm gonna like but it's so.
Scott: you know what?
Rym: I don't think you would like it at all because I remember that I was trying to get you way back to play all Those old quest for glory games and your primary I don't know.
Rym: I think this is more like a Baldur's Gate unless like your primary complaint was that you're thrown into a world and You can go anywhere and do anything and there's no like.
Rym: here's the thing to do next.
Scott: Yep, that games a lot like that I know But it's first person as opposed to the because the thing I disliked about Baldur's Gate the most was the controlling the combat.
Scott: We had like pause it and shit and it was the worst interface, but oblivion is first person.
Scott: So I'm thinking that might have a chance.
Rym: Have you ever played a first-person RPG before?
Rym: Did you ever play Ravenloft or Menzoberranzan?
Scott: No But I've played things like dungeon master.
Scott: the ones were like you you see like a dungeon in front of you and all you can Do is you know face nor you can change your facing north-south east.
Rym: wait dungeon master or dungeon hack Dungeon master dungeon hack was one of the first PC games.
Scott: I purchased legitimately Wow And you know.
Scott: you drag the items like into the arm slot and yeah, yeah Ravenloft was kind of like that.
Rym: Those are sometimes okay, I've never played a game like that.
Rym: that was even moderately.
Scott: Okay, I've played two that were okay.
Rym: I mean the best.
Scott: one of them was a share where I got back in the AOL days downloading off AOL And the other one was I forget But it's not the point.
Scott: The point is.
Scott: the point is is that they're very few Xbox 360 games I'm excited about and the prospect of the fact of People around the world making a shit ton of crazy games for it for very little cost that hopefully I'll be able to download for free and possibly make my own game is Worth the price of a ps3 and the fact that it the cost of entry is the price of an Xbox 360.
Scott: I say whoo
Rym: Plus just the fact that I think of all the crazy Awesome game ideas that the front row crew comes up with on a regular basis that we can't do solely because we don't have the And it's not worth it to make a game like that for nothing.
Scott: Like the thing is a lot of our crazy game ideas are for the DS or the Wii.
Scott: Yeah, so it's still gonna be hard but I Note that the Xbox 360 has the steering wheel and the headset of talking which could provide for many interesting games.
Rym: Someone should make some sort of tie fighter ish game.
Scott: I Predict someone is going to make some sort of beat mania or be money games involving various peripherals.
Rym: huh Yeah, it seems like every time so he does something stupid Microsoft counters by doing something smart.
Rym: Yep speaking of Sony Of all the people in the world who are pissed off at Sony which is rapidly growing to include every living human being EA now has a bone.
Scott: don't make good TVs kinda sort of.
Rym: maybe we only bought that TV because it was cheap.
Scott: I know there are people who make better TVs, but Sony TVs ain't bad.
Rym: Yeah, Sony DVD players.
Rym: However, whoa Now?
Rym: EA is slightly miffed with Sony right now because EA Wanted to invest a lot in the PSP and make a whole bunch of EA games for the PSP.
Rym: Now the PSP is failing and even EA admits this.
Rym: In fact EA's primary complaint with Sony is that they're letting the DS beat the PSP and that the PSP is fast becoming a non viable console.
Rym: And they're basically trying to force Sony to lower the price of the PSP lower the licensing costs and Aggressively promote the system before it dies completely.
Scott: You know what if they lower the price of the PSP enough, I'd buy one to do everything but play games.
Rym: You know what if I didn't own an iPod, I probably would have bought a PSP if it were cheaper.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I was thinking today.
Scott: Hey, you know if I had a PSP it has Wi-Fi So I could totally do stuff with it like control different things around the house and shit like that.
Scott: But it's too much money.
Rym: Yeah, plus I mean Oh, you can listen to mp3s on it.
Rym: Like I can in my iPod.
Rym: Oh, you can surf the web on it without a touchscreen.
Rym: Oh the DS has an opera cartridge.
Scott: Yeah, the opera on the DS though hasn't been getting the greatest reviews.
Scott: I don't think I'm really.
Rym: I've seen a lot of people give it really good reviews.
Scott: I don't think I'm gonna get it just because I don't have a use for that.
Rym: I mean I kind of do.
Rym: I don't have a laptop or anything and I don't plan to buy one anytime soon.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I guess if you have a smartphone then it's kind of silly to get it.
Scott: But if you don't have a smartphone or a laptop, so it might be good for you.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I am definitely cell phone wise I buy I get the freest cheapest most durable phone I can get and when it breaks I get the next cheapest most durable phone I can get.
Rym: Yep Mainly because I beat the hell out of my phones and I tend to leave them places.
Scott: Yeah, good job.
Rym: Yeah good job.
Scott: Oh PSP you know, I think what it is is that EA Doesn't really make hit DS games like the kind of games EA makes don't do well on the DS.
Scott: And I think that's why EA realized and they're pushing the Wii pretty hard is You know?
Scott: like that, you know, they think they can make games for that.
Scott: try something new.
Scott: But yeah, you look at the hit DS games.
Scott: There are no EA titles in there.
Scott: EA makes games that are for the PSP.
Rym: Well EA for the longest time mean their games are pretty formulaic.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, they've got a formula to make games that make money and the formula works really well.
Rym: The formula doesn't work on a system that has something special going for it.
Scott: Yeah, that's why I think what they did is they they do have a big DS push.
Scott: They're making all these DS games, you know, but where they they don't have.
Scott: I mean Wii games But they don't have good game.
Scott: EA has Wii games, but they don't have DS games.
Scott: So the PSP dies.
Scott: EA's portable gaming is pretty much down the shitter.
Rym: I also have the sneaking suspicion that EA has put a lot of money into training people to develop for the PSP and That money will go completely down the tubes if the PSP actually completely fails.
Rym: Oh, that's a good thinking Yeah, and it doesn't cost them anything to yell at Sony I mean what a press release that cost like five bucks.
Rym: Yeah, but enough about the PSP for now.
Rym: I have a couple of interviews.
Rym: We took at Otakon That I'll play at the end of the episode where for the first time in a long time We found people at an anime con who had PSPs.
Rym: Holy crap, and we talked pretty much.
Rym: I talked to almost every person who had a PSP that I saw at the con.
Rym: I didn't interview all of them, but I interviewed a few of them and The general consensus among the PSP kids was that either they should have gotten a DS or that the PSP is kind of meh
Scott: You know the only comment I really have on this is that I learned that a lot more people do have PSPs than you'd think and Many of them are not using them to play games, you know, they're using that.
Scott: I mean they do play games one or two games But they're mostly using them to listen to music or watch videos and stuff or emulate Nintendo games.
Scott: However, a lot of people the reason it doesn't look like there are so many PSPs at a convention is because a lot of people They keep them hidden.
Scott: They're not using them.
Scott: They don't have them out.
Rym: Well, they're not really a social system.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, there might be at a convention.
Scott: Let's say you go to a convention and half the people have DSs and half the people have PSPs.
Scott: the people have PSPs.
Scott: they have these things in their pockets or in their backpacks that were at their iPods.
Scott: I mean, you don't see a lot of iPods at a convention, but you know, there's a shit ton of them.
Scott: It's because it's not something that you'd walk around with at a convention.
Scott: Yeah PSP is gonna talk to people with headphones in your ear.
Scott: you don't do that.
Rym: a PSP is.
Rym: you sit there and you're bored in line with no one to talk to.
Rym: so you play your PSP for a while.
Rym: Yeah a DS you don't?
Rym: you don't see many people sitting alone playing a DS.
Scott: You'll walk through the can see them huddled in a circle.
Rym: or you see a guy with a DS and you whip yours out and you Say you want to play Bomberman and he says, oh, yeah Let's bomb it.
Rym: or you jump in a picture chat and there are 16 people drawing penises.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, you see the DS, you know, if you're sitting at a panel No one's gonna take their PSP at a panel because that's an intention stealing device It doesn't you know, it takes you away from the panel to play PSP.
Scott: DS is an enhancing device.
Scott: You can have your DS out at a panel and Picto chatting adds like a sub channel to the panel.
Scott: It doesn't distract you from it.
Scott: So Keep even though there might be a lot of PSPs out there It doesn't seem like it because people don't whip them out.
Scott: DS is are constantly whipped out constantly all the time.
Rym: Anyway at the end of this episode the bonus content for this week will be that you'll get a couple of those interviews.
Rym: We did the ones that were actually legible.
Rym: and well that legible but understandable things of the day Thingy.
Rym: How do you always say thingy after I say things of the day?
Scott: Wasn't there somebody Python thing where they were like thingy thingy.
Rym: There was a fish a fish a fishy.
Scott: No, I'm pretty sure there was some sort of thingy thingy thingy Tangs, I don't remember.
Scott: they said thingy at one point.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I've got the whole box set.
Rym: We have to watch it all.
Scott: maybe it was in one of those video games or something.
Rym: All right Anyway, I it might be there's a lot of good jokes in those video games.
Scott: I had one for Windows 3.1.
Rym: I had the a holy grail game and but the biggest thing I remember about it was that there was one game Where there's cows falling from the sky.
Rym: you have all these soldiers or Knights and when you click on them They go right and they turn right.
Rym: Yeah, and that was the whole game.
Rym: It was fantastic awesome.
Rym: Anyway, my thing of the day.
Rym: I Couldn't really find a good thing of the day other than that.
Rym: I have a slight correction from yesterday's thing of the day.
Rym: It was actually our good friend Kat who was the one who showed us dad's home.
Rym: Okay, I didn't remember and she reminded me So it was cat.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Anyway, I was looking for a thing of the day and I discovered something somewhat startling.
Rym: This is one of Scott's done this before.
Rym: it's an ad for an old video game or video game system.
Rym: This is from the 80s.
Rym: And it's a. it's an ad for the Atari 2600.
Scott: Oh God It's 70s commercial.
Rym: No, it's definitely from the 80s.
Rym: All right, in fact, there are comments Talking about how the people who said is from the 70s are dumb because defender came out in the 80s for the Atari.
Rym: Okay, among other things.
Rym: Mm-hmm All I have to say is I own in to Atari 2600 space and an
Scott: Atari 7800 and when I was
Rym: a small child It was my life's dream to own an Atari 5200 because for some reason I had it in my mind that that was the best gaming system ever.
Rym: Yeah Probably because I'd never seen one or played a game on it.
Rym: Yeah, that would probably be why it was like this rare magical thing.
Rym: No one had ever seen one, but I'd heard of them I'd seen ads about them, but I'd never actually seen touched or felt one.
Rym: So I wanted one and then I got a Nintendo and yeah.
Rym: Yeah, that was the end of that.
Scott: It was indeed the end of that.
Scott: All right, my thing today is something everyone's seen by now.
Scott: someone took Megaman X and Megaman X 2 and they turned them on at the same time and Using the magic technology of emulation.
Scott: What they did is they basically plug the same controller into both systems.
Scott: So they push a. You know both Megaman jump.
Scott: if they push B Both Megaman shoot in both games.
Scott: if they push left both Megaman go left, etc, etc.
Rym: Now how far does he get in these games?
Scott: Well, it's not actually a person playing because a person playing would die.
Scott: However, because it's not a person playing it's someone scripting all the input.
Scott: by magic emulation technology They actually beat both games Goddamn.
Scott: Yeah, so the exact same series of input into the controller can beat either Megaman X or Megaman X 2 both games which I have beaten on separate occasions.
Rym: Yeah, it does come down to the fact that Nintendo games are deterministic.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you input these buttons in this way as in, you know, hold down left for three seconds push a you know Then you'll beat the game.
Rym: So they just figured out one possible set of inputs that would beat both games Which is pretty cool Because currently the main thing is speed runs Figuring out the exact sequence of buttons to beat the game in the quickest amount of time.
Rym: I could see this becoming a thing where people try to find weird games that you can beat with the same input.
Scott: See though because it's Megaman X and Megaman X 2 which are similar games with similar inputs I want to see like Tetris and Mario 1.
Scott: Yeah, I want to see weird I want to see more than two games.
Scott: Also, I want to see like four or five games watch every Megaman game.
Scott: Oh No, no, but one thing they kind of do to cheat it's not really cheating is like They'll beat one level and you know in between levels there's parts of the game where no matter what button you push It doesn't do anything.
Scott: So during those times in the other game, they're going as fast as they can just straight ahead.
Scott: You know stuff like stuff like that, but it works out in the end.
Rym: But anyway for everyone who doesn't live under a rock we spent the last weekend prior at Otakon and then we spent the week right after that in the front row.
Scott: crews typical yearly retreat called the week of awesome week of Awesome and this year's week of awesome was awesome.
Rym: Yes So we've got two bits of gaming coverage.
Rym: first gaming at Otakon as a whole which we don't do a lot of mostly because Otakon We can get gaming at any time.
Scott: too much partying.
Scott: No time for gaming though.
Rym: We did play in the video game room.
Scott: Yeah, we spent more time in the video game room this Otakon than ever before.
Rym: true though I do most of my gaming at cons at well gaming cons and Katsucon I actually game a lot because they have the old-school arcade with the old-school arcade machine.
Scott: They had a few old-school arcade machine.
Rym: No, they had an old-school arcade at Katsucon.
Scott: Yeah, I know but at Otakon they did have like five or six machines.
Rym: They did and they had a DDR machine.
Rym: Yep, Dan.
Rym: They never did that before.
Scott: If they did we didn't notice.
Rym: well, they usually had like red octane pads and then big projectors.
Scott: I think they also had those.
Scott: I'm not sure but I think it was an extreme machine, wasn't it?
Rym: There's no way they would have gotten a supernova.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, we got supernova.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we did.
Rym: Anyway, so we'll start with Otakon now Otakon's gaming room.
Rym: If you've never been to Otakon and it's no idea than
Scott: most Conventions
Rym: like both in size and a number of people and possibly in scale of events
Scott: yeah, if you Compared to like remember went to gaming for hope that it was a LAN party and it was a bunch of video game tournaments.
Scott: It was basically a fundraiser for child's play at the local college.
Rym: Yeah I'm pretty sure we talked about it on the show.
Scott: way back We had this an episode about it and we took up the entire Gymnasium or one of the gymnasiums at the school.
Scott: I think it was an auxiliary gymnasium, but it could have been the main one.
Scott: I don't really know because I don't walk around the school.
Scott: The point is is that was pretty big.
Scott: the gaming room at Otakon was Six times the size of that.
Scott: maybe a little more maybe a little more say So and that was just the gaming room of Otakon.
Scott: It took the game rule of Otakon is smaller than the dealers room of Otakon.
Rym: when we saw a game across the room that we Thought the artist alley of Otakon is the same size as the video.
Rym: We would see a game that was free.
Rym: We would have to walk for at least a minute to get close enough to that game to find out if it was worth playing Or not or even what game it was and someone probably sat down in the game before you did.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Though what did we play?
Rym: We played.
Rym: we played this awesome Japanese wrestling game for five players.
Scott: It was a Japanese pro wrestling game.
Scott: You basically pick a generic looking pro wrestler and then you mash buttons until you win or lose Fight.
Rym: I lasted until the end and That's only because I figured something out right away that no one else did for a while.
Scott: Yeah I didn't.
Scott: it took me like a minute to figure it out.
Rym: your wrestler gets tired.
Rym: Yeah, you hold down a button when no one's around you you can And catch your breath.
Scott: Oh, see my guy was going.
Rym: That meant you were over exerting and you had to rest but he wasn't Regaining any resting because you have to hold down the rest button.
Scott: I didn't know.
Rym: Yeah That's why I'd last until the end when we all gave up.
Scott: I also if I would have known how to play a little earlier.
Scott: I wouldn't have gotten tired as quickly.
Rym: Yeah, well mainly how you played this game.
Rym: We don't know what it was called or what system moves for you walk over and you hit a bunch of buttons in this Random a fashion as you can and hope that you pin a guy.
Scott: pretty sure it was a PlayStation.
Scott: What PlayStation 2?
Scott: what kind of controllers were we used?
Rym: It was something weird.
Rym: was all I remember?
Scott: Wow I don't even remember what controller I was using.
Scott: crazy.
Scott: Yeah, really crazy.
Rym: I don't think it was a turbo graphics 16.
Scott: No, no, no, though.
Rym: That is a five player system.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It is it is.
Scott: Huh?
Rym: Yeah other than that I mean, there's the gaming room at.
Rym: Otakon is a con unto itself.
Rym: I know people who go to Otakon and spend their entire con there not many but they do exist and you know what?
Rym: It's a pretty damn good gaming con in and of itself.
Scott: Yeah, most people just go and they sign up for one of those tournaments there or a couple of them.
Rym: Yeah, they do a lot of tournaments and the thing is Otakon tournaments are incredibly professionally run at least from what I hear I've never actually entered one.
Scott: Yeah, so we take that with some salt grains, but you know, they don't run any interesting tournaments.
Rym: They oh, yeah They had Mario Kart double-dash Smash Brothers Melee four-player Soul Calibur 3 beat mania Street Fighter 3 Third strike pop and music Smash Brothers Melee one-on-one.
Rym: That would've been kind of neat to watch.
Rym: DDR extreme DDR fifth mix and guilty gear.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Oh and that Naruto game.
Scott: Oh great For I'm so at least it wasn't the standard, you know, Halo What are the other ones that everyone does?
Rym: Yeah, there was no Halo tournament.
Scott: Yep So that was.
Scott: that was cool that there was no Halo tournament.
Rym: Well, the thing is it wasn't a lot of like.
Rym: there weren't so many Xbox.
Rym: You know the modern cool games that all the punk hip kids are playing.
Rym: It was mostly older weird games that people really liked.
Rym: like.
Rym: there's a lot of Bomberman around Yeah, a lot of Soul Calibur - you know, they always have.
Scott: I think what's really popular to kind of the shmups You know, they get a lot of.
Rym: they had a whole Karuga there.
Rym: There was a section of the Karuga's with TVs tilted on their sides.
Scott: Yep, because that's the only way to play Ikaruga It was the side tilted TV and I saw people playing Ikaruga.
Rym: basically I saw a few people who really knew what they were doing and then I saw people who play shmups the way I play shmups Trying to play Ikaruga.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I have pride and I'm somewhere in between.
Rym: I'm humble enough to admit that I am bad at shmups.
Rym: I cannot play them.
Rym: The only one I've ever been even remotely passable at was area 88.
Scott: Yeah, you can't even play raptor.
Scott: call the shadows.
Rym: Raptor was actually really easy.
Rym: Yeah, I wouldn't really count that that was too easy or Galaga.
Rym: Oh, I suck at Galaga Galaxian?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I suck at all those games.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I just can't do it.
Rym: Hmm, in fact having me on your team and Ikaruga as a second player only fucks you.
Rym: Yes, it does All right, but yeah Yeah outside of the gaming room There was a lot of DS gaming going on too much in fact to the point that usually at cons We do a lot of DS gaming, but we really didn't have time.
Scott: But I can say that almost everywhere I went there was a group of people playing their DS's And whenever you turned your DS on there was a picto chat and whenever you went into a picto chat Someone was asking to play Mario Kart or Tetris or something.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Oh, this was definitely the biggest game.
Rym: I don't know a lot of people were trying to play Bomberman Yeah, but I still.
Scott: Tetris has definitely been the number one game of the week and Otakon and every.
Rym: yeah At least for us Tetris has been the big game.
Scott: Yeah I saw Tetris going on more than anything else even just at the con between other people because I think with the Tetris It's just so easy to do the pickup games.
Scott: It's like up Tetris up Tetris up Tetris, you know, the other games are a little bit more difficult sometimes, you know now There's really not much more we can honestly say about the Otakon gaming.
Rym: Well, there is.
Scott: there was a little gaming area for tabletop gaming.
Rym: Oh, yeah I didn't even go over there.
Scott: Basically all that happens over there is like one company promotes the Inuyasha card game And that's about it.
Rym: It was mostly people hanging out looking for a place to sit.
Scott: Yeah They put that in the corner of the artists alley and it's also an area where people eat food after buying it at the nearby Concession stand.
Scott: so, you know people aren't really into that so much.
Rym: at Otakon, which I guess is okay but I mean at other cons we go to I tend to play a lot of gaming so I can cover it and I You know, I watch the tournaments and I talk to the people running.
Rym: I'm gonna interview people.
Rym: but at Otakon again, it's just so big I didn't have time.
Rym: so Look tomorrow for our primary coverage of Otakon And we really don't have anything else to say about video gaming at Otakon because we did most of that in Wildwood and in Beacon, ah Wildwood, New Jersey where there was so much DDR.
Rym: Yeah so Wildwood you can tell that we were kind of we had to do the Otakon part forcibly so we could get to the Wildwood part a while back at the 4th of July.
Scott: how many DDR supernova machines do they have?
Rym: Oh god There's like 12 on the whole boardwalk.
Scott: There were three in that one arcade.
Rym: Yeah, the we played.
Rym: in fact I played more DDR in Three days in Wildwood that I have played in the last two years combined.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Scott: I also.
Scott: I regained my DDR skill, you know It's like, you know You play DDR and you build up to your maximum skill level and then you sort of have like this maintained level of skill Where no matter how long you go without playing you'll always be at least this good You know.
Scott: and you slowly decline down to that level and I had declined mostly to that level and You know, so but after playing, you know, I would play a game here and a game there and that wouldn't really get me You know improved at all, but at Wildwood I played enough that I was like, aha I'm back in this and I was like I was failing some six-footers and now it's like seven foot or whatever.
Rym: Yep, in fact by the end of the third day we pretty much maxed out our doubles skills again.
Rym: Yep Yep.
Scott: Yeah, I love them doubles.
Rym: Yep but I mean we got there and We talked about it before that there's all these DDR 9th mix machines and there's one arcade that has five DDR machines all in the same area.
Scott: Well, one of them is an in the groove - one of them is an eighth mix.
Rym: What does that make?
Rym: seventh me.
Scott: one of them is the seventh make.
Rym: the other three are supernovas.
Rym: Oh supernova Good God was.
Rym: there's so much gaming going on.
Rym: It was just insane.
Rym: Constant DDR playing so basically for three days in a row the entire front row crew except for one day.
Rym: What about half of the front row crew did?
Rym: it would go to this arcade and for like four or five hours?
Rym: Just constantly play DDR Like I'd play a set with say Jess and I'd finish and then I'd walk over and I see Scott about to start one.
Rym: So I jump on his pad.
Rym: we finish then Scott goes and plays with James and I play with Pete and then I go play With Yuko and Jess goes plays with Lisa and we just constantly played DDR.
Rym: I must have spent at least 60 or 70 bucks.
Rym: I didn't spend that much money Well on all of my gaming total, but I played a whole lot of DDR there because in his first on the gaming of DDR Was air hockey.
Scott: Oh air hockey.
Scott: which on the last night they freaking taped up the air hockey machines.
Scott: We couldn't play.
Scott: it was bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, you know what Rym was ahead by what three games?
Scott: Yeah, cuz I didn't get to play you on a day when I wasn't tired.
Scott: and yeah When you were tired they taped up the machines.
Rym: I am confident that I would have won.
Scott: no, I'm confident I would have won.
Scott: When I lost I was confident I would lose.
Rym: So yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The thing is I'm up over all too.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see It doesn't matter.
Rym: We're like Mugen and what's-his-name in samurai.
Rym: Champloo when it comes to DDR mean air hockey.
Scott: Yeah, when it comes to DDR, we're not that good.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: We were that good compared to the punk kids at the shore.
Scott: Yeah, there were a few punk kids who were actually good.
Scott: Well, the thing is most of them are like rail grabbing teen punks.
Rym: Yeah, there was only one other person at the shore.
Rym: I could see who could play DDR.
Rym: Well without holding on to that bar.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: There were those punk kids who gave us pogs because we were so awesome.
Scott: Well, those were crazy pog kids.
Scott: We'll talk about Thursday.
Rym: Yeah, I think we will because that's under the Boardwalk hacking episode.
Rym: Yeah, but when it comes to air hockey specifically I don't think anyone in the world except maybe like the master air hockey players We obviously don't run into in our travels could beat either of us.
Rym: The only people who can beat us are each other.
Scott: I think that that's a great exaggeration.
Rym: Well, the thing is I want someone to challenge us and beat us.
Scott: I think is that we're better than average people at air hockey But people who are actually good at air hockey would kick our ass.
Rym: But is anyone actually good?
Rym: all of the air hockey leagues I found are completely dead or just completely terrible.
Scott: I think that there are people who are actually good at air hockey like, you know Hit the puck over to them and then they hit it and it comes right at your goal every single time.
Rym: The thing is I remember specifically we were like we played against each other a bunch of times and pretty much played to his tail Mate, and then our friend Katsu was like, hey I'll play with you guys and he played against Scott and Scott just kind of beat him into the ground without even blinking
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and then I played against him and I beat him into the ground without even blinking.
Scott: Well, it's like this right if you go to a baseball game Is the star of the team and he's just amazing.
Scott: and there's the people who were like the bench warmers now The bench warmer in Major League Baseball.
Scott: while he may suck in terms of Major League Baseball He could beat the shit out of anyone in the stands in baseball at hands down with no without effort at all.
Scott: But you know, they're the real players out there.
Scott: The thing is we haven't encountered any real players because they're rare.
Rym: So here's here's what I'll do.
Rym: I got an idea.
Rym: We've tossed around the idea a lot of.
Rym: if someone is so deserving of awesome someone so incredible We would night them.
Rym: we would make them a GeekNights.
Rym: You know get geek naked kind of a play on words there.
Rym: so I will say now that if anyone out there can challenge either of us to air hockey and Beat us in a two out of three match.
Scott: Well, I don't think Beating us is just enough.
Scott: It's like you have to completely dominate us.
Scott: I mean if you're on our level, it's like okay, you're on our level.
Scott: You have to be above us.
Rym: Yeah, they could beat both of us.
Rym: You know two out of three match cuz.
Rym: then at that point they're at least better than yeah.
Scott: It's like if you're also a bench warmer in the major leagues like we are.
Scott: that's like, okay, you're cool But you're not.
Scott: you know more awesome than us.
Scott: You have to be like get to beat the shit out of us at air hockey like we can't beat you.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know how we'll pull this off because there aren't so many good regulation air hockey tables about.
Scott: no There aren't.
Scott: a lot of times you go to an arcade and they have that stupid table that goes.
Scott: It's not a real table.
Scott: the real tables are from dynamo.
Rym: Yeah, we want a photon table.
Scott: There's photon and they make a few other tables that are official real tables.
Scott: No other company makes real air hockey tables And the thing is the real tables are only like two or three thousand dollars.
Scott: The freight shipping is what kills you because those things are fucking heavy.
Rym: Yeah, though the thing is if we ever get a house with a basement, we're probably going to buy a regulation air hockey.
Scott: It's gonna take a lot of effort to stop me from buying a regular.
Rym: good God good God.
Rym: and you know what?
Rym: We'll play whatever style you play.
Rym: clap or no clap.
Scott: Yeah If you don't know clap is.
Scott: some people play air hockey where you can take the little The puck the the shuffler the thing.
Scott: you hit the paddle the paddle and you can slam it down on top of the puck to Stop it in its tracks.
Scott: and some people say no you can't do that.
Rym: It seemed at least where I grew up everyone played clap or they can just pick the thing up all the time.
Scott: Where I grew up no one ever did that.
Scott: It was like you can't do that.
Rym: and then yeah and some looking around online Seemed to determine that it really depends on where you grew up how you play.
Rym: Yeah, and all the league seemed to play no clap with a couple exceptions.
Rym: So what we can do?
Rym: both?
Rym: we both learn both ways.
Rym: I taught Scott the clap and he taught me the non clap.
Rym: Yep, and then I gave Scott the clap.
Rym: Yeah All Right, that was a super inside joke.
Rym: Yeah, we'll save that for an episode on RIT.
Scott: All right What are the gaming?
Scott: - oh well at the Shore house, we also played a bunch of GameCube games Yes, including that x-men gauntlet game.
Scott: Oh god.
Scott: All right Let's talk about the other games first cuz that one was so bad.
Rym: Did we play anything else?
Scott: I played a little bit of Rampart.
Rym: No, we didn't.
Rym: Oh, you didn't play but I know cuz you know what the one day in between the two days of DDR When I went to play DDR you guys all stayed in the house and played GameCube games.
Scott: I played rampart surround castle to stay alive.
Scott: Good job red commander, and I played a bit of sinister run coward and I played a bit of What do we play?
Scott: we played that Star Wars game?
Rym: Oh, yeah, you guys all played that.
Rym: I hate that game.
Scott: It wasn't so good.
Rym: I mean it seems really cool.
Scott: if it was the only space shooter in the world It would be great.
Scott: But the fact that TIE fighter exists means the game is crap.
Rym: I've ever came out over a decade ago.
Scott: I know that no one has made a better free space combat game.
Scott: That's well, that's why it said well descent is okay And free space is okay, but they're not as good though.
Rym: I mean, yeah No, I don't think so.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, all right, then maybe it's not TIE fighter and it's like a lion.
Rym: X-wing alliance, however is essentially the same game.
Scott: just that up I'm not saying you're saying like, you know, the x-wing alliance is like the best and everything else sucks.
Scott: I'm saying this descent this free space and there's the x-wing TIE fighter series and there aren't any others like wing commander.
Scott: Fuck that shit.
Scott: That's crap.
Rym: Well, when was the last time a free space game?
Rym: That was actually free space came out Descent three.
Rym: when did that come out?
Rym: Yeah Last millennia.
Rym: all I remember is that when I bought my sound card it came with descent 3 as a free gift.
Scott: Yep, I bought descent 3 in the box and it was around the time.
Scott: I got my new computer.
Scott: Well my Pentium 3 Which was 1999 or 2000 so free.
Scott: I remember there being free space 1 free space 2 which were sort of like Descent but out in outer space instead of in a planet.
Rym: Yeah Plus TIE fighter had that plot going for it.
Scott: Yeah Descent had a plot.
Rym: Yeah, x-wing alliance has a plot.
Scott: Free space had a plot.
Scott: if I remember I only played the demo.
Rym: Yeah The problem with x-wing alliance was I didn't care at all about the plot because it had nothing to do with the Star Wars universe.
Rym: It was mostly just OMG pirates.
Scott: I think the real reason those games died is because joysticks died, you know Yeah, I mean you can't buy a good joystick anymore.
Scott: It's really like it's weird because the first-person shooter is pretty much it destroyed those games and not anything else.
Rym: You know, I mean back in the day for 70 bucks I bought a flight stick Pro and it was this heavy Really really durable really well constructed hard joystick and it was awesome.
Rym: Now I go to any you know computer store.
Rym: There's not a single joystick that even comes close to the durability or the functionality of that thing.
Scott: Logitech's got a few and what's the other company?
Rym: but they still feel flimsy.
Scott: they do they all feel flimsy.
Rym: They just they don't resist me.
Rym: The force feedback is usually negligible or broken.
Scott: Yeah What was the?
Scott: let's see like sci-tech?
Scott: sci-tech makes the other ones the ones with all the million buttons.
Scott: Yeah, the buttons that break immediately Yes, I take used to make a really awesome ones But now they make these like things out of cheap plastic that just break all over the place.
Scott: And the other thing is, you know, the demand for joysticks is down.
Scott: So the demand for those games is down and vice versa, you know It's just like these two things dragging each other down.
Scott: one of them needs to be boosted to boost the other one.
Rym: Oh Well, yep.
Rym: I also played two quick two games worth of House of the Dead for Yeah, I played one game of it and I gotta say I found the game really really fun and really really easy.
Scott: Yeah, it's surprisingly you don't die so much.
Scott: I don't know if they had the machine set on easy because not a lot of people were playing it.
Rym: So maybe they set it on easy to get more quarters in Yep Or maybe it might just be that the game really really rewards you.
Rym: if you're a good shot and you know anything about zombies Pretty much headshots win the day all the time with few exceptions.
Rym: And what yep?
Rym: aim for the head and sweep or aim for the explosive thing that the zombie is carrying or aim for the explosive Thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much you know You.
Scott: a new kind of monster appears and you have to figure out where to shoot.
Rym: and if you keep you know Doing the smart thing you keep going and the boss fights are pretty much hit the target enough before it damages you.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Oh Well, it was fun.
Rym: Yeah, I played another round of time crisis for some
Scott: rounds of time crisis for
Rym: I think it's my favorite time Crisis, but I haven't played it enough to be sure
Scott: crisis 2 is still my favorite one But I
Rym: like the time
Scott: crisis 4 is just I think more of time crisis 3 with some extra good.
Rym: I just really like the fact that you use all the weapons a lot more.
Rym: You don't feel bad about wasting the ammo at all.
Scott: Yeah, I just still time crisis 2 though Just the setup of that game and the levels and the fact that it was the first one to have the two players and the Two screens.
Rym: Well, I was gonna beat time crisis 4 but then when I finally went over to display it One of the sides was broken and I didn't want to go to another arcades.
Rym: That was the end of that pipe dream.
Scott: Yeah, you can never play that game with a broken gun.
Scott: It's like forget it not even worth it.
Rym: At least they taped it off.
Rym: It was completely.
Rym: you couldn't use that side of the game.
Scott: Okay I guess it but it's no point in beating the game one player.
Scott: That's even stupider.
Rym: Yeah, just not fun.
Rym: You gotta yell at someone.
Scott: see what they really should have done.
Scott: is they should at?
Scott: they should make a time crisis.
Scott: where?
Scott: It's for.
Scott: it's a four seater and it's two on two.
Rym: That could be really interesting.
Rym: Oh, yeah That's what they got to do like those Japanese arcade machines where instead of standing side by side It's like it everyone faces each other in the games in the middle So you can't see the other person's screens or anything exactly.
Scott: my point.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: We just need Japanese arcades.
Rym: Exactly, that would make me the happiest man in the world.
Scott: All right, so let's talk about the x-men crap game.
Rym: All right, it's pretty much gauntlet.
Rym: only you are x-men.
Rym: Yeah, we play have a cool game.
Scott: We played was x-men legends 2 and it's gauntlet.
Scott: It's.
Scott: you walk around and all you do is hold down a button and all the bad guys die and numbers go up.
Scott: now the game has numbers go up you get more powers and all that means is you hold down the button and different shit happens.
Rym: the game has this Leveling aspect and you can do it manually where you pick all these powers and there's this really cool stuff That really doesn't matter at all and it would appeal to me a lot more if I were ten years younger.
Scott: Yeah It's like you can choose which mutant powers you level up over time and it's all complicated as a crazy system and you can min max it.
Scott: the thing is it doesn't matter which mutant power you pick because They all work equally well at killing bad guys.
Scott: So Except for things like, you know building bridges and flying over stuff Which you can do when you're level one if you choose the right mutant It really doesn't matter which mutant you pick or what powers you use.
Scott: so we just chose automatic everything and all the bad guys just got the shit kicked out of them and everything was easy.
Scott: and All we did was walk around holding a button down and bad guys died.
Rym: As far as I could tell.
Rym: the only joy the game offers that if you are nightcrawler You can grab someone and then BAMF off of a cliff with them.
Rym: Yep Or Scott Johnson can just walk off of a cliff and die.
Scott: I say the game is slightly better than World of Warcraft, but only slightly and that you're actually kind of I don't know Walking around pushing a button.
Rym: I'd say it's at least twice as good as gauntlet legends only in that there are more Buttons to push and more things to bump into.
Rym: yeah
Scott: And I'd say it's less than city of heroes because city of heroes is kind of like PvP online X-men legends -
Rym: yeah,
Scott: so yeah X-men legends - if you like looking at x-men Here's a game you should play If you like just holding a button down not thinking and and seeing the end of the game.
Scott: It's also a game you should play.
Rym: Now.
Rym: it might seem like we have cut short on the Otakon and Wildwood and week of awesome coverage thus far.
Rym: And I say to you now tomorrow is the day.
Rym: Tomorrow is our full coverage of Otakon.
Scott: Did we played a few more games didn't we?
Rym: Not really?
Rym: No We didn't lay any board games.
Scott: We played some Mario soccer, but we did a whole episode on that.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't play that much of it.
Scott: I'm better at Mario soccer now.
Scott: I can actually beat the game on the second difficulty level.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta start playing the one player.
Rym: Yep, the third difficulty level still gets me though But tomorrow we'll have the full coverage of Otakon with all the interviews and everything.
Rym: Thursday is going to be a big episode.
Rym: We'll have our full coverage of some things we did in Wildwood, New Jersey.
Rym: I don't want to be more specific than that because good God, this is hilarious and awesome.
Scott: Oh, I mean I see trouble This way.
Rym: Yeah, we caused some trouble.
Rym: We sure did and we have pictures of the trouble being caused.
Scott: Oh, do we?
Scott: we?
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's been trying to get out of me for the last two weeks.
Rym: I can't wait to tell all of our listeners what we did in great excruciating detail All righty.
Rym: So without further ado here are some interviews I did at Otakon with people I found who had PSPs and Stay tuned tomorrow for the Otakon coverage that I know many of you new listeners are really really waiting for.
Rym: All right, we're here in the pre-reg line for Otakon and for the first time in a long time We've seen a PSP at an anime convention.
Rym: So what do you think of the PSP?
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: It's not as good as the DS really but I mean it's got a lot of cool features.
Rym: It's a shame though because the US doesn't really see a lot of good games releases.
Rym: I mean a lot of it like.
Scott: I know PSP max portable for the it's Korean game.
Rym: It's supposed to be pretty cool.
Rym: I know loco roko is already out in Japan and China and everywhere else except for the US.
Rym: So I take it.
Rym: you got a DS and a PSP.
Rym: No, no, it's just what a lot of seen with the DS.
Rym: I mean Nintendo is great for the platforming.
Rym: I mean they put out a lot of great stuff and then they put out bad stuff.
Rym: But I mean, there's a lot of great stuff to esteem themselves very high.
Rym: Yeah, so when you come to cons with the PSP, do you bring it whenever you go to a convention?
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: I just brought it because I thought I was gonna listen to music and everything.
Rym: But I'm here with some friends.
Rym: So Not something.
Rym: I was about to leave at home.
Rym: friend took it All right, so I'm here with another person with a PSP.
Rym: This is a record for me seeing two at a con.
Rym: So yeah, I have a ds2 or just a PSP.
Scott: I just have a PSP.
Rym: I mean, it's a good system, but are there any good games for it now that you're playing?
Scott: I'm only play like only God because a lot of her friends at work at
Rym: it and we were playing like a lot of like
Scott: Liberty City stories the multiplayer because it was fun because you know the guys sitting right across from you can laugh at him After you
Rym: put him down, so do you come so often?
Rym: Do you bring the PSP with you?
Scott: Um, this is the only one and only conduct I actually go to and I this.
Scott: I brought this the first year I had it so I brought it with me just in case.
Rym: Aha, so if you ever seen a crowd of people at like a convention spontaneously playing PSP games Not really because it's like you're either walking to go to like a panel or you're doing something else.
Rym: Now how long you been standing in line here?
Rym: It's about you know, a million degrees out like what 20 minutes 30 minutes 45 minutes you think you're gonna make it.
Scott: I'm used to this heat all the time.
Scott: He's got a PSP, dude.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at Www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.