Rym: It's Tuesday July 18th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk about that old standby and German style gaming settlers of Catan.
Rym: Also geek back about arcade games and some talk of the new steam games coming out.
Scott: Let's do this Now.
Rym: I'm normally not one to complain about the heat.
Rym: I mean I like it when it's really really hot in the summer.
Rym: You know hot and humid and miserable for everyone else.
Scott: Well, I like it when the weather is you know not too hot not too cold just right.
Scott: but After having lived in Rochester for many many moons, and you you mean the ice planet fucking Hoth.
Scott: You mean Hoth - Hoth - and after living there for quite a while I do prefer you know more Sun.
Scott: I would rather die in a fire than die in an ice cave.
Rym: I just generally like it hot.
Rym: I mean the summers.
Scott: I grew up like it hot.
Rym: It's a great movie.
Rym: We're actually a lot hotter than the summers.
Rym: I experienced.
Rym: You know in Rochester and living down here, but Today it was a special brand of hot.
Rym: now I'm at work, and it's really really hot and the air conditioning is barely keeping up and You know I poke around in the weather to see if there's a thunderstorm or anything coming.
Rym: and I see that for beacon.
Rym: well first of all Driving into work there were big signs Everywhere warning people that there was an ozone alert and that you shouldn't go outside at all.
Rym: And they were like take public transportation don't walk outside.
Rym: It's dangerous Alright, whatever.
Rym: so I you know I look at the weather.
Rym: There is a air stagnation warning for beacon in addition to an ozone warning and a thunderstorm warning.
Scott: well air stagnation is important for Sailors and ozone is important for old people and thunderstorms.
Scott: That's not a warning.
Scott: That's like a hooray thunderstorm.
Rym: Now I never really lived in a place where ozone was an issue.
Rym: I mean in sterling heights, Michigan.
Rym: Everything's flat.
Rym: ozone doesn't accumulate anywhere.
Scott: I've never noticed an ozone issue before ever.
Scott: I mean if you wouldn't have told me I wouldn't have known well.
Rym: You didn't do anything Every day this week.
Rym: I've just been biking outside.
Rym: You know when I get home and doing stuff and today bikes broken There's this ozone warning.
Rym: so whatever I've heard about these things in New York City before and we live kind of downstate, so I figured alright Just one of those things.
Rym: It's probably nothing to care about.
Rym: I mean I've gone biking in hotter weather than this.
Rym: it was only like 94 or something when I went out and When there's a lot of ozone in the air you can't breathe so well which Really got to me.
Rym: I went out and started rollerblading And I got barely a mile away from the house And I stopped and my body was just trying to die and I couldn't make it and I had to hobble my way back home.
Scott: I would like to know how much of that was psychological like what if you didn't know there was no zone warning?
Scott: What if the same result happened?
Scott: you know what knows?
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: cuz I got kind of Sick, and I really had to get home and cool off and it I I biked in hotter weather And I've run in hotter weather, and I've never.
Rym: I've never had trouble breathing before.
Scott: yeah Anyway, I guess we'll never know unless maybe we tell you it's an ozone warning.
Rym: when it's not go ahead and do that.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I'll be able to tell because I'll be able to breathe or not breathe.
Scott: Yeah, anyway In addition to that.
Scott: I just want to let everyone know that if you have an ionizing air filter Throw it out because basically even though it does kind of filter the air sort of maybe It filters the air really well.
Scott: It fills your house with ozone.
Rym: Yeah, actually this is something I told Scott about back at RIT and now we crusade against it.
Rym: Yep, because ionizing air filters You know they use ions and electricity to pull particles out of the air as an air filter.
Rym: But you know that smell after a thunderstorm or that smell after you've had an old NES running for a couple hours.
Rym: That's ozone.
Rym: It is generated by electric electricity.
Rym: basically I'm not gonna go over all the details of it, but electrical devices and electrical discharges generate ozone.
Rym: Ozone is somewhat toxic and displaces oxygen in the air among other effects.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you think ozone and you say oh great the ozone layer blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: It doesn't float up there.
Rym: No stays down here and fucks you exactly.
Scott: It's not something you want to breathe It's an ozone just like o3.
Rym: yes It's o3 with uh I forget that I forget the names anymore because it's been Over it.
Scott: I used to know in 10th grade chemistry.
Scott: now.
Scott: I don't know anymore.
Rym: It's been over a decade since I took a chemistry class.
Scott: I took a chemistry class freshman year of r18.
Scott: You know what that that class should have been an a class Like.
Scott: I knew everything because I had just taken chemistry in 10th grade and reviewed all that stuff again.
Scott: Did you just not do the homework?
Scott: No one day.
Scott: where I happen to not go to class is the first incredibly easy test And he lets you drop one test.
Scott: So I ended up dropping this test that I probably would have gotten a hundred on which is basic.
Scott: What's it called stoichiometry?
Scott: Yep?
Scott: Yeah?
Scott: Which I would have gotten a hundred on.
Scott: so that kind of screwed it over.
Scott: And that guy actually was proud that he gave bad grades.
Rym: Yeah, well I can say back in high school.
Rym: There were a couple of classes where the average grade was about 35%.
Scott: yeah, this guy was like I give the lowest grades on average and all of our team.
Scott: Whoa ha ha.
Scott: and this is my first quarter ever at RIT.
Rym: Wow You know that's one of those situation.
Rym: cuz.
Rym: maybe it was cuz.
Rym: I had a hair trigger.
Rym: in basic chemistry I would drop a class at the drop of a hat.
Scott: a lot of people did drop But I mean RIT had.
Scott: I went through RIT with no Barely any.
Scott: I don't think I dropped or W to anything.
Rym: I dropped like 10 classes, and I double you'd at least four.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't use my W's.
Rym: yeah I didn't.
Rym: well actually I didn't double you so often just because Usually I could tell within a week if I liked a professor or not and if a professor even looked at me the wrong way I was like fuck it and I'd quit.
Scott: yeah the other thing is I Really didn't want a W because that would delay me getting the hell out of there.
Rym: Yeah, I was taking all superfluous classes.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: See
Rym: the trick is I always signed up for one more class than I needed in any given quarter
Scott: And then W'd one of them
Rym: or either W'd one of them Or I just drop one like I'd sign up for 16 or 20 credit hours when I only needed 12. that way if one Class sucked, or just the workload wasn't worth it.
Rym: I just drop it and not worry about it, and I still learn something.
Scott: hopefully Mm-hmm.
Scott: all right.
Scott: anyway, let's do the geek back, which you still don't have music for.
Rym: So we got this email from kid with these yes the title of which is quote.
Rym: I hope so.
Rym: the dead for is the shit.
Rym: exclamation point.
Scott: only one exclamation point.
Scott: Yes a query it is pleased Quite all right, let's.
Scott: I'm probably gonna read the complete first and last paragraphs, but the middle paragraphs are gonna get pair.
Rym: of course You're gonna read the complete last paragraph.
Scott: Anyway Hey Rym and Scott, I'm an avid listener of your podcast especially your anime and tech shows.
Scott: even though I'm a rabid Sony fanboy I tend to agree with most of the shit you give Sony especially about their goddamn Proprietary software and the potential failure the ps3 may be.
Rym: Where's the good news?
Rym: where's the good news?
Rym: just keep pounding in pounding in pounding you.
Scott: it's bad news.
Scott: Bad news after bad news.
Scott: all right I've got the Sony nwa 20 gigabyte mp3 player.
Scott: okay, I don't know.
Scott: I have to go look that up to see what it's like.
Scott: Which as a player is great, but the bundled mp3 transfer software?
Scott: I've blissfully forgotten.
Scott: the name is mind-boogling Lee crap.
Rym: yeah welcome to the club.
Scott: You wanted two G's and not two O's.
Rym: I sympathize with this kid.
Rym: Haha kid bully because my little recording bit we use for conventions is equally terrible that the recording bits great.
Rym: The software is godforsaken Unmitigated crap.
Scott: yeah luckily they re-released their sonic stage software Which does run surprisingly smoother, and I can just about live with Sony's ass.
Scott: poor attempts at making their own software.
Scott: Why God why?
Scott: Exclamation question exclamation question exclamation.
Rym: are you gonna do the AWO thing of read all of the no.
Scott: Is this a test of my faith by the way?
Scott: I love the show about the Mac you got to do your podcasting.
Scott: take that you condescending Mac users.
Rym: Actually the fun thing is the Mac has found a very useful home in our house considering that now we know about Mac's which we didn't so much before and It's actually a very good living room PC other than a few annoyances.
Rym: We're still working on.
Scott: yeah It can't do something.
Scott: well, we'll talk about that another show.
Scott: yeah, but yeah the Mac is not living room PC And overall it's better than our previous living room PC But it still has some minuses.
Scott: all right anyway.
Scott: see any of the people in the forum who made a thread about mp3 players.
Scott: Now you know about Sony players.
Rym: Yeah Probably don't buy one unless you're willing to put up with that crap.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: And my real question is I guess these Sony players don't work on Linux.
Scott: Maybe do they work on Mac?
Scott: That's a really good question.
Rym: I've run out of actually the recording bit I have does not work at all on the Mac.
Rym: Huh it is Windows only.
Rym: in fact It is Windows 2000 and XP only.
Scott: well and like what about people who?
Scott: I know a lot of people use their iPods and other mp3 players with their Xbox 360.
Scott: Can you use these Sony players with that?
Scott: probably not?
Rym: Anyway to continue the email because here's the part that's really relevant to tonight's episode mm-hmm.
Rym: anyways I wanted to write about my own first-hand experience with the new time crisis for and house of the dead for arcade games.
Rym: Both are crazy fun, but I think house of the dead 4 comes out on top as my main coin guzzler and eventually an unhealthy addiction.
Rym: I'm currently doing a summer job at Hong Kong.
Scott: It's a memory chip.
Rym: all right all right a Sumerian job.
Rym: Ooh, it's a Sumer Sumer All right, I thought I thought we weren't gonna make fun of that.
Scott: start control joke Murn Murn.
Rym: We are the Murn Murn and there are a buttload of arcade centers one of them being just down the road from my office.
Rym: As soon as I listen to your podcast on the new TC 4 and hot D 4 I had to go out and try Them for myself.
Rym: suffice to say I spent a ridiculous amount of money at the arcade that day.
Scott: yeah Personally while I like arcade games a lot other than competitive racing games and DDR a gun game I like gun games, but I tend to play them beat them, and then never put any money in them again.
Rym: See well it depends on the game.
Rym: I mean games like time crisis.
Rym: I'll play through once with someone like you and then I'm done with it, but a game like I don't know police 911 I'll just play it over and over and over and over and over and over.
Rym: I never get sick of it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like occasionally I'll play time crisis one or two while I'm standing around.
Scott: But you know if I'm not playing the games are.
Scott: those are games you play to beat because there's actually some kind of a plot.
Scott: They're kinda And you want to see it.
Scott: Yeah, yeah All right.
Rym: Well, then he goes on to review time crisis for and house of the dead for separately.
Rym: yes It's got you want to handle the time crisis for since time crisis is your game.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not gonna read the entire time crisis for a review, but he says he's a fan of time crisis.
Scott: He likes the pedal the separate screens and the players taking separate routes adds to the realism The he says the guns are too bulky, but he likes the kickback.
Scott: it's called You know force feedback.
Scott: well force feedback and recoil.
Rym: Yeah, well or kickback I guess a lot of people call it kickback.
Scott: Okay, anyway.
Rym: I don't know what your problem is against kickback.
Scott: Yeah, personally.
Scott: I think that I want that like a heavy heavy gun to play.
Scott: It's got a feel real freaking sturdy.
Scott: the sturdier the better.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is if it if it's as heavy as a real gun you'll get tired right.
Rym: quick playing a game like that.
Scott: Yeah, but if it's you know as light as say the games for area 51 back in the day It's like it's too light.
Scott: So it's really hard to aim because any small movement of your arms.
Scott: Just you know the gun moves a lot.
Scott: It's too easy to move the gun around anyway.
Scott: Uh His main gripe with the game is that it's a little too hard.
Scott: the switching view mode is overwhelming at times Especially when you're completely surrounded, and he forgets to switch views.
Scott: well I didn't have the problem of not knowing to switch views because it puts these giant left and right arrows on the screen.
Rym: Yeah, though you didn't get so far in the game yet I have a feeling it gets kind of nuts.
Scott: I do have a feeling it gets a bit nuts and also this they can.
Scott: you know you have to keep switching weapons because in certain Parts you need the right gun, but at the same time If the game is too hard that all depends on how the arcade operators set the difficulty if people don't realize this.
Scott: but pretty much every arcade game even things like pac-man and Galaga have Internal difficulty settings where if you open up the back panel you can set it to like easy normal hard stupid hard and Generally what they do is on our very very popular arcade games They set them to stupid hard so that that way people will play lose real quick, and then play again.
Rym: Yeah, like stupid hard sinistar exactly.
Scott: and when games get you know you know older and older and are played less Arcade people put them on easy like you'll know an easy Galaga machine Because you can just hold the button down and the ship keeps shooting, but on a hard Galaga machine It's it's the real Galaga.
Scott: He shoots one two one two you know.
Scott: so yeah anyway He keeps getting shot, maybe his reflexes are crap, and he hasn't perfected dodging bullets.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much.
Scott: time crisis is all about is when you see the thing you let go of the pedal.
Scott: however I have noticed that in time crisis You know one two three when you're about to be shot this like a red ring Appears around a bad guy whose bullet is going to hit you and when you see the red ring you pretty much have to let Go of your pedal immediately or else you're gonna get hit in time crisis.
Scott: for at least the ones that I played on the shore I had no chance personally.
Rym: yeah the
Scott: time that you have Reflex wise to escape getting shot is almost nil like you'd pretty much have to let go of the pedal Like a millisecond after the red ring appears And I don't know if that's because of the difficulty setting on the machine or if they just made time crisis for harder.
Scott: in general The great choice of weaponry is a superb addition that you will generally stick to the pistol.
Scott: The weaponry actually of you know the pistol the machine gun the shotgun and the grenade launcher.
Scott: those were added in time crisis 3 Not time crisis 4.
Scott: I don't know if there's any more weapons because they didn't get very far in the game.
Rym: I think maybe his point might be that the weapons seem like in time crisis 3.
Rym: I almost never changed weapons like I never even thought.
Scott: he says here You'll mostly stick to the pistol.
Scott: however in time crisis 4 They do give you a lot more ammo for all the guns.
Scott: like in time crisis 3 you start out Only with pistol ammo and time crisis 4 you have ammo for everything and you're actually Required to use the other weapons to get through certain parts of the game.
Scott: in 3 the weapons are just kind of there to use whenever you're having a hard time or you know just have fun with a machine Gun in time crisis.
Rym: for their actual gameplay elements I seem to get a lot of ammo for those things which was Surprising and I ended up using them a lot more than I would have expected.
Rym: cuz I'm a hoarder in games like that.
Scott: in any Game the shotgun especially.
Rym: that gives you choice of weapons, and they're all limited ammo like eternal darkness.
Rym: I would use that axe or the knife or whatever Non-ammo weapon I had on Every freaking enemy and then I get to the end of a stage and have a million bullets for whatever guns I had because I never used them.
Scott: That was always my problem and especially FPS is I would just save up every.
Scott: well except for doom and doom I just waste my rockets like really doom I would count like individual shotgun.
Scott: it's weird in doom the game where you need to save stuff the most.
Scott: I don't hoard at all.
Scott: I just spend it because I love shooting that plasma and everywhere, but in half-life 2 I'm just like saving every goddamn ammo and using the weakest weapon possible to kill the enemies nearby.
Scott: I'm like Ooh, let me move this way.
Scott: I can kill those guys with a barrel and you know the fire barrel and a pistol Instead or I'll throw a blade at them with a gravity gun instead of wasting a bullet.
Scott: All right, all right.
Rym: now then House of the Dead.
Scott: Oh he gave time crisis for eight out of ten.
Rym: true true Well, no he gave it star star star star star.
Rym: eight over ten.
Rym: star star star star star star star star star.
Scott: It's like eight forward slash ten.
Rym: nah Alright, I'm going to try to actually read the second paragraph here in the review section.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: House of the Dead 4.
Rym: I've never really liked playing the House of the Dead games, but this version is ridiculously addictive.
Rym: The new Uzi-style guns are fairly easy to handle, but unfortunately with the addition of the shake mechanism, they didn't include a kickback mechanism.
Rym: The new shake mechanism adds another fun interactive feature to the game, but the situations where you use it are easy to complete, like a zombie or a boss grabs you.
Rym: I believe they've also integrated the shake mechanism into reload, so you don't need to aim off-screen to reload, you just need to give the gun a shake to reload, which is very useful when dealing with a horde of zombies.
Rym: My friend and I attempted to complete the game, but we gave up when the final boss respawned after an extremely drawn-out final battle.
Rym: Yeah, Crystal Chronicles, ahem, ahem.
Scott: Every game made by Square ever, ahem.
Rym: No, I don't think we can ever express to anyone who hasn't played Crystal Chronicles how long the final boss fight is.
Scott: Well, when we were the minimum level necessary to do it, basically.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: If we had leveled up for like two more days, we would have been much shorter.
Rym: Hours!
Rym: Hours on one boss, and every time we killed it, a new boss came.
Rym: Anyway, anyway.
Rym: This game was crazy fun to play and extremely addictive.
Rym: You put a great emphasis on crazy fun.
Rym: There is a decent variety of zombies and monsters to annihilate, and although there are no weapon upgrades, you do have grenades, which can be useful in a sticky situation.
Rym: You gave the game 9 out of 10.
Scott: Yeah, personally, you know, I didn't really, I mean, House of the Dead was always cool.
Scott: It was the gun game to play when Time Crisis wasn't there, but I personally, the thing I don't like about House of the Dead in general is that you're shooting so much, 'cause you take, you can't just shoot the zombies dead, or shoot twice the zombies dead.
Scott: Like in Time Crisis, shoot a guy in the head, he falls over, unless he's wearing armor.
Scott: It was just, aim at a guy, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, aim at a guy, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot, so many times to get these zombies to fall down, and it was just kind of hurting your hand, and there was a lot more just pulling the trigger a whole lot, and a lot less aiming and doing cool things.
Scott: Yep, the ooziness really seems to mitigate that, 'cause now it's just, brr, brr, brr, Exactly, you just aim at the zombies, you hold it down, you sweep across the zombie heads.
Rym: And it just, it has the whole survival instinct of only shoot the zombies that are a threat, ignore the ones in the back.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Alright, and okay.
Scott: By the way, on a completely unrelated note, I'm starting my third year project sometime in the coming university semester.
Scott: He studies aerospace engineering at the University of Manchester.
Scott: Good game.
Scott: In the UK.
Scott: And his project title is "Bluetooth as a Communication Device for Wireless Sensors".
Scott: My knowledge of Bluetooth is pretty basic, so if you guys read my email on your Geek Bag segment, yep, here you go, then some info on the Bluetooth system would be much appreciated.
Rym: We got some people we could probably get on the show to do one hell of an episode about that sort of thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Hope you guys have a chance to check out these kickass games, we already did, and thank you to the great podcast.
Scott: Cheers.
Scott: Kid.
Scott: Um, yeah, Bluetooth, I actually had a job that I did, making, well not making the wireless sensors, but writing code for a wireless sensor concentrator device thingy.
Scott: And from what I know about Bluetooth, which isn't a whole lot, I've never actually used a Bluetooth device, but from what I understand, it's rather slow, and its range is fairly limited.
Scott: And for a wireless sensor, I'm not sure it would really be the best choice.
Rym: But it depends on the application.
Scott: It really does.
Scott: And also, you know, he's coming at it from the standpoint of aerospace engineering, whereas I'm computer science, so I really, it's a lot more difficult for me to talk from his angle.
Rym: Though, we could definitely do a Monday show sometime probably after Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, I think before we did that, we would need to get some Bluetooth devices and try to work with them.
Rym: Yeah, we could also get like, we could get James on the show.
Scott: Or Steve.
Scott: Steve Pomeroy.
Scott: Steve knows a lot about Bluetooth.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So we've got some guests we could do for that.
Scott: So that's the end of the Geekbag segment.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We'll probably cover these two games one final third time.
Scott: After we beat them.
Rym: Yeah, after we go to the shore and pump quarters in until all the zombies are dead.
Scott: God, it's gonna be like 30 bucks a game.
Rym: That's fine.
Scott: We could buy a DS game instead.
Rym: There's no new DS games I want.
Scott: There are gonna be real soon.
Rym: Yeah, quiet you.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: We've been talking about board games as our main bits on gaming day for a while now.
Scott: And so we're gonna do a news today.
Scott: that's about video games.
Rym: So see, today we covered arcade games, video games, and soon to do, board games.
Rym: All in one go.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: So if anyone hasn't been paying attention, there is a game called Team Fortress 2 that has been promised by Valve for many, many years.
Rym: God, I was in high school and I remember people telling me TF2 was coming out.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Like, up until a few years ago, you could go to Valve's website and the same message about Team Fortress 2 was still there.
Scott: Until, I think until Steam came out, the same message was there.
Rym: Yeah, because basically, real briefly, there was some of the original mods for Quake 1 back in the day.
Scott: There was one called Team Fortress.
Rym: They were all, they were very similar.
Rym: They were all Team Fortress or Team Fortress style where it's like capture the flag but with classes.
Scott: Mega Team Fortress.
Rym: Yeah, Weapons Factory.
Scott: Yeah, they were all Team Fortress-ish.
Scott: And when Half-Life came out, there was a mod called Team Fortress Classic.
Rym: That was very, very popular among people who played Half-Life.
Scott: It was like Team Fortress but slower but also more polished.
Rym: I didn't like it at all, personally.
Scott: I didn't like it, however, there was, most of it.
Scott: I didn't like, however, the Hunted game mode was good because that was essentially CS Assault before CS Assault existed.
Rym: See, I'll sound like an old man with my brittle old man hit, but honestly, of all the Team Fortress style capture the flag games, Weapons Factory and Mega TF just to me are hands down the best ever made.
Rym: And I'll try this Team Fortress 2 but it's been so long and that genre of gaming has really kind of died away.
Rym: I wonder how much of an impact it'll have.
Rym: Maybe it'll revive the genre.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm hoping, you know, especially with Valve's new engine, they could do some really interesting stuff because one of the big things about a Team Fortress games are all the different interesting classes and weapons.
Rym: Yep, and just the fact that games like this tend to really lend themselves to a pickup game.
Rym: I mean, Tribes 2, as great as it was, once a game, like if a game started, if you just joined a game, you couldn't really get into it, it was too late, you had to be there from the beginning and you could only get the full experience if you played with a bunch of people you know and a clan, but these Team Fortress style games really seemed to allow for the lone wolf and really allowed pickup games to work really well.
Scott: Yeah, even better than Counter-Strike.
Rym: Yeah, in a lot of ways.
Scott: Which is, yeah.
Scott: Anyway, the point is that Team Fortress 2, which has been promised for years and years is finally really promised.
Scott: They might beat Duke Nukem forever to the punch.
Scott: And what's gonna happen is when Half-Life 2 Episode 2 comes out, which is going to come out, I don't know, possibly next year, I'm not quite sure, Team Fortress 2 will also come out.
Scott: Supposedly.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: Yeah, Duke Nukem's gonna come out too.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see which one.
Scott: But anyway, yeah.
Scott: And also, supposedly, when Half-Life 2 Episode 2 comes out, another game from Valve is going to be released called Portal.
Rym: Now, we just watched, well I just watched, Scott had watched it before I think.
Scott: I didn't, I watched it for the first time just now.
Scott: Oh, great.
Rym: The video kind of demo of what this game is about, and I went from completely uninterested to quite interested in about 15 seconds.
Scott: If I could describe this, I mean, Half-Life 2 is a first-person shooter adventure.
Scott: You know, it has puzzles, but it also has shooting.
Scott: Portal is a first-person puzzler.
Rym: It's just an FPP.
Rym: There's no shooting, as far as we can tell.
Scott: I think there was a bit of shooting, but I don't think it was the shooting skill.
Scott: It was more like Chip's Challenge, avoid the laser.
Rym: I think there's less shooting in this game than there isn't.
Scott: I wonder if anyone listening knows what Chip's Challenge is.
Rym: Can I remember Chip's Challenge?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I wonder, no, it might be on that hard drive.
Scott: It might be.
Rym: That dead one.
Scott: I think I might be able to get a copy of it anyway.
Scott: The point is, is that Portal, you know in Half-Life 2 there's a gravity gun, which allows all sorts of new, interesting gameplay in a first-person shooter?
Rym: Well this game has the portal gun.
Scott: Yes, what it seems like is you shoot the portal gun, and whatever solid surface or wall that you hit, it makes a portal.
Scott: And you can shoot somewhere else to make the other end of the portal.
Scott: And then you walk through.
Rym: Now the engine handles this in an incredibly awesome, pretty way.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You just walk right through.
Rym: You can just see into the portal.
Rym: If you can set up situations where you can see yourself in the portal.
Scott: This guy was going through loops and stuff.
Scott: It's cool because for puzzles, there'll be a puzzle like, get this block into that hole.
Scott: So you'll have to make a portal, throw the block, the block goes through the portal, lands near you, then you, you know, crazy 3D interactive environment puzzles involving you creating portals, moving blocks, dodging things, jumping over things, going indoors.
Rym: It seems like a game like this could be really, really intellectually stimulating because it's, I mean, there's the old 2D puzzle games, you know, push the blocks around, avoid the doohickeys, you know, collect the jemmies and put them in the holes.
Scott: Lolo.
Rym: This is a three dimensional version of that that seems to be implemented in a way that no one has ever done before, i.e.
Rym: well.
Scott: I'm really thinking because, you know, we were talking- Notice how I used i.e.
Rym: correctly.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Pig fuckers.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, um, you know, early on in this podcast, in our early episodes, we talked a lot of how PC gaming was dying and it still is as far as I'm concerned, but it really seems like Steam, the one PC gaming platform that, you know, I still had hope for, is really starting to pick up, well, Steam.
Scott: You know, and I mean, the ship came out, which I'll talk about later because I bought that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And, uh- I mean, really- Half Life 2 Episode 1 was really good, if short.
Rym: The only thing that's lacking on Steam right now is a new multiplayer crazy hit game because nothing's really supplanted Counter-Strike, even to this day.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But, yeah.
Scott: Hopefully NS will, NS Source will come out.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Honestly, Natural Selection Source is one of the few reasons in the world that I want to build a fast enough PC to play Half Life 2.
Scott: Yeah, see, my- I'm really considering, uh, you know, possibly next year buying a computer that does one thing and one thing only.
Scott: Run Steam.
Scott: And if I was Valve, you know, Valve the company, 'cause- SteamOS?
Scott: Well, 'cause what they've done is they've basically supplanted, uh, the game store.
Scott: You don't need to go- you know, Game Stops and EB's have less and less space for PC games now.
Scott: And Steam is allowing games that would otherwise get nothing, games like The Ship and, uh, Darwinia and such, and they're giving them, you know, a huge store to be sold in at reasonable prices that can be downloaded and- I mean, there's now effectively no barrier to entry.
Rym: You can just write a pro- a game, or a mod, and you can sell it to Steam.
Scott: If it's good enough, Valve will sell it.
Rym: And if it's not good enough, the barrier to entry is your own stupidity.
Scott: Yeah, the barrier to entry is Valve approves of your game and thinks it's cool.
Scott: Yeah, so there's- no one has the excuse of- Or Vivendi or whoever the- you know, I don't know how- I don't know the actual how it works out.
Rym: No one now has the excuse of, "Oh, the industry is blocking me out and won't let me in and blah blah blah blah
Rym: blah.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, you know, Steam really, I think, is the hope for the future of PC gaming.
Rym: The great white hope.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And, uh, if there was some Steam OS, or perhaps even a device, like, "Here, buy this box.
Scott: This box does nothing other than run Steam flawlessly.
Scott: It's a thousand
Scott: dollars.".
Scott: You know, something like that, I would totally go for it.
Scott: Yeah, that- we probably- Or, you know, Steam for Linux, hello?
Rym: Hello?
Rym: I really don't know why they haven't.
Rym: I mean, it wouldn't take that many resources- Steam for Mac OS, hello?
Scott: What's up?
Rym: Actually, yeah, it's Intel Mac now.
Rym: It'd be even easier.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I don't know what the problem is.
Rym: In fact, because OS X is BSD-like, it'd be- if you ported it to either one, it'd be trivial to port it to both.
Scott: It's pretty much- they only need to do one port, 'cause they won't- just forget the PPC Mac.
Rym: You know what the problem is?
Rym: DirectX.
Scott: Yep, I mean, Half-Life 2, you know, they pretty much gave up on the OpenGL.
Scott: It's all the DirectX.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one thing that really bothers me, is that- I'm beginning to think that's why Half-Life 1 Steam and Wine runs well, because it's OpenGL, yet the Half-Life 2 Steam and Wine doesn't- it works.
Scott: It is working perfectly, except for the performance is less than a frame a second.
Rym: It just seems that Microsoft is leveraging DirectX with ATI in order to make it so that no platform can run games other than Windows, thus ensuring that gamers will all buy it.
Scott: Which is also DirectX, and Windows.
Rym: Yeah, well that's just a PC, running effectively Windows.
Scott: Sort of, but yeah, you get the idea.
Rym: It's running all the parts of Windows that matter.
Rym: For gaming.
Rym: When you think about it.
Rym: For everything we would use Windows for.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: If only- I think they are gonna release a lot of these games to the 360, but I really need the whole Steam experience of modding things and all that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And the keyboard and the mouse.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: And the monitor.
Rym: Because honestly, the golden age of PC gaming is long past us, and despite your opinions on whether or not gaming is actually dying or not, no one could argue with me successfully that PC gaming is anywhere near the heights it achieved in the mid to late 90s.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: I'd like those days to come back, and I hope they will, I'm just not terribly optimistic.
Rym: Though I think these two games and all of the assorted bits around them are the best hope we have right now.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Things of the Day!
Rym: Now I can't hold back on this one.
Rym: I was looking for a thing of the day, as we usually do before the show, we poke around, we show each other some things of the day, try to figure out, alright, does that pass muster?
Rym: Is it good enough to be a GeekNights thing of the day?
Rym: Is it topical?
Rym: You know, whatever.
Rym: Is it old news?
Rym: Maybe I'll call it retro and then it's not really old news.
Rym: That sort of stuff.
Rym: Now, I kind of randomly stumbled upon this, and I had no idea what it was other than that it had the words "skeleton" and "prank" in the title.
Scott: Ooh, those are good words.
Rym: So I started, and it's this Spanish dude, or Mexican dude, in a, he's wearing like a black cape and a black top hat, and he's got a microphone and a mustache, and he looks like a really, not evil, but evil in an awesome way dude.
Rym: And he's speaking very rapidly in Spanish.
Scott: I think it's Spanish.
Rym: He's explaining some sort of prank or something that is about to go down.
Rym: And I'm wondering, alright, what's going on?
Rym: Are they going to show me where the prank is?
Rym: Then he shows you this skeleton sitting on a motorbike.
Scott: Or a bicycle, we can't really tell.
Rym: Yeah, it looks like a motorbike, because it makes motorbike noises.
Scott: It does.
Scott: And the skeleton is rigged up, so when he talks into the microphone, the skeleton's mouth moves.
Rym: Alright, so.
Scott: And the sound comes out of the skeleton with a speaker.
Rym: So I'm wondering, what's this all about?
Rym: Then it immediately cuts to a dude walking down the street, and this skeleton on a motorbike rides by and yells something at the guy, and the guy just loses it.
Scott: You have to watch this, it is fan-fucking-tastic.
Rym: I mean, I've seen a lot of funny things of the day.
Rym: There's a monkey thing of the day we haven't used yet, that is just of the highest caliber.
Rym: But this is the first time- It is Tuesday.
Rym: This is the first time in a long time that I not only lolled, but I roffled.
Rym: I was laughing uncontrollably when that skeleton rode by the dude, and the dude just freaks out and runs away and trips over himself.
Scott: So the lesson for today is that skeletons, fake skeletons talking and scaring people while riding motorcycles equals a rofelcopter crashing into a loller coaster.
Rym: The best one is there's this homeless guy, like the last one they get, he's sleeping under a rag or a blanket or something, and the thing rides up, and the homeless guy, he drops his rag as he's running away, and you see him, he turns around to try to grab it, but then he sees a skeleton, and he's scared shitless, but then he really needs that thing, and he doesn't know what to do.
Scott: Okay, my thing of the day is from some guy on LiveJournal.
Scott: But don't let that get you down.
Scott: This guy was in Japan, and as you may or may not know, or you should know being a geek, Akihabara, or aka Electric Town, is the geek mecha of the entire universe.
Scott: And if you go there, there are many many stores which sell things like electronic doodads, retro video games, incredible amounts of video games, manga, toys, old, old, incredibly old school video games.
Scott: Anything awesome that a geek could want can be found in Akihabara.
Scott: However, little do many geeks know that the true mecha of video gaming shopping is not in Akihabara.
Scott: No it is not.
Scott: It is in three stops away, it is on the train, three stops away from me on the Togani line to Gumyo.
Scott: If you go there, and then you walk for 30 minutes in sweltering humidity, a skeleton will ride by and yell at you.
Scott: Exactly, you can tell that I'm paraphrasing this guy's blog.
Scott: You'll find this store that has more video games in one place than I've ever seen in my entire life.
Scott: You could take this store, fly it over to the U.S Do you remember the thing of the day of the guy who had an incredible video game collection in his basement?
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: One shelf of this store puts that guy's entire collection to shame.
Rym: They could lift this up, bring it over to the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: stick it in Manhattan and make it a museum.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I mean, not only do they have pretty much every Playstation game, every NES game, every SNES game, blah blah blah, etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: They've got every obscure thing you could possibly imagine.
Scott: Now of course the prices are high for things at this store.
Scott: If you want to buy a DS, I wouldn't recommend buying a DS there, or an Xbox there.
Rym: But if you need some sort of old NES game...
Scott: If you need an ultra rare Sega Saturn game, if you need a Neo Geo, if you need a Neo Geo PC LT, or...
Rym: If you need a Sega CD so you can play Sewer Sharks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you need games for, you know, hard... If you need a Sega Master System, they've got a mess of them.
Scott: This is the place to go.
Scott: And there's really not much more I can describe to you with words.
Scott: You just have to see the pictures.
Scott: You just have to see the pictures of this place.
Scott: They even have stacks and stacks and stacks of manga.
Scott: As well as on one wall, they have the Playstation 100, which are the 100 most popular used Playstation 1 games.
Scott: So yeah, this store is the amazing.
Scott: Now there's one more thing you have to know about this store.
Scott: Next door, there is a store that is "full of one coin figures, models, toys, and more Gundam goods than you could point a stick at.
Scott: This is for another
Scott: day.".
Scott: The guy didn't go to that store.
Rym: That says a lot.
Scott: So there is an amazing store that is basically the king of video games, as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: I've yet to see any other store beat this store as being the ultimate video game store.
Scott: And next to it is what is supposedly the ultimate toy store.
Scott: I mean, a little figurine store.
Scott: So there you have it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Akihabara is bait to lure the geeks away from the true mecha.
Rym: I really just have to go to Japan.
Scott: I think so too.
Rym: I could spend months there just seeing all of this.
Rym: Seeing like the... It's weird how much of the media and geekery I consume comes from Japan and Japan alone.
Scott: I really have to go there and then go to this store, buy stuff, ship it home on UPS, go to this store, buy stuff, ship it home, over and over again until I've gotten everything I needed.
Rym: I think I'd be content just looking at it.
Rym: I'd buy like one thing and keep it in my house as a relic.
Rym: Like when you go to a sacred shrine and you take the rock home.
Scott: See, here's the thing, is that I would be content just looking at it, but I also want to play a lot of it.
Scott: Now, if there was some way I could go to the store...  Emulation is your friend.
Scott: .
Scott: Some of these things can't be emulated, that's the point.
Scott: I don't want to play like SNES games, whatever.
Scott: I want to play like the ultra rare Sega Saturn games or, you know, these ultra rare Neo Geo games.
Scott: Things that no one else can play.
Scott: Things that aren't emulated.
Scott: Things where there are no emulators for them.
Scott: Those are the things I want to play.
Scott: real bad.
Rym: Yep, but anyway, we should probably move on to the main bit since we are trying to cut the show back down to a reasonable length.
Rym: And we've already gone on far longer than we expected.
Scott: Okay, so today we are talking about the classic board game that everyone in the whole world should play.
Rym: It's the marijuana of board games.
Rym: It is the gateway game.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I mean, pretty much anyone I know who's into German games who wasn't so cool to be into it before German games were cool, got into German games via playing Settlers of Catan.
Rym: In fact, I remember very specifically when I went to RWAG, which was the giant, giant gaming club at RIT, where, you know, I went there before.
Rym: I went to the anime club, even though the anime club was far more influential in my life.
Rym: But I went and I saw people playing this game called Settlers, and everyone was saying like, "Oh, Settlers is the best game.
Rym: Oh, you have to play
Rym: Settlers.".
Rym: Everyone talked about it.
Scott: I heard a lot of people talking about it, but I didn't play it until many, many moons later.
Rym: I played it quite a bit sooner than Scott, and you know what?
Rym: I got my ass handed to me.
Scott: There were guys there who were real good at it.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is, now we are both completely equal to them, and in fact everyone who is good at Settlers is all equal, but we'll get to that later.
Rym: Now the game, the reason we're going to talk about this is it's an old game, and we know that all of you German game fans know about this game, but a lot of people have been asking us or talking about how to get into gaming, how to get into German games, and this is really, other than possibly Carcassonne, one of the best games ever to start your German habit with.
Scott: Yes, the thing is, as we'll explain later, it is not a good game to continue your habit with.
Rym: Yep, now the game is very simple in how it's constructed.
Rym: You have a board, and the board consists of hexes, and every hex is a different type of resource.
Scott: Yeah, there's what, the grain?
Rym: Grain, wood, brick, stone, and sheep.
Scott: There is also one desert tile.
Rym: Which is nothing.
Scott: And is surrounded by water, and some of the water has ports on it.
Scott: Pretty much every other water has a port.
Rym: Now everyone goes around, and you start with two villages on the board, and a village will - Settlements.
Rym: Well yeah, but it doesn't matter.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: Little houses.
Rym: Little houses that you put at the intersection of three hexes.
Rym: Now every hex will also have a tile with a number on it, and the number corresponds to a possible roll on 2D6.
Rym: Two six-sided dice.
Scott: Which means two through twelve.
Rym: Now say you have a little house next to - One of the hexes touching your house is a forest.
Rym: It's a green tile, and there's a four on it.
Rym: And whoever rolls the dice rolls a four.
Scott: You get a tree card.
Rym: You get a green resource.
Rym: One wood into your hand.
Rym: And the whole game is you go around, and every turn, whoever's turn it is, rolls the dice.
Rym: Everyone collects their resources.
Rym: Then you're allowed to trade freely with whoever's turn it is.
Rym: So you can be like, "Anyone got any brick?
Rym: I got plenty of sheep, but I need a
Rym: brick.".
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Because what'll happen is, number one, the game is a fight to try to get more resources than everyone else.
Scott: Because you can always trade in four resources of any one kind for any other resource.
Scott: So if you can get enough of one thing, that's the same as having a whole bunch of different stuff.
Rym: Yeah, the game is basically you'll get these resources.
Rym: You want to trade them.
Rym: And the reason you're doing this is that you have a little card that shows you what all the things you can build cost in resources.
Scott: Yeah, so you can build roads, you can build settlements, you can build cities, which are upgraded settlements, and you can buy Stiffy cards.
Rym: Which are just like special hidden cards that have powers.
Scott: Most of them are soldiers, but the point of the game is that pretty much anything you buy will directly get you a point, or possibly slightly less than a point.
Scott: And if you can get ten points, you win, and everyone starts the game with two points already.
Rym: Yeah, and first one to ten wins.
Rym: It's a straight-up race.
Scott: Yeah, so the race is get the most resources, get the right kinds of resources, spend them to build things and expand your total settlement, and in the end, get to ten points before anyone else gets to ten points.
Rym: It's primarily a strategic game in that you pick, I mean, the way it works is actually, it's a cool mechanic, especially people who have never played German-style games before and never run into anything like this.
Rym: Whoever starts first puts a settlement down, and then you go around clockwise and everyone puts a settlement down on the board.
Rym: Then whoever placed last starts again going counterclockwise and puts their second settlement down.
Rym: So basically, whoever went first also goes last.
Scott: Yep, so it's a really fair way to place your settlements, because assuming that everyone puts their settlement in the best, their starting settlement, in the best possible position, the guy who goes first gets one settlement in the best position on the board and another settlement in the second best position on the board.
Scott: Now my favorite thing to do is, if the other players are inexperienced, I like to go fourth because they all put their things in stupid places, and then I take the two best places.
Scott: If everyone is really experienced, I like to go second or third.
Scott: It really doesn't matter either way.
Rym: Now the thing is, you're probably not going to have settlements on all the hexes that you need to generate all the resources to build different things, and furthermore, different types of things require different types of resources.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to build roads, you need bricks and woods.
Rym: And if you want to build cities and stiffy cards, you need a lot of rock and sheep.
Scott: Yeah, rock and grain also.
Rym: But you need sheep for everything.
Scott: Yeah, so some people start off the game getting lots of brick and wood, which is great because they can build lots of roads, which you need to connect your settlements, and maybe they'll get the odd sheep and grain to build some more settlements.
Scott: But they don't get any rock, which means they're going to have a hard time making stiffy cards, and they're going to have an even harder time building cities.
Rym: Now, you get a point for everything you've got on the board, well, every main thing.
Rym: A settlement is worth one point, and a city is worth two points.
Rym: And the other ways to get points are that there are two tiles, longest road and largest army.
Scott: Yes, whoever has the longest road in the game that is at least five roads long, I think, gets three points.
Scott: Two.
Scott: Two?
Rym: I think it's two.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: And whoever has the most soldiers, at least three soldiers, right?
Rym: Yes, at least three.
Scott: Gets two points, three points, whatever it is.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: And that's really the whole game.
Rym: The only other mechanic is that, as it goes around, you know, you're drawing resources.
Rym: Any time a seven is rolled, the robber comes out.
Rym: The robber!
Rym: Now, first off, anyone who has more than seven cards in their hand, more than seven resources, has to discard half of them rounding up.
Scott: Yep, now, obviously, if everyone is rolling 2d6 on their turn, seven is the most common result.
Scott: However, you know, seven compared to all the other results combined is not the most common.
Rym: Then you take the robber, because you rolled a seven, and you put it on a tile, and whatever tile he's on, even if that tile's number is rolled, nothing comes out.
Scott: So if I put it on the four that is next to Rym, you know, let's say Rym's settlement or city is next to a grain that has the number four on it.
Scott: I put the robber on top of that.
Scott: Now Rym rolls the number four, he doesn't get any grain where he normally would have gotten two grains.
Rym: Yeah, and then I punch Scott in the face.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's what the robber is all about.
Rym: Now the game is mostly just having the strategy of, I plan to start here and here, I want to build roads this way, I want to build settlements this way, this is how I'm going to get the victory points to win.
Rym: It's slightly tactical in, alright, that guy is going for the same place.
Rym: I'm going, I got to trade for the wood and bricks.
Rym: I need to build the road to block him off so I can build my thing.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: The only randomness in the game is the dice, which is actually kind of annoying, you know, because the dice can often decide the game, you know, just randomly, hey, they kept rolling four, I don't get anything on four, Rym gets three resources whenever a four is rolled.
Rym: I'd rather have three Reese's.
Scott: Yeah, but Rym is probably going to win if that keeps happening.
Scott: I mean, monkeys are, oh, okay.
Scott: Yeah, but, you know, assuming an even distribution of dice rolling, you know, a bell curve of dice rolling, you know, you can say at the beginning of the game, alright, well I'm going to spend my resources in this fashion, I'm going to build that, then that, then that, then that, then that, and that's the fastest way that I can get ten points based on this starting position and the resources that are available.
Rym: Now, all of that is very, very quick.
Rym: The only part of the game that takes a lot of time, and it's the most important part, it's also the most fun, especially for people who have never played a game like this before, is the trading.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Because you want to trade with other people, but you've got to be careful, because any time you trade, you're obviously helping the other person almost as much as you're helping yourself, unless they're an idiot and they're allowing you to get away with a steal.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: The problem in Settlers is that the highlight of the game is trading.
Scott: Anyone whose turn it is can freely trade resources with anyone else.
Scott: You can't trade, like, if it's Rym's turn, anyone can trade with him and he can trade with anyone.
Scott: But if it was my turn, then Rym couldn't trade with Joe, because it's my turn.
Rym: Even though a lot of people will ignore that rule.
Scott: Yeah, and they'll just wait until someone's turn and then make the trade.
Scott: But the point is, is that the trading is a lot of fun.
Scott: You have certain resources, you need other resources, someone else has them, and you trade them resources they need for resources you need.
Rym: And of course, you make a lot of jokes the other way, you know, "I got a lot of sheep, I need some
Rym: wood.".
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You know, "Uh, uh, you know, my sheep, they need grain to eat, cause they're full of
Scott: bricks.".
Rym: There's also implements like there are ports around the edges and they let you trade in resources.
Rym: Like a sheep port makes sheep more valuable for you.
Rym: We don't need to get into all that, because if you're gonna play the game, you'll read the rules.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The point of the trading, though, is this.
Scott: It's a lot of fun, and it's the highlight of the game.
Scott: It's what makes this game exciting for new players.
Scott: The problem with it is that there are really only three ways a trade can turn up.
Scott: Number one, you trade with someone and they rip you off.
Scott: It's a not fair trade in their advantage.
Scott: You basically just screwed yourself.
Scott: Number two, you rip someone off.
Scott: Well, good for you, now you're probably gonna win.
Scott: Number three, you didn't even trade with someone else.
Scott: Basically all that does is speed up the game, because it boosts both of you equally in front of the other players.
Rym: However, the reason you do that is if you're gonna trade, you try to trade equally, especially the players who are losing.
Rym: If someone's losing, you want to trade with them all the time, because you don't care if you help them out.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: You might even let them rip you off if you really need a resource.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Now, here's the thing, though.
Scott: Imagine a four-player game, right?
Scott: Let's say I make an even trade with Rym, then I make an even trade with Joe, and then I make an even trade with Jill.
Scott: Now, I've made each of them, it's an even trade, and it boosts both of us equally.
Scott: But I've been boosted three times, and each of them has been boosted once.
Scott: Do you see how that works?
Rym: There is also a big element of the Stiffy cards we mentioned.
Rym: They're like hidden cards that you buy, and most of them are soldiers, which allow you to move the robber around, and you can get Largest Army with them.
Rym: Some of them are also special cards, like build a bunch of roads, or Monopoly is the best.
Rym: Monopoly is, you name a resource, and everyone gives you all of that resource that they have in their hand.
Scott: So let's say you don't have a lot of rock, and everyone else has a lot of rock.
Scott: You say, "Monopoly rock," and everyone has to give you all their rocks.
Rym: Or one of the first devious strategies someone will come up with when they play this game.
Scott: It's the basic strategy that noobs only fall for once, and experienced people never fall for.
Rym: Say I've got a lot of grain, and I have a Monopoly, because keep in mind, these cards are secret.
Rym: Like, a lot of times, someone will have a Stiffy card, and it might be a victory point.
Rym: Some of the cards are just straight up one victory point.
Rym: Some of the cards, you know, they have the power, some of the soldiers.
Rym: And someone rolls a seven, and they're out to place the robber on your space.
Rym: You hold your Stiffy card up, you're not allowed to show it to them, but you can say, "This is a soldier, and I will fuck you if you put that thing on my
Rym: text.".
Rym: I suggest you put it on someone else's text.
Rym: Preferably Scott's.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: There's also the element of giving people resources to say, "Please don't rob me.
Scott: Take this
Scott: resource.".
Scott: But I've always had the policy of, "Don't give anyone
Scott: anything.".
Rym: Yeah, well that's all.
Rym: I mean, people who... Generally, people who are less experienced with German games, and less experienced with Settlers, enjoy the game a lot more.
Rym: Like, someone will roll a seven, and people are bribing them like, "I'll give you two rock if you dump this on
Rym: Luke.".
Scott: Yeah, see, that's a lot, a lot of fun.
Scott: when you're bribing people to not rob you, you're bribing people to rob someone else, you're trading resources with people.
Scott: There's a lot of stuff going on, and it's a lot of fun mechanics.
Rym: Yep, but before we go on with this, I just want to say, if you're new to German board gaming, or German-style gaming, or real board gaming in any way, I highly, highly, highly recommend Settlers of Catan.
Rym: Also, if you are into German gaming, but you've just never played Settlers, I highly, highly, highly recommend it.
Scott: You have to play it at least once or twice, until you figure it out.
Rym: But, now the disclaimer's gone, once you get into German gaming, and you've learned a lot about it, and you start learning game theory, maybe not the math behind it, or the theory behind it, but a practical application of it, meaning you can apply game theory in a is a 100% random game among experienced players.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, really, if everyone playing the game is very, very, you know, experienced at the game, they are all going to play perfectly.
Scott: There is going to be barely any trading.
Scott: No one will ever bribe anyone who has Robber.
Scott: They'll just say, "Rob me!
Scott: You'll get one resource if you rob me.
Scott: If we all bribe you, you're gonna get one resource from each of us.
Scott: Screw
Scott: that!"
Scott: You know?
Scott: And the game pretty much comes down to who went first, because everyone will put their settlements in the optimum position, so whoever just happened to be in the, you know, the way the board is laid out, and also the dice rolls.
Rym: Now this was evidenced most powerfully for me, because I hadn't played the game in a long time, and I went to a sanctioned Settlers of Catan tournament.
Scott: Whoa!
Rym: This was at UberCon two years ago, and they had the qualifiers, and everyone was talking about qualifying rounds.
Rym: I beat everyone into the ground, and I won, like, out of hand.
Rym: In one of the games, someone else almost beat me.
Rym: It was like ten, nine, and they would have won on their turn.
Rym: I just got a little lucky.
Rym: And then we finally, you know, that narrowed everyone out, you know, elimination.
Rym: Then we got to the semi-finals, where now it's all people who are good at the game.
Rym: It is all people who understand the game, are good at German gaming, have a very good grasp of how the game works.
Rym: At that point, the game was done.
Rym: It was completely random.
Rym: Because after that point, like, when I played with the qualifying, everyone was yelling and screaming and yelling and having fun and playing with each other.
Scott: There are a bunch of noobs that you can trade with, you know, if there's a bunch of noobs playing the game, you trade with all of them equally, and that way, you know, you get boosted times three and you win.
Rym: Or you pick one of them who you know is just really dumb, and you trade with him the whole game.
Scott: And you just keep ripping him off and siphoning his resources.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or you king make, where, say you have a situation where you can help yourself and help someone else.
Rym: Even if you'll help the other person more than you'll help yourself.
Rym: If you know the other person is not smart enough or not in a position to win, despite being helped like this, you help them as much as you can to elevate both of you so far ahead that no one else has a chance to play.
Rym: They can't win.
Rym: And now the game is only between you and this idiot.
Rym: It's kind of how a lot of Roman emperors got put into power.
Scott: So there's a game of, Settlers is mostly played with four people.
Scott: You can play with three.
Scott: It sucks.
Rym: Five and six is really fun.
Scott: There's an expansion pack that allows you to play with five and six players.
Scott: It's fun, but it ruins the game even more, I say.
Rym: Yeah, to a point.
Rym: I mean, in some ways, it makes the game a little more skill-based, but at the same time, it also makes the game a lot more random.
Rym: It's hard to explain unless you play it.
Scott: Yeah, we're talking about the basic four-player Settlers with no, there are a lot of expansions for Settlers, and a lot of alternates to Settlers, like Starfares, Seafarers, Cities and Knights, Settlers of Canaan instead of Catan, yeah.
Rym: But I mean, we got to the semi-finals, and everyone played perfectly optimally.
Rym: No one said a word.
Rym: I think there was one trade in the whole game, and literally, the victory points was like, everyone has two, then one guy has three, then everyone has three, then someone has four, then everyone has five.
Rym: And in the final round, I kid you not, it was the guy who won had ten, the rest of us all had nine, and all of us would have won on our turn.
Rym: Like, I'm not exaggerating at all, this is exactly how it ended.
Rym: We all looked at each other, and the one girl who was sitting to the right of me said, "Yeah, I don't know why they had a Settlers tournament.
Rym: This is kind of
Rym: silly.".
Rym: And that was the end of that.
Scott: Yep, it really, if people are skilled at Settlers, it comes down to randomness.
Scott: It really isn't a game of skill, it is the purpose of Settlers of Catan, it is probably the best game in the world for introducing people to German-style gameplay, and having a lot of fun trading things if you haven't figured out the game yet.
Rym: Alright, and on that note, I believe we are out of here, and actually on time and schedule for once.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: I don't know what I'll do.
Scott: Free up a lot of space on Libsyn.
Rym: Yeah, actually the Libsyn problem was resolved.
Rym: I gotta say, as a quite quick meta bit before I leave, that Libsyn, I mean we complained about them a lot early on.
Scott: We did, rightfully so I believe.
Rym: Yeah, definitely.
Rym: But they've been getting steadily and steadily better.
Rym: So I'm not gonna endorse Libsyn 100% yet, but they're doing adequately and it's worth the money.
Scott: Hooray.
Rym: That's what I'll say for now.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com.
Scott: And if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight, Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.