Rym: It's Monday January 30th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight.
Rym: We were going to talk about something else, but we end up just arguing with each other about Wikipedia for pretty much the entire episode.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So as you all know I was out of town for the weekend back at my old alma mater or RIT in New York And I was sitting at home.
Rym: Yeah, though magically I still did the episode fancy how that happened.
Scott: You know technology we have magical powers.
Rym: actually it's funny.
Rym: We've always tried to get ahead on GeekNights like we try to record like bits to have around for days when we're tired.
Scott: Or we record the bits and then we use them immediately.
Rym: There was a time when we were ahead.
Rym: we had three extra bits waiting around for whenever we had a day Or we didn't have enough stuff to talk about.
Rym: we used them all almost immediately, and we've never gotten ahead since then.
Scott: I don't think we're gonna get ahead ever.
Rym: But anyway I went to see the old RIT anime club and Despite the fact that I haven't been the president of that club for two years now The fact that I walked up on stage and everyone knew my name without me having to introduce myself made me feel very happy.
Rym: But more importantly and well, I'll talk about this in much more depth tomorrow.
Rym: But regarding the DS versus the PSP in terms of games I've got to say that the DS seems to be coming ahead as the clear winner In terms of games.
Scott: I mean the PSP is a great video player, and I guess podcast receiver But I mean this anime club.
Rym: there's you know 150 people give or take at the meeting and Many many many of them had their DS's with them.
Rym: as in I tried to join a Mario Kart game And it filled up to the point that three or four people were like hey who's in this game?
Rym: because I didn't make the cutoff and I was at the front of the room You know a big auditorium, and I just said to someone casually like all these kids with Mario Kart I'll school them and half the room yells what a bet.
Rym: and they all whip out their DS's like bring it Yeah, and they got schooled.
Rym: I imagine yeah, I quite thoroughly hosed them.
Scott: I just I don't think anyone just understands how to play that game.
Rym: I mean honestly I just today I tried to play online and of the four races I did three of them ended with everyone I was racing against disconnecting before the end And one of them the last guy didn't disconnect.
Rym: So I actually got to finish it and rack up some victories And I think the only reason he stayed was because I kind of held back and let him win a couple races.
Rym: So he would think he had a chance.
Rym: Wow people just don't drift.
Rym: They don't even read the instruction book.
Scott: How did they beat like the 50 100 and 150 CC and all that stuff if they don't know what the hell?
Scott: They're doing.
Rym: I don't think they did.
Scott: oh See if I was making the game I just wouldn't let you do online play until you or I would have come on.
Scott: It's like everyone else has learned all these lessons of making online playable games.
Scott: like you know even Warcraft would it be like Ranking the players and only people of certain rank.
Scott: you would match them up People playing against noobs.
Rym: no the reason there was a lot of reasons that can't work partly just because the games are real quick and There aren't that many people playing Mario Kart DS online at any given time.
Rym: There are plenty of people playing Mario Kart DS to match up into quick games because people want to play almost immediately.
Rym: They're not.
Rym: people don't want to sit around and wait a couple minutes While it finds good people for them to race.
Rym: They just want to race whoever's there.
Rym: So it's not going to do a lot of matching up skills.
Scott: They should let you do the manual matching up like every other freaking game.
Rym: Oh, this is a console thing.
Rym: I don't think any DS games are going to do it the way you seem to expect In the way.
Rym: every multiplayer game every multiplayer PC game where it's a completely different and Xbox Which is also a completely different type of game.
Scott: It's not different at all.
Rym: Yeah, there's active servers, but you join as opposed to just randomly hooking up with people out of the blue.
Scott: No There's no on the Xbox.
Scott: There are no servers.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't say Xbox.
Rym: Let's talk about just PC games.
Scott: I'm just saying and yet.
Scott: There's no reason.
Scott: there's no technological reason or Reason.
Rym: there's a lot of logistical reasons like what.
Rym: the main reason I think is that most people who seem to have the DS aren't very tech savvy and don't know or care about any of that Stuff.
Scott: they can see a list of games and join it.
Scott: I mean MSN zones and Yahoo games have lists of games and you join one.
Rym: You know we work for Mario Kart the way it's set up Mario Kart you race for racing is done.
Rym: It takes about five minutes.
Scott: if someone clicks create new race and then beat three people join it and then they click go And then it.
Scott: you know if you see one that you want to play and you click on it.
Rym: Nintendo wanted this to be so simple.
Rym: you don't even have to do anything you just yeah.
Scott: But there's a point.
Scott: you know making it simple is all good You know, but there's a point at which you make it so simple that it's not.
Rym: I have no problem with that.
Rym: The only problems I have with the game or that most of the people who play are just terrible.
Scott: yes And the way to solve that problem is to do exactly what I say.
Rym: no cuz I don't think that would help all right.
Scott: So what do you think would help mr.. Genius?
Rym: I don't care.
Rym: I just don't care.
Rym: Wait wait.
Scott: so you're like.
Scott: I have one like.
Scott: I don't think that your your suggestion is a solution I don't care.
Rym: There is no solution cuz I didn't say it as it's a problem.
Rym: It's just that's.
Rym: there's one.
Rym: the only thing that's bothered me about the game.
Scott: wait I thought you didn't care, but now you're saying it bothers you.
Rym: I Don't care as in it's not an issue.
Rym: I worry about.
Rym: it's just like oh this game is perfect except for this one thing but it's not anything that I care enough about to worry about.
Rym: and Mostly considering the fact that the game's out And it can't be changed unless they release a new game It doesn't matter at all.
Scott: no in the future the other games should do things properly and not be all.
Rym: yeah third parties Well, I don't think Nintendo games will.
Scott: Yeah well Then they're gonna have a problem.
Rym: because I've noticed the only people who really care about this seem to be the crazy fanboys in Like a few sections of the game facts forums and everyone else just seems kind of different.
Scott: They just play well because you know they play But they keep quitting and jumping out.
Rym: Discover that most of the people who quit do so actively because they they have this thing against people who snake or people who mini-turbo And if they see you do it they quit immediately because they.
Rym: that's what if?
Scott: anyway I see if Nintendo keeps doing this sort of automatic matching up You know thing with all their games, and they don't have you know proper matchups or something proper in your eyes anyway.
Scott: If they don't do that think about when like Smash Brothers Revolution is gonna come out.
Scott: people are gonna be dropping out all over the place.
Scott: You're never gonna be able to get a game on and people will say you know I really love playing Smash Brothers online But it really sucks because you can't really get a game going on because people just quit all over the place.
Scott: They need to learn the lessons that everyone else has already learned in the past Fundamentally different types of games, and it's not fundamentally different.
Rym: anyway I thought it's a game.
Scott: just play it online.
Rym: look at counter-strike counter-strike.
Rym: You have a server.
Rym: That's going constantly and people come and go.
Rym: Mario Kart.
Rym: you can't just have people come and go.
Rym: Everyone has to start at the same time and end at the same time.
Rym: yeah, so So you'd have to completely rework how it works.
Rym: you have to make it.
Scott: look at Yahoo games backgammon.
Scott: everyone joins at the same time and ends at the same time.
Scott: yeah Yeah, any yahoo game you know everyone.
Scott: some guy says new game people join it It fills up the guy who started it clicks start everyone plays and then when it's over.
Scott: It's over.
Rym: Yeah, there's more overhead for a real-time game like Mario Kart as opposed to backgammon.
Scott: There are real-time games on Yahoo games and msn zones and all those other stupid little online things that If you're gonna complain about it then do something.
Rym: complain to someone who cares.
Scott: I'm worried because I Think what's gonna happen is if Nintendo keeps the system this way the Nintendo online experience will continue to be Subpar and eventually people will be like oh who cares if it has Wi-Fi?
Scott: the Nintendo Wi-Fi sucks You can never get a game on and it's always a bunch of losers and quitters.
Rym: See I think part of the problem is just the types of people who are on the Wi-Fi are Generally poor as I've discovered.
Scott: yes, and there's no way to control that.
Scott: so you have to have.
Scott: you know You did some sort of system.
Scott: Well.
Rym: You know what my system is.
Rym: I play with people.
Rym: I know I am in counter-strike and natural selection.
Rym: I didn't just join random servers.
Rym: I found a few servers that always had good people, and I was always join them.
Scott: Yeah, I did that too, but the thing is so with this I just.
Rym: I only play with my friends.
Rym: like I am.
Rym: I am someone.
Rym: hey you want to play Mario Kart alright Get whoever I can get together, and we just play yeah, but eventually they gets pretty old and people aren't always available play.
Rym: I have enough people on my list now to where people are pretty much always available to play.
Scott: But they're not also choosing friends.
Scott: They're choosing other.
Rym: knowing as in I I am them and say hey Let's all play and then we all pick friends.
Rym: No one just picks friends and goes there.
Rym: aren't a people in your friends list.
Scott: for that to ever work You could have a crazy friends list.
Scott: well I hope there's a.
Rym: there's a very small limit to how many people can be in your friends list and then it starts knocking them Off.
Scott: it's pretty big though.
Scott: It's like 40 or something.
Rym: It's not that many people.
Rym: the odds of four of them being online at any given time are pretty slim.
Scott: It's like 40 years.
Scott: That's
Rym: not so many
Scott: It's plenty because what people do is they join me they go online and they whatever website that they're affiliated with they you know add Everyone on that site to their friends list and they all do it for each other and they lock them in and then they always Say all right everyone always pick friends whenever you play, and they always seem to get games together.
Rym: You haven't done it at all.
Rym: You just you're using anecdotal evidence there.
Rym: You don't know.
Rym: you don't know people are doing it.
Rym: Most of the people I see do it.
Rym: they Organize games in real time as an art.
Rym: Let's play now, or they schedule a game.
Rym: Let's play it this time.
Scott: Yeah, that's your people.
Scott: That's not the people.
Rym: I see yeah, you didn't play the game.
Rym: What do you know?
Scott: Yeah, there's a reason.
Scott: I don't play.
Scott: the game is Impossible to get a game online together.
Scott: that doesn't suck.
Rym: Oh you won't play against us when we're over either.
Rym: I think it's because you're not so good anymore because I'm disillusioned with it.
Scott: It's not so great.
Rym: Yeah, I think Where you were saying it's the greatest Mario Kart ever.
Scott: cuz it was.
Rym: and the game.
Rym: The game is the same game that you said was awesome.
Scott: nothing changed because I hadn't played the whole game.
Scott: It's like a magic.
Rym: I mean you hadn't played the whole game.
Scott: I hadn't played the whole game at that.
Scott: I just got it.
Rym: What hadn't you played?
Scott: Most of the game, what do you mean, so you met.
Rym: you found a track that you didn't like?
Rym: No, there was.
Rym: you discovered a character that ruins the game.
Scott: barely played it online at that point and The I at that point it didn't even work online.
Scott: at first the online was completely broken Right and - I don't even beat the game, so I didn't know what was like.
Scott: a man doesn't do anything.
Scott: Yeah, it does you figure out what it's like on the the faster modes and such?
Rym: Okay And it was a fully play.
Scott: the entire game There's a lot of you know is like no one can watch the first five minutes of a movie And it's the greatest thing in the road.
Rym: Playing playing even one of the 50cc isn't much different from playing the hardest hundred and fifty CC.
Scott: My impression of the game changes.
Scott: I played more and more of it.
Rym: I think your impression of the game changed as you got worse and worse at it compared to everyone else.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Scott: uh-huh I think that You know just cuz I don't want to play a game because I don't like it and you really want to play against me And I don't want to see you come up with some thing you know to try to be like.
Scott: If you're not playing with me that must mean you suck.
Rym: Well, I mean I noticed that you've wanted to play with me all the time when the game first came out until I beat you And then you never.
Rym: you haven't played me since that one time.
Scott: I pick your ass Nothing to do with it.
Rym: I just seems quite a coincidence.
Rym: You know you're kicking my ass you're beating me, and then one day I kick your ass into the ground, and then you never play again.
Scott: Because maybe that just happened to be the time and I have other stuff to do.
Rym: All right you had other things to do.
Rym: it just happened to coincide.
Scott: What am?
Scott: I had free time to play this movie game.
Rym: plenty of free time?
Scott: No?
Scott: I don't.
Scott: what do I have free time?
Rym: He sat around for hours today?
Rym: Just watching last exile and dickin her.
Scott: I was watching last exile.
Scott: Yeah, whatever, and then I was eating dinner, and then I was doing groceries, and I was doing laundry pizzas.
Scott: Yeah, now.
Scott: I'm making a podcast All right, and then I gotta go mess with my video card, and then I had to go to bed.
Rym: Oh, I guess that's at least somewhat topical because well, it's not video game day It is sci-tech day, and I guess there's technology involved in the DS.
Rym: Yeah Though the only other thing I did in Rochester is I caught an Amex game hockey for those of you who don't know Mm-hmm, and that's one like.
Rym: I've seen a bunch of different types of hockey different leagues whatever But I'd never seen that level of hockey.
Scott: Yeah, you had.
Scott: we went to it in Bridgeport, Connecticut.
Scott: Did we win?
Scott: we went to see the Hartford Wolfpack play the?
Scott: Bridgeport Sound Tigers.
Scott: Yeah, well we did.
Scott: you were there.
Rym: Yeah And the Amherst won, but I got to say that hot level of hockey is really not so great.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: they were pretty terrible like I've seen the high school and college teams that just had better puck control.
Scott: Well the Amherst were the.
Scott: I think they won last year didn't they?
Rym: yeah, and you know what they're doing pretty poorly And they were on a losing streak.
Rym: And then they beat this team by as far as I can tell sheer lock and just by out shooting him.
Scott: Maybe they lost with the good players last year because they won so that all their players went to the NHL or something who knows?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It was still fun though the coolest thing was there.
Rym: We had an exchange student with us and He'd never seen hockey before never seen hockey.
Scott: where's he from?
Scott: oh god.
Rym: I don't remember South America.
Scott: I think they don't have hockey.
Rym: most people don't have hockey.
Rym: hockey is not popular in most of the world.
Rym: in fact the majority Of the world is and they don't even know what exists.
Rym: They don't even know what exists in most of the world.
Scott: I mean I did searches for hockey in strange places, and I found like weird scary hockey leagues in like Japan.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but as far as the world's concerned most people just don't care at all about hockey.
Scott: Well those people don't care about most sports.
Rym: Hockey is very much a northern American Canadian Russian and northern Europe.
Scott: There's a Harris poll the other day, and it was like how many people you know care about sports, and it was like 20% 80% of people just don't care about any sports at all just that.
Rym: But he'd never seen hockey before.
Rym: so we were describing it to him because he really liked soccer.
Rym: He's good at soccer.
Rym: It's almost saying that it's a lot like soccer and that it's low scoring and goaltending means a lot and breakaways blah blah blah Mm-hmm, and then we described yeah, but there's like and he's.
Rym: he heard that it's violent But he'd heard a little bit like he'd heard of hockey, and he knew it was violent.
Rym: So we explained yeah It's real violent.
Rym: in fact if two guys get into a fight on the ice the refs aren't allowed to break it up until someone Wins mm-hmm and sure enough not five minutes into the second period Two guys throw down their gloves and duke it out all right.
Rym: It was fantastic.
Scott: That's what's all about.
Scott: you go to the shittiest talking game in the world the worst teams ever and a fight will break out.
Scott: It'll be worth the price.
Rym: It was a fun game, and I won the lottery at it of all things.
Rym: Oh really yeah lottery for what New York State Lottery was there or something?
Rym: and this there You know the t-shirt girls that come out of sporting events, and they throw t-shirts if you mean Stephanie.
Rym: yeah Well I caught a t-shirt, and I was very happy with it, and I opened it.
Rym: It's just a math tax shirt uh-huh.
Scott: Well you can proudly wear that at your next Bingo night or whatever.
Rym: yeah, yeah, hi Rola Big winner no whammy no whammy no whammy stop.
Scott: Well, and let's see what did I do this weekend?
Scott: I sat around.
Rym: didn't you buy a car?
Scott: Yeah, I bought a car.
Scott: I went to those board game guys played some nice new board games.
Scott: You know met some people.
Scott: they were cool.
Scott: The board games are fun.
Rym: If I talk about them tomorrow and gaming day.
Rym: yeah, cuz we already talked today about the DS.
Rym: I don't need to repeat that.
Scott: no You know pretty usual sitting around looking around great walking around looking around That sort of thing yeah, I had to defrag the hard drive in this computer windows box.
Rym: Yeah, this laptop here the work one see I'm not used to the idea of defragging anymore.
Rym: neither.
Scott: It was like don't use windows like oh, yeah, so apparently unless you have 15% of your hard drive for you Can't really defrag properly.
Rym: Oh, yeah system administration That's like the number one thing.
Rym: if you want to defrag a server's hard drive That's because a lot of servers just having to be windows for various reasons You usually just copy all the data to another drive and then back.
Rym: That's the by far the best way to defragment a hard drive in Windows.
Scott: Yeah, so I Can't get enough data deleted off of this to defrag it properly.
Rym: well Then buy an external drive copy everything to it and copy it back.
Rym: It's not my.
Scott: this is a works computer.
Rym: I'm not doing shit and tell them to do that.
Scott: I'm gonna tell that I'm probably just gonna get a new hard drive for it and take the one out of here and put a new one in Whatever whatever because it's really too small.
Scott: It's only 40 gigs.
Rym: That's plenty.
Rym: you shouldn't need to have much on that laptop.
Scott: No It's full of shit from the guy who had it before me.
Rym: delete all that I can't.
Rym: why not?
Scott: because it's like Licensed software and company crap and it sucks.
Scott: it sucks having a computer That's not yours and having to use just booted Ubuntu live CD every time you want to use it.
Scott: I can't cuz actually stuff on it.
Scott: I have to use Wine.
Rym: man.
Scott: no like blackberry shit.
Rym: Get all that to work in one.
Scott: not really.
Rym: yeah, you ever tried.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Rym: I could look I'm kind of a wine expert.
Scott: Yeah for real.
Rym: It's pretty much my job at IBM lately.
Scott: sucks to be you.
Rym: But anyway to actually move into our real news We got one bit since we figured we'd talk long after the long weekend.
Rym: But Wikipedia has had some trouble like in the past.
Rym: You know there's people who vandalize Wikipedia.
Rym: They'll go into a post about I don't know Strawberries and just add like aliens to it or just they'll replace an entire article with the word fuck.
Rym: You know just people vandalizing for no good reason.
Rym: Lately the people who have been vandalized in Wikipedia have been wait for it.
Rym: Members of the Congress of the United States of America?
Scott: well not personally, but their staff.
Rym: yeah They're staffers sometimes on their orders sometimes on their own.
Rym: It's it really is a tricky situation here.
Scott: But basically Wikipedia has articles on just about everything and absolutely everything even scary things you didn't know about.
Rym: Yep, and as you all know I often write for Wikipedia though I do so anonymously.
Rym: usually I find pseudoscience, and I flag it as such as Vitriloquy as I possibly can.
Scott: that's not a word.
Rym: Vitrilo is a word.
Scott: add suffixes to words you don't say Vitriloquy you say with much vitriol.
Rym: Yeah, you know what it has the same meaning and you know what I meant.
Rym: And I feel that making a word like that by adding suffixes and or prefixes is perfectly grammatically legitimate.
Scott: Well, then you can't yell at me when I do it anymore.
Rym: I don't yell at you when you do that.
Rym: Yeah, I yell at you, and you freaking make up words or use adverbs and adjectives incorrectly.
Scott: you just made up a word.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: There's a difference in making up a word and they can have a word and making up a word You just make up.
Rym: I mean adding a suffix to a word is not in the same class as stringing eight letters together.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: It's making up a word.
Scott: It's not a word.
Scott: you made it up.
Rym: you realize a large portion of the words in English language Would wouldn't really be in the dictionary.
Rym: They're just a root word plus a prefix or suffix.
Rym: Yeah, or they're just completely made up.
Rym: No a lot of words in English that we use today were made up.
Rym: Shakespeare made up a whole bunch of words.
Scott: Oh Shakespeare was allowed to make a whole bunch of words.
Scott: Why cuz he was Shakespeare?
Scott: Yeah, you're not.
Rym: We'll see about that.
Rym: Yeah, well Where your collected works, but anyway among all the articles Wikipedia has they obviously have articles about politics and political parties and members of Congress and things of that nature.
Rym: Mmm, well Members of Congress who say do something bad and then that something bad is in an article on Wikipedia Had their staffers go around either deleting it or deleting the articles entirely or creatively editing articles about them to make them look better or Astro turfing or all sorts of just nefarious activity.
Rym: and it's actually fairly widespread to the point that Wikipedia Considered it an emergency as they tend to consider things like that and they blocked the Congress's IP addresses from accessing Wikipedia or editing Wikipedia for a week while they debate what to do about it.
Scott: Awesome Give them what for I?
Scott: really think that I don't know.
Scott: it's like There should be some sort of a system in Wikipedia where?
Scott: There's some sort of nomination and election, you know how like Gentoo works where each package has a maintainer, you know There's an official maintainer of the package, right?
Scott: and So like there's an e-build for the gimp and there's some guy who Jahu's job It is is to maintain that e-build.
Scott: So when the gimp is updated he has to update the e-build and if there's something wrong with the e-build He has to fix it and it's all his job and he's assigned to it.
Scott: Sure, you can edit the e-build and you could send in like a submission to him like hey check this out You could do.
Scott: this is better, but it's up to him.
Scott: He's the man for that piece.
Rym: Well, there's a lot.
Rym: I see where you're going with this and there are a lot of reasons why that wouldn't really work.
Rym: One it's kind of I've you ever written for Wikipedia.
Rym: Yeah Well, if you write on similar articles a lot, you know Every other's an article and then every article has a talk page associated with it Mm-hmm and that's where the authors all talk to each other.
Rym: Yep, and I found through all my editing that most pages Have a small group of people who have just come to be in charge of that page Unofficially and they always watch it and they add it and they talk about it constantly And every page seems to have this sort of organization on its own ad hoc.
Rym: Yep And I don't know if I'd like the idea of making anything like that official because the main thing about Wikipedia Is that it's really just any.
Rym: Joe Schmoe just edits it whenever he wants without even like wondering or thinking about it.
Scott: Well see what this with the idea that I have is you would still have any.
Scott: Joe Schmoe edits it, right?
Scott: But then it would be sort of like the like.
Scott: there would be drafts and revisions So you just go in and edit the current working draft whenever you want it And then the guy who's in charge of that page would do you know would say?
Scott: Ah, and then you would write it in a way that is written properly and not just people hacking sentences into each other.
Rym: No that that you know.
Rym: see they've.
Rym: they've considered that a lot and I see that same idea proposed on talk pages Constantly and even the high of Wikipedia.
Rym: people have a lot.
Rym: I mean, I don't remember all their reasons, but they talked about a very specifically like it's a bad idea.
Rym: for these reasons.
Rym: They're like one to the rise tons of reasons and they've aided it to death and they decided it's just it's not gonna happen.
Scott: I think as long it cuz then Wikipedia would only have to monitor this one set of people who are in charge of pages.
Rym: You know see Wikipedia doesn't monitor anything really.
Rym: they just watch for abuses that are obvious.
Rym: like if the same IP address Reverts a page three times one the page immediately becomes protected.
Rym: No one can screw with it until someone looks at it.
Rym: and two it just automatically prevents that IP address from editing anymore And all sorts of protections like that.
Rym: And I've noticed that most Errors like this like even these Congress things get noticed almost immediately by just people reading Wikipedia and fixed.
Rym: and whenever there's a war You know when someone makes an edit and someone else edits back and someone else edits back It seems that people notice that right away there are flags that it'll automatically flag an article that this article is being fought over and then it comes to the attention of the People who are a couple of steps up from me in terms of writing for Wikipedia Who really care about it a lot and they'll swoop down and fix it and set it straight And it all just seems to work out.
Rym: I've never run into a page that was broken beyond repair.
Scott: I've run into some pages that are pretty scary or Pages who are like the worst.
Scott: what's worse than something that's broken is when someone comes in and writes a page That's like a sentence and that's it.
Scott: and it's like you didn't even put any effort into that at all.
Scott: Why it's like God.
Rym: you know what they do.
Rym: pages like that are still marked as stubs.
Scott: No no no no no no no like.
Scott: it's actually an article But it's it's barely even anything.
Rym: And you know what when that happens as soon as someone finds that article and sees that there's almost nothing in it They mark it as a stub even though there's content there Mm-hmm.
Rym: so it'll have the stub thing at the top and then whatever was already written.
Rym: or if an article is poorly written Though it'll be flagged as warning this article is poorly written.
Rym: We're looking for people to edit it.
Scott: see but who's doing this?
Scott: flagging anyone?
Scott: I don't see any of that.
Rym: I see it often in fact many of the pages I edit since I tend to edit Various pseudoscience things where there are a lot of crackpots out there who are trying to edit back the pages get these flags all the time
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: like if you if a page is recommended for deletion It'll be shown that this page is recommended for deletion discuss And then people can eventually come to a consensus and then it'll be it of a permanent flag saying on such-and-such date This article was put up for deletion and deletion was voted against.
Rym: so people don't bring it up again stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah, Wikipedia I still say was more useful like two years ago and when Before all the crazies in the world started messing with it.
Rym: see I have.
Rym: I have not found any major Inaccuracies in Wikipedia in my recent reading at all.
Scott: It's not so much inaccuracies.
Scott: It's it's like Because things are being fought over and whatnot.
Rym: not much is being fought over.
Rym: a very surprisingly small Amount of Wikipedia is subject to any excessive abuse.
Scott: Yeah, but that's because that's the flagged part.
Scott: That's what you can count.
Scott: the rest of it.
Scott: No one's paying attention to because it's not controversial.
Scott: But the stuff that's not you know right there that just no one notices.
Rym: because yeah And you know what people eventually notice it.
Rym: because honestly part of what I do is when I'm bored I'll just randomly.
Rym: I'll just go to random Wikipedia pages and give them a quick once-over.
Rym: I'll just fix a little grammar.
Scott: The worst though is the stuff where you you have no way of knowing whether it's right or wrong.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: if you have no way of knowing whether it's right or wrong Then that's not the kind of thing you look up on Wikipedia.
Scott: Wikipedia, but that's the but.
Scott: then what's the point?
Scott: The point is to find out stuff.
Scott: I don't know not to go find stuff.
Scott: I do know if I do know it.
Rym: I don't need to look it up on Wikipedia Yeah, but if you're a hundred percent ignorant on a topic, you're probably want to gonna want to do some more.
Scott: Of course Verifiable research of course, but then you know then what's the use of Wikipedia then?
Rym: well You know what the use of Wikipedia is that despite all this I have never had a problem with the accuracy of the information I've sought Ever.
Rym: I have never once run into a problem with using Wikipedia for research.
Scott: I Haven't had any specific problems, but it's like sometimes I'll go to look there, and it's just.
Scott: it's just not helpful at all.
Scott: I haven't had like a problem where oh, I went to a page, and it was full of crap.
Scott: You know the word fuck a hundred times.
Rym: What have you been searching for in Wikipedia that you have all this trouble?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't remember last time.
Scott: I went there was like a few days ago, but okay.
Rym: And what did you look for?
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: so you're saying there's these problems?
Scott: Yeah, I remember going there for like three different things ending up with like just useless empty page.
Rym: one things I don't remember.
Scott: What do you want?
Scott: me think I am like a freaking.
Rym: uh so you've got.
Rym: no Don't even have anecdotal evidence.
Rym: You're just saying stuff just cuz.
Scott: I don't remember what it was.
Scott: just cuz I don't remember what I was searching for.
Scott: doesn't mean That my memory of the fact that I searched and what the result was is invalid?
Rym: It might be cuz.
Rym: I'm curious as to whether you actually had a problem or what articles you saw that for whatever reason I mean why were these articles bad?
Scott: They were just like one sentence, and it was completely useless.
Rym: What were you searching for?
Rym: and if it was just?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I just remember what there is.
Scott: the result was like and that it was.
Rym: you're saying that you found it on a whole article Not marked as a stub a separate article.
Rym: that was just a sentence.
Rym: Yeah, show me an example of this and maybe we'll talk.
Rym: did you look on the discussion page?
Rym: Maybe they were.
Rym: they just deleted it because they were rewriting something Whenever someone person there wasn't any little notices at the top or anything.
Rym: all right.
Rym: Did you look at the talk page?
Scott: No, I never look at the talk page the talk page.
Rym: We always have to look because whenever an article is being edited heavily What they'll do is they'll copy well They'll cut and paste all the stuff out of the article into the talk page and take it off of the article And then they'll edit it there, and then they'll put it back when it's readable or good.
Rym: Hmm, so maybe you just found pages that were in transition and weren't flagged yet.
Scott: But see if things are moving.
Scott: see that's also annoying because if things are moving around all the time Then it's you know it's like I have no trouble.
Rym: things are moving around.
Scott: you look in the talk page And you see I have to go and look in the stupid talk page.
Rym: Yeah, you see research isn't easy.
Rym: it never has been and it never will be because you can't trust many sources And you have to back things up constantly.
Rym: Wikipedia is the same way.
Rym: if you want to use Wikipedia for more than just a cursory Glance of some information you have to look at the talk page.
Rym: you have to look at who's been editing the article.
Rym: You have to look at what's going on And you have to think to yourself whether or not this article seems legitimate and possibly do a little bit of side research to Make sure that it is in fact.
Scott: I don't use Wikipedia for anything serious.
Scott: I use use it if there's like a fact or two.
Scott: I want to know you know and if there's no facts there whatsoever It's like.
Scott: it's just not worth the effort.
Scott: You know it's like I want.
Scott: it's the point isn't?
Scott: I want to.
Scott: if I'm doing real research I'm going to go to the library or Realize that.
Rym: the other point is if you search for something on Wikipedia, and there's no information there about it Then that's your problem not Wikipedia's.
Rym: you should step up and write the article do the research and write it.
Scott: you know if I'm Looking for something that's because I don't know it.
Scott: So I'm not really the person to write the article on it.
Rym: Yeah, so if you don't find the answer on Wikipedia But you still want to find the answer and you eventually do you should go back and put it in Wikipedia.
Scott: The thing is if I if I really want to know the answer.
Scott: I'm not going to be looking on Wikipedia.
Scott: I'm going to be reading a book on it.
Scott: I look on Wikipedia when I'd like to know the answer and it's not really worth that much to me.
Scott: But Wikipedia is really easy.
Rym: it takes a second, but you realize that there was a time when there was nothing on Wikipedia.
Rym: now There's more, but if you find something that isn't there.
Rym: That's not a problem.
Rym: Wikipedia is not perfect, and it doesn't have all the information in the world in it.
Rym: There's no way it can ever have all the information in the world.
Rym: there will always be something you can search for that won't be on Wikipedia.
Rym: Yeah The point is most things are there most things people search for are there and Most things that people search for are there and fairly accurate and good.
Scott: I still think it's getting more messed up over time.
Rym: I'd say just the opposite.
Rym: I'd say the most as times gone on especially in the last six or seven months the quality of many articles has improved precipitously.
Scott: No, that's not what I see because I remember articles that you're reading I don't even know.
Scott: I remember because
Rym: you realize I make it a point if I read one Wikipedia article every single day Just as part of my editing and I've I can think of one or two articles in the past several months that had any Major problems with them or any sort of bad grammar beyond just things that I wouldn't expect people to worry about.
Scott: I Remember like in my late college years Wikipedia was like amazing and everything on there was great.
Scott: and lately all there is is you know People yelling about it, and what do you mean?
Rym: Where are these people yelling?
Rym: What are you talking about?
Scott: Isn't that just the story that we were talking about?
Rym: Some people some people were defacing some pages and Wikipedia blocked all.
Scott: there was a story a couple weeks ago where another guy was defacing a page about himself.
Scott: There was one man, and there were pseudo science people messing with pages and putting lies on them And there are culties going in there religious people going in there And you realize that's a small fraction of the total of Wikipedia.
Rym: And there there are thousands and thousands thousands of articles that aren't contested at all.
Rym: like the other day I was reading out of the article on rabbits Just rabbits the animal and I was reading the article and going through it and the talk page had almost nothing in it.
Rym: There was nothing controversial about rabbits.
Rym: No one was fighting about rabbits.
Rym: No one is even defacing rabbits.
Rym: It was just a useful article on rabbits.
Scott: How do you know?
Scott: but see here's the thing.
Scott: there's no way to verify what you know?
Scott: I could have gone into the rabbit page and written something like see there I could have made up a species of rabbit photoshopped a picture of it put it on.
Scott: there wrote that that rabbit eats I don't know cats and There would be no talk or discussion on it because no one cares about rabbit.
Rym: see there probably would be because that thing that sort Of thing does happen from time to time.
Rym: We're a completely benign article.
Rym: some Article was recently but there was one where someone just added something crazy to it just randomly and they just slipped it in and it Looked legitimate, but people reading the article picked up on it immediately and it was a fairly obscure article.
Rym: I'll try to dig it up and I'll post it if I find the link.
Scott: I Know what losers are out there going around Wikipedia looking for stuff like that.
Scott: I am no way to go.
Rym: Every day I read at least one article and then I edit it if necessary.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you know about whatever you're reading there.
Rym: Well, the thing is I generally have a sense of it's fair.
Rym: It's usually fairly obvious because I'm fairly knowledgeable about a lot of topics.
Rym: if something is BS or it'll set off the wait a minute Sense and I look it up further.
Scott: Well, I have that I can do that too.
Scott: But I mean, you know, if I'm not the authority on something, what's my business?
Rym: I mean, what's your point?
Rym: You're really knocking Wikipedia, but I think Wikipedia does is very good at what it does.
Scott: It's less useful than it used to be.
Rym: I don't I say just the opposite.
Rym: the more I use Wikipedia I think it's improving greatly in recent months.
Scott: Well, that's not been my experience.
Scott: My experience is you know a couple years ago whenever I look something up I would always find something great and lately whenever I look something up I always been looking up to.
Scott: I defy you in the next just cuz I don't remember what I've been looking up.
Rym: I really don't believe you because you have nothing.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I'm just making it up that you know, I wouldn't put it past you.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: I mean really you're just making it up.
Rym: I look at the Wikipedia article on rabbits, which I just read.
Rym: It was fantastic.
Rym: Look at the talk page.
Rym: Look at the Wikipedia article on indigo children Which I just edited fairly heavily not too long ago.
Rym: It's fine.
Rym: No one's even tried to revert the chain.
Rym: Someone tried to revert the changes I put in once and someone else who's smart just fixed it and there hasn't been a problem since.
Rym: hmm Recently, I read one on the Gulf War.
Rym: the Wikipedia article on the original Gulf War is extremely accurate and well done.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you're an expert in the Gulf War.
Rym: I know enough about it to know if an article is accurate or not.
Scott: You might know some parts are accurate but you don't know.
Rym: plus you realize everything in any Wikipedia article has to be backed up by a citation and a link to that citation and It's very easy to look at the citations.
Rym: See if those are legitimate.
Rym: See if they actually back up.
Scott: Not everything is cited.
Rym: If there's something that's unsighted It Wikipedia policy it either has to be cited or deleted.
Rym: In fact, there's a specific rule against original research if there is no site or if anything's original It cannot be on Wikipedia and it will be deleted as per Wikipedia's policy if something isn't cited there.
Scott: Where are these citations?
Scott: because sometimes I'll see like at the bottom of the page some links or you know, some bibliography Yeah, but there aren't like, you know little footnotes and citations in every single sentence on many many articles.
Rym: There are numerous numerous numerous citations dozens and dozens.
Scott: I don't see him and I don't see every single fact and every single paragraph being cited.
Rym: You do realize that if there's a site at the end of a paragraph Oftentimes that site relates to the entire paragraph.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I know this but many many paragraphs just don't have anything.
Scott: It's just paragraphs of information.
Rym: Um, that's not been my experience.
Rym: I found that almost everything I read on Wikipedia is actually fairly well cited.
Scott: I don't even know where the citations are half the time.
Scott: They're just like bottom under Citations.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of times will be this giant article and at the bottom They'll be like two things.
Rym: Um, if that's true point them out to me and I'll fix them or I'll delete them because that's the exception to the rule.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's not what I see.
Rym: then didn't point it out to me.
Rym: Show me.
Scott: Why do I have to show you?
Scott: Why don't you show me all the the whatevers?
Rym: All right, look at all the ones I just described - - that's a great.
Scott: You know sample size there.
Rym: All right, let's see I read one on the Crimean War which I actually know quite a bit about.
Rym: it was very well done.
Rym: It was a little short, but it was about what you get from high school history book.
Rym: I read one recently on the Articles of Confederation From you know, but they document the US used before the Constitution.
Rym: It was actually extremely well written and accurate.
Rym: I read one on the Civil War not too long ago.
Scott: That one was fairly well cited But you're not an expert in any of those things.
Rym: Actually, I know I'm not an expert but I know a lot about the Civil War because my grandfather is is very I wouldn't say Nutty, but he's extremely interested in and well versed in the American Civil War Partly because his family's from Tennessee and he's just.
Rym: he's really big on American history like that.
Scott: See your grandpa would be able to say whether it is that doesn't say anything about you.
Scott: I Mean, I could.
Rym: I wasn't using these as examples of oh I read this article and it's perfect as in.
Rym: I'm using them as examples Of oh, I read this article.
Rym: It was really good and here.
Scott: Oh, look, here's the one about rabbits.
Scott: Let's see where I can find a citation.
Scott: No, there aren't any citations yet.
Scott: No, there's still no citations.
Scott: Still no citations Still none.
Scott: There are three links there in the middle of the page Under the human relationships with rabbits.
Scott: There's three links at the bottom of it Uh-huh.
Scott: I don't see any footnotes.
Scott: I don't see any citations.
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: They're inter Wikipedia links and at the bottom of the page, there are two external links and three see.
Scott: also I don't see any citations as in this book this page or this scientific Journal entry this anything.
Scott: so according to you we should delete most of this but also according to you It's well-written.
Scott: Where are the citations?
Rym: Most of that information comes from the links at the bottom.
Rym: They don't didn't cite everything because a lot of the information but it's not in both cited.
Scott: a citation means Parentheses with telling me where that information comes from.
Rym: How do I know which of these paragraphs of information you realize comes from which link you realize that?
Rym: Citation is not a formal word and that there are many different kinds of citation.
Rym: There's MLA citation, which is a very specific in exactly what the formatting of the site It also has to do with what information you include in the citation.
Rym: There's a Citation.
Scott: means you say which information came from which source.
Scott: all this says is no Citation.
Rym: just means you say where the information came from.
Rym: That could be a very vague broad fantasy.
Scott: which information came from where you can't just say yeah You call this information came from either here or here.
Scott: That's not citing.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: That's you may not consider that citing but the definition of citation is fairly broad.
Rym: All right Well, let's look at this link rabbit org, which is the primary Cited reference for the Wikipedia article.
Rym: it contains in extreme detail everything included in the Wikipedia article and more.
Scott: So why even bother having the Wikipedia article?
Rym: Wikipedia article is just a Useful reference and it points you in the right direction.
Rym: if you want more than what's on the Wikipedia article Then you can follow the links for the more exact information.
Scott: See now, how do I know which information on this rabbit page came from?
Scott: which of those?
Scott: what?
Rym: if you don't know?
Scott: Then just don't use Wikipedia so you may have noticed around various websites on the internet is a lot of supposed pictures of what the User interface on the revolution is going to look like the virtual console or whatever you want to call it.
Scott: pretty much all of them are fake and In fact, the one I've linked to is fake confirmed.
Scott: But the point is is that people are talking like ah is Nintendo Just making a whole bunch of these and flooding the internet with them to create some hype.
Scott: Are they doing it to?
Scott: You know get people confused.
Scott: So if the real one ever gets out there people won't believe it.
Scott: Or is this some guy doing it on purpose to be silly?
Scott: or you know, there's all kinds of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, it's hard to say but all the ideas we see.
Rym: one.
Rym: These photoshops are really well done.
Scott: They're really well done.
Rym: I mean we look at this one like they even get it where you see like the Projected image on the guy standing in front of the screen.
Scott: Yeah, it's really good.
Rym: and two all these things are kind of badass Like they're all products that ooh or ideas that ooh, they make me get all the Twitter about Nintendo.
Scott: Yeah, you know and it's the one that that looked the most believable to me was the one that looked a lot like the DS interface.
Scott: but I have a feeling that the Revolution interface is going to utilize the revolution controller in some way like aiming and shooting or some such like that.
Scott: Yeah, you know perhaps something 3d could be done with the new controller.
Scott: That would be about mad cool.
Scott: You know cuz 3d interfaces right now all suck.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: Though for me over the weekend I had the pleasure of seeing a movie that not many people in the world have seen.
Rym: it's it was never released ever.
Rym: It's had a few special screenings.
Rym: In 1984 it was shown in Seattle for four days.
Rym: It was shown one day in New York City a few years ago.
Rym: It was shown in Rochester, New York over this past weekend once and the movie is called nothing lasts forever.
Rym: It was basically, you know Saturday Night Live like old Saturday Night Live back when like John Belushi and Dan Aykroyd All them were on it.
Scott: So not super old just semi old.
Rym: Yeah, like the golden age.
Rym: Well part of it is that back then the original concept for SNL included having short films In every episode like there'd be the musical act and the comedy bits and then short film Mm-hmm, and there was this guy.
Rym: His name was Tom Schiller and he made a bunch of these movies and anyone who's old enough to remember the old SNL I remembers these movies.
Rym: They're just little shorts and they're often hilarious.
Rym: One was kind of scary and prophetic.
Rym: It showed all the characters from SNL dead except John Belushi And he was walking over all their graves like yeah Fellow this one died of this and blah blah blah and then a lot of them ended up actually dying early Including John Belushi,
Scott: yeah,
Rym: but this movie has all those people in it like every big name for I mean Bill Murray Dan Aykroyd.
Rym: John Belushi was gonna be in it, but he actually died right before Bill Murray.
Scott: You said him.
Rym: Yeah, I said him But I really can't describe this movie other than that.
Rym: it was odd and hilarious.
Scott: It's hard to not be hilarious with that kind of lineup, I mean I just to give a small sampling.
Rym: I mean, there's a transit strike, right?
Rym: So the New York Port Authority takes over Manhattan.
Rym: Okay, yeah, and then they go to the moon on a bus and There's the already bus.
Rym: No, but then there's these bums that are living under the city and they're actually the secret masters of the universe.
Rym: All right And Bill Murray plays this guy and he's odd.
Rym: I'm really not sure how to describe it at all.
Rym: I could the movies.
Scott: it is a reason that no one's seen it and no one wants to see it.
Rym: It's really good.
Rym: It's hilarious and it wasn't released only because Warner Brothers didn't like it and There's a lot of like stock footage used in it.
Rym: So they're copyright issues with actually releasing it.
Rym: But if you have one if any of you out there have a copy of this movie That isn't that one screener bootleg that's going around.
Rym: that's unwatchable.
Rym: I'll probably pay good money for it.
Scott: I'm sure there has to be a way.
Rym: there's a horrible broken screener that you can buy and it's just like Unwatchable.
Rym: it was aired once on Australian television.
Rym: It was aired once on German television.
Scott: I'm sure we can get it up from Australian television.
Rym: I don't know if anyone taped it.
Rym: I don't think it was ever aired again.
Scott: There's got to be something.
Scott: there can't be Epps.
Scott: I mean you.
Scott: you just watched it the other day, right?
Scott: You just saw it, right?
Scott: Yeah The means is a film that exists.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there's film.
Rym: It has to be a narrow transfer of some sort somewhere something.
Scott: It might require great pizza of Lupin, but there's a way to get this movie and watch it.
Rym: Yeah, so if anyone out there has seen this movie one, I'd love to get some audio feedback from you.
Rym: Maybe you can describe the movie in a more coherent way than I am able to - if you find the movie I'm prepared to pay you handsomely for it.
Scott: It's just bit torn it.
Scott: Come on.
Rym: Yeah If you find it on bit torn God.
Rym: Yeah, this movie just fantastic and it's weird and it's kind of a backhanded thing of the day because while one It's this awesome thing that I want you all to see there's almost no way for you to see it.
Scott: Yeah, I really hate it.
Rym: when things are Lost yeah, like all those episodes of Doctor Who that the BBC just destroyed and they're gone forever.
Scott: Yeah, when things are gone forever it sucks.
Scott: and that's why copyright sex because it makes things get lost forever.
Scott: without copyright Nothing would ever get lost because some nothing that matters.
Scott: I'm not would make a billion copies of it.
Scott: Hold on to it forever.
Rym: Well things that didn't matter would get lost but there's cuz.
Rym: no one would like them live.
Scott: No one likes them deserve to get lost.
Rym: You can't find even one guy willing to hoard what you did.
Rym: It probably isn't worth knowing about a thousand years from now.
Scott: Yeah, seriously, there are people who collect like I don't know spoons.
Scott: If there's a guy who's willing to hold on to a spoon and he's not willing as some there's no one willing to hold on To what you made?
Scott: Wow, it sucks.
Scott: Wow, or it doesn't suck enough because if something really sucks people will hold on to it for its novelty like hard rock zombies.
Scott: Yeah like that.
Rym: but Yeah, we're not gonna do our main bit today just because we yelled at each other for 45 minutes about other things.
Scott: pretend That's the main bit.
Rym: Yeah, and We're not sure if we're gonna do it real soon.
Rym: We might wait a couple weeks depending but I'm sure all of you are aware.
Rym: and for those of you who aren't aware Otakon the anime convention has Violently changed its artist Alicey artist Ally policy to effectively ban fan art.
Scott: Well, they haven't.
Scott: they haven't officially Made this the permanent final policy yet.
Rym: Well, despite the fact that they say they haven't made it the official policy It was posted under a thread entitled official changes for 2006.
Rym: Yeah, and there's this big rigmarole.
Rym: anime news network Reported on it and then Otakon called him out and then anime news network jab right back and said you reported this is official.
Rym: It's not our fault.
Rym: Mm-hmm and the fans exploded and they had a lot.
Rym: Lisa they had to lock the thread twice because people just were screaming about it and every forum where people find out about this is just going nuts.
Rym: and We've got at least one very good person to interview about this and we're gonna do a whole episode on the Otakon artist Ally issue.
Rym: so stay tuned.
Scott: if it gets resolved We'll still do an episode on it too because there's a lot of things that could be discussed about it that are interesting And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.