Rym: It's Thursday January 26th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We finish up our series on how to attend a convention.
Scott: Let's do this alright, so Rym went to Rochester for anime club, but actually he didn't because it's still Wednesday, and he's right there And we're just recording this right now.
Scott: You know with just me to give the illusion that we're actually recording Thursday when we're not.
Rym: Actually, I'm packing and I'm doing post-production for the two episodes before I go out of town So I don't have time to actually talk on the show today, right?
Scott: But you people listening will be hearing this Thursday night Unless you happen to be cool enough to be on our forums in which case you would get this the day early Which is when it was made and so if you're not in our forums, you should probably join them.
Scott: So even if you don't join the discussion on the forums At least become a member so that you know when we release a podcast early or make a special announcement You can be the first one there and also when we we're gonna redesign our blog the the theme on the front page of front.
Scott: recruit calm at some point in the future when we finalize our logo and all that and you will no longer be able to comment on The different entries there.
Scott: so the forum is going to be the only place for discussion to happen.
Scott: So if you're a regular listener join the forum, I don't know how many times I'm gonna have to tell people to do this until Eventually one day I'll have to tell them not to join because there's too many people there.
Scott: Anyway, so it being Really Wednesday.
Scott: I don't have any Thursday news, but I do have an awesome thing of the day.
Scott: It's this video of this 12 year old kid Playing the drums drum solo no band.
Scott: No singers.
Scott: No nothing.
Scott: It's just his kid on his own playing the drums and I gotta say For 12 minutes.
Scott: It's not even for a 12 year old for anyone no matter their age.
Scott: This is some amazing freaking drumming.
Scott: Now I'm not an expert drummer or an expert on drum playing But I don't think you have to be to recognize how awesome this drumming is.
Scott: And then when you add that to the fact that he's 12 years old, it's just even more awesome.
Scott: Now first I thought maybe he was the you know One of those kids where the parents took him since the age of zero and made him do this thing and he has no social Skills and he's a loser and whatever.
Scott: But if you watch the video and you hear him talk at the beginning He seems like he's a cool happening kid who knows the score and is you know?
Scott: Intelligent like someone you want to hang out with it.
Scott: So watch it and enjoy and now listen to the Podcast that we recorded many days ago.
Rym: Alright, so today we're going to conclude our little series on how to attend conventions with the final bits and then some nice regular closing advice.
Rym: So like we said last time we're gonna cover the artists alley the dance slash rave because every con seems to have a different kind of dance and some are scary and You really got to know where you're getting into.
Rym: and Also, we want to yell you to make sure you don't end up being that glow stick waving smelly fanboy That's always in my way when I'm trying to dance.
Scott: if you're that guy.
Scott: Oh my god I'm coming to get you.
Rym: Yeah Drama drama con because there's no drama involved with our grooms.
Rym: ever since one convention the first Otakon We went to where a couple people in our room had some issues and ended up having some drama We basically we did all the drama out and while we're friends with people who cause drama.
Rym: They are not allowed to stay with us at conventions, which makes our life.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: And then leaving the convention because leaving is actually a fine art and if you fail at it, you'll ruin your whole Sunday.
Scott: yeah, leaving is yeah, it can be harder than arriving actually and Basically the longer it takes you to leave and the more you fuck up leaving The less time you have at the final day of the convention
Rym: because we stayed up way too late Saturday night at the last Otakon and we fucked up leaving in the morning and we basically missed a bunch of stuff and it was horrible.
Scott: It wasn't horrible Yeah, yeah.
Rym: So artist allies now for any of you haven't been to a convention and this is really true of anime and gaming conventions Especially comic conventions also have big artists allies.
Rym: I've never actually been to a comic convention.
Scott: a comic convention is sort of like an anime convention because has the artist alley which is almost the same thing and it has the panels and it has but it doesn't have like the big events like concerts and dances and things and Instead of having like, you know a dealers room and then everything else separate It's pretty much this giant room where this is booths and every booth is Either a dealer or a comic guy or both.
Scott: And you just you.
Scott: basically at a comic convention you walk around to all the booths and the booths are kind of like the expensive Ones for people with money and the artists alley is where the poor people are.
Rym: But at most conventions basically all the artists alley is is you'll see the dealers room and that's where all the professional stuff is.
Rym: Costs a lot of money to be in there and everyone's trying to make money.
Rym: artist alleys tend to be Anyone who ponies up some paltry amount of money.
Rym: or sometimes it's just free And they get a little space on the table and they can do whatever they want with that space As long as it follows certain rules.
Scott: and usually they just present their art and try to get people to like their art And maybe get a few commissions sell a few little pictures or something.
Scott: Maybe some arts and crafts.
Rym: Now at small conventions just go and have fun and don't even try to make money.
Rym: You might make money, but it's really not the primary focus.
Rym: It's just artists hanging out.
Rym: but if you go to a big convention like Otakon or Anime Central There are people who make big money.
Rym: Yeah like we have friends who make a lot of money sitting in the in the artist alley all day for like the whole convention just Selling their art or doing commissions or making stickers.
Scott: It's actually pretty awesome that you know someone who?
Scott: Doesn't get much coverage and you know, they they have really good art skills.
Scott: But you know, no one pays attention to them and they're not well known.
Scott: You just sit in this room all day and people will notice them and then pay them a lot of money.
Rym: I mean honestly, I used to go to the dealers room and I was like my big thing.
Rym: But as I've been to more conventions and I've seen every little anime gadget gizmo Plushie you can buy and I've got all the ones I want.
Rym: I don't buy so much in the dealers room anymore.
Rym: I spent almost all my money in artists alley buying either Commissioning things or buying little prints or buying the originals if I can and bidding on art.
Scott: Yeah, I mean artists alley used to be like I'm not really too keen on that whatever.
Scott: I wasn't too interested in it You know and the dealers room was like, oh, yeah, look at this stuff all this stuff I can't get in America my little, you know action figure you guys and Model kits and all kinds of cool stuff, right?
Scott: But then eventually they don't make so much new stuff.
Scott: So like once you've been to the dealers room Especially the Otakon one or you go to online and you look in dealers, you know dealers websites.
Scott: You eventually see everything there is and there isn't too much new amazing stuff.
Scott: It's just like more of the same and once you find the more of the same that you want and buy it all you're pretty Much like alright unless there's a rare gem in here somewhere.
Scott: I don't care but an artist alley.
Scott: There's all kinds of people who think like you and are making the things that you know You wish they made officially but they don't.
Rym: I mean you'll see a lot of just unique stuff.
Rym: However, the first thing that really made us realize how awesome it was is way back I think was our first Otakon.
Rym: We I saw this little that little print for sale.
Rym: Yeah, super Mario Super Show Joe Brothers and it was all the characters from shoujo kakameo Tena dressed up as characters from Mario Brothers And I realized that there are infinite possibilities in the genre of something dressed up like something else.
Scott: Yeah, but you realize that that's just also in the realm of scary fanfic and whatever.
Scott: Yeah It's it's weird because if it's a scary fanfic, I'll be like, that's just a scary fanfic.
Scott: get that the hell away from me.
Scott: But if someone draws a really cute picture it all depends on the quality of their drawing.
Scott: Like if they draw it really crappily, I'll be like that's a scary fanfic picture, but if they draw it really amazingly It's like holy crap.
Scott: Someone needs to scan that and put it all over the internet stat.
Rym: I Mean, what was it?
Rym: We saw this year that we really?
Rym: Oh, right.
Rym: It was Princess peach.
Scott: that was last year.
Rym: I think that was last year.
Rym: Well last year there was a big one and this year there were the prints and I got a little print Yeah, and you got that freedom Gundam whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta figure out where I put those.
Rym: we can get him framed.
Scott: I think they're on your desk somewhere or something.
Rym: Yeah, I put them somewhere safe and I'm not sure where I put him.
Rym: good job Yeah, I'll dig him up.
Scott: Yeah, but it was like Princess Peach with like crazy armor sitting on a Yoshi With like this crazy umbrella.
Scott: It was just an amazing amazing picture that like anyone who likes Mario would like kill to have on their wall.
Rym: I Way back there's only one for sale.
Rym: It was in the auction it went for some crazy amount of money and the guy was like I can't believe that was popular.
Rym: So we came back selling prints of it and he sold like all of them right away.
Scott: Yep I mean if you do something good, you'll make a killing.
Scott: All right, so to get into artists alley Basically, you just go to the website for whatever convention you're going to and read the instructions.
Scott: Read the instructions very carefully and do it early as early as possible.
Rym: I mean Otakons artist alley sold out within an hour of going live.
Scott: Yeah, that's only Otakon though Other cons should be okay But like a medium-sized con you might have a little trouble if you wait till the last minute.
Scott: So as soon as you decide you're definitely going to the convention.
Scott: follow the artist alley instructions.
Scott: if you have to like call someone or email the people at the convention or something to make sure you've done it right and Maybe confirm a couple times just to make sure 100%.
Rym: Yeah cuz there are often a lot of stupid legal things you have to deal with in an artist alley because like Marilyn for one has all these laws about vending and you have to apply for a vendors permit before otherwise The police will literally come bust you up.
Rym: Mm-hmm Some states are more lax.
Rym: just find out whatever the rules are.
Rym: The convention will tell you and just do them.
Rym: if you're under 18 You might have a lot of trouble and there's really nothing that can be done about that.
Scott: Under 18 just don't bother or you know, just hang out in artist alley or find someone who's.
Scott: you know.
Scott: usually if there's someone who's over 18 and They have a table and you can make friends with them or they are your friend already and you just sit with them or they Let you sit with them.
Scott: No one will notice or care, you know, something like that.
Rym: I mean my main advice if you're gonna sit in artist alley is one Get a bunch of friends with you because then it's it's just fun to hang out there all day with all your friends doing art.
Scott: Yeah, what really sucks about artist alley is you don't want to end up sitting there all day and all night and not enjoying The rest of the convention at all.
Scott: You need to have some sort of rotation with people where you get up and you sit down And you do have an easy way to get your stuff in and out of there because you don't want to leave it.
Scott: They're unattended because they'll just be stolen or destroyed or something.
Rym: I highly recommend.
Rym: you share an artist alley table with a friend.
Rym: It makes the experience much more enjoyable like infinitely Alright.
Scott: the second thing you got to do is you got to figure out what you're gonna do with the artist alley table and I recommend there are two ways you can go about it.
Scott: If you're like a super artist, you pretty much just have to display your art and people will come and patronize you.
Scott: It's that easy now.
Rym: It depends on what you want by patronize.
Rym: Do you want to sell prints?
Rym: Do you want to sell originals?
Rym: Do you want to generate buzz for your online webcomic project?
Rym: Do you want to get people to commission you?
Rym: That's that's one of the primary Motive forces and artists alleys these days is people seeking commissions.
Scott: Yep Of course if you want to make lots of money You're not pretty much gonna have to Face the the truth and you're not gonna be able to do what you want to do and what you like to do.
Rym: if you Want to make lots of money you're gonna have to pander to the fans and the fans want something that's cute and relatively cheap That can be produced in mass quantity that no one else is offering.
Scott: Yeah, it has to be unique.
Scott: So let's say there's a super new anime called Amazing crazy whatnot?
Scott: show and there's a cute animal in the show, but there are no plushies of that animal and everyone in the show wears These special sunglasses and those sunglasses are not available for purchase or they're very expensive in the dealers room for the official ones.
Rym: If you can make those sunglasses, even if they're kind of crappy if they're just good enough, you'll sell all of them immediately
Scott: Mm-hmm, and you know you make a plushie of that cute little animal or you make like a hat that looks like the animal or A car or anything pictures of the animal.
Scott: you'll be freaking sold.
Rym: I mean like the year right after FMA came out and was really popular.
Rym: and then Otakon happened.
Rym: There was almost no full metal alchemist merchandise in the in the dealers room just because it hadn't gotten over to the US yet.
Rym: Mm-hmm and The artists alley.
Rym: a few people Realized this and came with a pile of like full metal alchemist buttons and stickers and they sold.
Rym: I think they sold them all.
Rym: I still have my huge sticker.
Scott: Yeah, I got a little huge pin.
Scott: I have an official huge pin and I have a huge sticker.
Scott: That's really cute.
Scott: stickers go well if you have cute pictures on them that no one else has.
Rym: Yeah, stickers are key, especially stickers that easily fit on someone's con badge.
Scott: Mm-hmm I remember what was big in the dealers room.
Scott: I was looking for Death Note stuff because Death Note was not highly merchandised in the dealer room.
Scott: So pretty much anything with Death Note on it.
Scott: that was in artists alley.
Scott: I just picked up.
Rym: It's hard to say what's gonna be the big thing this year.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I think Death Note is gonna be past its prime in the sense that a lot of people are gonna be doing It.
Scott: yeah, but at this it's gonna be huge though because the manga is actually out in English now true as opposed to just other Languages and so now all the other people have picked up on it and it sold quite well.
Rym: Yeah, cuz back at Katsucon last year There were two Death Note items of art in the entire convention in the auction and I bid on them and lost.
Rym: Well, yeah that anecdote didn't go anywhere.
Rym: No, I didn't like meet the artist and then like she tried to kill me or anything cool I just lost.
Scott: now if you're an artist alley visitor, it's a little different.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: What you want to do is You want to go there as soon as it officially opens.
Scott: But you want if you do that, they're not all the artists will be set up yet because they're mostly lazy.
Scott: But you still want to do that.
Scott: in case anyone sets up something crazy That's gonna sell out like, you know crazy gonna.
Rym: it's basically just kind of walk into the room Give a scan make sure there's nothing weird going on.
Scott: Yeah, if you see something like a crowd of people throwing money around whatever that is It's it's 90% chance.
Scott: It's awesome and you want it.
Scott: so you better run over there and fight with the best of them.
Scott: but then you want to come back like at least once a day and Check everything because artists rotate in and out and there'll be something different every freaking time.
Scott: And this is a really tiny con in which case, you know, you'll pretty much see everything in one go.
Scott: But if it's any even the medium-sized cons now have respectable artists alleys that you have to visit multiple times.
Rym: Yeah, the one kind of doesn't surprisingly is anime Expo.
Rym: We've never been to it But from all my friends who have gone or told me about it their artist alley unless it's changed very recently Is like a hole in the wall under a stairway in the back middle of nowhere.
Scott: Well That's kind of surprising.
Rym: Yeah well anime expo is very much a business side oriented convention and Otakon is definitely a Fan oriented convention and that's why it is to win fair.
Rym: now a lot of people give commissions or they try to sell commissions in artist alley and Basically, if you're not really familiar with the concept It means you go to an artist who style you like and you ask them to draw you something and they tell you how much?
Rym: It'll cost to do that and they'll either mail it to you or you can pick it up at the end of the con.
Scott: Yep You can get like.
Scott: you can ask for anything from like a two minute like a two second sketch like just sketch it real quick And it'd be like a few dollars to draw me a giant thing in full color or make me a tapestry which will cost you From hunt, you know, maybe 50 bucks to a hundred to thousands of dollars depending on the artist and all kinds of stuff.
Rym: Yeah there's this guy who makes these awesome anime like tapestries and It'd be a couple thousand dollars for what I want.
Rym: But I'd like to commission like this giant utenna tapestry and just hang it in our kitchen.
Rym: Yeah, great mainly to cut down on the echo in there that rooms too big and has too little in it.
Scott: Get some stuff to put in it.
Rym: We got one FMA wall scroll.
Rym: I don't think it's dampening the sound so much.
Scott: Yeah, we'll get something else, but I don't think a giant thousand dollar tapestry is but most economical decision.
Rym: I have two basic warnings.
Rym: if you're if you're doing commissions for other people Be warned that at least half the people who come up to you will probably ask for something horrible and pornographic.
Scott: Now if you don't mind drawing that you'll make a ton.
Scott: Yeah way to go but I Wouldn't draw that if I was an artist, you know, so yes guys you guys got to say no It depends on your level of scruples.
Rym: But don't be afraid to say no not even if it's porn if it's something that you don't think you can do.
Rym: something is too Ambitious or you won't have time for just don't be afraid to say no.
Rym: more people will come and they expect that because That's what happens.
Rym: Not everyone can do everything.
Scott: Another good strategy is if you're a really good artist you can just say oh you want something porn double price Yep, you know.
Scott: and those fanboys.
Scott: They're freaky.
Scott: They'll pay it?
Rym: Yeah, and yeah, they really will.
Scott: and if you don't you know and you can get away with drawing it a little shitty You know and what do you care?
Scott: It's just a porn thing.
Scott: Don't put your name on it No one will know, you know, they'll be like, oh that's shitty, you know, it doesn't look like they drew it whatever.
Rym: now if you want a commission for yourself from an artist a Lot of people don't seem to realize that you actually have to put a little bit of thought in it.
Rym: If you just walk up and say draw me a giant robot Doing something awesome.
Rym: That's really not enough input.
Rym: Yeah, you have to start like hate that some some people like to run with it.
Rym: But most artists I've known hate it.
Rym: if you ask for a commission or a sketch and then you really don't give them any idea.
Rym: Mm-hmm, like if you want them to draw your Dungeons & Dragons character dressed up as a la card from housing You better have a good explanation of what your character looks like or you're not gonna be happy with the result.
Scott: Yeah the thing is if someone's your friend like you know them then they kind of know what you like.
Scott: or if you just tell an Artist draw whatever you want.
Scott: They'll draw whatever they want.
Rym: Yeah, my friggin artist friends if they know that if they draw like an air pirate in the sky Doing something awesome and some sort of steampunk era I'll just go nuts over it.
Scott: Yeah, but if it's some if it's an artist You don't know and you just walk around.
Scott: you see their style is awesome You know.
Scott: tell them I want you to draw a pirate posing like this and do a pose and then be like wearing you know an eyepatch and a peg leg and they're standing on a ship and it's real windy and There's a crazy weird cutesy animal flying around, you know, that looks like this.
Scott: That's about a good enough description.
Scott: I Know you can't just be like I want a pirate Cuz.
Scott: they'll just draw like a little stick figure with an eyepatch and give you a finger.
Scott: at least they should.
Rym: I Mean, I guess we could talk about artists alley forever just because we love it.
Scott: Oh, yeah It's not all about artists alley is it?
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: but check out artists alleys go to a convention.
Rym: They're an experience that you can't really describe.
Rym: You just have to see it.
Rym: Yep now The dance or the rave or whatever you want to call it.
Rym: Wow Now I'm going to.
Rym: we might make some enemies here because we have basically there are two camps When it comes to dances at conventions and these two camps are split about 50/50.
Scott: and well There is a third camp which I can I can talk about.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but they're not.
Scott: they're not in the same third Camp I'm thinking of.
Rym: I might be I don't know.
Scott: I don't think you are.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: but basically There are the people who want dance rave music and there are people who want to dance to anime music Or your Japanese music in general and there seem to be two unique separate subcultures dedicated to these two types of dancing at cons and every con handles it differently.
Rym: and I guess in my opinion Katsucon has the best dance of any convention on the East Coast Because they definitely cater to the kind of dance I like and they know who's going to their con.
Rym: on Friday last year They played 80s music like bad 80s music from my childhood Scary and it was me and all my friends who all grew up in the 80s Dancing with other geeks who also grew up in the 80s at an anime con and it was fantastic.
Rym: It included the ninja rap for it.
Rym: Wow, and then Saturday They played a lot of OC remixes a lot of anime music with bass beats added You could dance to it a lot of para para max type stuff and they had big Projectors like.
Rym: they played River City Ransom stuff that you could dance to and they had projectors with two staff guys playing River City Ransom Fighting each other in time with the music.
Scott: Did he get the lead pipe?
Rym: I actually don't remember.
Rym: I was too busy dancing.
Scott: Yeah, that would do it.
Rym: Yeah And watching my poor friend who's true who met this cute girl and they're like dancing with each other and then our scary friend Scared her away.
Scott: It always seems to happen.
Rym: It was.
Rym: I'll describe that story someday But basically it was the biggest cock block in the history of the world.
Scott: I've seen bigger cock block.
Rym: I this story.
Rym: if I tell this story in detail I think you will agree that this is the biggest cock block in the world.
Rym: when a scary man Runs up and tries to headbutt the girl you're trying to split with.
Rym: that's the end.
Scott: Yeah, it is but I've heard worse.
Scott: Believe me I actually have heard worse.
Rym: Now Otakon seems to definitely tend to more more toward the rave aspects.
Scott: Yeah, well you thing is if it's not an anime convention, you know.
Scott: If it's any other kind of convention and they have some dance of some sort, you know, it's just rave is what you do.
Scott: There's not.
Scott: you know other conventions don't have a type of music associated with them.
Scott: Yeah, you can't really play D&D music at a gaming convention.
Scott: It just doesn't you know.
Rym: I mean we went.
Rym: I went to or we all went to a penguin con a Linux convention in Michigan and They had a dance and they played mostly 80s music that we'd recognize And like the time warp and all that freaky stuff that people at those kind of cons like to dance to.
Scott: But it wasn't like they could play Linux music.
Rym: They could play DCSS.
Scott: I guess they could but that's not very dancing if you know what I mean the hell right paren right paren.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so But an anime conventions.
Scott: they can play anime music if they want and that's what we prefer because you know What's the point.
Scott: I can go if I want to go to a rave I can go to a rave out anywhere Anytime, you know I'm coming to this convention is because it's it's about anime and I like anime and I like anime music And that's what I want to.
Scott: you know dance to and I know that you know It'll be easier to find cool people if they're also dancing to that because that's what cool people will do if you have a rave.
Scott: That's what drags in all kinds of ne'er-do-wells and such.
Rym: Yeah, well part of the problem with I guess very large conventions is that the dance is pretty much an unmitigated Disaster in terms of maintenance planning and security.
Rym: There's just no way to actually police it and there's just crazy people running around swinging Joe's dark glow sticks around on sticks or strings and People just like laying in the back asleep getting stepped on or people to stand in the middle of dance floor not even dancing.
Scott: Yeah, I hate when dancers gets you crowd and you can't do anything except bounce up and down.
Scott: That's just like alright I'm out of here.
Rym: see I'm fine with a really crowded dance floor if everyone's actually dancing But when it's ten people standing in a circle or God circles, don't even get me started on circles.
Scott: Yeah One guy who can like do a backflip is in the middle of the circle just backflipping Repeatedly will?
Rym: everyone stands around in a circle just kind of shimmying Just watching the guy ask any professional DJ or professional lighting dude for a cop for any sort of dance club.
Rym: Circles are the end of your dance.
Rym: if circles are forming it means you fucked up and the music is not danceable Or the people at your dance just suck.
Scott: It is usually the people sucking.
Rym: I mean there's nothing wrong with someone showing off their bad b-boy skills But not in the middle of the dance floor preventing all of us who are trying to actually dance.
Scott: Yeah, that's agreed, but the key to succeeding at a dance is Don't don't worry about your eyes.
Scott: Don't worry about your ears.
Scott: We're about your nose.
Scott: if you smells bad Move your feet to somewhere else.
Rym: Good God, you can smell Otakon's dance from halfway across the convention center.
Scott: It's really nasty like The guys who are swinging the glow sticks.
Scott: Yeah, they should put some deodorant in them glow sticks and then Crack them open and pour them on the pits.
Scott: cuz god damn.
Scott: you know these people who didn't shower since the morning or possibly the previous day and They're basically non-stop moving their bodies sweating all over the place.
Scott: They're not stopping and there's a whole bunch of them in a really crowded room with poor ventilation.
Rym: Now don't let that dissuade you.
Rym: maybe it'll dissuade you from Otakon's dance But in general con dances even if you're kind of shy or you're afraid of dancing or you think you look silly.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Go you'll have an amazing time.
Scott: Yeah If the only reason you're not dancing is you think you'll look silly just look around.
Scott: Yeah, not like a nightclub where you know people kind of know how to dance or they pretend to.
Scott: You know, whatever.
Scott: This is a bunch of nerds.
Scott: They all look silly.
Scott: No one cares.
Scott: No one's looking at you You know.
Rym: And I see.
Rym: you see that bad b-boy in the middle of a circle and he looks like he's doing something crazy and complex with A Joe stick jar up up.
Rym: Why don't keep saying Joe stick?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: because Oh because of Tokyo Joe.
Rym: All right Yeah, that's what we used to call those types.
Rym: Yeah, but they got a glow stick and they're doing something crazy with it And it looks really awesome.
Rym: No, it's not if if you turn the strobe light off He's just kind of moving his hand around in a circle and it's something anyone can do with them with zero practice.
Scott: Yeah, don't be intimidated.
Rym: That's the key cuz go in flail your arms meet a cute girl or cute guy and just dance with him.
Scott: Yep, and trust me anyone there who's not already dancing with someone wants to dance with someone Yes of the opposite sex.
Scott: and if they don't want to dance with the opposite sex They'll just tell you because gay people are cool like that.
Rym: Yeah anime cons are Great places to meet compatible people.
Rym: if you're a geek and You're at a con and you see a cute girl go over there dance with her play DDR with her or something.
Scott: The real key is just to have social skills because or and not smell.
Scott: if you don't smell You're not ugly and you have any amount of social grace any amount at all?
Scott: of course, you know, I guess that's sort of false because you either have grace or you don't.
Rym: but I Have grace I don't want grace.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, but if you have any social skills whatsoever You know and there's a common interest duh, you're at the same convention about the same thing.
Rym: There's already a common interest cuz that's the first like barrier most shy people seem to have over actually getting up the nuts to go Ask a girl out or do you want to dance with me and girls too?
Rym: I'm just using the guy example.
Rym: cuz I'm a guy.
Rym: is that you know, what do I say?
Rym: It's an anime con.
Rym: talk about how much you hate Shinji.
Rym: Yeah, you've all seen the same shows.
Scott: or hey, they're playing this great anime song.
Scott: go up and be like, dude I love this song blah blah blah blah blah and start singing it.
Scott: Maybe they'll start singing it.
Scott: cuz trust me girls anime cons love to sing songs.
Rym: Yeah I mean God.
Rym: we used to run dances or anime music nights.
Rym: We call them at our club at RIT and whenever we play that frickin Inuyasha song I want to change the world.
Scott: that's an Inuyasha song.
Rym: Yeah Frickin the girls there would scream it at the top of their lungs.
Scott: if you sing it with them.
Scott: They will like you.
Scott: Yes, they will like you as long as you don't sing it like.
Scott: How is that?
Scott: I tried to make a painful noise without making it loud.
Rym: you just sounded like the cheat.
Scott: Yeah, yeah the cheat.
Scott: he can totally rock the house with his switchlight raves light switch raves, yeah, so After you're done with the dance and you go back to your room and take a shower.
Rym: you got to worry about how to leave the convention on Sunday, yes, and Basically, this is very critical in the sense that if you do not do it Like I said earlier and you do not do it.
Rym: Well, you will lose your Sunday.
Scott: Now Sunday is an important con day.
Scott: This is the last day for the dealers room Which is when they'll be mad sales Because dealers will be trying to get rid of all their stuff that they brought with them because the less they have to bring back They can might be able to get a smaller truck and they save money, you know, yes
Rym: You'll find deals like our friend Scott Johnson.
Rym: He just wanders around to every bin where someone's like five DVDs for five bucks get these out of my store.
Scott: Yeah I'll just buy them all over spent a lot of money to get their dealers table at Otakon so they need to.
Scott: they're gonna sell as much there as they Can to get their money's worth, you know, you know, they bring it back to this store.
Scott: They basically lost money in some sort of indirect way.
Scott: So they're desperate to sell whatever they can and on Sunday when it's the last day You can freakin rake it in if you know what you're doing.
Rym: Yep Don't be afraid to haggle.
Rym: just if you see something you can't afford.
Rym: just ask them if they'll sell to you for five bucks Less if you'll pay cash.
Scott: Yeah, the only real reason to buy something before Sunday is if it's really, you know You might you know have trouble carrying it or something.
Scott: There's some sort of situation or it's gonna sell out right away.
Rym: cars a cactuar.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah way back We always wanted a cactuar plushie and they hadn't been manufactured for a while and they definitely weren't being sold in the u.s.
Rym: Legitimately.
Rym: and One day we saw one at the con and this dealer this dealer guy who was like wearing stilts We're standing there holding it and we ran over like can we buy your cactuar?
Rym: can about your cactuar.
Rym: and he looked at us And he hugged it close to his chest and he shook his head.
Scott: That's cuz it was his and not for sale.
Rym: Yeah bastard fast forward two years into the future I'm at katsucon and I look and I see this little bin and then this bin.
Rym: I see a cactuar and I Freak out.
Rym: I reached to grab it and my friend Bruce is right there next to me who also wanted.
Rym: one reaches to grab it And we're standing there and we're holding this cactuar.
Rym: It's ultra rare plushie and we're looking at each other and he's in the Navy so he can pretty much just kill me and take it.
Rym: and Then we look and there's another cactuar.
Rym: there were in fact three in the entire convention and we bought them both and the third one sold immediately to some guy who was standing right there and the whole rest of the con.
Rym: Everyone kept asking us where we got the cactuars and we told him yeah that dealer.
Rym: Sunday we run into that dealer and he sees the cactuars and he says and I quote So you're the bastards, you know, how many people have been asking me for freaking cactuars?
Scott: Yeah, that's what happens if you get something ultra rare.
Rym: They're not that rare anymore.
Rym: It looks like they remade him.
Scott: They remade him, but I think those are a different version.
Scott: They're not the exact same cactuar.
Scott: I'll say yeah I like the one we've got the best.
Scott: the other ones are not so good.
Rym: Our friend Alex did the same thing with a little Tonberry, but I think he ordered it online somewhere.
Scott: actually Oh, he went to the dealer and the dealer didn't have something he wanted.
Scott: So he said do you have this and the guy says no But I have it at my store and the guy the dealer went to his store that night got it and brought it back To the con so Alex could pick it up for him the next day.
Rym: Yeah, talk to the dealers.
Rym: They'll work with you.
Scott: Yeah, so like if a guy is every plushie in the known universe like I remember There was a these pac-man and you would put batteries in them and they're the pac-man ghosts and they would walk around and they're really Cool, but they didn't have green.
Scott: so I was like do you have green?
Scott: and they were like, you know If they did if they made green we'd have it.
Scott: So I found out they didn't make green.
Scott: But you know what if they?
Scott: If they would have made green and they just didn't have one there they would have brought one for me.
Rym: Now to get back on to the actual advice part instead of us reminiscing Leaving the con on Sunday Basically, you have to forego sleep.
Rym: Just remember that you can sleep Sunday night when you get home.
Rym: You can sleep later.
Rym: Don't sleep Sunday morning and don't sleep in most hotels make you check out around noon So you got to be out of the room and paid by noon and the cons usually end early afternoon.
Scott: Very few of them go all day Sunday.
Rym: now that in itself doesn't sound so bad.
Rym: Like alright you get up at say, you know 11 get out of the room check out and go to the con.
Rym: No first off.
Rym: Everyone else has the same idea.
Rym: So you'll get real.
Rym: you'll be ready to leave your room.
Rym: You try to go downstairs and there will be an infinite number of fanboys standing around every elevator.
Rym: Half of them will break from the strain.
Rym: It takes about two and a half hours to actually check out of a crowded convention hotel Mm-hmm.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: So basically what you have to do is seriously get up at like 6 in the morning Gather all your stuff and if everyone else in the room socks and isn't gonna do it do it on your own.
Rym: Get all your stuff put it on your car pay Wherever you have to pay and then get the hell out of that room and go.
Scott: enjoy the convention Mm-hmm cons on Sunday.
Scott: They start at 8 a.m.
Scott: Or whatever, you know, and if you wait until like, you know Noon to get your stuff out of your room.
Scott: You basically missed 8 to noon.
Scott: That's 4 hours.
Rym: Just threw away if you check out by 9 a.m It'll take you about 45 minutes to check out and clear out the room and all that stuff.
Rym: If you try to check out around 11 or noon, it'll take you about an hour and a half Maybe two hours.
Scott: Now make sure that you go over that room and you make sure absolutely No, nothing is left in there because people will leave shit there.
Scott: I guarantee it.
Rym: Yeah, we've had people leave shoes.
Rym: We told you about all that in another podcast.
Rym: Yeah, I think we did but basically keep your stuff together and worry about your own stuff first.
Rym: If you kept all your stuff in a spot, like we told you before you probably have much trouble unless someone moved it.
Scott: Someone moved it.
Scott: God help them.
Rym: And If you're the one who paid for the room and you didn't collect money yet You're screwed.
Rym: collect the money before you even let people into that room.
Rym: Yeah There's no way you're gonna hunt everyone down and collect all that money while you're checking out.
Rym: Also, if you need the cash to check out don't make the mistake.
Rym: We did the first time we ever got a hotel room at a big con.
Rym: Sure, everyone paid me before it was time to check out.
Rym: Most of them wrote me a check.
Rym: So I'm standing where means got her standing at the checkout desk of the hotel.
Rym: We've got like eight checks with us for varying amounts of money, but no cash to actually pay.
Scott: Yeah, the hotels don't like that.
Scott: They can't really take a check from you Yeah, and if you don't have a nice credit card then they're gonna yell you.
Rym: yeah, of course now We have a million credit cards.
Rym: You actually have money but back then we didn't have money.
Rym: Now Sunday at the con there's actually a lot going on but not so much for the events.
Rym: Sunday is generally a really laid-back day and you'll usually just run into all the people you might have seen once or tries During the con and just chill with them.
Scott: Mm-hmm That's a hanging out that you definitely don't want to miss out on.
Rym: Yep one year we just sat in a lobby and played a Puerto Rico German board game until they kicked us out of the convention center and a Bunch of people came over and joined in and talked to us and it was just fun.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And one thing I can highly highly recommend is that most cons have some sort of closing ceremonies or feedback session.
Rym: They are usually hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, the opening ceremonies are usually like lame Like no one goes to them for a reason.
Rym: Yeah anime central is really the only con I've ever seen that had a funny opening ceremony.
Scott: But at the closing ceremonies all the con staff they're like done doing all the work they have to do.
Scott: They're just like yeah, whatever.
Scott: It's all over.
Scott: I don't care anymore.
Scott: They have.
Scott: no they haven't had enough sleep.
Rym: You know back panels are our exquisite treasures to reminisce forever.
Rym: I wish someone recorded them all the what the first con feedback panel we ever went to.
Rym: we went to it on a lark.
Rym: It had everything.
Rym: it had stupid fanboys complaining about things that no one except stupid fanboys would care about and con staff telling them to You know be quiet and just ignore not worry about it.
Rym: It had crazy cosplay people complaining about the cosplay in ways that I didn't think people could complain about cosplays.
Rym: It had the staff actually answering questions.
Rym: We had very logically and concisely.
Rym: What was it you asked about?
Rym: chairs at the concert, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why did the concert have chairs?
Scott: Why wasn't it just general admission?
Scott: and the guy was like I wanted to be general admission so bad But I couldn't do it and I'm like as long as I know you wanted it to be so bad.
Scott: It's okay Yep, and then like he came over to me and he was like, oh my god You know if the guy comes over to you after answering your question officially to talk to you more That means your question is probably good.
Rym: Now last and least and we're gonna do a whole show on this someday because it applies to life in general.
Rym: But we're gonna talk about it now specifically from a con perspective drama.
Scott: Drama is only caused by stupidity.
Scott: if there is no stupidity there can be no drama by definition.
Rym: Yep, we started talking about it earlier.
Rym: We got sidetracked, but basically You can be friends with people who have drama surrounding them But and you can have fun with them at a convention But if they're in your room, you're gonna have to deal with their drama.
Rym: If you have friends who are prone to drama not to be mean, but have them stay with someone else.
Rym: You'll thank yourself later.
Scott: I mean this drama can range from two people in your room, you know Or maybe one person in your room Just having a fight with someone and being all mopey or being all grunty around your room to like I don't know someone in the room Doing it and then trying to kill themselves and God knows that kind of crazy stuff.
Rym: Yeah, we had some friends Who basically to cut a long and embarrassing and kind of scary story short?
Rym: This dude like took a stole a cosplay costume from some another friend of ours who was doing a cosplay or something and none of these people were in our room and it basically came down to one person's older brother appearing and Actively trying to beat to death the said person who took the cosplay object.
Scott: It was an asshole doing something assholish because he was stupid and then a stupid guy Deciding to try to solve him problem with violence instead of police because he was stupid and Drama ensued.
Scott: stupidity plus stupidity equals drama.
Rym: now Luckily half the people who were in that room I have to saw her who were involved in that Said hey, we want to stay with rumin Scott this year because there's no drama with them ever.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So think about it.
Scott: There was a drama involving what maybe three or four people total, right?
Rym: And it almost ruined the con for all of them.
Scott: Yeah, and in the room with those people were like in their group were like eight people total.
Scott: So four people almost had their cons ruined by four people who were all dumb.
Scott: So those four people if they would have stayed with us with our drama listeners, they would have been all set.
Scott: Yeah, so if you get caught with drama just run away.
Rym: run away and don't involve yourself with it whatsoever Like if a guy and a girl who you're friends with are dating But they're in the middle of a bad row and they're fighting with each other all the time.
Rym: You don't want them in the room because conventions add stress and stress causes violent breakup in the middle of your Saturday night party Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, that would be scary.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there have been situations where someone was just kicked out of their room and didn't have anywhere to stay for the night.
Rym: What other stupid stories have we heard?
Rym: people get drunk and pass out and almost die?
Scott: People spend all their money and then start begging for it God.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if basically this really applies to the people who run the rooms don't let people who have drama stay in your room With you.
Rym: and of course, I don't know how that'll help because then the people who have drama I don't know where they stay.
Scott: I guess Other they stay alone or they don't come.
Scott: if they don't come it makes the convention better because then more drama less people come.
Scott: yeah You know, it's all good.
Scott: Eventually, we'll get rid of all the stupid people and then the common cons will be perfect with no drama whatsoever.
Rym: Well, I mean, I guess we it's partly that we've been lucky and to that We have a really good group of friends and like even primary friends and peripheral friends.
Rym: They're all really cool.
Rym: Like we leave all our money and wallets out in the room No one even like considers the idea that someone would steal anything.
Rym: But yet I hear stories from people who like someone stole 20 bucks out of the hotel fund before they left.
Scott: Yeah Now Another thing is no matter how nice or helpful or whatever you think you're doing Don't try to help solve a drama.
Scott: Don't try to avert a drama.
Scott: Don't try to do anything to it because you know what.
Scott: as soon as you put your hand in there to try to change it For better for worse you're now a part of it.
Rym: It's like when two dogs are fighting and you try to break them up and then they both bite you.
Scott: Yeah, now you got to worry because if you're a smart guy like us, right?
Scott: Let's say we let's say it was Let's say it was me Rym and three other people and you're one of the three other people and the two other people that I haven't mentioned Get in a fight and you try to help them.
Scott: when we cast away those two people We're casting away you with them is because you're attached.
Rym: Yep, basically in every group social group of people There are designated problem solvers.
Rym: It just seems to happen.
Rym: naturally like there's always one or two people who whenever there's shit that goes down they're the one who steps up deals with it and meters out the consequences and Our group we tend to be those people Mm-hmm, so find someone like that in your group.
Rym: If two people are fighting and you're not a hundred percent confident that you can deal with it Don't deal with it Let someone else deal with it or walk away or just vow to never let them stay with you again.
Scott: I got nothing to do.
Scott: That's all I gotta say.
Rym: I guess the only contradiction to that advice is that if there's a dangerous situation deal with it immediately.
Rym: Yes, of course I mean if you have to call the police if something bad happens at a con don't pretend it'll go away Unless it's something minor and stupid.
Rym: if there's a real problem.
Rym: Just let a professional handle it.
Scott: Yeah, and even though you might look like an idiot There's nothing wrong with yelling really loud at the convention for security or con staff.
Rym: Yes going on at Otakon.
Rym: if you yell for security special ops is there in a second?
Scott: Yeah, you know people might look at you be like hey you were yelling.
Scott: that was weird and you know You'll get attention, but you'll fix whatever was fixing.
Scott: if it was needed do it.
Rym: Yep now if you're the kind of person who's confident to deal with these situations and you think that you have enough authority over your friends in That circumstance to deal with the problem go for it, but be warned that that's a very dangerous road to follow.
Rym: Mmm, I mean I've personally intervened in some situations like that before both in my official capacity as you know Running an anime club back in the day and just as my Unofficial position of I happen to be there and in both cases no matter how well you think you're handling it There's always something you're not thinking about or there's just there's too much stupidity around.
Rym: you're gonna get caught in it.
Scott: It's time for the fun analogy game if someone's about to fall off a cliff And you try to reach your hand over to grab them and catch them and pull them back up You might end up falling down.
Scott: Yep, so don't let drama ruin the convention.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the only real advice there is that Either don't let people who have drama come with you, and if they do let their drama burn them and not you mm-hmm.
Rym: So I think we've pretty much run out of useful things to talk about for a series on convention So I'll probably end it here.
Scott: great now.
Scott: What are we gonna do next?
Rym: Maybe we just do one where you just tell stories from conventions We got.
Rym: it's not like we don't have an infinite number of them.
Scott: Yeah, well the convention season starting about now We've got some February cons coming up.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We're not doing anything at it, but I'm at least gonna be at Katsucon.
Scott: Yeah, and I think I'm almost certain I go into the New York comic-con and possibly uber khan.
Rym: Yeah, I think we're both going to uber khan unless it conflicts with things.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna be speaking doing at least one panel at an amazement in May.
Rym: I think mm-hmm There's some tentative news that we might be doing GeekNights live at Otakon.
Rym: maybe we mentioned that in the forums a while ago.
Scott: Yeah, that's why you should keep checking out the forums cuz you'd find out cool stuff like the fact that this podcast is available yesterday.
Scott: So if you're not checking our website in your forums, you're you're getting stuff a little slow there.
Rym: Yeah times cuz we actually got the news that we're most likely going to be doing many GeekNights things at Otakon About a week ago and everyone who reads the forums knows about it, but you guys don't Mm-hmm.
Scott: So if you want to check us out just go to Otakon and you'll meet us a hundred percent guarantee it.
Rym: Yeah, oh, we'll also be at Tora Khan at RIT in Rochester.
Rym: Oh, yeah they don't have the website up yet, but I'll yell at him about that.
Scott: and That's not all.
Scott: we might go to some more conventions as we decide to.
Rym: Yeah, because now that we have money and we're not poor college kids We go to almost any convention that's worth going to.
Rym: that we can afford to.
Scott: Yep, according to the rules we talked about three podcasts ago.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well two podcasts ago Because I used to go to anime central and I love that con It's still on my list of one of my favorite cons, but Chicago is too far away from New York City.
Rym: It's real flying socks.
Scott: It's too expensive.
Rym: Yeah, though a son was really worth it.
Rym: I had some damn good times there.
Scott: So go there.
Scott: Yeah I'm going to PAX.
Rym: Oh, we've always wanted to go to PAX.
Rym: It's just a matter of you know in there.
Scott: the one thing that really keeps you from going to PAX is the East Coast PAX rumor.
Rym: Yeah, if there's an East Coast pet well, actually we had a plan that packs is the penny arcade Expo if you don't know.
Rym: and We decided one year that we were gonna go to PAX.
Rym: and because our tradition as our group of friends is generally we go to Otakon and then we are good friend.
Rym: Scott Johnson has a beach house in Wildwood, New Jersey And we'll go there then for like the next week afterward and just chill and reminisce about the con and swim.
Rym: And we decided that we were gonna get a bunch of sand and seawater from the East Coast.
Rym: And if we ever went to PAX, we were going to anoint Gabe and Tycho either forcibly or Maybe with some sort of permission depending on the circumstances
Scott: Mm-hmm, but They did come to the East Coast actually relatively recently again for I think the second or third time But they went to the Baltimore comic-con, which we couldn't go to Con but it was real small.
Rym: Yeah I mean Otakon takes up the entire Baltimore Convention Center and more The Baltimore comic-con takes up like couple of rooms and the convention is smaller than the dealers room of Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, so we didn't go to that.
Scott: and then I think they went to some other.
Scott: I think they went to MIT and spoke or something, but we didn't go to that either.
Scott: Yeah, we're actually busy.
Rym: There's a reason why we didn't go.
Scott: Yeah, but you know those bastards they were gonna come to Otakon once and they didn't.
Rym: Yeah that Otakon we were at.
Rym: we expected him to be there but now they backed out last minute.
Scott: Well, I knew they canceled right before the con but you know still bastards We'll get them one day one day.
Rym: Yeah in closing go to conventions.
Rym: They're awesome.
Rym: Mm-hmm I don't know what else I can say There and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.