Rym: It's Tuesday, February 14th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about our experience at UberCon.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So, today, in lieu of doing our normal bit of having news and all that sort of thing, we're just going to cover our experiences at UberCon.
Scott: Expect this to happen for many, many weeks to come as we go to many, many cons, and thus devote entire shows to them.
Rym: Yes, and not all cons get a whole show, but, UberCon, one day of UberCon was enough to give us an entire show.
Scott: Mostly because we did some awesome things there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So UberCon, for those of you who may not know, is a gaming convention primarily.
Scott: It happens, I think, two times a year?
Rym: Yep, twice a year, usually in the wintery time.
Rym: It's in North Jersey, near the Meadowlands, and it's about an hour, hour and a half drive for us, so we just went for the day of Saturday.
Rym: We didn't want to get a hotel room, we didn't want a pre-reg or anything.
Scott: It was much cheaper that way.
Scott: I mean, it was still forty bucks for a day, which is quite a bit considering some cons are forty dollars for all the three days.
Scott: But, it was worth it.
Scott: Well, gaming cons- Especially since we didn't pay for hotels or anything.
Rym: In general, gaming cons tend to be more expensive than any other type of con, just because they actually provide a lot more to you.
Rym: There's not so much of that people milling around doing nothing.
Rym: Everyone there wants to be doing something, or they get pissed.
Scott: Mm-hmm, that's true.
Rym: You also gotta buy a lot more equipment.
Rym: A lot more stuff, all that sort of thing.
Scott: You know, like games.
Scott: And there's a lot more insurance because games and things get broken and all kinds of crap.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, whatever.
Rym: So we drove down there, we registered, and registration was probably the most painless registration I've ever had of any con ever.
Rym: We just walked in, I didn't have to do anything.
Rym: I said my name, they said, "Oh, you've been here
Rym: before."
Rym: And they just took my money and gave me another badge.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: The best part was I hadn't been there before, so I had to fill a little piece of paper.
Scott: And then they took my money and gave me a badge.
Scott: Actually, they almost forgot to take my money, but I reminded them.
Scott: But, yeah, apparently the guy who is a, I forgot his name.
Rym: Yeah, but he's the head of Stonekeep.
Scott: Yeah, Stonekeep, I think, registration, Convention Registration Solutions or something.
Rym: Yeah, they're basically a little company that makes registration stuff for conventions.
Scott: Well, they made a registration solution.
Rym: Yeah, they provide registration services.
Scott: Yeah, so they have a system of taking names and money and printing out these awesome real cards for conventions.
Scott: And if you won't have a convention, you can hire them to do it for you.
Rym: And he seems to do a very good job.
Rym: I mean, I know Otakon considered using them in the past and turned them down, and I really don't know why, but I'm real impressed with the way they do their business.
Scott: I really like the cards, the quality of the cards and the quality of the computer setup.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The remembering of previous conventions, I think that's all really, really cool, and that's the way it should be.
Rym: Plus, the guy who was running all this was sitting around, and we ended up having food with him for dinner, and he's a really cool dude.
Rym: I can't believe I forgot his name.
Scott: Yeah, he went to RIT also.
Rym: Yeah, like before we were even born.
Scott: Yeah, he went to RIT in 1982, and we were born in 1982, and we went to RIT in 2000.
Rym: He's describing buildings as new that we thought of as the old crap buildings they were going to get rid of.
Scott: Yeah, and he was in Computer Science House like the second or third year of it.
Rym: Yep, it was fun.
Rym: I can't believe I forgot his name, but I don't feel bad because I forgot the names of most of the people I met at this con.
Rym: And I only remember the two I'm going to mention because I have their business cards in front of me.
Scott: Yeah, we should have taken his business card.
Scott: I'm sure he can find it at his website.
Scott: I think it was at stonekeep.com or something like that.
Rym: Yeah, I'll find him.
Scott: If it's not stonekeep.com and there's something bad at stonekeep.com, don't blame me.
Rym: Yeah, so we go in then, and I guess I knew what to expect because I've been to gaming cons before, but I think Scott and our friend Peter came with us.
Rym: We were a little bit underwhelmed at first.
Scott: Well, I knew what was going to go on there, but it was much smaller than I thought it would be.
Rym: Just a few rooms.
Scott: Yeah, I figured there would be a lot more... I mean, the gaming library, like the pile of board games, was about the size I expected, but the number of tables and space was a lot less than I thought.
Rym: Yeah, well, the main reason for that was simply that this con moved hotels, and this hotel wasn't as good as the previous hotel, in my opinion.
Scott: Yeah, this hotel, I mean, it looked like they had panels in the pool.
Rym: Yeah, they really did have panels in the pool.
Scott: So that's not good at all.
Rym: They used pretty much every room they could use, and every game we played, it was just a cacophony constantly.
Rym: We failed at learning to play a game, a first for us, because of that, which we'll get into later.
Scott: Yeah, so the first thing we did was we were supposed to be a burning wheel demo at 10, and that's what we really wanted to do, was try out this burning wheel RPG system.
Rym: Yeah, we've mentioned a lot, but it's something that I demoed the combat for last year at UberCon with the same dude, Luke Crane, and I thought it was awesome.
Rym: And this year, since I was bringing two of my friends with me, I figured, "Alright, let's do it with YouTube so you can see how awesome it was, and I won't just feel like I'm
Rym: crazy.".
Scott: Yep, so it was supposed to be at 10, I go at 10, and the guy said, he was doing it for two other guys, and he said, "Come back at
Scott: 10.30.".
Scott: So we hung out around, you know, looking around the con, which took about five minutes.
Rym: Yeah, we ran across many scary people.
Scott: That's what gaming cons have, scary people.
Rym: I mean, I guess I'm really used to anime cons, and I forget, but in an anime con, I'd say the ratio of cool people to normal people to scary people is heavily weighted toward cool and normal people.
Scott: I'd say for every 10 people at an anime con, you'll have one or two cool people.
Rym: By cool, we mean, like, you know, someone you go, "Oh, that's that guy," something like that.
Scott: Yeah, maybe five or six, you know, normal people, and then, like, one or two schlubby, nasty people.
Rym: There were quite a number of quite large individuals with quite odiferous zones of control wandering about like blimps.
Scott: I'd say the con, the gaming con is pretty much half disgusting people, half not disgusting people.
Scott: And cool people, a handful.
Rym: Yeah, well, we ran across, like, there was a lot of cool things, like, I forget his name, but one of the writers who kind of took over the work of Lovecraft after he died.
Scott: He was a guest of the con, I think.
Scott: He's C.J.
Scott: Henderson, I think.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah, that was his name.
Rym: Cool dude, he was like, "Hey, check out my books,
Rym: woo.".
Rym: And then we ran into this thing called Scared on Staten Island.
Scott: Now, at first I thought it might be like, "Ooh, you go there and, you know, you have fun in some old building or
Scott: something.".
Rym: Yeah, they had this video and it showed people, like, wandering around with little electronic devices, looking for things.
Rym: It looked like some sort of cool LARP-type infiltration thing.
Rym: Yeah, I thought
Scott: it was maybe like a LARP, like, that involved some sort of ghosts, and, like, you would carry these devices around, and then they set up things in the building on Staten Island to make them go off, to make you think there are ghosts there, and then you're supposed to do stuff based on that.
Rym: Yeah, so we stood there watching the video to see what it was all about, and you know what?
Rym: Just for Andy, it's just frickin', they think there's ghosts and they're hunting them, they're like paranormal investigator bullshit.
Scott: You know, it didn't even seem like the people selling it actually thought there were ghosts.
Scott: It just seemed like they wanted you to think there were ghosts, and they were selling some amusement thing.
Rym: Yeah, they talked a lot about the equipment they used to detect ghosts, and oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, it was just a bunch of bullshit trying to take money from people, you know.
Rym: I mean, I won't blame UberCon, because I guess anyone who pays them money will get some space there.
Scott: Yeah, it seemed like they paid a lot of money and they weren't getting a lot of attention, so I think that worked out well.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Yeah, so if you see anything called Scared on Staten Island or Scared Anywhere, and it looks like that, don't do it.
Scott: It's just a waste of your money.
Scott: So, then we did the Burning Wheel demo.
Rym: Yeah, and it was awesome.
Scott: Very awesome.
Rym: Now we're gonna do a whole show separate on Burning Wheel at some point, because there's just too much to say about it, and we'd really like to get the creator of it on the show.
Scott: And we'd like to get our books.
Rym: Yes, we actually, we all ordered the books for Burning Wheel the day after we got back from the con.
Rym: We didn't order them that night for reasons that we'll get into at the end of this show.
Scott: So we're gonna avoid talking about the system itself, and we'll just talk about the game we actually played, and what happened in those games.
Scott: So, the demo was three characters, which just fit us like, whoa.
Rym: Yeah, it was a conniving little scrawny thief guy, Scott.
Scott: It wasn't a scrawny thief guy, it was a- Two little knives!
Rym: You could maybe poke me a little bit.
Scott: It was a wicked knife criminal, like, guy.
Rym: Yeah, some criminal.
Scott: On his path, like, if he got levels, I guess, whatever it is, he would have become like a mafia something.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I was a froofy elf trying to get back the sword of his father.
Scott: Froofy elf.
Rym: And our friend Pete was a freaking dwarf with a big sword who also wanted the other sword.
Scott: It's the same as always.
Rym: Yeah, and basically, Luke Crane, the guy who made Burning Wheel, was running these demos.
Scott: I'm pretty sure he's the guy who made it.
Rym: Yeah, he is.
Rym: And he set up this demo, basically, just to kinda show off how the system works.
Rym: And it was set up so that there was conflict in the party right away.
Rym: All three of us had goals, only one of us was gonna get our goal, and it showed us the various systems within the game that allow conflict between characters or role players to be resolved.
Rym: And it worked really well.
Scott: All too well.
Scott: I guess that's what happens when something is, you know, set up.
Rym: Well, I think one thing that really helped it is that Luke is one hell of a dungeon master, and he really gets into it.
Scott: Yeah, he definitely does get all over it, but at the same time, it makes it seem like being the GM in a Burning Wheel game is either a whole lot of work, or like you kinda have to get into it, or else it, you know.
Rym: Well, it depends a lot on what you're doing, 'cause I could see a game of Burning Wheel where you don't even need a GM.
Scott: Yeah, it's like at one hand you can go with a lazy GM, but on the other hand, the GM needs to be awesome and know everything about the game in order, you know, it's kind of a weird, you know, I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, part of that might be the fact that we don't know the system yet.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So we definitely relied on him to tell us when to pick up dice.
Scott: Well, we know it, we just don't know all the details.
Scott: We know the very general, we know enough to play if the GM can handle everything else for us.
Rym: But we don't know, like, alright, when is this skill applicable, how many dice do I pick up and throw against this, how many successes do I need, blah blah blah.
Scott: It seemed like when this skill is applicable is sort of subjective to me.
Rym: Yeah, well, I saw a lot of times, I mean, here's an example of something that happened.
Rym: Most role-playing game systems seem to be set up where the only game mechanic that is used to resolve conflicts other than role-playing is combat, fighting with people.
Rym: Imagine if there were a combat-like system for characters arguing with each other.
Scott: So you can resolve conflicts non-violently with dice and role-playing combined.
Rym: It, we'll explain that in greater detail, but it basically- In some other show, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, the main thing this seems to do is that, one, I tend to play, I'm very charismatic, I role-play really well, I'm not trying to, you know, oh, but yeah.
Rym: And I often would end up playing a character with a very low charisma, especially at cons or whatever.
Rym: But I'd end up talking circles around someone else and playing a character that had a much higher charisma than my character actually had.
Rym: This prevents all that bullshit, and you're, you can only do what your character can do.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, uh, what happened in the game first?
Scott: I just, they were arguing about who should take the sword and I just went and took it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And then they tried to physically stop me.
Rym: And he ran away.
Scott: And I ran away, and then I couldn't run away all the way, and get it, escape.
Rym: And then we had the argument, and this is when the dice came out.
Rym: It was me, the elf, and Pete the dwarf, arguing within the confines of this game mechanic on who should actually, who is the rightful owner of the sword.
Rym: And the way it works, basically, to simplify really, really, really broadly, is that you make a point, or a butler or whatever, and you have to role-play it a little bit, but if you make a point, no matter what you say, it only counts as a point action.
Rym: Like, point, it's my fucking sword, you asshole.
Rym: Or point, something cool that I say in a first-person role-playing way.
Rym: Then I roll dice to see how effective that is.
Rym: But the thing is, if you're gonna make a point, or you're gonna make a rebuttal, or you're gonna make a, you know, an instigate, or whatever you're gonna do, you have to actually role-play it.
Rym: If you can't come up with it, you can't do it.
Rym: But at the same time, it doesn't matter so much how well you do it verbally, because all that matters is how well your character would have been able to do it.
Scott: And then, the other cool thing is, people can help you out.
Scott: Like, when Rym and Pete were arguing, I didn't really want either of them to win, I wanted them to just kind of bring each other down.
Scott: And, you know, like, they both hurt each other, and then I can kill whoever's left.
Scott: Easily.
Scott: You know, it's like, oh yeah, make both of you, make each other weaker, and then one guy will eventually lose, and I can pick off the weak guy, because I'm unharmed.
Scott: But, so what I did is, when they were arguing, they would make points at each other, or whatever.
Rym: And he'd help back and forth, like, he'd help Pete with a point, then he'd help me with a point, and we'd just whittle each other down that way.
Scott: And so when you help someone, you give them a dice, and it's pretty cool.
Rym: Now, the main thing, the main effect this seems to have on the game is that, whenever there's a conflict, it's broken down into incredibly abstract terms.
Rym: I mean, probably more abstract than any system I've ever played before.
Rym: Basically, if you have a conflict, character A wants X, character B wants Y, instead of having to, you know, dance around it within a system, you just, alright, open up the conflict rules, I want this, I want this, you resolve it so that now you know what the end result is.
Rym: No matter what happens, this is the result.
Rym: This is the person who will win the conflict.
Rym: And then you can roleplay it all out from there.
Rym: So you don't have to worry about technicalities, or, "Oh, if I just fail, I'll try again," like people tend to do in D&D.
Rym: It's just resolved.
Rym: Scott ran away from us, me and Pete, with the sword.
Rym: And he got away.
Rym: So we could chase him for, pretty much, over and over and over again, but he'd always get away, because we'd already resolved that, plot-wise, he'll get away.
Rym: So we have to try to resolve this in another manner.
Scott: And then we already resolved that I would not escape.
Scott: So we would roleplay me escaping a little bit.
Scott: And if we wanted to, we could roleplay me escaping a little bit more.
Scott: But I would never escape all the way, because you already found out that I'm not going to escape all the way.
Rym: So it seems to remove a lot of this meta-game kind of crap, and just forces you to play your character right there, deal with the conflict, and I really can't explain how beautiful it is, you just have to play it.
Scott: Yeah, I like how on the character sheet it says your beliefs and your instincts.
Scott: It's like, here's what you're going to do.
Scott: There's no more having a problem where you don't know what your character wants, or having to think it up.
Scott: It's right there on the paper.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, the way combat and all these things seem to work is that you have a piece of paper, and they have a piece of paper, and you choose your actions, but you choose them simultaneously with the other person knowing.
Rym: So you choose your action and the next two actions in the future.
Rym: Then you both reveal your sheets and play it out.
Rym: So it's real quick, it's real brutal.
Rym: Two people fighting with a sword does not last long, because someone gets stabbed and bleeds right away.
Scott: Stabbed in the face.
Scott: Alright, let's leave any further details for another show.
Rym: Yeah, well, we'll talk about this again at the end of this show, when we describe at least the game we played.
Rym: Because we played a demo in the morning, and then at night we played a full-on, story-based game with a whole bunch of other people.
Scott: Yeah, the demo was just for us to figure out how the system works and whether we liked it, and then the night time was actually a game of real.
Rym: Night time is the night time.
Rym: Ah, nice interruption.
Rym: Let's do some things of the day and then get back to UberCon.
Scott: So since it's, uh, it gets Tuesday, right?
Scott: So there's games, but we're not going to do any video games, really.
Scott: But I have a thing of the day related to video games.
Rym: This is actually kind of cool.
Scott: So, I don't know if you've played Kung Fu for the NES.
Scott: It's a game where this guy just basically walks sideways, and when bad guys come up to him, you punch or kick them.
Rym: It's one of the original, original Nintendo games.
Scott: Original, original, it's real hard.
Rym: Like before the MMC chips, Nintendo games.
Scott: Yeah, this ran on the same chip that, like, baseball, and, um, ice hockey, and...
Rym: Ice climbers.
Scott: Yeah, Metroid.
Scott: Well, not Metroid 1.
Rym: No, Metroid was an MMC.
Scott: Yeah, that was like one of the first ones, though.
Rym: Yes, I think it was the first one.
Rym: Anyway, anyway.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: It's really old.
Scott: And some guy took, uh, Kung Fu, and in Flash, he made Kung Fu the Remix.
Rym: It's like an OC Remix, only it's an actual remix of a video game instead of video game music.
Scott: So it plays just like Kung Fu, except the bad guy is a little different.
Scott: And he added an awesome plot with some pixel art.
Scott: And he added some new moves.
Scott: So, like, after you beat level one, you get the Haruken, and you can use it.
Scott: And it's pretty awesome.
Scott: And, like, when you jump kick guys, their heads come off.
Scott: And... yeah.
Scott: It's a whole lot, it's a lot more fun than the original Kung Fu, I'd say.
Scott: It's a little hard to control with the keyboard, but you can kind of customize the keys a little bit.
Scott: The music, I love the music a lot, because it feels like old arcade game music, you know?
Scott: That's all awesome.
Scott: I like that kind of sounding stuff.
Scott: But, uh, it's real, it's really, really hard.
Scott: Like, even on easy mode, it's hard, hard, hard, hard, hard.
Scott: I couldn't beat...
Rym: Well, good.
Rym: The original Kung Fu was hard, as well.
Scott: It's harder than the original Kung Fu, even on easy mode.
Scott: I couldn't beat more than level one.
Scott: Level two, I died.
Scott: So, um... have fun.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So, I don't know how many of you have lived with cats before, but... Well, a lot of people, a lot of the front row crew types, always laugh, "Oh, Rym, he likes the cat
Rym: girls.".
Rym: But, honestly?
Rym: I really don't like cats that much.
Scott: You like the fox girls and whatever.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But I really don't like cats that much.
Rym: I mean, I don't dislike cats, but I always get the feeling that most cats are barely aware that I even exist.
Rym: And this was fortified by having to live with some cats for a while when I was on co-op a long time ago.
Rym: But, anyway... Do you know how cats seem to react to things in strange ways?
Rym: Well, this is a video that basically proves to me that cats are automatons.
Rym: Because if you put a piece of tape on a cat in different places, the cat will... you can control the cat with tape, basically.
Rym: Just watch the video, you'll see what I mean.
Scott: I think, basically, what the video teaches us is that cats move based on their feeling and not based on looking with their eyeballs.
Scott: Like, if a cat feels a wall on its left, it'll go to the right.
Scott: So you put a piece of tape on the left side of the cat, it thinks it's touching something on the left, and it wants to get away from that, so it goes to the right.
Rym: This did remind me of our friend James and Lisa.
Rym: They had a cat named Lily.
Rym: And they would stick a little hair clip to her tail, and that was the end of her.
Rym: She couldn't walk.
Rym: As far as she was concerned, that was the end of the world, and there was a lead weight tying her tail to the ground.
Scott: Yeah, the cat would just slump on the ground and not move.
Rym: Yeah, watch the video, you'll see what we mean.
Rym: Freakin' cats.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's funny because it's Japanese, too.
Rym: Yeah, also, strangely enough, a while ago when I emerged "Update New Year's Deep World," which meant I upgraded all the stuff on my Gentoo box, sound stopped working in Flash and Google Video, and it magically started working again.
Rym: And I haven't done anything to my computer.
Scott: I think you did something with some sort--there must be some sort of blocking going on with OSS also.
Scott: Yeah, there's something, so I'm going to look at my AOS-- I don't think you can figure your DMX stuff properly.
Rym: Yeah, I'm going to look through my AOS stuff and try to figure that one out later.
Rym: Or, you know what, I won't care because I'm buying a new computer in the next month.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: But anyway-- If you're a new Bunty, you won't have those problems, theoretically.
Rym: Yeah, well, part of the reason I use Gentoo on this box is that this box is slow as shit anyway.
Scott: Mm.
Rym: Bunty is not any slower or faster than-- But anyway, so after the Burning Wheel demo, we went to a mall nearby to try to get some food.
Scott: I got some food at this Italian place, got a chicken parm sandwich for five bucks.
Rym: Yeah, now Pete and I did much better, because this is a--you know how almost every mall food court now is the same?
Rym: They've got that Chinese place, and next to it, the Cajun food place that is the same food the Chinese food place has?
Scott: Not every mall food court, but all mall food courts that have been invaded by that company are all the same.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, this is an old-school food court.
Scott: It's not really old school, it just hasn't been invaded by that company.
Rym: It's old school compared to this company, which seems to be spreading like wildfire.
Rym: Mm.
Rym: And they had this one little Greek diner-type place in it.
Rym: And Pete and I went there, and we got gyros.
Rym: And these were the best gyros we've ever had in our lives.
Rym: He had a giant flank of meat, and he cut pieces off of it, put them over a fire, and then gave them to us.
Scott: It's called shawarma.
Scott: It's an Israel in every single block.
Scott: And in Israel, it looked a lot better than his solid-colored piece of meat, let me tell you.
Rym: Yeah, well, what do you want?
Rym: We're not in Israel.
Rym: You're lucky to see anything like that.
Scott: I know.
Rym: And you know that the Greeks probably call it something else.
Scott: Well, it's, you know, it's a big leg of a lamb.
Scott: It's a lamb on a stick that spins around vertically.
Rym: The point is, we got good food.
Rym: But at the mall, we ran into some scary UberCon types.
Scott: It looked like this normal little girl, I guess.
Scott: She looked like the kind of girl you see at an anime con.
Rym: Yeah, kind of cute.
Rym: Definitely young.
Rym: I mean, probably a decade younger than me.
Scott: Probably high school looked like.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And we just had a weird encounter with this girl.
Scott: She just came up to us and was like, "Hi," and then started to talk.
Scott: She said weird things.
Rym: Well, she walked over to me and shook my hand and said she knew me from somewhere, and I didn't know her from anywhere.
Scott: And she looked at us all weird, and then we escaped.
Rym: The only thing was, the only reason I was confused by this is that she looks scarily similar to a girl I knew a long time ago.
Rym: Like, creepily similar.
Rym: So she was looking at me, and I was looking at her, and I thought, "There's no way.
Rym: that's what's her name.
Rym: There's no
Rym: way.".
Rym: And it wasn't, but it was just weird.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: Luckily, we were able to avoid any sort of contact with creepy people for the rest of this con.
Scott: So also at the mall, I managed to get the Darth Vader that transforms into a--well, TIE fighter that transforms into a Darth Vader.
Rym: Yeah, the one you couldn't find anywhere, but when you finally got it, discovered that it's actually really a crappy toy.
Rym: It's not that crappy.
Rym: It's crap.
Rym: You broke it immediately.
Scott: I fixed it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It doesn't--alright, to tell you how shitty this toy that Scott bought and is talking up is, basically when it's transformed into Darth Vader, it looks like a robot with a tiny little Darth Vader head floating over it.
Scott: You know, if something wasn't designed in the first place to be transformable, it's a miracle that it does that well at all.
Scott: Nah, nah, nah.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: For, uh-- You know what?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: A turd is not designed to be an airplane.
Rym: If I fashion a crude airplane out of a turd, it's still a turd.
Rym: I just wanted to say turd a bunch of times.
Scott: You're a turd.
Scott: No, but it's much better.
Scott: It's pretty much the best it can be.
Scott: My gripe with these toys is that they made them with the shitty, shitty, shitty, shitty, shitty plastic.
Scott: Like the shittiest plastic available.
Scott: If it was made with better plastic, it'd be a better toy.
Scott: Just, ding.
Rym: I point out that at least in terms of the kind of toy it is, it's a step up from Darth Vader on a motorcycle.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it's a TIE fighter that transforms into Darth Vader.
Scott: It's Star Wars and Transformers.
Rym: No, no, don't say that.
Rym: It doesn't transform into a Darth Vader.
Rym: It transforms into a big, blocky, robot-looking thing with a tiny Darth Vader head floating over it.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: It has a red lightsaber.
Rym: The head is floating.
Rym: It's not even a-- It's just this floating Darth Vader head.
Rym: It doesn't look like it floats to me, but-- It's like three sizes too small for the body.
Rym: It's absurd.
Rym: Yeah, also in the mall, we went to a GameStop, and we ended up walking out.
Rym: They had something I wanted to buy, an Intellivision game collection for the GameCube.
Rym: What did you look for online?
Rym: Yeah, so I stood in line, and I ran into the problem that basically I've never successfully bought something at GameStop without having to stand in line behind some stupid kid and his mom selling back like a hundred games, and every GameStop employee there is helping this one kid who's gonna take forever instead of ringing me up and letting me get on with my life.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like the game stores, especially the GameStops I guess, just don't process, you know, customers at the counter quickly.
Scott: It's like that's not their priority.
Rym: Not even quickly?
Scott: They're not even thinking about it.
Rym: They don't even do it properly, let alone quickly.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, okay, there are like three things you can do at a GameStop.
Scott: You can pre-order something, you can buy something that's on the shelf, or you can sell something back.
Scott: I guess you can return something, which is different from selling something back.
Scott: So four things you can do.
Scott: The only transaction that is quick and easy is buying something.
Scott: Pre-ordering takes forever, selling stuff back takes forever, and returning stuff takes forever.
Scott: You need to streamline all four of those things so they all take barely any time.
Rym: You know what, in the very least, if there's a kid selling back a hundred games and you've got two employees, how about employee number two takes care of that growing line of people who just wants to buy something?
Rym: Instead of you both helping the kid, well, I get pissed off enough to drop my game on the floor and walk out.
Scott: Yeah, seriously, I mean...
Rym: I've walked out of like three games, three of the last six times I've gone to a GameStop, I just walked out and didn't buy what I wanted just because I wasn't going to stand there for ten minutes.
Scott: I just don't, it's like they're not, the employees there are just not thinking.
Scott: They're just, that's what happens when you...
Rym: Well, I've met very few intelligent GameStop employees.
Rym: No offense to all of you out there, but goddamn.
Scott: I've met very few intelligent employees in brick and mortar stores, period.
Rym: I used to know a cool guy who worked at a Best Buy, but he knew all the Best Buy scams and didn't care, and he got me a lot of discounted stuff, so he was a cool guy.
Scott: Anyway, enough about, they had every Resident Evil for the GameCube, even the rare ones, but they were thirty bucks, so whatever.
Rym: Yeah, if they were cheaper than that, we would have picked them up.
Scott: Yeah, I currently only have Resident Evil 1, so I need 0, 2, 3, 4, and Code Veronica.
Rym: But thus refreshed, we headed back to the con, and they had an open gaming room where you could just check out a board game, go to a table, the table thing didn't frickin' work, oh my god.
Rym: We ended up stealing tables from people.
Scott: This is a problem, is that you look around the room, and you have a board game, and you want to play it, and you need a table.
Scott: So there's a room full of tables for this purpose.
Rym: Alright, let's see, there are currently, let's say there are four tables that currently don't have anyone playing a game at them.
Rym: Table number one has Fat Dude eating his Chinese food, taking up the whole table.
Scott: So now we can't eat at that table.
Scott: So now there are two tables playing the table.
Scott: So there are two tables that are completely vacant.
Scott: One of them, we go over to the table, and there's stuff on the table, and there's stuff in the chairs of the table.
Scott: That makes it look like someone's there.
Scott: Now we don't want to be all breaking the table etiquette and kicking them out of their table.
Rym: But at the same time, what if they're just leaving their stuff there like asshats, which it turned out they were.
Scott: Yeah, um, what are we supposed to do?
Scott: So there's no one around in the area that looks like they're claiming the stuff.
Scott: So we can't say, "Excuse me, are you using this table?
Scott: Can we play a game
Scott: here?".
Scott: And there's a schedule on the table of official events happening at the table.
Scott: And they're not happening right now, or they're not happening soon, so we don't know.
Scott: Is someone coming?
Scott: Are they not?
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: So it was very difficult to sit at a table.
Scott: So we ended up sitting at one, and then a guy came over, and he was like, you know, "Oh yeah, I have this table
Scott: now.".
Scott: But then he said, "You know what, I'm going to play the game we're playing with
Scott: you."
Scott: Which was Vegas Showdown.
Scott: That was a good game.
Rym: Yeah, it was actually really fun.
Rym: Scott had played it before, and he talked about it, and now I got to play it, and Pete got to play it.
Rym: I won by a lot.
Rym: I'm proud of that.
Scott: Well, that's because I forgot two of the ways to score, which is filling up the hotel and filling up the, uh, museum.
Rym: Yeah, I was also real canny with my money.
Rym: It's weird, I'm really good at, the first time I play a game, I'll often win it, and then I'll lose for a long time.
Rym: Because I'll come up with the, "Oh, that's the obvious stupid strategy that'll only work against people who've never played the game
Rym: before.".
Rym: And then after that, I have to come up with a real strategy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I messed up, because I knew how to play, because I'd played it once before.
Scott: And I got, at every auction in the game, I bid for something, and I always got it real cheap, which was great.
Scott: But that was because I thought I was buying the right things, which I was.
Rym: You were buying all lounges.
Scott: Well, yeah, because the last time I played a guy who won, he won because of the cards that said, you know, uh, you know, "Get bunches of
Scott: stuff.".
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but you know what, there's also cards that say, "Get bunches of stuff if you have
Rym: restaurants.".
Rym: That's why I won.
Scott: Yeah, I think the thing was, is when I played with that other guy, we had like a six people game going on.
Scott: So a lot more cards came out, and so, you know, it was very different.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And also, there was a lot more outbidding people in that game, as opposed to this one, where a lot of times we just all bid on different stuff and got it for the small price.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But we played that.
Rym: That was fun.
Rym: The guy was cool.
Rym: And we'll get back to the guy later, because we actually went and played more games.
Scott: Yeah, there was a reason he had that table, is because he was using it to demo games from his company.
Rym: Yeah, so after that game, we left to let him use the table to actually demo the games he wanted to demo.
Rym: And we did something that we're very ashamed of.
Rym: Well, first, we wanted to play the Doom game, you know, the Doom board game.
Scott: Well, we wanted to at least see what it was like.
Scott: I figured it was going to be like Zombies.
Rym: Yep, I figured it was going to be something similar.
Rym: So we check it out, we open it up, and it's a mess of pieces, and it's basically the same as HeroQuest or Necromunda.
Scott: Yeah, only it's a lot more complicated than either one of those.
Rym: Yeah, so it looked fun, but it wasn't really what we were looking to play at that juncture in our lives.
Scott: And it was so incredibly complicated and large, we didn't have time for it.
Scott: Especially since we had time to figure it out.
Rym: Not in terms of rules, but in terms of stuff we had to set up physically.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, at a game convention, I want to play new games, but at the same time, I only have so many hours there, especially since I'm only gaming for one day.
Scott: So if it takes more than a few minutes to figure out how to play, that doubles the time it takes to play the game itself, and you end up losing a whole lot.
Scott: So you want to find someone to teach you how to play, and that's really the best.
Rym: It wasn't the kind of game we wanted to play, but we could have figured it out, so we just put it away, whatever.
Rym: And then there's Goa.
Scott: Goa was a game I had seen many people play, and many people spoke highly of.
Rym: We wanted to play it for a long time, and there it was.
Scott: So I figured that's the perfect game to try to play.
Scott: It'll probably take just the right amount of time, and we'll be all good.
Rym: This was the first time in any of our lives that we have ever failed at learning to play a board game and given up in frustration.
Scott: I think that part of it was the room was very loud.
Rym: Yeah, the room was a cacophony.
Scott: And part of it was that we didn't have a whole lot of time.
Scott: We were sort of like rushing in, like trying to hurry up and play the game, because, you know, we're at a convention, we don't want to lose time.
Rym: But don't let that dissuade you from the fact that Goa is an incredibly fucking complex game.
Scott: Oh my god, is the game complex.
Rym: Imagine, to sum up, me reading the rules.
Rym: Alright, there are three kinds of turns, blah blah blah.
Rym: On a turn you can take any of six actions.
Rym: There is a whole page describing each of these actions.
Rym: There are tigers and fucking fish.
Rym: That's a whole separate game mechanic.
Rym: There are these cards that do everything, and they have a million symbols on them.
Rym: There's these other cards that do something else, but only when you do the first thing.
Scott: That was really what screwed me up, is the cards.
Scott: There are cards.
Scott: There are many different decks of cards.
Scott: Some of them are like different currencies.
Scott: Like, they're not actually different money, but they're like colonists.
Scott: So like, they'll be colonists cards of three and colonists cards of one.
Scott: So you can have a colonists card, you hold it, it's worth three colonists.
Scott: You know, that kind of, it's like a currency, but the currency is called colonists.
Rym: It was just, it was painful.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There are cards, there's a deck of cards, and on the cards themselves are pictures of crazy stuff.
Scott: Like, tons and tons of symbols from all parts of the game board.
Scott: And I couldn't decipher what these cards meant, and every single one of them was different.
Scott: And I was just like, wow.
Rym: Yup, so what we're breaking through, basically we're going through the rules in order, like step by step.
Rym: And we were like, I'm reading the rules out loud, and they're moving stuff around, we're figuring it out.
Scott: It didn't help that you never referred to the front page.
Scott: You'd be like, yeah, move the colonists card.
Scott: And we'd say, what are the colonists cards?
Scott: And you'd say, the colonists cards.
Scott: But you never looked at the beginning of the book to show us that's what a colonist card is.
Rym: You know why?
Rym: Because the page that described all that was open in front of both of you.
Scott: Yeah, it was upside down and facing away from us.
Rym: Oh no, it was upside down and away from you, not you.
Scott: And when you were reading in the middle of the book, it was on the front page, and we had to turn your hands to go see it.
Rym: I point out that by the time I got to the middle of the book, it didn't matter anymore.
Rym: Well no, because we, when we found out- We'd already figured out what everything was at that point.
Scott: Well, there was a point at which we figured out the progress board, whatever it's called.
Rym: Well, that was way later.
Rym: Basically, we just worked through the game, bit by bit.
Rym: We figured out how to figure out what to bid on, and then we figured out how this progress board thing worked.
Scott: The progress board, I think, was cool, actually.
Rym: Yeah, and then we figured out how the turn order went, and we figured out what the six actions you could take were, and how they related.
Rym: Alright, we're set.
Rym: Then I turn the page, and there's a whole 'nother?
Rym: section?
Rym: to the book, dedicated, just as thick as the whole first section, dedicated solely to describing what each of the individual tiles did.
Rym: And then there's this thing about tires and fishes, and- Expeditions or something?
Rym: Yeah, and, oh my, we just gave up.
Rym: We couldn't do it.
Rym: We gave up, we put the game away, we were defeated by the board.
Scott: I was still confused about the different, like, spice bags, and what was in open field, and what wasn't, and where you could put the spices, and where you couldn't, and what you did with them.
Rym: It didn't help that there's two kinds of rules in German board games, I found.
Rym: There's the old school and the new school, and it seems that the new school rules are very concise, they use the same kind of language that RFCs use.
Rym: You can do this, you may do this, you must do this, that sort of thing.
Rym: In old school rules, it's basically just a paragraph and some examples, and then a paragraph and some examples.
Scott: It says do this, do this, do this, do this, do this.
Rym: And the rules are basically just a whole bunch of examples, and you're supposed to learn the game from these.
Rym: And I don't like that way at all.
Scott: I think that's just the people who wrote the rules have bad powers of explanation, so they need to say, you know, if it's like this, you do it like this, you know.
Scott: You know, if it's like this, then you do something like this.
Rym: 'Cause I like Entecker, but Entecker's written that way, too.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's all the old, like, old style games are that way, it's weird.
Scott: We should make, like, a hobby of rewriting game rules in awesome ways.
Rym: I'll bet someone's already, we should look at the BoardGameGeek page on Noah.
Scott: BoardGameGeek might have it, we should go check it out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, we'd failed, we gave up, and we had to give up the table we were at anyway.
Scott: Don't let that make you think Goa's a bad game, 'cause I'm still pretty sure it's a very good game.
Scott: It might not be the best game ever, but I think it's a good game.
Rym: If we sit down in a quiet room and learn how to play the game, I think we're gonna have fun.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So, then we look up and we see the guy we'd played Vegas Showdown with earlier sitting alone at his table.
Rym: No one's come to demo his stuff.
Rym: Or at least, no one's currently demoing.
Scott: He didn't look like he was asking people to demo, he was just kinda sitting there.
Rym: Yeah, but his name is Alan Earnstein, and he's apparently the head of Hangman Games.
Rym: I have his business card, I'm holding it.
Rym: I'll link to it in the post about the episode.
Scott: He seemed like a pretty cool gaming guy.
Rym: Like, he makes games, and he had all these games he'd made there.
Rym: So, we went over, we're like, "Hey, so show us what you
Rym: got."
Rym: And he pulled out this game, it was called, what, Gem Fair?
Rym: Crystal Fair?
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: Something around that...
Rym: I'm sure it's on his website.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, it's coming out April something, right?
Rym: Yep, like the game hadn't come out yet, it's coming out real soon, and he had his demo copy.
Rym: And we played it.
Rym: And he basically ran us through the game.
Rym: And I gotta say, it was an independent little game.
Rym: Like, he just made this.
Rym: You know, laminated pieces of whatever, and little jemmies.
Scott: Yeah, the game was just little shields to hide what you've got, paper money, little glass jemmies that you can get for almost nothing at a game store.
Rym: Like the counters you used in Magic back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, for your life.
Rym: What?
Rym: No, you used a D20 for your life.
Rym: You used those for tokens.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You used them for whatever.
Scott: Glass baubles that are generically used in all sorts of games.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And a card that had rows for each of the colors, and then numbers on the sides.
Rym: And basically, it's a game of, you have gems, and they're secret.
Rym: And everyone else has gems, and they're also secret.
Rym: And different gems are worth different amount, and there are different numbers of different gems.
Rym: And you take turns trading gems with people, semi-secretly, trying to get the most points at the end of the game.
Rym: I'm not gonna go in greater detail than that, 'cause...
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It was just a surprisingly fun game.
Scott: The only reason I lost is 'cause it took me two turns to actually figure out what was going on.
Scott: Like, oh!
Scott: 'Cause there were so many purple gems.
Scott: You know, I figured, the purple gems aren't really worth anything.
Scott: There's so many of them.
Scott: No, you can score just as many points with the purple ones as you can with the ultra-rare white ones.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: By the end of the game, Pete had racked up all the purple points and just dominated us.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So that was not, you know, the great... I should've realized it's not about which some colors are worth more.
Scott: It's about, you know, you gotta hoard, you know, certain colors and get rid of other colors in order to get more of the same color.
Scott: That way you can score points.
Rym: It's mostly a statistics game, and a bluffing game.
Scott: Yeah, it's a bluffing game, and it's sort of a stock market game, too.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, it kinda is.
Scott: Imagine with more players, the stock market part would matter more.
Rym: Now, we're not gonna go into more detail on that, but it's Hangman Games, and the guy Alan was really cool.
Rym: We're gonna try to get him on the show for an interview sometime.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And then we'll probably talk more about this, but if you've never experienced the indie kinda games that are, you know, they're kinda under the radar, check this guy's website out, 'cause the games he makes seem to be really high quality.
Scott: I'm gonna go to his website sometime and see if any of his games are really, really awesome looking, and maybe I'll buy one.
Rym: Hey, he lives in Maryland.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: We should tell him to come to Otakon with us.
Scott: I don't think he's the big Otakon type.
Rym: No, he definitely seems to be the gamer geek alone.
Scott: Alright, so when we were done with that, we were just pretty much waiting for the Burning Wheel demo, and we were hungry.
Rym: We were hungry, we were exhausted, and our ears were ringing from being in that loud room.
Scott: So we went to the lobby, where it was nice and quiet, and there was free milk, and the registration guy was there, and some other ObraCon people, and a bunch of guys playing MAME and whatever emulated games on Linux.
Rym: They were playing Bomberman at the time.
Scott: Yeah, Super Bomberman it looked like.
Scott: Or MAME Bomberman, I couldn't even tell.
Scott: Anyway, they had a nice little MythTV Linux emulating going on.
Rym: Yeah, we talked to the guy who set that up, and we got some tips.
Scott: We talked to some girl, I don't know what her name was, I forget.
Rym: What, the staffer?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, I totally forgot her name.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I hope she got the piece of paper I wrote.
Scott: Yeah, she seemed pretty cool and smart, and whatever.
Scott: We tried to play the camel game with her through the desert, but we failed because the food showed up.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Oh god, the food.
Rym: So we wanted to get food, we didn't want to leave, so we go ask the hotel, and they said, "Yeah, there's a Chinese place and a pizza place," and they gave us both.
Scott: We really wanted Chinese food.
Rym: We're about to order it, and then this is how we met this girl, she comes over and she's like, "Don't order the
Rym: Chinese.".
Rym: I ordered it an hour ago and it hasn't come yet.
Scott: And we're like, "Oh, we can't afford to wait an
Scott: hour.".
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So we ordered Domino's Pizza.
Scott: And we saw a Domino's guy come in and leave the hotel, and when he left, we asked him, you know, "Where do we tell you to deliver
Scott: to?".
Scott: And he just said, "Tell me to deliver to the lobby,".
Scott: and he's like,
Scott: "Okay.".
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So we order pizza, and it comes still before this poor girl has gotten her Chinese food.
Scott: Yeah, like literally 10, 15 minutes after we order, the Domino's guy is back, and he's got our stuff.
Rym: It was fantastic.
Scott: We shared it with the registration guy.
Rym: I forget how poor gamers are, because I guess I used to be real poor when I went to cons like that.
Rym: Me too.
Rym: Because later we bought two liters of Coke, and we were drinking one, and the other one was just sitting there unopened.
Rym: And this gamer comes up and he's like, "Dude, I'll do anything if you'll give me some of that
Rym: Coke.".
Rym: And we're like, "Here you go, take the whole
Rym: thing.".
Rym: And he didn't know what to do to that.
Rym: He didn't know how to react.
Scott: Yeah, he's like, "I can't just take it from
Scott: you.".
Scott: And we're like, "It's a dollar, two liters of soda.
Scott: None of us really want it.
Scott: What the
Scott: hell?".
Scott: And he's like, "Let me give you
Scott: something.".
Scott: I'm like, "I don't know, do a
Scott: dance.".
Scott: I don't forget what we made him do.
Rym: We made him say who shot first in Episode 4 of Star Wars.
Scott: That's because he had a Han Solo shirt.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I noticed the Han Solo shirt and I was thinking of the same thing, but I figured that was real stupid.
Rym: Yeah, it was real stupid, but I wasn't going to take his money.
Rym: He's obviously a poor gamer.
Scott: Yeah, so whatever.
Scott: We fed a bunch of people and we made friends.
Scott: I talked to this old guy who brought his 16-year-old son there about some stuff.
Rym: Yeah, he's definitely cool because he doesn't seem to be in with the geek thing, but he understands his son is and he's letting his son do it all.
Scott: Yeah, he figures it's better than doing drugs and all that stuff.
Rym: He's right.
Scott: He seemed like a smart dad.
Rym: Yeah, so we told him about Otakon and there's a good bet this kid's going to Otakon now.
Scott: I also asked him about comic books and it was pretty funny that I said, "Did you read Uncle Scrooge
Scott: comics?".
Scott: And he was like, "Oh
Scott: yeah!".
Scott: So now I really like asking people that just to see.
Rym: Now I'll note that we mentioned that we were going to UberCon and we basically told you that if you want to see us there, you won't be able to miss us.
Rym: We stand out.
Scott: And no one came to see us.
Rym: However, we do stand out and we have evidence of this now.
Rym: While we were sitting in the lobby, we were just talking about other cons and stuff.
Rym: One of the staffers of UberCon comes over to us and is like, "Hey, could you guys write down all that stuff you just said?
Rym: You guys really sound like you know what you're talking
Rym: about.".
Rym: We're like, "Oh,
Rym: okay.".
Scott: Even though what we were talking about really had nothing to do with suggestions for UberCon, it was more like- I think we were talking about Yowie at that point.
Scott: Yeah, I think we were talking about other cons and stuff.
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But, whatever.
Scott: We wrote down that they should fix their table problem because that's the only problem they have.
Rym: Yeah, we wrote down a very specific, detailed solution to that.
Rym: We'll see if they implement it next year.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Who knows?
Rym: Maybe we'll see if they'll want us to be staff or something.
Rym: Maybe we'll do GeekNights there live.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: I'd like to do some GeekNights there.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Scott: So, next, we finally made our way to the awaited Burning Wheel game.
Scott: The name of the game, I think, was- Oh, I forget.
Rym: Yes, Inheritance.
Rym: It was a Viking funeral.
Rym: So, the game started where- Well, first off, keep in mind, Scott, we probably shouldn't because this is a thing that he does often.
Rym: And he's run the same game at many places.
Rym: I don't think we want to spoil the plot.
Scott: Oh, we'll tell the summary of the plot.
Rym: Yeah, we'll tell- Don't tell how it ends or all the secrets or anything.
Scott: Well, it ends the way the players make it.
Rym: Well, yeah, but not the secrets, at least.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: We'll not reveal the secrets.
Rym: Like the text of the will.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, the characters are the Grandpa Viking, who is dead and is going to Valhalla.
Scott: And you start the game at his funeral.
Rym: There is- His son, Tyrvald.
Scott: Uh, his other son, Kair, Kair, I think.
Scott: We didn't have a PC for that.
Scott: We didn't have a player for that character.
Rym: Wait, wait, hold on.
Rym: I've got my notes from the frickin' game.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: Oh, the notes from the frickin' game are from the perspective of my character.
Rym: Great.
Scott: There was Kair, who was the other son.
Rym: Yeah, he was a berserk.
Rym: Well, I don't know how much you guys want to hear about the details of the game in that regard.
Scott: We're not going to give too many details.
Rym: Yeah, basically it was a bunch of Vikings, and the game started, and I guess the coolest part of this is that we ended up playing this with a really cool group of people.
Scott: Yeah, when I got there, they were like these schlubby guys, and I was like, "Oh, they look like schlubby guys.
Scott: Ehh.".
Scott: But then they turned out to be cool guys, so.
Rym: Like one guy who was sitting there was this really big guy.
Rym: Not big like Phat, but big like Pete.
Rym: Like a big, muscular kind of Viking-looking dude.
Scott: Tall.
Scott: He was pretty tall.
Scott: He had a big beard.
Rym: Booming voice and a beard.
Rym: And he played Tyrvald, the Viking father.
Scott: The new Viking father.
Rym: And he was so in character that when, I mean the game got really heated, but heated in character.
Rym: Not heated out of character.
Rym: We're all laughing with each other afterwards.
Rym: But like, it got to the point where one of the kids who was playing a Viking insulted this man in front of his host, like at his lodge.
Rym: And he's yelling at the guy, and it was just amazing.
Scott: Yeah, that was good stuff.
Rym: That guy was scary in character.
Scott: The only disappointment I had in the game as my character was this like magic immortal dwarf guy or something.
Scott: And I was the one who had the will, and I was all awesome.
Scott: But I had these magic runes.
Rym: Magic runes!
Scott: And they had the power to change someone's belief.
Rym: Like bind someone to their fate.
Scott: Yeah, it was really cool, but I never got a chance to use them because I was going to use them at one point, but I ended up just winning the duel battle of fate or whatever.
Scott: It's a duel of wits.
Scott: So I didn't need to use it.
Rym: I thought the way Scott handled his character was really good.
Rym: I mean it was a powerful character who kind of never did anything directly, but he influenced other people and in the end got his will.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I mean the only really direct way I would have done anything is with the magic runes, and that was like, it said on my paper like the magic runes will send a man to hell or something like that, so I really didn't want to use them.
Scott: So I always tried to get my way by any other means possible first.
Rym: I love when you smack the Christian priest down about his god.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's a god now!
Rym: That was classic.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But the basic plot, to sum up, was that, alright, the grandfather...
Scott: The Christian priest was Pete.
Rym: Yeah, Pete is quite the scientist, and he ended up playing the Christian missionary priest.
Scott: Which is awesome.
Rym: It was hilarious.
Rym: But basically, the grandfather, the elder Viking, is dead, and it begins at the funeral.
Rym: Now, the current father, Tyrvald, the cool guy who was playing him, is like the leader, he's not the king, but he's basically the leader of where we live.
Rym: His three sons, the first son was murdered by the third son ten years ago, so the third son, Einherjar, was banished forever.
Scott: Einherjar.
Rym: Now, he was supposed to be killed, because I played a priestess of Odin, Gethion, who wanted him dead.
Scott: He was the priestess.
Rym: Yeah, I played it, girl.
Rym: Get over it.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Actually, my character was kind of cool, though.
Rym: It wasn't what I expected.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the son murdered his eldest brother, and the father, instead of killing him, had him exiled.
Rym: So now the son, the prodigal son, has returned after the grandfather has died, kind of vying for the inheritance, kind of vying to get back into the family.
Rym: And it was quite a heated scene.
Rym: You kind of felt like you were really at this Viking funeral, and these large men are yelling at each other.
Rym: It was just an amazing scene.
Scott: I liked it a whole lot.
Scott: It was the best roleplaying I've had in a long time.
Scott: Because I haven't had a lot of roleplaying in a long time, but also because it was really awesome.
Rym: Well, also, the way Burning Wheel seems to work is that it really enforces you to play.
Rym: It really enforces playing in character.
Scott: I think it's like the system itself, instead of... It seems like D&D and other systems, like, the purpose of them is to abstract the reality in which the roleplaying occurs.
Scott: So the roleplaying is completely the burden of the players, and the system just helps you work out combat and what physically happens.
Scott: But Burning Wheel, it does that in a fun way, but it also seems to be a roleplaying catalyst.
Scott: Like, instead of, "You have to roleplay, and here's the system to figure out everything else," it's, "This system makes you roleplay, unless you're a complete
Scott: doofus.".
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, there was one kid who was a little kind of schlubby, definitely wasn't as smart as all the other kids we were playing with.
Rym: And even he played his character really well, just because of the way the system forced him to.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean, he didn't have really the biggest part, but, you know, he did stuff.
Rym: And actually he was a primary mover of the plot, because he insulted Tyrvald in his hall, which led to a fight, and someone got stabbed.
Scott: Yeah, and it was in character, and it was according to... It's just great.
Rym: I mean, it's interesting to watch a system that allows characters to be yelling at each other and arguing, and this conflict should just flare up, and then suddenly it comes to blows, and there's a flurry of blades, and now someone's on the ground stabbed.
Rym: And it was so realistic.
Scott: Well, it wasn't really realistic.
Scott: There was no stabbing and blood.
Rym: Yeah, there was.
Scott: For real.
Scott: Yeah, someone was really bleeding.
Rym: Yeah, we frickin' hung Pete at the end.
Rym: He's not gonna be on the show anymore.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Don't talk about that.
Scott: We're gonna get in trouble.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But basically, I mean, in the game, the way your characters are set up is you'll have beliefs and instincts.
Rym: But one of the beliefs of... Well, I don't think I'll say what the beliefs are, because I don't want to ruin this game for anyone who might play this demo with Luke Crane in the future.
Scott: Let me say, an instinct of my character that's generic was, "I don't make an oath that I can't
Scott: fulfill.".
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Or the instinct of my character, one of them is, "In times of crisis, sacrifice to the
Rym: norns.".
Scott: Yeah, so that really helps you out.
Scott: In D&D, you don't have that sort of information about your character.
Scott: You have to come up with it, and you have to try to think, "What would my character
Scott: do?".
Rym: No, I like that.
Rym: I'm fine with that.
Rym: But I know a lot of people, ahem Scott, ahem, have trouble with that.
Scott: Well, no.
Scott: See, I don't have trouble.
Scott: The trouble isn't doing it.
Scott: The trouble is coming up with it in the first place.
Rym: So you do have trouble with it.
Scott: Well, it's not the same kind of trouble as you're implying.
Scott: It's a different kind of trouble.
Scott: The trouble isn't, you know, being the character that I know.
Scott: It's knowing the character in the first place.
Scott: And if I come up with a character that, you know, I don't really think about a whole lot, and come up with these things, then I can't really do it, because there isn't a character to do.
Rym: See, for me, it's more that, I mean, I come up with this stuff for my characters anyway.
Rym: I write pages and pages and pages and pages of backstory like a frickin' gamer nerd nut.
Rym: But what this game does is you have to codify your beliefs in very specific ways and put them on your character sheet, and you get in-game rewards for playing in character.
Scott: I think what's really awesome, though, is that, Burning Wheel, you don't need to have pages and pages and pages and pages of backstory.
Scott: All you need is, like, maybe one paragraph and, like, a few sentences, and you've got just as full a character, you know, you might not have the history, of course, to go along with it.
Rym: Well, you don't have as full a character in terms of backstory, but you have as full a character in terms of role-playing.
Scott: In terms of role-playing, it's just 100%, it's full-on, you've got it.
Scott: You don't have to do tons and tons of effort in coming up with all this other stuff.
Rym: Now, of course, I'll point out that we've never played a traditional campaign of Burning Wheel at all, and all we've experienced are scenarios.
Rym: In this, there was a scenario set up, and we were all given characters, we chose them, and then we played them.
Rym: So, at the very least, this system allows for that really well, because it allows inter-player conflict.
Rym: that's handled gracefully.
Rym: D&D doesn't handle inter-player conflict at all.
Rym: If two characters start fighting, it just doesn't work.
Scott: It's just broken if characters in D&D are fighting each other.
Scott: The system wasn't designed for that.
Rym: In this game, at least in terms of the mentors we'd played, you're expected to fight, you're expected to hate each other, or at least have a disagreement.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, I think what's... I can't say that Burning Wheel campaigns don't work, but I get the feeling that there's something missing.
Scott: But I don't know, because I haven't read the book, so it's just a feeling that's based on nothing.
Rym: I don't think it's so much that Burning Wheel can't do a campaign, I think it's more that Burning Wheel really shines when you play a one-off scenario from start to finish.
Scott: I think when you play Burning Wheel, and you have a scenario that is set up already, but the players don't know the scenario, and they just pick characters and go with it.
Scott: The GM tells them what's going on, because not a DM, it's a GM in Burning Wheel.
Scott: And then you go at it in one shot, one night, or a few hours, and that is when it's super, super awesome, for guaranteed.
Scott: And if you're going to do one-shot role-playing, Burning Wheel is definitely the way to go for the most awesome fun that I've ever had, at least.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So, when we do a whole show on this, and we actually interview Luke Crane and maybe some other people, hopefully we'll be able to shed some more light on more of these specific reasons why Burning Wheel is so awesome, and how it actually works with the dice pools and everything.
Scott: Yeah, and hopefully in the future, when we actually get the books and run games ourselves, we'll talk about those in hopefully a way that is not painfully nerdy, but also entertaining and interesting.
Rym: I mean, I guess, put it this way.
Rym: Currently, Scott and I, we live here, and Pete lives nearby, but he lives far enough away where he can't just hang out every day.
Rym: Now, we can't play D&D with the two of us, because that just wouldn't be fun.
Scott: People do play one-on-one D&D, and there's a funny video on Google Video about it.
Scott: you might have seen, but it's bad.
Rym: Yeah, I've done it occasionally, but not as a campaign, more as a, "Alright, it's time to role-play out this thing that only my character's doing while everyone else is eating
Rym: cheese.".
Rym: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Rym: Or, "Everyone's out of town except the two of us, let's move the
Rym: plot.".
Rym: But I really think Scott and I could set up little scenarios and actually play them out in Burning Wheel, just the two of us, and I think it would be fun.
Scott: Maybe we could.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll talk about this a lot more.
Rym: Burning Wheel has added a new element.
Rym: It's revitalized my love of role-playing games.
Scott: I think what you could actually do with Burning Wheel is you could be like, "Alright, let's say there's a...".
Scott: I don't know, let me think of something really quick.
Scott: "There's a merchant, and there's a thief, and the thief stole something from the merchant, and he's hidden it on his body, and...".
Scott: Go.
Scott: Want to use the thief, want to use the merchant.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That simple, and then you have two pieces of paper, and one has the beliefs of the merchant, which are, "That guy stole something from me, I want it back, goddamn this
Scott: thief.".
Scott: And the thief has beliefs, "I stole this, I want to keep it because I'm poor, this merchant's rich in
Scott: greed.".
Scott: And then you just go, and it'd be a duel of wits, and it'd be a great fun time, give you at least a half hour of entertainment.
Rym: I mean, I wish you all could have seen this game, especially as it wound down, and the plot was revealed, and everything was resolved, and...
Scott: People were screaming and yelling like it was like, "Oh my god,
Scott: woo!".
Rym: Yep, and we got some really good in-character speeches at the end by everyone.
Rym: It was fantastic.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I mean, I'd love to just tell the whole story of the game, because this would be a story.
Rym: You could just take what we did, and write a short story, and it would be awesome.
Scott: A very awesome short story.
Rym: But we can't ruin it for you.
Rym: If you ever get the chance to play a Burning Wheel demo with Luke Crane, do it.
Scott: Yeah, look for gaming conventions.
Scott: I think he has his convention schedule on his website.
Rym: Yes, he said he does.
Rym: And of course, we'll ask him about that when we get him on the show, because he seemed very open to an interview.
Scott: Yeah, he seems like, "Oh, I love podcasting,
Scott: whatever.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And he was amazed that we do four shows a week, which everyone should be.
Rym: Yeah, so we've gone for a long time, but that's good, because there's going to be no podcast on Thursday, I'm going out of town.
Scott: Yeah, so now we're going to tell you about the non-gaming part of UberCon, getting home.
Rym: Yeah, so as you might have noticed in the link, if you go to the website, that I mentioned a blizzard, and I mentioned New Jersey.
Scott: Now, I knew there was going to be some blizzard-y snow, but I didn't care.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't really consider the blizzard in our planning.
Rym: We just ignored it.
Scott: I considered it, but I also ignored it.
Scott: Yeah, I just ignored it.
Rym: I figured, whatever, worst case, we'll stay at the hotel.
Scott: I didn't think it was going to be that big or that dangerous, and you know what?
Scott: It really wasn't that big or that dangerous, you know?
Scott: I mean, it wasn't like, I've had ice storms before, which are infinitely worse.
Scott: I've had like three feet of snow, which is infinitely worse.
Scott: This is pretty much a normal snowstorm, you know?
Scott: I mean, snow piles up, and it snows, and whatever.
Scott: But we leave the con, we get in the car, we clean off the car, which kind of sucked, and we get in, and we start to drive really slowly onto the highway.
Scott: And we got to the highway pretty easily, which was nice.
Scott: Going north in the Garden State.
Scott: Now, going north in the Garden State to our house, there's a trick.
Scott: If we keep going north in the Garden State and don't stop, eventually it becomes I-87 North, which is exactly where we want to be, because that takes us to 84 East, which takes us to our house.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: There is a way to get from the Garden State to 87 North.
Scott: It's really the same road, but there's like this magic shortcut.
Scott: I don't understand quite the geography of it.
Rym: Yeah, it involves 17.
Scott: It involves like 17, 287, and I-80, and something else.
Rym: I go that way often when I go to Philly or Horsham, but going to Philly or Horsham is completely different from going to Jersey, so I couldn't be of any assistance.
Scott: Yeah, I've mastered this shortcut going south.
Scott: Like, going south, I just take exit 14A on 87, and then BOOM!
Scott: Okay, I'm on the Garden State much faster than just going south in 87 forever.
Scott: But going north, I have a problem with it.
Scott: So, I saw an exit.
Scott: First of all, we're going really slow on the highway, and the worst thing about it wasn't the cars driving shittily around me, because that was to be expected.
Rym: Yeah, there was one that spun out and almost hit us.
Rym: It was fantastic.
Scott: Yeah, you know, and it wasn't, you know, any problem with my car, because my car was brand new and great.
Scott: Well, actually, there was a problem with my car is that it's so new and great that if you step a little bit on the gas, it accelerates a lot.
Scott: So, sometimes I would step on it a little bit too much from nothing, and it would go whoop, and then spin the tires a little bit, but it was never really trouble, because the anti-lock brakes were great, and, you know, the steering was great, and the big tires are great.
Scott: Anyway, so I see an exit for 17, and I'm like, "Aha!
Scott: 17 is a road I know.
Scott: That seems like the shortcut to
Scott: me.".
Scott: And I was close, real close, but not quite.
Scott: I got on 17 north.
Scott: North is good.
Scott: North is good, because that's right where I want to go, but it wasn't getting there any faster, and we're still going really, really slowly.
Scott: We couldn't see the lanes.
Scott: The worst thing was I couldn't see the lanes.
Rym: Now, keep in mind, it's still snowing, and we've just been gaming for over 12 hours, and we're tired.
Rym: Real tired.
Rym: It's like one.
Scott: Yeah, and we're going really slow.
Scott: What should be a 90-minute trip eventually became a two-and-a-half-hour trip.
Scott: So, now you know how long it took us to get home, and we did make it home.
Rym: Well, obviously.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: But not being able to see the lanes was absolutely the worst thing there was, because I wanted to drive in the lane, and I wanted to drive in the tire tracks of the guy in front of me, and where there was the most traction.
Scott: But it was almost impossible to do all those things, especially in unplowed, unsalted, unsanded areas.
Scott: It was just, that was the hardest part of driving, was?
Scott: it didn't matter the cars around me.
Scott: I didn't care about them so much.
Scott: They weren't really bothering me.
Scott: It was keeping my car going where I wanted it to go, straight.
Rym: Now, independent of that, New Jersey has some issues when it comes to their roads, particularly the signage.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, so we get off the Garden State, we're going north on 17.
Scott: Now, to get back on a highway, usually the signs, and they have little arrows saying, you know, "Here's how to get back to a
Scott: highway.".
Rym: So we're driving, and we see a sign, "Garden State, this
Rym: exit.".
Scott: I figured, alright, screw this 17 road, I'm getting back on the Garden State and going north.
Scott: So a little green sign says, "Garden State, this
Scott: away.".
Scott: So I made a right turn, and I went that way.
Scott: Then there was a, I could either go straight or right.
Scott: I didn't know, because there wasn't another sign to tell me the Garden State is straight, or the Garden State is right.
Rym: Yep, so assuming, you know, it didn't say, it would just keep going straight.
Scott: Yep, I went straight, we went right, we went around in circles twice, and we didn't find any more signs to tell us how to get back to the Garden State.
Rym: Yeah, imagine this, we're going straight, we figure, alright, we're gonna hit the Garden State.
Rym: Eventually, we get back, it takes us back to 17, and we pass the same goddamn exit.
Rym: It just took us in a circle.
Scott: We went in two circles, then we went into a parking lot to rest, and there were some high school kids fooling around.
Scott: Then we went to a gas station to rest some more.
Rym: In fact, didn't they write the word "vagina" on someone's car?
Scott: I think they did, and some girl got mad.
Scott: It was funny.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: They could do what they want.
Scott: We rested at a gas station, which was a much needed relief, peeing and such.
Scott: Then we just kept going north on 17 until eventually we hit 87, thank God.
Rym: The moment, the second we passed into the borders of New York, the roads were suddenly great.
Scott: It could have had something to do with that fleet of plows that was coming from the New York Department of Transportation.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It was a little tough avoiding them with my car, but it worked out.
Rym: We're not really making fun of Jersey.
Rym: It's just the fact that we have trouble almost every time we drive in Jersey.
Rym: We don't have trouble anywhere else.
Rym: We drive halfway across the country to go to conventions.
Rym: No issues.
Rym: Jersey?
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: If you're going north on a road, there'll be exits that don't exist if you're going south or vice versa.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: There'll be ways to get off a highway, but then no way to get back on it.
Scott: It's really because the roads are divided, right, with those Jersey dividers, and they're real long and real fast, and it's real hard to figure out how to get to anywhere from them.
Scott: You know, it's like imagine if the highway had stores on the side of it, on both sides, and it's not easy to get to the other side.
Scott: They're very infrequent U-turns and very infrequent left turns, and anything that's off of those main highway divided roads is really, really tricky and scary.
Scott: And you just don't know where the hell to go, ever.
Rym: Now, independent of that, it's dark and it's snowing.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Rym: And we're tired.
Scott: Mmm, and hungry.
Rym: Yeah, real hungry, because, all right, we got Domino's Pizza, like we said, right?
Rym: I've determined that Domino's Pizza is not food.
Rym: I was not satisfied.
Scott: Well, Domino's Pizza might not be great, and it's not.
Rym: Well, that particular Domino's Pizza did not sit well with me.
Scott: Well, I didn't eat the meat pizza once I saw it.
Scott: I realized it wasn't going to be good.
Scott: I ate the pepperoni.
Rym: Yeah, but you were just as bad off as I was.
Rym: I was pretty bad off.
Scott: My stomach wasn't the happiest.
Rym: I was full of food, and my stomach was pissed off at me for some reason.
Rym: But I was still hungry, and I knew that I wasn't getting any nutrition from this pizza.
Rym: But I was so full, I couldn't eat any other food.
Scott: The thing is, Domino's Pizza might not be anything compared to any other pizza place.
Scott: But Domino's Pizza is closer to pizza than Taco Bell is to Mexican food.
Rym: Yeah, but I like Taco Bell.
Scott: I don't like Taco Bell at all.
Rym: It's poison.
Rym: I eat White Castle.
Scott: Yeah, that's even worse.
Scott: The worst.
Rym: See, get this.
Rym: I like Taco Bell, even though I don't consider them tacos, but what they are, I like.
Scott: What they are is poison.
Rym: What they are isn't so bad.
Rym: It's terrible.
Rym: I'll eat Arby's.
Scott: I'll eat Arby's, but I think we already ate it, so I can't eat it again for a whole year.
Rym: And I freaking love White Castles and Hott & Now's.
Rym: Mainly because I grew up in Detroit, where we lived right near a White Castle.
Scott: No, not eating any of that shit.
Rym: But even the thought of a McDonald's or a Burger King just makes me nauseous.
Scott: Oh, I can't eat any of those.
Rym: Except McDonald's breakfast, which are freaking awesome.
Scott: I won't eat a McDonald's anything ever.
Rym: You make McDonald's eggs, so I don't know why you complain.
Scott: I don't make McDonald's eggs.
Scott: The milkshakes at McDonald's taste good, actually.
Scott: What?
Rym: No, they don't.
Scott: Yeah, they do, but I know they're full of chemicals, so I always get real ice cream ones from diners and stuff.
Scott: Because they taste the same as the McDonald's ones.
Rym: Alright, so anyway, we've talked a long time, but that's okay.
Rym: Once again, no podcast on Thursday since Katsucon.
Rym: Unless Scott decides to do something on his own.
Rym: That's all him.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see if you know how to use the mixer and everything.
Scott: It's plugged in, I just start talking, and I push the record button.
Rym: Yeah, I guess you could boot an OpEx on my computer and then record to an external hard drive somewhere.
Scott: Or I could just take the mixer into my room and...
Rym: Yeah, we'll see if you know how to use the compressors.
Rym: Though, I ordered a compressor.
Rym: Well, I'm ordering it.
Rym: I'll have ordered it probably by the time you listen to this episode.
Scott: I thought we ordered a disco ball.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: A disco ball.
Rym: Don't ask, it's late.
Rym: Scott, we're either going to get a dynamic range compressor, like a valve compressor, to stick in to the line between the mixer and the computer for recording.
Rym: Or we're going to get a disco ball and hang it in our little studio here.
Scott: Both of them should increase the audio quality of the podcast significantly.
Scott: So it's really a matter of price/performance ratios and such.
Rym: Yeah, the good disco ball is $10 more than the cheap compressor.
Rym: But I could get the $100 compressor.
Rym: But is that worth the difference in the disco ball?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think the 24-inch double mirror disco ball with the colored stripes, as long as we get good, bright white LEDs to point at it, should be the best.
Scott: Even though it's a little more expensive.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, in sum, UberCon was awesome.
Rym: Burning Wheel is awesome.
Rym: Hangman Games are really cool.
Rym: All of you who didn't come to UberCon and see us suck.
Rym: Though, to the people in Australia and the UK, I kind of understand.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: Oh, and Jersey sucks.
Rym: Yeah, at least North Jersey.
Rym: I like Wildwood a lot.
Scott: Well, it's not so much that the state itself sucks, it's the road suck.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We'll be at KatsuCon.
Rym: I'll mention that again, because I want to see people.
Scott: Well, you'll be at KatsuCon.
Rym: I'll be at KatsuCon.
Scott: I'll be at the New York Comic Con.
Rym: Yeah, I may or may not be at the New York Comic Con.
Scott: Two weekends from now.
Rym: Now, Scott, if you want, there's another spot in our room at KatsuCon.
Rym: I burped.
Scott: I don't really want to pay for that.
Rym: Eh, it'd be cheaper than what I'm paying, because it'd be one more person.
Scott: Yeah, uh, no, because then it would make your price go down.
Rym: Yeah, it'd also make your price go down.
Scott: Well, it'd make my price go up from zero to your new decreased price.
Rym: Yeah, well, you'd get free transport, because I'm just driving to D.C.
Rym: Thursday after work.
Scott: No, I can't go Thursday.
Scott: That's too early.
Scott: What?
Scott: No.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, this was a long episode.
Rym: I've said that a bunch of times, so we're done.
Scott: We're done.
Scott: Cheers.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com.
Scott: And if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight, Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.