Rym: It's Wednesday October 4th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We have Emily on the show and we finally get around to talking about Scott Pilgrim.
Rym: Let's do this For some reason.
Rym: Scott's tired.
Rym: I'm not really sure why cuz he doesn't do much.
Scott: I told you I woke up early right and you know sometimes in the middle of the night you wake up And then you go back to sleep right away, right?
Scott: You know what?
Rym: when that happens It's usually like one of those magic nights where you know maybe it's a six-hour night But it ends up feeling like you know a year or two.
Scott: No that that happens to me a lot.
Rym: You know you wake up, and then you fall asleep And then you wake up, and you feel like you slept all night, and it's been like ten minutes.
Scott: Yeah, that happens to me a lot, but anyway this morning I woke up like an hour or so early and I woke up and my windows are wide open.
Scott: You know cuz I have my new furniture arrangement.
Scott: So I'm looking out the window, and I see this fog and it's a crazy fog.
Rym: Yeah, this is a new fit.
Rym: I mean we've lived here for long enough to have gone through all the seasons But we've never had a fog season before.
Rym: I think there's an extra season in Beacon.
Scott: I think it goes spring winter summer fog fall yep, so you know there's a crazy fog.
Scott: So I'm kind of tired and falling back to sleep.
Scott: But then I keep looking at this crazy fog, and I can't stop looking at it.
Scott: It's so crazy, and I'm like man.
Scott: I hope that fog stays so I could drive in it.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I did drive through it and It was really cool for about I don't know eight minutes Mm-hmm, and then it just made traffic go really slow.
Scott: Yeah, by the time I woke up and got in the car the fog wasn't as full as it was when I woke up You know earlier.
Rym: yeah, see the thing is I got up early to go to work early So I could leave work early, but for various reasons there wasn't much work to do today, so getting there early served no purpose.
Rym: I Mean I got there early like I'll get some work done.
Rym: There was nothing to do like damn it And I had stuff in the afternoon all canceled.
Rym: Yeah, I got a new project, and then the project was canceled before they finished giving it to me.
Rym: So I thought all right fuck it I'm gonna play Defcon cuz I got a Windows computer here And I ran into the problem that apparently like five percent of people have Where if you have a certain sound card whatever that game just won't fucking work.
Scott: Why just disable the sound card in the bot the BIOS?
Rym: I can't really do that.
Scott: about the device manager I don't.
Rym: well.
Rym: I need the sound card for other work stuff.
Scott: You need the sound card for your work.
Rym: They're voice over IP crab and I mean I could but it would be such a job great at DirectX stuff.
Rym: Everything's up-to-date.
Rym: a lot of people have this problem And it no one's really sure what causes it and all the workarounds work for some of the people But not other people, and it's just.
Rym: it's annoying.
Scott: it sounds like a crazy problem.
Scott: Well the thing is.
Rym: apparently the other game Darwinia that they made has the exact same problem.
Scott: Then why didn't they fix it for Darwinian?
Rym: probably because it mostly affects people who aren't gamers because I think the kind of hardware it Effects is hardware that gamers wouldn't willingly use.
Scott: but the point of their games is that they run on 600 megahertz CPUs with 128 Meg's.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: all I know is I didn't get to play DEFCON at work.
Rym: So I ended up not doing what you should have played my thing of the day.
Rym: Now you'd think gladiator gladiator gladiator that okay?
Rym: I could have done a lot for GeekNights.
Rym: You know found some news.
Rym: no You know what a lot happened in the world today and Fuck all of it had anything to do with anime Or manga or comics or anything.
Scott: yeah, that was really nothing.
Rym: so I was.
Rym: I thought Oh, I'll do a news about the fact that the Gitmo inmates are all fat.
Rym: And while that's funny and all and I could make a lot of jokes there I'm gonna save that for not a Wednesday.
Rym: instead my news is that this weekend October 6th 7th and 8th We are going to be running crazy events in Utica, New York.
Rym: also at the same time at the same place There happens to be an anime con called CITACON S I T A con.
Rym: we're gonna be guests there.
Rym: We're gonna be running crazy awesome events.
Rym: I absolutely guarantee.
Rym: if you go and you find us And there's no way you won't find us a good time will be had or your money back.
Scott: Well there is a way by your money back to find us.
Scott: if you are blind and deaf you might not find.
Rym: yeah, I mean if you go to this con just kind of walk around and wait for a ruckus to happen or look for loud people and We will probably be at the center of both the ruckus and the loudness.
Scott: now because of this convention Rym is thinking about copping out of a show tomorrow, so I said hey instead of doing a show Why don't you put up the?
Scott: Infamous clown pistols all right?
Rym: now the reason Scott brings us up is one.
Rym: a lot of people have been asking about this and I've Responded to most of you just privately.
Rym: the fact is that we recorded it.
Rym: the recording wasn't so great because we use GarageBand and One of the microphones was shitty.
Rym: so it required a lot of editing.
Rym: also It was on the Mac in some Mac format.
Rym: So Scott went through a lot of effort to get it into a wav format And it sat on my hard drive being neglected because I didn't feel like sitting down for an hour and editing the thing Because it'll take me more time to edit that down to be listenable then it takes me to do a month's worth of GeekNights
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so all right Scott.
Rym: I have the wav file.
Rym: so a couple weeks ago I thought I'm gonna do it.
Rym: And then I discovered that Scott through no fault of his own made the wav file wrong and it ended up being one channel Which defeated the purpose of having two channels?
Scott: Yeah, it was Apple's fault.
Rym: Yeah, it was GarageBand's fault.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway Everyone go and pester Rym to edit the clown pistol and you'll be able to hear it tomorrow night.
Scott: Us yeah, that's right rims gonna do that for you tomorrow.
Scott: You're gonna hear the clown pistol ing.
Rym: finally Here's the deal.
Rym: I'll do the clown pistol.
Rym: I will do what it takes to put up the clown pistol and all that tomorrow.
Scott: Aha, but but what in exchange?
Rym: you have to take care of getting all those flyers copied for the con.
Scott: alright Give me the I'll go print them out of the copier at work.
Scott: alright I can't be.
Scott: I can't vouch for the quality of the copies.
Rym: well make one copy make sure sure it's not shitty And then make a whole bunch more.
Rym: Maybe I will and if that fails well there aren't any kinkos anywhere near us.
Scott: No there aren't.
Scott: I'm sure there's one in Utica.
Rym: Well, no there's a bunch of coffee places around.
Rym: go find one.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think our listeners want to hear this part.
Rym: No, they don't though actually in the future.
Rym: We're gonna start putting up as a special occasionally the pregame Where we actually do the you know pre-production stuff for the show because the people have been asking about that.
Scott: yeah So anyway, I got a news.
Scott: you got a news.
Scott: Yeah, you remember the X Prize the you know.
Scott: they gave them millions of dollars to whoever can make like a reusable Spaceflight vehicle whatever and someone won the prize.
Scott: Yeah, yeah Oh, they have a new X Prize.
Scott: the X Prize Foundation has a new prize And they will give it ten million dollars to any team who takes X server and makes it work.
Scott: well no that can completely decode the genes of a hundred people in ten days and It ain't like ten days from now like you've got.
Scott: no In a period of ten days, so you'd have to basically decode ten complete DNA is per day You know.
Rym: so it's make an awesome computer.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically make a way to decode genes really fast.
Rym: you heard it here first.
Rym: I'm based on things.
Rym: I know I'm going to hazard a bet that IBM is going to win the X Pro.
Scott: Well now I think there's more to it than just the computer part.
Rym: Oh no no no I can't say, but I'm basing this on knowledge as to specific applications That IBM is known to be using cell processors for either way very Specific application.
Scott: if you win they'll pay you another million dollars to decode another hundred gene people people's genes in another ten days.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: it doesn't say that.
Scott: but the point of it is I want our much smarter Biologist listeners who I know exist who you know have decoded DNA before Unlike us who haven't decoded any DNA at all.
Rym: actually I've done electrofluoresis About ten times in my life.
Scott: how long does it take to decode one person's genes in the entirety?
Scott: I?
Rym: Can say that it took me?
Rym: Four attempts to correctly set up electrofluoresis where the gel didn't just suck.
Scott: Well if you know what the hell you're doing You know that's the people.
Rym: also electrofluoresis is not really anything compared to what they're doing.
Scott: yeah What is that the best you know?
Scott: Equipment in the world of the best lab in the world.
Scott: how long does it take?
Rym: yeah Pete you ever all remember Pete?
Rym: He's been on the show a couple times.
Rym: He's the GeekNights resident scientist To help us out here.
Rym: We'll do a show on this.
Scott: yeah And how?
Scott: how hard would it be to do ten full people's DNA in a day here?
Rym: I got the rip the scrim prize forget the X prize.
Rym: I will give a dollar to the first person who sends us a Succinct Comprehensive explanation of what it takes to do what the X prize is asking.
Scott: yep all right things of the day time.
Rym: Yeah, so Pete come and get your dollar.
Rym: Yeah, I expect Lisa dancing things of the day.
Rym: Now of course we've got three things of the day, and I guess I'll start with mine because it's totally not Anime manga or comic related.
Scott: that's fine.
Scott: mine is an anime manga or comic related.
Scott: either Fantastic
Rym: Alright, so actually Scott found this but I watched it and it really exemplifies everything that I strive to be in my life, or it is a 18-minute video of Moderately clever to incredibly hilarious pranks being pulled on people now not like the Japanese toilet prank Which while probably the second funniest prank ever
Scott: done?
Scott: It was just downright cruel.
Scott: It wasn't cruel.
Scott: That was awesome.
Rym: It was cruel in an awesome way.
Emily: You know they never showed any women did they like?
Emily: there were some girls who went into it But they didn't show it when it came out though.
Rym: Yeah, cuz they took those videos home.
Scott: No, but these the practical jokes in this video are actually.
Scott: a lot of them involve fursuits.
Rym: Yeah, they're not so much the kind of pranks like we usually.
Rym: you know a guy skeleton on a motorcycle scaring some homeless guy Best one ever.
Rym: it is much more along the muss.
Rym: It's very much more.
Rym: this idea of freaking squares, I mean the first one really exemplifies.
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: No one gets hurt or anything.
Rym: It's a guy just walking down the street and then suddenly about a hundred Fursuiters just suddenly run around the corner and chase him down totally out of the blue.
Rym: or There's a display of a Santa Claus, and then he beats up this other guy just totally out of the blue.
Rym: It's almost more like performance art than a prank.
Scott: Yeah, it's 18 minutes long though So it is prepared for a sit.
Rym: It's well worth it.
Rym: In fact, if you watched the owned video the own compilation This is probably that quality only pranks instead of people hurting themselves severely.
Emily: Okay, but some of them I must admit we're pretty good All right.
Scott: So my thing today is this flash game called swords and sandals and it's about gladiator gladiator.
Scott: Yeah, it has this music where that goes gladiator gladiator gladiator.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of cat really fucking annoying.
Scott: Yeah, but the way the game works really mostly because Scott keeps singing.
Emily: Yeah, I was gonna say I didn't hear the game, but I heard Scott in his room going.
Rym: gladiator I'm sitting at work.
Rym: I was wondering what that was all about.
Emily: Like I'm sitting out there reading a comic and I hear from the Gladiator I'm like Scott.
Rym: He doesn't even if no one's around Messaged me at work to say the word gladiator And then he said it again.
Scott: so this is a really simple flash game where you have a gladiator that you customize and level up and buy equipment for and then You fight against other gladiators in the arena and you try to beat all the gladiators.
Scott: and you know what?
Scott: It's impossible to win without cheating.
Scott: So cheating is very easy.
Scott: Let me tell you the secret to cheating.
Scott: create a new HTML file and embed the flash game in that HTML file.
Scott: Modify the 8th the script that embeds the flash to allow you access to the full flash menu.
Scott: Enter the arena right click on the flash game and click forward.
Scott: This will take you from the arena to the screen which allows you to give your gladiator three skill points.
Scott: Yes, you can repeat this indefinitely to give your Infinity skills.
Rym: Let me get this straight.
Rym: you Sat around with this impossible to beat flash game.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Wasted time figuring out how to cheat at a single player.
Scott: a forum gave me the idea so I didn't.
Scott: You have no life.
Scott: what do?
Scott: I was doing?
Scott: nothing at work?
Scott: What do you want from me?
Rym: I'd say do work, but I didn't do anything.
Rym: today.
Emily: You guys are crazy.
Rym: It's like oh, I have no work.
Rym: I'm miserable.
Emily: They pay me to do.
Scott: It's really fun to cheat in this game because I mean you walk up to a guy.
Scott: I had so much strength.
Scott: My gladiator was twice the size of the enemy gladiators and I poked them with a sword and they fly across the screen Into a spiky pit.
Scott: it it was pretty funny I'll show you later.
Scott: But I yelled at a guy with the taunt command and that taunt caused the guy to fly back 20 feet and land in a spiky pit.
Scott: 20 feet really far.
Rym: Okay, not like 15 feet a bajillion feet.
Scott: It's 20 feet all the way across the arena 40 feet from one side of the Coliseum to the other great.
Scott: That's how far.
Scott: It was awesome Paunting.
Emily: it was crazy.
Emily: if they could do that in baseball games like, you know, I want to see that Flies.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Emily: If you're doing it in hockey There wouldn't even be any fights because people would be you know Thing to that I came was I mean RIT hockey was went to the men's hockey games.
Rym: but our senior year we started going to some of the women's hockey games and I mean our women's hockey team was really good, but no one went to see the game as they can't fight.
Rym: Yeah, they can't check check They can't fight and honestly the best player on the team was actually pretty piss poor Compared to even like the worst high school hockey player.
Rym: Yeah, I really felt that but it was still fun to go because you know They.
Rym: they really liked if people actually showed up and cheered and it was really a cool thing.
Rym: But I always brought my trumpet because I was the bugle boy in RIT.
Rym: I played the bugle.
Rym: You know when the other team was losing by a lot I'd play taps over on their side that kind of crap.
Rym: and if I played my trumpet at the girls hockey games Effectively everything stopped because it was so loud.
Rym: No, it's no one knew what to do.
Rym: It was like What's going on.
Emily: it's kind of funny and sad at the same time.
Rym: At least our girls hockey team kicked the asses of any other girls hockey team that they did.
Scott: that they did.
Emily: They had fun playing.
Emily: Um Well, so I was at my friend and former roommate Macy's house last weekend in Long Island and her sister's a major Jayrock fan.
Emily: so we ended up hanging out on the computer a long time.
Emily: well, Macy counseled her friend who was having issues with and So I was hanging out with younger sisters.
Emily: Okay.
Emily: Okay, that's that's unimportant.
Rym: But so anyway, I don't like the phrase issues with stuff.
Emily: You know a public forum here.
Rym: so, you know respecting privacy and all that you really in the future We have a week planned called the worst people we know personally by name.
Rym: Oh You know.
Emily: so So I was watching internet videos with the little sister and she showed me this Abridged yugioh.
Emily: and the guy is actually pretty ambitious, you know, cuz he takes an episode a week Shortens it down to about five minutes three minutes or such and dubs it and it's it's sort of one of those Evangelion we death, you know Nescaflowne kind of dubbing parodies, but it's it's pretty well done.
Emily: And even though it's pretty lame.
Emily: There's at least one good laugh per episode.
Scott: So check it out.
Scott: Yeah, I just watched part of one of the episodes and there was a. there was a ridge racer joke And also the dubbing is really good.
Emily: The best part are the intros because every time they'll do like it will be in Spanish Or they'll do it like a soap opera or something like the.
Emily: the intros are the parts.
Emily: They really mix up and screw around with.
Emily: Yeah, this is kind of a time waster, but you can check it out.
Rym: You know, we're all about time wasters Things that the day are for.
Scott: it's funny.
Rym: All our other friends complain about.
Rym: you know I have a job where they work me to death for no money and we if Josh we don't do anything We get a lot of money and we're just as angry and unhappy.
Scott: I'm telling you that's how it's the scale of business.
Scott: the guy who gets paid dick the janitor, right?
Scott: You know, you'll miss him if he's gone But you pay him shit and he works real hard.
Scott: the CEO.
Scott: if they change the CEO You won't notice a difference at all, but he gets paid the most and does nothing.
Rym: Well, he does things.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, like I do things.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway today we're talking about perhaps the greatest English literature ever produced by the world Onto man and beast Ever put out by a man named Brian.
Rym: Hey, man.
Emily: Hey, man.
Emily: Is it more discouraging than chickens as literature?
Emily: I heard a great you be white quote.
Scott: It's it's good, but it's not that good.
Rym: You see I was building up to a joke that you really kind of killed.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah I was gonna make a joke.
Rym: There was a joke at the end of that.
Rym: Scott Pilgrim is not the best thing ever.
Rym: However, Scott Pilgrim is pure love.
Scott: It's Awesome.
Rym: now if you've not read Scott Pilgrim, we're not gonna spoil much Probably gonna spoil a couple things.
Rym: but most importantly go read Scott Pilgrim.
Rym: There are only three trades out right now.
Rym: You can just go buy them all.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, they look like manga, but they're not.
Emily: Yeah, I picked it up in the bookstore cuz it was you know in the manga shelf and I saw Scott pilgrims precious little life And I was like, that's a great title for a comic book.
Emily: so I picked it up and I leave through it and it.
Emily: the art is what really first caught my eye because it was the Eyes are drawn very big and circular like his very very highly stylized and drawn with like a brush.
Emily: So it's like this ink ink strokes very thick lines and stuff.
Emily: And so it's got certain manga stylings, but really it's.
Emily: it's very unique and as far as its art style.
Emily: But what really makes it is the script?
Rym: Yes, I mean it's hard to explain what is like what it is like why this is different from other comics.
Rym: It's about kids in a rock band.
Scott: Yeah It's also River City Ransom, it's also Freaking every awesome video game pair.
Emily: Yeah, it's a million bajillion Nintendo games like old school.
Rym: And the plot the actual plot of Scott Pilgrim is very simply okay It's not.
Rym: pilgrim likes a girl.
Scott: No, Scott pilgrim is awesome.
Emily: Okay, Scott pilgrim is awesome.
Emily: Scott pilgrim is dating a high schooler is the first lie.
Rym: In fact, that's the name of the first chapter.
Emily: Set up right.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Scott pilgrim has a gay roommate who's awesome.
Emily: Who's also all this is the best character.
Scott: I I say Scott pilgrim is in a band called Sex Bob-omb, which is an obvious homage to.
Scott: yes There are other bands.
Rym: There are other bands in this comic called such things as clash at demon head Which if you don't know what that is, you are not from the video game generation Sonic and Knuckles.
Emily: Yeah, all the bands are named after old Frickin.
Rym: everything this is nothing but references to pop geek culture from the mid 80s to the mid 90s.
Scott: Basically the the course of the story is that there is a girl Ramona flowers who Scott pilgrim kind of digs more than Knives chow who's in high school?
Emily: She's a delivery girl for Canadian amazon.com.
Scott: amazon.ca.
Rym: Well, you know, yeah dot ca.com.
Rym: Okay, we're not really good.
Rym: I mean we could talk a lot about the specifics because the way he actually meets her Really kind of sets the stage for what this kind of comic is.
Scott: The whole plot is there.
Scott: she Ramona flowers has seven evil ex-boyfriends and Scott pilgrim Has to fight all of them in order to date her.
Rym: Yep, but she totally likes Scott pilgrim.
Scott: So she totally does and he totally likes her.
Scott: but he still has to fight the seven evil ex-boyfriends.
Scott: in each volume Some evil ex-boyfriend or boyfriends show up and are fought.
Rym: now I mean, it's even finding the point that they don't say right away seven.
Rym: They're kind of vague like five or six.
Scott: He's like not to fight them all at once.
Scott: Well, maybe not all at once, but maybe not one at a time either.
Rym: Yeah, now this comics put up by Brian Lee O'Malley Draws it and he writes it.
Rym: It's being published by oni press who's awesome.
Rym: It's coming out real slowly.
Emily: You know, I I'm not a fan of LiveJournal or stalking people on LiveJournal, but after you read the comic I'd suggest checking out his blog because he does this thing called annotated Scott pilgrim and he puts up all his reference photos Explains what you know.
Emily: all the settings and characters and stuff are based on like.
Emily: it's so full of inside jokes Like not even just Nintendo jokes and stuff, but he gives a lot of props to his friends in there, you know He's like, oh, you know, I'm gonna write my like his roommates based on an old roommate He used to have.
Emily: you know, I'm not sure if they wait a minute.
Emily: Wait a minute.
Emily: So no Wallace.
Scott: Wallace is a real guy.
Rym: There's a real guy out there who's like Wallace.
Emily: Yeah, I don't know if they actually like shared the same mattress or anything.
Rym: Homosexuality plus plus.
Rym: Now Wallace is the man.
Rym: in fact probably my favorite.
Scott: Almost every character is the man even if they're the woman.
Rym: but what my favorite scene in the whole thing Barnon is.
Rym: Scott is laying on the ground and he's sad and he's pissed off.
Rym: He's miserable and the world's sad and he's laying there and he's like, you know, what sucks everything everything sucks.
Rym: And Wallace is standing there and he's making bacon and he says listen to this.
Rym: Okay, just listen You hear that that's market bacon hitting the pan today.
Rym: A child is born unto us and his name will be bacon.
Rym: Smell it.
Rym: Do you smell that smell that everything does not suck?
Scott: It's true.
Rym: I mean the humors all like that is kind of this low-key but yet at the same time Completely out of the blue out of the water over the top people flying through the air throwing knives at each other.
Scott: Yeah I think I think what makes this comic more than anything else are all the characters that are awesome and the dialogue Interaction just has a really nice flow to it.
Emily: It's like a lot of back-and-forth kind of banter.
Rym: It's very much the kind of banter that you hear between two people playing a video game.
Emily: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Now the thing is it starts out really kind of mundane, you know, there's a little weirdness But it's kind of just a story.
Rym: and then it gets more and more video gamey.
Rym: like at one point Scott beats this guy The best part.
Rym: I love One guy and money falls out.
Rym: He's like sweet like a dollar.
Rym: But then he beats one guy and his own head appears floating and he freaks out.
Rym: He's like the hell is this?
Rym: It's creeping me out and they're like, it's an extra life dude.
Emily: He's like, oh sweet.
Rym: He grabs it.
Emily: I Still think the funniest thing.
Emily: Well other than the coins falling down.
Emily: It's like spare chains falling down and My favorite one was there.
Emily: They're in a club like before a gig and so they're all waiting around.
Emily: and there's this He looks over in the corner and there's this white glowy spot, you know This is before he's going to talk to his ex-girlfriend.
Emily: So he's really nervous and he sees his white glowy spot in the corner.
Emily: He's like, what's that?
Emily: Is it a safe spot?
Emily: and Kim is like, yeah, it's a safe spot and he makes for it.
Rym: Gotta go and see.
Rym: it's like this normal world with normal people except at the same time It's this video game world and got like magic portals and like super excited.
Scott: Yeah, my favorite video game joke is when he says so are you guys an item and he's his items and you see a mushroom A star and a flower.
Scott: that's like.
Rym: that's all he can think about.
Scott: Yeah, he's like.
Scott: no not that item.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: You can't the 10 Pokemon.
Rym: You can't have 10 pokemons.
Rym: You can't read 10 Scott pilgrims.
Scott: You can't read 10 Scott phone cuz it's only three Scott pilgrims.
Rym: There's going to be only six.
Rym: It's already halfway over.
Scott: wait But I thought there were seven evil ex-boyfriends.
Scott: What's up for that?
Scott: Huh?
Emily: Let's see, he's already beaten three of them and that you we know spoilers OMG.
Scott: They did say that Scott pilgrim was like the best fighter in like the area There's so many is up against vegans.
Scott: Scott pilgrim is just that.
Rym: no, it's not that vegans have psychic powers It's just that the guys like watch out this guy's a vegan and everyone knows just like.
Rym: oh He's got vegan powers then.
Rym: Yeah, and it's just straight-up.
Rym: vegans have powers.
Rym: Yep I mean that he'll throw in all this weird stuff, but it's so mundane.
Rym: You just it's just part of it You don't even wonder.
Rym: I mean the first guy he fights the first ex-boyfriend Just summons a bunch of demon hipster girls and then they have a dance-off.
Emily: It's one of those things where he achieves a remarkable level of suspension of disbelief, you know Good way to put it.
Emily: funniest thing is it's been optioned for a film and you know It was rumors on the internet and it's even on his site and I checked on studio systems and it's got.
Emily: It's.
Emily: it's not been written yet, but it's got a script writer assigned and it's been optioned.
Rym: and everything in 2005 Universal announced I'm coding Wikipedia that they have optioned the property for a possible future film adaptation.
Rym: Edgar Wright is attached as director and Michael Bacall is to write the screenplay.
Emily: So I'm looking forward to this.
Emily: if it's ever done as animation it could be really slick Yeah, or even live-action might work.
Emily: Yeah, actually, it might be really really funny as live-action considering the whole sort of magical realism video game world Maybe.
Scott: I think you would just it would definitely because animation is the way to go.
Emily: I mean the art style is so cute, you know, it'd be a damn shame not to see that It would be hard to do all the brush lines Mmm, you couldn't just animate it the way it's drawn.
Emily: Yeah, it would be.
Emily: it would be more difficult.
Rym: Think how about with computers if they just made models and stuff course then because the art changes a lot.
Rym: It's real.
Rym: the character designs are really kind of loose.
Scott: Yeah sometimes I get a little bit confused as to who's who because there's no color and you need to kind of it.
Emily: sometimes they'll point out Like they'll draw a little line and say she dyed her hair Like Ramona is kind of like me cuz I'm always doing weird stuff with my hair and You know dyeing it and chopping it off and stuff.
Emily: And so Ramona is doing the same thing and she's got a different hairstyle every chapter and it does get a little bit confusing.
Scott: Yeah, I made like Scott Pilgrim here.
Scott: He worries about a haircut and then you know, they make a big deal out of it.
Emily: He doesn't like getting its hair cut.
Rym: He also doesn't realize that bread can make you fat.
Rym: I'm just I'm flipping through it.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of things he doesn't realize.
Rym: Yeah now, I mean all the characters are awesome.
Rym: We should probably talk about him a little bit.
Rym: I mean, there's Scott Pilgrim.
Emily: Let's do an introduction.
Rym: Scott Pilgrim He is the best fighter around even though he actually seems to kind of suck and everything And he doesn't.
Emily: he's actually kind of soft-hearted and he doesn't want to fight Sometimes and he won't hit girls and that was a big thing.
Emily: a bunch of evil girls jumped out of movie posters and attacked him and he refused to hit him and and Ramona had to come and kind of wasn't that in like a web thingy.
Emily: No, that wasn't free comic day.
Emily: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: That's actually how I found.
Rym: It was I do who kept telling me read Scott Pilgrim read Scott Pilgrim.
Emily: I know Yeah, she was.
Emily: she'd like do little things of her characters in the same style and stuff.
Rym: Yeah She's probably the biggest guy I know I've ever seen.
Rym: and she telling me read Scott Pilgrim read Scott Pilgrim And then she introduced us to Brian Lee O'Malley.
Rym: We got to meet him.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: He probably wouldn't recognize if we met him again.
Emily: He did a little sketch.
Rym: There's a little Ramona sketch.
Rym: Yeah, I got.
Rym: he drew a tiny little Ramona in the in the book that I got.
Rym: Mm-hmm But yeah, and then I got free comic book day.
Rym: There was the free scout pilgrim and it was unmitigated awesome.
Scott: It's all of its unmitigated awesome.
Rym: So Ramona flowers pretty much a ninja delivery girl Also has seven evil ex-boyfriends and wants to date Scott and she's not stupid as Scott.
Scott: She's pretty smart.
Rym: She is a really cool well-rounded Character with a secret history that is obviously going to come into play with this guy.
Scott: Yeah, she's got that's.
Scott: the only thing wrong With Ramona is that she has like these secrets.
Scott: I don't know what the secrets are like.
Scott: she could be up to no good, but she's probably not.
Emily: Oh, I don't think she's up to no.
Rym: She's got a past and she's trying to you know, she's trying to leave it behind But yeah, but there are references to the fact in the third one that she might actually be evil and this is all some sort of Yeah, I didn't get that.
Emily: that's gonna have to read it again.
Rym: I was getting yeah.
Scott: It's kind of sketchy like because you could try to get stuff but it's not so Fleshed out fully.
Rym: so you're kind of iffy on a lot of especially when again it is hard sometimes to tell Exactly, like you'll change pages and the scenes all switched around.
Rym: It's hard to tell who's who.
Scott: Yeah It's so low is sometimes a little messed up.
Rym: My advice is to not try to figure out what's happening or not what's happening, but what's going on and just roll with it.
Emily: You'll get a city action like there's a.
Rym: you could figure out a whole bunch of stuff and it's totally not worth it.
Rym: So then there's knives child the 17 year old girl that Scott Pilgrim was dating in high school Who and I think Emily agrees with me is probably the best representation of a high school girl I've ever seen in a comic.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: It's so accurate as to what high school girls are like.
Rym: no offense to our high school girl listeners But you were all like this girl.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: I mean good God all of them.
Emily: Maybe they don't go around attacking people with.
Scott: you know, ah, I knew a girl in high school But Scott Pilgrim dates knives chow and you know, then he kind of doesn't.
Emily: yeah She does the Asian Asian gossipy thing where she's like reward as a fat white girl Yeah, and Bobby's kind of Fabi and stuff like that.
Emily: She talks like some people.
Rym: I know it's so funny But I mean while she's an annoying high school girl But your character is also very cute and endearing and very sweet when she's not stabbing people.
Scott: She's not bad He's just you know, he's just the way high school girls are.
Rym: Yeah, and of course the only reason this mom of this comic actually exists and the only reason to live Wallace Wells Scott's gay roommate.
Scott: Oh my god Rims gave her me.
Rym: there's a section of like 10 Parts of this manga where I keep calling it a manga.
Emily: It's not it's a kind is I mean they classify it in the manga section?
Rym: Yeah, but I mean they all put it in the manga section.
Rym: it sounds like manga.
Rym: a lot of people call it manga.
Rym: Yeah, the word is kind of broad.
Rym: It's a graphic novel, but there's this whole.
Rym: They very often will have a little black box next to a character with like their name their age And then something about him relevant to the scene.
Rym: and it happens all the time.
Rym: It's like a running gag.
Scott: Well, I'd say at the beginning of every book the first time you see a character, you know in each volume They'll put a little black box telling you the characters name and a sentence about them.
Rym: Yeah, but they also do it sometimes randomly and almost always Wallace gets incredibly gay.
Emily: No, pretty dang game.
Rym: And then it'll point to Scott Pilgrim like not gay or or the other Scott What was it?
Emily: He doesn't have a last name.
Emily: They just call him the other.
Emily: Oh, that's also done one.
Rym: Now that would be school, yeah, especially in the third when they introduced all these other characters that totally don't matter But they all get a name.
Emily: Yeah and a funny bit about them, but like so many He actually knows and the places are just you know.
Emily: on his on his blog He posts up all these like.
Emily: this was taken from this place and it's just all his old hunts in Toronto.
Rym: it's kind of funny but Wallace Wells is easily the funniest character in this comic.
Emily: He's very kind he's got kind.
Emily: he'll kind of tease Scott and pick on him, but he's very generous.
Rym: He's also Scott's kind of Yoda.
Rym: He teaches Scott.
Rym: He guides him.
Emily: Yeah, it's kind of like Scott's.
Emily: He's.
Emily: he's clueless but endearing.
Emily: Yeah, it's kind of like Oh Scott.
Emily: You're being a dick again.
Emily: Why are you doing that?
Emily: And then like Wallace Ramona will talk some sense into him.
Emily: That's kind of nice.
Scott: Yeah, it's a voice of reason.
Scott: it seems like those are the only two characters who are really like smarter than Scott and everyone else is.
Scott: You know, it's like Scott is in the middle and everyone else is either like stupid normal or evil in some way.
Rym: Well, then there's the other only character.
Rym: I really want to talk about Kim pine.
Rym: Kim is good who is easily the smartest character in the comic.
Rym: She's very grumpy.
Rym: She doesn't care at all about any of this going on.
Rym: She's the one who's always like it's a one-up.
Rym: Yeah, it's a save point.
Emily: Scott's high school girlfriend.
Emily: Yeah kind of sullen.
Scott: and now she's the drummer for sex Baba.
Rym: She's kind of surly and she reminds me of some people we know because she's surly in the not actually surly kind of way.
Emily: Am I surely?
Emily: no.
Emily: Oh good.
Emily: Okay.
Rym: I was referring See again the privacy because I'm saving it all.
Emily: or When you come out with the episode that just disses everyone our friends.
Rym: Lee Nesbitt 41 Rochester Street was a total dick to us when we were sophomores in college.
Scott: Oh, yeah Rym pine was this total dick.
Scott: Kind of jokes got me some real tires.
Emily: That's kind of like kind of like a dream sweepers greatest hit.
Rym: Kind of joke your mom makes when she's tired.
Emily: My favorite joke was when he's complaining as the bus drives away like I think Wallace Tells him he can't come home or he's having somebody over so he has to go to.
Scott: Yeah, that's always an issue is like when Scott wants to have a girl over.
Emily: He doesn't even have his own bed and one time they have a diagram of the room and it's just.
Emily: you know, like Wallace's TV It labels everything and tells who the owner is and it's less just like Wallace Wallace Wallace Wallace.
Emily: And then it's like mess on the floor Scott.
Emily: Don't be poster Scott and that's like the only thing.
Emily: so basically he's just Borrowing all his roommates things.
Rym: No, Scott feel good.
Emily: I mean I think that shirts mine.
Emily: It is.
Emily: Yeah.
Emily: Well, I wore it yesterday.
Rym: Yeah, the comic keeps alluding to things in the past that it doesn't explain at all.
Rym: So it's pretty much totally open and they can just make up whatever they need to make up whenever they need to make anything.
Scott: Uh, who's they?
Scott: he one guy makes the whole thing.
Rym: We have like the characters themselves couldn't make it.
Rym: Oh, yeah Yeah, it's just totally up in the air as to what's actually going on at any point.
Emily: That makes it sound just too random though.
Emily: It is really kind of random Yeah, but you know in a way that doesn't drive you off like some things stay there too Fragmented and it's really hard to follow any sort of through line of the characters.
Emily: Where's this?
Emily: Yeah, that's the point.
Emily: Yeah, that's just nonsensical Monza.
Rym: I kind of yeah, but like it's got pilgrim Don't try to read it like you would read a deep work of comic literature.
Rym: Don't like puzzle over every page and read every word like huh Scott said this.
Rym: I wonder if that means blah Just run with it read the whole book in one go and then go.
Rym: that was awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's really the only problem with it, you know.
Scott: other is that it's kind of disjointed and it doesn't you know.
Scott: I mean the pacing of it is good like the rate at which things happen, you know, and depending on what's happening is really good Except sometimes you can get lost because sometimes someone will say something that feels like it should be a page ahead.
Scott: You know, it feels like you lost a page.
Scott: You're like is a page torn out of the book what happened?
Scott: or sometimes you'll feel like you went back a page.
Scott: you know, it gets a little weird but Other than that, it's it's fantastic Very inventive.
Emily: things like.
Emily: I like the one where he does the little Panels as I was gonna say that before things that I thought were funny.
Emily: But as as well as says you can't come home You got to go over to Ramona's place and the bus is driving away and the panels just like divide by half And they get really really tiny and you have to have practically a magnifying glass to read the last one.
Emily: It's just like him insulting Wallace's go in.
Emily: It's just kind of like as the bus goes Insults - they're my they were good in size.
Rym: So if nothing else, you'll get a lot of good insults out of this.
Scott: Yes Now especially if you're in high school, these won't work so well outside of high school But in high school these apart, I think they'll work really well among our demographic.
Scott: They will indeed That's another thing.
Scott: Is this comic?
Scott: if you're not in the geek?
Scott: Demographic.
Scott: this might not hit home.
Rym: you weren't born between 1979 and 1989.
Rym: Scott Pilgrim will make no sense to you most likely.
Emily: So this is this is a great part.
Emily: Wallace is heckling this one band from the balcony and they play really really passes.
Emily: it's not a race guys and the.
Emily: the girl who's the vocalist is.
Emily: The song is for the guy who keeps yelling from the balcony and it's called we hate you.
Emily: Please die one, two, three Goofy little things like that.
Rym: Yeah, every joke is the throwaway joke.
Rym: Yeah, there's a million of them.
Scott: Now if you don't it seems like the whole thing is just an excuse to pile on these throwaway jokes.
Rym: But yet the story is Pretty good like at its core.
Rym: the actual story if you take it at face value seems like a good story.
Rym: It's not even story.
Emily: It's more like the emotions behind it.
Emily: It's like Scott being lost.
Emily: you really feel for the characters.
Emily: It's not even so much you're engaged in a in a story as you're engaged with the feelings of the characters and you empathize with them.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there's a scene in the third one where a character was a bad person and everyone agrees and that character gets kicked in the nuts And that is such a moment of vindication in that comic.
Rym: It is in deal.
Rym: you're right there with everyone in the crowd really.
Rym: Yeah, that guy got kicked in the nuts.
Rym: Totally deserved it.
Rym: now if you don't believe us is how awesome Scott Pilgrim is.
Rym: I'll note that it was a Nominated for two Eisner Awards two Eagle Awards.
Rym: it didn't win any of these.
Rym: it was nominated for all of them.
Rym: O'Malley won the Outstanding Canadian comic book cartoonist award and The dog right award.
Rym: Yeah for best emerging talent.
Scott: If you go to the official Scott Pilgrim website I'm sure there are some free previews of Scott Pilgrim.
Scott: so you can read some.
Scott: Scott Pilgrim before You know buying Scott Pilgrim and then after you decide that you like it because you're not gonna come to any other conclusion You're gonna go to the store and buy all three volumes that are out right now.
Rym: Yeah now don't make the mistake.
Rym: I did cuz.
Rym: for some reason there seemed to be a lot more copies of three around than there are of Two.
Rym: so I had one and I didn't see two anywhere.
Rym: But I saw three.
Rym: so I bought it and it sat there and I couldn't.
Rym: I didn't have two Available and I kept saying I'll just read one page of three and put it down.
Rym: I'll just read one more page and I read the whole thing before I read two and it didn't make any sense.
Scott: All right Cinecon.
Rym: So we're pretty much gonna wrap this up because we do have to prepare for Cinecon which again will be going to this weekend October 6th 7th and 8th.
Rym: I promise I won't plug it anymore because I don't need to.
Rym: we're going.
Rym: it's coming.
Rym: It's done tomorrow.
Scott: clown pistols.
Rym: Yeah, clown pistols.
Emily: I'm sad.
Emily: I didn't get to talk about my movie to start your own podcast Suck.
Scott: I didn't get to talk about the boob sword or the boobs or wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Scott: There's a boob So I can't say anything.
Emily: We've run out of time.
Emily: It's impossible.
Emily: what I really wanted to say though is it was funny because I was on the forums after I did the show last time and I was Incredibly amazed because people are like that Emily lady should come back on.
Rym: I was like.
Rym: I have never blessed so hard.
Rym: We got more.
Emily: I can't be back about Emily being on the show I was like and you said I had an accent which I thought was funny.
Rym: Well, you kind of do.
Rym: it seems to be more pronounced when you use.
Scott: I don't think you have an accent.
Scott: Sometimes you don't talk normally like you're right now.
Scott: You're talking and like kind of like the cute voice intentionally.
Emily: No, I'm not.
Emily: Well, that was that was when I was talking normally.
Emily: That's like cute small voice.
Emily: people say I have a different voice when I talk in Japanese - My voice gets higher, which I think is funny.
Rym: Anyway, yeah We're going to have Emily on the show in the future because many of you have expressed interest in a couple of topics and I'm going to Finland.
Rym: so Finland Finland the land full of They something something All right From Japan.
Rym: that is some way moving pictures on a screen.
Rym: So if you have questions about Emily in Japan Yes questions questions about living in Japan because the thing is like.
Emily: I said, I tried to record stuff before But I think I couldn't do a podcast, you know, I tried to do it.
Emily: It just felt and none of us didn't have any energy at all And so I can't just sit here Especially when these two are around and talk about things that they are not able to have input on.
Emily: So it's even though I want to talk about.
Emily: these three movies are actually four.
Emily: No, no, no, no.
Emily: five movies No, six six movies five is right out.
Emily: No anyway, um, I Wanted to talk about these these films.
Emily: I saw they haven't seen them yet.
Emily: So on one hand.
Emily: I'm like, haha I know something you don't know but on the other hand, it doesn't make the show this this woman You would not believe when full metal.
Rym: Oh, that was great.
Rym: I was like.
Emily: you have no idea.
Rym: Thing of if someone sees something.
Rym: before someone say the only thing you can say is you have no idea.
Scott: Yeah, oh my god.
Scott: You have no idea.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: So of course because Emily understands Japanese She was watching Full Metal Alchemist almost a week ahead of all of us.
Rym: So every week I get a phone call.
Rym: you have no idea.
Rym: I'm like, yeah, I have no idea.
Rym: I get it son of a bitch.
Rym: I Was tempted to rosh bras, but that doesn't work so well because I only understand the useless parts of the language.
Scott: I also understand all of the useless parts.
Emily: I'm also happy cuz my comics cost half as much or less True.
Emily: I bought.
Rym: I bought Eva comic Scott and I have talked about this on the show before.
Rym: if we could afford.
Rym: Well one.
Rym: if we could read Japanese if I could read I would buy so much manga.
Emily: I would oh It's kind of like me me when I was in Japan.
Emily: I was like, oh I get the Discount at the bookstore.
Rym: So I'm gonna buy all these models actually like, you know There would be a pile of every piece of gecky guy in the world in this house.
Scott: I would go like there's so many manga that I'd like can't read now and aren't gonna be out here for years like 20th-century boys and other stuff and like they're like 30 plus volume relations are Yeah, I don't go for that.
Rym: You read almost all of Death Note scans lated.
Scott: Yeah, but it wasn't so great.
Rym: Yeah, it was you raved about it every day.
Emily: The funniest thing is some of the translators.
Rym: you got caught saying something that wasn't fully true.
Emily: This this might sound kind of you know You know But some of the scans laters they I don't know if they have English as a second language or what but it's kind of hard.
Emily: Understand some of the dialogue on some some of these translations.
Emily: It's almost more straightforward If you'll know Japanese to just buy the one dollar comic off the internet or off a book off if you live in a city And and read that instead It's a learning experience.
Rym: So anyway, come to Cinecon, especially if you're Australian And if you have questions for Emily about Japan anime in Japan Japanese culture Upcoming live-action adaptations of anime or Anything along those lines post them in the forums.
Rym: We'll do.
Rym: is an interview segment in the future in the near future.
Rym: so get them in quickly and There will probably be a recording of me being shot in the face with a clown pistol tomorrow.
Scott: I also got shot in the face with the clown pistol.
Rym: Yes, but slightly after me slightly after Yeah, and also I don't think as much of the powder went in your goddamn eyes cuz I saw it coming a mile away.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.