Scott: It's Wednesday January 4th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We talk about the boy who saw the wind.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I fell asleep at work again.
Scott: You actually fell asleep at work like I
Rym: was sitting in the control center this like data center We have with the hum of all the machines and all the coolers And I was looking at a packet capture And I just fell asleep like sitting there staring at it, and then like a minute later I woke up like what what where the hell am I?
Rym: oh crap?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: Wow really asleep?
Rym: Yeah, I really haven't slept more than a few hours since our party on New Year's which was many days ago.
Scott: You know in all of school ever I mean I've rested But I've never.
Scott: I only fell asleep asleep in a class once.
Rym: what in school?
Rym: I would regularly go into a class plop my head down and just go right to sleep.
Scott: Well like purposefully.
Scott: I only fell asleep really asleep one time because it was just so damn boring.
Scott: Oh my god
Rym: See I would go to classes specifically to sleep like I'd be tired but I will go to class pretty much just in case the professor decided to give us homework or Told us when the test was and I'd kind of like find out that way or maybe there was homework do and I'd find out That I didn't do it and America turned it in late.
Rym: but Other than that I didn't care about anything else going on in the class.
Scott: I just sleep in the back, and I always messed up like which classes to go to and which ones not to.
Scott: yeah I refresh from in year.
Scott: I skipped like a chemistry class on a Friday, and there was a test and you could drop one test But that was the easy test.
Scott: so they don't get a bad grade.
Scott: because I skipped the easy test and I took the hard test That came later.
Scott: even though I knew all the stuff from like high school chemistry I just totally didn't care about it and forgot yeah luckily I didn't have to take any science at RIT.
Scott: I got that all taking care of in high school Yeah, and then let's see like software engineering There was like a lecture for part of the quarter, and I skipped like all of them But two or something crazy like that.
Scott: I just know I don't even remember the.
Scott: I didn't go to it at like all.
Rym: I don't know what I was thinking, but I probably should have gone to that even though It was kind of crappy and boring one class I accidentally didn't skip like I accidentally went to class because I forgot what day it was and that actually saved me.
Rym: I Was visual basic - and VB is probably the stupidest language ever and the class was stupid.
Rym: and there's a lecture in a lab and the lecture consisted entirely of An exam like 80% your grade this exam And then the rest was a pass/fail lab and like a little bit of lab work.
Rym: so I went to the labs because I had to but I never went to the lecture after the first day and I went on what I thought was the last day of class to take the exam and Then I discovered that actually it was Wednesday, or it was it was Wednesday, but for some reason.
Rym: I thought it was Thursday.
Rym: So and also the exam was two parts over two days.
Rym: So I accidentally showed up the day early when the exam started and thus I didn't fail.
Scott: luck Yeah, what if you had gone in the last day?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: About 20 people showed up on the first day of the exam and about 60 people showed up on the second day.
Rym: Wow Yeah, that's how awesome that class was.
Scott: that's awesome.
Rym: I got an A.
Scott: That's really awesome.
Rym: Yeah, the professor was like I haven't seen any of you before.
Rym: sure you're in the right class.
Rym: He was this final Japanese guy, but he wasn't that interesting.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know if it was because of the subject matter if he was just a boring guy, but never saw him again.
Scott: if only I had a DS in those days.
Rym: Oh Well When I had that laptop or that tablet PC, I was testing for the school I just took it to class and friggin red slash dot like I never really did anything.
Rym: I didn't pay attention any.
Scott: that's I think is a good thing.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I didn't have a laptop in college because that's what I would have done.
Scott: I wouldn't actually paid attention any class.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of our classes took place in labs with computers So I just be dicking around on the internet or doing homework for other classes.
Scott: It's great when they have a lab with rows and rows of computers facing the front.
Scott: the teachers at the front.
Scott: He can't see what's on any of the monitors.
Scott: Yep Yep, and then you walk by and this wind is glass wall and you can see what everyone's doing And half the people are in aim and half the people are playing poker Man.
Rym: I miss those days so much Mmm, yeah, you know what?
Scott: I laugh at them now because guess what?
Scott: I got a degree despite all that fucking around.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We got degrees and jobs High-paying jobs.
Rym: Yeah, we're adults.
Rym: Very it's kind of scary.
Rym: I mean, I got my tax thing in the mail yesterday and it wasn't the 1040 easy.
Rym: No, it was the 1040 a which is like the.
Rym: you're an adult and you have to pay real taxes.
Scott: form Mmm, I'm gonna have to do that.
Scott: I think I do it myself.
Scott: I'm like a website somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, I used to use H&R block just because it's free and it's easy.
Rym: But I'm gonna do it myself because I got a lot of like weird deductions and I don't trust them.
Scott: I'm either gonna use a website that I just fill it out for free or I'm gonna use the website where I pay a little Bit of money or something like that.
Scott: It shouldn't be too bad.
Scott: Yeah better than mailing shit.
Rym: so the DS Reached the 10 million mark.
Scott: as in there are 10 million ds's.
Rym: as then 10 million ds's have been sold.
Rym: Now know what I say sold and not shifts because that's what Sony has this thing where Sony Will say how many PSP's were quote unquote sold, but they mean sold to retailers not sold to people.
Rym: Nintendo in the press release Specifically said 10 million ds's have been sold to people.
Rym: We have shipped many more.
Scott: those 10 million are the ones that people bought Mm-hmm kind of a jab at Sony in their number faking Mmm, well, you know what it always happens that when you're winning the numbers game You always want to stick to the truth in the numbers game and do that.
Scott: But when you're losing the numbers game, you always want to you know, fudge it and then make up some talky-talk.
Scott: I mean when Nintendo is losing the numbers game with the GameCube, they did the same thing.
Scott: So it's it's just that's just how they play.
Scott: Yeah But it makes it easy to just you know.
Scott: You never know the exact number unless someone goes and finds it out with a lot of money and research to you know Do the real stuff.
Scott: but it just lets you know, who's winning is the people who are going?
Scott: These are the real numbers of the winners.
Rym: So DS winning yeah, and you know what.
Rym: there I think I see all the reasons why it's finally all come into clarity.
Rym: For one I noticed that all the old guys in my office who like don't even know who Mario is and I have no idea About video games.
Rym: They all got their kids ds's and Nintendogs or things like that like Animal Crossing for Christmas and They had no idea how the Nintendo Wi-Fi worked and I had to spend like 10 minutes today explaining to them what it was And how to use it.
Rym: They just like didn't get it.
Scott: Nintendo did everything that possibly could to make it easy for people.
Scott: Well, I don't know why they don't just sell the Wi-Fi things to people like in the store.
Scott: Like if you want it you have to kind of get it online.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But they were amazed when I showed him Nintendo Wi-Fi calm and they discovered that Wow every McDonald's Everywhere just about has a Wi-Fi.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: They were like, how do they?
Rym: why would they do that?
Rym: It's not that popular is it?
Rym: and I was like, well one it's super popular and two.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, shut up I Mean having free Wi-Fi.
Scott: the McDonald's just keeps fat people.
Scott: another reason to keep sitting there to maybe get another burger.
Rym: well, a lot of people around here don't have broadband like Surprisingly a lot of people considering how close we are to New York City.
Rym: Mmm, I mean either it's not available or they just don't see a need and a lot of them are paying a lot of money For really crappy dial-up.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know why anyone used dial-up anymore.
Scott: Just don't get it.
Rym: Actually, my dad just got dial-up.
Scott: He just got it.
Rym: It's $8 a month.
Scott: That's not so bad.
Rym: Yeah, considering all he does is surf the web a little and check his email.
Scott: No, I mean just check an email.
Scott: What though?
Rym: Yeah, cuz the cable company out there was raping him Mmm, even with the discount for having cable TV.
Scott: I've heard of DSL people raping but not cable.
Rym: Yeah, the cable people here are raping us a little compared to what we should be paying.
Scott: Yeah, but that can be expected because we're trying to screw their business model, you know, it's yeah.
Scott: At least it works and it's fast.
Rym: Though the other factor aside from you know little kiddies playing in ten dogs That we really really found out and we really really pushed to the max.
Rym: at our New Year's party.
Rym: We had eight people and eight DS's.
Rym: Let me tell you eight person bomber man where Every single person in the game is a real live person who's sitting next to you and punching you in the arm after you blow Them up is one of the most fantastic experiences a man can have Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean it's pretty amazing back in the day when you had like four game boys with that wire thing.
Rym: Yeah, those stupid wires you're huddled like in a corner all together.
Rym: You can barely move.
Scott: someone pops their cable out in the game's over Yeah, but like while it worked, you know, it was the greatest thing, but there was just frustration like Overhead.
Rym: this is that times a million like we're at seven I remove all the frustration overhead and you double the fun.
Rym: We're running around blowing each other up.
Rym: one person like gets up to go to the bathroom.
Rym: They just bring the DS in there with him and keep playing because it's wireless.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and Eight player Mario Kart pretty much defines that game.
Rym: I mean if you've not if you don't have seven friends with DS's kill some hobos and Reanimate their corpses as zombies and then give them DS's and teach them how to play and then race against them Why just give the hobos DS's?
Rym: They're hobos.
Rym: what you rather have a zombie than a hobo Zombie is better is tomorrow is tomorrow.
Scott: All right Yeah.
Rym: So the DS wins and the sales are actually split pretty much 50/50 between the US and Japan.
Rym: Japan has like 1 million more.
Rym: it's like 5 million Japan 4 million US and then like one in every other country They have a percentage.
Scott: wise that's not so good If you look at the number of people total in US.
Scott: first total in Japan That's like many many.
Scott: a big percent of Japanese people are DSN and many many small Percent of US people are DSN.
Rym: a lot of people have pointed out that.
Rym: one reason for that is that in Japan?
Rym: There's one more gamer market.
Rym: that games have come out for that.
Rym: Haven't hit the US yet?
Rym: those train your brain games I just don't understand.
Scott: I mean Nine, there are some games that are very difficult to bring across to other countries and that's understandable.
Scott: I mean if you make a game about learning the Japanese language or a game about learning English and it's all in Japanese or very very text heavy games You know where there's like actual writing of text like a Tokimeki thing where it actually read.
Scott: they have a huge Very powerful complex system of reading Japanese words out loud Text-to-speech.
Scott: I can understand not bringing that thing over directly because it's very difficult.
Scott: But there's no reason you can't bring something over like they still haven't brought over Shonen jump The fighting game.
Rym: Yeah, even though every fanboy in the world imported it.
Scott: Yeah, I know it's like Why.
Scott: it would take me maybe maybe a few weeks if I had a kit to translate the game if I had also had a translator with me and Put it out in the US.
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: Just even if you want to delay it like a little bit put it out in the US Three weeks later put it out in the US a month later.
Scott: It's been like months and months and months and months.
Scott: what the hell's wrong with you.
Scott: There's no reason not to release Every single game you can and every single market you can.
Scott: you know, if you have to I Remember when they released Katamari in the US.
Scott: they didn't know it was gonna be huge But someone must have pushed for the release to happen.
Scott: That's why every store sold out because they didn't know is gonna be a big game.
Rym: They just bought like it like two copies in each store or whatever and then also that See they should do what the anime companies do and just go to gamer conventions anime conventions and just look at what kids are talking about and then import those games.
Scott: and Or what they should do is like the game stops and the EBS should import games like or at least offer a game import service like.
Scott: here's a list of games that you can import for like 20 bucks more than The normal price and then see which games get imported.
Scott: and as soon as a game gets imported like a single store Like two or three times it's time to you know, get that game over here.
Rym: Yeah Pronto but these train your brain games.
Rym: they hit this demographic of gamer that has not yet been touched in the u.s.
Rym: It's older people who want mental stimulation.
Rym: It's basically the same market as people who like really get into crossword puzzles or like Sudoku.
Scott: I don't know what's up with this Sudoku thing.
Rym: God a guy work out like.
Rym: really he discovered and got really into it.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It looks to me like I didn't.
Scott: I've seen Sudoku before in my life and I knew about the puzzle and I always thought it Was a dumb puzzle because a computer can solve it in about two seconds.
Rym: It's the same as minesweeper you sit there and it's a task that you can miss repetitive and once you learn the pattern It's just a matter of iterating it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There's no actual thinking involved.
Scott: It's just you know, once you know how to find the solution.
Scott: You're just performing an algorithm that the computer can perform and it's not really like a strategy or a complex thought or anything.
Scott: but anyway enough about the game itself.
Scott: I Saw it a long time ago because I used to get all those little game magazines, you know for stuff to do unlike trains and stuff and planes or long trips in the car.
Scott: and Sudoku is one of the puzzles that was thrown in.
Scott: it wasn't any different from any other ones.
Scott: I usually didn't do it because it was boring but It's like.
Scott: all of a sudden I started seeing these things like Sudoku's the latest craze.
Scott: And then right after I heard Sudoku was the latest craze I saw books and I saw like pages and newspapers and it was all over the place.
Scott: and I'm thinking to myself I didn't see it being a craze Before.
Scott: I see it being a craze now, I think is a manufactured craze.
Rym: I could see that.
Scott: I could really see that I really think Sudoku is a manufactured craze.
Scott: No one was interested in Sudoku.
Scott: It was just some other dumb puzzle just like all those other dumb types of puzzles, but I think someone said hey We can make books out of this and make a lot of money.
Scott: Let's do some PR Make everyone think it's a craze and then put out books right before the holiday season and put it in newspapers and it worked.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So if they can man your if I want to find out who manufacture if it is indeed manufactured because I think it is I'm 90% sure.
Scott: I want to find out who manufactured the Sudoku craze and have the manufacture crazes about all sorts of nerdy things.
Scott: I like to make them popular and cheap.
Rym: but moving on in slightly less Video game related news because you could consider voting a video game.
Rym: I guess it's just a really boring video game and the end always sucks.
Rym: Wisconsin did something awesome.
Rym: land of cheese Basically, they have.
Rym: well they did a little while ago and you might have heard of it.
Rym: But today the governor signed it into law and this law states that one Anytime.
Rym: an electronic voting machine is used in Wisconsin.
Rym: It must be fully 100% open source.
Rym: That's good - there must be a paper trail.
Rym: that is both untamperable Like you can't tamper with it and you can visually verify your own vote before you leave the booth.
Scott: That's good, too.
Rym: It's pretty much exactly what anyone who's smart has been advocating for the last forever should be a federal law.
Rym: Yeah, well, Wisconsin did it die.
Rym: bold is very pissed He'll d bold.
Scott: Yeah, well Their choices are not sell voting machines to Wisconsin or make voting machines that don't suck.
Scott: Yeah, see the thing is is this great?
Scott: because you know normally Devold could technically get away with giving good voting machines to Wisconsin and bad voting machines to everyone else, right?
Scott: But it's not profitable for them to make multiple different kinds of voting machines, especially just for one exception.
Scott: so either they can just give up on Wisconsin and lose that money which they probably will do and someone else will fill the void or They'll just make all of them the Wisconsin way and then you know sell the same machine to everyone.
Scott: But then is the problem of states might not actually use the paper trail.
Scott: They just might not put any receipts in it or whatever, you know, who knows?
Rym: Well, this law says you have to.
Scott: oh, yeah But I'm that's it only in Wisconsin.
Rym: Yeah, so even though even then if it's open source It's a lot harder to screw with it because if there's a back door some geek will see it and say hey, why is that there?
Scott: Well, I don't think that debolds about to release any source that incriminates them.
Rym: No, cuz honestly not to be sound like anything.
Scott: do that'll be the most Larry's thing ever?
Rym: I mean I'm not saying that debold through the elections or anything like that because there's really no way to know even though there's a lot of Circumstantial evidence.
Scott: Yeah, a whole lot.
Rym: The thing is there's too much circumstantial evidence that even if they didn't affect this election They set themselves up to be able to affect an election that is not in dispute.
Rym: There are obvious Easily exploited back doors that just alter the vote count and then cover the tracks Like.
Rym: that's not cool.
Scott: Not cool at all.
Rym: So we don't know if they ever did it or not, but they obviously could have Mm-hmm, and I don't think they're going to open up their source because that would incriminate them.
Rym: So if they want to sell voting machines in Wisconsin, they're gonna have to start from scratch.
Scott: I think what probably gonna end up happening is it's constantly some other voting machine.
Rym: Yeah, or they'll go back to you know, non-electronic voting.
Scott: I like non-electronic voting.
Rym: I like it in some ways.
Rym: I don't like it in other ways.
Rym: What's wrong?
Scott: Well, I don't like writing writing on a physical ballot and I don't like the hole punching.
Scott: I like the clicky machine.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: even the clicky machines are bad because they don't always Work perfectly.
Rym: and then you have to.
Rym: you have to figure out what to do with the broken ballots.
Rym: Remember the hanging chads in 2000?
Scott: Yeah, that's the hole punching.
Rym: Yeah, but all voting machines have issues like that.
Scott: I Yeah, they when you it's like there's odometers in the back Just like in your car.
Scott: has you know the odometer?
Scott: and when you vote the odometers go tick tick tick tick tick And they count up one.
Scott: it pretty much works unless the machine is broken.
Rym: Yeah, and you know machines often break because they're not very well maintained.
Rym: They're not used often.
Rym: No one really knows much about them.
Rym: Yep, but I mean look at look at go to when you vote.
Rym: look at the people running the election.
Rym: People don't have jobs or crazy people.
Scott: Yeah but they do test all the machines before they use them to buy Voting on them and then looking in the back to see what the numbers are.
Scott: yeah, and then you know if that checks out then it checks out and They you know.
Scott: if it's broken then usually what happens is when you pull the lever It won't pull or it won't ding or when you try to click certain switches down.
Scott: They won't click.
Scott: That's how you know, it's broken.
Rym: Yeah, usually but the thing is if one does break There's really no way to get the votes back.
Scott: Well, you know audit trail Let's say a hundred people vote and then it breaks.
Scott: You open it up you write down the votes and then you use another machine or you just start using paper ballots.
Rym: if you can Write down the votes depends on how it breaks.
Scott: Well, there's an odometer in the back So the voting person opens it up and writes what says down there.
Rym: Yeah, what if we just start?
Rym: what is it spins wrong?
Rym: What if one of the gears is screwed up and spinning backwards?
Scott: I I don't know if that could happen.
Rym: It's I'm just saying the fact the fact that there's only one method there needs to be and and some sort of checksum some sort Of.
Rym: there are two parallels separate methods of counting the vote.
Scott: Hmm Usually what happens though is if the mechanical machines break they use paper ballots, but you can't really have two Ways of voting without having people vote twice on two different things.
Rym: You know, well you can.
Rym: to Wisconsin you vote on one touchscreen.
Rym: it prints out a Verifiable like name of the candidate you voted for behind glass on a receipt that then goes into a big Pile of receipts in a sealed box and it also counts electronically.
Scott: Hmm I guess.
Scott: but what if like, you know, it has to display the receipt to you, right?
Rym: Yeah
Scott: so there'll be like a little piece of glass and the piece of paper will show up under the glass and you'll look at To make sure it's right and then if you like say no it goes in like a trash bin and you say yes It goes in the voting bin.
Scott: What if like there's actually an hidden receipt under that one and that one goes in the bin too.
Scott: that you couldn't you know?
Scott: You couldn't see it down there or something like that.
Rym: If you set up see it's a lot harder to fool people with mechanical things than it is to fool them with electronic things.
Rym: It's real easy to just not do what the screen says in electronic thing.
Rym: It's real hard to make a complex device because remember one It'll be open source so people can just look - it'd be pretty obvious if such a complex mechanism to cheat was actually in there.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: But however open source could still fool people because let's say you know There's the motor control code that controls the motors and makes them spin and makes the machine do its physical printing thing.
Scott: If you don't actually have the machine and the code together Looking at just the code like on the internet won't tell you that.
Scott: hey that makes the machine Spin like extra votes down into the machine on paper or something, you know?
Scott: Or even that.
Scott: let's say you use a barcode on all the paper.
Scott: What if the barcodes don't match what the words say?
Scott: so it might say voting for Joe blow.
Scott: But the barcodes are all the same on every single one of them and they use the barcodes and the paper recount because they're lazy.
Rym: The thing is frauds like that are much more difficult to perpetrate Because they're much more easily noticed.
Rym: That's the whole point here.
Rym: It's not to make fraud impossible It's to make it difficult because the more difficult is the more likely.
Rym: if someone tries it they get caught.
Rym: and if you get caught Rigging a vote.
Rym: That's the end.
Scott: What is the penalty for vote rigging like?
Rym: no idea?
Rym: Like I don't.
Rym: it doesn't matter.
Rym: the legal penalty doesn't matter at all.
Rym: If if a presidential candidate were actually caught cheating that they're done isn't it?
Scott: I don't think any presidential candidate actually cheats.
Scott: I think people cheat for them.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and then the question is didn't you know?
Scott: should the president be responsible if someone cheats for them?
Scott: Because if that's true, then I'll know the other guy.
Rym: I found out Nixon didn't break into the Watergate Hotel.
Rym: Some guys just broke in for it.
Rym: Yeah, but he told them to yeah, you can't prove that a hundred percent It's true.
Scott: But what if I go down?
Scott: Let's say I I join the election volunteers and beacon right and the next presidential election is a verse B and I'm gonna vote for a. I like a but I Cheat in the election to boost B and then people blame B and say B's a cheater.
Scott: well, that works out well for me, doesn't it?
Rym: Well, they have to catch you first and Otherwise, it's just it'll but one it wouldn't even matter.
Rym: things like that generally don't get reported.
Scott: I know that's I mean.
Rym: in the 2004 election There were a lot of scandals all over the place that hit the mainstream news and then disappeared and no one talked about him again.
Rym: Yeah, and in a lot of recent elections in Chicago And it wasn't I'm not just single in Republicans both Republicans and Democrats had a lot of people vote for them who happen to have Died long before the election.
Rym: dead.
Scott: people vote in every election.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what that shouldn't be.
Scott: it definitely shouldn't be.
Scott: I don't know how.
Scott: They didn't even check my ID.
Scott: I just registered to vote.
Scott: I came in.
Scott: I said who I wasn't.
Scott: I voted.
Rym: Yeah, they didn't.
Rym: they didn't want me to verify anything.
Rym: They showed me my name and then they asked is that your address?
Scott: and I said, yes Even asked me if that was my address or anything.
Rym: and then I signed a scribble.
Rym: I saw the pencil.
Rym: they didn't have a pen.
Rym: They had a pencil.
Rym: Yeah, and I was like, can I have a pen?
Rym: They're like, why would you want a pen?
Rym: I was like, so no one can erase my signature and vote again.
Rym: Mmm, and they were like what?
Rym: because they were there was like these two old ladies.
Rym: They were like a hundred thousand years old.
Scott: Nah, I Think the thing is is that they want so much freedom of voting and that if you want security of voting you're gonna need to Reduce freedom of voting.
Scott: and You know while I'm all for freedom, I think voting right now is a little tiny bit too free Like a tiny bit like you can just walk in and click no matter what.
Scott: Yeah, that means you can go in and click twice.
Scott: You can go and click in different places.
Scott: You can go, you
Rym: know, plus like if I was an election worker I mean when I went I voted kind of late in the day and In this most recent election the election that almost no one voted in And one they I asked like so many people voted today and they're like no one was gonna come after me.
Rym: It was obvious and like 200 people out of the like 6,000 person little voting district.
Rym: I'm in had actually voted Mmm, it was kind of sad.
Scott: Well, that was a local election.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, no it was the.
Rym: it was Election Day Yeah, but it was there just there just didn't.
Rym: there was only there were two state issues.
Rym: We voted on.
Scott: yeah, but compare that to a presidential election.
Rym: like a thousand of people come out Even in a presidential election only about half the people vote.
Scott: if that yep, but people don't really care about all right.
Rym: So there's two election workers in the whole place.
Rym: at this point It'd be real easy for them to just put scribbles on the names of all the people who haven't come in and then put their Votes in forum.
Rym: Yeah, there's no way to know.
Rym: There's no way to stop it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I Don't know what to do about that.
Rym: I just don't trust people and Rightfully so because I can think of how many ways I could gain the system if I wanted to and I know there are people Who are smarter than me with fewer scruples?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: All we need I'm telling you we need to reduce no matter how distasteful it is.
Scott: We need to reduce Freedom of voting because it's too free to introduce some Guarantees of voting because if you can't guarantee voting then democracy really just doesn't even matter, you know.
Rym: so my thing of the day may not be the newest thing, but it's new to me and I hope it's new to you because it's hilarious and The payoff was much greater than I expected when I first started watching it.
Scott: I have no idea how new it is.
Scott: But when I haven't seen it until just just recently which means Wow Yeah, we watched it we.
Rym: one of the things we did our New Year's party when we were bored is we have the computer hooked up to the TV downstairs and We were just sitting around taking turns showing everyone else funny things on the internet and always a great thing on the internet.
Rym: but this particular thing is the ultimate showdown and That really says it all.
Rym: I
Scott: Always love those, you know, I'm not a fan of fanfiction but a lot of fanfiction is just like showdowns between guys or You know people from different universes or different stories like getting together
Rym: Yeah, getting together in a BL kind of way Yeah,
Scott: but you know the ultimate showdown is pretty much everyone from everything getting together and just great.
Rym: Yeah, any any nerd loves that action and I'll warn you the tune is a little catchy and it might get stuck in your head But eventually it'll get annoying and you'll not want to hear it anymore.
Scott: Yeah It's one of those types of songs.
Rym: It's definitely worth seeing.
Rym: I laughed my ass off, but I was a little drunk.
Scott: I have a feeling that it's at least is new.
Rym: It's newer than the Chuck Norris page because it has Chuck Norris in it true Though the Chuck Norris page just came out of a joke on Conan O'Brien show if I recall correctly.
Scott: So then this must be newer than that joke, at least.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All right, so my thing of the day.
Scott: well You ever use MAME the arcade emulator?
Scott: Yeah Yeah, well, there are a lot of people out there who use MAME apparently and have all sorts of ROMs for it and everything And I used to have some but anyway apparently the practice of making MAME Machines as in constructing arcade cabinets to run MAME on them or Taking arcade cabinets and replacing the insides with a computer that runs MAME is a lot more common than I previously believed.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, like so common that this one guy made an entire webpage displaying pictures of MAME machines that he thought were crappy and explaining why they're crappy
Rym: and explaining why they're why they're crappy in a Very funny and eloquent way I might add
Scott: a ranting hilarious sort of internet funny guy kind of way.
Rym: Yeah, I remember.
Scott: Hey crackhead Yeah, exactly the same type of thing.
Scott: and just to show that he's not a complete idiot.
Scott: He has he displays one of his own MAME cabinets and he says yeah just to make sure I'm not an idiot.
Scott: Here's one of my cabinets - look how ugly it is.
Scott: I can't believe I did that.
Rym: See, I mean some of them are like wow.
Rym: someone tried to make something cool and it's not that cool.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: some of them are like wow, it's like you went out of your way to make something uncool.
Scott: It's really just people trying to make one with the best of their Craftsmanship ability and not having so much ability or design sense or anything and just making something crappy.
Rym: It's like when I tried to make my DDR hard pad.
Scott: Yeah exactly like that I mean.
Rym: it turned out really well except that it didn't work.
Rym: and then when I made it work It was ugly and I ended up just throwing it away.
Rym: No, it was a good experience, yeah, I learned to not try to make a hard DDR pad.
Scott: Here's the best.
Scott: one is pretty short.
Scott: It's a looks like a normal arcade cabinet.
Scott: it's got sticks with six and buttons next to them and a start button for each player and There's a monitor in there and he has the the centipede marquee on it.
Scott: But the size of it all have that marble texture on them and he says marble.
Scott: It's still awesome because he made fun of one previously for having a marble texture because they're all ugly.
Scott: Then he says better yet.
Scott: It's got a centipede marquee and he doesn't even have a goddamn trackball.
Rym: You know I should make a main cabinet and just only have one game in it Rampart and I'll have a freaking trackball three trackballs.
Rym: It'll be cue balls from a billiard set.
Rym: See I'm gonna get real Atari trackballs if I could find him see.
Rym: the only my gripe about the Atari trackballs Were that they weren't massive enough.
Scott: They're pretty massive.
Rym: Yeah, they're more massive than those massive giant like cut off the tips of your fingers trackball.
Scott: I remember them being more massive than billiards balls.
Scott: So I don't know why you would want to use billiard balls instead.
Scott: Maybe I'm Emma wrong.
Rym: I think you do.
Rym: billiard balls are kind of massive.
Scott: apparently what a lot of people do is they get the balls from You know those golden tea golf machines that are popular in bars.
Rym: Those are the stupidest things ever.
Scott: They're pretty dumb, but they have that ball in them and that's an art.
Scott: that's a good arcade ball and a lot of people either get them from golden tea golf machines or They get them from the supplier who makes the golden tea golf machines, huh?
Scott: so that's where you can get.
Scott: you can still get the balls for arcade machines nowadays and The thing is looking at a lot of these main cabinets.
Scott: It's kind of scary.
Scott: I think a lot of people are running golden tea golf on there because they have the balls Positioned right in the middle of the controls, but golden tea golf is a bad game.
Scott: I know but I guess these people It's like some of them are obviously only playing certain games on their meme because they only have certain controls.
Rym: Well, then there's that one guy who has every control.
Scott: Yeah and there's a few people who have like every control scheme possible because obviously they're trying to play every type of game, you know, I It's not worth it.
Rym: But anyway, it's anime day and we watched one new show.
Rym: It's not that new but it's a movie.
Scott: actually.
Rym: Yeah, it's a movie called kazayo mita shonen or the boy who saw the wind.
Scott: I Like it a lot It's alright.
Rym: I liked it.
Rym: It's it a lot of people think it's a Ghibli movie.
Rym: In fact on nausicaa.net it's on the page of movies that are commonly mistaken for Ghibli movies And many VCD bootlegs of this movie have the studio Ghibli logo on them.
Scott: when I first downloaded it it was pretty much just.
Scott: I was on the anime ski and I saw a torrent for The boy who saw the wind Ghibli style movie and I said well, I never heard of this But I'll get it.
Scott: and I got it.
Scott: and we I watched it alone a long time ago and forgot most of it But we watched it all together again.
Scott: Just this weekend.
Rym: See it's alright.
Rym: It's really pretty like it looks like it's just in a really old style But the style is really well done.
Scott: I think it was done in 2000.
Rym: It's RIT's not that old Yeah, but it looks a lot older than it is.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and it's just the typical, you know, there's a boy.
Rym: He has a power.
Rym: He goes on adventure to save people and it's good, but it's kind of simplistic.
Rym: Like there's good guys.
Rym: They're perfect.
Rym: There's bad guys.
Rym: They're absolutely silly Lee evil.
Scott: Oh The bad guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, the bad guy is like imagine Hitler.
Scott: only I think they could have made that a little better if they would have Added some.
Scott: they they could have shown the the rebellion sometimes in a bad light like look they're killing people, too Yeah, but they always had the bad guys with those like masks on so that you know.
Scott: Then when they do that kind of thing if they would have humanized those guys in the masks a little bit more to make the Rebellion that seem you know, not perfect and great and if they would have had that evil scientist lady
Rym: Not turn insane Yeah
Scott: They should have actually like made her someone who is Nice and is like forced into evil.
Scott: so you kind of like feel bad for instead of going out She's a crazy not get rid of which is what they seem to start doing right away And they just forget like alright, she's crazy.
Rym: They make her crazier than Ritsuko's mom from Ava.
Scott: Yeah, every other anime seems to do it the way I just described this one was just like forget.
Scott: It's not worth the effort, but it was still good.
Rym: It was just.
Rym: it was really simplistic.
Rym: like every time they needed to move the main character somewhere else for a change of scene or To move the plot along they'd have him fall from a great height Be knocked unconscious and wake up in a strange land.
Scott: Yeah, they did that twice right at the beginning.
Scott: Yeah, it was great.
Rym: It happens a grand total of three freaking times.
Rym: Yeah, they need Another way to move the plot.
Scott: They didn't only hope or a trap.
Rym: It's a trap.
Rym: Yep, but it's definitely worth watching.
Rym: I mean I enjoyed it and There's a lot of good characters.
Rym: It's real sad at points.
Rym: We can't ruin the end and I suggest you watch it because there is a twist that I didn't see coming.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I'd seen it before and I forgot what happened at the end and then I was like, oh, right Not like the other ones where there's a twist that it was so strong.
Scott: you remember it that way when you see it again You're like, ooh, it's gonna happen again.
Rym: It's just a it's a it's a twist.
Rym: You don't see coming.
Rym: That's really all I can say.
Rym: I Did not expect the movie to end the way it did.
Scott: It was a good ending.
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't think there could have been a better ending for what they had already done in the show had the ending not Been the way it was.
Rym: I probably would have written the show off because other than that it was just kind of a Typical predictable.
Rym: see that was the worst thing.
Rym: It was pretty much a hundred percent predictable.
Rym: watch other than the twist Every single thing that happens.
Rym: you can predict from like the previous two things that happened.
Rym: And as we as we were all watching the show because we watched it at the party We had everyone here and it was basically just everyone was yelling out Oh, obviously blah blah blah is gonna happen and then blah blah blah happens.
Rym: It's like every time there's a happy scene There's a sad scene right after it.
Rym: that pretty much is a direct thing that ruins whatever was happy.
Scott: That's a problem though with all kinds of things these days is that when you've seen enough anime or you've seen enough movies or television over the course of your life.
Scott: Everything gets predictable and you need to watch really complex or really weird stuff to find something that's not predictable.
Rym: Yep, you know thing is even they get predictable because the the unpredictability itself becomes predictable.
Scott: Yeah It's like oh, he's gonna do the opposite of what's normally gonna happen.
Scott: So he's gonna do this.
Rym: Oh, I got it, right Yep, like we started a while ago.
Rym: We were watching like Hitchcock movies.
Rym: We were watching the old Hitchcock movies like early in his career.
Rym: Like they're they're good, but they're hard to watch.
Scott: and oh like in the first one I figured out what was gonna happen like, you know, right before it happened at the end.
Scott: Yep, but then later on I was like saying what was gonna happen like Like minutes and minutes before it happened.
Rym: cuz back then like it seems like the big thing with movies back Then was to put a twist at the end like every movie had a twist.
Scott: Well, no, that's not the big thing back then.
Scott: That's Hitchcock's thing And I've seen a lot of other movies from that era of course, but Hitchcock is like the twist master.
Rym: The problem was once you like start figuring out how the twists work.
Rym: You always predict the twist because it's always just think what's the least likely thing to happen?
Rym: Well, that's obviously how the movies gonna end.
Scott: Well, it's not the least likely thing to happen.
Rym: The least likely thing to happen is something crazy the least likely thing to happen that is still possible to happen.
Scott: It's not really something that's least likely.
Scott: It's actually very likely.
Scott: It's just unexpected.
Scott: It's the thing that is most Unexpected to happen but still makes a whole lot of sense and is very exciting a lot of times though.
Rym: They didn't make sense.
Scott: Those are the bad Hitchcock movies that no one remembers.
Rym: Yeah, like the one I don't remember which one it was.
Rym: where they're?
Rym: they're conflicted.
Rym: The bunch of characters are conflicted about killing someone and then they end up not even having to worry about it because a freaking bomb Blows up the train they're on and the guy dies.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, that's just something crazy.
Scott: But like 39 steps is very make sense You know.
Scott: and and me?
Rym: yeah, yeah, they're also highly predictable.
Scott: some of it was highly predictable, but it's one of those things where You can predict it if you remember everything that happened in the movie Because the twist is something that you forgot.
Rym: that happened way at the beginning though Regardless this movie is highly predictable.
Rym: if you've seen like three or four other anime in your life You'll probably just know exactly what's gonna happen in this whole show, but it'll still be fun.
Scott: If you like movies and things then if you've seen them all and you're looking for more of that and Ghibli doesn't supply frequently enough and you're bored and you want a movie to watch Boy who saw the wind is great.
Rym: there's also a really funny.
Rym: he ends up wake one of the times when he gets knocked out and wakes up somewhere.
Rym: he wakes up in this village and Apparently their sole source of food is hunting these Zabbi Zabbi Zabbi our giant fucking man-eating kill-you-all fish like a whale Barracuda mix thing.
Rym: like a bunch of villagers die and they finally take down this fish and then they have a big feast and then Later and then everyone in the room with us is like why don't they just hunt smaller fish or something?
Rym: This is kind of silly.
Rym: and then in the show one characters like why do we hunt these stupid Zabbi all the time?
Scott: Yeah, that's great.
Scott: I Something and then whoever made the show gave the message that's not good.
Rym: Yeah, the moral of this show is really heavy-handed.
Scott: It was like you're disrespecting the Zabbi by not eating it.
Scott: Like it's already dead You know and you know, we eat it and it eats us and it's come, you know They tried to make a message out of it.
Rym: That was pretty Yeah, not deep in its presentation like the evil dictator at the end when he like.
Rym: Try to do this not ruin anything.
Rym: basically at the end of the movie when the evil dictator whatever is happening to him He pretty much is like oh, I wasn't evil.
Rym: I was just lonely.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they say it right right out whereas other shows are more subtle and subtle is not like.
Rym: surely Stimulating the show is definitely not subtle not subtle at all.
Scott: it's hard to be subtle when you have a kid flying around and You know cute little animal going me me me me.
Rym: Oh, yeah the cute little animal.
Rym: I totally forgot about that.
Scott: and then they had the cute little animal babies.
Rym: Yeah, that was really cute too cute.
Scott: I mean I seen cute things but those the little babies were just like where the tail was more than half the body.
Rym: Oh my god, I think they were supposed to be foxes.
Scott: If for nothing else, you should just watch the show to see the cute animal.
Rym: and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: also, please visit our website at www.front row crew comm for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.