Rym: It's Thursday March 23rd, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about South Park and Futurama.
Rym: Let's do this so as you all may have noticed the hosting is down or was down for several hours today at least.
Scott: Yeah, it's so pleasant when this happens.
Scott: You know it just makes my life terrific.
Rym: Yeah, well it has nothing to do with me.
Rym: It's all Scott at the hosting.
Rym: so if you have complaints send them to him where he'll ignore you.
Scott: Yep, and I'm working on it.
Scott: You know I noticed before anyone else noticed.
Scott: so No amount of yelling at me is gonna make it fix sooner.
Rym: damn it Scott fix it.
Scott: You know what.
Rym: now I'm gonna go slower all right that hurts You just as much as it hurts me.
Rym: cuz your blog and everything's up there, too.
Scott: I don't care so people won't miss it.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's the end of the world.
Scott: Scott's blog isn't online.
Scott: Podcast website isn't there Mmm.
Rym: Anyway, you had some things you wanted to say before I started with the news.
Scott: Oh, yeah all week I've been trying to remember to tell everyone about.
Scott: We got the frapper map Frapper comm slash front row crew where you put a little pushpin on the map to say where you are.
Scott: so you know It'd be cool if everyone did that.
Scott: also, we have a separate feed for each day now and When the blog comes back up you can go to front row.
Scott: crew calm and there's a little how-to With links to all the separate feeds and the links of separate feeds are on the right side of the page in Case you only want to subscribe to maybe just Thursday or just Monday or something.
Rym: yeah Even though I'd recommend that you subscribe to all days for various reasons.
Scott: yep The forum is there when the site comes back up which everyone should join and have a lot of fun talking in.
Rym: Yeah, even though we just started a fairly awesome thread that got killed by the fact that the forums currently down.
Scott: Yeah, it's just terrific.
Rym: Yeah, and thanks to all you people who keep messaging me telling me.
Rym: It's down.
Rym: I know.
Rym: yeah I know.
Scott: of course you won't hear this until much later when it comes back up.
Rym: Well actually you can't hear it until it comes back up because unless I make my own RSS feed on Libsyn There's no way for us to put the episode up even though Putting the episode up has nothing to do with the site other than the fact that WordPress makes the RSS.
Scott: Yeah, couldn't we just like go tell feed burner to add a link or something?
Rym: no No damn.
Scott: oh well whatever.
Rym: I might make a backup RSS feed on Libsyn Just so I'll be able to put up episodes even if the hosting goes down.
Scott: There might be a good idea.
Rym: so then the only people who are fucked are the people who don't subscribe and just go to the Site.
Scott: actually the only people who are complaining right now are people who use the forum right yeah And people who actually visit the website which is a small percentage.
Rym: and all the people on our jabber server who got pissy after jabbers Working that.
Rym: yeah, it's working now, but it went down and knocked them all off.
Scott: Yeah, it did.
Rym: But in the news Nintendo made two very very interesting and happy announcements at GDC.
Scott: Yep, the first one is Zelda dm the phantom hourglass.
Scott: It's always the something something you know well.
Rym: the first one was just the legend of Zelda.
Rym: Then it was the legend of Zelda's.
Rym: oh yeah the adventure of link mm-hmm.
Scott: So yeah, they always add something Better of time.
Scott: you know.
Scott: it's always some object and then the object has some power.
Rym: uh Minish cat.
Scott: Yeah, it was a hat and it was Minish.
Rym: Word doesn't mean anything.
Scott: It was a made-up word.
Scott: It doesn't matter the wind waker It was this wand that wake the wind you know?
Rym: yeah, anyway this game looks.
Rym: I mean you can download a trailer preview II thing.
Scott: yeah There's a video floating around the night.
Scott: you can go look at if you want to.
Rym: I'm excited.
Rym: I just hope this game is good unlike the Minish cap which was disappointing to say the best.
Scott: yeah It looks like it's some sort of in between 3d 2d kind of game But mostly it's in the style of the awesome portable Zelda games.
Scott: but there's some stylus type puzzles going on in a few of the rooms and It looks generally awesome.
Rym: I'm also really hoping and I really I'm reasonably certain that there will be some sort of cool Wireless multiplayer even if it's not a full-on game.
Rym: I can imagine something.
Scott: They really just put four swords DS out.
Rym: Yeah, that'd be fantastic.
Rym: I know they keep saying that Crystal Chronicles DS is gonna come out, but yeah, we'll see about that.
Rym: Yeah, it's still at the bottom of game.
Rym: facts on the announced, but no date list.
Scott: great.
Scott: The other announcement is that the revolution we all know it's gonna have some old-school Nintendo games for you to download and emulate and all That.
Scott: yep, NES SNES now.
Scott: It's gonna have.
Scott: officially There's gonna be some Genesis and some turbo graphics games.
Rym: now They said that it's not gonna be every game But I think the words they used war were a best of compilation.
Scott: so bonks adventures a guarantee.
Rym: Yep, maybe the original turbo graphics 16 Bomberman or our type.
Scott: This turbo graphics 16 is pretty much just an R-type machine as far you know and there's a cool racing game.
Scott: I forget the name of.
Rym: Yeah, there's a bunch of cool racing games actually.
Rym: yeah beach volleyball wasn't that bad?
Scott: Yeah, there's a really good volleyball for the NES Super Spike V ball.
Rym: yep Actually, I got a guy at work who has a turbo graphics 16.
Rym: It's the most modern gaming console.
Rym: He owns other than the DS He bought for his daughters.
Rym: well I went over there and played some awesome racing game.
Scott: if I like how the games for the turbo graphics It's you know like these little plastic cards.
Rym: Yeah, and how a lot of them are five player.
Scott: Yeah, that's crazy.
Rym: Yeah, what the hell?
Rym: I mean, it's it's not for like every other game system ever.
Rym: I mean the Atari was even for player.
Scott: Yep, I don't get it, but whatever turbo graphics 16 is cool.
Scott: I like how.
Scott: I had a turbo on the controllers.
Rym: that was something else - yep You couldn't call it cheating if it came with it.
Scott: You know what I remember about the turbo graphics 16 is a long time ago.
Scott: when it came out the mall had like this event like they came to the mall with like a million kiosks of Turbo graphics 16 machines and filled the hallways and handed out videotapes so that would like demonstrate the software to you and all this sorts of crazy stuff.
Scott: and like I didn't even never heard of this thing before until I went to the mall and saw it and then after that No one ever bought one.
Scott: We just it was just this thing that happened at the mall one day.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't.
Scott: you know if it was like a new Nintendo?
Rym: I never knew anyone back in the Nintendo days who had one.
Scott: the only people I knew had one were like my rich Distant cousins and I went to their mansion once and played it and that was that.
Rym: now We did have a friend who had a neo geo.
Scott: Neo geos are cool.
Scott: Yeah, but they're really only cool if you're in Japan where they have all the neo geo arcade machine.
Rym: I just remember when the kid was telling me how much each game cost and I remember wanting to just cry because I wasn't rich.
Scott: Yeah The whole point of the neo geo was supposed to combine the arcade in the home experience.
Scott: So like you would go home and practice king of fighters And then you would go to the arcade with your memory card and play king of fighters against people.
Scott: That was the point of the neo geo.
Rym: Yeah, the problem was it was hellishly expensive.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Oh Yeah, but in actual as in non video game news Internet Explorer has another horrible critical rootkit security hole.
Rym: Great it's unpatchable.
Rym: It appears in every version of Internet Explorer currently in use all the way up to and including The most recent beta of a ie7.
Scott: it really is in the eyes beta whatever.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's in beta 2 of ie7.
Scott: That's like the newest.
Scott: I can't believe it.
Scott: There's a bug that means that they didn't completely rewrite ie from scratch and they made beta 7.
Scott: Yep Wow It's.
Rym: it's a horrible bug.
Rym: Apparently it's been well known among script kiddies and leet hackers loser types for the last 40 or 50 days and Someone just discovered this in a forum where people were talking about exploits.
Rym: They've written using it and he posted it to some full disclosure list.
Scott: Okay, so if you're still using Internet Explorer.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: You know what?
Scott: No, if you're using an explorer and something happens to your computer You have no one to blame but yourself.
Scott: Firefox is free.
Scott: if Firefox wasn't free.
Scott: You could have an excuse but no, it's free.
Scott: Yes Opera opera Mozilla and Firefox works in old shitty computers too.
Scott: So what the hell?
Scott: Everyone use Firefox damn it.
Rym: Yeah or something?
Scott: Yeah, come on.
Scott: What the hell now?
Rym: I have it on good authority that Microsoft has known about this for at least a month and no patches come out.
Rym: yet Let's cuz.
Scott: they only patch in like the second Tuesday of the month.
Scott: It's always called black Tuesday.
Rym: Yeah, except the last time something like this came out for ie they released that patch early.
Scott: They really should if it.
Scott: how severe is this vulnerability?
Scott: Is it like I can move your computer and all you have to do is visit my website?
Rym: I saw the three words that I always see and these are the words that always scare me when I see him.
Rym: in any Sort of bug list remote code execution At administrator level or not The advisor guy read doesn't actually say if it can be if it's run as administrator or not But noting that 99% of all Windows users are always logged in as administrator.
Rym: I'm fairly confident that it is a administrator remote code execution.
Scott: Well, I'm also fairly confident that if you can remotely execute code at user level that there's some other exploits somewhere that you can take Advantage of to promote to administrator.
Scott: Yeah, at least in Windows Linux is definitely better about that And Linux is pretty much no way you can promote to administrator.
Scott: unless you grab a user who's like in the wheel group or something Yep, or you know anyone is a decent password.
Rym: That's not gonna happen Yeah, or you know if you just socially engineer your way into root Yeah, that's really the best way to hack Linux.
Rym: Just get to know some nerd who?
Rym: Admins a Unix server out there and steal his password.
Scott: Oh The you know, there's other ways to hack Linux though, like wait for someone to use a really old version.
Scott: Oh the hostings back up.
Scott: I fixed it.
Rym: Haha Hooray, yeah.
Rym: So any of you who are smart out there can correlate the two and figure out exactly when we recorded this episode.
Scott: How would they were figure out when we recorded the episode?
Rym: because they could listen and then they'd know.
Rym: But we mentioned that the hosting just came back up.
Rym: then they could look and see when the hosting came back up.
Scott: How would they find out when it came back up?
Rym: because they're obviously sitting there hitting f5 Every three seconds waiting desperately for GeekNights to come back because their life has no meaning without it.
Scott: Oh GeekNights.
Scott: Is that good?
Rym: Awesome, and the answer that riddle was 947 p.m Yeah, Eastern Standard Time.
Scott: Oh, my clock says 945 must be off.
Rym: Mine syncs up to the atomic clock.
Scott: Well, let this be a lesson to everyone.
Scott: mod PHP doesn't take that long to recompile even if your processor sucks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So if you ever host a popular podcast and you accidentally update something and it breaks something you can recompile it fairly handily.
Scott: Yeah It seems it seemed to be.
Scott: what happened was the configuration file for mod PHP had updated or possibly not updated.
Scott: The configuration file that updated didn't match the library that updated because I paused it right and then The.
Scott: then the server went down.
Scott: then I restarted.
Scott: so I must have paused it in between.
Scott: updating the library in the configuration.
Scott: So remerging it fixed both of those things.
Rym: Yeah Actually now that I think about it I paused something once a while.
Rym: It was Firefox.
Rym: when I was I compiled Firefox instead of using the bin and I gave myself a whole shitload of trouble here.
Scott: Let's give everyone a little handy Linux tip from Scott.
Scott: ready.
Rym: Alright Linux tips from Scott.
Rym: if we had music we'd play it.
Scott: Okay, when you're using Linux Let's say you type in a command and then it starts doing a lot of stuff and it takes like 10 minutes and text is Flying by in your terminal.
Scott: Well, you really don't want to sit there and wait.
Scott: you want you know And you need to use your computer for something else and it's slowing your whole computer down.
Scott: you push ctrl Z. This will give you your terminal back and it'll say stopped.
Scott: What it will do is it will stop doing whatever it was doing.
Scott: and now your computer.
Scott: you can go about your business.
Scott: Of course, it's still sitting in RAM.
Scott: Whatever who cares?
Scott: now You can do what you're gonna do in your computer watch a video or whatever that you know.
Scott: It can't be slowed down by some background compiling or whatever.
Scott: Yeah Then when it's nighttime and you can go let it finish doing its thing since nighttime is the right time.
Scott: Nighttime is that I. you go back into that terminal and you press F G for foreground and you press enter and that will start it up again.
Scott: So that's how you pause and restart things in Linux.
Scott: All right that in Windows Not at all.
Scott: That's not even an option.
Scott: Even if you're the god administrator, you can't do that.
Rym: Well you some applications have that built in.
Scott: some do Think of it like when you have your DS and you close the lid on a game and then open it again.
Rym: Yeah So imagine if you could close the lid on the DS and then there was another screen on the outside and you could use that.
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of what the analogy breaks down.
Scott: It really does.
Scott: You're basically pausing a program So the program doesn't use your CPU or anything, but it still sits in RAM Exactly the way it was when you paused it and then you could bring it back from the dead if you need, you know.
Scott: So if someone that's all it is.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah now I'll just say this What do you guys think of that?
Rym: Do you guys want us to periodically just give random tips for say Linux or computing in general?
Scott: Yeah, that's an idea.
Scott: I just came up with two seconds ago.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I could do a whole episode of Linux tips from Scott.
Rym: Yeah But I don't think anyone wants to listen to a whole episode because anyone who would be interested in that Probably already knows most of them.
Scott: Especially I know at least two of our listeners or at least two of my friends who I know Probably listen at least once or twice if not every time no more about Linux than I do.
Scott: I'm like the third most knowledgeable Linux person.
Scott: I know so they would probably Occasionally yell at me for getting something wrong or doing something an even worse way or Something like that.
Rym: So I you know, yeah, but if you guys like it, we'll just periodically sprinkle little Linux tips in.
Scott: Yeah, could be fun.
Rym: If anything for those of you who maybe don't use Linux might be interested in it just starting it'll be a nice little.
Rym: oh I didn't know that.
Scott: Yeah, plus there's a lot of things in Linux are like I know one piece and I know another piece But I never put the pieces together to like.
Scott: do something awesome.
Rym: Yeah, if you're new to Linux Wait, do you realize just what you can do with pipes?
Rym: Yeah, I mean, but that'll all be for another day.
Scott: It will be Okay.
Scott: Yeah finally found something we can go on and on about.
Rym: So my thing of the day since we were talking about Nintendo and a little bit about Nintendo Wi-Fi.
Rym: As you all know Metroid Prime hunters came out recently.
Scott: So did Tetris DS whoo Now one.
Rym: we just went to the Nintendo Wi-Fi site for Tetris and it is the highest of a chi oldest of old-school Quality website.
Scott: Well, you know the Tetris DS.
Scott: the the big thing about is a bunch of different Tetris modes and each mode has a theme from a different old-school Nintendo game.
Scott: like.
Scott: There's a mode that goes a Donkey Kong and a mode that goes with Mario and a Zelda mode and you know Whatever modes it's cool.
Rym: Now.
Rym: That's not my thing of the day.
Rym: I just noticed that my thing of the day is that Nintendo Wi-Fi keeps track of who's doing well in all the games.
Scott: Oh, yeah in Mario Kart They only kept track of like who played the most and you could see that.
Scott: but it seems like they learn the most Lesson from Mario Kart.
Scott: Yeah in Metroid.
Scott: They have like most headshots most consecutive kills, you know winning percentage All sorts of other great stats that actually mean something.
Rym: Now the leaderboard.
Rym: that shows who is winning in all these stats and there is one player who is obviously the best player At this game currently because he is winning four of the category.
Rym: of four categories He has points games played Consecutive wins and headshots.
Scott: It sounds like this guy's playing a whole lot and he's mastered hitting headshots.
Rym: Yep, though I point out that there is a person Nintendo of America guy who has a 100% kill rate it sounds to me like that guy played one game and One and then didn't play any other games.
Rym: You know what if I buy that I win season Nintendo of America guy.
Scott: Obviously, he made his account before anyone else.
Scott: surprised because he has the earliest account his name shows up.
Rym: Yeah, if that's true, I could see Nintendo saying All right, you have to play a game until you lose or something.
Scott: They don't really care.
Rym: Anyway, but my thing of the day is not that this exists or any of that.
Rym: No, it's something much more base and low brow.
Scott: I'm quite low.
Rym: So what the guy who's winning these four categories?
Scott: his name in the game is I Eat poo, that's a pretty typical name for an online FPS type of action.
Rym: Yeah, usually though the people who have those kinds of names don't do very well.
Scott: Well, no, they do quite well.
Rym: sometimes Depends on the game.
Scott: I mean in now you tell you encounter strike.
Scott: There have been quite a few Osama bin Laden's that successfully bombed.
Scott: I think what's funny about it.
Scott: Is that it's a Nintendo and it's you know, it's a bad Somewhat dirty thing but it's on a Nintendo website.
Scott: I mean if the guy's name the guy could have named himself fuck fuck But in that would have showed up on the Nintendo website, that would be awesome.
Rym: Yeah, you know what though?
Rym: I think I like the.
Rym: I eat poo because it's definitely a level of humor where everyone can appreciate that Everyone likes a good poop joke.
Scott: Oh, of course except for when it's you doing the pooping then you don't like it.
Rym: Yeah, like you this morning.
Scott: Yeah, I had some pooping problems.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's got some bowel Issues.
Scott: damn my bowels.
Scott: That's what I get for having the rest of my body.
Scott: being so incredibly perfect is a messed up bowels.
Rym: Anyway, what's your thing of the day?
Rym: even though I already know I'm just asking because it's a nice segue.
Scott: So this is flash game called don't shoot the puppy.
Rym: It's harder than you'd think.
Scott: so the way this game works is as a puppy and There's a giant freaking piece of artillery like a howitzer some shit right and it's pointed right at the puppy.
Scott: and There's this sign with a smiley face and there's some words and the words say start.
Scott: See if you click on the words that say start the words that say start disappear and the puppy begins to walk away from the gun And towards the sign with the happy face.
Scott: That's all well and good If you give any input whatsoever.
Scott: because look you just click start which means the focus of your mouse is the flash game Which means if you move the mouse, it'll know.
Scott: if you push a button on your keyboard It'll know.
Scott: any time you give any input to this flash game whatsoever The gun fires and if the puppy is in front of the gun it dies.
Scott: So then you lose if you move the mouse.
Scott: So you basically click start and then don't do anything and you wait until the puppy gets off screen.
Rym: So it starts out.
Rym: the first round one the puppy just walks off the screen.
Scott: in Round two it walks a little slower to make it more frustrating so that you might click or move the mouse.
Scott: in round three It pops up a fake pop-up window that I fell for the first.
Scott: And you know this pop-up window shows up and you go to click X But as soon as you move the mouse the puppy dies And you go damn it.
Scott: So basically you just have to resist doing any sort of input whatsoever for as many levels as possible.
Scott: I was only able to do it for about three minutes.
Scott: now It's like six level.
Rym: favorite two levels is.
Rym: there's one level where the puppies walk in slowly and someone throws a ball at it And it walks over picks up the ball and slowly walks off the screen.
Rym: No big deal.
Rym: the next level the ball.
Rym: you see it go flying from the left of the screen way off to the right where the gun is and then passed off it off the screen.
Rym: and the puppy very slowly starts walking to the right away from the gun off screen and Then like a minute later makes his way back and starts walking across in front of the gun again.
Scott: Yeah But you can feel free to do input while the puppy is to the right of the gun because you can't shoot him over At least if the game isn't that stupid.
Scott: where the gun would you know flip over and kill him?
Scott: But yeah, I I think if you just waited long enough every level would give you something new and humorous.
Scott: But I don't know how many levels there are or how many I could stand to sit through.
Rym: see I like games like this.
Rym: It's the same kind of game as the old classic pick up the phone booth and die.
Scott: yeah It's a great game.
Rym: I've any of you out there have ever actually played pick up the phone booth and die?
Scott: the text adventure?
Rym: Yeah, it's very simple.
Rym: We'll play it right now.
Rym: I'll be the computer and Scott can be the player.
Rym: all right I'll do a simple file.
Scott: I know we'll start with the blank.
Rym: look you see a phone booth.
Scott: Open phone booth.
Rym: you open the phone booth.
Scott: I thought you couldn't open it and pick up the phone.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: I haven't actually played pick up the phone booth and I played it once anyway.
Rym: All I know is if you type pick up phone booth.
Scott: It says you die and any other sort of Things that you might attempt might yield humorous results, but the game won't go anywhere.
Scott: You'll still be standing there in front of that phone booth like you can make a call But it just says something funny on the screen doesn't actually do anything.
Scott: But the only thing you can actually do to get the game to go anywhere is pick up the phone booth And that's all it does is kill you.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's all game.
Rym: All right, so today is Thursday meaning we can talk about whatever the hell we want.
Scott: Awesome, what the hell do we want to talk about?
Rym: see honestly?
Rym: We really didn't know until just a little while ago.
Rym: We were trying to think of something nice that didn't require a lot of research or effort mm-hmm and Coincidentally South Park.
Rym: now you all know that Isaac Hayes the noted Scientologist and nutball was a stroke victim.
Rym: Yeah was the voice of chef and after they did their expose on Scientology, he left the show and Then they got in trouble and weren't allowed to show that episode anymore for some shady dealings that the internet is still trying to figure Out.
Scott: yeah, the internet is like.
Scott: maybe Tom Cruise used his Mission Impossible 3 muscle to prevent.
Scott: Maybe they're like Isaac Hayes is still.
Scott: he didn't really quit.
Scott: They quit.
Scott: the Scientologist quit for him because he had a stroke.
Scott: He's not no condition to quit anything and It's just a bunch of crazy batshit, which is what I expect from the Church of Scientology.
Rym: now the South Park guys Decided that you know they're gonna handle the situation in the only way they know how.
Rym: So the season the episode one of the newest season came out just now.
Scott: Let's spoil the whole thing All right, because the internet does it anyway.
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't matter I mean spoilers for South Park.
Rym: Yeah, Kenny dies.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, you know what, you know what they call a Jewish woman's boobs?
Rym: That was the most random throwaway joke I've ever heard in my life.
Scott: What do they call the Jewish woman's boobs?
Rym: I don't know Scott.
Rym: What do they call them jubes?
Rym: Actually, I loved in the beginning the episode when they're sitting there playing Uno and just like draw two fatass perverse Jew and they just yeah, you're a verse to Jew.
Rym: But anyway, they basically set it up where chef was brainwashed by this crazy cult and they used Audio from previous South Park episodes to create the episode so that it sounded like Isaac Hayes was still there
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and basically they made chef a pedophile and such and then they killed it.
Scott: well It was pretty interesting because the only things that chef really does when he's in an episode even in the early South Park which is what I mostly watch is he talks to the children and He talks about making love to women.
Scott: In fact, there's this whole song I want to make love to you woman that he sings all the time.
Scott: so they took that song and they made an episode where chef wanna make wants to make love to the children because that's the Easiest thing they can get him to say with the dialogue available now.
Rym: the best part of the episode was that this episode was in direct response to the whole Scientology debacle and What they did is basically they made up this new crazy call that they called something else that nothing to his Scientology and then it got to the point where they're going to explain what this cult is about.
Rym: and For those of you who saw their Scientology expose they basically show the whole story of Xenu and all that Scientology be crazy crazy batshit BS.
Rym: and then during it they start flashing the words on the screen.
Rym: This is what they actually believe Mm-hmm.
Scott: That's the one you laugh hysterically because it's all true Absolutely true.
Rym: now this episode did the exact same thing only with this made-up called it was obvious that they were just talking about Scientology The.
Rym: the going theory seems to be that Comedy Central refused to allow them to say the word Scientology in this episode.
Scott: I wish we will just be more transparent.
Scott: I mean if someone muscled you into doing something they should say they did it and you should say they did it.
Scott: I'm tired of people doing things all secret e and leaving the internet to guess Yeah, like someone's got to have some nuts and just say be some you know open.
Rym: No one has nuts anymore.
Rym: There's no such thing as Cajones Mojo Moxie in the world.
Scott: They looked they looked in their pants and they saw their own testicles.
Scott: so awesome.
Rym: But anyway by watching this episode we thought all right we'll talk about to American animated shows that we've liked modern ones not like Ninja Turtles or mask or or go-bots Pretty much.
Scott: There's only four shows that fit in this category.
Scott: It's South Park feature.
Scott: I'm a family guy in The Simpsons which are made by the same guy and three of which are on Fox.
Rym: Yep, actually, I would throw the critic in there to Forget the critics a little old duck man's also a little old.
Rym: I love duck man.
Rym: I could do a whole show on duck man Could you really?
Rym: yeah, I've watched duck man religiously.
Scott: I didn't watch enough of it cuz it was on kind of late.
Rym: I watched it.
Rym: The thing is as my parents started seeing what the show was about they were kind of leery of me watching it because I was A young kid and I remember the one time I watched it in my grandparents house And my grandma's sitting there watching it.
Rym: My grandpa's laughing hysterically and my grandma's just like I don't think he should be watching this.
Scott: Yeah, what about do you want to get this beavis and butthead count does?
Rym: Honestly, I watched a beavis and butthead off and on but I didn't really like it that much.
Rym: However, the movie I think was actually an excellent piece of film, but everyone thinks the movie was excellent.
Scott: But the movie was also just a vehicle to push some hit music of the time.
Rym: Yeah, but so was beavis and butthead.
Scott: Yeah, well beavis and butthead didn't really push hit music.
Scott: It pushed like this crap metal and shit that no one cares.
Rym: Hey, they like guar.
Rym: Yeah, I like guar.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So anyway today we're gonna talk about South Park because I don't know whatever we could talk about whatever we want.
Rym: and Then Futurama because we actually just rented a Netflix.
Rym: all the Futurama that's ever come out in order.
Rym: Well, well to kind of fill in the gaps that we've missed over the fact that the show is gone like gone gone alright, so What's the best episode of South Park ever?
Rym: See that's a really tough for me.
Rym: It would have to be that the spoof they did on the Lord of the Rings.
Scott: Oh for me, it's the one where the kid Cartman makes the kid eat his parents.
Rym: I made you eat your parents.
Scott: I made you eat your parents.
Rym: Now a little bit of history of South Park.
Rym: it came out pretty much just as we were going into high school.
Scott: Yeah, like late middle school times for us.
Scott: Wait, so the story was is they made some like goofy little like thing about a snowman or something.
Scott: It was like they literally cut out construction paper and made this show that was like it was like 10 minutes long.
Rym: You could find not even that it's so short and crappy.
Scott: You could find it on the internet somewhere.
Scott: It's short and shitty.
Rym: then they made a second episode Jesus vs.
Rym: Santa.
Rym: Yep, and That was the thing that basically Catapulted them into actual stardom because after that they were approached and hey make us a show.
Scott: Nowadays people make shit like that on the internet all the time and no one approaches anyone for a show.
Scott: The thing was is they made this little cardboard cutout thing Before.
Scott: people were making things like that every five minutes and they made it like with effort and such and it was actually funny.
Rym: Yeah, though it was very I mean the show like The Simpsons and every other show like this started out very differently until it found It's kind of groove.
Rym: I mean The Simpsons for those of you who might forget was about Bart.
Scott: when it started It was all Bart and then it was Homer jokes, and then it finally, you know found the thing of.
Scott: you know Show a plot and give a message.
Rym: Yep, you know South Park was the same way.
Rym: It started with a bunch of foul-mouthed kids swearing at each other.
Rym: That was pretty much the whole show for an entire season and really just nasty stuff like poop jokes.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it was funny, but I think it was only funny in retrospect because I was in high school.
Scott: Yeah, I think the first the first episode that really people thought was hysterical was the Thanksgiving episode.
Rym: Actually remember that one.
Scott: Yeah, that was the point.
Rym: Yeah, but then as the show evolved it actually started becoming one political But not political in any in particular direction just political and topical in general and to it pull The Simpsons Instead of just having it be about you know the four boys and the crap whatever jokes They always made they expanded it and added all these other characters that used to be side characters in his main characters.
Scott: You know I think what it is is when you make a show.
Scott: in your early days You're just trying to make your show and you think real hard about it.
Scott: But then eventually over time you get into a groove and you develop a formula and the formula is what allows you to keep making Shows forever and ever.
Scott: the thing is is that if your formula is really good you can keep making really good episodes forever and ever like mushishi had a good formula and Guess South Park has a good formula in The Simpsons has a good formula.
Scott: Yep I mean the South Park formula is pretty much like you know.
Scott: something terrible happens.
Scott: The boys go and basically say wow this is dumb Man our parents have done some shit.
Scott: Don't ever actually really do anything to fix it.
Scott: so much is just you know.
Scott: go around and talk right to the idiots who are Making the stupid things happen, and then somehow the stupid thing is resolved and usually after some crazy event like you know involving sex and violence or Vomiting or some other hilarity.
Scott: and then the episodes over and they teach you a lesson.
Rym: now when the show started It really was quite literally just swearing and poop jokes
Scott: yeah
Rym: And it wasn't very stimulating in any way other than on a very low brow level
Scott: Yeah, and then they they went into like some sort of sensationalist kind of crap old TV type of stuff like.
Scott: they made the Christmas Episode and they introduced you know they have like a Christmas poop, but it was his name.
Rym: Oh, mr.. Hanky.
Scott: yeah, mr.
Scott: Hanky the Christmas poo that was it.
Rym: yeah, they basically are trying to be the grossest most sensationalist crap They could come up with.
Rym: yeah And then this actually culminated in one of the most infamous practical jokes that's ever been played on.
Scott: I was gonna talk about it.
Rym: Oh the Terrence and Philip thing.
Scott: yeah So Cartman if you don't know one of the characters is Cartman the fat kid no one likes And he has a mom who's a whore and his dad doesn't exist in the show.
Scott: Yeah So they were gonna do this two episode thing and reveal his father in the second episode.
Rym: So they dragged it out to all hell.
Rym: Like dragged it out and dragged it out, and then they were what it wasn't it like.
Rym: alright You'll have to find out like next season.
Scott: No.
Scott: Yeah, it was find out.
Scott: It was.
Scott: I don't was next season or next episode or something.
Scott: What happened was the.
Scott: you know they showed you an episode And you were pretty sure that in the next episode they were gonna tell you his father was because they said so the next episode They were about to tell you and then they showed the whole episode was Terrence and Philip farting at each other.
Rym: They literally just made this other cartoon and showed it for a half hour And then it was over and they didn't tell you.
Scott: and then the next week They fixed the result.
Rym: they actually got in trouble with Comedy Central over that.
Rym: yeah I mean they got complaints.
Rym: people stopped listening and the show actually lost a lot of viewers for a while.
Scott: Mm-hmm I mean they all probably too You know because they could find out what happened just by looking on the internet or something.
Rym: yep They're watching the news though not too long after that the show actually got clever and currently in its current incarnation I actually really enjoy it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like for a while after that I stopped watching mostly because I stopped watching TV not because I didn't like South Park anymore But it's like I sort of forgot about it, and then you know it's still around.
Scott: I mean this.
Scott: the chef episode just now was season 10 episode 1 season 10. these guys have been doing this for 10 years.
Scott: Yeah, 10 years All right, but yeah now it goes into the formula that I described already And that seems to be what every South Park episode is and they're all pretty good and honestly I mean the guys who do it.
Rym: They're smart.
Rym: They've made some crap things before.
Rym: the thing is I think they did it on purpose.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is they seem to be able to.
Scott: really a lot of cartoons can't be very topical like The Simpsons.
Scott: Can't you know talk about something that's going on right now because The Simpsons was never any more topical than like Conan O'Brien was?
Scott: Yeah, it seems to be.
Scott: you know most cartoons are timeless like they kind of say general stuff And they can't be very specific.
Scott: South Park can be real specific because I don't think it takes them very long at all to make one.
Scott: I mean they just made the chef one in a few days if I'm not mistaken
Rym: Yep, and I gotta say I actually gained a lot of respect for them after they made the Scientology episode And I recommend that anyone who hasn't seen it because we've talked about it It's
Scott: all over the internet.
Rym: Yeah, we've talked about it multiple times on this show.
Rym: It's on Google video.
Rym: It's on YouTube Yeah, I mean because basically they were told as far as anyone can tell by Comedy Central to not ever show that episode again.
Scott: We don't know.
Rym: Maybe they will maybe they won't but it's everywhere on the internet and no one's doing anything about that.
Scott: Well, no one can do anything about it.
Scott: Yeah, but what is it?
Scott: Scientology is a crazy cult.
Scott: don't join it.
Scott: And if you see a Scientologist harass them harass them harass them harass them some more.
Rym: now the fact that South Park actually had the balls.
Rym: They stood up.
Rym: they made this absolutely scathing show about Scientology.
Scott: Oh, it's not scathing.
Scott: It's just truthful.
Rym: Well, yeah, it's truthful, but it's also scathing a hundred percent truth.
Rym: the truth hurts.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing you know.
Scott: exam What's the word that exaggerated exaggerated or hyperbolic about it?
Rym: I mean it was funny and explaining Xenu the alien and that when those words this is what?
Rym: Scientologists actually believe started flashing on the site.
Rym: I lost it.
Rym: I just I just cracked up.
Rym: I couldn't take it anymore.
Scott: Yep, at least it informed a whole bunch of people who didn't know.
Rym: Yep Cuz I remember someone messaged me who listens to GeekNights right after we watched the episode and then talked about it.
Rym: And they asked me is that really true?
Rym: and I had to respond with a link to clan bake.
Scott: Yeah, followed by the word Yes Scientologists really believe in the Thetans and the evil alien overlord Xenu and the airplanes and the volcanoes and the whole thing.
Rym: I just liked a bit at the end where they basically just told yeah sue us.
Rym: Come on do it sue me.
Scott: Yeah, I think they because the.
Scott: I think the deal was that The Church of Scientology what they like to do is if you do something to make them look bad They'll come and sue you.
Scott: so it's sort of a deterrent.
Scott: but South Park has there.
Scott: those guys are so smart They wanted Scientology to sue them.
Scott: that way they can make a lot of publicity about how Scientology is crazy.
Scott: It was like, you know free Anti-scientology Advertising if they actually got into a lawsuit.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I actually would have liked to see a lawsuit.
Scott: that would have been hilarious Double more hilarious than the show.
Scott: No, so let's talk about some more.
Scott: the episode where Cartman makes his kid eats his parents So Scott tenorman must die is another episode that I highly recommend.
Rym: Basically what we're doing now is if you saw South Park and knew it was crappy and poop jokes and stopped watching a long time Give it one more chance.
Scott: Yeah, so this episode what happens is Cartman who's a kid that deserves everything he gets.
Scott: but These older kids who are like middle school or maybe even freshman in high school or something start bothering him and picking on him.
Scott: But he deserves it because he's Cartman, but who cares?
Scott: They start making like jokes about him with like pubes.
Scott: They're like a pubes pubes.
Rym: Yeah, I just said that the show got clever and wasn't poop jokes anymore.
Scott: Yeah, it's still dirty But it's it.
Scott: there's something to it.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: It's very clever.
Scott: and Then like all you know Cartman tries to get revenge and he doesn't.
Scott: he tries to get revenge and he doesn't And he tries to get revenge and it looks like he you know doesn't fine, you know, yeah
Rym: They set up like this huge elaborate like Wow Cartman's plan is hugely elaborate and we know it's going to fail because information the show Is given to us.
Scott: Yep, and then somehow Cartman's plan is like his final plan isn't completely stupid like all his previous plans.
Scott: It's actually incredibly intelligent and in the end He actually like gets this kid turns his parents into chili and the kid ends up eating his own parents and then the kids favorite rock band comes and tells him he's a sissy for crying and It's just insane and
Rym: I guarantee it's actually funny not just horrible like we just described.
Scott: It's it's funny because it's horrible.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, I guess just give South Park a chance if you gave up on it a long Time ago, it's clever and topical and I enjoy it.
Scott: I also enjoy it.
Rym: now.
Rym: We also thought we'd talk today a little bit about Futurama.
Rym: Futurama is awesome, which is one of my favorite Television shows not including anime ever.
Scott: Yep, and for anyone who doesn't know We're 90% sure there are going to be four DVD only movies of Futurama a new stuff that is going to be released in the future,
Rym: which is Fantastic because all the voice actors and Matt groaning and everyone love Futurama
Scott: mostly because of bender.
Scott: It's all about bender and his shiny metal ass his glorious golden ass is splintery wooden man.
Rym: Yeah So Futurama was done by obviously Matt groaning the same guy who did the Simpsons And the only real.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: at first the shows look very similar.
Rym: They're done in a similar style just you know ones in the future and ones in Simpson's land.
Scott: well Futurama is a lot more CG because in the future Yeah, and it has a lot more pop culture II jokes and the Simpsons has more like society Human nature type of joke Simpsons used to.
Rym: from what I hear the Simpsons now is nothing but topical jokes.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Yes, what I've heard.
Scott: Well, I haven't seen it.
Rym: I haven't seen the Simpsons in like four years.
Scott: You'll have to go check it out.
Rym: Yeah But anyway, the show is it's very similar to in terms of just the humor and the way it's set up Except that the characters are more real more fleshed out.
Rym: The show is not always funny.
Rym: it's actually multiple times very serious or sad or heartwarming and There's a plot.
Rym: it is episodic.
Rym: You can just watch random episodes, but there is a General slowly advancing plot.
Rym: that kind of climaxes in the last episode Mm-hmm.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: it's not really a big plot.
Scott: It's just sort of like oh these things sort of connect and then they make a story out of it.
Rym: Yeah, well that and all also just it actually does kind of explore ideas of what if you were frozen and came back in the Far far future and everyone you knew and loved was dead.
Scott: Yep That's a yeah.
Scott: And also I like how it.
Scott: Not only does it explore that but explores like what would the future really be like of this world and a lot of the things They do in the you know in the future.
Scott: It's just silly like all kinds of crazy aliens and all kinds of drinking robots.
Scott: You know, it's funny stuff.
Scott: But a lot of the stuff is like, you know Like like the famous people's heads in jars and stuff and It's a lot of commentary on like advertising and it's definitely realistic.
Rym: in the same way that snow crash was realistic.
Rym: It's obviously hyperbole.
Rym: But then again, you wouldn't put it past some people to try some of these things.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing a lot of future on my episodes do that's really good is when they go to alien worlds that have crazy Situations.
Scott: so it really lets you do lets the creators do all sorts of crazy stuff crazy crazy And of course bender.
Rym: Yeah bender benders my man.
Scott: I think the best episode of Futurama is the one where benders like floating in space and He becomes God because there's a bun this little Lilliputians living on him and then he meets God for real.
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: Yep, actually, that's a very good episode from a number of perspectives.
Rym: It's funny, but it's also very poignant.
Rym: Yeah serious good philosophical interesting.
Scott: Yeah, it's not just like, you know some silly joke.
Scott: It's actually like oh, it's silly because you know the people do something but it's also.
Scott: Look, that's what people do.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: We can't talk about Futurama without mentioning the infamous dog episode.
Rym: Oh Remember the one where fry finds the fossil of his the dog that he used to have?
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Alright, he finds that this episode for people who are fans of Futurama It's widely known because the end is just so incredibly sad and unexpected.
Rym: but he finds this fossil of his dog and The professor says oh I can use my science to to bring make a clone and bring the dog back.
Rym: and Fry is so excited about this that he forgets about all his real friends, you know vendor And I'm not really gonna ruin the episode, but it just ends on just this sad like there's not even a joke there.
Scott: It's just sad Mmm, I imagine the dog dies or something.
Rym: No, it's actually sadder than that.
Rym: Like that basically the at the show is and it's a typical episode and then the end of the episode While the credits are rolling you realize that there's no joke coming That they weren't making a joke and it just it ends.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I Just a lot of people have mentioned this episode when they talk about Futurama.
Rym: So we could definitely not go without speaking of it.
Scott: Yeah, let's talk about two of my other favorite episodes.
Scott: It's the one where the pair of box.
Scott: Yeah, there's basically this box and if you go in the box It takes you to another dimension.
Scott: So what or another universe?
Scott: So what ends up happening?
Scott: Is this two different versions of all?
Scott: The main characters together one from one universe a and another from universe B. The only different we're.
Rym: universe awesome.
Scott: Yeah the leaders in universe A and B is that in universe B every coin toss came up on tails instead of heads and vice-versa and That has some interesting results.
Rym: It's one of the most quotable episodes of Futurama ever.
Scott: that sure is because the best part is where they're running through all these different boxes trying to find The Zoidberg's who ran away the two Zoidberg's.
Scott: Yeah, great Right goes Edward.
Scott: so they're all the other characters that aren't Zoidberg's are looking for the Zoidberg's and the two benders and One of them comes out of a box and he said he is holding a like a pot full of gold and he says Hey See what I got from the leprechaun universe and
Rym: the other benders.
Rym: like leprechaun universe is well and good if you haven't seen pirate universe.
Scott: and then he brings out this pirate chest full of gold and Chalices and whatnot?
Scott: faith and begora faith and begora Yeah pirate universe.
Rym: and just the scene at the end when they finally like they come out of the box and they all pop out of The box into the incinerator where Hermes finger is hovering over the button to destroy them all because he was supposed to destroy the box.
Rym: Long story short the box says no and they all pop up and Hermes is sitting there with his finger on the button and the Professors looking at him like Hermes whatever you do don't hit that button.
Rym: and Hermes obviously sits there for like five seconds Considering before he decides not to.
Scott: Hermes is really the only guy in the show who he's like the straight, man.
Scott: You know, I mean sure he has.
Scott: he's not perfectly straight.
Scott: I'm not talking about his sexuality and talking about you know in terms of like Abbot and Costello straight, man.
Scott: And yeah, man, like he does the limbo and it's funny and he has a couple episodes dedicated to him but he's mostly the only one who's intelligent and smart and not wacky.
Rym: now the other episode that we Personally love and oh The one that ends with the words and that little one is how Papa gets freedom.
Rym: and now Bon-hui bon-hui to you all Bon-hui, it was just this random Gargoyle themed ending.
Scott: Yeah, so the episode is where the beginning.
Scott: the professor is dealing with his gargoyle Right, and then the gargoyle gets away right and then The episode.
Scott: something else completely hat different happens in the episode.
Scott: there's like a fountain of youth or something and like everyone falls into the fountain of youth and Like while the professor is in the fountain of youth.
Scott: He's like I curse.
Rym: Yeah, the professor's dying and he just screams with my last breath.
Rym: I curse Zoidberg.
Rym: It's just the most random like as whole ish act.
Scott: Yeah, and then It's like if I was if like I was bleeding to death on the ground that I said with my last breath Curse Rym and then I died.
Scott: But then the gargoyle saves him from death and it's you know, the gargoyle hadn't been there since early in the episode.
Scott: So I was like all the gargoyles back and then the gargoyle Talks to his little baby gargoyle at the end of the episode and he says and that little one is how Papa gets free them Bon-hui bon-hui to you all.
Rym: it also has because the whole episode is about old age and old people and Like.
Rym: they're going through this whole thing and then they find like they're trying to get the gargoyle back for the professor And he the whole thing is like he's not an old man.
Rym: I'm still young blah blah blah.
Rym: and They finally like are tracking down the gargoyle and they say something to him like look We're gonna get your gargoyle and he's like my wife my wife My wife my wife and the way he says why it's hilarious My wife.
Rym: Yeah, you can tell we're geeks.
Rym: We fixate on the most like specific random bits of humor.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, that's how it's how it is though.
Rym: I can imagine that we'll be talking about Futurama more Periodically and randomly for the next several weeks and months.
Rym: as we watch all of it again.
Scott: Probably what'll end up happening is this bender says funny things.
Scott: I'll just remember them and say them again.
Rym: Yep Now we were going to talk about the Simpsons and Family Guy and the critic, but we've gone long enough today.
Rym: So that means we just have fodder for another Thursday someday.
Scott: awesome Family guy rules.
Rym: and last but not least the hosting is as we said earlier up.
Rym: Whoo.
Rym: So go to the forums.
Scott: I'm so awesome.
Scott: Haha Maybe now I can actually update it without breaking it.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: We'll see if Papa gets freedom.
Rym: So with that bonne.
Rym: Oui bonne Oui bonne oui to you all.
Scott: and with the last bit the podcast I curse And That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.