Scott: It's Monday March 27th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We cop out and do a tech news roundup.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, we're back after a long weekend of playing board games.
Scott: quite awesome new board games.
Rym: Yeah, we had some friends iron in from out of town.
Rym: We went to play some new games with the Moz types that we'll talk about various Tuesdays to come.
Scott: yeah We got some new games coming in the mail.
Scott: We bought some new games.
Rym: Yeah, I'm impulse.
Rym: I bought a giant giant expensive board game that I played once and I bought two Normal-sized board games that I've one of them.
Scott: I played once and one of them.
Scott: I played nuns zeros.
Scott: Alright, so I don't know who's out there.
Scott: you might enjoy such Wonderful cartoon such as Voltron.
Scott: who is the best ever?
Rym: yeah Scott thinks.
Rym: This is news.
Rym: It's all him so a lot.
Scott: for a long time people have said hey Every other freaking 80s cartoon is on DVD.
Scott: where the hell's Voltron?
Scott: Voltron is the best?
Scott: where's Voltron?
Rym: I haven't been saying that really.
Scott: not you, but everyone else who cares everyone else.
Scott: Yeah, yep well right at Voltron.com there was really nothing about Voltron.
Scott: it was like this shit website that no one cared about and People said hey we want freaking DVDs god damn it.
Scott: and we want Voltron merchandise and toys and everything.
Scott: well now Voltron.com is finally something cool in two hours and two days and 14 hours as of Right now, so I don't know when you're listening to this, but it could be already happened or mere hours away.
Scott: Voltron.com will relaunch with awesome with supposedly awesome DVDs and forums and all kinds of great things just like every other Wonderful website out there.
Rym: We'll see if it Stands up to the test of time.
Scott: the best thing about this is that there's a little flash thing on the site right now With the countdown and there are like these great great quotes on the on the official site like here.
Scott: Let me read one of them It sucks that when you go to Voltron when you go to the Voltron website You can't get any news about Voltron stuff.
Scott: almost every 80s cartoon cut has come out on DVD.
Scott: Don't let the go butts DVD come out before Voltron.
Scott: I'm getting really close to buying the crappy bootleg DVDs on eBay.
Scott: I won't Voltron so bad.
Scott: That's serious stuff right there, and this is the people who own the rights to Voltron in America putting those quotes on their site being like We're bringing it.
Scott: you wanted it.
Rym: Well at least they know that there's a market.
Scott: yeah And I think they're hitting that market dead on.
Rym: are you gonna buy it?
Scott: Maybe maybe there's a lot of Voltron all right.
Scott: I can't.
Scott: it could be too much money.
Scott: I might just again.
Scott: the other thing is a lot of Voltron episodes especially later seasons are really just.
Scott: You know a row beast appears Voltron the guys getting Voltron they fight the row B's they win the episodes over repeat repeat repeat.
Scott: But the first season has a little bit of plot and action going on.
Scott: so I might buy like season one and then forget the Rest.
Rym: you should buy the last season.
Scott: I don't think Voltron ended.
Scott: of course I never seen all the episodes in order or anything.
Scott: So I don't.
Scott: I think it just.
Scott: it just kept fighting row beasts until it was cancer.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I never really watched it when I was a kid.
Scott: I watched it other shows I watched it plenty, but I didn't you know.
Scott: I was a kid and I watched it more recently like in high school.
Scott: But the only episodes I saw were all.
Scott: I've seen the first few episodes a whole bunch of times But other than that the only episodes I've ever seen our fighter row beast episodes over.
Rym: so all right yep.
Rym: So now today is Monday and sci-tech day So we'll be getting to science and tech in the second half of the show as we usually do a little bit of a cop-out In how we're gonna do that, but we'll get to that when it comes.
Rym: now I have some actual non science non technical news to discuss And it's something that Scott actually was unaware of until I told him about it And it's not really being widely played out on the media yet.
Rym: But to make a long story short a law was passed by our government that was never voted on by the House of Representatives.
Rym: The president signed it and it's a law now.
Scott: in other words In a democracy someone made a law Without the people's permission or without the people representing the people's permission now.
Rym: This is kind of a complicated situation.
Rym: I'm gonna sum it up really really briefly, and then you'll get some I guess enlightened commentary from me Scott And I.
Scott: I guess if you understand how the American government works, or it's the United States government works It'll help a lot in your understanding.
Rym: you've ever seen Schoolhouse Rock.
Rym: You'll know what I'm talking about.
Scott: yeah, but If you're from a foreign country, which I know some of you are.
Scott: just ignore this shit.
Rym: Yeah, you know we're screwed up over here.
Rym: Yeah, but all right.
Rym: so this law called the deficit reduction omnibus reconstruction act of 2005.
Rym: Great this law was the one that cut all those social programs and cut you know student loans and whatever And it was basically an effort by conservatives to say that they're actually trying to Do something about the deficit and the debt and all that sort of thing.
Scott: well We don't actually care about the content of the law.
Scott: It's
Rym: a major in which the law except for the fact that it was a highly partisan issue as and also it now Originally it was written right and for all of you Don't know the Senate and the house Basically will write two separate laws that do the same thing
Scott: except for those laws that have to originate in the house because they do Yeah, oh
Rym: yeah, but then the Senate will write their own.
Rym: basically now what happens is that they'll write it.
Rym: They'll both pass theirs.
Rym: Then a committee will get together between the two Reconcile the differences make a new law that they both then pass.
Rym: that law is than the one that goes to the president Mm-hmm, but the Constitution basically says that a law has to be passed by both houses of Congress.
Rym: Mm-hmm that is key.
Rym: That is one of the fundamental tenets of American democracy.
Scott: That's that's like the first thing.
Scott: How do you make a law?
Scott: you write it then one house votes the other house votes?
Scott: And if they both say yes, then it's a law and that's the only way.
Scott: there's no other way to make a law.
Rym: now.
Rym: There was a conflict that happened like this around the turn of the century And I don't know the details of that one.
Rym: Really other than that It was a similar situation and the Supreme Court Ruled that they had nothing to do with it and they washed their hands of it and Congress had to sort it out on its own Which doesn't bode well for us today?
Scott: No It doesn't.
Rym: now basically what happened is the bill would barely pass like Barely, it was a tie in the Senate Which means the Cheney cast the tot the tiebreaker vote to make it pass and in the house it passed by like 11 votes I think like it barely squeaked by.
Scott: wow, that's close.
Rym: so then eventually it gets in and they start rewriting, you know, everything to try to reconcile the two versions and they come to a final version and to make a long story short the version that the Senate passed in the end is different by the tune of two billion dollars from the version that the house passed.
Rym: and the Committee that was supposed to reconcile all this instead of you know Doing the proper thing and having it voted on again in the house and rewriting it and fixing it just gave it to the president to sign and He signed it.
Rym: and now it's law and the House of Representatives has never actually voted on the actual law that got put in.
Scott: So wait, the law that was given to the president is exactly the same as the Senate one.
Scott: It was not modified in any way whatsoever.
Rym: No, no, no the final Senate one.
Rym: Okay, though the only difference is there's one clause that's different.
Rym: they think it's due to a typo at some point in the process.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Rym: The thing is the one that was passed is the typo version not the original version.
Scott: Oh Great.
Scott: So there's a typo in the law.
Scott: Can we use that?
Rym: Um, actually there is a precedent.
Rym: It's called the enrolled bill rule and the Supreme Court vetted this out back and I think 1892 sometime turn of the century.
Rym: and basically they say that Even if there is outright fraud in terms of a clerk changing something or just outright Like the person in responsible just wrote the law differently didn't tell anyone.
Rym: It still stands.
Scott: if it's passed and kind by the president the rule is the one that the piece of paper that was signed by the president is the law.
Rym: well the rule is if a Enrolled law a law that has been passed by the House and Senate is given to the president and all the proper Signatures are on it those signatures constitute proof that it was voted on not the actual record of Congress.
Rym: The only actual proof is the signatures.
Rym: So the people who sign those documents chose to just sign something that wasn't voted on.
Rym: Oh Because they basically they didn't want this law to go back into the house Because there's a really good chance that might not have passed this time at all.
Scott: Well, doesn't it need the signatures of like, you know the house people?
Rym: Yeah, and they signed it.
Rym: Well, the house didn't vote on it.
Rym: Yeah, the leadership of the house decided to just run with it.
Scott: well I got one thing to say.
Scott: that's against the Constitution and I'm gonna say the same thing I said earlier which is that it's you know, relatively easy to break a normal law like oh, I killed someone.
Scott: Well, I guess that's not so easy to do depending on who you are.
Rym: It's fairly.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, I robbed a convenience store.
Scott: It's relatively difficult and rare to break not just a law but to break the Constitution.
Scott: you do something in a way contrary to the way the Constitution says.
Scott: you should do things as in Be a congressman and make a law that limits free speech.
Scott: That's not easy to do.
Scott: I Guess the easiest thing I could think of to do in the Constitution that would break it would be to be a policeman and search And seize without a warrant which actually happens all the time happens all the time, but that's not you know It's not the point.
Scott: the point I'm making is that if you do something that's against the Constitution I don't care.
Scott: if you do something that's against the law that happens all the time.
Scott: Smoking weed is against the law.
Scott: if you do something that is against the Constitution like you enslave someone or You I don't know.
Scott: all kinds of you make a treaty with a foreign government.
Scott: Yeah, you should just lose your citizenship and get kicked out.
Scott: you don't want you.
Scott: obviously you went against the fundamental But founding document of the entire country.
Scott: You don't obviously don't want to be here.
Rym: see I go back down more to the specific instance here because people are.
Rym: some people have Said that oh, it was just a typo.
Rym: Don't worry about it.
Rym: Even though for some reason they passed the typo version.
Scott: It's not about that.
Scott: I don't care about the content of the law.
Rym: No, I'm talking about is that that everyone's saying oh, it's just a typo.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: It's not a big deal.
Rym: It's only two billion dollars position which isn't much in the grand scheme.
Rym: But I contend that this is just bad precedent for future abuses and this needs to be stopped now before someone uses this for something more.
Rym: Sinister.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Hey, here's what I'm gonna do.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: Everyone's gonna vote on this law that says You know We're going to cut taxes or something and then I'm gonna be the clerk who gives it to the president and I'm just gonna you know Change all the words before I give it to him and it's gonna say give Scott all the money.
Rym: Now the president the enrolled bill rule Basically came out of the fact that it used to be very tedious to go through documents and make sure they were identical.
Scott: Oh very so.
Rym: they decided that it was better to let flawed documents get passed as laws Than to prevent Congress from ever doing anything because they just there weren't enough manpower Available to actually vet everything.
Rym: Mm-hmm nowadays computers make that stupid.
Scott: computers do make it stupid but I don't know about the computer and IT workings of the You know legislative branch.
Rym: Point out that the I'm not gonna get into this but it's very archaic.
Scott: our legislative branches vote in the most archaic Obsolete just and that's what I was gonna say is that if they had some awesome computers, it would be all good.
Scott: But no, they're using shit.
Scott: Crap.
Scott: They're not using anything shit.
Rym: Crap.
Rym: Is that a technical term?
Scott: It's called Windows.
Rym: No, they're not using Windows.
Scott: What are they using?
Rym: They're using systems that have been around for a long time.
Scott: Yeah, maybe someone should rewrite that shit.
Rym: What do you mean rewrite?
Rym: They're not computers.
Scott: Maybe they should get some computers.
Rym: See they know that most of these people don't know anything about technology.
Rym: Hence all the Legislation that gets passed regarding it.
Scott: Yeah, maybe there should be some sort of a law about that.
Rym: but anyway Regarding this actual the thing that happened despite the fact that the president and the leaders of the House and Senate say that oh It's no big deal.
Rym: There are Numerous lawsuits springing up everywhere regarding this.
Rym: Hooray and various civil organizations and law professors are all over it.
Scott: So we will use terrible laws and bureaucracy to counter a broken law and bureaucracy.
Rym: Well, actually the people who brought this forward and brought it to light were basically washed-out groups Which are private organizations that exist solely to keep an eye on the government because we need that big time.
Scott: Yeah, that's not sarcastic.
Rym: want to just move to like Scandinavia.
Scott: I don't know I don't speak their language.
Rym: So, well, I'm sure we could learn it like Swedish.
Scott: I don't speak the Swedish I know Dutch don't don't speak that either.
Rym: We know a little bit of German.
Rym: I think we could pick up other similar languages fairly quickly.
Scott: Yeah, Dutch is the closest to English.
Scott: It doesn't sound the same.
Rym: So for things of the day You all know that I at least currently work for IBM and I'll tell you this that there are based to basic Help desk numbers that we call internally at IBM.
Rym: there is a 1-888 IBM help which is for normal tech support II crap and 1-800 IBM serve which is like I'm a real IBM or I need a new Dasty unit for this server, whatever.
Scott: So these are things that IBM employees call not things that IBM customers call.
Rym: Well, I was about to say that actually one of them the normal tech support crap.
Rym: one Anyone can call and in fact anyone can call the other one, too.
Rym: I just I work for IBM.
Rym: So we call them internally.
Rym: Ah, but anyway, the thing is it's 1-888 IBM help.
Rym: It used to be as in while I worked here not too long ago 1-800 IBM help.
Scott: Did they not pay the 800 phone number bill or something?
Rym: No, nothing like that.
Rym: Just let me finish my story.
Rym: How do I keep interrupting?
Rym: You don't know anything about this?
Rym: So a while ago I mean I used to call 1-800 IBM help to get various things and not too long ago someone in our department called 1-800 IBM help not knowing that it had been changed to 1-888 IBM help and We discovered that 1-800 IBM help is now a phone sex line
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: So when they changed the number and got rid of the old one Someone must have just bought it either on purpose or it was just reallocated.
Rym: and they got it.
Rym: because I know 800 numbers are kind of scarce and Yeah, it's still published on a great number of internal documents as a phone number to call for help I just lead is leading to great amounts of hilarity.
Rym: double awesome Dig has a story on it, which is what I linked to.
Rym: but nine people have dug it because no one seems to care about This.
Rym: but I found it funny.
Scott: Yeah, I called it.
Scott: It was pretty.
Scott: it was like one of the best phone sex lines I've ever called.
Scott: I mean Understand.
Rym: What was that?
Rym: I'll tell you a story one of the best phone sex lines you've ever called.
Scott: Let me tell you a story about this.
Scott: We're at Dorney Park In Wild Order Kingdom, Pennsylvania.
Scott: Well, we weren't actually getting in.
Scott: we were waiting outside because it was rained It was raining and they wouldn't let us into the park until it stopped raining.
Rym: Well, that's weird.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, it was pretty weird.
Scott: anyway, we're a bunch of like seventh grade punk kids hanging outside of an amusement park Wanting to go inside and the only thing there is out there besides us and the counselors is a payphone.
Scott: So we start calling like 1-800 hot tits 1-800 gay guys 1-800 fat girls.
Scott: 1-800 all kinds of weird shit.
Scott: great because we got none better to do.
Scott: and it's really weird that there's all these phone sex lines.
Scott: None of those numbers will actually get you to actual phone sex.
Scott: All you do is you call them and you hear a recording of an advertisement for another phone sex number.
Scott: They're like call this other number now to get the real phone sex and pay us money.
Rym: Yeah Well, wait, so what did you expect?
Rym: free phone sex?
Scott: We were little kids.
Scott: What do you want?
Rym: I've never actually called a phone sex line.
Scott: So I never called one that you know, I've only called to hear little advertisements when it's funny.
Rym: Uh-huh Yeah, all right.
Rym: All right, I believe you See.
Scott: then we this one I called and it was like so much more Crazy than any of the other ones I've ever called.
Rym: It's hilarious.
Rym: If you want some fun next time someone has trouble and it happens to be an IBM computer Just tell them to call 1-800 IBM help.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: this awesome website I found today.
Scott: I didn't quite understand it at first, but now I get it completely.
Scott: It's the movie timeline.
Scott: What this does is it puts the entire history of the entire universe in one giant text timeline.
Scott: However, this takes into account a few assumptions.
Scott: number one The real world.
Scott: history is not the history.
Scott: We're talking about the history We're talking about is the history?
Scott: that would be true if every movie was the actual truth.
Rym: All right.
Rym: What about all the movies where the world gets destroyed?
Scott: All of those are in here, too.
Rym: Okay?
Scott: So it's pretty funny.
Scott: it starts out with in the beginning is the first date and then it says God created heavens and the earth The Bible all right, whatever.
Scott: then it says the next one is a long time ago.
Scott: Luke Skywalker and Han Solo lead a rebellion against the evil Empire.
Scott: Uh-huh, then 26 that's got to be billion trillion BC Los Angeles and everywhere else the earth crust begin to harden adaptation.
Scott: I don't even know what that movie is But anyway, it's a bunch of boring stuff for a little bit until you get to when the Predators come.
Scott: 2897 BC October 10th, bové Island Antarctica predators arrive for their feasting ritual on xenomorphs and humans.
Scott: 2080-97 no 2797 BC.
Scott: it happens again 26 97 25 9 24 and every hundred years It's just a million predators arrive for their feasting ritual on xenomorphs and you great.
Scott: And of course eventually as more and more things happen in between centuries the predator feasting is Separated by actual other events like King Henry.
Scott: the second plans a reunion to name a successor in the lion and winter.
Scott: I've never seen that movie.
Rym: You've never seen the lion in winter never heard of it.
Rym: Wow Do you know about that?
Rym: What happened that story?
Rym: I mean it really happened.
Scott: I know about Was a King Henry the second, but I don't know about.
Scott: you know, the movie really?
Rym: what about King Henry the second?
Rym: What did he do?
Scott: planned our Union?
Rym: Yeah Yeah, we just won't get into that.
Rym: Yeah now I saw something similar a long time ago where people were talking about television continuity in the sense that What if basically they go from one show and any time there's a cameo between two shows then obviously those shows are in the same Universe and everything that's canon and one has to be canon in the other?
Rym: and if you do that, it turns out that 99% of all television that has been shown in the last 40 years Actually was an autistic kids dream.
Rym: because there's one show that the final episode.
Rym: You find out that the whole show is just an autistic kids dream And it was known as one of the biggest cop-outs in the history of television.
Rym: Wow now if anyone out there knows what the name of this show is because I do Posted in the forums and the first one to do it wins the as yet to be determined prizes that we've been saying.
Rym: we might Give out some day that nobody has deserved or won yet.
Rym: No, no, Alex got the Duchy of Grand Fenwick.
Scott: Okay, so it's all you know, it's all your prize.
Scott: you give it to him.
Rym: Yeah, I'll give him something.
Rym: But if anyone knows the show that caused all TV to just be some autistic kids dream it ended with a snow globe.
Scott: Aha, so one more thing to note about this movie timeline is it seems to bunch up around major events in history The funniest of which I think is the Titanic because it's like a bunch of entries for April such-and-such in 19.
Scott: What was it?
Scott: 1913?
Rym: I think I know two movies where the Titanic was saved.
Scott: Yeah, so The funniest one is your April 15th.
Scott: time-traveling dwarves appear on Titanic.
Scott: briefly All right, all right.
Rym: so it's Monday and basically all the topics we'd thought about doing would either take research or Time or some sort of preparation which we weren't quite prepared to do.
Scott: Yeah Now if you know me or you might not know me I'm a computer programmer kind of and there according to Larry Wahl the creator of Pearl in the first camel book There were three great virtues of a programmer which he listed those being laziness impatience and hubris.
Rym: Yeah, that pretty much describes Scott.
Scott: Yep, so We're gonna go with the first one here.
Scott: Yeah laziness and today we don't really have a real topic.
Rym: basically whenever we say it's a tech news roundup That means we were too lazy to come up with anything real.
Rym: So we sat and went through slash dot FARC dig and Google News until we found enough things to talk about.
Scott: so The other thing is that we have a lot of ideas for what to do on Monday But a lot of them require going against laziness Impatience and hubris.
Rym: either that or the laziness either.
Rym: that are the things that we think might be interesting to some of you But we're not sure how many of you would really want to listen to us talk for an hour about how cell phones work.
Scott: Yeah, so we need you people's who are listening to this show To go to our forums and also email us.
Scott: GeekNights at front row crew.
Scott: calm GeekNights at front row crew.
Scott: calm GeekNights at gmail.com.
Scott: also works.
Scott: who cares and Tell us what topics you want us to talk about for science and tech on Mondays?
Rym: Yeah, we'll do it, but we need some guidance here.
Rym: Otherwise, you're gonna get an hour of us talking about how cell phones work.
Scott: Yeah, and because I predict a very low turnout of people's actually sending in Requests of what we should talk about.
Scott: if you send one in you're pretty much guaranteed to get that show.
Scott: So this is like Total request GeekNights here.
Rym: Yeah I mean basically we know exactly how many people download a given episode and we know how many people post in the forums and One number is a lot bigger than the other number.
Rym: So we know you're out there.
Rym: We know you're listening.
Rym: Yep So anyway tech news roundup the last several weeks in tech mostly the most recent week because that's where all the news we remember happened.
Rym: So I guess we can start off with.
Rym: I know I mentioned that there was that Internet Explorer bug the third huge horrible Unfixable ie bug that lets anyone root your computer with just you going to a website.
Scott: So when do we talk about that last week?
Scott: Yeah, is it still unfixed?
Rym: Not only is it still unfixed and not only is it existed for a long time, but attacks are on the rise Immensely, I forget the number I saw but the the number of websites that are exploiting This is just exploding if you use Internet Explorer on the Internet at all.
Rym: You're done.
Rym: at this point The Internet is just the Wild West.
Scott: can I can a firewall save you?
Rym: nothing can save you.
Scott: Nothing can save you if you have a Windows computer no matter what network or no matter why using the special private beta of Microsoft Windows Vista.
Rym: with Internet Explorer 7 the newest newest rewritten version it has the same bug.
Scott: There isn't even an unofficial security patch from some hacker in Norway or something.
Rym: There are a bunch of obtuse workarounds like turning off active scripting, but doesn't that make I sort of Yeah Get firefox.com Get firefox.com Luckily on the feed side.
Rym: I've seen a grand total of one person subscribe to our feed with ie.
Rym: they still do.
Scott: I can subscribe to feed.
Scott: apparently they must be ie7.
Rym: I don't think ie6 five or six or it's at least hitting the feed on a regular basis.
Scott: They might not be subscribed and they might actually be visiting fees.
Scott: that feed burner calm.
Rym: Yeah, whoever you are I mean last time we called someone out for the PSP.
Rym: They actually got back with us.
Rym: So if you're using Internet Explorer to hit our feed burner feed We're not gonna tell you to stop listening, but they are gonna put the exploit up there.
Rym: No, we're not here We are.
Rym: we're gonna force you because I can't edit the HTML of the feed burner feed.
Scott: We'll get it on on some other site.
Rym: I don't need to whoever you are you might want to run some antivirus because you're probably already rooted.
Scott: You might want to reformat your hard drive and install Linux.
Scott: That'll help.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So there's these guys, you know how if you get a credit card?
Scott: So like I have a Sony credit card to get these Sony points Which means I could get Sony stuff for cheap like our television.
Rym: Yeah, we got the cheapest television in the world.
Scott: because of that it goes like a hundred bucks for a 27 inch awesome flat glass not flat screen TV anyway.
Scott: And you can also get frequent flyer miles and who knows what they're coming out with credit cards Where the more real money you spend on the credit card you get either World of Warcraft gold or Second Life Linden dollars.
Scott: This is kind of really good for the credit card companies because basically they give you an incentive to spend more money Yet they give you Immaterial nothings.
Rym: It's genius.
Rym: I Say more power to them.
Rym: This is fantastic.
Scott: more power to the credit card companies.
Scott: But at the same time if I ever see someone with a World of Warcraft credit card or a Second Life credit card It's an idiot tag.
Scott: It's like hey, they could be getting Actual goods points if they used a different credit card, but no they would rather have immaterial goods.
Rym: Basically, it's the same tag is like say people who drive an h2 Hummer.
Rym: Yeah I mean, it's something where there's really no excuse.
Scott: I mean these things that they give on credit cards like the worst ones are the ones where they say Anyone who every time you spend money on your credit card during these months You're entered for a chance to win a giant prize Those are the worst.
Scott: but anyone who spends more money in order to get points or get stuff or enter contests is dumb Unless you're working a scam.
Scott: unless you're working escape.
Scott: You got a scam going on way to go.
Rym: I mean if you've ever seen a punch drunk love where the guy does the scam with the freaking flyer miles Anything like that is awesome.
Scott: I never seen that.
Scott: but okay I'm all for any scams.
Scott: I'm a mad scammer Not a random as long as not a Randy scan.
Rym: yeah, oh we didn't talk about the reflex ology.
Scott: We can do that some other time.
Rym: We'll talk about those Thursday.
Rym: All right, so Yeah Alright, so remember a while ago.
Rym: We talked about that new law in Japan not new law But a law that finally came into effect that basically banned all old technology and Rym said he didn't believe it.
Scott: But no he was wrong.
Scott: there really was a law.
Rym: Oh, no, there really was a law but the law didn't do nearly what Scott said it.
Scott: Well, no, it was going to originally.
Scott: then people protested.
Scott: so what happened is they did a slight amendment to the law.
Scott: They're like, okay now some stuff is okay, but some stuff still wasn't okay.
Scott: So what happened is literally People took to the streets with their old technology and now the law has been changed once again.
Scott: So now you can.
Scott: it's not completely erased like.
Scott: the law is still there.
Scott: But there's a loophole like 10 miles wide in diameter that says you can rent old technologies.
Scott: so if you go to Japan and try to buy some old Famicom, the guy might make you sign a paper about Renting it but you can just ignore that.
Scott: It's totally yours.
Rym: Yeah No I mean even before the law wasn't really that bad.
Rym: all it stated was basically that things that weren't certified under the new Electrical safety guidelines had to be recertified to be resold.
Scott: Yeah, but it also retail space.
Rym: it also didn't really affect private consumers that much.
Scott: well it did.
Scott: it made a lot of things that Already existed like we're never gonna be certified again because they're unsafe including
Rym: The uncertified it
Scott: was okay to only just
Rym: couldn't be sold in retail spaces, basically
Scott: Yes, but you know
Rym: and you could also get them underwritten privately and then it'd be okay again.
Rym: most likely I didn't see that.
Rym: Well, that wasn't in the law, but that's a legal thing that someone could probably have done.
Scott: maybe Japan's laws are weird.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: but I was that there are many many geeky stores in Akihabara and such and Japan is often the only place to get many old Awesome electronics and all of those that are your stores that exist solely to sell these things and they were basically gonna be totally reamed.
Scott: But now they're okay because now they're rental shops in quotes and it's all good.
Scott: I just think it's cool that the people of Japan took to the streets like literally Yeah People in this country don't take to the streets when their Constitution gets broken.
Rym: there's a picture of Japan.
Rym: take to the streets when a Casio keyboard becomes illegal.
Scott: There's a picture of a dude dancing around with this Casio keyboard.
Scott: I think he's a musician in the street with Casio keyboard.
Scott: It's awesome.
Rym: So, uh, I'm out.
Rym: I know a while ago we were talking about campaign finance law and how there was a move to Basically censor the internet and force bloggers to count anything They say politically as though it were campaign contributions and various things like that.
Rym: It was decided today that no that's BS.
Rym: you can say whatever you want on the internet as long as you're not paid directly to Do so.
Rym: Hooray I believe I don't remember the exact quote But they basically said that you can't hold Certain members of the media accountable to one standard and other members to another.
Rym: standard members of the media are on equal ground.
Rym: Yep, that's so.
Rym: women loggers a lose for the mainstream media and it's also a win for graft and corruption, but whatever.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one thing I was gonna say.
Scott: now any old candidate can start up some blogs Make up fake people to run those blogs or hire some people to run those blog.
Rym: No, you can't be paid.
Scott: Ah, but what if they don't know?
Rym: now it includes a whole bunch other things.
Rym: one really big one is that you cannot be denied the right to use your computer from a corporation or an educational facility or anything like that for political things as long as you do so on your own time and Specifically you can post
Scott: your political blog during lunch, but not during the morning
Rym: basically.
Rym: Yeah Now in regards to the graft and corruption and everything I'm not worried because if you list all the rights in order, I think freedom of speech trumps the danger of graft.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm not saying that I disagree.
Scott: This is great compared to what the odd the previous alternative was, you know That was terrible.
Scott: That would have been like the worst thing ever.
Scott: But now I still.
Scott: I wish there was some way we could make a law that to get rid of the graft and corruption without Limiting the freedom of speech.
Rym: There's really no way not the way our country's set up or at least stop it a little bit.
Scott: You don't have to completely eliminate it, you know, just get rid of that evil corruption.
Scott: It should be like the anti-corruption act of such-and-such.
Rym: Yeah, you know how many laws are called the anti-corruption whatever whatever that don't do anything or that make more corruption or open up loopholes For extra corruption.
Rym: Yeah, there's really no way There would be a way.
Rym: oh, yeah people were.
Rym: No, if people were civic-minded and voted out corrupt people.
Scott: Yeah that too, but it's hard to tell who's corrupt sometimes cuz that's part.
Scott: No, it's really easy.
Rym: right now almost everyone Yeah, I mean the only person who might not be corrupt is possibly Elliot spitzer.
Scott: Yep, and who knows it's like a 50/50 shot.
Rym: Yeah, think about it toss He's probably the most trustworthy person in the government of the United States right now And all he is is the Attorney General of one state and even then we only trust him halfway.
Scott: Yeah, and he's might be a governor.
Scott: that that'll be something.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see.
Scott: Yeah Obama's a little bit corrupt but not much.
Scott: Yeah, so I guess he's number two.
Scott: everyone else is terrible, all right, let's Beat our favorite dead horse.
Rym: Yeah, Sony.
Scott: So Sony item number one the ps1 factory is closed.
Rym: now I've mixed feelings on this one.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: That probably wasn't making money anymore and whatever they can do ever They want plenty of ps1s in the world.
Rym: Yeah, you can also perfectly emulate the ps1 on pretty mediocre hardware these days or in a ps2.
Rym: Yeah, the games are a dollar each.
Scott: four dollars four dollars.
Rym: I've seen some for a dollar.
Scott: Those are the games you don't want to play now.
Rym: The one thing is that the ps1 is actually really popular in South America.
Scott: Oh Kenny, South America is like the land of PlayStation ones and Genesis is yep.
Rym: Now the reason I'm not worried about that is quite simply I'll bet someone's just gonna start a factory in South America and start making ps1s.
Scott: Oh, no, but you know, you'll see.
Scott: you know, how there's all these like the NES X and all.
Scott: yeah It's a Nintendo consoles in NES, but it's made with newer chips and fewer of them for cheap.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna see a lot of like, you know Some guy makes something that is basically a ps1 for like 30 bucks and is a bunch of bootleg.
Scott: it'll say like, you know may station on it or Play play sensation or who knows.
Rym: now This isn't a big deal because the PlayStation 2 was pretty much 99% compatible with the PlayStation 1.
Rym: Yeah, so I mean people have a piece like the Xbox 360 Yeah, or unlike possibly the ps3.
Rym: Yeah, Sony won't commit to saying that it's actually going to be backwards compatible.
Scott: Well, let's talk about the ps3.
Scott: They're having a few problems with it.
Rym: All right one blu-ray is still Expensive and difficult to make.
Scott: well, so is HD DVD.
Scott: So who cares?
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is HD DVD wasn't a prerequisite for the Xbox.
Scott: No, it was.
Rym: ray is most definitely I think.
Scott: I think Microsoft was thinking about it and then it is decided that they would go for the quick release instead.
Rym: Yep, and they gave Sony some rope and Sony must have thought they could pull something off here, but they haven't.
Scott: Yep Well, the thing was at the game developers conference, which just happened.
Scott: They wanted Sony to plug in the ps3 via an HDMI cable to get some HD going on And Sony wouldn't do it.
Scott: They kept it on a little analog cable.
Rym: I wonder why?
Scott: maybe the ps3 not doing so?
Scott: well don't the technology not not quite there yet?
Rym: Yeah I wish I could say cuz I mean I work at the freaking IBM factory where we make the chips that go into it And all that stuff and I know a lot more about this than I can say.
Rym: But I think I can say perfectly legally that Sony is having issues and the issues are caused entirely by Sony.
Scott: No one knows No one cares.
Rym: But well a lot of people care.
Rym: a lot of people really are waiting for the ps3 to come out and that's why they might Be holding off on the Xbox.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people see Sony is winning in this round.
Scott: See, I don't know the only people I think who see that it seems to be like these army of Japanese RPG addicts.
Scott: those are the only people who go for the PlayStation.
Rym: honestly a lot of Gamers, but not gamers like us but like the new generation of gamers who don't read the news and they really know what's going on.
Rym: All they know is that a PlayStation 3 is coming out.
Rym: They don't actually know about it or what's going on.
Rym: So I don't think they realize all the trouble Sony actually has having.
Scott: I don't think they actually like, you know It's only like real crazy gamer types that know like more details than just the word PlayStation.
Scott: you know, it's like there's people who just want to play like the new Madden and the new GTA and they have two choices of system to play it on and You know, they go by.
Scott: name recognition is really the only difference like oh I'm playing it on my PA, you know That's.
Scott: that's why they're arguing of when you see all these discussions of like all the Xbox 360 It's gonna be more powerful than the ps3 Because there's people who are gonna play the same games that are available for both systems and they're not playing any Exclusive games.
Scott: They're not gonna play Japanese RPGs and they're not gonna play halos.
Scott: They're just gonna play Madden and EA games.
Scott: so they have to pick a system based on which one has the best graphics.
Rym: Now let's talk about the technology here behind the Sony PlayStation 3 because one they've missed all their dates.
Rym: I mean originally wasn't it.
Rym: they're gonna have a release in like November.
Scott: Well, they said spring of this year and then they find it's everyone's like you're not gonna make it the spring of this year.
Scott: Well, it's finally.
Scott: they said there was gonna be a delay.
Scott: finally.
Rym: Yeah, and it keeps getting pushed off.
Rym: It looks like now the earliest it'll come out in Japan is near the end of this year like November.
Rym: Awesome, and as for the US release, I don't think anyone believes they're gonna be out before March or April of next year.
Rym: Well, that means the revolution is gonna beat him by quite a bit.
Scott: possibly the revolution I guarantee I'm like 99% sure will be here by the holiday season of this year.
Rym: now it uses the PlayStation the IBM cell chips, which Independently are very powerful things.
Rym: The difficulty is that it takes a lot of programming expertise and special compilers to write software that'll actually take advantage of it.
Rym: so Developing for the PlayStation 3 is not the straightforward process.
Rym: It was for the PlayStation 2 in that the same expertise is not useful.
Scott: Well, actually programming for the PlayStation 1 was like crap easy.
Scott: It was literally like you code and scene you write some OpenGL.
Scott: They even had a thing called the Yaro Z J a ro Z e. that was like $750.
Scott: it was a black PlayStation 1 that you could use to make PlayStation games And I remember a lot of people bought him and did.
Scott: there's still people out there who have them and do crazy stuff with them.
Scott: You might even find one on eBay.
Scott: Yeah, the PlayStation 2 basically was a lot of the same but it just made everything more complicated more difficult But still manageable and the PlayStation 3 seems to just be up insane.
Scott: No one's ever programmed like this before.
Scott: Everyone has to learn it from scratch.
Scott: It's a huge pain in the ass.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the cell chips are not what a lot of people seem to say They are.
Rym: I don't think many people out there actually really understand what they do now.
Rym: I'm not gonna go into that but if anyone if you guys have feedback if you really want to know I can talk about quite a bit of exactly what the Cell chip is and why it's powerful and in my opinion why Sony I think made a bad move Not in terms of using a technology in terms of not giving the developers enough time to be able to use the technology.
Scott: That's one thing.
Scott: Nintendo is real smart With the revolution.
Scott: what they doing obviously is it's mostly the same as coding for the GameCube.
Scott: The only difference is now you have some new input devices.
Scott: you can handle from slightly more power to work.
Scott: You know more memory more, you know that kind of sort of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: if you know how to make GameCube games You can make freaking revolution games.
Scott: It's not that different except for of course There's a new library to handle the internet wireless business and coding for the Xbox.
Rym: just code for a freaking PC.
Scott: I know the Xbox is basically you write DirectX games and the Xbox 360 you write DirectX games.
Scott: It's no different now.
Rym: If so That's why you see all these.
Rym: if Sony had working hardware if Sony had had their working hardware together And they were ready to go already Then it wouldn't be that far off for them to put all the dev kits out.
Rym: put everything out Let the developers learn their new environment and then go nuts.
Rym: The problem is Sony doesn't even really have their hardware in line yet Which means they can't really give the dev kits out and Say that these are gonna be the dev kit or this is going to be the platform Which means the developers haven't been able to do any real work.
Scott: We don't even know what the controller is gonna be.
Scott: I mean they showed that horseshoe controller and then I put that thing on my blog about how's a ripoff and whatever whatever.
Scott: and Now they're saying oh, that's not the final end.
Scott: They're not committing to anything.
Scott: They're so non committal that you might as well just say there might not even be a PlayStation 3.
Scott: They haven't even committed to that yet Or that might be.
Scott: the only thing they've committed to is that there will be a PlayStation 3 on some date.
Rym: Now in terms of blu-ray and HD DVD I think Sony realizes that there's been a lot of flack about blu-ray lately because they made that nice gesture of hey All right We won't do that analog down sampling even though what they really meant was all right.
Rym: the first few DVDs We release ourselves won't make use of that feature.
Rym: that will in fact be in all the players anyway.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Also the fact that I don't think consumers really give one shit one way or the other.
Scott: I think HDTV HDTV because their HDTVs are selling.
Scott: when you look at TVs that are selling now a lot of people are buying HDTVs as opposed to regular.
Rym: yeah despite the fact that the standards change and a lot of people are getting screwed with obsolete HDTVs that can't watch modern encrypted things.
Scott: But yeah the thing is is that consumers don't actually under.
Scott: they can barely hook up like a VCR to a TV.
Scott: They can't even get the 12 to stop blinking on their VCR.
Rym: now HDTV.
Rym: remember that statistic I pulled up months ago where they basically interviewed people and discovered that a good 75% of people who think they have HDTV actually don't because they don't have it hooked up right and it's not really working.
Scott: Yeah, like my dad.
Scott: He had an a bought an HDTV It's a Sony wega and he had this non digital cable, and there was no source of HD Content going to the television at all.
Rym: the thing is people think they see it because an HDTV Independent of the digital is a very high quality television.
Rym: Oh, yeah, which means even if you put a crap signal in it It'll look better than it looks on your crap TV.
Rym: the thing is it doesn't look that much better with the full HD Than it would.
Rym: anyway.
Rym: very few things actually take advantage of HD and in fact some mediums Well media are actually hurt by it for example daytime sitcom type things HD.
Rym: if you film those in HD the poor makeup becomes readily apparent, and it actually looks worse.
Scott: Yeah, if something wasn't designed to be HD, and you up sample it or watch it on a TV That's better than it was supposed to or you film something in HD that shouldn't be.
Rym: yeah You can see the freaking actresses pores, and it doesn't look good.
Scott: Yeah, actually I think HDTV is useful.
Scott: the number one thing that I think HDTV should be used for sports Yeah, this is the best thing in the world is watching hockey, and you can see more hockey two movies that are designed for it.
Scott: Yeah There's a website that shows you Lord of the Rings HDTV and not HDTV.
Scott: basically all the pictures are non HDTV and when you mouse over them the HDTV image takes its place.
Scott: There's a freaking striking difference.
Rym: like the thing is while the difference is striking in a still Because of the way TV works these old TVs with the interlay scanning if you actually watch it moving the difference is far less Noticeable.
Scott: difference is far less.
Scott: another thing I noticed is that a lot of TVs you'll see in stores the brightness is cranked all the way up because that's what sells TVs Is bright colors and hot bright bright colors and high contrast because that looks really cool.
Scott: You see like you know bright blue sky yellow flowers green green stems waving you know.
Scott: But really if you want to the real picture is supposed to be much much darker like I know.
Scott: on our TV There's like vivid.
Scott: normal pro and custom are like the four settings.
Scott: if we had HDTV pro is what you want to set it at.
Scott: yep.
Scott: But if you've just been looking at vivid pro looks like it's dark or something and you're like I can't see.
Scott: But that's how it's supposed to look.
Scott: and if you actually set it on pro and leave it there on an HDTV And you dark in the room when you watch That's there it is.
Rym: That's the real image, but I guess my final take on HDTV is that it's nice It's not worth the money.
Rym: It's not worth the DRM.
Rym: It's not worth the complication It's not worth the fact that it goes obsolete constantly because they're so afraid of piracy that they're crippling their own formats.
Rym: If it had just been HDTV if the industry had just said all right.
Rym: Here's the standard.
Rym: With over the next 10 years we're gonna have better television for everyone.
Rym: yay, that would have been great.
Rym: But no everyone's fighting with each other.
Rym: They're more afraid of their consumers than they are of each other.
Rym: even so they're fighting against us.
Rym: They really have no allies here except for crazy not to always buy TVs whenever a new thing comes out.
Scott: Yeah, those guys who need that 100 inch TV.
Rym: Yeah, the guys who basically spend their lives watching movies.
Scott: I'm probably gonna buy an HDTV Probably maybe five six years from now because when Nintendo comes out with the next console They said I think our water was talking about it.
Scott: How the reason they did the real reason they didn't do HDTV now is because sure it wouldn't hurt to throw it in.
Scott: you know It might increase the cost of the console, but they're already so much cheaper than everyone else.
Scott: It wouldn't matter so much and whatever.
Scott: There are a bunch of other reasons not to do it that are obvious But the number one reason was that there's no standard for HDTV and people wouldn't even really get it to work.
Scott: and who knows it would work on every HDTV.
Rym: and yeah plus making games.
Rym: And HDTV is mostly silly because all it does for now at least is add development time.
Scott: Yeah, it adds you need more processing power.
Scott: It's hard to develop.
Rym: You need more graphics and honestly the differences I mean when the Xbox 360 came out and I played a bunch of the demo games It didn't really look much better than previous similar games.
Scott: I saw on the Xbox normal Yeah, and you know sure even a 1080p TV doesn't come close to a PC monitor And you still don't have the interface to do the PC type of games, so It just makes it look shiny, which doesn't affect the game at all.
Rym: Yeah, and of course we see the problems with overheating in the Xbox.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure the PlayStation 3 is gonna have some similar problem, but a few years down the road I'm sure there will be one HDTV standard, and you know everything will start to work eventually Hopefully.
Scott: if it doesn't then fuck them all yeah, and by then Nintendo will say okay HDTV is this standard and they'll make the next console after the revolution will support that.
Scott: and that's probably when I'll buy an HDTV because there'll be a standard and it'll make sense to buy one and the price won't be stupid insane.
Rym: Now what else is Sony screwed up?
Rym: They had the root kits which they're still being sued over.
Scott: They're not beating the iPod.
Rym: Sony online entertainment with their Star Wars galaxies is pretty much in the shitter.
Rym: Yeah, and they're like it's done.
Scott: World of Warcraft killed off all their MMOs.
Scott: their Playstations are dead their electronics are getting kicked Their ass by Apple.
Scott: their computers not so good the memory sticks getting beat by sanders.
Rym: stock is dropping and honestly Mama, here's my prediction Rym's a randy million-dollar challenge psychic prediction for the future of Sony.
Rym: I think that Sony Sony hardware is going to eventually somehow split itself off From Sony intellectual property, that's not the actual names of them.
Rym: But I think there's gonna be a schism between the two Sony's.
Rym: Because currently I think most of Sony's problems come from the fact that half of Sony Wants to make things to sell to people like devices that do things people want and that's a very lucrative market.
Rym: The other half of Sony wants to sell ideas that are free anyway to people for a lot of money and doesn't want those devices To exist.
Rym: so instead Sony has to compromise and sells shit Shit devices that barely work and don't do everything we want.
Scott: I mean Sony's.
Scott: the real reason Sony didn't beat the iPod isn't because they didn't come out with a Better cheaper device soon enough.
Scott: I mean there were some pretty good Sony mp3 players.
Scott: The problem was that originally they didn't support mp3 and they didn't plug into computers easily.
Scott: And they were.
Scott: you had to use the stupid a track 3 thing.
Rym: and yeah, and I mean look at mini disc.
Rym: Mini disc was awesome, and then they crippled it to all hell.
Scott: well mini This was kind of big in Japan actually.
Rym: yeah Not in the u.s.. Not so much.
Scott: mini disk if you don't know is like a little tiny CD in a plastic case.
Rym: Thank you was magneto optical wasn't it yeah?
Rym: You can actually record on to it You know but it worked like a tape in that you couldn't.
Rym: I won't get all the details.
Rym: if you don't have one you don't care.
Rym: if you have one you already know.
Scott: yeah But just imagine you know it was supposed to be better than CD.
Scott: It was supposed to be like oh, it's CD quality, but you can record on to it like a tape.
Rym: ooh Yeah, it was a tape CD, and it was small.
Rym: and then is it's actually kind of handy until MP3s came around and kicked its ass, but they DRM crippled it to hell and it ended up being almost useless.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you could have let people you know buy mini discs in the store for a good price Then copy tracks off of them on to other mini discs and mix it up.
Rym: They copied them onto computers and all it would have been great couldn't even get consumer equipment that would record easily To mini discs especially not from any sort of digital source.
Rym: Yeah, and if you wanted that equipment you had to buy the professional mini disc stuff that cost ten times more.
Scott: of course It wasn't really that different at all.
Scott: I just had a digital input.
Rym: Yeah, I mean technologically it was identical almost.
Scott: It just had the word pro on it and a bunch of extra dollar signs.
Rym: So yeah, we'll see if Sony ever actually gets his act together and splits off.
Rym: But if it doesn't I don't think they're gonna be a viable company in the next decade.
Scott: who knows the only thing that really I think Keeps them from splitting isn't intelligence.
Scott: It's Japanese pride.
Scott: You know a lot about Japanese pride.
Scott: super agree I super agree super agree.
Rym: Yeah, those guys.
Rym: Well, I'll admit at least I mean they're racing f1 cars.
Rym: They're probably enjoying themselves.
Scott: Yeah, do you know what cars?
Scott: you know where those cars came from?
Scott: where they're four-year-old arrows cars Mm-hmm.
Scott: In other words, that's like if you went to.
Scott: Let me try to think of a really good analogy.
Rym: Well anyway.
Rym: for those who don't know in Japan They they have.
Rym: there's this one f1 team super aguri and they are basically they only exist so that there will actually be Japanese people racing Mm-hmm, because they're the two worst drivers in Formula One.
Scott: Well, no, I taka Masato probably isn't the second worst driver in Formula One.
Scott: He's one of the who was the one that crashed in Bahrain crash.
Rym: He hit the wall in the pit.
Scott: No crash.
Scott: He didn't.
Rym: he didn't bumped into it and then he bumped into one of his dude.
Scott: No, he didn't hit the wall He just hit one of his dudes.
Scott: That's UGE day.
Scott: He actually that guy comes from Japan.
Scott: Grand Prix's like What's the JG TC and all those sorts of things?
Scott: Like they're special Japan only racing circuits and such and that he's won a few things there.
Scott: But f1 is so far beyond any other race even in the shitty four-year-old arrows car that he's got nothing.
Rym: So those are all the major Technologically inclined stories.
Scott: We have various commentary about this week And if you don't want to hear us do boring just like every other tech podcast out there, you know Send us ideas of what to talk about on Monday.
Scott: Yeah, anything you want us to talk about that has any Slight connection to anything science or technology.
Scott: We'll do it unless we know nothing about it whatsoever.
Rym: We'll do it.
Rym: Anyway, yeah Yeah, we'll do anything.
Rym: we'll do the first one we get.
Scott: yeah if you want to hear about you know, like a National Geographic Documentary and giant squids.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: I just think about squids.
Rym: I think part of the problem is that we put science and tech on Monday Which is it's not a difficult topic for us But it's difficult to come up with a good idea to talk about that.
Rym: wouldn't yeah the hell out?
Scott: I know more about technology than I know about almost anything else But most I could talk about just informative technology stuff for hours and hours and hours.
Rym: Just today's I was talking to Scott.
Rym: I could drone on for a couple hours about nuclear weapons.
Scott: Yeah, I could.
Rym: I mean if you guys wanted something like that we could do it.
Scott: But I could sit here for like three hours telling you how to configure a Linux kernel based on your hardware.
Rym: Now the other problem is that Mondays you'd think oh, it's the beginning of the week.
Rym: We're fresh off the weekend.
Rym: No, we're absolutely wrecked from the weekend because we spend the weekend playing board games with friends usually Mmm, great.
Rym: Yeah board games.
Rym: I consider them to be as exhausting as physical activity.
Rym: only it's meant to lock exhaustion Mmm, and as you can tell we're rambling currently, so that's the end of today's episode tonight's episode going to bed.
Rym: tomorrow is Gaming day.
Rym: Yeah, I forget what we're gonna talk about.
Scott: I can tell you though that you even if you aren't Unusual subscriber to the Tuesday feed you will want to listen to tomorrow's episode.
Scott: Download it manually if you must because I have some excellent things of the day.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Yeah, really Actually, I have to agree with him on this.
Rym: It's kind of relevant to technology because it harkens back to a technology platform That is so maligned that most people don't even know it ever existed.
Scott: I knew it existed and I remembered something no one else remembered about a Games on it.
Scott: I did also anyway, yeah, we've talked about it at least once before in the show we have.
Rym: in fact It was my thing of the day a while ago because I had some video from it awesome And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: you can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and If you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206. three three three one five three seven.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.