Rym: It's Thursday September 14th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We conclude origins week with how we got into atheism.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Today sucked now.
Rym: Why would today suck?
Rym: I had a pretty good day today.
Scott: Well, I went to work and I played DDR at work as usual, but wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute You already had a better day.
Scott: and then after that I Went to do the finishing fixing of my parents computer.
Scott: now That sucked ass.
Scott: like you know how.
Scott: if you do something for the first time like build a computer and you're learning all kinds of Stuff it's a lot of fun, but then if you do it again, and you're not learning anything It's just a pain in the ass You know because all I wanted to do is finish fixing it and get home But I couldn't.
Scott: it just took so goddamn long like it took me from like three or four hours to do this stupid computer.
Scott: Uh, oh, yeah, but the worst part is nobody told me and I didn't know about ATX 2.0 power supply connectors.
Scott: apparently on newer 64-bit motherboards The ATX motherboard power connector has four more pins on it.
Scott: So I was trying to put a new motherboard in an old case With an old power supply and it didn't work.
Scott: No I had to go out to the store and buy a new case with a new style power supply to plug in the stupid.
Scott: Oh god Grumble grumble.
Rym: see.
Rym: it just goes to show that while everything in computer consumer computing technology has increased exponentially in the past six years in terms of the Actual, you know standards or things you need or requirements or prerequisites for everything There's really no centralized repository of that information.
Scott: it's mostly concerning the power supplies.
Scott: I mean everything else is sort of a no-brainer.
Scott: You just match up the letters, you know.
Scott: You buy one part and you buy another part that has the same set of letters on it.
Scott: You know PCI Express card for a PCI Express slot on the motherboard, you know, you match it up.
Scott: But for the power supplies, it's not obvious how many watts you need.
Scott: It's not obvious which power supply you need, you know You can't tell like could I have bought one a hundred watts less and save money?
Scott: Could I you know or did I need the hundred watts more it?
Scott: It's very difficult to find that information and it depends on so many factors that it's quite difficult to calculate Especially since a lot of the information isn't available anywhere.
Scott: So it kind of sucks, you know considering the power supply is such an important part of the computer.
Rym: Well, the conventional wisdom was always to buy the largest power supply you could afford.
Scott: Yeah, the problem with that now is that there are 1000 watt power.
Scott: Yeah, there are stupid power supplies now.
Scott: I mean like pretty much if you're making a desktop computer.
Scott: I would say that like a four hundred and fifty to a five hundred and fifty watt power supply depending on how many drives and Stuff you have is going to be enough most of the time.
Scott: But I see people now with like these seven hundred and fifty watt power supplies eight hundred watt.
Scott: It's crazy.
Scott: and you know, especially if you don't want to pay for your electric bill, you know If you get a power supply, that's more than you can afford more than you need.
Scott: Not only are you paying more for the power supply itself, but that's going to in the long run be relative little.
Rym: Are you saying that the the power supply the larger wattage power supplies draw more power?
Scott: Well, it depends.
Scott: they might.
Scott: they might be shittier, you know, cuz a lot especially a lot.
Rym: I'm just curious Do you know how that works?
Rym: How about what a power supply does?
Scott: Yeah, I know how it does.
Scott: But if you plug more stuff into it, then it draws more power.
Rym: If you don't plug more stuff into it, then it doesn't draw more power Alright, so in that case then why would be having a large power supply affect you negatively other than the fact that you spent a Lot of money on it?
Scott: because it seems to me that like a lot of these power supplies with the incredibly large wattage numbers On them are sort of like.
Scott: not, you know They're not like the high quality looking ones that you get in the.
Scott: you know, the the mean wattage numbers They look all shady.
Rym: So you're saying that the cheap power supplies leak a bunch of power.
Scott: Yeah, okay At least that's what it looks like to me.
Scott: I really I really wish that someone would do some research on this.
Scott: so we could you know like get a whole bunch of power supplies and get like an Intel machine an AMD machine and then like dual cores of each and then you know compare like which power supplies on which boards and how much power they draw and how much is needed.
Scott: with like just keep adding hard Drives until the power supply goes down and see how many you could add.
Rym: or you know You can look at the specs of say your processor and your hard drives and see how much power they draw and then Choose accordingly, but the problem is here.
Scott: if you do that is number one.
Scott: It's not obvious.
Scott: You have to actually do some work.
Rym: Well - I'm pretty sure it's still there.
Rym: I haven't looked at AMD's site in a long time But AMD used to have a large matrix that showed if you have this chip get a power supply at least this big.
Rym: Yeah, this chip get a power supply at least this big.
Scott: thing is the video cards.
Scott: nowadays Some of them need their own power.
Scott: some of them don't you know?
Scott: some things draw a lot more than other things do like Some of the CD roms and DVD burners nowadays draw a lot more power than some other models.
Scott: and The other thing is a lot of power supplies lie sort of like how those monitors lie About their dot pitch and stuff like that.
Scott: There are a lot of power supplies out there that are lying and they just you know Put kind of budged up numbers on them because no one can actually call them on it.
Rym: Yeah, I guess this is all you because I haven't even bothered looking at the current standards of computers because I'm not building my computer Until next year.
Rym: All I'm saying is that I if someone knows of a guy All you're saying is that you screwed up and you didn't buy what you needed.
Scott: so I went to the store and bought one.
Rym: but But I believe that's the gist of the story that Scott the computer expert bought the wrong component because they changed the technology without telling me You didn't look.
Scott: Anyway, there needs to be a guide about power supply purchasing.
Rym: Yeah, because because anyways is a valid deflection of the fact that you just you screwed up.
Scott: Are you trying to put this on me?
Rym: because it was your fault.
Scott: you would have screwed up.
Scott: also you didn't know.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: I would have looked.
Scott: you didn't know.
Rym: You didn't know I would have looked.
Rym: the thing is I haven't even looked at Motherboards in months.
Rym: you didn't know that would have screwed you to now because when I realize every time I build a computer I do about a.
Scott: but I wasn't building a computer.
Scott: I was replacing a motherboard and a CPU.
Rym: So the thing is you you did a computer upgrade without any planning.
Scott: I had the plan.
Rym: apparently it was a shitty plan Doesn't matter.
Rym: your plan was by component.
Rym: that won't work.
Rym: bitch about it on GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah, you know you give me a hard time when you give me a hard time like if I see something on the internet five Minutes after you do.
Rym: Yeah, that's right Even though Yesterday and this is a total aside before we do the news, but Scott is Laughing at his computer, and he turns to me.
Rym: He says did you see this guy?
Rym: and I are see you hacked himself with the loopback address?
Rym: And I looked at him and I said Scott that was on bash.org like six years ago.
Scott: I wasn't on bash.org six years.
Rym: That was all over the internet six years ago.
Rym: That is You want to talk about old news.
Rym: that is like the oldest thing fuck ever.
Scott: I wasn't in that crowd.
Scott: I didn't see that kind of stuff.
Scott: I was like I was like six months too late for that.
Scott: yes Like when that came out I was still playing like you know one player games at my computer.
Rym: Anyway to use Scott's deflection anyway to move on to our news We got one awesome news and one news that'll just piss you off And I'll do the piss off news first.
Rym: okay as I found out about this just now.
Rym: Now the I'm not gonna go over the exact details because you probably don't care which senator did what or who.
Rym: what's going on specifically?
Rym: But great the gist of the story is that the FCC commissioned a study with taxpayer money to figure out if a Concentration of media ownership would harm local content and harm local markets.
Rym: Because the FCC for a while has been trying to change the rules to let fewer companies own more TV and radio stations Or and newspapers and all the base.
Scott: It's so clear Channel and News Corp and all them.
Rym: Yeah Basically it would allow Turner.
Rym: it would allow the number of companies that run the major media in the u.s.
Rym: To be consolidated even further.
Rym: Monopoly I mean currently I don't remember the numbers, so I'm gonna make one up, but it's the last thing I remember.
Rym: reading was that Effectively, I think five companies controlled 95% of the media in the u.s..
Scott: The mass media at least.
Rym: yeah TV radio newspapers yeah, not counting pirate radio or anything.
Rym: not counting pirate radio not counting internet Just you know, but anyway the point is the FCC commissioned this study in order to you know find out if this would be harmful.
Rym: When the draft of the study came back, and they discovered that the study said yes It would be harmful their answer was to stop funding the study and then destroy all copies of it all right now.
Scott: all right Obviously number one.
Scott: I'm against destroying information of any sort if possible.
Rym: I have a much simpler point.
Rym: the FCC is supposed to be doing the common good And it seems like they're not doing the common good.
Rym: They're doing their agenda.
Scott: well That's obvious also.
Scott: But here's the thing if you just want you know if you already know what you want to do And you just want to create evidence Why fund a real study?
Scott: why not just write something that looks like you want to know why?
Rym: Because when the FCC has been trying to pull some of these shenanigans recently Congress has been saying no Good, they're doing their job.
Rym: So the episode.
Rym: so the FCC wanted evidence and when the evidence wasn't there Hey, you just got rid of it and swept it under the rug.
Rym: now the cool thing is.
Rym: The only reason we know about this is because someone in the FCC who was disgruntled Sent a copy of the study along with all of this stuff to senator Barbara Boxer Who you may remember for periodically being very awesome and periodically being crazy.
Rym: Yeah, one of those half-and-half senators She is one of the few senators who seems to actually at least stand up for what she believes in regardless of what people pay Her to say yep, that's pretty much it, but yeah There's not much more to it than that.
Rym: the FCC Commissioned to study the study didn't say what they liked so they destroyed the study and tried to pretend it never happened.
Scott: all I'm gonna Say is I hope that disgruntled guy gets transferred to other federal agencies and disgruntled all of them.
Rym: I hope that disgruntled guy becomes president.
Scott: that too.
Scott: He should be the president He should be like.
Scott: I'm the disgruntled guy.
Scott: vote for me.
Scott: I'm disgruntled.
Scott: I'll vote for you.
Scott: Everyone.
Scott: vote for disgruntled gay.
Rym: now of course you know politics, and you know our actual lives.
Rym: That's not real news the real news that the Wii was announced.
Scott: So Last night at least last night in the US.
Scott: It was like 2 p.m.. In Japan They had the Japanese Wii press conference.
Rym: If you have read the coverage of the Wii thing I suggest now that you read it again because all of the preliminary Reports were mostly horseshit.
Rym: Yeah, well no the only preliminary port that there was a all the ones I saw were like it's gonna come with two emotes, and it's gonna be.
Scott: well Here's what happened.
Scott: is the New York Times had an article ready because they had the inside scoop because that the New York Times and The information in the New York Times article was not all of the information.
Scott: But the information in it was correct And they put it out a little bit early and then in the Seattle newspaper Picked it up and put it online a little bit early.
Scott: So everyone knew the price and the release date of November 19th and the price of $250 early Before the press conference, but anyway the Japanese press conference is at 2 p.m.. In Japan last night Which it's gonna be 2 p.m.. In Japan pretty soon from the recording time of this and They're getting it on December something like December 2nd or something like that.
Scott: I forget I don't have the date in front of me for all about the same price and All I got to say is wow we get it first pun.
Rym: It seems one that all of the companies are kind of focusing much more on America than Japan Which is understandable from an economic perspective because the gaming market in America is Freaking massive
Scott: yep,
Rym: though it still surprises me that Sony turned their back on probably their most loyal fans.
Scott: Well, I think what Nintendo's starting to realize is that you know they support Japan so well with a whole mess of games and a Whole mess of everything and America gets the shaft And that's why they don't kind of go with the Nintendo.
Scott: well whereas the PlayStation and the Xbox get like these.
Scott: You know gets the shaft Europe You're every.
Rym: all three companies gave Europe the big finger and said hey, you'll get our system someday.
Scott: Well everyone else gets the major shaft no matter what like the whole.
Scott: think about the people in South Africa.
Scott: Are they getting Xbox 360s now?
Scott: think about that or then?
Rym: There's the people in Brazil are playing their master systems.
Scott: Yeah way to go.
Scott: master systems and Sega Genesis in Brazil and Sega Saturns possibly so.
Rym: anyway I'm sure many of you probably haven't but we're not gonna rattle off all the informations.
Rym: But the relevant bits.
Scott: yeah the relevant bits.
Scott: it comes with Wii Sports.
Rym: hooray I think this is a great move on Nintendo's part, but one now when it's sitting in the store and Mother who just now found out she can't get a PlayStation 3 sees that that Nintendo thing is real cheap And it comes with a game.
Scott: Yep, the other thing is I was kind of on the edge about Wii Sports because it looked like it wasn't much of a game But I kind of wanted it you know.
Scott: But I didn't really think that it was gonna be worth paying out.
Scott: You know a game price for it like not even 30 bucks.
Scott: It was maybe worth 20 bucks from what I had seen but they added bowling and boxing to it, which is awesome because I guarantee bowling is gonna be the most fun and They're giving it away with the system, so it's like hooray That's just what I wanted.
Rym: it also resets a precedent that has long disappeared.
Rym: Consoles don't come with games anymore.
Scott: Well they.
Scott: what happens is they do come with games But not at the original release.
Scott: like the GameCube didn't come with a game at release But then eventually they had like buy the GameCube that comes with Wind Waker buy the GameCube that comes with Metroid Prime.
Scott: Yeah, the GameCube that comes with bongos.
Scott: You know like the n64 they did the same thing.
Scott: There was the n64 that came with nothing and later on there was the n64 that came with Pokemon Stadium And the one that came with Donkey Kong 64 and all that stuff.
Rym: But like none of the modern says this is the only system now that comes with a game.
Scott: Yeah, they really should bring and it comes with a controller and a nunchuck.
Scott: They really just need to throw a memory card.
Scott: I mean and all that stuff in there be cool.
Rym: Yeah, I think they comes with enough.
Rym: it comes with more than I expected.
Scott: It definitely comes with a lot and I hear it's gonna be profitable.
Scott: So I think what they did is they put in as many accessories and stuff as they could.
Scott: Without you know, we'll still keeping a profit going.
Rym: Yep Now the actual we modes are kind of pricey, but they're not more expensive than like Xbox 360 wireless controllers by far Yeah, and you know, you're gonna have to buy them eventually.
Scott: So whatever now here's some other good really crazy news.
Scott: the the GameCube version of Zelda Twilight Princess is gonna come out like a week before The Wii and when the Wii comes out the Wii version of Zelda Twilight Princess will come out at the same time.
Rym: This is in my opinion while it is somewhat evil like it pisses me off like goddamn you but it's brilliant I can.
Scott: uh, it's a brilliant move of business.
Scott: because the thing is who's gonna buy the GameCube Zelda?
Scott: Why would you buy that when you can get the Wii one and you're probably the Wii is backwards compatible.
Scott: So why you know so many people?
Scott: everyone is a GameCube is gonna get away, you know, eventually I'm pretty sure.
Scott: So, you know who's gonna buy that GameCube Zelda?
Scott: not many people.
Scott: Well, if they can get it a week before they can get the Wii one a whole week They might do it because you could beat that game in a week.
Scott: Probably.
Rym: Yeah, you couldn't do everything in the game I thought I saw but dedicated number of fans buying it or the GameCube beating it and then not right.
Rym: not buying the new Zelda game again for the Wii right away, but buying it used later.
Scott: Yeah I see a lot of people buy the GameCube one play it when they get a Wii they'll put it in the Wii because they Backwards compatibility and continue playing it and then like way in the future because there's no way that There's not going to be a point in history in the future of this world where that is, you know before Armageddon where you will not be able to get a copy of Zelda Twilight Princess.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's not gonna be a hard game to get ever.
Scott: You can go to the store and buy Wind Waker now for like 10 15 20 bucks.
Scott: So you can go to the store and get Twilight Princess at any time.
Rym: Now the other interesting bit was that it looks like Unless Sony.
Rym: he drops the ball again.
Rym: The Wii is going to come out a few days after the PlayStation 3.
Scott: I am still not confident the PlayStation 3 is gonna come out.
Scott: Oh me either but few days before the Wii.
Rym: I wonder what Nintendo's motivation is.
Rym: I can think of a lot of ideas as to why they're choosing to do it that way and they all seem plausible.
Rym: But I wonder what Nintendo's thinking because they're not stupid.
Scott: Well, I think what it is is because they're focusing on the US where they're gonna release most of their systems.
Scott: They want to make sure that they get all the systems they can to the US, you know That's that's why they're going there first and also because the US.
Scott: you have a thing called Thanksgiving which they don't have.
Scott: you know in Japan a Black Friday and all that and then at least not the way Americans have it right.
Scott: and then You know a few weeks later, they're gonna go to Japan with all the rest of the systems, you know.
Scott: Like if they don't have enough it might be okay to shortchange Japan a little but I think they'll have enough.
Rym: well, there's also and people in slashdot have been talking about this and it seems Plausible and in the very least even if it wasn't intentional the effect will probably happen nonetheless.
Rym: but if there are well if when there are widespread ps3 shortages and Many many people go to the store before Christmas trying to buy the new PlayStation 3 for their kid and they can't get one And then they see the Wii they hear.
Rym: Oh that Nintendo system came out just now.
Rym: Hey, those are in the stores.
Rym: I can get one of those.
Scott: Yeah, huh?
Scott: Who knows all I'm saying is it's pre-order time.
Scott: Everyone pre-order you ease.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It also might have the effect of the PlayStation 3 comes out There's the press frenzy because you know The system actually comes out.
Rym: then the Wii comes out the PlayStation press disappears because now the Wii is the hot press It could be.
Rym: that is I think is what Nintendo's intention is.
Rym: or the other possibility that someone posited on slashdot And FARC do different people.
Rym: I'm pretty sure was that Nintendo is Confident that the PlayStation 3 is going to ship is going to slip its shipping date and as a result They'll get the announcement of wait.
Rym: Why is Nintendo going after the PlayStation then later?
Rym: Oh, no, the PlayStation slipped.
Rym: now the Nintendo is coming out first and they get more press as a result.
Scott: Yeah, that's my that's my guess right there There's no way.
Scott: I mean, come on.
Scott: There's no way the ps3s are gonna show up with games to play in November.
Rym: I mean yet anyone ever reported if the finalized dev kit ever got out.
Scott: Yeah, it's like what no one's finished a PlayStation game.
Scott: No, it's like what are they gonna do?
Scott: What do you think?
Scott: I mean, they've got working wheeze that they're traveling around the world with you know had letting people play As anyone played a PlayStation 3 other than a game developer or a Sony employee anyone.
Scott: There's no way.
Scott: I mean, I just don't believe that they could have it.
Rym: from what I've read They were pretty much done Testing the Wii itself and they've been testing the controllers and making sure the controllers are perfect for a long time now.
Scott: Yeah, they've been spending like months and months just honing and not you know developing.
Rym: It seems like the PlayStation 3 is spending the rest of this time Developing and not so much the honing not so much with the honing.
Scott: No, I mean, of course, I did hear one rumor that the Wii is gonna ship with like a firmware update disc, you know but You know, that's a good idea.
Scott: Well, it's like, you know you buy and then you put this disc in it to get it updated right away.
Rym: That is a good idea for a lot of.
Scott: well No What it means is that they didn't have time to flash them first and that you have to flash it when you buy it.
Scott: So they threw a disc in every box.
Rym: Well, what it also means is that they anticipate minor tweaks coming up But they didn't want to push back the date and they came up with a fairly elegant solution to that.
Rym: Yeah Whatever, I mean better than forcing a download or something unreliable.
Scott: Yeah, cuz a lot of be.
Scott: I mean the Wii is gonna be all about the connecting to the Internet's but a lot of people aren't gonna connect theirs to the internet because you don't know how they can't even get their wireless laptop to Work.
Rym: and that's one thing about Nintendo.
Rym: They'll always do, you know, they'll try new things and they'll do interesting things like that.
Rym: You know the internet access, but they always make sure to take care of all of their fans.
Scott: Yeah, so even if you don't use all the stuff you're taking care of You know a lot of people out there with DS is playing one-player games not using Wi-Fi not using nothing.
Rym: Anyway things of the day Since we don't want to go too in-depth on the Wii and since Rym forgot to put the things of the day in the show Yesterday.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the thing is because we had a guest on the show Emily.
Rym: I Guess but we hadn't had a guest in a while.
Rym: So I forgot to take that little thing of the day wave and stick it in the middle.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: So as a result, I'm going to put yesterday's things of the day one.
Rym: It'll be in the archive when we eventually release, you know season one of GeekNights.
Rym: eventually, I'm gonna re-fix the episode and Additionally, I'm going to put the things of the day as a special probably this weekend.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: Anyway, we do have things today for today and because they're part of the main bit There is no way they will not be in the show.
Rym: hooray, and mine is also very very quick and somewhat relevant at the topic at hand now.
Rym: a while ago in Afghanistan a soldier an American soldier was killed.
Rym: this American soldier happened to be a member of the Wicca religion and As he was dead his family and as he had wished wanted a pentacle on his military tombstone.
Rym: There was all sorts of rabble rousing by people who said you can't do that.
Rym: You can't put that on there.
Rym: it's not an official recognized symbol and There was a shitstorm and then it disappeared.
Scott: atheists have a symbol Wicca's can have a six have a symbol.
Rym: yeah, there are I think 32 symbols that are recognized by the military and Just now now they haven't agreed to put it on the actual tombstone yet as far as I can tell but that's coming.
Rym: but his memorial plaque is art.
Rym: they're putting the.
Rym: in fact, they already made it a Glad.
Rym: like every every now and then I get angry about how annoying politics are in this country America and how things are going.
Rym: and Whenever I get frustrated like that, it's always nice that at least every now and then someone does something right or something smart.
Scott: Yeah, they let us win those small into consequential Inconsequential completely meaningless battles when we lose all the actual meaningful ones.
Rym: It's something.
Rym: it's something.
Scott: it's something that doesn't really matter except, you know, you know what it meant.
Rym: I've always noticed that the American military Throughout history has always been in many ways much more progressive than society in general I mean when it came to blacks during, you know after the Civil War and during segregation.
Rym: The military is one of the first organizations to say we need soldiers.
Rym: I don't care what color you are.
Rym: Here's a gun.
Scott: Well, the military is sort of like, you know You can look at it if you want the American military as like the experiment for American society.
Scott: It's like where they try shit out before they let they try it on the real people, you know They try out all our other real people like yeah It's like the the internet.
Scott: they made the internet and then they gave it to the citizens and then you know They may they let black people in and then they let the black people in in the regular society.
Scott: It's like they see how shit works in the in the military.
Rym: I Think it's much more simple.
Rym: I think Many of the people in the military by nature of their job are very pragmatic and practical when it comes to doing Whatever works in a situation supposed to give a reasonable explanation.
Scott: You're supposed to give a funny one.
Scott: What's wrong with?
Rym: alright fine You know what?
Rym: Here's the funny bit.
Rym: I'm gonna join the military and die somewhere in some hellhole Just so a flying spaghetti monster can be on my tombstone damn straight.
Rym: Okay So what do you got?
Rym: so?
Scott: You know the kind of music with like the surf the Japanese surf guitar and the flute, you know You get the.
Scott: you know what that sound of music.
Scott: that then I do.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: if our listeners do Well, you're gonna listen to it.
Scott: cuz my thing of the day some guy the great Japanese guitarist Takeshi Terayuchi and his band the bunnies have played many many classical Melodies with the Japanese surf guitar of awesome.
Scott: It's sort of like, you know, if some guy to you know, does a bunch of rock versions.
Scott: This guy did surf guitar versions.
Scott: It's way cool and there's a lot of songs and they're all free mp3 downloads that are legitimate.
Scott: so the awesome He's got let's see.
Scott: He's got the.
Scott: the Swan Lake which is my favorite doesn't have a Tetris song in there.
Scott: Well, he has.
Scott: the fur Elise is no no Hungarian dance.
Scott: Number five is one of the Tetris songs, isn't it?
Scott: I think I forget how exactly how that one goes.
Rym: don't bring something up if you don't know.
Scott: I'm pretty Hungarian dance.
Scott: number five.
Scott: I'm pretty sure is in.
Rym: are you the?
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's gonna stand by that.
Scott: I'll bet on it.
Scott: 75% 75 cents.
Rym: Yeah, you'll bet 75 cents 75%.
Rym: so you're not gonna bet money.
Scott: No, I'm not.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Scott: He's got the fur Elise on here and saber dance.
Scott: It's good stuff.
Scott: You should listen to it.
Scott: It's awesome free music.
Rym: But actually if you you all have heard the saber dance when you hear it, you'll go.
Rym: Oh, it's that song.
Scott: Yeah, that's generally how a lot of classical songs are.
Scott: It's like, you know people hear it like someone will go And you'll go.
Scott: I fucking know that song and you'd be like, yeah What song is it?
Scott: and only smart people go in the hall of the Mountain King?
Scott: Everyone else goes.
Scott: I have no idea but I know the song just like chromatic episode 2.
Rym: You know the story of like the story behind the song in the hall of the Mountain King Like what story the song is trying to portray?
Scott: there was a mountain and there was a. there's a hall in the mountain with the king in it and there was like a An elf or some shit going to meet him or something and died.
Scott: and I don't know what.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Just make it shit up That's not it at all.
Rym: I just wondered maybe I'll do a show on something like that.
Scott: You do a whole show on the hall of the Mountain King.
Scott: Yeah, I'll spell.
Scott: I'll talk about this old DOS game I played that was a had.
Scott: that song was the only music and you were like this elf guy walking around with a net and you would capture things and then you would answer questions and then.
Rym: so It's not like that DOS or that ASCII dwarf game that our people in our forums are playing.
Scott: No, it's not like that at all.
Scott: This is like a children's game.
Rym: Anyway Anyway, the main bit today if you couldn't tell from the opener is we're going to because we couldn't come up with what we were Going to talk about today.
Scott: We thought we had no idea.
Rym: We thought origins week was great And then last night we finished the episode and I turned to Scott and I said What are we gonna do tomorrow?
Rym: and he didn't say anything and I didn't say anything.
Rym: and then we both Simultaneously said fuck.
Scott: Yeah, it was like we're gonna do the origins of how we got into sports and I was gonna be like I was right.
Scott: I'm a hereditary fan of New York sports teams.
Scott: yeah, the end and I talked about like how I got into music as a musician, but Scott's not a musician or Unless I'm more of a musician than most people but less of a musician than musicians.
Rym: I mean there weren't many things that we could both talk about that any of you would care about.
Scott: Yeah, and then that Rym was enlightened.
Rym: I Thought of it only because you know, I'm not sure why I thought of it probably are crazy forums.
Scott: possibly This episode is basically fan service for the forum folk.
Scott: And if you like this episode, you'll probably like the forum.
Scott: So go join.
Rym: Yeah, the forums are getting to the point where I can't deal with them on my own anymore.
Scott: Yeah, like it used to be like like it.
Rym: let me put it this way if Scott and I stopped doing GeekNights I'll bet the forums would keep going for a while a long while.
Scott: The thing is there's some forums I go to on the internet where I read only like a few stories, you know.
Scott: And there's some forums I go on the internet where no one's there.
Scott: Our forums are like on this borderline now where they're either growing.
Scott: it used to be that I could read every story.
Scott: now I can still read every post on our forums, but it's a lot and I'm getting tired.
Scott: So eventually real soon probably in a few weeks.
Scott: I won't be able to read the whole forums anymore.
Scott: I'll have to let some of it go.
Rym: Well, the thing is you all know, mr.
Rym: Period There's a good chance that he will be joined by mr.
Rym: Question mark.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Comma, mr Semicolon in the future because we and mr.
Rym: Period are not enough to handle the forums anymore.
Scott: No, it is getting out of control, but we digress.
Rym: Therefore no God.
Scott: Okay, there be no God anyway zero that the topic here.
Rym: We're good.
Scott: We're not gonna talk about Philosophy, yeah, we're not gonna argue for or against atheism.
Scott: We're going to talk about how we became to have the beliefs that we do have and first to define that was a great sin That was beautiful.
Scott: That's awesome.
Rym: before we do anything I want to define the terms and I'll use the definitions the simplified definitions that we are going to use now because This is one of those topics where the exact nature of what you say means a lot.
Rym: I mean, there's a huge difference between saying there is a God there might be a God there Can't be a God or there probably isn't a God and there isn't.
Scott: there's a huge Demarcation there and you could even get more specific.
Scott: you'd be like there never was.
Scott: there is now There isn't now there used to be.
Rym: there will be If you really want to get into it.
Scott: there might have been but there isn't now.
Rym: if you guys really want to have this argument Someday, or you really want to learn a lot about this read up on agnosticism as in what agnosticism really means and then Gnosticism and what that really means and then solipsism and what that really means and it's all philosophy Which Scott says is BS and I say is the only truth.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh and also I just want to note that Richard Dawkins has a new book I don't know if it's out yet or just recently out or coming soon called the God's illusion, which you should read.
Rym: I Thought you're gonna mention a different book that he wrote a while ago.
Scott: No, the one that he's kind of like the newest hot one the God's illusion is his new one.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway We're not talking about spirituality personal belief.
Rym: We're mostly talking about atheism and theology in regards to religion now.
Rym: I posted in the forums the thing but to reiterate Spirituality or Gnosticism are much more in line with philosophy and thought exercises than with practical applications Because they tend to fall along the lines of there may be a god or I feel that there is a god or I feel That there is something out there, but I can't prove it.
Rym: Therefore it's not scientific and it's not something that can apply to the real world or it doesn't have to exist because I exist Whether or not I believe in it.
Rym: Yeah, but religion is.
Rym: when you take that and you put a specific belief behind it It's no longer.
Rym: there might be a creator or there might be a demiurge It's now.
Rym: there is a specific god named Bob and he lives in the sky and his son ate peas on Thursday And that's why dogs have tails Ever.
Scott: people only exist because a flying spaghetti monster created us with this noodly appendage.
Rym: So just don't forget that while we talk about this that we're talking about religion not philosophy not spirituality.
Rym: Those are different topics.
Rym: So anyway You want to start or shall I?
Scott: I'll start because I'm a Jew.
Rym: Yeah, you were also much closer to anti theism than I am.
Scott: Yeah slightly but Anyways, I was born a Jew from Queens now culture nice Jewish boy by blood and by culture.
Scott: Well, I was you know, yeah, but I mean I was born that way.
Scott: but then you know I was a Jew, you know, and it kind of just like.
Scott: I didn't think about it that much.
Scott: I wasn't like, you know, it's an Orthodox Jew or you know, it's not.
Scott: it was kind of like yeah, I'm Jewish I didn't think about God.
Scott: I didn't you know think about Religion.
Scott: I thought about video games and cartoons and shit, you know when I was a little kid and I mean You know, he went to the synagogue and we did the Jew stuff, but I didn't think much of it.
Scott: It was just like a thing we do, you know, like, you know other kids did church and we did Jewish temple because that's the way it is.
Scott: you know these people do this those people do that.
Scott: who cares?
Scott: and I was a little kid I didn't care.
Scott: and Then you know, like I just lived my life as if I wasn't very religious.
Scott: I didn't believe in anything magical, but I didn't you know say I am an atheist.
Scott: Ah ha ha ha ha.
Scott: I just kind of didn't do or care.
Scott: I even did a lot of stuff hanging out with Jews and going to Israel and doing Jew trips and Making Jew friends and going to Jew temples and celebrating Jew holidays, but I didn't really ever you know Believe strongly or at all.
Rym: It was just kind of a Now what about things like Santa Claus or the Easter Bunny or Hanukkah Harry?
Scott: Yeah, Hanukkah Harry was just a joke that I discovered in high school.
Scott: It was always just kind of a joke.
Scott: I just like saying Hanukkah Harry Yeah, Santa Claus the Easter Bunny tooth fairy all that stuff like when I was a little kid.
Scott: I don't think there was ever a point at which I just said yes it where I believe that it was true.
Scott: I was pretty much like Questioning it.
Scott: I was like, I don't know.
Scott: I don't know That's really that was one thing.
Scott: is that the problem with Jewish white?
Scott: I've noticed that lately there are a lot of Jewish atheists.
Scott: They're like even like atheist rabbis like, you know, they're they're rabbis, but they don't believe that there's anything supernatural.
Scott: It's crazy.
Scott: Well,
Rym: I I just note that we I mean we go to conventions a lot and there are many times We'll meet like a webcomic artist or we meet someone cool we know and they're they're obviously Jewish and Scott will say something like hey Something something Jew and they'll be like, yep something something Jew.
Rym: and then Scott will pause a minute and he'll say Atheist Jew and without fail they've always said right on or yes or something to that effect Yeah, it's it's what I think my current theory not even very high.
Scott: not this is non theistic Jew.
Rym: Yeah, put it that way.
Scott: my current hypothesis about the atheist Jews is that?
Scott: Judaism is really a religion about studying this old and false book full of good stories and as a result modern Jews strongly emphasized to their children education like education the most important thing in the world like a Jewish mother cares more about the grades of their children, you know.
Scott: I think the only thing they care more about the grades of their children is the health of their children.
Scott: It's like are you eating?
Scott: Well, did you get an a?
Scott: it's like that's the heads that that's the list.
Rym: You look a little thin you only got an a-minus.
Scott: yeah, I know right.
Scott: so as a result the kid Jewish kids You know, especially recent ones my generation and newer are very very educated and when you're very very educated You tend not to be as religious, you know, I mean sure there are very educated religious people.
Scott: But as a whole, you know, if you look most non religious people tend to be more educated.
Scott: Well, actually that's why it's only a hypothesis.
Scott: I don't have a I don't have a causation I only have a correlation.
Rym: I bring up a couple of interesting studies over the years.
Rym: Well, there have been many studies showing that the prison population is in America At least the most religious group of people in the country Mm-hmm if you're people in prison are more likely to be Christians than they are to be any.
Scott: but is it because they're in prison?
Scott: And then they become religious or they?
Rym: it's hard to say.
Scott: Yeah, see there's another correlation without cozy, you know, but yeah.
Rym: But there are other correlations like the more the higher degrees a person has the less religious they tend to be.
Scott: Yeah stuff like that.
Scott: Yep I remember reading this great article about a guy who was a super Christian and then he had like he got many many PhDs in like theology and then he just had to become an atheist and he was kind of sad about having to you know Stop believing of
Rym: course.
Rym: then there was the Emperor Julian of Byzantine who was sent to study Christianity and he studied it more and more and more and the More he studied it the more he thought it was wrong.
Rym: But instead of saying I'm an atheist.
Rym: He said I'm going back to worship the Roman gods.
Rym: I'm a pagan.
Scott: Yeah, all right anyway, then he got killed.
Scott: The point is is that you know, I never really believed strongly in any of it.
Scott: I mean, I'm a huge fan and still a huge fan of like, you know Culture and heritage of Jews because I think everyone should be a fan of their own heritage.
Rym: in college I never would have guessed from the Israeli flag that you hang in your bedroom.
Scott: I only it's not there anymore actually, but Yeah, I bought it.
Scott: but you know, I'd like flags.
Scott: so when I went to Israel there was an Israeli flag.
Scott: So and it's a cool flag.
Scott: So I bought it and I hung it up.
Scott: It was you know, some people thought it was like in college.
Scott: I remember some Israeli came up to me and he's like, hey you from Israel and I'm like, no, I just bought it there.
Scott: I think it's cool.
Rym: Yeah, I wasn't trying to make a statement or anything Actually in my bedroom in high school for the longest time at a Russian flag, not the Soviet Russian flag But the modern Russian flag.
Scott: Yeah, because I was a fan of their hockey team It's not as cool as the one with the sickle and the hammer and the stars.
Rym: Yeah, I know I know I couldn't find the communist one easily to purchase but I had a Russian flag.
Scott: No, because you'd only find that in like a commie store Anyway, or on the internet.
Scott: so not ever really having believed strongly, you know I just kind of didn't care.
Scott: and then you know in recent years like I'd say within the past four to five years Mostly at college, you know religions started doing bad things.
Scott: We started seeing terrorists blow shit up.
Rym: We started I think it's more that you noticed religion was doing bad thing.
Scott: that also, you know And I noticed like I watch I was heavily influenced by like, you know, Randy Which I started reading the amazing Randy James Randy Randy org.
Scott: Yeah, I started noticing all these, you know, like I used to just ignore that stuff, you know Like it was like.
Scott: at one point I had the attitude of I'm not sure these herbal medicines are doing anything I don't believe in that.
Scott: Yeah, I don't you know.
Scott: and other people would be like no What are you talking about?
Scott: And then I was like wait a minute They really don't.
Scott: these people are crazy.
Scott: and I just started seeing.
Scott: You know faith and just belief in stuff without proof causing all sorts of harm everywhere.
Scott: So I'm like, alright now I'm now I'm pissed off.
Scott: So I'm actually gonna care.
Scott: It was like I was an atheist, but I wasn't really.
Scott: I just didn't care at all I didn't even have an opinion.
Scott: and then I started noticing that the non atheist was causing a problem.
Scott: So I had to you know move slightly to the other side and go girl.
Rym: So basically you were an atheist who became also a skeptic.
Scott: Yeah Something like that.
Rym: see my story is much more complicated partly because on my father's side the family is Catholic from Belgium.
Scott: Mm-hmm, though.
Rym: I don't think my father ever actually believed in it.
Scott: Yeah I don't.
Rym: it's kind of hard to gauge how much my family and I know my mom was both a hippie and a witch and A pagan and all sorts of fun stuff when she was younger and I don't think she ever quite gave up on all that.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean I went.
Rym: I lived in Detroit.
Rym: I was born in downtown Detroit, which basically meant being a frail nerdy white boy.
Rym: There is no way I could go to public schools.
Rym: No offense to Detroit, but those schools would have killed me.
Rym: so my parents spent a lot of money to send me to a Catholic school and as a result, I one had to attend religion classes and I had to go to church and we had to go to church every Sunday and I Never actually really believed it.
Rym: I mean I kind of when I was very young, you know, like elementary school like first grade I kind of just you know, my parents would say, you know Hey, we gotta go to church and I'd go to school.
Rym: They'd be like, ah Jesus did this and I just didn't question it because no teachers know everything.
Rym: And then I started noticing right around around second grade that a lot of it didn't make sense particularly this whole heaven business.
Scott: Yeah, I remember like the weirdest thing was that when I was in school like public school learning history, right?
Scott: And then we'll go to Hebrew school and learn history and I'd be like, alright, I try to match up the years I'd be like, alright, so what did Moses come before after this, you know?
Scott: I'd be like what the Egyptians are doing this.
Scott: I could never match up the timelines and then eventually I figured it out.
Scott: Oh those things didn't happen.
Scott: Yeah, those are just made up.
Scott: Oh But that's why it doesn't matter.
Scott: the
Rym: things that really struck me was that one if there's this all-powerful God Why does he care if I waste two hours of my Sundays my free time to sit in a box and listen to someone talk about things I don't care about and then give me some bread a little bit of wine.
Rym: and Then more importantly the idea of heaven was what bothered me the most because I thought about it and I realized that the concept Of heaven was frightening.
Rym: to me It sounded like the most horrid boring terrible thing that could ever happen because according to at least Catholic mythos If you heaven is where you will go and sing the hosannas to the highest forever.
Rym: basically, if you are good here, you'll see get sent to heaven where you can spend the rest of your life worshiping someone.
Rym: and at that point I thought straight up and this is like second grade if that's what heaven is I'd rather go to hell.
Rym: and Then I thought about hell and I realized wait a minute I'm only on earth for at most like a hundred and thirty years probably more like 60 or 70.
Rym: So, uh, let's say I do bad things in this God's eyes.
Rym: All right If I do bad things, he's gonna send me to hell forever Forever because I did one bad thing even I did a million bad things.
Rym: forever seems like a lot for a million bad things because it's infinitely bigger than a million.
Rym: and then I thought but the whole idea is kind of stupid because if there's a God and he made me.
Rym: why would he make me just so we can throw me in fire?
Rym: and Then from there, I pretty much thought oh there probably just isn't a God.
Rym: see I think that's one of the reasons that I just kind of just it didn't make sense Yeah, or I like the more I studied it the more I thought about it.
Rym: and this is like a second grader.
Rym: So most of the answers I got were I'd ask a teacher Who was a nun and they would give me some bullshit answer and then I'd say that answer doesn't make sense and they'd hit me.
Scott: Or they'd say well don't question it I Don't really like in least in the conservative Jewish temples, you know and all that stuff that I went to.
Scott: they don't really teach.
Scott: You know like stuff like that.
Scott: I mean what you learn in Hebrew school.
Scott: I mean other than people saying there is God he's ever, you know, they didn't even say he.
Scott: they said there's a God It's everywhere.
Scott: It's omnipotent.
Scott: It's omniscient.
Scott: Whatever the they don't really say, you know, like yeah, Adam and Eve is true Believe it.
Scott: Yeah, all this stuff is true.
Scott: Believe it.
Scott: They say let's learn Hebrew Let's learn the Hebrew alphabet.
Scott: Let's memorize these songs.
Scott: Let's sing and dance.
Scott: Let's eat food.
Scott: You know They don't really teach all this kind of stuff that I was able to question at least not at the age that I was still You know going and attending and all that stuff.
Scott: So there really wasn't anything to make me go.
Scott: Wait a minute You're you're full of shit because they didn't say anything.
Scott: They just taught me the Hebrew language.
Scott: They only taught me how to read it.
Scott: I don't understand most of the words but
Rym: yeah Catholics were much different in that they would say like
Scott: literally,
Rym: this is what happens and this is this and Jesus did this and God did this and the Holy Spirit is this and They just it didn't make any sense at all.
Scott: Yeah, the worst that we would get is yeah Moses parted the sea and I was like, oh You know, it was only like a little things here and there which I kind of ignored didn't really care.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: It's like.
Rym: it's like what do you want him in?
Scott: This is a pretty good movie.
Rym: When you watch utenna and something fucked up happens and you just think it's anime stuff like that happens.
Scott: Yeah, that's exactly what you don't question.
Scott: They tell me this story about you know, two people and you know One guy cheats on another guy and then guy does a bad thing and then you know And it's like other than like Noah's Ark which I guess, you know is kind of believable because I didn't imagine like some You know non possible flood.
Scott: I imagined a normal flood.
Scott: So, you know, it's kind of like You know, they tell these stories and I would imagine them in a way that you know made sense without you know.
Rym: crazy I'd imagine them and I couldn't possibly conceive of a way for them to make sense in a rational world.
Rym: So like
Scott: the Noah's in the ark like I imagine that there weren't that many people because it was so early in the history of The world that you know They were like all in one spot and then it all got flooded in one area where they were and then the flood went away.
Scott: So I remember one day this is the second or third grade the two animals though I did I just kind of didn't think about that the two of every animal.
Rym: I just remember there was a point at which I was sitting down.
Rym: I was in church I didn't want to be there and it was hot and it sucked.
Rym: and I just thought you know, what?
Rym: There's no God.
Rym: and then I thought I got last chance if you're there do something awesome right now.
Rym: Otherwise, you don't exist and nothing happened.
Rym: and I thought all right.
Rym: and the next day I told my parents yeah, so I don't want to go to church anymore and my parents didn't seem to care at all.
Rym: and They I think like I went to catechism when I moved out of public school or out of private school into public school For like a month.
Rym: and then I was like, this is horseshit.
Rym: I'm not going to this anymore.
Scott: Yeah, my parents like I don't think my dad really cares and I'm pretty sure my grandpa doesn't see anything.
Rym: I know at least my grandma was really religious.
Scott: Yeah, my grandma's not really religious, but I do think that she believes in some sort of you know, spiritual God.
Rym: Well, my grandma was always warning when I was a little kid to not get into all that occult stuff.
Rym: Cuz they'll steal my soul and sacrifice me to the devil.
Scott: Yeah, and all I thought my grandma says Why don't you find and marry a nice Jewish girl?
Rym: You get married a nice Jewish girl.
Rym: I get the devil will get you.
Rym: Yeah, don't do that occult stuff.
Rym: Of course, all I thought is the kid was.
Rym: but that occult stuff sounds awesome.
Rym: Yeah Because I gotta say I really like a lot of the cultural aspects of not so much the modern religions But the older religions like.
Rym: there are things in them that I really like and I like cultures in general.
Rym: So, I mean I do a lot of silly things.
Rym: like whenever I drink wine I always leave a little bit of my glass with glass which nominally is for the fairies, which I know.
Rym: Yeah, they're not out there, but I still I thought I'd like to think like it's cool.
Rym: It's kind of a cultural thing an affectation.
Scott: It's because you're a fairy And I'm very philosophical.
Rym: I still I think a lot, you know, I I have existential crises pretty much every day.
Rym: But I think a lot about philosophy.
Rym: and what am I and where did I come from?
Rym: But the thing is No religion.
Rym: There's never been evidence in all of history For the existence of any of the supernatural things that any known religion has ever claimed.
Rym: never yet Every religion known to man you can find historical origins of it and those historical origins have always been secular.
Rym: You can see the political and the cultural and the social forces that brought about these religions.
Scott: Yeah, like it the the Old Testament is like the easiest one cuz like okay is this book?
Scott: Let's see where it came from.
Scott: Let's see where each part came from.
Scott: Oh, well, look, here's a part that's called in a Apocryphal text that didn't make it that used to be in the book.
Scott: Oh, here's a part Deuteronomy that was written by these guys the Deuteronomist in year X. They were just some guys.
Rym: Well, here's here's a really really useful anecdote.
Rym: because this was I got in trouble for laughing out loud in class And I wouldn't tell my teacher why in high school.
Rym: But we were sitting in a social studies class and we were talking about India and and like reverence for cows panacheads and things like And things like that, you know where that comes from?
Scott: now someone where I got that from right someone.
Rym: I'm just letting that go.
Scott: Why don't you?
Scott: why don't you share with the class?
Scott: Why why I said who panacheads?
Rym: So, oh, come on you suck We'll have to forums to meter that one out.
Scott: All right, we'll see.
Scott: if they guess why I can't.
Scott: I came to mind suddenly.
Rym: So we are talking about and he's talking about.
Rym: the cows were sacred but that came about because Invading forces realized that I forget the exact details that the cows were more useful in a famine Situation.
Rym: for their milk and the pen they're dung and then they were for their meat and if you killed them It was a waste of a resource.
Rym: So they're sacred now there.
Scott: that way people won't kill them and people will be better off a lot of yeah A lot of stuff in the in the Old Testament's like that too.
Scott: Like, you know don't eat pig.
Scott: was because in those days gnosis if you ate a pig you got your kenosis.
Scott: Sure to eat a pig.
Rym: I don't remember the details But I remember that we had this discussion and then this girl raised her hand in class and she said and I remember it very clearly Well, so you're saying that their religious thing just came from what some guy said to trick them.
Rym: and the teacher says yeah We have a lot of evidence this.
Rym: and she says well, why do they still believe it?
Rym: Didn't anyone tell him?
Rym: And I Remember that she was a Christian and I was.
Rym: I just I started laughing cuz I didn't.
Rym: I just wanted to stand up and say Christians are just Joe's but they were just uprisings in Judea.
Rym: They came from this cult.
Rym: We know exactly where it came from.
Rym: It's no different.
Rym: What the hell?
Rym: It was the most.
Rym: it was so ironic your religion came from some guy just saying stuff - aha Or it might have come from some guy writing stuff.
Scott: Oh Huh doesn't matter either way.
Scott: Yeah, I could have come from some girl right and stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but in terms all this I mean, I never believed in Santa Claus or the Easter Bunny or any of that at all.
Rym: I pretty much knew from the start.
Rym: It was my parents at least from the moment I was sentient yeah, and I played along because I knew that my parents were trying to do this thing and I kind of gathered what it was like The idea of it.
Rym: and also I had a little brother and I wasn't gonna ruin it for him.
Rym: So I Pretended to go along with it.
Rym: But I knew and I always used to set little like traps because I knew it would catch my parents.
Rym: So like I'd string tripwires the night before Christmas in the living room.
Rym: Yeah, just cuz I knew a trip my dad up.
Scott: The only thing really a bit magical about Hanukkah is where the hell did she hide those presents in the basement?
Scott: I couldn't find them.
Scott: I looked down there the day before.
Scott: where were they see?
Rym: I knew where my parents had the presents.
Rym: I didn't look at him out of respect.
Rym: I don't because I didn't want to ruin that moment of finding out what they were.
Scott: I never.
Scott: I knew they were hidden in the basement.
Scott: because you know eight days of presents and every night We're standing in the kitchen.
Scott: Mom goes down to the basement.
Scott: We watch her go down there.
Scott: She comes back up with presents.
Rym: you go down there.
Rym: You couldn't find him.
Scott: I would go down there like, you know the day before Hanukkah look at that couldn't find shit.
Scott: I'd go down there during.
Scott: I couldn't find shit.
Scott: I don't know where the hell she hid those things.
Scott: I still don't know.
Rym: Maybe I should ask her Yeah, I I knew where my parents hit all of them.
Rym: I just didn't look at him.
Scott: they hid it in the basement some tricky place and it's you know, it was of course.
Rym: I remember my parents taking me to see Santa Claus and I remember every time just thinking why are they putting me through this?
Rym: It's obviously some fat old guy making minimum wage.
Scott: Yeah, I always knew it was a fat old guy making minimum wage.
Scott: There was no question about that.
Rym: Yeah scary Yeah, but also a nice little aside here in terms of the word atheism a lot of people confuse it.
Rym: Atheism is not anti theism.
Rym: They're similar.
Rym: but anti theism is the belief that there is nothing supernatural or at least that there are no religious things or no No gods or however you want to define theism atheism is Effectively the belief that there aren't anything because there's no evidence or it's.
Rym: there's the similar Agnosticism that you believe you can't know and therefore you don't care.
Scott: Yeah to me.
Scott: I really I don't care what you believe.
Scott: I mean if you believe in the Flying Spaghetti Monster for real or if you believe in the Christian guy It doesn't matter.
Scott: What matters is how you live your life.
Scott: You know if you live your life as if there is an all-powerful All-seeing God who will punish you and you do and the actions you take are based on Your fear of some imaginary thing then you're living your life in a very different way from someone who makes decisions based on things that happen in the real world and real consequences and One kind of person is very dangerous and one kind of potentially very dangerous and the other kind is Quite likely much less dangerous and in fact beneficial to the world as a whole.
Scott: and you know That's what really matters to me is it's like are you a crazy nut who's gonna you know?
Scott: Go blow up an abortion center because you believe some crazy batshit or you someone who's gonna go You know research some science because you know that there ain't other shit out there.
Rym: You know that was almost eloquent until you said the words there ain't other shit out there There ain't other shit out there.
Rym: That was that was horrid.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what to say to that.
Rym: That was just horrid.
Rym: Yeah And I'm just.
Rym: I mean, I'm very much more philosophical.
Rym: I mean, I think I think a lot about what where's my consciousness come from and where is it going?
Rym: And where?
Rym: what did anything make it?
Rym: Was it always there?
Rym: Was it formed?
Rym: Is it just physical?
Rym: is some quantum thing?
Rym: I don't know about.
Rym: And you know all those sorts of things.
Scott: I'd like the answers to those questions, but really even if I had all of them, they really wouldn't affect.
Rym: you know I guess you know what I think I that's that's one of the big parts of not a Idea that if if there is a creator or if there isn't a creator It doesn't matter because what you're observing happens the same.
Rym: and the theory you have about what you're observing Doesn't require the creator because you found another alternate solution.
Rym: Therefore it doesn't matter if the creator exists or not.
Rym: So you don't have to worry about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah You know, I'm not.
Rym: I mean, I'm not a Gnostic.
Scott: I'm just saying that's why I'm not a hundred percent with that.
Scott: But I can't.
Rym: I am a philosophical solipsist and basically nothing.
Scott: It's mostly that I care about the physical world that I'm.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I'm.
Scott: I can know that the the physical real world that we are living in and podcasting in Is true a lot more than I can know that some made-up idea of a god is true.
Scott: So I'm gonna go with that and atheism really fits with that and the other things don't see.
Rym: but I'm also a very Speculative theologist like I always wonder they like.
Rym: I'll just sit around and think like what if this was true?
Rym: What if this thing was happening out there?
Rym: What if there were gods but they were like this?
Rym: or what if?
Rym: what if I'm God?
Rym: Or what if Scott Scott or what?
Rym: What's going on?
Scott: I am God.
Scott: I didn't let you know.
Rym: Oh shit, see the sad truth is that I'm God.
Rym: I made you think you're God so you wouldn't bother me shits.
Scott: Or I thought I made you think you were God you could think well, you know what I put the poison in both cups.
Rym: Oh crap yeah, but I think about those things a lot and I don't I mean I said this a lot in this episode but I got To say it again because people always seem when we have these arguments in the forums to Selectively read what we post like.
Rym: I'll say something like religion is like.
Rym: it's not true and someone will be like blah blah blah Blah blah blah blah.
Rym: There's a chance.
Rym: There's a chance philosophy philosophy.
Rym: And I have to say something like I didn't say no philosophy.
Rym: No philosophy.
Rym: There's no chance of a god.
Rym: I said what you just said is not true and here's evidence for that.
Scott: Yeah, people really gotta pay attention to specific wordings of things when it comes to philosophical debates.
Rym: Yeah, believing something might exist is far different from being convinced something specific exists.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if someone says to me, you know, yeah, there might be God I'll go like yeah There's a you know I'll give my argument about the chance of there being one so infinitesimally small that it's stupid to bet on it.
Scott: But it isn't false that there could be.
Scott: there could be some God some all-powerful force Who's making everything the way it is right now and is invisible to us?
Rym: Yeah I'm much more like and I think is much more feasible the idea that there are probably beings that are I don't want to say higher or lower because that's all relative but more powerful than us.
Rym: But we're not interacting with them in any way we know.
Rym: so even if we are interacting with beings like that somehow We don't know it.
Scott: We can't know it.
Rym: We can't show it therefore effectively whether or not they exist or not.
Rym: It doesn't matter Yeah, but the I still like to think about whether or not they exist.
Scott: Yeah, my point is is that if someone comes up to me and says, you know There is this there is a guy named Jesus and he did this and this and this.
Scott: that is such a specific thing.
Scott: It's not just like yeah, there might be something it's.
Scott: this specific thing is true with no evidence for it whatsoever.
Scott: It's like no you're an idiot.
Scott: Shut up You know, it's like goddamn what what how could you uh?
Scott: That's what I'm against is when someone has a you know, this is the way it is.
Scott: I got no way to prove it, but that's the way it is And if you say otherwise, you're wrong and you go to hell.
Rym: Well, we could talk about this forever.
Rym: And I know this was kind of fragmented partly because we're actually really fucking tired.
Scott: I'm so goddamn tired one.
Rym: This topic was a cop-out because we couldn't think of anything else tonight - we're really.
Scott: it's also fan service.
Rym: Yeah, it's fan service because if you've been in our forums you see that we we have discussions like.
Scott: it's a popular topic of debate But it's not.
Rym: there's not a lot of debate.
Rym: There's mostly a lot of philosophical pondering and then a lot of jokes.
Scott: That's the best way.
Scott: That's the way it should be.
Rym: but a Final closing bits here not about this topic, but about GeekNights in general.
Rym: We see a lot of you out there who are new.
Rym: So one welcome to GeekNights.
Scott: Hello We are you doing.
Rym: if you meet you if you've just started listening.
Scott: I think you'll come again.
Rym: you go to our website Www.front row crew.
Rym: calm and join the forums because the forums are rocking.
Scott: also Put a little thing on the frapper map.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The frapper map shows where our listeners are.
Rym: We have a lot an audio.
Rym: We have a lot of overseas listeners.
Rym: So if you aren't in the United States, we know and we think that's awesome.
Rym: Don't be afraid to join the forums.
Rym: They're not in any way us centric.
Scott: Yeah, and send us an audio with a little link there.
Scott: What else can you do?
Scott: you can send us an email.
Scott: GeekNights at front row calm.
Rym: We respond to many of the emails we get and at least remember if you send us an email Even if we don't respond we read it.
Rym: I guarantee that we both not only read it, but we remembered it and we there's a good chance We'll address it someday in a geek bag.
Scott: Yeah, and also go to the website for a crew calm.
Scott: You know, maybe you're listening to this on like some other site like Yahoo podcast or something.
Scott: So go to front row crew calm Go there, yes, we have show notes.
Rym: We have links to every news item and thing of the day we talked about in addition to the forums and all the fun stuff Links to like my delicious.
Rym: in case you want to see what we're gonna talk about ahead of time.
Scott: I think the last thing I got to say is that next week our favorite sport ice hockey begins the 2006-2007 NHL.
Scott: I think it starts on like Tuesday or Wednesday the first NHL games.
Rym: now We often do themed weeks.
Rym: But we're not going to do a hockey themed week because we know a lot of you don't care about hockey.
Scott: Yeah, and there's not much to say about hockey.
Scott: me What are we gonna?
Scott: we're gonna turn this into like the sports show where we give the results of the games.
Scott: I mean you could listen to ESPN for that.
Scott: Yeah, plus I mean and they're better than we are You're not big hockey role.
Rym: Not we're not big sports fans.
Rym: We're a much bigger video game fans.
Scott: Yeah, we're not gonna all of a sudden Thursday and a sports day or anything.
Rym: But what we are going to do?
Rym: because things of the day along these lines have been popular in the past and several people have Suggested this we are going to do hockey fight week or things of the because everyone knows the best part of hockey is the fighting.
Scott: So all next week all next week all eight things of the day are going to be hockey fights nothing But hockey fights nothing but hockey fights.
Scott: In fact, I one of them is in fact They're going to be the top eight hockey fights that we can find on YouTube and Google video.
Rym: Yes, except one of them that I'm going to talk about.
Rym: There's no video of it that I know but I can describe it.
Rym: Let me just say more people than just the players were fighting by the end of it.
Rym: Haha Okay, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.