Rym:
Rym: It's Thursday September 28th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight on our new periodic segment throwaway Thursdays We talked about how to survive the zombie apocalypse with part 1 out of a thousand how to gather zombie intelligence.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So on the way home from work today.
Scott: I listened to one and a half Extremely profound podcast.
Scott: Oh really yeah, really the first one I listened to was boing boings get illuminated.
Scott: now you might know boing boing the blog We've linked to it for things of the day and stuff.
Rym: It's a directory of wonderful things.
Scott: It's a very important blog that pretty much everyone in the world should pay attention to.
Rym: yeah I don't read it But the best way I found to follow boing boing is to wait for someone like Scott to link you to it Periodically.
Scott: now for everything on boing boing is gold.
Scott: But they just recently started podcasting.
Scott: one of their podcasts is called boing boing boing Which is just all the boing boing bloggers talking about the stories on boing boing.
Scott: That's an okay podcast.
Scott: But they have another one called get illuminated which they only put out one episode of so far where they interview like Amazing amazing people who can illuminate.
Rym: well who did they interview?
Scott: they interviewed my man Doug Rushkoff Who is basically a genius?
Scott: It's really hard to describe what this guy does but he writes books.
Scott: he writes comic books He teaches at NYU.
Rym: Scott is filled with man.
Rym: Love over Douglas Rushkoff.
Scott: Hey, not really.
Rym: no You don't know.
Rym: it is.
Rym: it is entirely heterosexual and based solely in logic and reason.
Scott: It's sort of like the way, you know It's like.
Scott: yeah I wish I was not as that you have.
Rym: you have an intellectual hard-on for Douglas Rushkoff The same way that I have a creative hard-on for Neil Gaiman, I guess.
Scott: yeah something like that He also.
Scott: he did to nightline not night.
Scott: Is it nightline?
Scott: the PBS documentary things?
Scott: Uh-huh Yeah, he one of them was the persuaders and one of them was the merchants of cool.
Scott: He's basically an expert on new media Studies culture Everything awesome.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: That's quite a description Scott that just shows you how much smarter he is than I am.
Scott: So I urge you that if you have 35 minutes in your life download boing boings get illuminated episode 1 and listen to it and you should be thoroughly enlightened by you know, the musings of a Man from New York
Rym: or you'll be like the flatlander in flatland trying to deal with that sphere.
Scott: Yes, the other podcast I listen to is floss weekly.
Scott: now floss weekly is free Libre open-source software weekly and it's not really that weekly.
Scott: It's actually skipped a lot of weeks, but they interview very important people in the open-source software community You know like the guy who invented Python and the slashdot guys and people from Google and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: But in the most recent one, which I only listen to half of it's an hour long episode 13 they interview Eben Moglen, who is basically the open-source lawyer The guy like he works with the EFF to write GPL 3 definite article lawyer.
Scott: yes, this guy worked with Like Thurgood Marshall and stuff these.
Scott: serious lawyer like professor at law school.
Scott: You know professor of law history crazy, his resume is just insane.
Scott: and The where he works is this law firm and the purpose of this firm.
Scott: It's supported by all the big, you know players IBM Google HP everyone and What he does is if you're an open-source software person Their firm will provide you with advice and help to make sure you don't get into trouble.
Scott: License wise and copyright wise and patent wise and all that jazz Granted for most people.
Scott: I mean if you just take the GPL and use it, you're fine Yes, but if you listen to this I mean you take our episode on Monday where he talked about open-source licenses, you know Forget the episode we made about open-source licenses.
Scott: Just listen to floss weekly episode 13 And that's at twit.tv/floss.
Rym: Well while we're at it on my way home, I listen to Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentleman again.
Scott: Okay, which which episode do you listen to this time?
Rym: I'm not gonna get into specific episodes here But Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentleman is indeed fast karate for a gentleman.
Scott: We are very into the gentlemanly things, you know a lot like Wondermark.com.
Rym: very gentlemanly I gotta say the thing.
Rym: I've realized what it is about fast karate for the gentleman.
Rym: It's really I listen to it a lot lately one I kind of got burnt out on Penn Jillette.
Rym: So I've been kind of holding off.
Scott: I've also been slightly burnt out on Penn Jillette.
Rym: I really only listen to Penn now when he's got an interview or a topic.
Rym: I really care about.
Rym: yeah, the Phyllis Diller thing was good, but Dave and Joel have this.
Rym: the humor they use and the way they talk is very infectious and if you listen like if I listen to them and then I try to do the show and I'll end up talking like them.
Rym: Mmm, I think that's why Daryl kept stealing their bits.
Scott: It might be it's you know.
Scott: We talked about this before I think on the show about how if you hang around someone who has some sort of shtick the shtick Rubs off on you like oh, man.
Scott: So, yeah Dave and Joel they're all about shtick.
Rym: but we got some news Since that was basically the equivalent of us playing a promos.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Scott: We do have news.
Scott: All right, so now that it matters Pokemon Diamond and Pearl were released today in Japan the new Pokemon games for the DS.
Scott: now These aren't like, you know, they're new Pokemon games all the time and like Pokemon racing or whatever the hell they make.
Scott: I don't know Pokemon mystery dungeon.
Scott: This is a real Pokemon game and Basically what happened was they put out 1 million copies of diamond and 1 million copies of pearl and they're all gone.
Scott: They also put out a special edition Pokemon pearl, you know diamond pearl DS light and they sold half a million of those today.
Scott: and They they did.
Scott: they put out a million of those.
Scott: so there are half a million You know Pokemon DS lights out there to still buy but now think about that more.
Rym: I mean half a million Half of a million.
Rym: how many?
Rym: not to rip on Sony.
Rym: but how many PlayStation threes are there gonna be?
Scott: Total yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, but you know, the thing is I gotta tell everyone, you know, a lot of people go Oh Pokemon, whatever.
Scott: They don't care one.
Rym: Pokemon games whether you like it or not ushered in a new era of gaming.
Rym: Well, I guess internal that in terms of gaming itself, but in terms of culture around gaming Specifically the portable gaming the culture, you know The culture of Pokemon kids has a lot to do with why certain kinds of games get made today.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: Another thing is, you know Pokemon the TV show the anime crap, whatever Magga, awesome.
Scott: Well the original Pokemon adventures manga is actually really awesome with red and yellow.
Scott: Yes, the one and the original Pokemon games, you know the main line of Pokemon games.
Scott: You know Pokemon red blue gold silver.
Scott: Yeah, the main line habit the RPG Pokemon games of which diamond and pearl are the latest.
Scott: right those are actually good Games and they're based, you know, they were originally based on that Pokemon adventures manga, which is also good.
Rym: I think that you missed my joke about mainline because it's like a drug all addictive.
Scott: I don't know what you're talking about.
Scott: I don't get it.
Rym: Pokemon is like mainlining.
Rym: It's the main line I don't know.
Rym: main lining is a is slang for doing intravenous drugs.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Scott: Wow So I chose you.
Scott: how much of a druggie I am?
Scott: good game I didn't know.
Scott: a main lining is but now I know the more you know.
Scott: Yeah, I learned.
Scott: I learned basically everything about Pokemon over.
Scott: I read the Wikipedia and I realized I played Pokemon red and I played Pokemon silver.
Scott: and since then the only Pokemon games to come out were like these Gem, whatever ones.
Scott: I don't forget what they're called But if I play that and then I get either diamond or pearl I'm all caught up.
Scott: There's only.
Scott: I only really need to play two Pokemon games to catch up.
Rym: now.
Rym: I meanwhile have never played a Pokemon game ever not even in passing.
Scott: I'll lend you my a copy of Pokemon red.
Scott: You could play in your GBA.
Rym: Yeah, I don't want to bust the GBA out with its lack of a backlight SP.
Scott: That's downstairs.
Rym: Oh, you mean Pete's SP that he keeps leaving at our house.
Rym: That is effectively ours.
Scott: Yep, that one.
Rym: Okay Yeah, I'll put it right with Scott Johnson's DVD player you mean our DVD player.
Rym: that's right Yep, but no, I just I never played any Pokemon games.
Rym: I didn't even realize there were Pokemon games back then.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically I mean, it's an RPG with leveling So it's kind of a but really the leveling doesn't matter at all.
Scott: if you you know, if you use attacks at the right element, you know, it's all fun and games and You know, it's mostly exploring this map and talking to people and you know figuring out You know, how do I get through certain areas?
Scott: and you know?
Scott: What trick do I have to do to get this Pokemon to come out of a tiding hole and all that kind of stuff?
Rym: Don't forget trying to get the ultra rare uber whatever Pokemon.
Scott: No, that's not really necessary.
Scott: I mean I used to put the first time I played Pokemon I did catch them all and then in the second Pokemon the silver one There were 250 Pokemon instead of 150 and I caught you know, I brought my original 150 over But there was still you know, a hundred more to get.
Scott: I didn't care about it that I just caught whatever I felt like and I used the Pokemon I cared about.
Scott: screw all those other Pokemon And I think that's really the way.
Scott: if you want to have fun playing Pokemon if you try to catch them all.
Scott: It's not really that fun cuz.
Scott: now and Pokemon diamond.
Scott: They're like 500 some odd Pokemon.
Rym: You can't catch 500 Pokemon.
Scott: No, you can't catch 500 Pokemon.
Scott: Snorlax.
Rym: Porlax.
Scott: Yeah, so So, you know really all you do is you figure out which Pokemon you like, you know You like the way they look you like the way they fight and you use those Treat them like your babies.
Rym: and then I only really know the original Pokemon.
Rym: and I only really like Squirtle.
Scott: I like Dragonite.
Rym: Squirtle and Bulbasaur are my men.
Scott: Dragonite.
Scott: I like Dragonite and I like.
Scott: What's the other one I like?
Scott: oh the one that Adish.
Scott: I like Adish, uh-huh.
Rym: I kind of like Togepi.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Scott: and What's the other one?
Scott: I forget which ones I like.
Scott: I like.
Scott: I like a few Pokemon.
Rym: It's all about Squirtle and Bulbasaur.
Scott: Oh the guy with the swirly mouth Whatever his name is though a little known fact.
Rym: the voice actress who did the voices of many Pokemon including if I recall correctly Bulbasaur was none other in Japan than Mikumi Hayashibara One of the most highly paid voice actresses ever.
Scott: It seems like they give her a lot of parts doing like these little tiny noises for like one second in shows.
Rym: I don't know if just because she liked doing it or if it was just a gimmick or whatever, but it's funny It is it's it's great.
Scott: I'd like if I interviewed her.
Scott: That's what I would ask her.
Scott: It's the only question I really need to ask her is you know Why do you do these parts and shows doing like little animal voices, you know?
Scott: Maybe she's just very good at it and everyone else sucks in Japan.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: She is really good at it.
Rym: I guess though she is, you know, one of the most sought-after voice.
Rym: that was I don't think she's been in any anime recently.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think anyone.
Scott: I think she's sort of like, you know washed up and retired.
Rym: Yeah Well, she was super big when we first got into anime and then it kind of shifted and then Ayumi was really big.
Rym: Well, I mean he's always been big.
Scott: Well, Mikumi wasn't exactly the same.
Scott: She was a voice actor.
Scott: Well, you me is a pop star.
Scott: Well, I'll be is like my god.
Rym: Mikumi was a pop star Not like Madonna level but gumi was one of the big pop stars.
Rym: Anyway, yeah.
Rym: All right Now this was actually Scott's news and I stole it and pushed another news off because he really wanted to talk about it.
Rym: We didn't want to wait till Monday, and I don't know if you'll care or not.
Rym: But the patents the final patents on the gift image, you know, gi.
Scott: Oh Jeff No, technically
Rym: no because according to several studies about 70% of people in the world say gift Correct and the vast majority of human beings in America say gift
Scott: Yes, but somehow on the official website the guy who made gift says it must be pronounced Jeff
Rym: Yeah, now everyone
Scott: denies him now.
Rym: One of the reasons is that Jeff sounds kind of dumb.
Scott: Yep, it's a name of a peanut butter brand.
Rym: Also the fact that it's an acronym for Graphics interchange format like that.
Rym: Uh, gah, it's a plosive G.
Scott: It's not a graphics.
Rym: It's graphics Yeah, it's not giraffes.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: And of course last but not least the people responsible for gift are in many ways a lot like the GNU free people.
Rym: And in fact, I found a distinct correlation between people who say Jeff and people who are all GNU Yeah, so I guess we should start saying Jannu
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: but anyway I'm sure many of you are actually too young to remember this story or just didn't care enough about the internet.
Rym: Gifts were a big deal in the early days of the internet.
Scott: They were a huge deal.
Rym: now It was done by CompuServe but this company called Unisys did a thing that was covered by a patent that had that gift also used.
Rym: and then IBM and a bunch of other people also had patents and they all covered this thing that Pretty much everyone was using for free before all these companies started suing everybody.
Scott: Yeah, there was an image file format named gift and everyone was using it.
Scott: But a lot of the technology in that file format was patented by various other companies.
Rym: now Unisys was generally rat-bastardly about it.
Rym: But then you know They played nice a little while and then they started being really really really mean right before the year 2000.
Rym: And to make a long story short all the patents But one have expired and now at the beginning of October coming up real soon October 1st The last patent covering gift will expire.
Rym: at that point gift and everything involved in gift are 100% free public domain to the world forever.
Rym: Hooray This is.
Rym: it's such a rare thing that something like this happens in our day and age where something is actually for.
Scott: patents Don't last a thousand years.
Scott: They last a reasonable amount of time.
Rym: The thing is the patent for gift lasted almost be it through and beyond the useful life of gift Yeah, isn't useful anymore except for animated gifs on 4chan.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much You know, I mean it does still have its uses to make you know, very Light websites that you know can have a lot of bandwidth traffic because they are smaller than pings and JPEGs and anything else You're gonna use.
Scott: but at the same time you really if you use a ping it's not gonna hurt you that badly.
Scott: I mean, come on What are you worried about?
Rym: Well alpha which doesn't work so well.
Scott: a lot of things Yeah, but that's gonna be fixed soon.
Scott: not that gif has alpha in it, yeah Yeah, that's that's the realm of JPEG and paying and whatnot, but Yeah, gift is free if does have alpha these transparent gifts.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but it's not the same kind of thing that you can do in Ping.
Scott: Yeah, it's only because you shrink the palette and gift but it's pretty old.
Scott: It is pretty old.
Rym: I mean the only real news here is that Gif is free.
Rym: It is absolutely free.
Scott: if you'd ever wondered what came of all that stuff because a lot of new people I think a lot of you didn't even know there was trouble concerning gift Like they just thought a gift was a different kind of file format.
Rym: Yeah I mean I guess it was because of.
Rym: we grew up in a very specific and important era of the Internet Where all these things happened and they were big deals.
Rym: I mean there were gift versus JPEG wars while we were making websites on geocities back in the day Yeah, and nowadays no one even knows it cares.
Rym: people use whatever.
Scott: yeah, so but those days are finally over.
Rym: Yeah, there's no more trouble with using gift.
Scott: Yeah, and you will now see there There's a lot of software out there.
Scott: a lot of people like wouldn't use gift, you know For one reason or another for the patent thing, but now everyone's gonna use it without any qualms and it should make life a little Bit easier.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: In fact, there are a whole bunch of open source programs.
Rym: I think go script is one of them where they were actually waiting and starting October 1st They're going to release versions that support gift.
Rym: Yeah They waited this long.
Rym: Yeah Wow Wow things of the day.
Rym: Which day today today today not do I don't know where you're going with this?
Rym: But I don't see a funny joke coming anywhere three day.
Rym: There is no joke on the horizon here at all for day.
Rym: You're just gonna keep going with this.
Rym: I'll just turn off your microphone one day.
Scott: All right My thing of the day you may not know this.
Scott: In fact, I didn't really know this but there were airships.
Scott: Yeah, there were lots of them.
Scott: Yeah, like I knew that we had zeppelins But I didn't know we had airships like real airships dirigibles if you will.
Rym: Oh, do you ever see Indiana Jones the Last Crusade?
Scott: Yeah, that was like a blimp, but they didn't.
Scott: It didn't what didn't have airplanes on it.
Rym: It had one airplane on it one.
Scott: It didn't have a whole bunch of them on it.
Rym: Anyway, so I believe you're thinking today's the USS Macon.
Scott: Yes, see in 1935.
Scott: There was this USS Macon.
Scott: It was an airship 785 foot airship.
Rym: now think about that for a minute.
Rym: that is almost last exile in proportion.
Scott: Yeah, there's a picture of it.
Scott: you can go look at it and It had a hangar bay with four sparrowhawk biplanes.
Scott: You know, this is a big airship with planes in it and it fell into the sea.
Rym: See, I've always been a huge fan of airships and air pirates, but more importantly in the modern world I'm a huge fan of a lot of people who've been trying to bring back airships for intercontinental shipping.
Scott: Yeah, they're.
Scott: I mean you could pick up a warehouse with one of these things and fly it over the ocean real cheaply.
Rym: Yeah, I mean imagine instead of sending, you know load stuff onto a boat send the boat over load the stuff out of trucks Send it over to the warehouse.
Rym: You could just pick up the warehouse full of stuff from the factory.
Rym: Take it to wherever your distribution center was put it down pick up another warehouse and take it back.
Rym: Yep Unfortunately, pretty cool.
Rym: The primary argument I've seen against using airships in the modern world is nothing other than What if terrorists shoot it down?
Rym: OMG?
Scott: Uh They're not easy to shoot down.
Rym: Yeah, they are.
Scott: shoot it with.
Scott: you couldn't shoot it with like a guy.
Scott: you shoot it with like a rocket or something.
Rym: They're.
Rym: they're big and slow.
Rym: It wouldn't be hard to shoot one down.
Scott: Yeah, you just you couldn't.
Scott: you know, if you shot it with a gun it would go ding.
Scott: You'd have to shoot it with something better than that, you know, like certain sniper rifles.
Rym: I think a Barrett could take one out maybe but what's it gonna do?
Scott: good?
Rym: Um It'll do a little more than that.
Rym: It won't catch on fire like the Hindenburg.
Scott: No No, well that was because that one was poorly made.
Rym: but well Yeah to dispel a common myth the Hindenburg did not burn because of what was in it.
Rym: the Hindenburg burn because people didn't understand Chemistry so well and they painted the outside of the Hindenburg with what was effectively rocket fuel.
Scott: Yeah, basically that that's what happened.
Scott: You know, the hydrogen would just gone poof.
Scott: It wouldn't have started burning like that.
Scott: Yep Anyway, this particular airship fell into the sea and was lost.
Scott: Recently, they found it.
Scott: some fisherman a commercial fisherman caught a piece of it in his net.
Scott: it was some girder and he he showed it off at the local seafood restaurant and Thus be went huh?
Scott: Where did you get that from?
Scott: and up lo and behold there's the airship and all sorts of other goodies under the sea that are fun to look at, you know, and it's especially fun to look at cuz It's a fucking airship.
Scott: So check out this thing of the day.
Scott: Look at the pictures of the sunken airship.
Scott: sunken airship.
Scott: Isn't that kind of funny?
Scott: Well, you know it is a ship in the air But it's sunk in the water as opposed to like, you know floating out into space.
Rym: Well first it sunk to the ground and then it kept sinking.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, what can I say?
Rym: I like airships.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty damn cool.
Scott: Let me say that.
Rym: so my thing of the day.
Rym: I realized recently when I was talking about him that many of my friends have not actually seen his stand-up or didn't know that he Was anything other than mr.
Rym: Bean.
Scott: I got mr.
Scott: Bean stories used to calling mr.
Scott: Bean.
Scott: in high school At least a few people did you kind of look like mr.
Scott: Bean a little bit.
Scott: You looked like.
Rym: yes, you looked a lot more like him when we were freshmen.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, you did.
Scott: All right Well, that was real close to high school.
Rym: I mean not so much in your physical appearance But in your mannerisms and the way you walked around and moved your head around and looked at things And shifted your eyes.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: You had a mr.
Rym: Beanish manner.
Rym: Alrighty, then there's a trait in burning wheel.
Rym: But anyway, Rowan Atkinson the man who did mr.
Rym: Bean while mr Bean is often hilarious.
Rym: I would say that it is probably near the bottom of the funny things he has done.
Rym: I mean the least funny thing Rowan Atkinson ever did was the mr.
Rym: Bean movie, which is probably the second worst movie ever made.
Scott: I don't know a movie this mr.
Scott: Bean movie.
Rym: It was called mr.
Rym: Bean.
Scott: Okay, maybe y'all should see it sometime.
Rym: I would watch MD guys like eight or nine times before I'd watch that fucking mr Bean book is.
Scott: how could you not with you know?
Scott: A guy shooting a guy through the head and then using the same gun as a grappling hook in there?
Rym: I would even watch Clifford almost once before I'd watch mr.
Rym: Bean.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Good God, but anyway He's most well known for mr.
Rym: Bean, but he was also the black adder.
Rym: He was in the black adder which is an absolutely hilarious show and He was himself Rowan Atkinson doing stand-up stand-up skip comedy.
Rym: I've found on YouTube and Google video a collection of many of the routine Stand-up bits that he would do and if you have never seen such things as fatal beating or welcome to hell You've really missed out on one of the funniest comedians I can remember.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I mean the funniest in a comedian ever I had to say is Richard Pryor.
Scott: But this stuff is also the hilarious.
Rym: I pretty much Richard Pryor.
Rym: I put way up there.
Scott: The thing is the only reason I put Richard Pryor at the top is because I've watched a lot of stand-up comedy in my day Right, but one day randomly a freshman year at RIT.
Scott: I remember it specifically like I knew who Richard Pryor was whatever But I was flipping through the channels.
Scott: cuz actually that was the last time I had television.
Rym: breathe no more.
Scott: And I came upon Richard Pryor doing stand-up comedy on the TV Randomly and I was just uncontrollably Laughing it like from the time I switched to the to his channel to the time Beyond the time when it was over.
Scott: I just couldn't stop laughing harder and longer than anyone else.
Scott: See I gotta say though I think laughter is a good measure of the comedy.
Rym: Dana Carvey had a similar effect on me the first time I saw his HBO special.
Rym: Maybe maybe of course by the 80th time.
Rym: I wasn't laughing so much anymore.
Rym: Yeah chopping broccoli Make a time make a to make a team make it to and in fact you Yeah, I mean like George Carlin Lewis black I love them all.
Scott: yeah, yeah I'm a big fan of comedy in general stand-up comedy.
Scott: But yeah, awesome.
Rym: I still wish I Try to describe this comedians humor because then maybe one of you remember what his name was, but I can't really describe it.
Rym: I'll just let it lie But I'll let it be known that there was this comedian that I saw on Comedy Central three times three different shows.
Rym: Guy was utterly freaking hilarious and to this day.
Rym: I have no idea who that was and I've never seen him again.
Scott: Was he the guy that died Hedberg?
Rym: No, it wasn't.
Rym: Hedberg wasn't Mitch Hedberg?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: No, is that would explain why you never saw him again?
Rym: No, no, no, it was this.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into it because I barely remember anything about the guy and most of his jokes were more visual than they were.
Scott: Alright, well, let's get into our main bit then.
Rym: Oh the main bit that we've been avoiding because it's kind of a throwaway episode.
Scott: Yeah the throw episode.
Scott: now Some of our listeners particularly one unnamed listener has named Has been pushing very hard for us to do an episode about what we're going to do an episode about right now.
Rym: fact at Otakon during the GeekNights meet-and-greet where we were hanging out with a bunch of our fans and have a grand old time He asked us while we had a recorder out Exactly the question that we're going to begin answering in part 1 of how to deal with the zombie apocalypse.
Scott: Well, I don't like the word apocalypse because then you're assuming that it's a zombie apocalypse.
Scott: It's basically how to deal with any number of zombie happenings.
Rym: Yes I mean zombie apocalypse is one tip type of scenario.
Rym: The problem is zombie apocalypse.
Rym: in the end You're pretty much always fucked.
Scott: Yeah, because you're assuming there's an apocalypse.
Scott: So it is the end of the world and you're done.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much the dawn of the dead and you can try to survive longer perhaps But the end result is the same if it is absolutely a zombie apocalypse.
Rym: Luckily, you can't know during it if it is a zombie apocalypse or not or just a zombie outbreak.
Rym: 88 days later showed us.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Yes So yes the first thing you need to do when deciding how you're going to survive a zombie attack of some sort is Get information about the zombie attack.
Rym: Yeah now I get well.
Rym: before we go any further I just want to say that this is not going to be a multi-part in the sense that we're going to do a series on Zombies.
Rym: Oh, no, no, no, but every time we need to throw away Thursday.
Rym: I think it'll be instead of monkey Tuesday It'll be throwaway Thursday.
Scott: It's one of those geeky things that you know.
Scott: geeky people talk about and discuss for fun when they're bored and you know That's what we're gonna do when we got nothing better to talk about.
Scott: We'll just start talking about some hobbies.
Rym: So today we're going to go over how to figure out what kind of zombie attack it is and How we would determine what we're going to do.
Rym: But we can't talk about specifics because it really depends on the exact nature of the zombies that exists.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I mean what if there's a zombie outbreak in California and I'm in New York?
Scott: Well, that gives me a lot of time, doesn't it?
Rym: Now what if they're slow-moving zombies that don't turn you into a zombie unless you die?
Rym: What if they're fast-moving zombies that turn you into a zombie if they so much as scratch you?
Scott: yeah What if Rym is the first zombie?
Rym: Yeah, what are they lurching zombies?
Rym: Are they strong zombies?
Rym: Are they magic zombies?
Rym: Are they science zombies?
Rym: Are they disease zombies?
Scott: Everything hinges on these questions and their answers.
Scott: I mean It's changing the answer just slightly changes the whole strategy of how not to get killed and turn into a zombie.
Rym: Thus today we're mostly just going to talk about how to assess the zombie apocalypse.
Scott: Well, I think first what we should do is you should take things that are assumed to be true in any zombie situation that is zombies are Former humans of some sort.
Scott: they were human and now they are something else.
Rym: yes, they may or may not have been dead.
Rym: they may or may not be dead and They seek to turn other humans into zombies by some means or in the very I mean They might not be able to turn you into a zombie at all.
Rym: It might just be dead people.
Rym: It might just be I think the most common definition.
Scott: But there is a danger of lit non zombie humans becoming zombies.
Rym: Yes Though I there are some situations I could see where that wouldn't be the case.
Rym: I mean say a meteor went by and woke up all the dead people, but then the meteor crashed and that stopped happening.
Scott: Oh, so only the graveyards had zombies and then there was a limited Finite number of zombies and all the living people were never zombies and they're just living people.
Rym: So that is a possibility.
Rym: However remote.
Scott: Yeah, that would count.
Rym: Yeah, now I guess I mean the way you could really distinguish the zombie attack here is that regardless of how they came about?
Rym: zombies either are generally aggressive toward humans and or other living things or zombies specifically are attempting to either kill people and turn them into zombies or They just have a hunger for brains that can't be satisfied any other way except the vegetarian zombies.
Rym: Don't go make that fucking joke.
Scott: Great.
Rym: I hate you so much.
Scott: It's Thursday, leave me alone.
Rym: Yeah throwaway Thursdays Alright.
Rym: So so generally what we'll assume in any zombie case is that they are humanoid beings that were once human that have become Generally malevolent beings that have little intelligence and are attempting to harm and the very least humans Mm-hmm.
Scott: Another thing you had to realize though I just I was thinking about the case you just brought up where all the dead people come back to life as zombies and that's it.
Scott: There are more people alive now than have ever died.
Scott: Win that by.
Rym: you can't make a statement like that because we don't really know.
Scott: Yeah, we do.
Rym: No, we don't.
Rym: that is that is a contention.
Rym: That is up to a great deal of debate.
Rym: And also what do you consider a human?
Rym: What's the exact line?
Rym: just our species?
Rym: What about hominids?
Scott: Yeah, there are zombie elephants.
Scott: We're definitely in trouble.
Rym: So I'll be monkeys.
Rym: a Normal monkey could kill both of us if this room there were a monkey here in that blue chair and that monkey wanted to kill Us unless it was a spider monkey.
Rym: We'd both be dead Yeah, and if it was a spider monkey one of us would still be dead or at least covered in shit.
Scott: Vomit and god knows what other kind of mess.
Rym: god spider monkeys.
Scott: Yeah so How should we begin?
Rym: She'll propose a scenario and then or just generally how to react.
Rym: we could talk about that.
Rym: All right All right, so let's say we don't know.
Rym: let's say we're sitting here doing GeekNights right now And our friend Scott Johnson calls the cell phone that's sitting next to me the ringers off and I ignore it.
Rym: He calls it five or six more times.
Rym: So I think huh and I pick the phone up.
Rym: and Scott Johnson being the stalwart defender against all things malevolent Because you know your friend Scott Johnson is waiting for this day.
Rym: He is the first line of defense.
Rym: He is nor ad when it comes to zombies and vampires.
Rym: Basically, if any of those come to exist Scott Johnson will call the both of us first and tell us it begins and then we'll Do whatever.
Rym: do it.
Scott: I pick up the phone.
Scott: The first thing you have to do is get someone in the world to be your nor ad.
Rym: yes We have Scott Johnson.
Rym: You could have us but now you're one degree away.
Rym: You won't get worn right away.
Rym: I am going to do things before I warn you about this.
Scott: I can also be a nor ad.
Scott: the problem with that is you need to spend every waking moment of your life in a Constant vigil for zombie happenings.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: No, you could narrow it down.
Rym: I mean Scott Johnson is a Evil magic or evil zombie.
Rym: nor ad.
Rym: he's really broad.
Rym: He's watching for vampires.
Rym: He's watching for magic.
Rym: He's watching for all of that.
Rym: If you're just a zombie nor ad it's real easy.
Rym: Just watch the news.
Rym: Just watch all the news and the moment you hear about a disease anywhere that isn't explained go to like Def Con 2 and wait.
Rym: Yeah That's really it.
Rym: All you can do is watch the news.
Scott: Hmm unless the zombies are happening in your town Yeah, but even then you're you all.
Rym: you just kind of be generally wary.
Rym: Mmm-hmm.
Scott: Make sure when you see someone walking on the street if they're walking kind of slow if they got their hands out in front of Them go check them out.
Scott: Make sure you know, they're not Zombified.
Scott: Yeah, because seriously it could be that just one zombie and that's it.
Rym: However, Scott Johnson the nor ad the one thing that he is always impressed upon us in his knowledge of being a zombie.
Rym: Nor ad is that if you ever come across a zombie or Vampire or anything like that that immediately makes the odds that other similar things exist go from practically zero To not one but an infinitely larger number.
Rym: Yep I mean if you see one zombie That's when you start grabbing crosses and see if they work on things Start digging up people that you might think are vampires and staking them.
Scott: So when you get like Necronomicon and start reading them, yep.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You start trying to cast spells just in case.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I don't try to cast spells every day only because the odds are they won't work.
Rym: if I run into a vampire You can bet your ass.
Rym: I'm gonna find every old skin bound book I can get and read every word out loud.
Scott: I'll be sacrificing the lambs and shit trying to get some spell action going on.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so again, the first thing you have to do is have intelligence.
Rym: That is probably the most important thing.
Rym: the sooner you figure out What kinds of zombies these are and what kind of threat they pose the better chance you have of surviving until the end and possibly winning Mm-hmm.
Scott: Now you might be able if you're lucky to get all this information from the news and the internet and your friends and such because someone else far away will figure it out and Disseminate the information around the world.
Rym: However, if zombie movies are any indication, that's not gonna fucking happen Anything.
Rym: you'll turn on the news and you'll see a reporter freaking out and then being killed by a zombie and then there won't be any useful radio Television or anything even your hair.
Scott: you're gonna have to rely on your ham radio guys and those guys There are usually fat so they won't be.
Rym: So the step to know at least one radio nerd.
Rym: Every zombie movie worth its salt has the one guy who has the radio and he's the one who makes contact with that one other.
Scott: Or if you're seriously worried about zombies because I got to be honest, I'm not.
Scott: even though I'm prepared I'm not worried about zombies because the chances of zombies are pretty much yes.
Rym: I mean I'm ready for zombies if I hear that zombies exist Instead of freaking out because the normal human reaction is to freak out for like five minutes before you deal with it.
Rym: I'm ready, so I won't freak out.
Scott: I'll immediately a Mac enact rims zombie plan Yes But if you are worried about it I suggest becoming a ham radio hobbyist to getting your license and everything like that because that'll help a lot more than many other things.
Rym: Yep, I mean medicine is not gonna work so well, especially if they're infecting zombies.
Scott: Yeah, you're basically your second skill that you're gonna want.
Scott: after ham radio skill is gun the skill Alright, so here's the important question.
Rym: You can you've got intelligence, you know zombies exist.
Rym: What information do you need before you can figure out what to do?
Rym: You need to know very briefly one what kinds of zombies they are What creates them?
Rym: Where do they come from?
Rym: how can they be killed?
Rym: and Is there any like special thing like a special secret thing?
Rym: you know the plot point at the end of the movie like ah, if you say was it was it they explode or They only last one nights?
Scott: Yeah, the other thing you have to know.
Scott: if they poke what threat to these zombies posed to you They might be benign zombies.
Scott: It could be you know, they just walk around aimlessly and do nothing and then they die.
Rym: Yep, and also where did they spawn?
Rym: Did they all come from one place that they simultaneously appear all around the world?
Rym: That is really key because in the case of the former everything's gonna be okay.
Rym: It's probably gonna be like a really easy cakewalk.
Rym: If you know either a disease or something 88 something you'll get.
Rym: you'll feel safe yourself.
Scott: Yeah, if it was all in one place You know the National Guard or your country's military will surround that place and you'll have no problems.
Rym: plus It's probably a freak accident.
Rym: It's probably either some disease got loose or some portal to a dark world open or some necromance are fucked up Necromancer, but if zombies are appearing all over the world simultaneously You might have a Dawn of the Dead situation.
Scott: You might have a very bad situation because you basically can't run away anywhere.
Scott: You need to hole up and survive for as long as possible Perhaps in some sort of biodome or farm or space shuttle.
Rym: So I guess in or boat in order of what you need to know.
Rym: you start with.
Rym: Where are the zombies right now if they're in LA and you're in New York?
Rym: You have a lot more time to plan if they're down the street.
Rym: You've got to act immediately Mmm, so figure that out before you do anything and then right after that figure out what kind of zombie that is.
Rym: That is.
Rym: that is probably the biggest factor in your survival.
Rym: You can break it into a whole bunch of elements.
Rym: Are they fast zombies or slow zombies?
Scott: Yeah, are they?
Scott: Zombies that can turn you into a zombie or are they zombies that just kind of don't do anything?
Rym: if they're the former Do they do it by biting your neck by killing you by scratching you by being near you?
Scott: Are the zombies strong or are they weak?
Scott: You know do they wander around aimlessly or do they smell your brains and come after them quickly?
Rym: Are they living or dead?
Rym: if they're actually dead then it's either going to be one of those headshot Situations or destroy the head situations.
Rym: or you know some magical solution situation.
Scott: How are the zombies destroyed?
Scott: can they be destroyed?
Rym: because if they're living if they're living beings with a disease You can fight them the way you would fight anyone on PCP.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: You just beat them to death.
Scott: Yeah, can they?
Scott: can they jump?
Scott: can they climb?
Scott: How can you slow them down?
Scott: Will they be able to break through a barrier, you know?
Scott: Can you hold them off instead of killing them all?
Rym: can they detect humans or not?
Rym: And if so, how?
Rym: what draws them?
Rym: are they attracted to light?
Rym: are they attracted to shopping malls?
Scott: Are they attracted to Underground, you know train tracks?
Rym: if they see a human do they become aggressive or they just attack anything in front of them?
Rym: Mmm, do they attack non humans?
Scott: Do they attack non living things?
Rym: Do they attack each other?
Scott: Do they even attack or do they just go around aimlessly?
Rym: Do they just swipe if you're nearby and you also have to worry about a lot of tricky situations.
Rym: I mean fast or slow zombie, right?
Rym: I mean you've seen fast zombies, you know The zombie that runs at full tilt at you and then tears you apart.
Rym: Yeah, and then the slow shuffling Brains.
Rym: but zombie cannot swallow this injustice.
Rym: But there's a really tricky situation you got to watch out for and this has been a furious subject of debate among the front row crew.
Rym: Lunging zombies are one of the most dangerous kinds of zombies because they give all the appearances of a slow zombie.
Rym: They shuffle slowly and slowly Brains, but then when you're within, you know, eight feet They suddenly lunge like as fast as lightning and get you.
Rym: Mmm, but you won't know that right away.
Rym: It's real hard to figure out if it's a lunging zombie or not without letting someone die.
Scott: now the worst thing that can kill you you know is if they're a mixed bag if some zombies are fast and some are slow if some are strong and some are weak if some can get you with A scratch and some with a bite then you basically need to be prepared for all these different situations.
Scott: You know if some get killed with a headshot and some get killed with a silver bullet you're gonna need to get like silver Shotgun shells.
Scott: it's it's really gonna suck and it things just get worse when you have a mixed bag of zombies.
Scott: So you better hope that there's just one kind of zombie.
Scott: You better hope there's no kind but one kind any more than one kind.
Scott: you're in trouble.
Rym: So, let's say for the sake of argument that the zombies are in your town.
Rym: You don't know the situation in the rest of the world, but you know, they're in your town.
Rym: You can see them down the street.
Scott: All right, step one Can you get to the grocery store without going through the zombies?
Rym: Well, I think.
Scott: or the hardware store?
Rym: Yeah well before you do anything don't even worry about that.
Rym: get some binoculars or something and try to observe the zombies because hopefully Some curious neighbors will wander out and see what's going on and you can watch to see if they're lunging zombies or not if they're Fast or slow all that stuff.
Rym: Mmm I mean if they're slow zombies and and they're not lunging or anything, even if they're killing people don't fucking worry about it.
Rym: Yeah, those kind of zombies.
Rym: You could probably just close your door and go back to playing video games.
Scott: Maybe maybe but it also might be fun.
Scott: See, here's the thing, you know, that's the safest thing to do.
Scott: But you might want to go get in your car and run them over for fun Especially if you have a nice big truck.
Rym: But then you got to figure out if they're slow like let's say all right, we observe them We see that they're slow killing zombies.
Rym: They are killing people.
Rym: when they see humans they go after them.
Rym: now We got to figure out if they're massing anywhere or not.
Rym: Are they organized in any way?
Rym: because if it looks like they're massing the answer is always get the fuck out of town.
Rym: Because if they're massing that means you'll go to sleep you'll wake up in the morning.
Rym: Now your house is surrounded by more zombies than you can kill.
Rym: at that point You're dead because you won't get enough food and you'll starve to death.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you could like if there's a mass somewhere but it's not near your house.
Scott: you might be able to pull a trick like a throwing a Exploding propane tank making a big gap in the zombies and then driving through it to escape or something like that.
Scott: But you can't let the mass for too long or else.
Scott: It's too big for even a propane tank explosion.
Rym: Now we don't get a lot of go long on this and there's also the fact that we did this episode mostly as a throwaway.
Rym: But in the future when we do more of these episodes, I think we can illustrate a fairly important point.
Rym: There's actually a moral to all of these zombie episodes.
Scott: We love morality turn turn turn the moral.
Rym: and we talked today, you know about gathering the intelligence And we'll probably talk next time we do this about weapons and that sort of thing.
Scott: the fun part
Rym: Yeah, but in terms of this discussion think of it this way We are geeks we also have no drama in our lives and We very rarely have trouble because we usually plan ahead for just about everything every Possible contingency or at least we put ourselves in a situation where well, we haven't planned for a particular contingency.
Rym: we are ready to deal with it regardless of whether or not we've prepared and The key is simply to approach any problem in your life.
Rym: No matter what that problem is.
Rym: Logically if you wake up one day and you walk outside and there's a dragon just sleeping in the street Don't freak out and run around immediately.
Rym: Just think why is this dragon here?
Rym: What might he want?
Rym: Is he looking at me?
Rym: Is he going to kill me?
Rym: How can I deal with this situation in a productive constructive and possibly life-saving way?
Scott: Another thing you can look at it is a lot of people in this world completely lack Basic problem-solving skills, you know, they might know a lot of stuff and they might not be stupid But you know if their computer is broken or their car is broken They can't apply basic logic and saying oh this is caused by that Which means the problem must be in this area and such and such and such.
Rym: Yeah approach things logically.
Rym: at least try to.
Rym: if you if something bad happens at least try to figure out why it happened.
Rym: if there's a way you can avoid it in the future.
Scott: and Trying to figure out how to survive various zombie scenarios is a great exercise of your Problem-solving muscle and will help you in other areas of life in which you must solve problems.
Rym: You know, you know what?
Rym: I love more than anything and I think we'll end on this, you know being throwaway Thursday.
Rym: Yeah, we managed to turn a throwaway episode about killing fucking zombies into some sort of moral lesson.
Scott: yeah, so we're gonna have real episodes next week.
Scott: and then Next Friday Saturday and Sunday is Sitakan.
Scott: Yes in tomorrow a week from tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, like we always said in the anime club not this weekend But next week October 6 7th and 8th 2006.
Scott: Sitakan in Utica, New York.
Scott: Come see us and many other awesome people.
Rym: We've talked about it all week.
Rym: We've linked to it in the forums.
Rym: We're gonna talk about it more next week is gonna be an awesome con.
Rym: I suggest you go.
Rym: if you live at RIT, I suggest you spread the word.
Rym: That's about it and if the zombies come we'll be there waiting.
Rym: and That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-15 37.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.