Rym: It's Tuesday January 10th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about retro Atari classics weird worlds and civilization, too.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I had the interesting experience of me and my co-worker Upstaging high-level tech support today.
Scott: It's not hard to upstage tech support.
Rym: Well.
Rym: This isn't like normal tech support.
Rym: This is like privileged Calling that.
Rym: like the developers or the highest level of.
Rym: we will debug your problem with our Application and then if need be write a personal fix that we will send to you specifically to patch your program All right, or if you find a real problem.
Rym: We'll you know make a service pack that addresses that okay?
Rym: So I've been on and off the phone and sending emails or as they call them an IBM notes because they use Lotus Notes to this guy for a number of weeks and I'm not getting anywhere with him.
Rym: He just keeps asking for information and I keep eliminating all the things that he's trying to say this are the problem when it's obvious to me that they're not the Problem.
Rym: and finally I get sick of it.
Rym: So me my co-worker do some investigating on our own and we found the problem and solved it great.
Rym: So I called him back, and I was like all right tell you what.
Rym: here's what the problem is blah blah blah, so Wow Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I mean this was like the highest level in like.
Rym: Imagine if you called Microsoft and eventually they pushed you through to Bill Gates, and he was just like I don't know.
Scott: Well, he doesn't know I don't expect them to
Rym: yeah But say they say you had a problem with like a part of Windows and you had like the the platinum gold ultra whatever service plan and you got to the developer who actually wrote the specific code you're having a problem with and he was Just like I don't know Well, and then you solved this problem for him.
Scott: See the thing about Microsoft is that there they have like a different person writing different pieces And you can never figure out who wrote which piece.
Scott: and I remember reading stories on the internet about some guy who had like a Problem with some weird thing and he went running around Microsoft looking for people and it was undocumented.
Scott: Apis, and you know it's just craziness when you get with giant applications.
Rym: But I mean it was because usually when I have a problem like this with like a real software And I really need you know assistance Eventually, I'll get through to someone who knows the answer and fixes it.
Rym: for me It was really kind of a shock to realize that I had hit the end of the line.
Scott: Well, maybe it was just like someone got replaced And that wasn't actually the guy who wrote it it was just a replacement.
Rym: Well to not really.
Rym: I mean this.
Rym: probably wasn't the developer who did that part.
Rym: He's just a support guy for it.
Rym: But suffice to say there are a lot of people are having issues with this software.
Rym: It's not just me and You can usually get more help it seems by asking other people like me who had trouble and just fix it on their own.
Rym: They only get by calling the people who make the stupid thing.
Scott: Open source wins again.
Rym: Yeah, open source wins awesome.
Scott: so Apple has this magic power of dominating the news with basically no effort whatsoever.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's cool.
Rym: I share my office with this cool Korean guy and normally is real quiet And I'm real quiet, and I do my thing and he does this thing.
Rym: But today was the day when Mac stuff was coming out so all day He's.
Rym: he's like he turned to me.
Rym: He'd be like cuz.
Rym: he had a little like text feed look like a little RSS thing.
Rym: they just kept updating whenever like anything was Said at this Mac thing and he turned to me.
Rym: He'd be like Bob of lie and tell Bob a lot.
Rym: I was like yeah, I just saw cuz I was watching something similar at the same time And then later I I went because I wanted to see how much something was gonna cost and I went to the Apple store And I saw that note.
Rym: they're like the Apple store is down.
Rym: that note always comes up whenever Steve jobs is on stage and I was like crap and I turn to look and I see that he has just hit the exact same thing and he turns to me and I'm like Yeah, everyone's like oh the store is down.
Scott: that means new products.
Scott: You know that's how they can because sometimes people would be like is he even gonna announce anything?
Scott: is anything gonna happen?
Scott: They didn't even know if keynotes are gonna happen.
Scott: It was so secret and they'd be like up.
Scott: the store went down.
Scott: something's gonna happen or all the store hasn't gone down.
Scott: Nothing's going on.
Scott: go home.
Rym: Yeah, but there are some pretty big news.
Scott: all right the biggest news today Is the MacBook Pro Apple MacBook Pro.
Scott: well?
Scott: They're not calling it the PowerBook anymore because it's not based on.
Scott: it's not based on PowerPC But it's still basically a PowerBook.
Scott: So it's got an Intel core duo processor instead of a g5 and it's wicked fast Yeah, and a pile of RAM and all the goodies you'd expect.
Scott: basically you can either spend $2,000 to get like a half gig of RAM and 80 gig hard drive And you know a pretty substantial perfect laptop, or you can spend $2,500 and get the god mother God raper laptop.
Rym: I mean honestly I mean I'm kind of in the market to buy a new computer But I really want to spend money.
Rym: if I had a couple grand lying around one of these would have been pre-ordered already And then I will be checking the post office every day to see if it had been shipped.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's pretty badass, and I feel sorry for anyone who just bought a PowerBook.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, the only thing that pissed me off is it only comes in I think a 15-inch widescreen.
Rym: Yeah, you wanted a little 12-inch II.
Scott: if there was a 12-inch one of these for 1500 I'd have it already.
Scott: I would have clicked order.
Scott: do we shut up?
Rym: I mean this thing's got gigabit ethernet built in a backlit keyboard.
Rym: You know all the cool little fancy Apple backlit keyboard.
Rym: It's got an Apple remote.
Scott: Oh yeah, the remotes a big thing.
Rym: It's got a fast radio like a really fast radion DVI out giant ass.
Rym: hard drive DVD burner.
Rym: Wow, yeah burner dual layer DVD burner in a laptop.
Scott: Well laptops have those nowadays.
Scott: You're a little behind the times.
Rym: Yeah, I'm a little behind the times, but it's just awesome, and it's so thin.
Scott: Yep, it's basically Badass PowerBook plus everything and it since it has the x86 processor.
Scott: It's been confirmed.
Scott: You can do crazy Linux and Windows on it.
Scott: Can't beat that.
Scott: Yeah, and dual booting on a laptop is way more convenient than on a desktop because you turn it on and off all the time.
Scott: You know you turn it off put it in the bag take it out turn it on and usually when you turn it on It's a you're carrying it around somewhere, and you're gonna use it for a specific thing when you turn it on.
Scott: So dual booting is really just.
Scott: there's no inconvenience to it whatsoever Yep, and honestly it's fast enough to where.
Rym: if I got a thing like this it could be my primary workstation.
Rym: Yeah, it would just be my only computer, but I wanted to play counter-strike.
Rym: I just plug a USB keyboard and mouse and do it and go nuts.
Scott: yep That'll be it.
Scott: then of course it has the awesome screen of now.
Rym: so there's one complaint that some people had with it.
Rym: It doesn't have a PCMC.
Rym: I a slot.
Scott: I Say, what are you gonna put in that slot?
Rym: Yeah, and to which I had one Kind of useful answer is probably the only answer I could think of.
Rym: if you have a token ring network You need a slot to put a token ring card in.
Scott: I actually thought of something else Is at work.
Scott: we have these Verizon PCMC a cards to get on the evdu net wireless network Cellular networks.
Scott: you know when you're on the train or something you might go on the internet And there's no normal wireless about.
Scott: but you know what?
Scott: That's kind of an old busted way of doing things.
Scott: in the modern way is to use your Bluetooth to connect to your cell phone And it has the Bluetooth.
Scott: so you don't really.
Rym: it has this thing called an express card slot Which I don't know much about but it looks like it's kind of Apple's replacement for PCMC Ia.
Rym: for if you really need to add something yeah, I don't know enough about that.
Rym: Yeah, and I was trying to follow a link right now to talk about it But every link I clicked on is broken, so we'll have to talk about that another day.
Scott: well So there's the new MacBook and now there's a. they did the iMac again.
Rym: They just keep updating this iMac all over the place, and you know what the Intel iMac is just as badass as the Intel laptop.
Scott: Yep, it's basically the Intel laptop only.
Scott: it stands up, and you can't.
Scott: you can carry it around with you But it's the same design as the existing g5 iMac Only.
Scott: it has the core duo processor and the ATI video card and all that.
Scott: oh There's a 17 and 20 inch ones.
Scott: So you get a bigger screen with the iMac and then a bigger hard drive.
Scott: It doesn't cost much more than the previous iteration of a car yeah, and it caused less than the the MacBook $1,300 for the 17 inch and $1,700 for the badass one.
Scott: yeah, so if you don't need to carry your computer around But you want everything that the MacBook has iMac, and you know what honestly it's.
Rym: these things aren't that big.
Rym: You could probably just carry it around just not.
Rym: you can carry it around.
Scott: You just can't like use it on the train.
Scott: you can just bring it from house to house though easily.
Scott: yep All right.
Scott: next thing they've got is oh this is I don't know what to think about this.
Scott: They got this iPod radio remote control, so it's a wire that goes to your iPod nano or new iPod and At the it comes out a little wire.
Scott: at the end of the wire is a little the same control.
Scott: That's on a shuffle.
Scott: So you can kind of control the iPod without actually taking it out of your pocket.
Scott: You can just fiddle on with a little wheel on this wire, but the main thing is that it's an FM receiver.
Scott: It's also an FM receiver, so if you look at the screen on your iPod You can like listen to radio stations.
Rym: now I see no use for this for me because I don't really listen to the radio other than I listen NPR occasionally.
Rym: But I can download most of that yeah.
Rym: But uh a lot of people have complained for a long time that the iPod didn't have FM support and that even the crappiest crap mp3 players that FM tuners.
Scott: well the thing is is that it is true that even the crappiest of crap players from Southeast Asia have had FM tuners in them.
Scott: But the thing is is that I think the reason they ever put it in the iPod is because it's not really necessary And they don't want you.
Scott: the other thing is they don't want you listening to stuff On the radio because that means you're not listening to the stuff you bought on the iTunes music store.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: There's nothing.
Rym: listen to on the radio anyway.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: I mean, I don't want to sound like a bastard, but radio is dead.
Rym: Yeah, all I don't think it's dead You're wrong.
Scott: I listen to on my iPod mostly as podcasts and things.
Scott: so this is really not so useful for me I mean and the remote control functionality isn't worth the money like.
Rym: honestly I've been listening to the radio a bit for the last month or so.
Rym: That's just because the CD player in my car isn't working.
Rym: That's probably the only.
Rym: That is probably the single factor in the fact that I've listened to more radio in the last month than the rest of my life Combined.
Scott: well, I'm gonna get a new car soon, and it'll have a working CD player But I'm probably just gonna use the iPod in the car.
Rym: Yeah, for you probably want to get a car that has some sort of RCA input or a dock built into it.
Scott: I'm gonna get something cool like that for sure.
Rym: yeah, you know what we'll go shopping cuz I need a new car stereo.
Scott: alright Let's see the next thing they came out with.
Rym: oh, there's this little bundly thing that comes with a bunch of stuff for your nano.
Scott: Yeah, well no.
Scott: It's see it's an iPod AV connection kit, so it's a. there's an iPod dock and for the normal the video iPod a USB cable a remote control and a thing to plug.
Scott: so basically what you would do is you would download Videos from the iTunes music store or buy TV episodes and put them on your video iPod.
Scott: Then you would put your video iPod in this dock That's connected to your TV, and you could control it with this remote control to change the video control the video on the screen That's alright.
Scott: If you're the kind of person who's Buying videos on the iTunes you know store and putting them on your video iPod thing is this bundle is a hundred bucks.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, that's about right.
Rym: Not really that exciting.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the default iPod Earbuds are kind of crummy, so they charging $50 for some in-ear ones which are much better and You get the little lanyard so you can hang the nano around your neck and it's held on by the headphones.
Scott: It's actually a pretty you know clever when you look at it But it's still not much better than the earbuds that come with it.
Scott: It's not even.
Rym: that is like 50 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, so I spent You know like a hundred something on the extra quality headphones where there's you know no way I could damage my hearing.
Rym: Yeah, I think that was much better And I got to say I'm in the market real soon to probably just get a nano or something.
Rym: I'll probably also get some nice in-ear non hearing damaging headphones.
Scott: yep oh The last thing they came out with is a bunch of new software and I don't know I didn't read all the details of the software cuz just wasn't worth my time because I'm not gonna get it.
Scott: yep, anytime soon, but what it comes down to is You're gonna be able to Podcast photo cast and blog and all that stuff real easily and in a real slick fashion.
Scott: if you use a Mac Like you'll see a photo and you'll just drag it somewhere and you'll blog it and then you'll photo cast it And then it'll just make RSS feeds and put them in iTunes stores and do everything for you
Rym: because I like I've said a lot I'm kind of in the market for a new computer and The fact that GarageBand is so awesome is really pushing me toward Mac in a way that I've never been pushed before
Scott: Especially since you know the number one thing we need right now is a computer for podcasting action Podcasting then you know well, I
Rym: got it pretty down with all the free utilities and Linux.
Rym: Yeah, GarageBand has a lot of nice little features.
Scott: They added even like a bunch of sound effects and like bumper musics and things to GarageBand to make it easier for you.
Rym: Of course, you don't want to use those because that means every crap podcast in the world is gonna have all those then.
Scott: Yeah, but they added a feature to where you know They already have some so it's not so hard to add more and it's easy to use them once they're in there.
Scott: Yeah, you see how they made a space.
Scott: They made a space for It's like they created an area where you can put bumper musics and sound effects And they put they just fill the area up a little bit for you, you know.
Scott: in case you know There's something in there that's sort of generic that no one will notice that you're just using the ones that are default And then you put your own in and that's how you know.
Scott: It's better than right now where you don't have a space for it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I Think that's all the Apple news.
Rym: So things of the day Garfield isn't funny anymore.
Scott: Well Garfield hasn't been funny since I think the TV show and Garfield wasn't even funny on the TV show It was that farm part.
Rym: Yeah, Orville pig or whatever.
Rym: His name was Orson Orson pig.
Scott: It was the duck.
Scott: That was funny.
Rym: Now I kind of like Sheldon the guy in the shell.
Scott: Oh Anyway, so some guy made this awesome awesome web program where he's basically got a whole bunch of single frames of Garfield comics in a database or something and It randomly selects three of them and makes a new Garfield comic.
Rym: The sad thing is that three random frames from a large swatch of Garfield is usually more entertaining than actual Garfield.
Scott: Actually, it's can be incredibly entertaining compared to regular Garfield.
Scott: I mean even if it comes up with something that's complete nonsense It's still better than regular Garfield.
Scott: And if you really try to get something good you can get stuff that's hilarious.
Scott: Like.
Scott: we just got one that was pretty funny and I got one earlier today.
Scott: That was just like drop dead on the floor funny.
Scott: So if you're bored and you want some funniness You can just go play with this thing And basically what happens is you click go and it picks three frames and if you like one of the frames you can click Lock like video poker.
Scott: Yeah, and it won't Change that frame and you just keep randomizing until you get what you want.
Rym: I mean, I just don't get it because actually I was out not too long ago and I stumbled across a newspaper which I picked up and flipped through until I found the comics and They're terrible Most of them.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah It's cuz when you have to appeal to such a wide swath of humanity, but it doesn't actually appeal to that wide swath It's just inoffensive to them.
Scott: well, remember that um there was that thing in Britain where they had to figure out the funniest joke and It was like a joke that would make everyone in the world go.
Scott: Hey, hey, hey, you know, it wasn't a joke that would make anyone Roll over on the floor It's just a joke that would make everyone Chuck a little tiny bit.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is like family circus.
Rym: I can't see anyone chuckling even a little.
Scott: The ones with a little lie the dotted line.
Scott: I think we talked about this before.
Rym: Yeah, we did.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, uh point is is cool You've all seen goatse.
Rym: goatse is probably if the internet had a flag.
Scott: That's probably what's on it Internet the United States of Internet, it's just a big goatse.
Rym: On the very least it's the flag of fortune That's for sure.
Rym: But uh, I guess I'll link to it.
Rym: if you've never seen goatse I'll warn you that.
Scott: well Just link to the Wikipedia.
Scott: It's it's where people tend to do these days because goatse is not safe for work.
Rym: Go see is a horrible picture.
Rym: I'm sure you've all seen it.
Rym: There are now worse things out there like lemon party and top girl but goatse was the first one to catch on because it had a funny domain name and If you actually went into the site it had Odd stuff down there.
Rym: There's just this horrible picture very horrible.
Rym: well, I'm sure a lot of people remember the first time they ever experienced it and Someone has decided to go around showing it to people who didn't know what it was and photographing their reactions.
Scott: It's great.
Rym: Um, I think my favorite ones are one.
Rym: There's one guy who's not taken aback at all, but he just kind of looking at it in a pondering way.
Rym: I More taken aback than I expected.
Scott: Well, cuz you know, he doesn't do weird freaky stuff.
Scott: He just does.
Scott: no he just does chicks.
Scott: He doesn't do weird stuff like that.
Scott: So he's a porn star doesn't mean he's not you know, he likes looking at goatse.
Rym: Well, he seems like a cool guy because he was on.
Rym: if any of you watch Penn and Teller's bullshit They did a bit on how all those pills that say they make your penis longer don't work.
Rym: And they had Ron Jeremy on the show and he was talking about yeah, mine's big but whatever blah blah blah.
Scott: Yeah, he's not so weird.
Rym: no no But I got a little amusing anecdote regarding goatse Because when we were sophomores in college Scott had never seen goatse for more than like a nanosecond.
Scott: Well, I knew what it was and I knew I didn't want to look at it But he had avoided it like the plague and avoided it very skillfully I might add.
Rym: I try numerous times to get him to see it and failed and just ended up having to see it myself haha.
Rym: So one day I got up before he did and I decided that I was going to end this once and for all.
Rym: so I whipped out my Coloring jet and I printed a full 8 inch by 11 inch.
Scott: There should be laws of a printing goatse.
Scott: well There's.
Rym: there's another printing goatse story, but I'll do this one first.
Rym: I printed out a full glossy full color goatse and I taped it to his orange juice.
Scott: I saw it as soon as I opened the fridge and I. but I did see it and I managed but I did manage to quickly But I did see it there.
Rym: I just remember sitting on my computer and I hear he gets up.
Rym: like he always does he stumbles into the kitchen.
Rym: I heard the fridge open.
Rym: then I hear ah What the hell Rym?
Scott: Yeah, it's about right of course.
Rym: uh we got someone else later.
Rym: cuz the next time we moved out of the apartment and we moved back in and RIT the school we went to has a giant giant land.
Rym: So we plugged into the land and we're like resetting up our computers and everything.
Rym: and we look and we see that Some guy has a printer shared.
Scott: So the right thing to do is to print goatse out of his printer.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes I mean only a decent human being could do something like that.
Rym: I mean to have done otherwise would have been a crime.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's what I was trying to say.
Rym: So today is gaming day And we've got two new games and one really really old game to talk about.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well the two new games.
Scott: I'm the only one who's played them.
Rym: I Saw the first one you're gonna talk about.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Well, I have something to say about it.
Scott: What the Atari one?
Rym: Yeah the Atari one.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well Media play is going out of business.
Scott: So we went over there and I was looking at the DS selection because who can pass up 40% off a DS game?
Scott: Right, and the only thing that looked like it was worth spending my money on was retro Atari.
Scott: now Usually I shy away from these games.
Scott: I mean the best ones are those Midway classics for the GameCube surround castle to stay alive.
Scott: Good job blue commander.
Scott: But anyway The this one has let's see.
Scott: I think 10 games in it.
Scott: All right, and a lot of these are games I like.
Scott: so I figured what could be wrong.
Scott: So I'm gonna talk about each game in it just real quick.
Scott: Oh also each game has two modes a retro mode and a remix mode aka normal and stupid.
Scott: Yeah It's basically Clatt.
Scott: retro mode is what the original game look like maybe slightly updated so that you know You can see on the DS screen the the remix mode.
Scott: Basically, they make the game look stupid.
Scott: So, you know that it looks all redone.
Scott: They just change the graphics.
Scott: the game plays the same but it looks dumb.
Scott: You and a few of them involve these weird characters.
Scott: I don't even know what the hell's going on.
Scott: But anyway Asteroids is in there.
Scott: It's still as hard as the original asteroids.
Scott: good It's it's the same game.
Scott: There's nothing really wrong with that.
Scott: Breakout is in there.
Scott: I love breakout.
Scott: It's a pretty good breakout.
Scott: the one thing about it though, is that If you want you can control it with the stylus by you.
Scott: you.
Scott: basically this is little Circle at the bottom of the screen and you kind of grab it and drag it back and forth with the stylus.
Rym: Yeah, that sounds fantastic.
Rym: I played that in my web browser.
Scott: It's not a very good way to control breakout.
Scott: I mean you have to keep the stylus like on this circle if you like.
Scott: go up too high You'll you'll lose it and that's not good.
Scott: They should have just said, you know, put it anywhere on the bottom screen.
Scott: What do you need this little knob for?
Scott: I think just bad programming Centipedes on there.
Scott: I love centipede.
Scott: That's all I got to say about that.
Scott: All right, gravatar is on there.
Scott: I have no clue how to play gravatar.
Scott: I can't get it to work for I just can't play this game.
Scott: It's total crap remix or otherwise stylus.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: There's like the first time I tried to play bubbles.
Scott: I just have no clue how to play that game.
Scott: forget about it.
Scott: Lunar Landers on there.
Scott: I don't know if you played lunar lander, basically You have this little rocket, you know like the thing that land on the moon with the thing that touches down that Neil Armstrong comes out of and you have to control Various rockets on it to keep it for you know floating nicely.
Scott: and then there are.
Rym: there are numerous versions of this game all over.
Rym: Yeah, and you one we're referring to is the real one.
Scott: Yeah, this is where you want.
Scott: you basically have this thing and they throw it into basically this.
Scott: you know pixelated terrain and You have to make it land nicely on a flat surface and there's a few flat surfaces.
Scott: Usually it's really hard and In certain versions of lunar lander, I think the Atari one in the arcade one.
Scott: I can do it.
Scott: I can land the lander pretty well on this one.
Scott: I haven't gotten it to land yet and I gave up trying.
Scott: All right, perhaps the best thing in this whole collection is missile command.
Scott: Now I like missile command and a lot of other people like missile command.
Scott: That's the one where the missiles come from the sky and you defend the cities by shooting Explosives at the missiles.
Rym: I still have the original missile command cartridge for the Atari 2600 the Atari.
Scott: the Atari version was terrible.
Scott: It was fine.
Scott: No the arcades where it's at because you get the four you get the little tiny buttons one for each missile shooter.
Scott: But yeah, yeah.
Scott: Anyway, this is perhaps the best missile command ever because you play with the stylus So you just touch the screen and that's where you shoot.
Scott: It's great I don't know why anyone no one ever thought of that before But is perhaps the best Missile command implementation in existence.
Scott: So if you like missile command you have to get this Especially if it's real cheap.
Scott: I mean it was 20 bucks and then 40% off cheap cheap cheap Pong is in there.
Rym: This is a travesty.
Scott: It's pretty much a travesty.
Scott: I mean, it's pretty much Pong.
Scott: I mean except you're not going left to right you're going up to down.
Scott: Well, you're on the down and they're on the up and Uses the dual screens of the DS.
Scott: so it's not quite the same proportion as the original Pong.
Scott: but if you want to play multiplayer, you need another cartridge.
Rym: now, I Point out that Mario Kart does not require another cartridge to play.
Scott: but they cario frickin car But they couldn't get Pong to play on one cartridge.
Rym: See it's obvious to me that they either didn't look at the dev kit They got and just didn't know or more likely they wanted to sell twice as many cartridges.
Scott: No I don't think it's either one of those.
Scott: What this looks like to me is someone just got a DS dev kit and to you know to practice DS coding they just implemented a bunch of Atari games for it and then they said hey if we add like a few hundred more Dollars of development, you know to this then we'll be able to sell it as something cheap and make money off of it.
Scott: So they did and they didn't actually care about making it good.
Scott: They just cared about making it good enough to sell.
Scott: You know, this is like it's like the lowest crappiest thing that Nintendo will allow you to sell for one of their systems.
Scott: Let's see the other games sprint.
Scott: That's that racing game.
Scott: It's just hard and not fun Tempest.
Scott: Oh Tempest pisses me off on this because I Like tempest.
Scott: that's the one where you go around the edge of the circle and you shoot into the middle To shoot the other spaceships.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you can only control this one with the stylus.
Scott: really Like there's no way to control it with the arrows.
Scott: Okay, so it's pretty much impossible to play Like.
Scott: well, it just sucks.
Scott: Oh The last one the last one is good.
Rym: It's warlords warlords If you've never played it is a absolutely fan fucking tastic.
Rym: like for four player one verse one verse one verse one free-for-all.
Rym: Awesome game.
Scott: Yeah, you can play it with the.
Scott: you can use the stylus But you don't have to.
Scott: you can use the arrows and it's just.
Scott: it's better with the arrows.
Scott: think of it like versus breakout with four people.
Scott: so there's a you.
Scott: each person has a corner and each person has a little knobbly.
Scott: that goes around the edges of their square corner and It's a big plus.
Scott: and this little bouncy fireball bounces around in the plus area And you try to block it from hitting the blocks in your corner and try to hit the other people's blocks.
Rym: I used to play it for player on the Atari back in the day.
Rym: I still have it.
Rym: It's awesome.
Scott: It's really awesome and it's for the DS but the multiplayer again You need another cartridge.
Scott: It sucks.
Scott: I don't even know if you can actually play warlords multiplayer, huh?
Scott: Pretty much they put multiplayer on here But it's it's pretty much worthless because no one ever is gonna have more than one cartridge of this in any one place.
Scott: Great All right.
Rym: So we got two more games to talk about.
Scott: Yeah, the other game that I got just recently actually taiko recommended it and It was a PC game.
Scott: so anyone who's gonna start talking about how?
Scott: Oh Scott said there were no good PC games?
Scott: Well, this PC game will run probably on like a 486 so you can stop talking about that now.
Rym: Yeah won't run in wine though, so I can't play.
Scott: it almost runs in wine.
Rym: So yeah, yeah almost in wine doesn't count for shit.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it shows up and it's about.
Scott: it's working perfectly But you can't actually move the mouse in the window because there's some sort of weird bug.
Scott: But anyway, it's called weird worlds and it looks a lot like Master of Orion if you've ever played Master of Orion.
Scott: and but it's not a giant epic space development game it's a Sort of an exploring high score getting cut type of game.
Scott: You can add there.
Scott: your choices are basically you can play the science game the pirate game or the commander game and the science Game.
Scott: what you want to do is you want to fly around the galaxy collecting like Artifacts and scientific things and you want to explore black holes and that sort of thing.
Scott: the pirate game you want to go around collecting big money items and then bring them back.
Scott: and the commander game you want to basically explore and discover alien races and blow people up with your missiles.
Scott: and It's really fun.
Scott: like, you know you go around and there's a lot of item management But it's not difficult item management like an RPG.
Scott: It's like, oh look, I found a better gun.
Scott: Oh, look, I found a thing that lets me move around the galaxy faster, you know And you only have so many years of game time, you know before you you're done and you have to go back and retire.
Scott: So it's like can I do how much more can I do in this time?
Scott: Will that make my score go up?
Scott: Will it make my score go down?
Scott: What ship should I put this item in which they want an item?
Scott: What should I give them?
Scott: Where should I go next?
Scott: You know all the should I engage this combat?
Scott: Should I run away?
Scott: It gets really fun.
Scott: Thing is when I got I got bored of it for a while But then I rediscovered like the hidden secretness of the game like there's items that do crazy stuff But you don't realize and it changes like the whole game.
Scott: It's really it's.
Scott: it's pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah, I don't have much to say about it since I haven't really played it.
Scott: Yeah Basically it was.
Scott: there's a free demo which you can all play and the demo actually kept me occupied for a while.
Scott: but then I actually paid 25 bucks and got the full version and I'm not sad.
Scott: and even if I do eventually get bored of it.
Scott: I can mod it.
Scott: It comes a little mod kit and Modding a space exploration game.
Scott: That's gonna be way cool.
Scott: I'm gonna come up with something great.
Scott: That's for sure.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Rym: So since I haven't played any new games, I've actually been playing an old game quite a bit lately.
Scott: remember civilization - How could you not?
Rym: it's probably one of my favorite games ever.
Rym: It's right up there with the old quest for glory games and you have a fighter.
Rym: So civilization - in case any of you were you know living under rocks or just never heard of a video game before Sid Myers made this game called civilization.
Scott: Wait before that you made colonization.
Rym: Yes, and Basically the sieve games now?
Rym: Well the civilization games because there was a game called sieve which had nothing to do with Sid Myers.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Rym: Yeah, it's just this crap game.
Rym: Don't even don't don't get me started.
Rym: Okay, these games are basically they start you out at like prehistoric caveman times and you build a tiny little village and You control the destiny of this civilization up until like beyond our modern days.
Rym: Yep, it's a. it's a large epic civilization building game that has paid pretty much infinite possibilities.
Rym: The replay value is infinites.
Scott: That's the number one thing I like about civilization Is it you know?
Scott: There's so many ways to win which is?
Scott: I've heard interviews as Sid Meyer where he talks about it And I was pretty much is nodding my head the whole time.
Scott: It's like you can win by building a spaceship.
Scott: You can win by conquering the world.
Scott: You can win in the newer civilizations with culture.
Scott: You can win by you know doing all sorts of different, you know things and It's way cool because no one strategy is like the best strategy for winning.
Scott: It's pretty much if you play well enough and you know what you're doing You'll win no matter what.
Scott: but you get to choose which way you're gonna win so you can make it more fun each time you Play and
Rym: also just the the way the game works because usually you play in a randomized map or you can even play on like Real maps like a map of the actual earth and then you play on it.
Rym: But it seems that even though it's just a eyes you're playing against personalities develop and the game always progresses like I've always seemed to end up where I'll be playing and Through no fault of my own the game will just end up where there's me as a superpower and then there's other superpower And there's a big cold war and all these little states like bickering and underneath us.
Scott: Yeah, it's just cool how that turns out.
Scott: I think it's partially because of the program.
Scott: personalities of the different Nations.
Rym: it's always the freakin zulus.
Scott: Yeah zulus are pretty dangerous.
Scott: Gandhi is usually dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, for some reason Gandhi's really a war monger.
Rym: He'll just steal your stuff plunder your villages kill your men women.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why I mean he was such a nice guy, but it's civilization.
Scott: He's a bastard.
Rym: Actually, I'm a big fan of the Carthaginians.
Scott: I always play as either Babylon or Persia.
Scott: Nah, Persia You know, you got it.
Scott: You got to play the civilizations that no longer exist.
Scott: So that way when you get stealth bombers, you can be like, ah, this shouldn't be This shouldn't be.
Scott: I mean,
Rym: I've had so many good times in that games I used to play when I was in like high school Literally, I'd stay up at night like on the phone with people until 3 or 4 in the morning Just playing Civ 2 and independently that like chatting with people on ICQ or on the phone.
Scott: Mmm, I would just stay up all night playing Civ 2 and till I built the entire Spaceship as with as many parts as I possibly could and then taking off Yep, or I just I just colonize a world as far flung as I could cities everywhere.
Scott: I Never did that.
Scott: But sometimes I would do like these slow Methodical wars and I would fill my entire island with fanatics just to make sure no one could get me.
Rym: My favorite was the nukes that I always build like missile silos or I'd use a bug in the game You could fortify.
Rym: you could basically put an air unit somewhere and just leave it there and it would never run out of fuel or Disappear.
Rym: so I had a cold war.
Rym: I actually set up nuke like nukes nuclear missiles And I just set them all up off the coast of Asia waiting for Russia to.
Scott: you know, give me any shit mmm Nukes are always sort of this if you actually use them in the game like for strategy.
Scott: They were kind of like Stabbing yourself and then the other guy gets stabbed, too.
Rym: Yep, the game actually it handled nuclear diplomacy and just the whole nuclear weapons thing.
Scott: very realistically Am I realistic?
Rym: well as realistically as a simple game like that can in terms of how people react to it.
Rym: Because basically you could.
Rym: there's one you can develop the Manhattan Project which gives you nuclear weapons But then it doesn't just give them to you it gives them to everyone.
Rym: So there's always this point at which anyone who has enough science could research it But no one wants to because then everyone else is gonna get it, too.
Rym: But then eventually some bastard decides he wants it and he does it and then everyone arms.
Rym: But there's always some nation that doesn't have like missile technology so they can't really use it and it gets crazy.
Scott: Well, it doesn't actually give you the nukes immediately.
Scott: It's like it unlocks the ability to research nukes for everybody.
Scott: So it's like if you get Manhattan Project, then you can research nukes right away but other people might take longer and they'll be like don't threaten me with your nukes or You have.
Scott: you're lucky.
Scott: you have those nukes.
Scott: I'll do whatever you say We have them.
Rym: Yeah nukes work a lot like the Great Wall of China works early in the game.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much the same Like effect as far as the foreign policy is concerned.
Rym: There's so many funny little things in the game.
Rym: like you have to pick a government.
Rym: you can have Revolution.
Rym: sometimes your people were revolt on their own and change the government for you.
Rym: But if you pick democracy every time you start a war Your Senate will always just yell at you and then vote you down and stop the war like you'll be.
Rym: you'll have troops outside of the enemy city's capital and you're laying siege to it and you're all set to plunder and Suddenly the Senate's like, alright, you can't have a war anymore and they take all your troops away.
Scott: Well, sometimes it'll be the opposite like someone will declare war on you and normally you wouldn't want to declare war.
Scott: You might want to make peace and the Senate be like no we got to kill those guys.
Rym: Of course Usually what I do when that happens is I overthrow my own government install some sort of fundamentalist nutbag dictator.
Scott: Yeah I usually play the game where I go monarchy and then I go for a public democracy to get all the science and Then if there's a if I need to build stuff, I'll use communism.
Scott: But then as soon as I get the end and there's no more science left and I've built enough stuff fundamentalism the game has a nice funny jab at just that.
Rym: one of the government's is fundamentalism and Fundamentalism.
Rym: your people are always happy no matter what and they give you tons of money in the form of tides.
Rym: But your science rate the rate at which you develop science is cut in half.
Rym: Yep, huh?
Scott: Basically because but it once you reach the end of the game you don't need more science.
Scott: So it's fine to be fundamentalist.
Scott: You don't get that penalty.
Scott: and then you get this new unit You can produce.
Rym: the fanatic fanatics are great.
Rym: They cause nothing to maintain.
Rym: you think they're cheap to build and basically they just stand there and make a mess.
Scott: Yeah, you can just.
Scott: basically what I do is I'll build like a bunch of self bombers and cruise missiles.
Scott: And if anyone makes trouble, I send all the cruise missiles and self bombers over there to destroy all of their military units.
Scott: And then the fanatics invade the city and take it over and there's not much you can do about it Especially if the fanatics come by train.
Scott: Yeah They're just unstoppable.
Rym: I Mean basically we could go on and on about this game for hours But suffice to say if you've never played civil as a civilization game I highly recommend you download Civ 2 because it's abandonware.
Rym: You can just pick it up.
Scott: Well, actually that's technically an illegal link, but the guy still has it up and no one's bothered him.
Rym: So yes, you know what?
Rym: It's abandonware enough for me.
Rym: Yeah, this is a fantastic game.
Scott: They'll warn you It's not like it matters because you could buy it for five bucks in the store.
Rym: Yep, and Civ 3 played a bit.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: and Civ 4 which has just come out as supposedly like awesome.
Scott: Yeah, we'll have to see about that.
Scott: We don't know yet.
Rym: Yeah, cuz once again, I can't run it in Linux.
Scott: Yeah, but you know get any of the civilization games.
Scott: I mean even civilization.
Scott: one is good Yeah, not as good as two.
Rym: two is like, you know Considered two to be like the ultimate civilization game.
Rym: Yeah and three was good but a lot of people had complaints about it.
Rym: and they say that four Takes all the good from three and all the good from two and mashes them together.
Scott: And they say that four actually has multiplayer.
Scott: that makes sense Even though I don't know the specifics of that because the multiplayer in two and three really doesn't work out so well.
Rym: and That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: Also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.