Rym: It's Monday December 18.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about podcast directories.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: I Can't express to the masses out there The teaming mass is listening to the show how great it was to have a weekend where I didn't have to do anything, but relax.
Scott: Oh Man, I slept until there were two digits on the clock.
Scott: That was the awesome Yeah.
Scott: at the first half of the clock the second half of the clock, whatever The second half of the clock is always two digits, even if one of them might be a zero.
Rym: now Saturday I woke up when I wanted to wake up and then we spent the whole day playing board games.
Scott: It was a good day interspersed only by ice hockey also eating out one time.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we did eat out Yep, and we did a little bit of shopping.
Scott: We went to Staples didn't buy anything.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, that's the closest shopping as we ever get and we didn't go to the clothing store.
Rym: Yeah, well we tried to but then we saw those.
Rym: see we keep forgetting that there's this Jesus holiday Christmas And all the festivities around it.
Scott: Yeah, I remember last year there was a date and on that date We said we're not going up that road until the next year because it's not worth it with all these crazy people.
Rym: and in Rochester We used to do that every year pretty much right after Thanksgiving.
Rym: We would not go to the mall under any circumstances until the day after New Year's.
Scott: but well We didn't go to the mall.
Scott: But we definitely went up the road and got real close to the mall closer than we've been in a long time.
Rym: The stores are just crazy like we couldn't even shop at other places because it just wasn't worth it.
Scott: No, definitely not.
Scott: I didn't even get to go to the GameStop and use the gift card.
Rym: I get all right You got that gift card.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna go get.
Scott: metal slug is Probably the first day that it's not stupid crazy to go to a GameStop.
Scott: Yeah, and then I'm probably not gonna go to GameStop again.
Scott: Read today's penny arcade.
Scott: You'll find out why.
Rym: yeah And Sunday was doubly awesome since I. finally I watched the end of Gundam seed again and Emily saw it for the first time.
Scott: Yeah, you know when you don't watch an anime or you watch it one time you get the general gist of how it ended But you forget the details and I walked in for like two seconds at a critical moment and I remembered this Small detail that is crazy awesome about the end of that show.
Rym: Yeah Oh, yeah, holy shit cuz.
Rym: I forgot about a lot of things and I remembered things that happen But I forgot how absolutely intense they were.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's not just anime It's basically any movie or TV show or anime or anything manga?
Rym: That's really good.
Rym: You should always do yourself a favor and read it or watch it twice.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if something it depends on how many stars is mean if it's like three or four stars good Then you don't really have to watch it again, but anything that's five stars good, you know.
Scott: Especially if you haven't seen it in a while or read it in a while You should definitely go back because there are awesome bits you forgot that you will like to remember.
Rym: in fact I think the most telling evidence of that was it was a while ago months ago.
Rym: Emily was here visiting but she was up in the studio here working on an animation project and homework for school That she had to do.
Rym: meanwhile Scott and I are downstairs and we decided to watch Star Wars Episode 4 again.
Scott: That was a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, it was but even to this day.
Rym: how many times have we each seen Star Wars Episode 4?
Scott: I could watch Star Wars Episode 4 or 5 or 6.
Scott: It doesn't matter which one of those three I could watch each one a thousand time.
Scott: I could probably sit there for the rest of my life watching them in a loop and I would never Wouldn't get old.
Rym: but even then no matter how many times I've seen those movies when we watch Episode 5 and he kills like the Second Admiral, it's still like.
Rym: I remembered that happened But I forgot how it happened and it was almost as amusing as the first time I saw it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I totally didn't get that joke when I was a little kid.
Scott: cuz I did it over my head when I was A little kid.
Rym: I was just afraid of Darth Vader.
Rym: I Wasn't afraid of Darth Vader like I was like woohoo.
Rym: I mean all I could think was on the screen.
Scott: Oh, why isn't he on the screen more?
Rym: Like I didn't think it was funny that he kept killing those admirals.
Rym: I thought it was just like Siri like dead serious and I was just like whoa.
Rym: He just killed that dude.
Rym: now I'm older.
Rym: It's like yeah, good job Admiral so-and-so.
Scott: Yeah Cuz he said cuz he kills a guy who's an act cuz you don't really pay attention.
Scott: Usually you're like when I was a kid of me to pay attention like which guy's the Admiral and when which guy's the Grand Moff And which guy's the talking was the Grand Moff?
Rym: which guy's the commander which was a political appointment and not a military position.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: But now that I pay attention to that sort of thing, you know, I noticed that he kills Admiral what's-his-face.
Scott: and then he goes to the guy who is the second in command and he says, you know Proceed as planned admiral something something.
Scott: and I was like, oh he just promoted that guy.
Scott: I Didn't get that until I don't know high school days.
Scott: I didn't get that joke.
Rym: Yeah, plus being older a lot of those things became quotes.
Scott: I mean if this is a Get that joke into high school, but it wasn't funny until real recently.
Rym: but mainly it seemed to become funny with the advent of the quotable memes and Exactly can't quote end Star Wars.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like in the early days of college No one was like where is the ambassador?
Scott: But nowadays where's the ambassador?
Rym: I find your lack of faith disturbing.
Rym: Okay, right.
Rym: This isn't the Star Wars show.
Rym: No, no, we've talked about Star Wars multiple times already Have we?
Scott: I thought we only talked about it one time.
Rym: I'm pretty sure we've brought up Star Wars.
Scott: Okay It's hard not to bring up Star Wars on fucking GeekNights not to mention on Science fiction day in addition to science day.
Scott: I mean the only reason that we don't bring up Star Trek every two seconds because I don't like it.
Rym: I however really like Star Trek and you can die in a fire captain doesn't like Firefly.
Scott: Yeah, I don't like that either or battle star Galactica.
Scott: Not a fan.
Rym: See the thing is I like the new best.
Rym: I'm like.
Scott: I'm not a nerd.
Rym: No, no No, you'd only be.
Rym: I'd only be a nerd if I like Star Wars or Star Trek or I don't know underwear perverts.
Scott: Well, maybe I am a nerd cuz I do like like really old shitty sci-fi like Lost in space.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: If you like all that, how come you don't like the original Battlestar Galactica?
Scott: I never really saw too much really.
Scott: Yeah, I saw like two episodes of whatever Battlestar Galactica is up your alley.
Rym: It is what only cheesy people blowing stuff up and flying around and stuff up is good.
Rym: There's a lot of people blowing stuff up.
Rym: You'd probably identify with the main character cuz he's pretty much just a woman iser.
Scott: I'm not a woman iser.
Rym: Well, not there any fault of trying.
Scott: Not a woman eyes here in the classic sense.
Scott: I'm a woman eyes or the humorous sense.
Rym: Anyway We got some kind of big news today.
Rym: I'll let Scott take it.
Rym: It was gonna be my news, but then I saw your news first.
Rym: Well, alright, I'll do my news.
Rym: My news was gonna be the thing.
Rym: that's gonna be Scott's news.
Rym: But then I realized again that there's this news that angered me Much more so than the other news and lightened me or made me happy To not go into all the details.
Rym: a school and this isn't in the Bible belt.
Rym: This is pretty much right near us in the civilized part of downstate, New York.
Rym: Actually, it's in New Jersey But yeah, ten miles west of Manhattan.
Rym: So up here You can't knock this off as being somewhere out in the middle of nowhere in a rural community or like Utah.
Rym: Yeah teacher respected teacher teacher who probably has tenure at a fancy-pants school a good school a public school Supposedly also a good teacher.
Rym: Yeah loved by the students begins his studies by going on crazy Evangelical rants about how Adam and Eve lived with the dinosaurs and Noah's Ark was real and a Muslim girl in class is gonna go To hell and the Big Bang Theory and evolution are bullshit.
Scott: now one kid?
Rym: No, not not even a science teacher.
Rym: This is like a AP government class or something.
Scott: Wow, so one kid in the class is awesome.
Scott: He's a hero Definite hero.
Rym: Yeah, this kid saw what was going on and rightfully so thought that this is wrong Possibly illegal or at least contrary to the ideals of the Constitution of the United States and the principles of the separation of church and state and Really made him uncomfortable.
Rym: so he brought and he didn't see he would have just a normal kid would have just complained to his parents or complained to the School or written a letter or call a lawyer.
Rym: This kid was smart The got.
Rym: the teacher was so crazy and what he was saying that the kid didn't think that anyone would believe him.
Rym: So we stuck a tape recorder into class and recorded this.
Rym: teachers batshit rants about religion.
Scott: Now some people accuse the kid because I mean the teacher obviously must have done it one or two times on his own In order to prompt the kid to bring in the tape recorder.
Scott: People accuse the kid of like baiting the teacher to make him talk about religion more like for the recorder.
Scott: But if you actually listen to the recordings the kid never starts any of the conversations, although he does further their.
Scott: He extends them by furthering the line of questioning.
Scott: if you will See now.
Rym: this is why the news and I bring it up as such a big deal because it's not just That this teacher was crazy and doing these crazy things because that alone Happens with a variety of subjects on a semi-regular basis.
Rym: There are crazy teachers out there.
Rym: There are teachers who have bad days.
Rym: There are teachers who were just nutty but have tenure.
Rym: I had a teacher once who was so senile.
Rym: I don't think he even knew where he was, but he had tenure.
Scott: Yeah, I've had nutty teachers.
Scott: But you know, I realized looking back like a lot of things teachers said when I was a student I didn't realize that they were like avoiding talking about religion or anything, you know, yeah Now I realize oh those teachers said those things because of this and those teachers are hippies and those teachers aren't.
Rym: well I had one teacher in middle in high school who was a 100% died in the wool red communist straight-up communist.
Scott: I never had.
Scott: all my teachers are pretty much capital, but he definitely.
Rym: he Presented the material, you know in social studies in an objective and non-biased manner and you wouldn't know he was a communist at all.
Rym: He just seemed like a really good teacher and he was really good.
Rym: But because then he'd take the kids he thought were smart to the side and like give him a copy of various Literature and talk to them about communism, but he was really cool, dude I had a lot of fun with him But despite the fact that he had very deeply held convictions about certain things He kept that out of the classroom and just taught the objective.
Rym: at least as objective as history can be truth He taught what the curriculum told him to.
Scott: now there's a problem with the curriculum So be it.
Rym: but now what's?
Rym: the issue here is not so much that this happened or that the kid was smart but that the majority of the students in the school and the administration and the community are backing the teacher and Ostracizing this kid for stepping forward.
Scott: now I can understand that if someone goes against a well-liked teacher But when there's evidence right there and it's clearly illegal and the judge and everyone is like, yeah That's not cool and it's oh god
Rym: now I mean this kid's family even received at least one death threat from local People who are mad about the fact that they step forward.
Rym: the police are currently investigating that.
Rym: yeah now I'm sure that is not the majority.
Rym: I'm not going to cast any wide dispersions here But I'm betting it's a Christian person who thinks they're all good or at least someone who thinks they're Christian.
Rym: Yeah But what's the line of thinking that goes from?
Rym: yeah, I'm a Christian turn the other cheek, uh threaten a guy with death.
Scott: What's the line there?
Scott: Yeah, isn't he going to hell supposedly on his own?
Scott: What do you need to help him along for shouldn't?
Scott: isn't God gonna smite him?
Scott: What do you know?
Scott: you're gonna go to hell for killing someone.
Scott: thou shalt not kill what the fuck?
Rym: Well, I remember even when I went to Catholic school when I was a young kid And you know, I wasn't a Catholic by any stretch, but I would pay it like we'd have to take religion class.
Rym: That was part of going to a Catholic school.
Rym: My only other option was to go to Detroit Public Schools, which was not an option.
Scott: It was an option.
Rym: No, it was not an option.
Rym: It wasn't even on the list of options.
Scott: It just wasn't good.
Rym: It was not an option.
Rym: They would have killed me.
Rym: I would have died.
Rym: There would have been no Rym.
Rym: There might have still been a Rym Yeah But even then I remember that one of the points that the nuns always drilled into us aside from Don't write with your left hand and don't masturbate Was that you can't ever.
Rym: you're not supposed to punish someone for sinning Because God will take care of that and you're just supposed to let people be and do your own thing.
Scott: So wait, but then the nuns punished you for supposedly sinning, didn't they?
Rym: The nuns punished me for a lot of things.
Scott: So what didn't you say to the nuns?
Scott: I thought you're not supposed to punish.
Rym: Don't get me started on Catholic school.
Rym: Alright, the only nun that was nice was the one who gave me a gerbil.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: What?
Scott: The nun gave you a gerbil.
Scott: Where did she give you the gerbil?
Rym: The school had with the one nun Had a whole bunch of gerbils in the classroom this giant like maze.
Scott: and what were the gerbils for?
Rym: They were for looking at and playing with and one time one of them got stuck in a cardboard tube.
Rym: No in his cage.
Rym: I woke up one day ready to go to school.
Rym: I was in third grade, you know The nun did with those gerbils after school and I heard a noise and I look and one of the gerbils is stuck in a Cardboard tube like his butts hanging out.
Rym: and he's stuck and we're trying to get him out.
Rym: He's freaking out.
Rym: We can't pull him out.
Rym: That's not gonna work.
Rym: So my dad comes in.
Rym: we're looking at it.
Rym: My dad picks up the cardboard tube Puts his mouth up to the other end and just goes whoo and blows into it.
Rym: The gerbil just pops out the other side like a blowgun.
Rym: Gerbil was fine.
Scott: Her dad blows gerbils.
Rym: Yeah, he does.
Rym: the point is that this whole situation is just kind of crazy and I can't believe that.
Rym: Not not that anyone would argue against the separation of church and state because there are people who do argue against it.
Rym: The fact that so many people are on this teacher's side and not only don't want the teacher to be punished But commend him for doing the things he did.
Scott: there are people who want this kid to be expelled.
Scott: It's like what the fuck?
Rym: I mean if these reports have been believed he told the class that a Muslim girl in the class is going to hell because she's Not Christian.
Scott: Yeah That is not acceptable under any stretch.
Scott: I would send someone to like the local jail for a week for that kind of action.
Scott: I would just fire the judge if I were firing the teacher is a given.
Rym: Yeah That's all I do.
Rym: I wouldn't do anything else.
Rym: I wouldn't take any sort of punitive step.
Scott: I'm starting to think that there's a possible sentence that could be given out in this country.
Scott: Often that has never been given out as far as I know.
Scott: ridicule No prison for a day.
Scott: send someone to the worst prison for a day.
Scott: Most people will learn their fucking lesson.
Rym: if you know what I would learn my lesson cuz I go I drive past a prison And I learned my lesson.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Rym: so when our one of our friends works in a prison and She has some fucking stories.
Rym: Yeah talking to her for five minutes You would kill yourself before you go to a federal prison exactly.
Scott: So why?
Scott: there are a lot of people that do things that aren't so bad and you know They're basically good people, but they screwed up and they need to be taught a lesson.
Scott: And since we can't you know beat them with a cane or anything like they do in some other countries.
Scott: Why not actually for a day?
Rym: actually there's been an uptick in judges ordering people to non-conventional punishments really and most Recently a guy was caught.
Rym: He was parking in handicapped spots like a chronic guy.
Rym: He did it more than well.
Scott: He did it all the time so he could just park close.
Rym: Well, he did it enough to where the judge decided that a fine wouldn't be enough.
Rym: all right He had to stand at the store where he did it with a sign on saying that I am NOT handicapped yet I park in handicapped spaces for like a whole day at the handicapped space.
Rym: so people who parked there legitimately could Have words with him.
Rym: Uh-huh And they did a cop.
Scott: stand there and make sure you didn't.
Rym: yes, yes.
Rym: and there was another one recently where a shop a chronic shoplifter was caught and had to stand in the store with a placard saying That I'm a shoplifter for like a week.
Scott: I'm liking this action.
Scott: Yeah, I mean still prison for a day.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: Don't you think?
Rym: well my philosophy on the we.
Rym: we should do a whole show on this Like we keep saying well, but very very briefly before we go on to the other news I am of the mind that there should be two forms Really three forms of punishment and they should be totally different for crimes.
Rym: the first one and the one that should be used most often should be pure rehabilitation and if in the very least the redressing of Grievances as in if someone causes damage they have to repair the damage and if someone does something bad you try to make it so that they won't do anything bad again.
Rym: because that you want people to be good people and But screwing people over for minor crimes is not going to help them be a good person If anything is going to make them a worse person.
Scott: Most people are good people and there's a lot of people out there who might you know Repeatedly commit minor crimes like an awesome graffiti artist or something.
Scott: Just make them clean it up But what the hell man?
Rym: Well, if I mean generally if anyone on nonviolent crime if you're caught once I think Rehabilitation is should always be the primary form of punishment.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yep Not really don't even call the punishment.
Rym: Just.
Rym: the first goal should always be to get someone back into society and undo whatever harm they did.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: However, failing that like if our chronic offender like someone who keeps parking in handicapped spaces for years and years and years And he just pays the fines and keeps going about it.
Rym: or people who just keep doing thing Keep robbing people keep mugging people.
Rym: then you go to phase two where you don't you're still trying to rehabilitate them But you punish them.
Scott: punitive you've got because you if someone's recurring like that, you know that letting them out into the world They're only going to do it more.
Scott: So you have to keep them out of society to fix them as opposed to letting them be in.
Rym: so it's phase one is Give them a way to write themselves and be a good person.
Scott: This is gonna turn into the whole episode.
Scott: Let's hurry down.
Scott: All right.
Rym: phase one positive reinforcement.
Rym: phase two negative reinforcement.
Rym: phase three scientific research or execution.
Scott: Phase four if they're a nutcase put them in a nut house.
Scott: Well, yeah, but that's a lot of people who are nut cases and they need to be put in nut houses But you don't have anymore.
Rym: Yeah The sad thing is that most of those people now are either homeless on the street and don't realize they can get help or they're in jail.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Rym: Anyway, the more important news today Oh more important.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Well to us, okay.
Scott: So perhaps the most important website of the past year or so is dig.com.
Scott: Basically, we used to have sites like slash stop meme pool, etc, etc.
Rym: They're gone.
Scott: now dig I mean FARC is still around a bit.
Rym: and what do you mean if a FARC is strong as ever?
Scott: Well, yeah slash dot you could say as strong as I know if I wanted to.
Rym: slash shot is rapidly In trouble.
Scott: drudge is still around, you know, this site still exists, but dig is swiftly and has been swiftly Conquering all of them like a mighty stomping Monty Python foot.
Scott: Just squish squish squish.
Rym: Yeah dig is kind of like slowly becoming the convergence of all Popular internet culture.
Scott: Yeah, and Whereas sites like slash went without feature updates or anything for years and years and years and years, you know Where they didn't even change it.
Scott: to goddamn thing Dig seems to be upgrading with completely new versions that add vast new amazing features for the improvement of everything every few months.
Scott: and today surprise surprise Dig calm I think it's 3.0.
Rym: Yeah, I remember I was at work and I was.
Rym: I had some free time So I went to dig and I dug some things.
Rym: I was looking for news to talk about today and then I went out and did something.
Rym: I came back to my desk and I just hit f5, you know Refresh dig before I go about my business and a black screen came up that said dig is currently upgrading.
Scott: Yeah Usually they have like the dig the little guy with the shovel and he says we're under construction or something's going on.
Scott: We'll be back up soon and it's got a few links to stuff.
Scott: But this one was like upgrading bitches.
Rym: Oh shit Yeah Now we're gonna talk about probably at least the most important to us aspect of the upgrade as the main bit.
Rym: But suffice to say if you don't use dig at all, or you don't have an account on dig I highly recommend you get one because it's getting to the point where dig is actually a useful Usable wonderful site that will probably make your internetting experience a much better thing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's a lot of things to be said about dig that are negative but as I said dig keeps changing.
Scott: They're trying to make things better unlike other sites where people complain and the site would never change.
Scott: It would just keep adding news without changing the site itself.
Scott: Dig is always growing and growing better and growing more awesome all the time And it is basically the center of all that is importance on the Internet's as far as we are concerned.
Rym: Now the the thing that we really want to talk about we'll bring it up now Then we'll go in depth in the news segment is simply that they have added Podcasts to dig as an official legitimate fully supported thing.
Rym: It's beta now, but it's there.
Rym: Yes they opened it up today and You had to like we everyone had to submit podcasts to it and there was some trouble because it looks like and we're not sure That they are manually verifying and placing every podcast Like they're verifying that they're legitimate.
Scott: also I'm sure it takes quite a while for their software to you know, grab all the episodes in your feed, etc, etc, etc.
Rym: Yeah Cuz there's also the way dig is doing.
Rym: podcast is really different from the way anyone else is doing them Which I think is a wonderfully fantastic thing because I have beefs with things like podcast pickle or what's that?
Scott: Podcast alley podcast alley or pop currents odeo What are some other ones?
Rym: Yahoo podcasts podcast like.
Rym: they all had serious issues.
Rym: that then they really made him pretty much at least to me Unusable or not worth even going to.
Rym: but dig seems to have it down already.
Scott: Yep So dig has added a dig style podcast directory.
Scott: now the most important feature of dig actually is that they've split off the video Section because what was happening?
Scott: there are two things.
Scott: first of all videos are getting a lot more digs than any other news stories or anything else and they were upsetting to dig out of the rhythm because it's hard to tell when to bring something to the front page.
Scott: if a video is likely to get way more digs than A news story and they followed the same rule for getting to the front page Well, then these moderately popular videos are getting up there with the very popular blog entries and it doesn't really work out.
Scott: So they put videos in their own section just like podcasts are in their own section.
Scott: The other thing that dig has done is you know for a while Dig has had a feature where if you link to YouTube or wherever it would put a link so you could go directly to the You know video from and it would have a little preview of the video like one little picture.
Scott: They still have that but now you can watch the video in Dig, you don't have to go to YouTube and then watch it Yes, so now You know You can just watch all the amazing videos of the day from dig with no need to go to YouTube or Google video or any Of those other places depending on if it's supported by dig.
Rym: now of course the the selfish part is to follow and We've said before that we don't ever want to promote ourselves like, you know Go to podcast alley and vote for us because those sites are kind of crap and it's really crap to Be a podcast and have to ask your listeners to go do something like that on a regular basis just to make you more popular.
Scott: Yeah to make us more popular.
Scott: It should be us doing things not you.
Scott: It's not your obligation to do things to make us more popular.
Rym: Especially not a recurring thing.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to you know, go do things to promote us.
Scott: That's cool.
Scott: But we're not going to you know, ask you to do it.
Scott: It's yeah, it's up to you If you think we're good which you're gonna spread the word about us many views without us telling you.
Rym: I mean, we've had people email us asking if they would be allowed to distribute our flyers at conventions They go to that are too far away for us to attend.
Rym: Yeah, and that they that I mean people they ask like would you mind if we did this?
Scott: We're always like no do whatever the hell you want.
Scott: It's like if I read a book.
Scott: I don't need the odd.
Scott: if the author comes and tells me hey you like my book and I'm like well kinda he's like Go and tell people to buy my book.
Scott: Well now I'm not gonna bitch.
Scott: It's like if he would have just not said anything and I like the book.
Scott: I would have naturally spread the word just the way you spread the word about anything you like.
Rym: but more that's yeah Yeah, but more specifically the things like podcast alley where they make you keep going back.
Scott: Yeah, it's like not only what an is it an ass for an author to come and tell me to go and promote his book For him, but now he's gonna tell me that I have to do something every single month to promote his book for him.
Scott: Well, fuck you two times bitch.
Scott: That's why we don't ask you to go to podcast alley like other podcast.
Scott: If I am all our friend podcast, yeah every other podcast out there.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think Dave and Joel do that.
Scott: No, I don't think they care.
Scott: Oh, I don't know.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Well, they're 40 listeners might get mad.
Rym: I can't make fun of another podcast really.
Scott: Yeah, they deserve 40,000 listeners.
Rym: Yeah can say well considering that both us and anime world order blatantly steal their brand of humor whenever possible.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't know whatever.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: it's hard to not make jokes about space dollars.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, the point is that if you we're going to ask this now mostly because dig is doing it Right, and you only have to do it once and if you don't use dig yet You should be using dig.
Rym: So one if you don't have an account on dig.
Rym: I highly recommend you check it out.
Scott: Yeah, this is.
Scott: this is not like dig telling us to promote dig.
Scott: I don't think dig even really needs promotion because it's so huge now.
Scott: But if you're an internet person or a geek, you should probably have a dig account and you should probably be using dig Day at least daily at least once a day.
Scott: You should be going there and checking stuff.
Rym: I mean if you want to know everything that's going on in the internet really quick and you don't want to deal with bark Just go to dig once a day and you'll be pretty much as on top of things as we are.
Scott: Yeah, uber geeks like me and Rym.
Rym: We know everything that was important on the internet Because we read a lot of websites and spend a lot of time reading those websites.
Scott: Yeah and dig is pretty much the easy way to skim off the top unlike us where we go all the way down and we check Out everything.
Scott: if you just want to know we can't give everything to you in this podcast.
Scott: You can only give you two news and two things of the day.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: There's a lot of 10 news.
Rym: There's
Scott: a lot more than two news and two things of the day out there and you're missing them if you're not going to certain Websites, but if you go to dig you're not gonna miss much
Rym: now - and once again We'll never ask anyone to do this again and want to.
Rym: and also remember that we're only asking this if you actually agree with It.
Rym: if you like us you like GeekNights and you happen to have a dig account I would recommend I would suggest that you dig GeekNights.
Rym: We're in there in addition to all of our feeds and I Have.
Rym: being high up on.
Rym: dig would make us and any other good podcast very popular.
Rym: In fact, the fact that a lot of our friend podcasters have not yet submitted themselves to dig is kind of amazing to me.
Scott: No, I guess they're just not as geek because I thought like I'm not on top of this stuff cuz I was like Oh, alright this dig thing.
Rym: We're on there and I dug us.
Rym: I was like, alright now I'm gonna dig all my favorite podcasts and super pods on there and 12 is Dean Emperor's got a bajillion day because it's a freaking awesome podcast and escape pods on there.
Rym: And then I go to dig anime world order.
Rym: They're not on there.
Rym: and then fast karate.
Rym: ninja consultant.
Rym: They're not on there.
Scott: No weekly anime review.
Scott: I don't know if he's on there.
Scott: I got a look.
Rym: Hold on No, what?
Rym: last time when I first searched we were the only anime podcast there for a while.
Rym: Well, and then now there's two.
Rym: well, there's one other anime podcast because there are three and two of them are us.
Scott: Let's see anime.
Scott: I just searched for anime on dig podcast.
Scott: GeekNights with Roman Scott.
Scott: GeekNights Wednesdays anime manga comics.
Scott: r5 central.
Scott: all dig.
Scott: That's that guy who does it with the weird voice.
Scott: Oh It's Mike Dent and a cyber assistant AI.
Rym: wow, we're just promoting people left and right today.
Scott: Yeah, they always play that promo on anime world order.
Scott: I've listened to the show once and I think it's a show that like that we fit in with and Like that we would be friendly with these guys.
Scott: if it's more than one guy or just one I don't know.
Scott: but listening to the show is really kind of weird.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: This is an r5 central review.
Rym: Yeah, I know.
Rym: Well, I'll say that I know a lot of podcasters and I'm friends with him, but I don't listen to their shows.
Rym: I'll be perfectly honest.
Scott: Well, I mean seriously I'd like to be friends with hundreds of podcasters because podcasters tend to be awesome people but I can't listen to 100 shows.
Scott: You can't listen 100 shows.
Scott: So yeah, it you're always gonna feel bad.
Scott: So you're best off just you know, accepting the truth.
Rym: So once ever only if you were on dig dig GeekNights.
Rym: and it'll make us more popular.
Rym: and the more popular we get the more quickly we'll get swag out to you.
Rym: and The more quickly we get swag out to you the more quickly you can wear it.
Rym: Things of the day Oh hot damn We're gonna be real quick about the things of the day because I just noticed by looking at the time that we actually went way Long on the first half of the show tonight.
Scott: Ah shit.
Rym: So, uh, I got a video about an awesome parrot and I recommend that you watch it.
Scott: That was quick.
Rym: Hey, what else can I say?
Rym: It's a cool parrot.
Scott: Okay, I got a video.
Scott: some guys use jet engines to make their bicycles Go and what's way cool about it.
Scott: Is there not evil kenevils trying to go really fast and hurt themselves?
Scott: They just go at normal speed which is wicked.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: We should do that.
Scott: Yeah, go like 45 60 miles an hour down the road on bicycles.
Scott: perfectly safe cool stuff I did.
Rym: I got up to like 42 miles an hour going on a downhill on my bike once.
Rym: Imagine going 60 without having a pedal kind of like riding the cheapest motorbike in the world.
Scott: Actually, it's kind of better because you just have this heat exhaust going up behind you instead of like this thunder in your pants I imagine.
Scott: I think part of the experience of riding a motorcycle though is the Thunder in the pants.
Rym: I have a Sneaking suspicion that the range of the rocket-powered bike was not so far.
Scott: Yeah, probably went through that kerosene pretty quickly All right.
Rym: Anyway, we said before that we would talk about podcast directories and mostly we want to talk about how dig is handling the whole Podcasting thing because they're really doing it better than anyone else has so far.
Scott: Let's talk about how people did it in the past so that we have something to compare to all right.
Rym: first there was iTunes.
Scott: Well, no first iTunes didn't come until actually later.
Scott: all those other sites came before I.
Rym: before then is like the prehistory when there were like eight podcasters and nine podcast listeners.
Scott: Yeah, I know but no there was podcast alley.
Scott: now podcast alley was just a site that lists Podcasts and what you do is if you go there every month you can vote for a podcast and to vote for a podcast You have to like type in your email address.
Scott: Then it sends you an email and everything and it's kind of annoying.
Rym: now think about that.
Rym: You've got to go there every month and keep voting for something you like.
Scott: Yeah, and if you vote for it enough, it'll show up in like the top 10 for a category.
Scott: So let's say you're in the gaming category.
Scott: Then people who go and look at the gaming podcast might see that podcast in the top 10 if it got enough votes.
Rym: Now we don't need to tell you why this business model is stupid.
Rym: most of the it's simply that this was done I don't know 10 years ago in the where's scene and it was just a corrupt thing then and it's just a stupid thing now.
Scott: Yeah, it's real stupid.
Scott: I mean if you get enough votes you can get on the front page of podcast alley, but who goes to podcast alley?
Scott: It's like this site that people go to in order to vote for a podcast.
Scott: No one goes there to actually find new podcasts.
Scott: It's just a site that podcasters go to to vote for themselves and see how many votes they got and a site where podcast Listeners go to vote for the podcast that they already listen to.
Scott: it's really just this stupid kind of circular.
Scott: See now this was like a circle jerk, really.
Rym: But this was tried before in the some of the early days of the internet.
Rym: before search engines worked really well.
Rym: There were a lot of alternative means to search engines.
Rym: there were directories there were web rings and there were a lot of top 100 sites and basically, you'd have the same thing.
Rym: you'd have to go to the site every month and vote for your favorite sites and then they would go near the top.
Rym: and It's like it's just.
Rym: they're trying to get themselves free advertising in order to be popular on this site You have to force your listeners to go there Even though they probably don't want to actually go there and click on something for you.
Scott: yeah, I think the big mistake that all these voting sites make that dig doesn't make and I guess delicious doesn't make it either is That it's a site where the only functionality is the only real functionality I mean, there's other stuff you can do here, but it's not useful is voting.
Scott: It's like you have to provide a useful functionality that is improved by voting Like I dig sites to remember them and that happens to be a vote.
Scott: Yeah, I guess the alley you vote for the sake of voting.
Scott: It's kind of what the hell.
Rym: a site like this can only be actually truly useful and have any sort of longevity If people would go there Independent of just voting if they would go there on their own anyway.
Scott: Yeah, and I'm sure there are people who go to podcast alley to find new podcasts But they are not large in number.
Rym: by anything plus I mean It doesn't really select for the best podcast or the most popular podcast or the most relevant podcast.
Rym: It selects for the podcast that does the best job of tricking its listeners into going there every month and clicking on something.
Scott: Yeah, number one is muggle cast, which I sell which I assume is some Harry Potter podcast.
Scott: Number five is Snape cast and number three is Potter cast.
Scott: Well, they're number one is muggle cast.
Scott: So obviously the Harry Potter fans are very rabid and they like to vote for their pie.
Rym: Well, no, it's probably all.
Rym: generally Clusters of podcasts will get on the top of that site all the time as they all concertedly try to get all their listeners to collectively Vote for.
Scott: I see so that all the Harry Potter fans listen to all the Harry Potter.
Rym: give it a couple months and they all vote Collectively, yeah, so give it a couple months and they'll all fall off the ranking and some other cluster will move up to the top.
Scott: Yeah, it's not really the most useful thing in the world, especially when you consider what really is the number one podcast.
Scott: Podcast alley doesn't match that so well.
Rym: Yeah, then there's iTunes which Doesn't really let you have much real input.
Scott: well the iPod the iTunes directory is funny because it's.
Scott: it's actually useful directory for finding new podcasts and Listening to them and downloading them if you are an iTunes iPod user.
Scott: But in terms of it listing the best Podcasts, you know, it's not it doesn't have the best.
Rym: It basically ends up listing one the curt the most popular Podcast which rarely changes because they're kind of entrenched and they're always huge compared to everything else.
Rym: And two it'll pick based on various secret algorithms Upcoming new podcasts that might not be popular that it wants to promote for whatever reason.
Rym: and I hate to say it.
Rym: But I found that in many cases I mean the ones that are on top are usually well worth listening to and they usually deserve their spot.
Rym: But a lot of times a podcast will be featured in a category on iTunes, but it'll totally suck balls.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not gonna name names but I tried three different podcasts that purport to teach you French or Japanese or a language or something and They were featured meaning.
Rym: Oh, they must be good or there must be something to them and they were crap like Absolute crap.
Scott: Yeah, the podcast there that show up and like the top podcast Those are the ones that have a lot of people subscribing to them recently the ones that show up as featured.
Scott: I think they're I'm pretty sure they're actually editors of the iTunes podcast directory who pick those Manually, I have words for some of the people who have picked some of those podcasts.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what method they use to pick them.
Scott: I'm sure there's money involved.
Scott: It's for some of them.
Scott: I'm sure associations with existing Organizations matters a lot because you notice like ESPN is placed very highly Often and not that I listen to one ESPN podcast is really good But it's really just a recording of a really good TV show.
Scott: But ESPN to Disney to Steve Jobs to Apple.
Scott: Hello.
Scott: Come on It's obvious.
Rym: plus again iTunes is totally useless to everyone who doesn't use an iPod iTunes combo.
Scott: Yep, it's.
Scott: it's basically the I. the iTunes podcast directory is a tool for iPod iTunes users to subscribe to podcasts.
Scott: not really useful for figuring out which podcasts are the best Yeah, or discovering new things not the greatest but it's still compared to a lot of other things that are out there good enough.
Rym: It's okay, then like Libsyn has its directory and feedburner has its stuff, but those aren't really useful at all.
Scott: No, I don't even know why they even bothered.
Scott: It's like Libsyn.
Scott: The thing that you do.
Scott: Well is hosting.
Scott: Why are you trying to make a directory?
Scott: That's just sort of attacked.
Rym: Most people use Libsyn.
Rym: use the full Libsyn gambit with all the stuff they offer Which is great if you don't know anything about the internet Mm-hmm.
Rym: I mean, it's a really easy service for anyone to use but their their their community is really like.
Rym: the people in their forums Are some of the scariest dumbest people not the moderators, but doesn't matter because people are gonna podfade.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of them do.
Rym: I think that's part of Libsyn's business model.
Scott: I think that is the Libsyn's business model.
Scott: is the same business model that like.
Rym: Well, you know If a podcast is kind of lame and has like 10 listeners even if they go forever That bandwidth is not costing Libsyn anything.
Scott: No, it's the same Business model as gyms.
Scott: you go to a gym and they sell you a membership for a year.
Scott: If you if everyone who bought a gym membership actually showed up every day to work out the gym would go out of business.
Scott: They make their money on people who buy gym memberships and maybe they'll go a few times But they don't show up for the whole year that they paid for and that's how the gym rakes in the dough.
Rym: Now then there's like podcast pickle which has a lot of the same problems as podcast alley just in a different angle.
Scott: Yeah Podcast pickle actually tries to be a site that you can find new podcasts at and you can like mark podcasts as your favorite and whatever.
Scott: But you know, it's really what.
Scott: why would you go there?
Scott: You can find podcasts elsewhere.
Scott: You don't need to go to podcast pickle Yeah.
Rym: and then there's all the promo sites where podcasts will trade promos and you can go there and listen to promos and all that sort of thing.
Rym: and I'll say pretty openly that the vast majority of promos every podcast including us has ever done is terrible and lame.
Scott: Someone really has to figure out a formula for good podcast promos because I mean while I hate them.
Rym: Well, I think the problem is when I used to listen to the radio there was never ever in the history of my listening to the radio ever an Advertisement on the radio that didn't sound lame.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: There has to be a way to make a radio.
Rym: There is you know you do you do what we do and we don't play promos anymore.
Rym: We just say hey, I listen to anime world order the podcast about anime and worlds.
Rym: Oh Put it in order.
Rym: Well, this is Monday.
Rym: I'll suit a pod.
Rym: is a good horror fantasy mostly horror fiction.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: See so much easier than a stupid promo.
Rym: Yeah they could have had this like a guy pretending to be HP Lovecraft telling a story about Cthulhu and then oh It's about a podcast but that would have been totally lame and it's only at a place in our podcast.
Scott: It's like ruin some of your podcast to help ours out.
Scott: Yeah, you ever discovered a podcast via a promo?
Rym: I have never listened to a promo and thought hey, I should listen to a show.
Rym: In fact, I did it once and then I you were sorely disappointed.
Scott: Well, I wasn't but it didn't last very long.
Rym: Every podcast I've been referred to it's because someone a podcast I trust said like hey I listen to blah not because they played the promo.
Rym: Yeah, and in fact there have been numerous promos I've heard.
Rym: that just steal my conviction to not listen to those podcasts.
Rym: They might be good in plenty of those.
Rym: Yeah, so what is dig doing right here with their podcast?
Rym: Number one dig has a massive community already built around it.
Rym: There are a lot of people who go to dig on a like hourly basis.
Scott: Yep, number two digs podcast directory is primarily about usefulness.
Scott: It's hey Are there any you know?
Scott: Cuz you go to dig you don't go to dig to vote on things or to make things more popular.
Scott: Some people do.
Rym: we forgot to talk about Yahoo podcasts, but they're not that useful.
Scott: Well, Yahoo podcast is really the same as pretty much.
Scott: Let's forget Yahoo podcast all the rest.
Scott: There are lots of podcast directories out there lots of them.
Scott: There's pod Nova Odeo Yahoo podcast, etc.
Scott: Etc, etc.
Scott: And all of them are basically the same goddamn thing with slight variations in interface Like a little bit of tagging or a little bit of this.
Rym: or they took away that you can listen to the shows live Whatever.
Scott: pretty much what most of them have in common is you can listen to the shows on those pages.
Scott: So it's for inept people who don't have mp3 players and don't know how to use or for people who are looking For a new podcast.
Rym: instead of subscribing going through all that you just listen to a snippet and if you like it you subscribe.
Scott: Yeah, that that is a good use of those sites, but there's so many of those sites and all of them have Just there's.
Scott: so I don't know.
Scott: They don't do any.
Scott: there's no reason to go to them.
Scott: Basically.
Rym: Yeah now dig Meanwhile has integrated all the useful functionality of pretty much every one of these sites and more.
Scott: Yeah, you go to like I was saying you go to dig not to vote for things But you go to dig to find new information and entertainment.
Scott: That is the purpose of dig.
Scott: It filters the information and entertainment provided by the world wide web into one site.
Scott: So you can find links to it all and dig.
Rym: does it with podcast fully integrated?
Rym: So there's a dig.
Rym: you can dig a podcast.
Rym: you can also within that podcast Dig individual episodes.
Rym: if you go to a podcast it lists all the episodes they've got out.
Rym: It also lists on the right sidebar the top 10 most dug episodes of that podcast Mm-hmm.
Scott: Now if you go to the front page of dig podcast, so what you're going to see is Basically the most popular podcasts in all categories which are pretty much all the dig podcasts.
Scott: dig nation is number two.
Scott: Wait, dig nation is number one.
Scott: Twit is number two DL.
Scott: that TV is number three Etc etc.
Scott: It's it's obviously hey, those are the podcast that would be popular in the dig community.
Scott: Duh, hey, but when you go to the subcategories Right now you start to see some action going on.
Scott: Oh, wow You know if you go to the gaming and hobby subcategory right now, not only is GeekNights there.
Scott: But so is GeekNights Tuesdays on the front page.
Rym: No, I gotta hand it to our listeners.
Rym: I've.
Rym: we found out about this dig podcast right away and Scott and I both went immediately on our own.
Rym: Well, I'd better submit GeekNights and we both were cock-blocked by the fact that our listeners had all already done it.
Scott: I know who it was because they fessed up in the forum.
Rym: Yeah, but other listeners What'd you do?
Rym: other listeners were like.
Rym: I tried to submit you but I guess you already were on top of that.
Scott: That's cuz.
Scott: our listeners are all hip internet people who are on top of that dig every minute.
Scott: Yeah kudos to you guys Losers who you know where we say some old news from last week and they go why?
Scott: what did that happen?
Scott: No, our people are on top of shit.
Scott: They know what's going on.
Scott: But now the other thing that makes it really useful Because I mean knowing what the most popular podcasts are in all categories is not so useful.
Scott: I mean, come on I don't need to see dig nation twit and DL TV, you know, I already know about those.
Scott: You're either listening or you're not.
Scott: at this point What you need to know are on the right side.
Scott: is that all the useful stuff.
Scott: the first thing it shows you Are the episodes recently dug by your friends?
Scott: So if one of your friends found a really awesome episode of some podcast like holy shit some podcast random podcast had an amazing episode.
Scott: You'll see that over there that your friend dug it and you should make friends with all the people that you know.
Scott: Use dig that you know because then you know if they like the same stuff as you and they dig something you'll find out about.
Rym: They're also really trying to foster this whole.
Rym: they want a community around podcast within dig.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So they're setting up I mean they set ups.
Rym: you can comment just like a dig article on every single individual episode of a podcast and on the podcast Itself, you know, I don't think you can comment.
Scott: you can comment on the podcast itself.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I wasn't able to when I wanted to earlier when I was fiddling with it.
Scott: Let me check it right now.
Scott: You talk about something.
Rym: well well Scott checks it out.
Rym: the one thing that I really want to bring up because I think this is probably the thing the one Factor aside from the fact that dig is already popular like beyond that that's going to make this dig podcast thing So amazing.
Rym: every podcast directory has the problem of how do you pick?
Rym: what podcasts are good and which ones aren't which ones are popular and which ones aren't and which one should be listened to.
Rym: and Some people try to do it manually by having people like editors pick them.
Rym: some people let you just vote raw.
Rym: Some people make you go through hoops to vote to try to prevent vote spam dig.
Rym: any logged in user can dig anything.
Rym: So podcasts are no exception.
Rym: if you dig a podcast it's dig count goes up by one.
Rym: It is dug is now listed under your dude.
Rym: Yeah, it says that you have dug this podcast and list all the people who have dug it.
Scott: If you are not an active user of dig meaning you don't log in Periodically at least every two weeks like let's say I make a dig account just to dig my podcast But then I'm not actually a dig user.
Scott: I don't use dig every day.
Scott: You know, I don't I don't.
Scott: what the hell Do I care about this site?
Scott: I just came to make my podcast more popular and now I'm gone.
Rym: Now what dig does is if you dig a podcast specifically if you are podcast episode Yeah, and you don't log in for two weeks day or use dig for two weeks.
Rym: It will take away your dig.
Rym: It'll keep it listed in your profile and everything but your dig will not count in terms of how popular that podcast is.
Rym: so if you want to spam podcast votes you have to Regularly maintain all of the accounts on dig you made and log into them all the time and be active on them.
Scott: You have to.
Scott: basically it only counts the digs for active real dig users.
Rym: No, it's not awesome It's not stupid about it.
Rym: So let's say I use dig and I don't log in for a month because I'm living in Germany for a month.
Rym: for some reason.
Rym: If I then come home and I log back into dig after it's all over as soon as I log in all the podcasts I dug that lost my vote automatically get my vote back because I came back to dig.
Scott: Yeah, it's actually pretty cool.
Scott: There's a plus and a minus to it.
Scott: The plus is that you don't have to keep digging stuff and you actually get a pretty good fair popularity measure.
Scott: that is difficult to scam.
Scott: the minus is that you're only finding out what Podcasts are the most popular in the dig community and not what podcasts are the most popular period but that is definitely digs goal In in pot in this podcast thing and dig in general.
Rym: dig wants its own community and it's it has its own community now.
Scott: So you should be in that community because that's where the action is.
Rym: So when they make like this podcast thing, they're made very specifically making it so anyone can use it.
Rym: I mean, it's beta now.
Rym: So you need an account.
Rym: even look at it, but eventually accounts are free.
Rym: Yeah, sign up like every other web and eventually it's just gonna be on the site.
Rym: You don't even need to log in to look at it, too But you have to be an active dig participant in order to have a say on did Mm-hmm, and that seems to be digs biggest strength.
Scott: Yep Now the two other.
Rym: yeah, we won't.
Scott: we don't need to talk about digs specifically now but the two other features of the Podcasting thing that I think really make it shine and make it useful for finding new podcasts or number one It shows you up and coming podcast.
Scott: So, you know, of course the front page is only gonna have the awesome stuff of all time But if something recently is like gaining a lot of ground down in the grassroots and it has a lot of digs Relative like it's getting digs at a rapid rate If not in great quantity.
Scott: You'll see it show up there and then you might find it and start digging it which will then cause it to come up and that's a thing a lot of other websites have not done.
Scott: is Provided some it's basically impossible for the podcast that starts small to get big.
Scott: It keeps the big guys up in the small guys down.
Scott: This allows the small guys to get up while keeping the big guys on top where they rightfully belong.
Rym: but yet at least so far it seems like the ones that get the up and coming are Ones that are actually good and up and coming and not iTunes where a lot of times ones that are listed as new or up and coming Not so much.
Scott: The other thing that I like that it does is if you click on a podcast It shows you on the right hand side If like.
Scott: if I go to the page for GeekNights on the right side You'll see the most popular episodes of GeekNights because when you find a new podcast you listen to what the most recent episode Which is good and bad.
Rym: I mean, sometimes you get the gold but sometimes you get like our throwaway Thursday.
Scott: Yeah, sometime you listen to the most recent episode.
Scott: Sometimes you might listen to the first episode.
Rym: this bit me with dragons landing because Multiple people were telling me to listen.
Rym: So I finally check out dragons landing right and it was kind of meh and I was like what.
Rym: that wasn't so good.
Rym: That was kind of boring.
Rym: and then Scott's like which episode did you listen to?
Rym: and I'm like, oh this one.
Rym: And it turned out that the one episode of all the episodes they had up that I listened to Happened to be a special episode with two guest hosts.
Rym: It wasn't a normal dragon.
Scott: Notice how when we don't have a normal GeekNights we say at the beginning of the episode This is not a normal GeekNights.
Scott: They didn't do that.
Scott: So Rym thought it was a normal dragons landing when it was actually other people doing dragons landing.
Scott: like the one time the movies You should see people did GeekNights, which once again was fantastic.
Scott: Awesome, but we had to put a disclaimer letting people know it was going on.
Scott: so they weren't confused.
Rym: How come ribbon Scott are British and Scott's a woman?
Rym: and what's going on?
Scott: Yeah but dig when you click on a podcast it shows you on the right hand side the most popular episodes of that podcast.
Scott: so You know this.
Scott: this is why this is so good is because number one if you find a new podcast You can listen to the best episode right away and you'll know if that's something you're gonna listen to or not based on one episode.
Scott: number two if there's some podcast out there that just Randomly had like one hit episode and is actually a terrible podcast for example terrible podcast X interviews Amazing person why I thought you're gonna mention a specific podcast.
Rym: I was ready to either defend it or I couldn't even think of one.
Scott: I tried, you know, then you'll know you'll go.
Scott: when you click on that podcast You'll say wait a minute.
Scott: This podcast is actually terrible.
Scott: They have one really popular episode and every other episode No one gives a shit about.
Scott: I'll listen to that one useful episode and never listen to this podcast again And that's a lot more useful information than any other podcast directory has ever given ever.
Rym: So If you like GeekNights and you use dig then dig us To at least once.
Rym: if you like GeekNights and you don't use dig use dig if you use if you listen to us But you don't like us and you use dig.
Rym: Well, I guess don't dig us Lol.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.