Rym: It's Tuesday November 28th.
Scott: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review Wii Sports.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So for the last several days when I come home from work every day I walk past Scott who was in the living room with the Wii moving it around in funny ways.
Rym: I've been up in my room going through the Infinite number of pieces of paper with various glyphs on them that I've accumulated over the last quarter of a century frying desperately to throw away the ones that I don't need and Somehow put them into a fashion of order that will be useful for the next quarter century.
Scott: I don't know what you're saying about this.
Scott: me sitting there playing the Wii Several days.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Meanwhile, it's been two days yesterday and today yesterday also last week.
Scott: They mean last week before vacation.
Rym: even then I would come home from work and you'd be there with the Wii.
Scott: What day was that?
Rym: Why the day last week?
Scott: I Only went to work one day last week.
Rym: Yeah, I went to work more than one day last week.
Scott: either way Today I wasn't I only I barely played it even.
Rym: What are you talking about?
Rym: You were downstairs playing the Wii while I was up here doing my files When you got home and I only did it we can go.
Rym: look it was In the door.
Rym: you came down said something gave me my edgy CD which is installing next to me right now.
Scott: I actually I burned the edgy CD.
Scott: We're up here a lot longer than you think Cuz.
Rym: then I went upstairs and before I even opened my file folder to continue looking at my pieces of paper.
Rym: I hear downstairs Whatever you're looking.
Scott: go look the Wii keeps a record of how long we've played.
Rym: I'm well aware.
Rym: That's why I don't I feel completely justified in making this argument because you'll go down and look You'll realize how long you actually played the Wii and you'll be quiet today less than an hour.
Scott: But anyway, I dad played in total a great deal of Zelda because well Zelda games take a great deal of playing.
Rym: Yeah, and also Wolfie Link.
Scott: Yeah, and I got to say that Compared the the product Wind Waker was a great Zelda.
Scott: That was the most recent one.
Scott: oh, he's the most recent console and not handheld one and It was good, but my major gripe with it was that it was too short.
Scott: not enough dungeons this game Way too many dungeons.
Rym: these minish cat pissed me off for a great number of reasons far beyond the fact that that wasn't a Console one.
Scott: So not really counting it?
Rym: Yeah, well see the thing is for me my DS and by extension the GBA have been my primary gaming console up until the Wii Mm-hmm.
Rym: Well unless you count counter-strike.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah No, but this Zelda I mean.
Scott: I don't know if it's fair to say too many dungeons because if you ask me there can't be too many dungeons Nothing would be better than just infinity dungeon.
Rym: Yeah I mean probably one of the greatest moments in my life is when I was playing Zelda for the SNES.
Rym: and there's those three Dungeons and the three things you got to get and you get them all and instead of the game ending it's up.
Rym: Well, you've got the three things now.
Rym: You've got to go to the eight other dungeons and do all this other stuff.
Scott: Yeah, ever since the SNES Zelda they've always followed this pattern of you know, do a few dungeons You're confined to a small area where you use basic skills and then as you get more and more abilities You can go to a larger and larger area and eventually you beat three dungeons.
Scott: Then maybe there's a fourth dungeon or something and as soon as you do that the game opens up and then there's like the seven Dungeons.
Rym: Yep, and even then you walk or the eight dungeon You're always walking past rocks that you could bomb if you just had a bomb There was a little bit bigger.
Rym: or if you had a hammer You could knock that little tiny sticking out of the way, even though really link could just jump over it or kick it.
Scott: Yeah, well Zelda 64 followed mostly the same pattern.
Scott: So did Wind Waker.
Scott: I just had fewer dungeons after the game opened up.
Rym: Yeah But then there's Minish Cap where there's three dungeons and I fully expected the game to open up and instead the game was over.
Scott: Yeah, I cried but Twilight Princess man I just got the game to open up.
Scott: today After more than almost it's got to be at least a day of playing.
Scott: if not it's a definitely more than 15 hours almost 20 and I just got the game to open up.
Scott: and Even if I didn't get the game to open up, there's so much shit I had to do still in the not opened up game.
Rym: Oh my god See.
Rym: now think of this.
Rym: think about the amount of real-life time You've spent versus what you have caused link to do riding his horse around being a wolf cause and all sorts of mischief changing the World in that time in the real world.
Rym: I succeeded in throwing away approximately 3,000 pieces of paper.
Rym: Yeah, many of them at my feet right now.
Scott: think about this.
Scott: I played so much right and so far I've caught one fish.
Scott: I just did fishing for the first time today.
Scott: a major part of the game the fishing.
Scott: I fished one fish.
Scott: So there's a lot to go in this game.
Rym: a major part of the game.
Rym: They can't be plot involved in the fishing.
Scott: No, but the fishing is like a major side game.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I always kind of hated those side games in Zelda games.
Scott: I'm a fan of the side games.
Scott: I like to beat all of them, you know, not super completely But some of them give you pieces of heart and I like to get all the heart container.
Rym: Yeah, that's fine.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I'm my favorite Zelda games are.
Rym: of course I haven't played all the way through Ocarina of Time and I've never played Majora's Mask or any you don't want to play.
Scott: I haven't even played all Majora's Mask.
Rym: I played it for any of the Gameboy ones except Minish Cap.
Scott: Yeah The original Gameboy one that you got to play.
Rym: Well, just no Zelda game since Zelda 2 has given me that sense of awe and fear when finding a new place.
Scott: Let's see Zelda 64 for sure.
Rym: Well, I didn't play that all the way through but SNES Zelda at no point was I afraid.
Scott: No, I actually was a little bit afraid playing Twilight Princess just once when I got caught outside in the dark and I didn't want to go back inside because I wanted to go into the town during the day and Time doesn't pass if you're inside the town.
Scott: So I was hanging outside at night.
Scott: It was dark There are monsters and I wanted the Sun to come up.
Scott: so I go back into the town during the day.
Rym: What a terrible night to have a curse.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah, let's move along.
Rym: So, uh, we could do the anime world order thing.
Rym: Let's news.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: Let's not do that.
Rym: We don't have any news music.
Scott: go get some.
Rym: I thought I just never found anything good that didn't sound cheesy or would violate copyright in an obvious way.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so I'm gonna talk about this Problem in quotes of people breaking their TVs and breaking their wiimote wrist straps or not Using their wiimote wrist straps.
Rym: I often don't use the remote wrist strap.
Scott: Sometimes I don't use it but most of the time I do use it.
Rym: Yeah, I only use it because it's not my wiimote.
Rym: once I own a wiimote There's not even gonna be a wrist strap on that mofo.
Scott: Yeah, but what if you you know what?
Rym: you know what?
Rym: I am confident in mind the minimal level of dexterity and Consciousness that I have to not drop a wiimote or throw it against the wall or lose my grip on it somehow.
Scott: Yeah, see I'm more worried about the not so much worried about the wiimote breaking But as in other things breaking around if the wiimote gets thrown at them, I'm not gonna throw a wiimote.
Rym: In fact, the only time a controller has ever in my life left My hand was through my own volition When I was playing a game that I will not name for the NES a long time ago and I threw the controller at the TV.
Rym: It bounced off the TV and hit me in the foot.
Scott: Yeah, but this you know, this thing is one-handed.
Scott: it doesn't have like a Handles in it.
Scott: You don't have two hands on.
Scott: it could happen and it is happening to a lot of idiots out there.
Scott: Yeah People aren't using the whisk wrist strap and they're throwing the wiimotes into their TVs People are breaking the wrist strap.
Scott: Obviously if your wrist strap breaks is because you did not apply it properly.
Scott: You didn't slide that little piece of plastic down and you're putting strain on the little string instead of putting strain on the wrist strap.
Rym: No, I could see it breaking also from people using something I like to call probably the most of it.
Rym: This is like the underlying theme of tank police one of my favorite things.
Rym: It's called excessive force.
Scott: Yes, if you there was a video of a guy.
Scott: There was a video of a guy because it started out with just pictures.
Scott: people are like, oh you're faking it.
Scott: Then there was a video of a guy doing we bowling and he threw the wiimote like against the wall.
Scott: But he was we bowling.
Scott: if you watch again, you see just how hard this guy is swinging his arm.
Scott: You don't need to swing your arm that hard.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In fact when I was playing we golf For a lot of the things I didn't bring my arms all the way up and swing like I was playing golf.
Rym: I held it straight down and did this kind of wrist emotion.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's not really.
Scott: It's really not necessary To swing it so hard that it could possibly break.
Scott: if we're swinging it that hard You're swinging it harder than is possibly necessary.
Scott: You can get the maximum power in the game without swinging it with that much force and we're not saying you don't you know?
Rym: Get into it.
Rym: It's really fun when you're boxing or especially when you're playing tennis To kind of get into it and act like it's a real sport you're playing and that's really cool.
Rym: In fact, you probably should do that to get the most enjoyment out of it.
Rym: But you don't need to swing your arm as hard as possible.
Rym: You don't need to hyperextend your elbow.
Scott: Yeah Necessary in fact dangerous.
Rym: swinging something that hard when there's nothing in your hand to really be swinging That has weight is a great way to really hurt yourself.
Scott: Yeah, and actually someone went and looked.
Scott: you know All that annoying health and safety stuff that Nintendo's been putting on their products for a while.
Scott: Yeah, well someone actually went and read that stuff to see what it says about this issue.
Scott: And it says hold the wiimote firmly and do not let go Even while wearing the wrist strap.
Scott: make sure you don't let go of the Wii remote during gameplay and do not use excessive motion For example in Wii Sports bowling.
Scott: the proper way to let go of the ball while bowling is to release the B button on the Wii remote.
Scott: Do not let go of the Wii remote itself.
Scott: If you are having so much fun that you start perspiring take a moment to dry your hands.
Scott: If you use excessive motion and let go of the Wii remote the wrist strap may break and you could lose control of the Wii Remote.
Scott: this could injure people nearby or cause damage to other objects.
Rym: Truer words have never been written into clay or stone.
Scott: So a lot of people, you know, because this is happening a lot A lot of people are saying oh there's something wrong with the Wii remotes.
Scott: The wrist straps are cheap, etc, etc, etc.
Scott: No, there's just a lot of idiots out there.
Scott: And if you break your Wii remote because you used it improperly or your TV breaks.
Scott: I have no pity for you.
Rym: It's like that guy on dig a while ago who broke his fat DS.
Rym: Yeah, I can't imagine breaking my fat DS and I have dropped it onto hard concrete more than once.
Scott: Yeah, if you if your stuff breaks and other people have the same stuff doesn't have the same problem It's your fault and I don't feel sorry for you
Rym: Yeah, like certain people who have slowly but surely bent our banana chairs backward about 20 degrees from what they were when we bought Them.
Scott: Yeah, we got to go find some higher quality banana chairs.
Rym: No, well, the thing is we probably should have warned everyone that the banana chairs they say very specifically you can't weigh more than 175 pounds.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, we bought them for us cuz we're lanky dudes.
Rym: They're made for kids guys.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: What are the news is out there?
Rym: Well this I don't even know who's doing it.
Rym: I don't really care cuz I'm not gonna talk about the actual site because I could care.
Rym: I couldn't care less about the site But some people put together.
Rym: help me.
Rym: Am I I?
Rym: you know me we there's a lot of people using the.
Rym: you know Anytime you have an e sound put two eyes in and make it a wee thing or try to make it a wee thing.
Rym: And now that there's gonna be a web browser in the Wii as soon as they actually get that working and you can do it Without hacks, I think we're gonna see a trend of a lot of websites either Making well having a website specifically designed for use on the Wii Most often probably to provide something another website provides only in a we optimize fashion or else Content specifically for the Wii from companies.
Rym: Maybe they'll have you pay for it.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah I really hope they open it up to let a lot more people make me channel we channels because as it is There's not enough of those.
Rym: Yeah Well, I imagine we're gonna see a lot of we channels and days to come weeks to come and months to come.
Rym: But the web browser itself is gonna be a lot because I helped me is actually kind of this cool concept where they want to make this wiki kind of like game facts, but more of a Optimized.
Rym: so from the Wii if you need help playing a game You pause the game go into this website and you can just kind of navigate through this wiki.
Scott: That sounds you know, that's something really good because it's always annoying.
Scott: You know, you got a. you're having a problem in a video game.
Scott: You need some help.
Scott: You don't want to pay money to call the helpline.
Scott: You don't want to call your friend and have them spoil the game or laugh at you.
Scott: You don't want anyone to know you're looking and you don't to pay for the ripoff strategy guys.
Rym: Well, obviously you use some sort of anonymizer and secretly go to game facts.
Scott: exactly.
Scott: But you got to go upstairs or get a computer drag it over pause your game go to game facts search.
Scott: You know, it's annoying.
Scott: be a lot cooler.
Scott: If you just you're playing the Wii you switch over to the web browser Check game facts without getting up and go back.
Scott: make gamers a lot lazier a lot fatter.
Rym: Yep, granted my policy with game facts is very simple.
Rym: I rarely use game facts during a game But I often use it after I beat a game to find all the bullshit that wasn't worth finding.
Rym: Well, I use ham Crystal Chronicles and all the bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, I use game facts in three different ways.
Scott: the first way I use it is if an instruction manual is not complete or There's like some technique.
Scott: I'm supposed to know for a video game Usually a fighting game to learn special moves or you know like this I don't know how to play the game and I need the rules of the game, you know It's also good for Atari games because the manual doesn't exist anymore.
Scott: Yep Yeah And you want to know like what button does what or if it's possible to do something or if you do something in a game?
Scott: You're not sure how you did it.
Scott: You can look that up.
Scott: the second way I use game facts is if I am stuck somewhere and it is arbitrarily Stupid stuck like no amount of thinking will get me out of it.
Scott: It's a. it's a knowledge problem.
Scott: Like I do not know what I need to do next.
Scott: The game is a bad game.
Scott: it pretty much.
Scott: it only happens in bad games and most of the time I'll just stop playing the game if it happens.
Scott: But sometimes I might want to give it a little go especially if it's early.
Scott: so I'll go on game facts and say alright How do I get past this really dumb part of the game?
Scott: that's impossible.
Scott: and The third time I'll use game facts is if I already beat a game and want to know where some secret is.
Scott: or Like I don't know Maybe it'll be a part of the game where it says like collect the ten jammies and I found nine of the jammies and one Of them is still missing and it's a hide-and-seek thing and I don't really feel like looking around everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, or I've already looked everywhere and I haven't found the last gem.
Scott: so I'll just go to game.
Rym: But in terms of actually going to game facts I'll play and I'll only go to game facts if I get frustrated enough to stop playing the game.
Rym: Yes at that point I'm going up to my room anyway to be pissed off about the game for a while in which case I'm very likely to be On my computer complaining to someone about the game in which case there's a Firefox tab going to game facts.
Scott: But I do not condone the use of strategy guides and facts and things to actually play games without having to you know play the game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like hey, I invented this robot.
Scott: What does it do?
Scott: It plays quake 2 and beats the whole game perfectly.
Scott: look well, that's great.
Rym: See granted sometimes strategy guys are cool like back in the day when Nintendo released those Crazy strategy guides for like Final Fantasy 1
Scott: Mario 3 the cardboard one was the best
Rym: because those were really actually Cool had a lot of neat stuff in and that had nothing to do with the game at all.
Scott: Yep, that was good stuff.
Rym: and the Final Fantasy 1 one is to this day.
Rym: I know where almost every major treasure is in that game like down to the chest or at least the room and I could pretty much play Final Fantasy 1 half with my eyes closed.
Scott: That's great.
Scott: Yeah, that's a real.
Scott: I think there's really no point in a strategy like they try to sell you the strategy guide with the game And that just really I don't like it.
Rym: Yeah That's a bad thing of course.
Rym: now games are designed a lot of them where you kind of need the strategy guide.
Scott: It's like looking at the answers to a crossword puzzle and then just filling it in.
Rym: What about the games where they want you to buy the strategy guide and there's a lot of arbitrary stuff You're really never gonna figure out.
Scott: I think there's a lot of companies that still they do that on purpose and like in a partnership with the strategy guide companies.
Scott: They put secrets in the game that you can't possibly know about without the strategy guide Just to sell you a strategy guide and make more money.
Rym: Yeah like to get the special character.
Rym: you have to go into this room and play this arbitrary sequence on the piano that you could have found out if you paid attention to what the nine cats in the world that you can't get to anymore because it was Destroyed said and then remember the correct order based on their color because they were all the colors of the rainbow But you might not have found all the cats now.
Rym: It's too late.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That was an oddly specific example.
Scott: I came up with Yeah, see usually though It's something arbitrary like if you go into this room and play this exact sequence on the piano That you have no way of possibly knowing without the strategy guy.
Rym: I was thinking of Final Fantasy 7.
Rym: What were you thinking of?
Rym: Arbitrariness, oh, okay.
Rym: There's the thing in Final Fantasy 7 with the piano.
Rym: Oh, of course, then there's the thing in Castlevania DS with the piano.
Scott: I'm gonna do anything.
Rym: I'm gonna save you all a lot of trouble.
Rym: that piano room in Castlevania DS.
Rym: Just get the fuck out of there.
Rym: Don't worry about it doesn't do anything.
Rym: There is nothing to be found in that room at all.
Scott: bad guys This is occasional bad guys there.
Rym: Yeah, there's like two succubuses flying in the air.
Scott: So just hit him with your whip and move on.
Rym: Yeah, you don't have a whip.
Rym: you might unless you're playing Julius mode Hit him with your axe spear sword, whatever you're you and I got the death scythe.
Rym: I'm all set in that game.
Rym: I'm playing through hard mode and I still just mow through the bosses without even blinking.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not sure what weapon I had.
Scott: Maybe I had the death scythe.
Rym: It's the most powerful weapon in the game.
Rym: you had to trade a boss's soul and upgrade the strongest acts to these super strongest acts.
Scott: Yeah, I think I might have done that.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Scott: Yeah anyway Things of the day Man, I love this thing of the day so much Really?
Scott: Really?
Rym: Which one?
Rym: Oh, I remember which one you're doing.
Rym: You showed this to me about five minutes ago.
Rym: Yep, actually more like a half hour ago because we just did the first half of the show, but I digress.
Scott: All right Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well then I'll start with mine cuz mine is one we related and two not quite as good as yours, but very interesting.
Rym: So there are guys and we know them and they're a lot like the guy in my thing of the day.
Rym: You see this is GeekNights and we're geeks and a lot of our listeners are geeks and some of our listeners are nerds And I think this guy is probably the epitome of not Nintendo geek not video game geek But Nintendo slash video game nerd.
Rym: Oh this guy was waiting in line to get a Wii and he hadn't slept in five days and He admits that I think he was taking demerol and I really can't explain.
Rym: you just need to watch this guy.
Scott: good, I've seen guys like this at conventions and comic book stores at all sorts of Nerdly events of sorts and he is not out of the ordinary But he is scary.
Scott: and there are others like him.
Scott: beware lately I've been pretty much.
Scott: I've been really into these small-time RPGs, you know these I Don't know how to explain them but well, you don't play him or anything.
Scott: I haven't played him yet.
Scott: No, I think well, I played kobolds at my baby.
Scott: I think that counts as one.
Scott: but you know that these little tiny RPGs that come in really small books They have really focused like settings, you know It'll be like this is an RPG where you're a bunch of guys who do this specific kind of thing, you know They're not the kind of RPGs that you can have vast Multi-session campaigns with there, you know one time at a convention funfests anyway most of these RPGs have something in common and that is the character sheets are really well designed and they kind of fit the game and They usually have all sorts of neat stuff on them and they're actually sort of exciting and fun to look at.
Scott: so one guy who knows this made up a little contest and the contact.
Scott: the contest is called reverse engineer and The way the contest works is he gave people two weeks to make a character sheet for a game that doesn't exist and send it in and a lot of people made character sheets and sent them in.
Scott: and It's pretty cool because you can go to this website and look at a bunch of character sheets That were just made for games that don't exist.
Scott: Some of them are kind of crazy.
Scott: Some of them aren't so crazy.
Scott: Some of them are obviously good.
Scott: Some of them are not so good.
Scott: The best one is one created by Martin O'Leary.
Scott: So if you go to this website, just look on the left hand side There's a frame with a bunch of names in it.
Scott: find the name Martin O'Leary and click on it and it'll bring you to what?
Scott: I say is the best character sheet of the lot.
Rym: now he can describe it But you're really better off seeing this bad boy.
Scott: All I can say is the top of the character sheet says in Soviet Russia character sheet designs you Those stats at the bottom right now.
Scott: He then gave people two weeks to take one of the character sheets and make a game based on the character sheet.
Rym: You know reverse engineering the character sheet exactly.
Scott: So, you know not the same person who made the character sheet made the game, you know.
Scott: So if I made a character sheet someone else would make the game for it.
Scott: So it's kind of weird.
Scott: the guy who took this awesome character sheet made by Martin O'Leary His name was Nathan D Pauletta and the game he made was called is called Vesna thaw and the sub the subtitle is post apocalyptic community building in a post Soviet world.
Scott: Let me tell you this is an awesome game and it is Creative Commons license.
Scott: I didn't actually read all the rules of the game So it might not be a playable game, but it from what I have read of the rules It isn't entertaining to read the rules.
Rym: It is probably a lot like Hall which is pretty much the epitome of games that you read the rule book and laugh about.
Rym: But God help your soul if you decide to try and play.
Scott: I think this one might be playable one time.
Rym: I Highly doubt that Kobolds ate.
Rym: my baby is barely playable.
Scott: even once it's playable once Barely, it's as long as you have new people every time it's played.
Rym: I'll take.
Rym: my baby is able to keep my attention for approximately six minutes and that includes character creation.
Scott: You just don't want it.
Rym: Maybe just that you shouldn't be running Kobolds ate my baby.
Rym: Yeah, anyway That was a bad experience.
Scott: You know you guys didn't exactly help me out.
Scott: We tried we tried and you were like you were trying to ruin the game for the start.
Rym: What do you did if you've been trying to ruin the game?
Rym: is you know?
Rym: Interacting with the world in a realistic cobalt way and trying to do things like I see a chicken I attacked the chicken.
Rym: Yeah, we were trying to ruin it.
Rym: whoa the DM can't deal with it.
Rym: if I attack the chicken What do we do now?
Scott: I was dealing with it.
Scott: Just fun.
Rym: Yeah by killing us.
Rym: Yeah, I try to take the chicken you die.
Scott: What that's what says in the book.
Rym: I will say it wasn't the worst role-playing experience of my life.
Rym: that falls squarely on the time I tried to DM a system that my friend can had written.
Rym: Oh God The system wasn't done yet and they were playing with it a lot and I didn't understand the system and didn't read it very much.
Rym: and He had also provided me with a basic plot and a bunch of characters and I kind of just manhandled them all together And it was without question the worst role-playing the world has ever seen.
Rym: it was awesome.
Scott: I'm gonna try to play inspectors at some point in the future and we'll see how it goes.
Rym: Yeah, we will.
Scott: Yeah, either way.
Scott: This is an awesome website.
Scott: There's a lot of funny character sheets.
Scott: It will entertain you for a long time.
Rym: if you are a fan of RPGs And if you've maxed out your Vodak score.
Scott: well Yeah, if you max out the Vodak you are the win.
Rym: and if you don't know what Vodak is welcome to the internet Actually, no, cuz that's kind of an obscure and stupid thing.
Rym: So don't worry if you don't know what Vodak is.
Rym: In fact, if you don't know what Vodak is or why that's funny.
Rym: You're probably a better person than I am.
Scott: I'm gonna search for Vodak on Google.
Rym: It's really right now real-time Live GeekNights.
Rym: I got to keep talking.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: No, you'll if you search on Google, you'll you'll get it really.
Scott: yes, I've never searched for that because the The top link is the urban dictionary which will tell you what Vodak is and it correctly tells you what Vodak is.
Rym: You know, it's sad and scary that I've been not only on the internet long enough But reading Fark long enough to where I've seen the birth Rise Fall and death of numerous fart cliches in the course of my time here.
Rym: the haha guy appeared while I was a Farker.
Scott: Okay, wait, there are three definitions for Vodak free.
Scott: Yep The first one is I'll let everyone in on what Vodak is.
Scott: All right, I'll give it away.
Scott: The first definition for Vodak according to the urban dictionary, which is the only dictionary in which you will find Vodak Vodka as spelled after consuming insufficient quantities to further proof that even the most idiotic brain fart can become a meme.
Scott: and three Leetness incarnate Vodak plus God Wow, yep.
Rym: Anyway today we decided because we haven't been role-playing a lot lately though You will have quite a number of role-playing and Dungeons & Dragons Centric Tuesdays to come as Starting this weekend.
Rym: We are doing something we haven't done since college.
Rym: We are getting the group back together and running a gigantic monthly D&D campaign The likes of which we haven't seen since well college.
Scott: We'll see how this work granted.
Rym: It's not like college where we played every weekend.
Rym: Yeah sort of out of habit Yeah, but at the same time we're kind of getting a fresh start.
Rym: We're trying a lot of new things.
Rym: We're bringing back some things that we've kind of lost sight of over the years and I think this is gonna be a great time.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely beats a change which is what I'm looking for.
Rym: Well, you're all gonna get the play-by-play of us getting back into role-playing after a couple year hiatus.
Rym: I mean not counting our forum games and all that but regular in-person D&D sessions with something that we haven't had in our D&D For pretty much since I was in high school The table Oh Noah's.
Rym: yeah, we're gonna play around a table instead of lounging all around a room.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah, but today since this will probably be the last chance.
Rym: We'll get to talk about it for a while We're gonna talk about the Wii and review a Wii game.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Well we game we gonna review.
Rym: Well, we could review excite truck, but there's not much to say other than drive a truck really fast And the controls are pretty cool.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'll go play some after the week to the show.
Rym: I'd have to join you.
Scott: It's 10/11.
Rym: Yeah, it's 10/11 for those of you who listen to GeekNights time-shifted Which is everyone in the world except when Alex or Emily is in the house listening to us while we're doing 10 11 p.m So yeah, so it's a GeekNights for sure.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: That's 22 11 for you 24 hour clock people.
Rym: Oh Fancy.
Rym: So we're gonna review probably the most basic game for the Wii.
Scott: wait I think you don't need to say it cuz people guessed already.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna review the me system.
Scott: Oh Oh Yeah, these are pretty fun.
Scott: People can't get enough of making them.
Rym: Yeah, even Stephen Colbert is all about the Mies.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: No, we're gonna talk about Wii Sports.
Rym: It's a good thing We're not talking about the Mies.
Rym: cuz I got a fucking rant about one thing that really you can't get a unibrow.
Rym: No, I can't get a unibrow, but I can deal with that.
Rym: You see I made my me.
Rym: anyone who shared the friend code with us might see my me.
Rym: Oh, right My me looks in fact a lot like me like, you know Some people their me looks kind of like him.
Rym: some people's little off some people's really good.
Rym: My me is the spitting image of me.
Rym: It's other than the fact that I don't wear purple shirts and my stomach isn't round like that But no one's stomach is right.
Rym: Well some people have one person one man in all the world.
Rym: Yeah, we won't say his name.
Rym: Yeah, so now for those of you who know me I used to have a unibrow and a Rather austere and somewhat large mustache a mustache moustache In fact, my dad waxed his a couple times.
Rym: I could have waxed mine.
Rym: I could have easily grown my mustache to the point that I could have waxed it.
Rym: It grows back in about a week That's right.
Rym: But I decided partly due to something that our friend Yuko and our friend Emily drew on the fridge to make classic Rym with the unibrow and the mustache.
Rym: and The easiest way to do this I thought would be to you know Make a look a copy my me and just change those two parameters.
Rym: You can't copy a me.
Rym: Furthermore if you think you're smart and you want to be clever and you think oh, I'll copy my me to the wiimote I'll edit the one in the plaza change its name and everything and then bring the other one back.
Rym: No Nintendo is all about not letting you do that.
Rym: It knows that it's the same me and it overwrites the me you've got in the plaza.
Scott: Yeah, it was kind of annoying.
Rym: me's have some sort of hidden internal identifier that you can't change or get rid of.
Rym: Yeah, so be warned.
Rym: Anyway, no, we're talking about Wii Sports.
Scott: All right, she just go to the sports down in a row.
Rym: I think we should.
Rym: we'll start with tennis because that's the simplest Wii Sport and Probably the easiest one to review.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's also one I suck at.
Rym: apparently I'll give it a six or seven out of ten.
Scott: Yeah, it sounds about right.
Scott: I mean the main problem with tennis is that you know Granted none of the Wii Sports are going to be as full as say, you know a real like Mario tennis.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's a very simplified dumbed-down version of tennis.
Scott: The thing is it is dumbed down more than any of the other games.
Rym: well, the thing you got to remember our Wii Sports is that it is really a tech demo and Something to make the Wii more.
Rym: I guess you feel better about buying it because it comes with his game.
Scott: Well also it's to help you learn to use the wiimote.
Scott: Yes comfortable with it.
Rym: And of course it uses the me's.
Rym: It's the only game that uses the me's so far.
Rym: So otherwise the me's wouldn't have felt so useful.
Scott: No, they would have been kind of silly without Wii Sports.
Scott: It actually makes me sports a lot of fun to see all the me's in there Like my dad gets up to bat in baseball.
Scott: It's pretty hilarious.
Rym: Or Harris is in the background talking to classic Brian.
Scott: Yeah No, but tennis okay the tennis game basically the ball.
Scott: it comes at you.
Scott: you
Scott: swing
Scott: the wiimote you hit the ball
Scott: Continue now
Rym: remember
Scott: you don't
Rym: control the dudes.
Rym: It's doubles and there's two guys that you said.
Rym: you don't control the dudes You just control the swing and the whole game is very simply Timing your swing to hit the ball and Hitting the ball in the right direction to make it harder for the other person to hit the ball and also getting the ball.
Scott: You know in the keeping it in the court, you don't want to hit it out into the stand.
Rym: I think that falls under hitting it in the right direction.
Rym: Yeah captain out of the USS out.
Scott: Yeah, I am captain out.
Scott: I just tried to do the tennis training mode where you know, you practice your tennis skills.
Scott: Yeah And the first mode is this girl hits a ball to your side and all you have to do is hit it back.
Scott: and I was Able to hit six in a row and that was my record most of the time.
Scott: I couldn't hit the first one bag.
Rym: See, I'll tell you right now what your problem is with getting it out because how you hit the ball is not as Intense or important as say bowling but in terms of actually, you know hit it to the left hit it to the right hit it up a little bit hit it down the wiimote nose and You were hitting it to the left when your guy was already to the left and that's why it went out of bounds.
Scott: I keep hitting it way to the left.
Scott: I can't seem to hit it straight.
Scott: It's just like in bowling.
Scott: I can't bowl straight.
Rym: I think you need to strengthen your wrists.
Scott: No, it's like I'm hold.
Scott: It's not a man It's a matter of too strong wrist.
Scott: I can't.
Rym: I'm trying to do less wrist action not more but you need a strong wrist to hold your wrist ready while doing something.
Scott: I am I'm holding it dead steady, but I don't know.
Rym: Well, apparently you're not.
Scott: I don't know what it is I don't know.
Scott: I'll have to do it slow I think the other thing is I'm trying to do stuff too quick and I could do it slower with the same effect.
Rym: Yeah, yeah Now the thing is like all.
Rym: we are early.
Rym: we we sports type games.
Rym: you can play it two ways.
Rym: You can stand there and swing it like you're swinging a tennis racket Or you can just kind of twitch your hand and just kind of know what gestures make it go.
Scott: Yeah, you can do the toolbox.
Rym: now You can do the toolbox and the game works just fine.
Rym: But the boat the best way to enjoy this game is to get four people standing your living room and get really into it.
Scott: It's really the problem I have with we.
Scott: tennis is two things.
Scott: number one They should have let you move your we guy around with the nunchuck thing instead of having a move automatically.
Rym: That might have made the game a little too complex.
Scott: I don't think it would have made it too complex for this early.
Rym: So I'm sure there's going to be a tennis game that does that.
Scott: I'm sure there is going to be almost certainly Mario tennis most likely but or Virtua tennis if they make that for the week, but you know, it would.
Scott: it would still been a dumbed-down tennis.
Scott: It would have just been you know worth playing more than a few times.
Rym: I don't know because I find the tennis really fun.
Scott: Yeah, the other problem I have with the tennis the bigger problem is actually that you can't play singles.
Scott: It's doubles only.
Rym: so even if you play one-on-one it gives you two of the same guy on your side Which is kind of cool still because now you have this thing of do I hit with the front guy or the back guy?
Rym: And that's a very important strategic decision it is.
Scott: but at the same time I'd like to play singles, you know I don't want to have two guys there.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I'm not asking much of Wii Sports cuz it was free.
Scott: Yeah, I don't as much of it either but you know the the time comparing.
Scott: if you compare the sports to each other Tennis is not the best one.
Rym: No However, it is the quickest one the easiest one to get into the easiest one to enjoy and it requires the least effort or care.
Scott: Yeah, that is for sure.
Scott: You know.
Scott: if you just want to pick up the Wii swing it around for a few minutes and put it back Tennis is your.
Scott: tennis is what you're going for.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I really like the tennis.
Scott: All right What comes after the tennis?
Scott: Well, that would be baseball.
Scott: Oh the baseball.
Scott: see the thing with the baseball right is the hitting is actually a whole lot of fun, but the pitching while Fun, it doesn't use the wiimote as much as it could now in
Rym: fact The pitching instead of what you might expect where you swing the wiimote to the left or right to put a curve on the ball Or any of that.
Rym: it's mostly you swing it and that just initiates the pitch and before you swing You can hit on the direction pad up down left to right to say which direction you want the ball to go and you can Kind of do it behind your back like you're holding a baseball because when you hit it, it rumbles a little to say Yeah, I got your hit.
Rym: I know you've set your kind of pitch and then while you pitch you either don't hold any buttons hold a hold B or hold a and B and each of those combinations throws a different kind of pitch.
Scott: so there are four kinds of pitches you can throw and you set where the pitch where you're trying to throw it before you throw and Then when you swing the wiimote All you're really doing is saying how hard you want to pitch it If you want to throw a slow ball or a fastball
Rym: and I haven't noticed much difference no matter how hard or slow I move it.
Scott: Well, no pretty I've noticed a difference.
Scott: I'm able to throw like a slow medium and fast pitches pretty much, you know It's either 60 miles an hour 80 or 90 something.
Rym: now The batting is a lot more fun, even though it's not nearly as difficult as you might expect.
Scott: Yeah, the batting pretty much all there is to the batting is you either don't swing because the pitch is a ball and you don't Want to strike out.
Rym: though be warned.
Rym: The strike zone is pretty big.
Scott: It is a pretty big strike zone.
Scott: or you swing at the right time in order to get a hit.
Scott: If you swing at the wrong time, you're gonna hit it foul or get a kind of like the old baseball simulator games.
Scott: Yeah, so it's swing the bat with the right, you know.
Scott: Well, you can actually swing the bat slowly to get you know or take or faster to get more power on it.
Rym: yeah, and you can also.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that if you give it kind of a Upward tilt like if you're trying to hit a real home run at the end It seems that I get more home runs when I do that.
Rym: Yeah, but I can't say if the game knows or not.
Scott: I don't know that for sure, but if you swing the bat at the right time and you swing it quickly enough That's how you get the big hits.
Rym: now The timing to hit is actually very difficult to get right especially when the pitcher can change.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if someone if you just play the training mode where they throw you nice easy pitches over and over again You can learn to hit the ball.
Scott: But as soon as you play against a real person they keep throwing all sorts of different pitches different speeds And you know you have no idea what they're throwing.
Scott: It gets very difficult and the pitchers really have an advantage and the games are very low.
Scott: scoring.
Rym: Yeah, the game we just played a little while ago.
Rym: I got up by one Crazily with a home run and then a little while later Scott got up by one with two runs.
Rym: and other than that It was mostly strikeouts.
Scott: Yeah, mostly strikeouts a lot of ground outs.
Scott: because if you yeah, and then if you don't hit a foul ball someone in the field if it's not like a big hit someone in the field is gonna touch the ball and then you're out because There's no fielding.
Scott: and I don't I don't think that's a problem.
Scott: It was just pitching and hitting.
Scott: you don't need fielding.
Scott: That would be too difficult with the wiimote in this kind of game.
Rym: Yeah, I'd give the game again a six or seven.
Scott: Yeah, I think I like it more than the tennis But at the same time it's not as good as some of the other Wii Sports games.
Rym: Yeah But it's a tech demo kind of gives the positive.
Rym: the one nice thing is that when you're standing there ready to bat and you Move the wiimote the bat moves pretty much perfectly on your guy.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you know when I play actual baseball, you know, I like to you know We'll do a little shake the bat around up near the back of my head, you know And I can do that with the wiimote.
Rym: and that makes me feel really comfortable because it's a lot more like real batting plus I gotta say and as silly as it sounds having those Mies makes it so much more fun.
Rym: yeah, because Scott Johnson hit a home run and Our friend Yuko saved me by catching a ball and putting Scott I gotta say the Mies have the best effect in baseball because even though you're playing only two people are playing.
Scott: Let's let's say I'm playing Rym That means I'm the pitcher and he's the pitcher and we're both at the top of our respective lineups.
Scott: But all the other Mies that are on our system fill out the rest of the playing field.
Scott: You know, it's.
Scott: it's fun to see your friends come up to bat.
Rym: So Emily or James or Lisa Harris will come up.
Scott: It's like my dad will be on second and then you know friend James.
Scott: It's a home run and brings him in.
Scott: It's good stuff.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, so moving right along I guess we could hit up on golf Which I really like.
Scott: the golf actually is one of the better Wii games because it's it's a lot more of an actual game.
Scott: I'm not good at it.
Scott: But at the same time it's it's.
Scott: it's actually pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, it's basically a straight-up game where you can choose between you know, a driver and iron a wedge and a putter Mm-hmm, and it shows a little mini-map where you can see and this is the real thing I think is really neat.
Rym: you can point which direction you want to go and it shows a mini-map.
Rym: It shows the direction of the wind relative to where you're about to hit and it shows the line extending from your character Over this mini-map and it'll have like white dot white dot white dot yellow diamond.
Rym: Now when you swing and you can do as many practice swings as you want that don't do anything Like you're standing next to the tee not swinging at the ball.
Rym: it has a power bar above you that goes white dot white dot white dot diamond and However hard you swing determines a little power bar that shows how hard you're gonna hit it and say you get the little blue Power bar to go up two of the white dots then the ball is gonna land just at the second dot
Scott: Pretty close to it.
Scott: It's not exact.
Scott: There's a lot of other factors that come into it.
Scott: And wind and speed.
Rym: remember I'm talking about the first land before it bounces.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, and if there's no wind for which is Craig This is almost always wind and you get exactly two dots.
Rym: It'll land with the first bounce at exactly two dots.
Scott: Yeah about I mean, there's some other factors that come into it.
Scott: Like if you use the the driver, the ball is sort of more likely to keep going, you know.
Scott: And if you use the iron, it probably just comes and plops down.
Scott: it matters a little bit.
Rym: But yeah Well, I was at the first bounce will be exactly there unless there's wind.
Scott: Yeah, if you do it exactly right That's what I said.
Scott: It's never actually lands exactly there.
Rym: That's because there's usually wind.
Scott: Yeah, but it's a very good Way to you know that you know how hard to swing without actually having to gauge it.
Rym: Now the cool thing is if you swing too hard, you can send the ball a lot further But it'll hook or slice and sometimes it won't either and you you can't really control that.
Rym: But you can often use that to your advantage to hit the ball a lot further than you needed to, you know Or hope for a slice and aim in the wrong direction and just hit it really hard.
Rym: And if you time it right and you get it right and all the luck's with you You might get the ball way farther than you could have by playing correctly.
Scott: Yeah on some of the simpler holes that actually is a really good tactic is to just freakin.
Scott: who cares about you know Screwing it over and going way off the meter freaking.
Scott: hit the ball as hard as you can.
Scott: It'll get farther You'll.
Scott: you'll maybe save a stroke but on the harder holes if you don't hit it exactly, right?
Scott: It's going out of bounds It's going in the water.
Scott: It's going in the sand and that's not gonna be good.
Scott: That's gonna be real bad.
Rym: Yeah captain out of bounds.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The one thing I do like about the golf is how if you land in the sand or in the rough and then you like Try to use the driver It actually brings down the maximum power on the meter so that you can't hit it very hard without getting the you know The slice in the hook.
Scott: so it actually prevents people for doing silly stuff.
Scott: that happens in a lot of other golf games Like using the driver to hit out of a sand trap all the way to the hole.
Scott: You know, it actually makes landing on the fairway in the green pretty essential to getting a good score.
Rym: It's overall a really good golf game for what it is.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you compare it to something like Golf for the NES or golf for the Atari.
Scott: It's actually a better game than that.
Scott: Yeah It's not as good as a game as say Microsoft Golf or something like that.
Rym: But you know, what is for a Wii sport game?
Rym: I'd give it an 8.
Rym: I really enjoy it a lot.
Scott: Yeah, the golf is definitely I'd say it's equal to the boxing as the second best out of the boxes.
Rym: Yeah, so I guess we should get to your favorite game the game that you kick ass at the bowling.
Rym: Oh the bowling even though I beat you.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I just suck that game real hard.
Scott: Yeah, see is the thing.
Scott: the bowling is perhaps the greatest game in Wii Sports in that it does not dumb down the game of Bowling at all because bowling is already dumb enough that you don't need to dumb it down Even to Wii Sports.
Rym: It's pretty much straight-up bowling.
Scott: Yeah, you get it's scores exactly like real bowling.
Scott: It plays like real bowling.
Scott: It's pretty much perfect in every way.
Scott: You have a me.
Scott: your me goes up to the.
Scott: you know the lane.
Scott: He's got a ball.
Scott: You move left and right you you aim where you want to throw it.
Scott: Then you hold the Wiimote up in the air like you're holding the bowling ball up in the air.
Scott: You push B. as soon as you push B the guy starts his bowling motion.
Scott: you then start your bowling motion and When you want to let go of the ball you let go of B and then oh there goes the ball now.
Rym: This is the only part that at least me and a lot of other people but some people don't found a little counterintuitive.
Scott: It seems like some people do it just right and some people it really screws them up because you try to do your natural bowling motion and If your natural bowling motion isn't is way wacky and a lot of people have wacky bowling motions as their natural way to bowl You're gonna have a problem with the Wii bowling.
Rym: Well, the thing is also that you can't control the backswing or anything.
Rym: Once you hit B press a press a the guy just starts going Immediately starts bringing it back and stepping forward to bowl Mm-hmm, and you can't control how fast you're slowly brings it back.
Rym: So you pretty much have to match what he's doing.
Scott: a lot of people when you bought when they bowl will bring the ball back Hold it back and then bring it forward.
Scott: No, I don't do that.
Scott: Well, some people do but I like or the other thing is like my dad He would push B then he would wait a second and then he would start his bowling motion.
Scott: But by the time he'd started his bowling motion they got the me on the screen had already finished the bowling motion.
Scott: So he would end up letting go of the B way too late and the ball wouldn't go, right?
Rym: my things is the way I bowled and I kind of picked this up the one time I took a bowling class and that was Probably the best time I ever had in terms of bowling because I actually got almost kind of okay I am.
Rym: I got to the point where I averaged about a hundred and thirty which for me is Double what I normally do in bowling.
Scott: that's about my real-world bowling average something like that.
Rym: Yeah But I don't really hold the ball up Before I go when I'm in my neutral stance before I actually move forward to bowl I hold it kind of in front of me and I draw it back instead of having it up down and back.
Scott: Oh, see I do it up down.
Rym: So that totally fucks me up and we both yeah, it's gonna do that But other than that, it's it's actually really good.
Rym: The the amount of control you have over the spin is quite a bit more than you'd expect
Scott: Actually feels right like, you know, if you Try to spin the ball left or right or if you you know Don't swing your arm in a perfectly straight motion Or if you let go of be too early or too late or swing harder or swing lighter, you know It all seems to.
Scott: the ball seems to respond to all of those motions Exactly or close to the way a real bowling ball would or as close as it could possibly be for this sort of technology.
Scott: You know, they're obviously using the full Gradient of analog inputs from the wiimote.
Rym: so last and probably will certainly not least is boxing.
Scott: Yeah boxing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's it's it's great.
Scott: But at the same time it's not so great.
Rym: It's really really fun but it's not that precise or an Indicative of skill.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the controls are a little bit clumsy Like I tried to do the training and to do the training.
Scott: It's like okay punch the guy in in these examples Exact locations and I can't aim the gloves in exact locations.
Scott: I don't know what the hell they're thinking that's even possible.
Rym: Actually, I can do that kind of okay.
Rym: But the problem is when I play in the actual boxing it doesn't seem to work against a human opponent.
Scott: Yeah my strategy in boxing is pretty much I hold my gloves one in front of my head and one in front of my body to Block pretty much anything people throw at me and then as soon as I see openings I go punch punch punch punch punch and it seems to work pretty well.
Scott: I win a lot and it's fun, but not really.
Scott: It's it's not really at punch-out levels of bowling at bowling boxing.
Rym: That was awesome, yeah, yeah, there's not much more we can say about boxing.
Rym: really.
Rym: I mean you can punch to the head you can punch to the body.
Rym: You can do a hook You can dodge.
Scott: dodging is key.
Scott: Yep, you can block.
Scott: Yeah, it's fast paced.
Scott: You know if people know what they're doing it actually gets pretty exciting because your fight will go for three rounds.
Scott: Yeah, but It's also not really clear.
Scott: I mean, I know for a fact that if you get knocked down and you don't do anything You don't push any buttons.
Rym: You won't get back up, but we don't know what buttons to push to get up because it's a Wii.
Rym: It's not like the Nintendo where you just hit A and B. So whenever you're knocked down you end up flailing both arms and hitting every button on all the Wii modes Just hoping something will happen.
Scott: This is the kind of thing we got to look on game facts to see.
Scott: I'm gonna look at up right now actually.
Rym: Yeah, but other than that and it's fun.
Rym: but one problem that I have is that and I was surprised at this but the Cable between the Wiimote and the nunchuck is a little too long and it keeps hitting me directly in the junk.
Rym: When I'm standing there boxing it must be the way I hold myself.
Rym: Maybe it's from when we a bunch of us took like a kung fu class at RIT And you hold your fist kind of low so I hold my fist kind of low and that thing just keeps hitting me down there.
Scott: Yeah, well if I play boxing while sitting down in fact if I play a lot of nunchuck games while sitting down The stupid wire like I don't know what to do with it because it's like sitting in my lap and it's kind of in the way I wish the nunchuck was wireless or something.
Scott: Also, the nunchuck doesn't seem to risk like it seems to be a lot easier to hit with the Wiimote than it is to hit.
Rym: See actually for me it was the other way around.
Rym: every time I've won a boxing match or any time I do.
Rym: Well, my technique is to only punch with the left hand because I'm so much more accurate with it.
Scott: Really I'm.
Scott: so the Wiimote seems like I have a lot more control over that glove and the nunchuck.
Scott: I can't always get it to throw a punch like sometimes.
Scott: I'll try to punch and it won't punch.
Scott: It'll just kind of float around there.
Rym: See I get that with the Wiimote and the nunchucks weird.
Rym: Uh, maybe actually remember when we were playing before and you were beating me.
Rym: But then out of the blue I kind of knocked you down and got all your health out in one go.
Rym: I mean you totally won the match, but I knocked you down that one time.
Scott: Yeah Well that was.
Scott: I was slowly losing health over time as I got hit.
Rym: what I when that happened Most of the health I took away is I was I took the left We none Chuck and I went face face face face face face face face and nothing else.
Rym: That's my primary technique in boxing, but it only works if the other person I don't know.
Rym: I don't know when it works.
Scott: Think part of what it is is like with the Wiimote you kind of flick it like flick flick flick and with the nunchuck You kind of actually had to push it forward in space like a real punch true, you know.
Scott: And it's like two different motions.
Scott: So you try to do the same motion with both devices and it doesn't work.
Scott: You kind of have to punch the nunchuck actually physically forward like you're really punching but with the Wiimote you can just kind of flick your wrist like you're whipping or Smacking with a paddle or something like that.
Rym: But yeah, we sports is pretty fun.
Rym: It's definitely a tech demo.
Scott: yeah, if you get a we and all you get is we sports you probably won't be disappointed for a few weeks and Until the real party games come out.
Scott: This is what you've got to go on and it won't be so bad.
Scott: You'll have a lot of fun at parties.
Rym: Well, if you really really need a party game you can get monkey ball, which is not the best game by any stretch But it's got enough fun in it to hold you over in terms of party style game.
Scott: I've heard that Rayman has some multiplayer also, but I haven't played it and I don't plan on buying it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I've heard a lot of good things about Rayman.
Rym: I'll probably buy it used.
Scott: Oh, maybe it's all you.
Rym: Yeah All right, this went on long.
Rym: So I'm going to.
Rym: no I'm not going to bed.
Rym: I'm gonna play some excite rock.
Scott: You wanna go play some excite rock?
Rym: Possibly.
Rym: All right This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.