Rym: It's Thursday March 16th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We discuss a topic that normally and traditionally falls outside of the realm of geekery our favorite sports.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: so an email late Yesterday night, I think and it said we're gonna start having weekly staff meetings.
Scott: now That's bad news for me because it currently have zero meetings at all.
Scott: wow I have at least five meetings a week, and I'm in this middle of nowhere office all alone Which means the only way I'm getting to the meeting is by calling in on telephone.
Rym: Oh, that's fantastic.
Rym: Just call in and put the phone down.
Scott: the meetings at 8 30 a.m I have to be at the office at 8 30 a.m.
Scott: When I'm usually there at 9.
Rym: call it from your cell phone in the car in the car.
Scott: when New York I'll get a ticket, and I can't pay attention to driving.
Rym: well You're not gonna actually gonna listen to this.
Rym: I mean you don't really want to go to the meeting do you know?
Scott: but I if I don't have a hands-free I kind of had you know if I don't go to the first one.
Scott: They'll be like hey, where's Scott girl?
Rym: Well get a hands-free.
Scott: I got it before tomorrow at 8 3 a.m..
Rym: You could the mall still?
Rym: oh, no the malls closed now.
Rym: Yeah, okay, the mall was open an hour ago.
Scott: You could have gotten night's genius Not geek afternoon while the mall is still open.
Rym: You know we could have done it earlier if you'd actually helped me do the show.
Scott: instead of playing video games video games I have to play for the show.
Rym: yeah, yeah, all right I love how almost everything we do in our lives now is research for our show as opposed to just screwing around.
Scott: I used to just sit there and couldn't figure out what geekery to indulge in and now I force myself to indulge in some sort of geek.
Scott: I'm accomplishing a Nothing something.
Rym: I'm not sure what I think of that.
Rym: So I actually have standing meetings like many days of the week.
Rym: in fact today, I skipped them both.
Rym: But I theoretically had two required meetings to attend.
Rym: awesome, but anyway well that day I'm getting a new job somewhere soon anyway.
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: Yeah, I learned a long time ago I want a job with as few meetings as possible.
Rym: It depends meetings mean less work.
Scott: No, cuz I don't have work anyway.
Rym: Yeah, all right, so I had my own bit of annoyance driving into work today.
Rym: I usually listen to NPR Mostly because I hate the radio and everything on it and the CD player in my car doesn't work if it's cold outside.
Scott: Sounds like a job for an iPod and I trip.
Rym: I'm probably gonna buy an iPod.
Rym: I trip real soon Especially if I end up commuting on the train into the city every day.
Scott: well You don't need an i-trip if we're on the train you just need so well.
Scott: Here's the thing Eddie modick 6i headphones.
Rym: It's not worth a couple hundred bucks to get a good job Car stereo to replace my busted one.
Scott: Oh hell.
Scott: No well actually it sometimes best buy has it for like a hundred bucks.
Rym: It's still not worth it.
Rym: Yeah, it's not worth it to fix that because it works half the time.
Scott: Okay, so you only get one if it's 50 bucks now.
Rym: I would pay the cost of an i-trip to have a working car stereo Mm-hmm.
Rym: so if I already have an iPod buying an i-trip is a no-brainer.
Scott: I trips less than 50 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, you know what I discovered.
Scott: my i-trip is the best thing.
Scott: I always tune it to eighty seven point nine to that's NPR around here.
Scott: I Actually know it's nothing right in front of the house Yeah, but drive a little ways that way and it's something I don't know it works all the way to all the way to work.
Scott: It works.
Scott: Just fine.
Scott: I think it works so fine that all the people who have serious satellite radio are also using 87.9 to get it from their receiver to their car stereo.
Scott: great.
Scott: so When I drive around like every other day, I'll hear like five minutes of Howard Stern as someone with serious drives by me.
Scott: It's like all these people who have serious satellite radio only listen to Howard Stern.
Scott: They don't listen to anything else.
Rym: like I swear to God Man that means the I trips real weak.
Scott: It is pretty weak.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's supposed to be strong enough for just your car, but so is serious.
Scott: Well, the thing is I think the serious is a little more powerful.
Rym: Well, the I trip should be more powerful.
Scott: Yeah, there was a hack for the one of the older I trip minis that I where you could make it more powerful.
Scott: I'm waiting for the I trip nano hack to make it more powerful.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: But anyway, I'm listening to NPR on the way to work and they're doing this bit about survivalist nonsense.
Rym: You know, what are you gonna do if there's a bird flu pandemic?
Scott: There's a bullshit about that.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not going to get into the details of the stupidity I witnessed.
Rym: but during this someone called in And I'll get to the details of this other stupidity.
Rym: I witnessed.
Rym: that's mostly unrelated to the previous stupidity.
Rym: so this old lady calls in and she starts talking about how scientists long ago discovered that olive leaves are an antiviral and that they curates and The government hushed it up because you know patent whatever.
Scott: So why did the screeners even let this lady through?
Rym: Because they don't really screen so much and think of it this way.
Rym: say you're screening anyway And someone calls your radio show and says I want to ask a question about blah.
Rym: They say all right, and they put you in the queue.
Rym: Then you get on the show and you instead ask a question about blah.
Rym: blah There's nothing they can do.
Rym: but they push the button and you stop talking or they say oh, it's nice to hear from you click Yeah, but the thing is she sounded sane at first but they'd let her talk too long and then she turned crazy real quick.
Rym: One of those now, I don't mind the fact self nutcase.
Rym: She was just a crazy randy lady who seemed to believe that olive leaves will cure Asian bird flu if you get it and That you should stock up on olive leaves or olive leaf extract pills for the coming apocalypse.
Scott: We should put some Asian bird flu in her house and see what happens now be like, hey, how's olive leaves doing?
Rym: Yeah, now here's what bothers me.
Rym: I don't mind When someone like that has a crazy batshit belief.
Rym: What bothers me other than it?
Rym: maybe they hurt someone with that belief or they hurt themselves with that belief?
Rym: But when they present this belief To a public figure in a public forum who knows better?
Rym: because the lady who was moderating all this on NPR obviously knows better She's an intelligent person.
Rym: Instead of telling this lady exactly that she was wrong or this is complete bullshit She basically just fluffed it off.
Rym: as you know, I'm not really familiar with the research.
Rym: But yeah, it's a good thing to know.
Rym: Thanks for your information.
Scott: Well, that's the difference between mainstream media and blog type stuff.
Scott: If you're in the mainstream media, you had to be all polite and all this, you know, see ice.
Rym: I think that's a big fallacy not only on the part of greater human good, you know spreading truthful information instead of lies But more importantly from a money perspective.
Rym: Look how well all the shock jock crap Oh people do compared to mainstream media in terms of money.
Scott: Yeah, but it's NPR You have to.
Scott: you know, if you start doing that kind of stuff in NPR will be fired.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but here's the thing.
Rym: if NPR started doing that sort of thing How many new listeners would they get to the radio?
Scott: Yeah, but then how credible would it be to all the NPR people?
Scott: they would think it's all.
Scott: oh, it's just a one of those crap lowbrow things.
Scott: now It can't be respected.
Rym: See this is the problem.
Rym: I have is I am by no means a right-winger In fact, I'm the exact opposite of that in many ways in almost always.
Rym: However, I am NOT a traditional Liberal at least in terms of how what people mean by the word liberal nowadays.
Rym: I'm definitely not a leftist either dirty hippies.
Rym: now It seems to me that a lot of the people who listen NPR seem to be leftist in the leftist leftist sense.
Rym: Left on every issue liberal on every issue.
Rym: and because I've noticed that NPR carries a lot of not ads But you know promotional consideration kind of deals which are basically just ads.
Scott: I thought it was accurate.
Scott: does all the promotional considerations for NPR.
Rym: They get a lot of very stupid sounding herbal remedy Organic whatever bullshit lately, really?
Scott: Yeah Wow Those people shouldn't be allowed to advertise.
Rym: Yeah, more importantly NPR regardless of whether or not they need the money should really not be catering to this.
Rym: The thing is I think that their listeners want it, too.
Scott: Yeah, that's well, it's all about if they're marketing it on NPR.
Scott: They must be getting results in NPR.
Scott: Yep, so That's the thing.
Scott: That's so great.
Scott: Why I don't really listen to the radio or Watch TV anymore and I go all for the internet and podcasts and all that sort of thing is because when you go there Someone's not afraid to say you're batshit crazy.
Scott: Yeah, I know it was just an article today where this guy You know was said one Randy at the end and I was like actually know that Randy's false.
Scott: And then I went somewhere else and there was someone else in a comment saying yep that Randy's fault.
Scott: Haha It's like, you know, there's no comment section on an NPR radio show or on a TV show.
Scott: on TV You know and it's all filtered and crap on the internet.
Scott: You're gonna get you know, the truth Might not you know, not everything on the internet is true But the truth is there somewhere and if you put in effort you can dig it up and if you're smart You'll recognize it plus on the internet.
Rym: People are very much willing to give you your bad medicine.
Scott: Yeah, if someone comes around and says olive leaves will heal you bla bla bla bla bla.
Scott: a thousand people will say you're fucking nutcase.
Rym: The problem is and when we get to my thing of the day a lot of people even though they're told that there's fucking nutcase And there's evidence everywhere.
Rym: They still believe it.
Scott: Yes However, the fact that there will be a story that says olive leaves and then a million comments the same nutcase That person might stay in that case.
Scott: But at least people coming along seeing those comments won't also become nutcases.
Scott: Sometimes sometimes more often than if NPR says olive leaves are good.
Rym: I submit that if you read Fark more you'd have a much more cynical view of your fellow man.
Scott: Oh it's cynical, but I also like Darwinism Because you know creationism sure isn't real.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So anyway in the news, right Sony?
Scott: Now all of you know that blu-ray While it's supposedly better This is the same Sony that hasn't done anything successful since like the ps2.
Rym: Yeah Yeah The Sony that stock is dropping like a rock that doesn't have their next-gen game console out.
Rym: That looks like they're gonna be competing not with Microsoft but with Nintendo Or their launch window.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: And now that I think they Alright, so blu-ray was originally and still does Have DRM in it all sorts of DRM.
Rym: now one aspect of this has a bit in it where if you Use this token in your media and the media is played out of any Output that is either analog or not fully protected by HDMI.
Rym: It will pretty much cut the resolution of your signal in half Mm-hmm in order to prevent HD copies of anything from getting out into the real world via the analog hole.
Rym: All right now I Consider this to be a very terrible thing and so do you know all the people who have previous?
Rym: Generation HD TVs who won't be able to watch HD blu-rays because of this?
Scott: all the intelligent people.
Rym: Yeah now Sony just recently backpedaled and said we're not gonna use that we're not gonna have it and That's half true.
Rym: slash dot once again had a slightly misleading headline.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: This is a big surprise.
Rym: So basically all Sony said is Media that we release will not in the foreseeable future Use the capability that blu-ray has to down.
Rym: sample your media.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So basically they're trying to trick everyone who hates DRM into adopting blu-ray with an empty promise that oh, don't worry Yeah that DRM features in there, but it's not gonna be used.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I get the feeling that my my prediction and guess is that they're going to not use it.
Scott: That way people will buy blu-ray and they'll have all this hot HD TV and then after blu-rays been adopted Then they'll bow to the media companies.
Scott: and well, they are a media company and thank you captain obvious of the redundancy team squad.
Scott: Yeah, there you go.
Scott: All right as someone who doesn't watch TV I'm real happy if I can download TV shows on the internet Especially if it's some legitimate thing that doesn't cause money or is very reasonably priced.
Scott: AOL has this thing called into TV that everyone is kind of going nuts about.
Scott: Cuz.
Scott: they got some good shows here available.
Scott: Absolutely for free.
Rym: What shows do they have?
Scott: Well, the one that caught my eye was the one at the top of the list adventures of Briscoe County, June.
Rym: Haha, the show was awesome.
Scott: Super awesome.
Scott: All right, they got some nerds might like Babylon 5.
Rym: I was all right the Beetlejuice cartoon.
Rym: That was actually terrible.
Rym: I wish it would die.
Scott: f-troop.
Rym: I Used to watch f-troop, but I don't know if I liked it because I was a little kid at the time freakazoid Freakazoid.
Rym: Yeah freaky you freaking me hanging with mr.
Scott: Cooper.
Scott: Alright, so they've got awesome old TV the fugitive I think is the best one and they got some other stuff like pinky in the brain Whatever.
Scott: Alright, so they got good stuff.
Scott: The problem here is that the only way to watch it is if you have Windows XP what Windows Media Player 10?
Scott: what?
Scott: and Yeah, it's all DRM didn't shot to hell.
Scott: it's high quality like they're really high quality videos and everything.
Scott: But they're so DRM that like almost no one can actually watch them and you can't like download and put on your iPod or anything.
Rym: I wonder.
Rym: I wonder if I could run Windows Media Player 10 in wine.
Scott: Maybe it would be tough.
Scott: You need like the active X bullshit and there's a bunch of DRM and crap.
Scott: Yeah, and then you're gonna have to find a way to take that and encode it to like a divx or whatever.
Scott: God, it's just not worth it.
Scott: There's so much DRM.
Scott: It becomes difficult to watch.
Scott: It's terrible.
Scott: It's like they ruined it.
Scott: They could have had it just perfect.
Scott: Just you know, like a YouTube or a Google video where you go and click and it plays.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: I hate to sound like a shill for Netflix, but we can see all those shows in Netflix.
Scott: are all those shows on DVD?
Rym: Almost all of them are hotness.
Scott: I'm totally gonna rip them all.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Scott: Second thing here.
Rym: Yeah three news is today.
Scott: You may or may not know there's going to be this is not some bullshit thing a star to Star Wars television shows.
Rym: now I have mixed feelings about this.
Rym: either we're gonna get awesome Star Wars action on a regular basis or This is going to be the worst thing that has ever happened.
Scott: Well the if you other than episode 1 if you ask Lucas arts, they'll say there are a lot of people who want more Star Wars and We're not gonna make any more movies.
Scott: So we're gonna make a TV show.
Rym: What about episode 7 8 & 9?
Scott: They should have made those like in the 90s.
Scott: If you ask me.
Rym: Yeah, I want to see some Vice Admiral Thrawn coming back.
Scott: Dude, who should be Vice Admiral Thrawn?
Scott: I can't even think of a person who could be Vice Admiral Thrawn.
Rym: There's no one.
Rym: scary enough.
Rym: Maybe von Karma could have pulled it off.
Scott: von Karma is not real.
Scott: Exactly, all right.
Scott: anyway The articles I've read suggested there's gonna be two shows.
Scott: one of them is a. it says it's gonna be a CG computer animated show set during the Clone Wars, but Isn't there already the Clone Wars cartoon that was on Cartoon Network?
Scott: Are they talking about the same thing or something new?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, it could be something new that's computer-generated Animation or it could be that's.
Scott: they were talking about the show that already exists.
Rym: I don't think they're talking about the one that already exists because that one was very much not computer-generated Yeah, or it might have been really computer helped animation.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: very good though.
Scott: Yeah, so if you want if you like Star Wars You're.
Scott: actually the Clone Wars cartoon is better than episodes 1 2 or 3.
Scott: For absolutely sure.
Scott: 100% is gonna be a live-action Star Wars TV show and they've already got Guaranteed they're going to be at least a hundred hours of this show in existence.
Rym: Do they have the same actors for the parts?
Scott: We don't know anything about it.
Rym: If you if you and McGregor isn't in it, I'm not watching.
Scott: the only thing we know about it is it's going to be taking place between episodes 3 & 4. so That's the part of everyone wants to know about.
Scott: you know, what goes on between?
Scott: You know Yoda goes to Daiglebaugh and then you know Luke Let him beat you.
Scott: you had to let him defeat you.
Scott: you had to Okay, go crazy.
Scott: I went.
Rym: so things of the day.
Scott: well, I just talked about Star Wars and My thing of the day also involves Star Wars.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, really?
Scott: It's a little quiz online and it's a pretty simple quiz.
Scott: There's a long list of words on the left and for each word you have two choices.
Scott: You can either say that word is the name of a Star Wars character Or you can say that word is the name of a web 2.0 application.
Rym: now This is a lot harder than you would think.
Scott: All right, let's do a few flicker.
Scott: a web 2.0 Django spelled J A N G O obviously Star Wars.
Scott: DJ A N G O.
Rym: now, I'm gonna say web 2.0, but I have no idea what the hell that is.
Scott: It's a web 2.0 application.
Scott: I don't know what it does.
Rym: squid ooh That's a web 2.0 Thrawn.
Rym: Ha we just talked about thrawn Pando.
Rym: That's a Star Wars Meebo.
Rym: I know it's web 2.0 only because you mentioned it earlier.
Rym: Fauveur Let's go.
Rym: Star Wars.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I don't think we need to go through the whole survey.
Scott: Yeah, let me just say web 2.0 applications have.
Scott: a lot of them have similar names to Star Wars characters.
Rym: Let me put it this way I recognized a grand total of one thing on that entire list that I knew what it was if it wasn't Star Wars.
Scott: Wow, I got about four or five that weren't Star Wars.
Rym: I was still.
Rym: I did really well on the actual quiz part just because I know Star Wars real well.
Rym: So anything I didn't recognize the Star Wars.
Rym: I said it was web 2.0.
Scott: Yeah, I pretty much picked all the ones that I knew and the rest randomly, you know, cuz one of the two shot I got a 29 which is I think that says too much Kool-Aid.
Rym: I Also got a 29.
Scott: Yeah, the ideal score is between 11 and 20 because then you get the result of revel in it.
Scott: You've achieved a rare Zen balance of pop culture knowledge and techno prowess and apparently still have a life to boot.
Rym: Yeah It's not like that nerd geek dork survey where almost everyone who listens to GeekNights came up as a modern cool nerd.
Scott: I'm a pure geek.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: so for the most of you know that every now and then my thing of the day is something that just generally pissed me off as Opposed to something awesome and today is one of those days great.
Rym: Now.
Rym: This is on actually last week's JREF newsletter, so you might have already read it, but I think it bears repeating.
Rym: Now there's this woman and her name is dr.
Rym: Kaz DeMille Jacobson and she was going around speaking at churches.
Rym: and Well here, you know what?
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: that's a warning sign right away.
Rym: You know what I'm gonna do.
Rym: I'm gonna go through a list of things that she's claims as a speaker.
Rym: These are things that she actually claimed to have done or known or been in the course of her life.
Rym: Okay, and here's the thing the people who listen to her and believe her They believed all of the things that I'm about to say and this is a non trivial number of people.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: She is the illegitimate grandchild of film director Cecil DeMille.
Scott: Wait, what's her name?
Rym: Kaz DeMille Jacobson.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Is that a real name or did she change her name or what?
Rym: No one knows.
Scott: Great.
Scott: All right.
Scott: She's got something.
Rym: All right, she was married to famous pop star Fabian and then later to Roberto Andretti.
Scott: Who's Fabian?
Rym: Uh, I don't know Fabio.
Rym: I don't know Fabio.
Scott: I think if she was married to the Fabio That's that really big like yeah see romance novel but Roberto Andretti is of the famous car racing family.
Scott: Yeah Mario and Michael are much better racers and no one knows about Roberto.
Scott: if she would have said Michael or Mario people would have been Like that's a lot.
Scott: You're lying.
Rym: All right, she chooses like.
Scott: that's like saying yeah, I'm married to Waluigi.
Rym: All right, her production companies have won several Oscars and Grammys.
Scott: Well, you could just look that shit up.
Rym: Yeah, well someone did look that up and I'll let you guess as to what the results were.
Rym: Okay She founded worldwide charitable organizations.
Rym: very easy to you know, just make up.
Scott: I just found it too.
Rym: She has a net worth of over a hundred million dollars.
Scott: Me too.
Rym: She has been on presidential advisory committees under three American presidents.
Scott: Is that written down somewhere also?
Rym: All right, here's where it goes.
Rym: batshit like crazy.
Scott: She was anyway, it's not crazy batshit already now.
Rym: Keep in mind that up till this point I could understand how some fairly ignorant people could believe this woman But the rest of these they also believed.
Rym: She was in the elevator in the North Tower of the World Trade Center when the planes hit it on September 11th.
Rym: Although horribly wounded she courageously led others to safety running out of the tower just as it collapsed Yeah while hospitalized from her 9/11 wounds.
Rym: She was clinically dead for 28 minutes.
Rym: While dead she came.
Rym: she was taken to heaven where she met Jesus and God.
Scott: what what.
Scott: okay Wait a minute.
Rym: when she came back to life She had a rock in her hand given to her by Jesus himself.
Scott: Where's the rock?
Rym: Oh NASA tested the rock and said it was not of the earth nor of the moon and then refused to give it back and deny All existence of it.
Scott: Why would NASA do that?
Rym: President Bush sent for her and he and mrs Bush heard her wonderous story and then they knelt down in front of her and asked her forgiveness for letting 9/11 happen.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now this woman was going around speaking at churches and the churches she was she was speaking at were very Excited to have such a famous and important person coming to their church and they believed every word She said.
Rym: they considered her a wonderful promotional speaker.
Scott: Well, I mean if you're at a church that means you already believe that there's some crazy Jesus magic dude somewhere.
Scott: so It's not hard to convince those people of just about anything else.
Scott: I mean once you believe in something completely made up like I could get those people to believe in dragons and fairies and God knows what.
Rym: well, what was that quote?
Rym: because it came up today when we were arguing online.
Rym: Uh, I submit that you were just as much an atheist as me.
Rym: I just believe in one fewer God than you and when you realize why you don't believe in all those other gods You'll realize why I don't believe in yours.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's the one.
Rym: Yeah That's the one.
Rym: Yeah Yeah that there was a little inside joke.
Scott: I got a plan.
Scott: Oh, let's go around to churches claiming all kinds of crazy shit and then big mischief.
Scott: See my I note that for the entertainment of people like us everywhere.
Rym: How many times have we run across something like this where we realized how trivial it would be for the two of us?
Rym: To give up on our technology careers do whatever scam we're talking about and make millions.
Scott: Oh, we're not evil fuckers.
Rym: I mean audiophile stuff.
Rym: You wouldn't believe the magic wood paper, whatever I could build and sell to people on.
Scott: dude I'm gonna make wooden volume knobs.
Scott: They decrease bad vibrations in your Sound system.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: No, they also add tonal clarity.
Scott: Okay and bring out the rich Bases and they're made with special wood from rare trees and like the tropics and they're only five hundred dollars each.
Scott: Buy one now.
Rym: remember when we wanted to sell magic fairy powder on eBay.
Rym: Yeah, I remember that we were gonna grind up some sidewalk chalk.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: We should still do that.
Rym: See, we just have too many scruples.
Rym: But the thing is a lot of people out there don't have any scruples or they are scruples that didn't make sense I know because those people don't make sense.
Rym: That was the dumbest analogy ever.
Scott: you suck I'm just trying to be silly.
Scott: We're talking about grinding up sidewalk chalk and selling it as fairy dust.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So anyway, it's Thursday, which means we can talk about whatever the hell we want and it's favorites week Which means it has to be something that we like Now.
Rym: we debated for a while because there are basically infinite number of topics we could have talked about.
Scott: Yep, I mean it was really hard to pick one.
Scott: like.
Scott: what?
Scott: favorite movies.
Scott: Yeah fair books favorite anything.
Rym: favorite geekery?
Rym: I thought about favorite women.
Rym: We ended up on sports now.
Rym: I justify this in that one.
Rym: We actually liked sports more than you would think and I think that a lot of geeks out there actually enjoy certain sports more Than you would expect of the stereotypical geek nerd, whatever.
Scott: I think what it really is is that People who are more nerdy or geeky like some of them are just like anti sport, which is fine.
Scott: Some people are just like yeah, we don't care about sports at all, which is fine.
Scott: But it seems like there's a large population of people that like care about one or two sports and not any others.
Scott: When as opposed to the typical American like look at my dad my dad But no matter what time of the year it is.
Scott: He's got one or two sports He's watching no matter what cuz that you know.
Scott: when he grew up.
Scott: He was all sports action.
Rym: Yep The other thing is that it seems like non geeks tend to rally around sports as a safe topic to talk about at work And a lot of people seem to care about it way too much.
Scott: Well, that's because geeks have other things they care about in their lives like their comic books or their video games or their whatnot Whereas normal folk who don't have any hobbies and aren't geeks, you know There's not much for them to go on except for TV shows and sports.
Rym: I mean, this is kind of sick and sad but where I work the after the Red Sox won the World Series a Lot of people didn't come in to work the next day because they were Yankees fans and they couldn't deal with it.
Scott: Well, okay.
Rym: Yeah, they may they took sick days because they couldn't deal with the fact that their team lost.
Rym: I think that they're just using that as an excuse to Know you'd be these people when when something crazy happens in sports They get loud and angry and passionate about it.
Rym: They get more passionate about sports than they get about the war Iraq drugs, whatever and that's the reason that those sports exist.
Rym: Yeah, well bread and circuses.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So one thing we've noticed over the years is that there seem to be a certain number of sports At least we're mainstream sports first.
Rym: then we'll get into the more esoteric sports that geeks and seem to really love.
Rym: that Geeks tend to flock around more than maybe other people and definitely more so these sports than other sports.
Rym: Mm-hmm number one Surprisingly seems to be hockey.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: baseball basketball football ice hockey.
Scott: ice hockey seems to be like.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: Maybe it could be the violence.
Rym: It could be the fact that a lot of tech schools originally were up in the north where hockey was big anyway.
Scott: It could be that Hockey is only played above the Messier line where people are smarter.
Rym: Also, I just note that all the old engineering school, you know MIT Caltech MIT doesn't have the greatest hockey.
Rym: No, they don't have the greatest hockey, but the people who go to MIT love their hockey kinda RIT real big into the hockey.
Scott: Yeah, it's where he went.
Scott: So that's our big into hockey.
Rym: Yeah, well, I was big into the hockey pretty much my whole life mostly because I was born in hockey town, you know Detroit.
Scott: Well, yeah, but I was also, you know, I wasn't born.
Scott: I was born in Queens, New York You know, I was born in a city that calls itself hockey town.
Scott: Yeah, my family is all Rangers fans, right?
Scott: But we're also Mets fans and Giants fans and all sorts of you know New York teams, right?
Scott: but of all those things Back in like the 60s.
Scott: It must have been the 70s.
Scott: Maybe my family actually had season tickets to go to Madison Square Garden and watch Rangers games for like a couple years or so And like no other sport did they ever buy season tickets or anything?
Scott: So I guess it's also a family thing.
Rym: Well plus just hockey wise a lot of geeks I've known.
Rym: I mean, we're not like really into hockey.
Rym: I mean, we love it and we'll watch it, but we don't you know obsess over stats or Actually care who wins outside of the game.
Rym: We're watching at the moment.
Scott: Yeah, like if you know if I'm watching a game right now, I care who wins.
Scott: Maybe I won't if the teams or whatever.
Rym: Yeah But if we're at a game at RIT watching RIT play We want to win so we can ridicule the people sitting on the other side of the ice.
Scott: Yeah, and I wouldn't mind if like, you know, the team that I'm going for wins the World Championship or whatever.
Rym: We're not skipping work.
Scott: if our team loses no and you know, but if they lose whatever I don't really care.
Scott: It's just some guys somewhere that I don't even know.
Rym: I've just I've run into a lot of geeks who like hockey and I think definitely Statistically beyond random chance.
Scott: Yeah hockey is awesome.
Rym: Now aside from hockey at least us.
Rym: personally I have no more geek correlations other than ice hockey, but we generally enjoy f1 racing.
Scott: F1 racing if you don't know like it's not just a thing you see in video games.
Rym: There actually is Formula One racing and the thing is it's hard as hell to actually watch it.
Scott: It's only only way you can see it in the United States is on speed TV or the Pirates Bay?
Scott: Well, I only I think the only time I've never seen it on the Pirates Bay before the race that just happened last weekend.
Rym: And if this is a trend expect us to be talking about f1 races periodically.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to see an f1 race, you can either watch speed TV this Sunday I think and like 2 a.m.
Scott: Yeah Or curse they'll rerun the race at like sane hours on Sunday or just search on the Pirates Bay for Formula One.
Scott: Well, no, you're gonna want to search for Malaysia.
Rym: Well, you know what.
Rym: search for Bahrain because that one's out there we know.
Scott: yeah Well, who knows that torrents still up?
Scott: But yeah search for Bahrain to see the first race of this season or search for Malaysia Sometime after Sunday to this weekend and you can see the second Grand Prix.
Rym: Yeah now we're not gonna talk about.
Rym: I mean we could do a whole episode on the sport just like we could do a whole.
Scott: That's all you have to know about Formula One is the following.
Scott: They are the fastest most technologically advanced Four-wheeled motor vehicles on the face of the earth that run on gasoline and can turn.
Scott: and they turn left They turn right they go up hills and they go down hills.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's the best NASCAR can suck its dick.
Rym: Yeah, Formula One racing I mean I I've always enjoyed it as like as an idea as like the ultimate in racing.
Rym: But I never really liked it because mostly because I never really was able to watch it I was never able to.
Scott: I used to why.
Scott: I Remember there was like Indy racing and then Indy split up into Indian cart Which is now champ car and then open-wheeled racing which is you know race.
Scott: those low Indy style race cars that where you can see the wheels they're sticking out of the sides are taller than the car.
Scott: That's open-wheel racing.
Scott: that kind of died in the US and NASCAR took over with its stock car racing.
Rym: so actually I used to live up in the mountains in poke way while I was still working for IBM as a co-op and The lady I lived with actually races open-wheel Ford at lime rock.
Rym: Yeah, so she had all her race cars in the garage and I got to look at.
Scott: I remember in like my younger days Like I always you know, I would watch racing, you know He'd watch like the Indy 500 and the Daytona whatever until my dad eventually really got into NASCAR type of stuff, you know.
Scott: Yeah But you know, I always liked the Indy stuff more because it was really.
Scott: it was just a lot more interesting and they were going a lot faster.
Scott: But then it kind of died because like, you know bullshit.
Scott: and then I finally found f1 racing was real like Three years ago just by chance flipping through the channels at home You know and now it's I'm all on it.
Rym: if we had more money.
Rym: We'd totally get into go-kart racing, which is not a stupid sport.
Rym: It's actually very difficult enjoyable and awesome.
Scott: F1 racing is really just go-kart racing with a freaking jet engine Instead of a you know Lawnmower engine.
Scott: that's all f1 is really.
Rym: now.
Rym: as for the rest of the traditional sports I could really take him or leave him.
Rym: I mean American football.
Rym: I enjoy occasionally.
Rym: I usually enjoy the marching band halftime shows more.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like.
Scott: I enjoy a good game of football, you know But I don't really and I'll go to usually like one a year because my dad gets tickets or whatever.
Scott: I think I went to two last year.
Scott: It's like a Giants game and a Patriots game But like, you know, I don't really care and watch the Super Bowl and watch the Super Bowl in like six years.
Rym: I actually really enjoy watching tennis.
Scott: No, I don't tennis.
Rym: I think the only reason I enjoy is that I used to play it.
Rym: I I don't play it much anymore.
Rym: I just don't have time.
Scott: but Yeah, I don't like tennis Baseball, I don't mind going to baseball.
Scott: But yeah, I'm not that and I'm gonna watch baseball on TV.
Scott: Ah, but I really what I do really like to watch is if if I had TV I would watch ESPN Sports Center during baseball season and you see all the crazy baseball plays in like two minutes.
Scott: It's the best Because that's all you really want.
Scott: because you know, most of baseball is they're standing around Pitch throw it back.
Scott: pitch throw it back you.
Scott: if you cut all that out Sports Center shows you like the amazing baseball moments of the day.
Scott: It's terrific.
Rym: See what I like about a baseball game.
Rym: I don't mind going to one because it's half, you know There's a sport going on and half just hanging out eating peanuts with all your friends.
Scott: yeah, and baseball is really cheap compared to the other sports because there's so many games and Unless you're going to Fenway Park, it's not gonna sell out.
Scott: So, you know, you can just Have fun Basketball, I just have zero interest in.
Scott: yeah I think basketball.
Scott: the real thing behind that is at some colleges like they get all excited about it.
Scott: And then I can see me going to basketball for the you know school spirit excitement.
Rym: Yeah, I guess if RIT had an awesome basketball team instead of an awesome hockey team Yeah, you know you go for the school spirit But the sport itself.
Scott: the problem I have with it is that if they just score so often That it's completely unexciting and the only Potential excitement in a basketball game is if the score is close at the end.
Rym: There's opposed to hockey where if someone scores you jump up and scream Yeah, because when do they score?
Scott: in hockey?
Scott: You're lucky if you get three goals in a game, that's crazy.
Rym: Yeah, they've actually been scoring quite a bit more lately.
Rym: by quite a bit more I mean maybe four or five goals a game up to seven now, but that's just because they changed some of the rules.
Scott: It's like, you know That's the other thing football has going for it.
Scott: when someone gets a touchdown in football You know in baseball they you know, you know, they score one run.
Scott: you'd be like, yeah sometimes but Basketball it's like yay.
Scott: Yay Yay, yeah.
Rym: Yay.
Rym: Well football.
Rym: The only thing I really don't like about it is the culture around it.
Rym: I mean go into a football game.
Rym: You're surrounded by drunk loud idiots who care more about the game than you do.
Scott: Yep, that's true.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But it's actually strange because the fact that the ticket prices are so high at these events actually has a side effect.
Scott: See I never go to any professional sporting event unless the tickets are free, which I happen to get quite often actually through precarious means.
Rym: Yeah, I used to go to games that we paid for back when I lived in Detroit when the Red Wings but that was expensive As hell.
Scott: I would never pay for a professional sports ticket unless there was a damn good reason.
Rym: We paid to see the Stanley Cup finals when the Red Wings won for the first time.
Scott: yeah Yeah, that's it.
Scott: You know, there's a damn good reason.
Scott: Yeah, but You know what happens is these high prices?
Scott: They still sell out because you know, it's about supply and demand and capitalism.
Scott: So the high prices are justified.
Scott: They fill their arena with people but at the same time it keeps poor people out.
Scott: now, you know I don't know what the discriminating against poor people say.
Scott: whatever you want.
Rym: But it may think there's a very simple politically correct way to state this.
Rym: not all poor people are asshats But most asshats are poor people exactly.
Scott: So when you go to sporting events nowadays, you know professional ones Especially if you have really good seats, you know, the people might be drunk guys But they're like drunk business guys and not like big fat smelly drunk guys.
Scott: You know like when they show you on TV like the five scary fat guys this stuff painted on their chest.
Scott: Those guys are in the way upper deck all alone and there's only one set of them or they're at the NASCAR or they're at the NASCAR.
Scott: NASCAR has That's not that's.
Scott: here's something you want to get some perspective going.
Scott: The average like stadium can hold like tens of thousands of people at NASCAR.
Scott: They have grandstands that hold hundreds of thousands of people and they're just wooden benches that go way Up and the tickets are actually real cheap.
Scott: No, they're really not.
Rym: Well, they're they're real cheap if you sit in the crapo area and you don't have to drive to the place.
Scott: Yeah, depending on where you sit.
Scott: I mean if you sit way in the shitter in a NASCAR track, you can maybe spend 20 bucks.
Rym: Yeah, what's I'm saying?
Rym: It's because there's so many seats.
Rym: There are a lot of cheap seats available to cheap people Yeah, but they usually sell out most of their.
Scott: oh, yeah F1 is is so international that it depends.
Scott: it goes from country to country.
Scott: Like if you go to see like the middle of nowhere Grand Prix in the country, no one cares about.
Scott: it's gonna be pretty much empty, but if you go to see the Like the the European Grand Prix or the Monaco Grand Prix, it's sold out.
Scott: Forget it Actually, I think you can still get tickets to Monaco.
Scott: But how you gonna get there?
Rym: Yeah, where are you gonna stay?
Rym: Yeah, there are two places in Monaco.
Rym: There is the rich place Meaning orders of magnitude more money than you'll make in a year just to stay there for a week Or the poor place.
Scott: there really is no poor hotel.
Rym: No, no by poor I mean the shanty town on the other side of the mountain where all the servants live.
Scott: Yeah, you know, you can't actually stay there.
Scott: this there's no hotel there.
Rym: Oh, yeah You'd have to sleep in the street and be eaten by dogs.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't know about Monaco I'm sure there's a Wikipedia page about it.
Scott: You can learn all about the principality of Monaco.
Scott: It's basically a little tiny place that's full of casinos and hotels and fanciness and they have a race in the street there.
Rym: Imagine if the riches of Dubai and the poverty of Rwanda were next to each other.
Scott: Well the pie it's not that poverty.
Rym: No, but it's down there.
Scott: It's like Mexico.
Rym: No Mexico's got a lot of nice places.
Scott: Well, you know, it's like Mexican workers poverty.
Rym: Nah It's a little worse than that.
Rym: I think I don't know.
Scott: I've never actually seen it because you can't get a picture of it.
Rym: I remember we read a Wikipedia.
Rym: It's probably a slot like maybe one step above city of God.
Rym: Yeah, I were just talking on our asses at this point.
Scott: Yeah Pretty much all you have to know about if you want to actually go to an f1 race is let's say I wanted to go To the Montreal Grand Prix.
Scott: It's in Montreal not too far away.
Scott: It would cost me thousand dollars.
Rym: There are thousand dollars.
Rym: I could go to Japan.
Scott: Yeah that includes getting there staying in the hotel and the way they price the tickets is You basically don't buy the race.
Scott: you buy the race weekend because it's more.
Scott: it's just stupid not to and you have to go.
Scott: you Go to.
Scott: you end up going to two practice sessions the qualifying and the race, you know.
Scott: So you're there for like Friday Saturday Sunday going to all these different things And it cost you a thousand dollars in total.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So anyway, let's talk a bit about Non-traditional non mainstream sports.
Scott: Well, maybe let's try to keep it to things that are actually sports.
Rym: Oh, yeah, definitely sports We're not going to talk about.
Rym: you know, playing FPS is online.
Rym: Yeah, or DDR but still competitive events.
Scott: Well sports are specifically like games that involve physical activity or athletics in some way.
Scott: That's how I put it.
Rym: Well, I just want to bring up because I think one of our favorite sports and both of us actually are big fans of this Trobriand Island cricketing.
Scott: Trobriand Island cricket is freaking swear.
Rym: now to put it very very briefly the Trobriand Islands The.
Rym: it was the British who were there for a long time and I think they eventually left and the Islander natives Watched them play cricket and they liked the game a lot.
Rym: They used to learn how to play cricket from those guys.
Scott: Actually, I think the cricket they play is kind of broken, but doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah so then those guys left and they kept playing cricket and They did because of their culture and this whole aspect of community, you know, the whole community should participate Whole towns and villages in these islands.
Rym: basically a team of cricket will consist of everyone in the village yep, and they'll go and they'll put like a hundred people on the field and They do these crazy crazy Dances and rituals during the game and it's just awesome.
Rym: Look around try to find videos of it.
Rym: It's quite a sight to see.
Scott: and they actually use this like instead of war.
Scott: Yeah, like you have they used to stab each other.
Scott: now, they just play cricket and accounts.
Scott: Yeah, imagine if we could go play cricket with like Iraq and then when we won we own them.
Rym: Awesome, of course, we saw how that ended with the Zulu's.
Rym: Yeah The thing is I don't think the Trobri and Islanders are gonna stop playing their cricket anytime soon.
Scott: I don't think they are now.
Scott: Maybe there's a video going somewhere in the internet.
Scott: Now there must be an article in the internet.
Rym: There's got to be.
Rym: there's got to be.
Rym: Now, I know we've talked a bit about curling lately and I just want to say independent of the fact There's obviously a marketing blitz going on now trying to get people to like cricket for some similar reason.
Rym: cricket curling I've played.
Rym: I've curled before and it's fun.
Rym: It's not fun to watch in my opinion But if you ever get a chance, it's fun to play.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's as fun to play as like shuffleboard or bocce It's pretty much shuffleboard on ice.
Scott: Not not chess on ice shuffleboard.
Scott: Yes on ice my ass Yeah, and shuffleboard actually, you know, I'm not some word isn't the greatest thing ever.
Scott: But if I'm hanging with my grandpa down in Florida, I'll play shuffleboard with the old man a couple times.
Scott: Why not, you know, whatever It's cool.
Scott: So I just occurred to me that there are a lot of sports.
Scott: We've neglected very very important ones such as dodgeball dodgeball and Speedball wall ball kickball.
Rym: kickball isn't one of my favorite sports ever and It requires almost no skill almost no athletics.
Rym: a bunch of guys get together play about half a game then give up and go home.
Rym: wiffle ball used to play mad wiffle ball when I was a kid.
Scott: wiffle ball rocks.
Scott: You know all the things that nerds actually like to play instead of just watch.
Scott: I mean we don't play f1 racing We don't.
Scott: I guess we could play hockey, but we don't really play ice hockey, you know.
Scott: But yeah, we can play all these things.
Rym: I used to used to play a lot of roller hockey.
Scott: Roller hockey you could play but ice hockey not so much.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you know, I lived in the frigid wastelands of Michigan.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't see you doing it.
Scott: You don't even have a hockey skate.
Rym: Well part of it Is that I don't have free time anymore, too.
Rym: There aren't just like ponds and lakes all over the place where you can just play hockey Around here like there were where I grew up.
Scott: whatever the point is is that I'm talking about the the geeky sports that you can actually play.
Rym: that got to give a nod to a Marching band drill core stuff, which a lot of guys a lot of geeks in high school really get into.
Scott: I don't think it's really.
Rym: I consider it a sport.
Rym: It's the.
Rym: it's a sport in the same way that uh, synchronized swimming or Yeah skating anything like that figure skating.
Scott: I don't know if those are really sports because to me a sport is like, you know It's like a game but it involves physical activity.
Scott: Those aren't really games.
Rym: They are.
Rym: they're more like Shows, they're also competitions Petitions with definitive rules.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like you get a. it's like a subjective score from a judge.
Scott: It's it's as if like two people put on Movies and then someone like decided scored the movies according to some system and decided who was the winner.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: There's a system and it's at.
Rym: the system itself is actually very objective in most ways.
Rym: It comes down to you have.
Rym: it varies from sports to sport but a lot of sports like this you start with a perfect score or A near perfect score and you lose points if you do specific things in specifically wrong ways Mm-hmm.
Scott: So it's a showcase like I would just go out and come back.
Scott: I would just go out there and get.
Rym: well Here's the thing.
Rym: you also get points for take for actually pulling off difficult maneuvers more.
Scott: But I thought you said you start with the perfect score.
Rym: It depends on the sport.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into the details of all these different sports Mm-hmm, but or in the very least you start with a perfect score and there's a list of things that you must do.
Rym: Aha things like that.
Rym: It's actually much less subjective than a lot of people think and Marching band actual like drum corps competitions are the same way.
Rym: I mean it depends if you didn't go to a high school that actually competed in you know Like national or at least state like marching band competitions.
Rym: You probably didn't get any of this But there is a fairly fierce competitive marching band circuit out there and you can watch him on TV.
Scott: I don't have TV now and I've never seen it on TV ever.
Scott: really.
Rym: I can pull up a whole ton of them if you want to watch him.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: In fact, they were my thing of the day a while ago.
Scott: Yeah, you know what cheerleading is on TV.
Scott: I've seen that on TV.
Scott: You know what.
Scott: they know what.
Scott: that's not a sport either.
Rym: Well, I consider it generally a stupid sport.
Rym: It's basically the same as all those others in terms of how it's judged.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: that just doesn't fit into Scott's Definition of sport.
Rym: Well, it fits into Rym's.
Scott: It's got to be a game and it's got to involve athletics.
Rym: It's a game and it involves athletics.
Scott: It's not a game.
Scott: It's it's a show.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: It's judges though.
Rym: It's competitive.
Scott: Yeah, it's just not a game.
Rym: how is it not a game?
Rym: it's competitive.
Rym: someone wins.
Scott: It doesn't matter if someone wins.
Rym: someone wins by an objective measurement.
Scott: No.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh look sub.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: he's got 98 points.
Rym: Oh, he flubbed his double half turn.
Rym: Now.
Rym: He's got 96 points.
Rym: No, what do you mean?
Scott: No, it's not the same.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: It's a whole different thing.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: It's a whole different thing.
Rym: I said that it's no different.
Scott: Wait, you're saying that that You know you doing something and then some people judge you and give you a score is not is the same thing?
Scott: is you play a game based on rules and you know, you The game progresses and then you know, whoever scores the most points wins?
Rym: I say they're fundamentally the same because you if the game progresses whoever scores the most points wins based on a mostly objective System.
Scott: All right.
Scott: so now we're gonna make a German board game where you know We all just play and then at the end someone comes over and you know Looks at how he played and then gives us this well That
Rym: person has to have a predefined system that we all know and understand as to how he's going to determine the winner.
Scott: Then why even have the judges?
Rym: if there's a predefined system then because the judges are just the people who enact that system.
Scott: you idiot Yeah, but you don't need people to enact the system.
Scott: and like a game of baseball.
Scott: It's just you score points.
Scott: You say up we got three and you see the three points.
Scott: There they are.
Rym: Yeah, you realize the judges are basically just like the referees in a game of hockey They facilitate and they did and they take care of the scoring.
Scott: So, you know theoretically you could just have a competition without judges and you would know exactly how many points you got.
Rym: actually Yeah, depending on the sport some sports I mean some of those sports are very subjective and I don't really consider them in this but the ones that have objective systems of Scoring.
Rym: Yes, I don't know multiple judges would come up with the same score unless they screwed up.
Rym: That's why they have multiple judges.
Rym: So you can like if three judges say one thing and once there's the other thing it all evens out in the end.
Scott: How does that even happen if it's objective?
Scott: If it's objective, how can it happen?
Scott: that you know?
Rym: Just because something's objective doesn't mean you might not miss something one judge might not notice that he screwed that he did something wrong In a specific way.
Scott: one judge might sneeze See, but you can't mess.
Scott: a game of baseball is a game.
Scott: You can't mess up.
Scott: the guy steps on the plate You know, all right, you can.
Rym: they often mess up There.
Rym: it's very vague often as to exactly when something's a strike or not.
Rym: A lot of times a ref will make a bad call Determining in what the call is.
Scott: once you know what the call is you there it is.
Scott: You have a scorecard.
Scott: anyone at the game can keep score.
Rym: Yeah, you know what anyone at watching eyes are.
Rym: Figure skating can keep score too if they know the system.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: Anyway, I don't consider those sports.
Rym: All right, so now they're like performances of some side disagree with you And I consider them sports.
Rym: sports to me is a very broad.
Scott: I think if you weren't a marching band fanboy, you would not consider it.
Scott: as I point out that I considered cheerleading Which I think is stupid just as much only to support your argument of marching band being actually I'll take everything in the same category and say it is just to hold it up.
Rym: See actually now I just consider sport to be a very broad category and then within that there are subcategories.
Rym: Yeah I mean marching band and figure skating and cheerleading and all that are definitely not in the same category as you know ice hockey But they're still sports.
Scott: Nah, not their athletic performances.
Scott: They're not even athletic.
Scott: It's just a performance Actually, they're very athletic.
Rym: figure skating is.
Rym: it is extremely extremely brutal on the body?
Scott: Not any more than dancing.
Rym: Dancing is also extremely difficult and brutal on the body and athletic.
Scott: No, only if you're doing like crazy-ass dance.
Scott: that requires like jumping around or breakdancing or something.
Rym: Wow Anyway, whatever I disagree with you.
Rym: You're entitled to your opinion, but we've rambled about this too long.
Rym: So I think that's the end of the show for tonight.
Rym: All right, good I have to go freaking 830 in the morning and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.