Rym: It's Monday, October 23rd, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight and possibly for the next several days, I'm going to have to apologize for the audio quality, as during our wonderful interview with Luke Crane, the creator of Burning Wheel at UberCon, we lost the power cable to our compressor.
Rym: As such, we are compressorless until we can find a replacement part.
Rym: Thus tonight, we talk a bit about how it's difficult to get replacement parts to many pieces of consumer electronics these days.
Rym: Let's do this!
Rym: So once again, we're back here with GeekNights, and once again, we are back from a weekend out of town.
Scott: Yeah, we went to UberCon, well, we didn't go for the whole weekend, we just went to UberCon all day Saturday, and it was pretty awesome.
Rym: Yep, except for the fact that we interviewed Luke Crane, well, not except for that, because the interview with Luke Crane, the creator of Burning Wheel, was absolutely awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I listened to the interview, actually, in the car ride home, and my interview skills going in were weak, and it took about, oh, five minutes before my interview skills were times a thousand.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I'd make fun of you, because the first couple times I tried to interview people, it totally sucked, and I just ignored those interviews when I was editing things around.
Scott: Yeah, no, it's like I asked one stupid question, and then as soon as I asked one smart question, I couldn't stop but asking more smart questions, because he gave such nice long answers, I was able to think of another smart question before he stopped.
Rym: Well, if one word described Luke Crane, it would be, I wanted to say eloquent, but maybe long-winded with a hyphen.
Scott: But that's what I wanted, because his wind is mighty and interesting.
Rym: But no, the interview was fantastic, and we'll be covering UberCon probably next Tuesday, due to the exception here, which was that we lost the cable to the compressor, the power cable.
Scott: Yeah, so we have a compressor, but we can't turn it on, because we can't put electricity into its electricity hole.
Rym: As a result, GeekNights is now going to sound the way it did before we bought a compressor.
Rym: Maybe a little better, just because we've learned a lot more microphone discipline since when we started.
Rym: But just a heads up, for the next couple days, GeekNights is not going to sound as good as you're accustomed to, and I hope you appreciate the money we spent on that compressor once we get it back.
Scott: Yeah, and we'll either be getting, I guess, a newer, better compressor or a power cable in a few days.
Scott: Well, who knows when these people are going to get back to us.
Scott: We might just have to order a new compressor.
Rym: Yeah, or try to find an electronics store that doesn't suck as much as Radio Shack that might have the 16 volt, one amp, with the correct connector transformer that we need.
Scott: Sigh.
Scott: Yeah, but- We could try to make one at Radio Shack.
Rym: Well, I could make one now, but I don't have any faith in my soldering abilities anymore, because I haven't soldered a thing since I tried to make that DDR pad two and a half years ago.
Scott: Neither do I. Hey, maybe one of our listeners who's good with electronics could be nice enough to make for us a 16 volt, one amp, transformer.
Rym: I don't know the number and type of the power connector that goes into the compressor.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I guess we could figure it out, but yeah, if you are capable of creating a power adapter, send us an email and we will send you info and pictures and stuff.
Rym: Actually, that's definitely not going to happen, because it'd be, no matter what, it's faster to order a new thing or get the cable than anything shipped by one of our listeners would be.
Scott: Maybe we can buy a new compressor, the same one, or maybe a slightly better one, and sell this one on eBay sans power cable.
Rym: That's kind of shady.
Scott: We will say right up front doesn't include power cable.
Rym: Then no one will buy it.
Scott: Someone might buy it.
Rym: No, no one will buy it.
Scott: People buy shit on eBay, man.
Rym: Yeah, and not stuff that obviously is missing something you need, especially when they realize they can't get it easily.
Scott: You never know.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: See, back in the day, Radio Shack sold all that stuff.
Scott: Yeah, Radio Shack used to just be stuff that was the only stuff we needed.
Scott: Now, they got like a little TV sec- it's sort of like a little mini Best Buy, you know?
Scott: They have like a big iPod accessory section, a toy section, a cell phone section, and, you know, the actual electronics.
Scott: besides, you know, standard cables you need for home audio, video, home theater is pretty much non-existent.
Scott: There's a few big Radio Shacks still around.
Scott: Like, there's one in my town that has a little bit more stuff, but it's not much more.
Scott: They just have a lot more floor space for more displays of crap.
Rym: Yeah, and I have had mostly bad encounters with Radio Shack employees in recent memory.
Scott: The thing is, the Radio Shack website and catalog still includes all that good stuff.
Scott: They just don't put it all in the stores.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, the other day we wanted to play the Atari, but we don't have an RF switch because that's old technology.
Scott: So we're using our NES RF switch, which doesn't work with an Atari 7800. that well.
Scott: Well, it works, it works.
Scott: It works, but not that well.
Rym: You just can't see the bullets.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I can see them.
Scott: Oh, I can't see the bullets in certain color modes because, you know.
Rym: Yeah, but as a result, you know, we went to Radio Shack, hey, we need an RF switch, and they didn't have anything even close.
Scott: Not even remotely anywhere in the ballpark.
Rym: But anyway, aside from all that, I think we've gotten over trying to talk within the bounds of the tiny audio range of the sound card.
Rym: I think we can get into the news.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, IBM, whose business model, I mean, I worked for them for a number of years, and their business models seem to be looming more and more toward patent acquisition and patent enforcement, has sued Amazon pretty much for internet commerce.
Scott: What?
Rym: IBM has a massive patent portfolio.
Rym: I believe it's one of the largest, if not the largest, technology patent portfolio in the world.
Scott: I would believe that easily.
Rym: Well, also, I mean, when I worked there, we were under a lot of pressure to get patents.
Rym: I don't know what came of it, but at least one thing I worked on at IBM was up to try to be patented because they emailed me asking me for a bunch of information on it once.
Scott: Nah, eh, lol.
Rym: But they're constantly trying to patent things, and then they just sit on these patents and use them as legal fodder in the future, either to protect themselves or to go after people.
Scott: Oh, you know what?
Scott: While SEO is wrong, I can, uh, that's a tiny bit saying, "Yeah, go after IBM, evil patenters of many
Scott: things.".
Rym: Yeah, so what IBM did here is they sued Amazon for basically infringing on a whole mess of patents that are all extremely vague and open and basically patent the very idea of commerce on the internet.
Scott: Lol.
Scott: Now, furthermore- I patent trading.
Scott: You can't trade anything without giving me money.
Rym: Far more sinister is that this is not a new thing.
Rym: Apparently, many unnamed retailers and online places of business have settled or licensed with IBM quietly for a number of years.
Scott: Oh, geniuses.
Rym: And Amazon is the first company to stand up and say, "No, we'll see you in
Rym: court.".
Scott: Damn straight.
Rym: IBM's been trying to get a deal with them since, I believe, 2002, and Amazon has outright ignored them.
Scott: You know, while Amazon isn't a perfect company, you know, they got some shady stuff like Alexa.
Scott: I think Alexa is Amazon, isn't it?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I remember Alexa was awesome, and then we found out that they were shady.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty sure Alexa is Amazon, and, you know, they're not perfect, but they're not bad.
Scott: Alexa, you know, Amazon's pretty cool, and they do good stuff, and they're right in this case.
Rym: Well, I guess, I mean, I liked working at IBM for a number of reasons.
Rym: I disliked working at it for a number of other reasons,
Scott: but
Rym: I often disagreed ideologically with a lot of the things IBM did, and here is an example, one I can actually talk about because this is public knowledge, and it has nothing to do with what I did there.
Scott: Yeah, Alexa's an Amazon company, like I thought.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: All right, so I said last, there's been a whole bunch of tech news.
Scott: I was gonna use a different one, but I said I would talk about Flash 9 today, so I'm gonna talk about Flash 9.
Scott: If you didn't know, there are different versions of Macromedia, Adobe Flash Player, and you need Flash Player to do anything productive on the web, because too many websites use Flash now.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, YouTube- And a lot of websites probably shouldn't use Flash, but they do.
Rym: But a lot of websites use it and should.
Rym: I mean, YouTube, Google Video-.
Scott: Yes, Flash Video in particular has become very popular.
Rym: Yes, especially because as more and more codecs for video are on the market, hey, we're talking about codecs today.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A lot of people are having more and more trouble being able to play videos on the internet, because you have to keep up with it and always have the newest codecs for whatever fancy new thing the fan subbers are using over there in Japan.
Scott: Yeah, and Flash Video, it allows you to watch a video in a website, download it pretty quickly, even though it's very low quality, and watch it.
Scott: It's been better, it's better than watching videos in a webpage has ever been.
Rym: Yeah, you see, the purpose of Flash was that you can do all of these animation and things in this pla- no, they want-.
Rym: technically it was platform independent, but what they meant by that was it's computer independent.
Rym: It'll work on any computer if you have the plugin, but they only made the plugin for Windows.
Scott: Yeah, well, they also, you know, and more recently they've made more and more versions of the Flash Player, upgrading it, adding more features.
Scott: as the years have gone on, and I think Flash Player 7 was available for Windows, Mac, and Linux, and, you know, that was how it was.
Scott: Then they came out with Flash 8.
Scott: Now in Flash 8, they did a lot of new stuff.
Scott: Some people who made websites, like YouTube, who were using Flash, were smart, and when they made their Flash, they made sure that their Flash was compatible with old versions of, you know, the Flash plugin, so if someone had Flash 7 instead of Flash 8, and they went to YouTube, it would still work, and they wouldn't get all these, you know, "You must
Scott: upgrade!".
Scott: But there were a whole lot of websites, particularly websites with Flash games, that would not work with Flash, you know, 7.
Scott: You needed Flash 8 for them to work, it would not work.
Scott: You couldn't play a game with Flash on Linux.
Scott: You needed Windows.
Rym: And even aside from that, the Flash 7 for Linux sucked the balls of a llama.
Scott: Yes, it was terrible.
Scott: Unless you were using OSS, the old audio, you know, the way audio worked in Linux, I don't want to explain it now.
Rym: Open source sound.
Rym: Yes,
Scott: if you were using the old and busted method of sound in Linux, then it would work, but if you're using the new, correct, better way of sound in Linux, Flash wouldn't have your sound work properly, you had to do some special stuff to get it to play the audio.
Rym: Yeah, but even with the old way, I mean, it didn't behave correctly even for that.
Scott: Yeah, you had a hard time getting video and audio to synchronize, and there were other versions, there's an open source Flash, you know, some guys tried to recreate Flash, you know, just separately from Macromedia Adobe, and they did an okay job, but it's not even close to Flash 7, and Flash 7 for Linux is terrible.
Scott: So they hired one dude, well, it's one dude, but he has a lot of help, and he works at Adobe Macromedia, and his job is to make the Linux Flash.
Rym: In fact, we saw way back when the job posting for this came out, and all the Linux people were, "Ooh, they're finally gonna fix
Rym: it.".
Scott: Yep, and there was this guy blogged the whole thing, you can go read the guy's blog, he keeps updating it, even today, you know, and you can see the whole development of Flash for Linux.
Scott: Recently, as in last week, two weeks ago, pretty recently, Flash 9 Beta, not the final version, but the Beta, came out for Windows, Mac, and Linux.
Scott: All three systems.
Scott: And let me tell you, it is now the awesome, I mean, there are a lot of people having problems, you know, just, like, my parents had real problems on Linux, like, they'd go to websites, they'd want to do stuff, it wouldn't work, they couldn't go to a website and do what it said there, because it would just say, "Oh, you don't have Flash 8, tough
Scott: shit.".
Scott: Well, now they have Flash 9, and it is awesome.
Scott: The sound works, it's very fast, all the functions work when you try to play a game.
Rym: The only complaints I've seen were from people who don't understand Linux and didn't install it, right?
Scott: Yeah, I mean, all you have to do is take one file and put it in a folder, and then this will just work.
Scott: In Firefox, at least.
Scott: I haven't tried it with any other browsers, I probably should.
Rym: Some people have had trouble, because there is no 64-bit version.
Scott: Ah, that is true, there is no 64-bit version.
Rym: So if you're running a 64-bit computer, you have to have a 32-bit compiled version of Firefox, or it won't work.
Scott: Ah, that is true.
Rym: And a lot of people are mad, because they don't want to run 32-bit Firefox on their awesome 64-bit machine, even though, for Firefox, the performance gains are probably minimal if not negligible.
Scott: Yeah, the one thing I do have to say, you know, if someone's talking about open source, and you don't, you know, a lot of people say, "What do I care if I can get the source, I don't know how to mess with the code,".
Scott: well, that's true.
Scott: But if source code is available for a program, if it's an open source program, it is possible to build that source code for any platform, for any chip ever.
Scott: And that is, you know, to me, that is really the most important thing about open source software, is that if the program's open source, it doesn't matter what computer you have, you know, you can get that program to work on that computer if the computer is powerful enough.
Scott: And Flash, while now it works for Linux, which is good, a lot of open source zealots aren't gonna use it, well, you know, good for them, but it is annoying that, you know, we don't have the source, so we can't compile it for 64-bit, we can't compile it for Amiga.
Scott: It's pretty much Windows, Mac, and Linux, 32-bit, and that's it.
Scott: They decide what platforms Flash 9 will work on, and we don't.
Rym: And it's not really that they're being evil in this case, it's that they really don't know.
Rym: I mean, they couldn't make a working Linux plugin for the longest time, they finally admitted they didn't know, and tried to hire someone who knew about Linux to do it for them.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure this guy knows that it's not working in 64-bit, and I'm sure he's thinking about it.
Scott: I think he's probably just, you know, his blog probably has the answer.
Rym: I'm not talking about the guy, I'm talking about the company.
Rym: Oh yeah, but-- I mean, the company I work for now, they don't know anything about Linux or open source at all.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: I mean, I say, like I suggest, "Oh, just use an SSH tunnel for something," and I get blank looks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think that is really, you know, people say, "Oh,".
Scott: you know, they argue against open source, or they think that people argue against open source, like, "Oh, someone will hack it 'cause they can see your source and find your vulnerabilities and get you,".
Scott: or, "Oh, you know, it's free, it can't be
Scott: good.".
Scott: No, the real reason that open source doesn't succeed is because people don't know about it.
Scott: They're uninformed and ignorant of open source and Linux, and, you know, they either don't even know it exists, or they don't have the information.
Scott: And if we just had some sort of campaign of spreading the word, you know, that would do wonders more than, you know, arguing with people who come up with stupid arguments that don't mean anything, like, uh, what's another famous anti-open source argument?
Scott: "Oh, it won't work with anyone else's computers.
Scott: Well, we can't do
Scott: business.".
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, that was a valid argument back in the days of Red Hat 5.
Scott: Yeah, now it's not.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: I can't say it in my usual loud way because I don't want to trip the fact that I don't have a compressor in front of me.
Rym: It's really hard to do the show.
Rym: I gotta be careful about all this stuff again.
Scott: Compressor.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Of course, I mean, I thought, "Oh, what if it doesn't sound that bad?
Rym: 'cause we've gotten better and people will, you know, oh, they didn't really need to spend money on that compressor,".
Rym: but we just listened to it.
Rym: and yeah.
Scott: Yeah, we need the compressor.
Scott: It makes things a lot nicer and easier, and Ray won't yell at me 'cause he's an ass.
Rym: Yeah, I yell at Scott all the time about his microphone discipline.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: I'll do what I want.
Scott: Do you have a thing of the day?
Rym: Well, I do have a thing of the day.
Rym: Once again, it seems I had this thing of the day for like three weeks, but I keep saying, "Oh, 'cause I always find something better on Monday,".
Rym: and once again, I was on Dig today and I was looking around.
Scott: I always read the science section of Dig, mostly- That's the section I mostly avoid, specifically the health subsection 'cause it's full of bullshit.
Rym: Now, in fact, that's the reason I go there.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: I go into the health section and I go into the upcoming stories and the main stories and I bury every piece of Randy, every piece of bullshit, every piece of incorrect science, every link to a crackpot blog, all the bad science out there.
Scott: I do this every day and I- So you bury 99% of the stories in that section.
Rym: I bury about 10 to 20 stories a day.
Rym: I also go into those stories and mod or dig everyone down who doesn't know what they're talking about.
Scott: Wow, you really don't have any time.
Scott: I don't do anything at work, but I read a comic book today.
Rym: Oh, you know, it doesn't take me long to dig people down.
Rym: When I go into a Dig thread, I play a Mr.
Rym: Period in this case.
Rym: I will just go through and dig anyone down who doesn't have proper grammar at a glance, no matter what they had to say.
Scott: Good move.
Rym: And then anyone who's talking Randy, it's usually easy to tell because they say certain kinds of words and if you see that word, it's obvious.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Holistic is the word to watch out for.
Rym: So anyway, today there was a particular preponderance, I like my little alliteration, of Randy and it was all kind of similar Randy.
Rym: And then I noticed that all these Randy stories I was digging down and burying were from the same website.
Rym: And then I noticed they had also all been submitted by the same person.
Scott: Wait, wait, wait.
Scott: So maybe if we submit every single episode of GeekNights to Dig, over time, a bunch of them might get dug up crazily if we just keep doing it all day long.
Scott: Like if we take a day off work and just submit every episode of GeekNights to Dig one after the other.
Rym: It's worth a shot.
Scott: Yeah, and it worked for some person with a bunch of bullshit crackpot stuff.
Scott: It'll work for us, right?
Rym: Yeah, because some of these have gotten two or three hundred digs, which is really sad.
Scott: Some of them got to the front page.
Scott: They popped up in my Google Reader, which I wanted to talk about, but I'm not going to.
Rym: So my thing of the day is very simply, if you're on Dig, I highly recommend that you ignore anything ever posted by a user named Rhiannon1214.
Scott: In fact, can you make someone your enemy on Dig?
Rym: No, but you can block them so you never see anything they do.
Scott: Oh, I'm totally doing that.
Rym: See, I won't do that, because then I won't see them to bury them.
Scott: Oh, but you can book, oh, maybe, no, that's no good.
Scott: You don't want to mark them as a friend.
Rym: No, no.
Scott: What if you block them, right, and then you bookmark their page and bury them anything they have.
Rym: Something else I'd like to note about this.
Rym: This Rhiannon1214 may or may not be Mr.
Rym: Lou Rockwell, who apparently is the vice president of the Center for Libertarian Studies in Burlingame, California.
Scott: Wow, that's so fucked up, because it's so weird, because all the libertarians I know tend to be on the Randy side.
Scott: They don't like Randy stuff.
Scott: They're anti-scams and anti-bullshit medicine and they're for truth and science and all that other good stuff.
Scott: So someone to be all Randy and believing in bullshit medicine and being a libertarian, that's fucked up.
Rym: In fact, it says his name, comma, is an opponent of the central state, its wars, and its socialism.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, you know I always say, I'm a libertarian with a lowercase l. That's the reason why.
Scott: Yeah, that guy sounds like a nutjob.
Rym: So he's got this nutjob blog and it has all this pseudoscience nutjob stuff, and this guy on Dig keeps linking to it constantly.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Okay, I wish someone ... Yeah, actually, that'd be cool.
Scott: One of our listeners went through and dug every episode of GeekNights one after the other.
Scott: That way it wouldn't be us.
Rym: I would go dig them up, I guess.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: The good ones.
Scott: This one I might dig down.
Scott: I might bury this one deep.
Rym: I think I'll bury every episode we do until we get that compressor back.
Rym: God damn.
Scott: God damn.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Wow, it's so weird to look over at the compressor and the lights are not ... Alright.
Scott: My thing of the day, there's a show, there's a new TV show in the UK, so UK people, we need your help giving us more info on this, called The Big Idea, and it says here- Well, Scott, what's The Big Idea?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Well, they say that it's a TV show which pits inventors ... I'm reading from the website directly because I'm lazy.
Scott: It pits inventors and entrepreneurs against one another for a chance to have their invention or business idea realized and to win 100,000 pounds.
Scott: Alright, that sounds cool to me.
Rym: 100,000 pounds is a lot in American dollars.
Scott: Yeah, that's like almost 200,000 pounds.
Scott: And one of the commercials for the show is a video of 10,000 British pounds.
Scott: Now if you've never seen a single British pound coin, it's a really heavy coin.
Scott: I mean, it weighs, and it's thick.
Scott: It's like as thick as three quarters or two and a half quarters.
Scott: It's not as big as a quarter circumference radius size, but it's a big freaking coin.
Scott: You give someone a pound, it's like, "God damn, there's a
Scott: pound.".
Scott: And they lined up 10,000 pounds like dominoes, and they go ticka, ticka, ticka, ticka, ticka.
Rym: So we were going to talk about audio codecs today, like we said, to continue our codec theme, but one, we really don't want to waste a good episode on a night when we don't have all of our audio equipment together.
Scott: And two, our previous codec episode we didn't think went so well.
Rym: Yeah, because it seems like those of you in the audience who want to know the technical details can just look it up in Wikipedia or already know them.
Rym: And those of you who don't want the technical details don't really care at all about the codecs other than how to get them.
Scott: Yeah, we think we finally figured out.
Scott: the Monday episode is, you know, in college I took a lot of classes on like science, technology, and society.
Scott: There was actually a whole section of the liberal arts school called like STS, and I took that as a, I don't know if it was a minor, it was a concentration.
Scott: I think I took enough classes in it to be a minor, but I didn't do the paperwork.
Scott: I didn't care.
Scott: It didn't matter anyway.
Scott: And, you know, we're going to try to talk about like topics in science and technology, stuff like, you know, "Oh, well, how was this?
Scott: What kind of effect will this have on the
Scott: world?".
Scott: And, you know, "How does this change the way people think and the way people
Scott: act?".
Scott: And et cetera, et cetera.
Rym: Yeah, we're basically going to turn Mondays into more of an op-ed thing from our perspective as opposed to a straight up informative lecture.
Scott: Yeah, because the informative lecture seems to not work so well.
Scott: However, if you do have questions about computers and science, technology, and such, we don't know much about science.
Scott: Well, most science.
Rym: We have people we can ask.
Scott: Yes, we have people we can ask.
Scott: And we could probably solve your physics homework for you.
Rym: But actually, actually, yeah, I was bored out the other day and I ended up sitting down with my old program.
Rym: I wrote for my calculator and doing old physics problems.
Scott: Yeah, we could solve your physics homework for you, but we probably can't tell you any Stephen Hawking type shit.
Rym: No, no, we can make stuff up.
Scott: We could definitely make stuff up.
Scott: Anyone could do that.
Scott: But if you do have questions about technology, like how to information and help, you can either ask us in our forums or you can try to find me on QNU, Q-U-N-U dot com, which is a place where you can go to get help.
Rym: Or why don't they just ask us in the forums?
Scott: That, too.
Scott: But you can get me like on IM through QNU if you need help right now.
Rym: Or you can just track down his AIM name and get him directly.
Scott: No, don't do that, because I really don't like it when people IM me who I don't know.
Rym: But it's trivial to find your AIM name.
Scott: It is.
Scott: But I will most likely be rude to you and try to stop unless you're very unless you're really cool.
Scott: Like if you start saying really cool stuff, then I'll start talking to you because it'll be worth my time.
Scott: But most people who IM me that are strangers, my immediate reaction is, why is a stranger messaging me?
Scott: Go away.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: So you don't like it when strangers talk to you, yet you're all about this sense of community.
Scott: Well, the thing is that most strangers having me tend to the track record of strangers IMing me has not been good.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: Most of them, not all of them.
Rym: Scott, I'll note that the track record of strangers talking to us in the real world isn't much better.
Rym: I know.
Rym: So the situation is the same.
Scott: But in the real world, I can sum it up right away.
Scott: It doesn't take long.
Scott: And on IM, it's like wasting my time to figure out if it's worth it to talk to you.
Scott: You see what I'm saying?
Rym: Anyway, anyway, I could argue with that, but I won't.
Rym: I went to get a compressor because we'd probably get loud.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So the problem we had with the compressor gave us a topic for the show tonight because we noticed that, I mean, all my old equipment, I have a lot of old various bits of electronic hardware around.
Rym: And in the hardware manual, if anything I bought in the 90s or the 80s, it has a little thing where you can call them and order any replacement parts for anything.
Rym: I mean, the Nintendo, you could just order an extra power adapter or an extra RF cable.
Rym: All my old electronic stuff, like my electronics kits, you could order extra resistors or the, well, again, the power cable or the face plate or anything like that.
Rym: But now when we, you know, this compressor, we lost the power cable to it.
Rym: There's no way in the instructions or the website, at least obvious way, to order this part.
Rym: We've asked them, but there's no actual obvious way to do it.
Rym: And stores like Radio Shack don't carry things like that anymore.
Scott: Yeah, back in the day, Radio Shack used to be, if you were just a normal person, you couldn't go to Radio Shack.
Scott: What were you going to get there?
Scott: You know, it was all a tandy computer.
Scott: Yeah, it was lol or a Radio Shack coco too.
Scott: No, it was a place for electronics hobbyists, people who wanted to make electronics, fix electronics, fiddle with electronics.
Scott: That was the majority of the store with soldering irons, wires, chips, resistors, all that kind of stuff just laid out there.
Scott: Nowadays, what's in that store?
Scott: Track.
Rym: It's like Scott said in the first half of the episode, it's a tiny Best Buy with less selection and higher prices.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it is another example of stuff getting dumb.
Scott: When I was a kid, I got a stereo, I think when I was 10, you know, and this had like a turntable, two tape decks, a radio, like a whole equalizer thing.
Scott: It was on this big wheeling stand and two big speakers that were as tall as it was, you know, big freaking thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And in the instruction book was a whole schematic of the entire stereo.
Scott: Like I could have built the stereo from the schematic and it came with the stereo.
Scott: So if it broke, I could have opened it up and killed myself, but I could have been fixing it.
Rym: Now, Scott, all of my audio equipment, even the newest stuff, everything I bought came with a full schematic.
Scott: Yeah, but that's audio equipment.
Scott: My video card doesn't come with one.
Rym: Well, because the schematic for your video card would be useless.
Rym: It's much more complex.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: But I'm saying you can go buy a stereo at Best Buy today.
Scott: You won't get a schematic.
Scott: If it's a consumer electronics appliance, it won't have any of that good stuff.
Scott: It'll just.
Scott: it'll just.
Scott: it's just a thing made for people to use.
Rym: But I feel like the audio equipment I bought, the schematic isn't there for people to use because they can't actually buy replacement parts or anything.
Rym: It's like it's.
Rym: I mean, I looked at it and I could think of a few people who would care about the schematic, but their market segment, the people who buy Behringer and Samson audio equipment are not going to be looking at the schematic very much.
Scott: I don't think they will know.
Scott: Maybe it's just to be cool or I don't know why they put it there.
Rym: I mean, I know why a lot of high end audio stuff has that.
Rym: I mean, you really want to know the path and figure out where noise is going to come from and all that.
Scott: Maybe they just put it there to make to look like high end audio equipment, you know, because there's probably some high end guy who will look at it and say, I'm not buying that.
Scott: But he sees the schematic on.
Scott: He's like, ah, that's the sign of a good.
Rym: But he's actually a high end guy who look at the schematic and go, oh, he might be.
Scott: But there are those stupid people who think they're high end.
Scott: You know, the audio file types trick a few of them into buying your product.
Rym: That's probably why everything I bought has blue LEDs.
Scott: Oh, it could be.
Scott: blue LEDs are very clever.
Rym: Yeah, it's just frustrating that we lost a simple dumb piece of equipment, a power cable.
Rym: But because it was a specific power cable and there is no store within driving distance of us that sells generic power cables, we're stuck.
Rym: There is nothing we could do to have a compressor tonight.
Scott: You know, it's like there is this demand and it's a pretty high demand for, you know, a real electronics store like they had back in the day.
Rym: Well, is there really a demand?
Scott: But the demand isn't centralized enough in any one place for a physical store.
Scott: But to order on the Internet, it takes so long to get the product.
Scott: I mean, on the Internet, it's easy to get this kind of stuff.
Scott: You know, I mean, this particular.
Rym: really I looked in our particular one.
Scott: I mean, we could probably find a generic one on some other shady website pretty easily.
Scott: But this, you know, from the same company, it depends on the company.
Scott: But, you know, the Radio Shack website does have all the stuff that they used to have in stores all the time.
Scott: And so does the catalog.
Scott: They haven't taken anything out of it.
Scott: You can still get, you know, the pillow speaker, the famous Radio Shack pillow speaker still in there, you know, and all that good stuff.
Scott: But yeah, you can't get it immediately.
Scott: And a lot of electronic stuff you have an immediate need for, you know, if something breaks, you need to go out and get a new one right now.
Rym: Well, Scott, except the thing is, most people don't care.
Scott: Most people don't care.
Rym: So there really isn't a market for it.
Scott: Well, there is a demand.
Scott: And, you know, while it's not a majority of the population is a minority, it is still a big enough number to be a lot of money.
Rym: See, I don't think it is at all, because if it's dispersed like that, then there's no way to have a business that could serve that purpose and make a profit.
Scott: Internet business, pretty much.
Rym: But if it's an Internet business, then people can just get from other Internet businesses that already exist.
Scott: I know.
Scott: And those are the Internet businesses that are making money.
Rym: And even then, I still don't think there's enough demand because people don't care at all.
Rym: Very few people use equipment like this.
Rym: And what percentage of them lose the power cable?
Rym: And how many of them just buy another piece of equipment?
Scott: Yeah, it is a good point.
Scott: We often complain about non-geeks not knowing enough about computers, not knowing enough about technology.
Scott: And I think part of that is, you know, not just because you no longer have to know, but because they don't even provide the information.
Scott: You know, they just totally hide everything.
Scott: So even someone who might have figured it out on their own, you know, they're not going to because it's all this hidden mystery stuff.
Scott: now instead of being, you know.
Scott: Instead of being here it is, but you don't have to know it, it's we're not even going to show it to you.
Rym: Yeah, well, I guess the companies are smart in that they don't make any more money by providing all of these niceties.
Rym: I mean, a lot of equipment, electronic equipment back in the day would even come with like some resistors with it or an extra bit just in case it broke.
Rym: So you could just replace it and instructions on how to replace it.
Scott: Well, I think that actually is because back in the day, a lot of those things are prone to breakage and you needed that or else you were screwed.
Rym: Yeah, but even back then, I think including those things was from a market perspective.
Rym: I mean, I wasn't going to compare then to now on that regard.
Rym: I was going to say, but back then they didn't make any sales by having that in there.
Rym: That was a nice thing to do, but I don't think a significant number of people would have not bought the product had it not come with that.
Scott: I think also, if they don't allow expect you or if you're not expected to be able to repair your electronic devices and they make it so that you're so dumb, you can't possibly, you
Scott: know, even
Scott: think of repairing your electronic devices, you'll just buy a new one whenever one breaks.
Rym: Of course, that might also just come out of the fact, like with the video card, that a lot of things are complex to the point now that you really can't repair them.
Rym: or it's with, you know, economy of scale, it's not cost effective from anyone's point of view to just do anything other than replace, like a vacuum cleaner.
Rym: There used to be vacuum repairmen or VCRs, they're VCR repairmen, TVs, there were TV repairmen.
Rym: It takes so much manual labor to repair a TV that it's always cheaper, both from a labor perspective and a money perspective, to buy a new TV than to hire someone to spend their time and effort fixing your individual problem.
Scott: There are still a few TV repairmen
Scott: out there,
Scott: but they don't really do a lot of business, not that there's, you know, I mean, occasionally they might replace a backlight in an LCD, you know, but I said, you know, but
Rym: yeah, for anyone who wasn't listening recently, Scott has, I guess, gotten a virus that interjects the word, you know, into random sentences on a semi-regular basis.
Scott: The point is, a lot of those repairs, if they get done now, are done by the factory or by the retailer, like Best Buy, and they sell the units as refurbished.
Rym: Well, you know why?
Rym: Because if they, I mean, they know the types of problems that a product is prone to.
Rym: So if they get the products in, they can ship them off to an expert center where people have everything they need to fix them as efficiently as possible and get them back out.
Rym: And in that way, it's cheaper than manufacturing new ones.
Rym: They can sell them refurbished, recoup some of their costs.
Rym: But for an individual to go somewhere and get it repaired, they have to go to an expert who has to spend a lot of time figuring out what their problem is, figuring out how to solve it, solving it.
Rym: And by then, it's already cost more net human resources than just manufacturing a new one in the huge economy of scale factory.
Scott: Yeah, there does seem to be a business in computer repairs because it's a whole.
Scott: software versus hardware is a whole different, what do you call it?
Scott: Paradigm?
Scott: Yeah, that's the word I was looking for.
Scott: Ah, you know, finally, I said, what's the word I'm looking for?
Scott: And Rym said the right word instead of going, I don't know what the hell word you're looking for.
Rym: Well, usually because you'll say, blah, blah, blah, what's the word?
Rym: And I'll list like 10 words like, nah, nah, not that one.
Scott: Nah, we got it right on the first try this time.
Scott: We did.
Scott: And, you know, there seems to be a business in computer repairs because people don't know about computers, but they have one, they need one and they break often, especially if their windows can Dells and stuff.
Scott: Well, there's also the fact that yet, but there still seems to be a large contingent of people who get spyware and they'll just buy a new computer.
Rym: Well, yeah, because they think the computer is slowing down and they figure obviously it must be the hardware getting old.
Rym: So they buy a new computer.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what to say about that.
Rym: I think we just need to open our computer shop and capitalize on that.
Scott: I think we do.
Rym: I just don't know.
Rym: I think I would still feel like I was cheating someone if I charged them 80 bucks to de-spyware their machine.
Scott: No, I don't know, man.
Scott: It just screwed up.
Rym: You know, to go off on a tangent, this is a problem that a lot of technology professionals have in that they don't see the work they do as being valuable or difficult or full, you know, requiring much effort because the work is actually really easy because it's the thing we specialize in.
Rym: We know about it.
Rym: So when someone asks us to fix their computer, we usually just do it and don't even think about charging money or anything.
Rym: So a lot of people now have this expectation that technological or computer support is free and they could just ask their geek friend.
Rym: And then as a result, they don't actually learn anything on their own.
Rym: And at the same time, we don't get paid.
Scott: Yeah, and it just makes things worse and sort of a spiral if they keep asking for more help and we keep spending more time and it gets more and more annoying and, you know, then they never learn anything.
Scott: No one ever figures out how their computer work.
Scott: And it's it's really seems like the consumer electronics industry wants to make everyone dumb so they can take more money away from them instead of.
Scott: if people were smart, it would be really hard for them to make money, especially look at cell phones.
Scott: If people knew about technology, cell phone companies couldn't make any money because no one would pay for a ringtone.
Scott: No one would pay to download a video.
Scott: Everyone would plug their cell phones into their computers with USB or Bluetooth and do everything from there for free with their home Internet connection.
Scott: They customize the hell out of their phone.
Rym: I think that's very much a post hoc Procter hoc thing in that the cell phone companies know and they restrict the technology specifically to prevent that.
Rym: And even if they I mean, a lot of people are finding out that cell phones the rest of the world are much better than U.S.
Rym: cell phones and there's nothing they can do about it.
Rym: It's not like they can go to the competition.
Scott: Well, no, but there are quite all the it seemed.
Scott: if you go to forums like I was looking at the forums for the Motorola Q, you know, which is a Motorola's new smartphone.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I might get it.
Scott: I'm not sure yet.
Scott: I got to actually play with one.
Scott: All the smart people who know what they're doing have unlocked these things and they do all the shit.
Rym: But a lot of phones just can't be unlocked.
Scott: Well, those are shit phones.
Scott: that, you know, the smartphones are the phones that are actually capable of doing interesting things.
Scott: The normal everyday phones aren't really capable by old phone.
Rym: That old ass phone.
Rym: Remember that thing?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That thing had GPS stuff and I could have done a lot of stuff with that, but they specifically prevented in the firmware any of the GPS data from ever leaving out of a data port.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's some things a phone can do and some things a phone can't.
Rym: But I think in terms of other industries, I doubt many of them actively think let's keep the customers dumb and milk them for money.
Rym: I'll bet it's just they think it's not worth it to provide a level of support or we don't have to care about it or, huh, they're buying more computers, whatever.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But what was the thinking back in the day?
Scott: Who was the guy who said, you know, when they were putting together the instruction manual for my, you know, two tape decks and a, you know, turntable, any, you know, and a turntable stereo that they should put the circuitry diagram in?
Rym: You know what I'll bet it was?
Rym: The engineer who designed it said these are the things that are commonly going to fail.
Rym: Let's include them and some instructions.
Rym: And now there is a middle manager who says, why would I include that?
Rym: That just costs more money.
Rym: I think the engineers used to be closer to the final product, which wasn't always a good thing because it often ended with somewhat obscure ergonomics or somewhat obscure interfaces.
Rym: Non-intuitive methods of using things, instructions that were written not for the consumer, but for another engineer.
Scott: You know, I think it also goes back to the whole open source, closed source thing is back in the day, originally, computers were all open source.
Scott: There was no such thing as closed source.
Scott: You know, everyone knew the source code because you wrote an assembly and that you looked at it and there it was.
Scott: And then they had, you know, the computer clubs that people like Steve Jobs and Woz and Bill Gates and all the things they did.
Scott: That was all open source.
Scott: Everyone was showing off what they did.
Scott: And, you know, all the circuitry.
Scott: You'd go to Radio Shack, you'd buy a computer.
Scott: Everything was obvious.
Scott: You know, you just bought the same chips that were in that computer, put together your own computer.
Scott: Everyone knew how everything worked.
Scott: All the documentation was, you know, gettable in some way, even if it was hard to get.
Scott: Everyone was sharing.
Scott: And then they closed up the source and they also closed up the hardware documentation and all that other stuff all at the same time.
Rym: Well, I know the 486 that I got, my first computer, my first real computer, at least, came with two instruction books.
Rym: It came with an instruction book for all the software it came with.
Rym: And it came with an instruction book for the hardware that went down to showing the voltages, the pin outs on the serial cables and the parallel ports and the internal comports and the modem and all the PCI cards and where the firmware stuff and a diagram of the motherboard, what all the dip switches did.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, some stuff still comes with a pretty good manual.
Scott: But if you compare like the motherboard manual I got for my Pentium 3450 to the one that I got for the newest computer, there is a tremendous, tremendous difference in the amount of useful information there.
Scott: I mean, the one that came with the Pentium 3450 motherboard, it tells you what every single pin on the motherboard does, even the ones you're never going to use.
Scott: And it tells you every single BIOS option and exactly what it does.
Scott: Now, the new ones are just kind of like, yeah, choose this and this and this and this and very vague descriptions of what things do.
Scott: And it doesn't tell you which pin exactly is which, just like, yeah, those pins over there are kind of for this and those ones are kind of for that.
Scott: You'll figure it out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, we just ran in for a bit since we kind of got thrown off topic by not having a compressor.
Rym: I apologize again for the audio quality, which may be more or less apparent to you, depending on whether or not you're listening in a car or whatever.
Scott: If you're listening in a car, this episode might be unlistenable.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Luckily, I think we'll mitigate this by possibly playing our Luke Crane interview tomorrow and hopefully by Wednesday we'll have a power cable so we can use the compressor again.
Scott: Who knows when we're going to have a power cable?
Scott: We might have to put in like a special order for a new compressor.
Scott: If anyone wants a compressor without a power cable, we will sell it to you.
Scott: Possibly.
Rym: I'm pretty sure we can get a hold of a power cable, hopefully, if we can't, though.
Rym: Yeah, we'll think of something.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com.
Scott: And if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight, Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.