Rym: It's Wednesday November 21st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott And this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We finally do it.
Rym: we discuss hentai.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: so I've been riding the train to the city for many moons now and the day before Thanksgiving is Consistently the most busy train day of the year.
Scott: They don't put out any extra trains for some reason.
Scott: Yeah, they do do they?
Rym: Yeah, there were like four extra trains.
Scott: I didn't notice any extra trains, but even if they were the trains going to the city On this day are always really empty because no one goes to work or at least a lot less people go to work.
Scott: But the trains coming home are packed to the brim standing room only.
Scott: it's crazy now.
Rym: Scott warned me I didn't even think about this because I hadn't been working down in the proper part of the city.
Rym: I've been working up in the Bronx, so I'm thinking you I'm gonna get my 410 train home and Scott's like yeah I'm getting on the three something.
Rym: Oh my god the craziness.
Rym: So I walk down.
Rym: It's about 406 it's about 405 and I walk into Grand Central.
Rym: I see my 410 train and then I see about to leave a 405 train that goes to one place beacon.
Rym: Oh, yeah, well and Poughkeepsie, but that's past beacon.
Rym: so it doesn't exist.
Scott: It also goes to New Hamburg which is in between, but that doesn't matter Hamburg exists even less.
Scott: I know.
Rym: I went there once when a friend of ours visiting us missed the stop And I had to drive to New Hamburg and pick him up.
Rym: But yeah, I get on this train and like Scott said it's standing room only.
Rym: yep I was not lying until I realized that no it wasn't standing room only in the three across seats.
Rym: Almost every one of them had no one sitting in the middle.
Scott: well You gotta understand that the way the train is laid out at the ends of the train cars There are these four-seaters with this two seats facing two seats and you can fit two people there.
Rym: if you're lucky.
Scott: those things are God-awful, it's mostly because any you know as long as it's for children You can fit like six children there.
Scott: But because your knees are gonna You're basically if two people sit across from each other your knees at the other person's knees.
Rym: now remember This is only on the old crappy cars.
Rym: if you take the nice new electric cars that only go to Croton Harman It's not a problem.
Scott: the problem is we live so far away from the city that we have to use a diesel train which has Different train passenger cars.
Scott: the electric trains have very nice better passenger cars that are superior in every way But anyway, but they want to extend them electric Other than the four-seaters where it's two seats facing two seats.
Scott: There the others the all the other seats are One half of the train is three-seaters And then there's an aisle to walk down and the other half of the train is two-seaters.
Scott: now for some reason people have no Problem sitting two people and the two-seaters, but in the three-seaters People don't like to sit three people in the three-seater.
Scott: They only like to sit one person in one seat one person in the other and then one nothing in the middle.
Scott: They don't like anyone sitting in the middle.
Rym: rule on any New York City transit is that if there's a seat you have to make it available and you cannot take up more than one seat no matter what.
Rym: yes, so I Well, I've never had to stand on a train because there's always a seat somewhere.
Scott: The last time I was on the last time I took the train the day before Thanksgiving the entire train Every two-seater had two people and every seat three-seater had three people and every four-seater had four people and people were standing in the Isles.
Rym: so today ever like there's hundreds of people to stand and ever in the aisles in the vestibules And I look and there's a bunch of seats.
Rym: So I just walk up to a random spot, and I say excuse me is anyone sitting in the middle there?
Rym: And the guy looks horrified Absolutely horrified.
Rym: II he got a mumble something to me Nicely dressed guy and the guy sitting there's on the other end is just kind of quiet and he kind of gets up to let me in and I sit down in the middle and Then he walks away and stands for the whole hour ride home, and I got the seat to myself.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Then everyone else is just standing there.
Rym: There's plenty of seats But no one would just ask if they could sit in the middle which they are allowed to.
Rym: everyone's just so afraid of Touching another person or talk to another person.
Rym: It's kind of scary.
Scott: Yeah, I have no problem asking to sit in the middle or anything like that.
Scott: I just if I if there's a seat I'm gonna take it.
Scott: the problem was last time the train was so crowded there was no seat But I guess this time on the train I was riding today.
Scott: many of the three-seaters were had three people But there were a few that only had two and there are plenty of people standing.
Rym: so but anyway I figure we should get right into it because I don't have a news.
Rym: We've been trying to Shall we say avoid the anime news now?
Scott: Is that in America in the United States where anime is imported and not something we make so much?
Scott: it's very anime news.
Scott: Anime news network is pretty much as a monopoly in anime news.
Scott: It's not like they control the anime news and don't let anyone else report on it.
Scott: It's just that they report on all of it and no one else really does.
Rym: so they're basically The AP wire for anime and that the anime is something.
Rym: wire and then awesome anime world order and everyone.
Rym: we pretty much just Look through there for the news.
Scott: Yeah, so we're trying to avoid doing an anime news so much because you know There really isn't that much anime news right now and anime news network is the only place it comes from and you can read anime News network, you don't need to listen to us.
Scott: So unless you have an interesting commentary on the news.
Scott: What's the point?
Rym: Well, there was the odex news, but I don't really care.
Rym: Anyway, we got a geek back here.
Rym: It's kind of long, but I'm gonna read it and I think I believe that What I'm going to respond is going to be kind of self-evident by the end of it and we've had an ongoing Conversation with this gentleman for the last few hours.
Rym: So this is from Ray Moo.
Rym: I Just listened to your 10-7-7 show where you discussed shounen fighting anime and I must say I'm disappointed.
Rym: Your argument was not very well thought out or coherent.
Rym: The first point you raised was that you dislike the use of deus ex machina plot devices to revolt resolve conflicts in the show.
Rym: However, this is a criticism of the show's writing and not of the genre itself.
Rym: Not only that but there is nothing inherently wrong with that mechanic either.
Rym: Look no further than Gurren Langan just a lagann Example of where it is used to great effect.
Rym: after that you expressed dismay for long drawn-out fight scenes.
Rym: yet Once again, there is nothing wrong with this mechanic.
Rym: Another contemporary example is Akaki.
Rym: Let me finish reading his email before I get to that which is you which uses this technique masterfully At the masterfully and I could hear two words.
Scott: I would not but anyone.
Rym: there are multiple Episodes that encompass the single a single round of mahjong.
Rym: Wow, okay.
Rym: Yet the show Creates an insanely tense atmosphere that has you on the edge of your seat the whole time because you're waiting like an hour for something to happen and holding your breath with each draw of a tile.
Rym: the pacing also allows time to digest the complex Involved in mahjong and fully appreciate what's going on?
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's ultimately.
Rym: your critique of shounen fighting genre is that you don't like bad writing and for execution.
Rym: did it editing.
Rym: Apparently we don't like bad writing in for execution, huh?
Scott: Apparently this is thanks for telling me what I don't like.
Rym: This is hardly revelation and hardly a critique exclusive to the genre.
Rym: I never said that.
Rym: I Never said that at all.
Rym: There's some other anime that is Poorly executed and written badly.
Scott: Oh, I can aim a whole bunch.
Rym: On a final note.
Rym: I feel like if you don't have the time to give an anime a fair shake Then you aren't qualified to discuss it.
Rym: There's nothing wrong with skipping episodes in certain cases either.
Rym: now I responded that last thing first because Dave from fast karate for the gentleman brought this up I think fairly succinctly.
Scott: they also did a whole show, you know talking about what reviewing means and I think This emailer here would do do well to listen to that episode of fast karate.
Rym: If you don't have time to give an anime a fair shake, what does it entail?
Rym: I mean if I watch the first I don't know 14 episodes of a show and it's not good.
Rym: I think it's fair to say that the show is not good.
Rym: Now if the show gets better 14 episodes in Well, something's wrong.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you have something that's all good.
Scott: That's part good and part bad.
Scott: You kind of have to sum up the whole thing.
Scott: It's only half good.
Scott: There are things in the world that are all good.
Scott: Those things are better than the thing that is half good.
Rym: That I mean, I'll put it this way Gasaraki is a great show, but it is kind of a slow show.
Rym: I would say that the pacing of gasaraki and the Investment build-up for payoff that is the line as far as I can go.
Rym: anything That's slower than that or has less payoff than that or just is.
Rym: ah, I couldn't deal with it.
Rym: That is it.
Rym: I barely watched gasaraki and while it was worth it.
Rym: I was barely worth it.
Rym: Anyway in regards to Akagi I don't know if you've played mahjong.
Rym: I don't know if you got everything, you know about mahjong from that anime, but Mahjong is basically a glorified game of chance.
Rym: It's kind of like poker.
Scott: It's really.
Scott: Mahjong is basically the same game Effectively the same game as gin rummy only with tiles instead of cards and different odds and slightly more free rules.
Scott: I've played and know how to play both the original Chinese mahjong at least how it is played these days and old Jewish lady mahjong, which is a sort of a bastardization of the game.
Scott: that is the way Jewish ladies like to play it and both of those games are.
Scott: You have to learn some basic strategy in order to be able to play the game.
Scott: But once you've mastered that strategy, which is simple the game comes down to randomness.
Scott: You might as well if you have the same.
Scott: if you and someone else both know You know how to play the game well enough you might as well just roll a d6 and see who wins.
Rym: See at least in poker like Texas hold 'em while the game is mostly random It comes down to how well you play your opponents.
Rym: in mahjong There's no playing your opponents.
Rym: That's not gonna happen.
Rym: I guess unless your opponents are stupid.
Scott: but yeah, it's just.
Scott: it comes down to your ability to remember what tiles have been thrown and What tiles your opponents likely have and likely want and don't give them those tiles?
Scott: I mean, you know sure there might be some psychology and you know someone might throw out a tile that might make you think You know that you know you they need this tile or that tile, but that's like such the you know,
Rym: so
Scott: Not even counting as a factor compared to just remembering what tiles have been out there and what tiles people have taken which matters So much more it doesn't even come into it
Rym: now in regards to saying that Akagi uses this technique Masterfully Akagi was boring as shit.
Rym: It was.
Rym: it was awful.
Scott: Don't watch Akagi I'll use a terrible show.
Scott: I watched like a few episodes of it.
Scott: the art and character design was you know It's stylistic and different for most other things you're gonna watch but it's also ugly unpleasant to look at and terrible the characters who are Simplistic and cliched.
Scott: the plot was you know, if you're gonna look for to compare Akagi to anything You got to compare it to hakara no go and hakara no go is a million times better than Akagi.
Scott: So What else you want me to say?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I mean we kept discussing with this kid and he won't let it go at least to his credit.
Rym: He writes fairly well, but he isn't really.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't really see anything I can argue with.
Rym: I mean Deus Ex Machina is good.
Rym: No Deus Ex Machina bad.
Rym: that means you didn't write well and didn't have any good foreshadowing or You're just making it up as you go.
Rym: And maybe it's not gonna be consistent in the long run.
Rym: It's usually a cheap way out.
Scott: Yeah, I can't think of any examples of a Deus Ex Machina that I can say.
Scott: I mean you might have something that's entertaining with a Deus Ex Machina.
Scott: Or if you have a really subtle Deus Ex Machina that doesn't seem too out there, you know It could somehow make sense within the setting then it won't be too bad.
Scott: But you don't really.
Scott: you know, if you don't go to writers class and they say yes Deus Ex Machina That is a sign of good writing that you won't say see anyone say that plus saying that it's a criticism of a show's writing And not the genre itself.
Scott: Almost every Shonen fighting show I've ever seen pulls the Deus Ex Machina Regularly and I would I would go so far as to say is that the plot structure.
Scott: if you were to write something Anything even if you were the bet even if you're Alan Moore, right a great writer If you were to write something with the plot structure required for it to be in the genre of Shonen fighting It is automatically bad writing
Rym: because remember
Scott: Unless you're doing a parody of a show to fighting to
Rym: show like initial D or even Akagi I'll give Akagi this credit if it's a real thing Then the audience can have realistic expectations about it and therefore there's a lot of implied Foreshadowing.
Rym: in a show like Naruto where they just make it up completely.
Rym: It's like we make up a technique But then we make up the way to beat it and then we make up the shadow technique that beats that technique.
Rym: That's very often not going to end with a good story.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: Oh You done with the I'm done.
Rym: I could just I mean he goes on to.
Rym: Scott basically responded to him and said Akagi is the worst show I've ever seen.
Scott: It's not the worst show.
Scott: It's one of the worst though.
Rym: Well, it's one of the worst that we actually watched more than I don't know.
Rym: five minutes of that's true.
Rym: We gave it a chance.
Rym: I'll give it bad Yeah But the fact that we gave it a chance and that it ended up being so bad it I think that show really does suck.
Rym: I really do I defy anyone to like that show other than this guy Someone who's like crazy about mahjong.
Scott: and actually there's a game of strategy instead of luck to any of you like it.
Rym: We played mahjong for like a year and a half at RIT and then one day We're all sitting there and we're like, wait a minute Isn't this game just random?
Rym: Yeah, it is just random.
Rym: Wow This game is really kind of random and crap and we never played it again.
Rym: Not once.
Scott: Nope Alright, so I have a tiny news which wasn't on my news network and that is you know It's the.
Scott: it's the week of buying shit in the u.s.
Scott: Here's there's a lot of buying going on.
Scott: So what are the anime companies putting out for you to buy?
Scott: because you know if they want to make mad moneys They're gonna put out good stuff this week, right?
Scott: They put out Death Note DVD number one.
Scott: Oh Snap that that.
Scott: what else can I say?
Scott: if you're a lot of people are into that it's good Buy it.
Rym: You know what holiday present if I hadn't read Death Note that that would be like the best anime I'd ever seen.
Scott: Yeah, probably but I read it.
Rym: So but even though I've read it I plan to watch a few choice episodes.
Scott: Oh on an unrelated note if you want Death Note volume 13 how to read sort of the supplementary appendix volume of Death Note that comes that sort of like explains stuff but is not actually part of the story.
Scott: you Can pre-order it this month for and it will ship two months from now in January Okay.
Scott: Now in addition to that I'm gonna do a geek bite.
Scott: you see I Think I've talked about this for a while.
Scott: But I pre-order the comics and they come in the mail and whatever and you know, I pre-order everything I know I'm gonna want and then sometimes I pre-order some stuff on a whim or I pre-order some stuff based on the description Or I pre-order some stuff by a writer I know but I'm not sure if this is actually good or not, you know, or I pre-order something that sounds good I don't know or something someone recommends whatever
Rym: and
Scott: most of the time when I pure to stuff like that I go Oh Disappointment.
Scott: This was why did I order this?
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: it's not so good, right?
Scott: But in the latest giant box of comics there were a couple things that I ordered You know just on a whim and they were pretty awesome and I was like whoo lucky me.
Scott: so One thing I read was basically this book called dungeon, right and it's by John I'm not I'm not sure if I'm pronouncing the person's name, right?
Scott: It's John's far which is the person who wrote rabbi's cat and Klezmer and you know the.
Scott: they write a lot of good stuff mostly Jewish stuff But dungeon is not Jewish in any way whatsoever.
Scott: It is literally a story about a dungeon and I you know that alone made me think huh?
Scott: This might be cool and I got it and it is hilarious in that sort of Hagar the horrible but more intelligent kind of way.
Scott: Aha, it's like a bunch of lovable characters in a dungeon and funny stuff happens in the dungeon And it really kind of makes me want to play dungeon keeper even though I never played dungeon keeper.
Scott: I know what it's about though and then I realized a new dungeon keeper 3 never came out and maybe someone should make a dude dungeon keeper game.
Scott: and yeah, if you like Dungeons and monsters and magic and that sort of stuff and dungeons There's a bunch.
Scott: I think there's like six volumes of dungeon and one or two volumes of dungeon parade.
Scott: I read the first volume of dungeon and the first volume of dungeon parade Which is actually the correct order to read them in and I was not disappointed.
Scott: I was in fact pleasantly surprised.
Rym: Huh funny you mentioned that because uh, it seems like we might be talking a little bit about dungeons in the second half of the show.
Scott: so The other book I got was I think it's James Sturm's America God gold and golems and it looked kind of cool.
Scott: You know, I like Americana kind of stuff and it was a comic and it was kind of highbrow looking.
Scott: so I got it and it's three stories and the first story is about God and the second story is about gold and the third story is about Golems and the golem store is the best because it's about Jews playing baseball.
Rym: Make a golem to play baseball.
Scott: No, it's better than that.
Rym: They make a golem to kill the other team while playing baseball.
Scott: No, it's.
Scott: it's very.
Scott: it's very poignant and American.
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: the first one takes place in like 1801 and the second story takes place during like, you know Gold rush, huh?
Scott: and the third story takes place in like the 20s and it's.
Scott: it's actually very kind of serious and and meaningful and and It's good stuff.
Scott: Wow, and you should you should get it if you like Americana or and Comics.
Rym: All right.
Rym: one last thing.
Rym: I know I've been mentioning this every week but I feel like I should and I will give all the details before it actually happens, but December 7th 8th 9th, New York City, Jacob Javits Center the New York Anime Festival.
Rym: We are going to be guests there.
Rym: we're doing a whole bunch of events.
Rym: want to see our match game want to see our Somewhat infamous gecky got panel only this time without the without the infamy without the stylings of one Gerald Rathcald Who may if we can convince him return to do it with us at katsuka.
Scott: I don't think he's gonna.
Scott: If he doesn't I'm saying he will to sort of apply pressure just in case.
Rym: Well, if he doesn't I'm gonna see if he'll give me half.
Scott: No way.
Scott: He promised he promised.
Scott: now he has to go.
Rym: Yeah This just in Gerald Rathcald is coming to katsuka.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No But maybe I can convince him to give me half of his visual aids.
Rym: I hope you understand which half I want and which half I don't.
Scott: Yeah, but the kind that won't get us in trouble because our panel is not 18 plus.
Scott: it is all ages now.
Rym: So well the pebble depends.
Rym: the panel at New York.
Rym: is it three o'clock on Friday?
Rym: Yes, it is pg-13.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: We can trade into our territory a little bit All right now.
Rym: the one at Katsucon we were gonna go.
Rym: pg-13 are but multiple independent members of the Katsucon staff have been periodically Emailing me and saying so you get a show that thing you showed at the end of the last one again.
Rym: Oh my god, that was the funniest thing ever to which I say No, probably not.
Scott: Anyway, whether the New York and a festival is good or bad because we have no idea.
Scott: It's a brand new Khan.
Scott: That's totally up in the air.
Scott: though I can say there's good things going for it and bad things going for it.
Scott: the parts we do will be good.
Scott: You know that for sure.
Rym: plus I mean it's being run by people who did the New York comic-con and they seem to know how it works And they seem to be running it pretty intelligent.
Scott: It's the same company, but the guy running the Khan itself the employee of that company seems to he knows what's up.
Rym: He really does seem to know what's up and he's trying real hard.
Rym: So we're gonna have an alley table.
Rym: anyone who goes you're going to see early sketch art of our swag in addition to basically all the previews of our swag.
Rym: and Even though we may not have all the actual swag there in time.
Rym: We're probably Possibly maybe going to be able to take preliminary pre-orders Prolet pre pre-orders free pre-orders first way.
Rym: I imagine if we do pre pre-orders how that'll work is.
Rym: if you commit to getting it you'll get a discount when it comes out.
Rym: Uh-huh, yeah, but seriously, we've got an artist working on some t-shirt designs.
Rym: They are of the highest quality.
Scott: Yeah, we just it's gonna take a while.
Rym: Well, it's hard.
Rym: I can make generic t-shirts and I'm thinking of making coffee mugs and all that stuff.
Rym: That's all easy, but T-shirts that are awesome and not just awesome to GeekNights listeners, but awesome to everyone.
Rym: Harder to get done and then harder to get printed.
Rym: and then we got to put forth all the money to print thousands and thousands.
Rym: And yeah, so well despite not wanting to use the anime news network for news I kind of noticed randomly that they have a webcomic right like anime news network.
Scott: the webcomic It looks like.
Rym: well it.
Scott: it's about it like Biting commentary on anime news.
Rym: It's an average webcomic.
Rym: Okay However, I went through much of the archives kind of quickly and I did notice this one gem.
Rym: All I want to say is that if you think that this comic is satire or that this is somehow an exaggeration of the truth The answer is that it is not.
Rym: so far from exactly what goes on at these cons.
Scott: No This comic could be.
Scott: I guarantee this exact thing happened at least once.
Rym: a hundred percent Exactly as you see it depicted in this comic, you know, there are people who'll read this comic and go I don't get it.
Scott: Yeah, they'll probably like hey what's going on?
Rym: What's wrong with that?
Rym: I mean, obviously he thought about this thoroughly.
Rym: That's quite a good commission there.
Scott: Yeah Good Alright, so I don't know if I've talked about this on the show before.
Scott: I tried to figure it out by searching But I'm not sure but it doesn't matter.
Scott: There's a guy named Lawrence Lessig and he is a famous lawyer a very important lawyer because he's pretty much like the Creative Commons Copyright kind of lawyer guy.
Scott: He's a semi moved on to dealing with issues of corruption instead of copyright because he came to the conclusion that Issues like copyright and global warming that he cares about aren't gonna be solved unless he solves the corruption problem first.
Scott: Regardless he gave this wonderful presentation at TED in like March of 2007 But it wasn't posted until November 2007 Which is now.
Scott: so you can now watch the presentation that he gave at TED in March and He's really good at presenting.
Scott: you can see him give all kinds of talks on YouTube and Google videos.
Scott: if you search It's not hard.
Scott: He's given tons of them and if you want to really know the deal of you know Why this Creative Commons going on and what it means.
Scott: and he doesn't actually mention Creative Commons in this because he's not allowed to sell Anything at TED.
Scott: that's sort of like the deal with the TED conference is you don't sell things there.
Scott: So he even says like yeah, I could mention something but I'm not allowed to sell anything.
Scott: He's talking about Creative Commons, but He talks about like Jean Philip Sousa saying, you know back in my day, you know kid people used to sit on the porch singing the songs of the day or the old songs and these Infernal machines are gonna ruin the vocal cords of the world.
Scott: and he talks about that in a modern Context and it gives three stories in one argument and if you he also used an anime music video as an example a particularly funny one involving a number num and Vampire Hunter D. Oh, man, so you should.
Scott: you should watch this.
Scott: It's very enlightening I think even if I use it similar Lawrence Lessig speeches a thing a day in the past.
Rym: Well, we have but it's always been on Monday and there are many many people who only listen to Wednesday GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, so if you're not like some tech nerd caring about copyrights, you're just looking at it from your anime fan sub perspective.
Scott: You should watch this video and it takes like it's 20 minutes long, which is kind of long to ask but you should watch it.
Rym: Anyway, so, uh Scott you you've been watching a lot of anime for all these years.
Scott: I've been watching anime since like 1990.
Scott: Well and knowing it was anime since like 98 99 Something like that and I've been watching anime not knowing it since I was like three watching transformers.
Rym: Yeah Since I was in fourth grade and I saw the sci-fi channel Saturday anime, but Ever seen any of that there?
Scott: hentai You know, it's kind of hard to go on the Internet's and the animes without, you know And being an anime communities without seeing some hentai, you know, I see some at the artists alleys I see some at the art show for hilarity.
Rym: one time our friend Steve just Randomly came into our apartment and showed us a bunch of hentai anime music videos.
Rym: Yeah unprovoked I might add.
Rym: yeah, you know, you know, we're sitting there we're bored.
Rym: Hey guys I got something we can watch.
Rym: it's on my laptop.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: What the fuck Steve?
Scott: Yeah, I've heard of things like the blue girl and the erosigatoshi.
Scott: Those are unavoidable.
Scott: I've seen I've read the miko 2010 manga.
Scott: I mean they're volume of it.
Rym: They're different levels.
Rym: I mean hentai.
Rym: we're not gonna get into the technical term of what is a hint a and what is it this and what is a Whatever.
Scott: I'm not even I don't care.
Scott: Yeah all we have to say is that if you don't know already hentai which is a word Americans use to refer to Anime and manga porn and in Japan the word hentai just means pervert.
Scott: That's and they.
Scott: but they also use it to refer to perverted things.
Scott: But they also say things like ecchi and arrow arrow and stuff like that.
Rym: now I am going to.
Rym: we're gonna use a kind of broad definition.
Rym: I think we'll consider hentai just for the purposes of discussion to be any of that perverted anime stuff.
Rym: pretty much cuz I mean.
Scott: I guess you could count a lot of those doujins and those slash things and oh my I mean if you wanted to like Sanctuary and like crying Freeman and all these like a lot of the gecky guys.
Scott: have you know straight up?
Scott: Well, you know uncensored screwing going on but it's not hentai because the Basically, my line is it's a hentai if it is a work of art that you know in manga anime form that is specifically made to arouse the reader or viewer through depiction of perverse and sexual
Rym: acts while some scenes in say dominion tank police when Anna Puma and Una Puma do that dance or the scene in Let's see.
Rym: What's a good example.
Rym: Oh in sanctuary when what's-his-name is having sex with that woman But she's on top and then she jumps off and makes a killer stock trade and then jumps back on Yep.
Rym: Seems like that can be erotic or arousing particularly in tank police, but that they're just a part of a wider story.
Rym: It's not like the story is as happy as a fence I would put it.
Rym: guy comes home guy gets laid guy gets tied up in the basement guy dies from getting laid First the large women then the speed to women then the large women again.
Rym: But no, I mean in fact sanctuary is even billed on the back as an erotic political thriller or something along those lines.
Scott: Yeah, so I guess if you took parts of sanctuary out, it would be just a hentai.
Scott: but in fact Maybe 10% of it is hentai in nature and 90% is not.
Rym: there's the gray areas Like there's wicked city and then there is as Dave from fast karate I keep bringing him up called it easy mode wicked city.
Rym: Demon City Shinjuku.
Scott: yeah, you know it's stuff that's got a lot of crazy crap going on a lot of screwing perhaps some even rapin and Tentacles and maybe lots of bits hanging out and excess boobage were unnecessary.
Rym: But now this is definitely different from fan service or that edgy stuff where oh, no I saw a panty.
Rym: it had a picture of a panda on it.
Scott: Yeah, but the like if you want something like Demon City Shinjuku, you know There's a nakedness.
Scott: Maybe this there's a lot of violence and some perverted stuff.
Scott: But it even though it's really bad It is a story about you know fighting and beating a monster and all that kind of crap.
Rym: So are a lot of hentai.
Scott: I know I know but that's it's a monster.
Rym: It's a monster of a different stripes.
Scott: There's more focus on them.
Rym: on this the plot often a soft focus, right?
Scott: Whereas if you watch something like Le Blue Girl, the plot is she's gonna get tentacled.
Scott: She's gonna get tentacled.
Scott: Oh, look, she's getting tentacled and you're it's sort of designed The.
Rym: they created it with the intent that people watching it would be spanking the monkey now back in the day Not to sound old but it used to be different with anime because I mean before people really got it anime was widespread Most of us kids.
Rym: after we found out about anime from the sci-fi channel the only way we could really get it was either to spend exorbitant amounts of money for single VHS's at Suncoast or We go to the local Blockbuster and the people at the Blockbuster didn't know what the hell anime was.
Rym: Sometimes they had a anime section.
Rym: Sometimes they had a Japanimation section.
Rym: Sometimes it was just in with the kids stuff.
Rym: But one thing was for sure Orochika doji and Armageddon would be sitting there right next to like go panda go panda.
Rym: Because they had no idea and furthermore a lot of us just we didn't really.
Rym: you know We wanted any anime we could get and I would pretty much.
Rym: every time I went to Blockbuster I grabbed the most interesting looking cover that I had not yet seen.
Rym: as a result a lot of earlier anime fans from our generation Saw hentai by accident I mean, I've got one of our friends.
Rym: we were talking about this over the weekend.
Rym: dragon half is hilarious.
Rym: Dragon half is one of my favorite like short funny OAVs.
Scott: It is absolutely all two episodes of it.
Rym: Well, there's a reason there's only two episodes.
Rym: Yeah, we're not gonna get into that.
Rym: So He had heard from a friend.
Rym: Yeah, there's this anime about a dragon girl.
Rym: It's called like dragon pink or something.
Rym: It's hilarious and he you know, he thought oh it this sounds great It sounds really funny and he went and he got dragon pink instead of dragon half.
Rym: Oops Uh, yeah, I'm not gonna tell you what the plot of dragon pink is, but you can guess.
Scott: Yeah Well part of what you know back in the day when they first brought anime over the way they marketed it was hey You know, let's if we you know, we want to market this.
Scott: as you know Animation that's not for kids and we want to aim for those nerds.
Scott: So they got the most sexiest mostly violent stuff.
Scott: they could get to show how different it was and that's what they marketed and they got all the violent stuff like the ninja scrolls and Whatnot and the hentai and they're the over fiends sort of came along with that.
Rym: Now the other thing was that as a kid, you know, a lot of shows kind of blindsided you with it, too.
Rym: I mean vampire hunter.
Rym: D was all awesome.
Rym: He's cutting that thing in half and he's cutting that other thing in half and then he cuts all those things in half.
Rym: He cuts that guy in half That other guy cuts that first guy in half and there's a lot of cutting in half and eyeballs getting stabbed.
Scott: I like the the faces in hands.
Scott: That's my favorite part of that guy was awesome.
Scott: That's the best character, but you'll notice him in my thing of the day.
Rym: I remember as a kid I saw it on the sci-fi channel.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: So I rented it and I brought it to my grandma's house.
Rym: I was like, oh man Cartoons and there was a bunch of scenes like.
Rym: I remember a scene where the girl was taking a shower then D's sitting outside Kind of acting strange and then that scene just kind of cut away and there was a different scene And then I remember I watched it.
Rym: No, he goes in there and has sex with her in the shower.
Rym: Huh or die?
Rym: I don't think he does that.
Rym: I think there's just a naked scene.
Scott: I don't really remember it Yeah, but basically like that.
Scott: that's sort of like, you know, you watch a live-action horror movie in the u.s.
Scott: And there's always like the obligatory like chasing the girl her shirt gets ripped off.
Scott: kind of scene, you know That's what that was in.
Scott: vampire.
Rym: hundred is sort of a horror accidental nakedness or like winds wind of amnesia Which was actually pretty good.
Rym: I at least I remember liking it.
Rym: I have not seen it in over a decade for all.
Rym: I know it's bad, but I liked it except the end was pretty much.
Rym: All right plots over.
Rym: Everything's been resolved.
Rym: you we've given you our Lesson on humanity.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: Now the guy's gonna have sex with that alien girl for like five minutes.
Rym: Alright, so let's talk about focused on him licking her nipple for a while.
Rym: It's like I just remember sitting there as like a sixth grader being Really uncomfortable and not wanting my mom to walk in.
Rym: but I didn't.
Rym: I wanted to see the end because I was worried that be More plot.
Rym: I really wasn't aroused.
Scott: I was just sitting there like All right, so let's talk about actual hentai here right?
Scott: so you got hentai.
Scott: It's it's someone drew a picture or animated pictures of people doing sex often Which is impossible sex type stuff and someone out there is watching this and being aroused.
Rym: Are you aroused?
Scott: because I'm not.
Rym: Well the most aroused I ever was by an anime was in Dominion tank police.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I really like, you know, I can watch me.
Scott: a normal porn, you know, as long as it's not a freaky porn You know.
Scott: and some porn is arousing some is not most is not actually but there's some porn out there.
Scott: It's hard not to be aroused unless you are I don't know biologically dead or you need vag or something, but Hentai really just doesn't do it for me and I kind of wonder about the people that it does do something for me.
Scott: Like what about their psychology or their biology?
Scott: Is it that makes them that way?
Scott: Is it is it a?
Scott: is it a born thing?
Scott: Or is it an environmental?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: What I'm not a I'm not a furry vore file.
Rym: I was just born that way.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: What do you think?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I really don't know and I need your nurture.
Rym: on the hentai enjoyment I really don't think I care to be honest.
Rym: I really just to me.
Rym: I look at it from a very simple perspective.
Rym: It's out there some people like it.
Rym: You can pretty much classify anime fans into people who don't really talk about it People who watch it and then that category gets broken up into two sides People who are aroused by it and then the people I didn't realize existed for a long time.
Rym: Ah, yes You can tell this one.
Scott: Okay, the thing about hentai right is that if you just watch a hentai for the purposes of arousal I mean not everyone who does that is a total scary freak But most people tend to be I mean the stereotypical hentai guy.
Rym: I mean I have never.
Rym: well with rare exception and because I can't say never I've actually met a few people.
Scott: I've met a few people who watch hentai and are not scary freaks You know and just get aroused at it the same way.
Scott: I watch porn and it just happens to be their thing.
Scott: There's nothing wrong.
Rym: I can say though that the majority of people I have spoken with who watch hentai are hentai.
Rym: There is one guy in particular.
Rym: I remember at RIT won't mention any names, but no doesn't matter was another Steve We knew like ten Steve's.
Scott: so yep.
Scott: It was a different Steve than the one who showed us the music video.
Rym: It's also a different Steve from the Steve that case Western warned us about.
Rym: and it's a different Steve from another Steve.
Scott: and There's a lot of Steve's.
Rym: half of them were good.
Rym: half of them were scared.
Scott: I know Steve in high school too, so it's like getting out of control.
Rym: so uh this guy You know he hangs out with us.
Rym: You know I like anime.
Rym: do you like anime?
Rym: And I'm like yeah, I like anime you like anime - we can be friends.
Rym: We're in college We can all be anime friends, and we're all at the anime club.
Rym: We're walking out from the anime club, and he's like man.
Rym: You want to come back to my place and watch them whatever and I didn't know what that show was.
Rym: no I want to go do something else okay, and I kept saying the names of these shows And I never heard of anyone.
Rym: and I thought I knew a lot about anime But I'd never heard a half of the things he'd bring up.
Rym: and then one day He just starts describing one while like two of us are eating breakfast at Gracie's, and he's like yeah So then he
Scott: disembowels the girl - Gracie's is the food court by the way - yeah,
Rym: then he disembowels the girl and then and I'm like wait a What he's like yeah, and this is when it gets really good.
Rym: And then they start to and he goes into a graphic description of this horrible hentai.
Rym: and at that point I was like ah all right look we're gonna.
Rym: We're gonna leave.
Rym: We're hoping that you'll stay there until we're gone.
Rym: So you keep eating.
Rym: You can have the rest of my food if you want.
Rym: I don't think it's.
Rym: uh.
Rym: I don't think I need it anymore.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: but then thanks to the people at the Happy House of hentai We were enlightened that you know while the vast majority of people watching hentai Are kind of scary and some are not And while we are not personally aroused by hentai that hentai does have a purpose in this world Basically the Happy House of hentai podcast.
Scott: we met them at Cinecon and we went to their panels because there wasn't much else doing Really for us.
Rym: I wasn't sure what to expect because most cons were.
Rym: I'd gone into a hentai panel.
Scott: It was scary.
Rym: and the worst is I went to one anime con, and it was late at night.
Rym: And I wander into a showing room and there's hentai on alright, and I look at the crowd.
Rym: It's like five dudes sitting there in silence enjoying it.
Rym: That was that was frightening to say the least.
Scott: yes But the Happy House of hentai people what they did in their podcast is there?
Scott: their podcast has some good bits.
Scott: It's like they.
Scott: they answered.
Scott: they go he goes online.
Scott: You find some like questions that people ask doctors about their you know sexy problems And he answers almost always dude go see a doctor.
Scott: I know, but it's so funny.
Scott: The answer is these questions.
Scott: I could just he could do a podcast of just answering those questions.
Scott: It'll be enough for me.
Scott: But they review hentai and I see review in the way that say I don't know.
Scott: Dave and Joel review things or the zero punctuation of the anger video game.
Scott: nerd review things you know.
Scott: they review hentai and They describe the plot of hentai in it.
Scott: It's sort of different hentai as they watch and sort of a literal not so literal way.
Scott: And if you look at it from the ironic standpoint, it's just hilarious.
Rym: I mean, there's.
Rym: it's kind of like.
Rym: you know.
Rym: you see something happen, and you don't really think much of it But then someone else just kind of lays it out for you.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you look at it directly like if there's a hentai and someone's disemboweling someone and screwing their insides I don't know or tying their penis with a rope so they can't ejaculate and then torturing them or if it's just What's the word ah?
Rym: Fortune ah You all right dick girls.
Rym: Oh futanari futanari.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: This is the thing you said.
Rym: what's the word?
Rym: and I had no context for that.
Scott: yeah So even if it's futanari or something right if you just watch futanari you just go.
Scott: ah oh god.
Scott: But if someone sits around if you sort of meta And you sort of like watch and take a step back and realize that This is a someone drew a picture of this it suddenly just becomes a big joke sort of like if you watch fist of the North Star.
Scott: it's like a dude making people's heads explode and some people they like a dude making dudes heads explode.
Scott: I could go for that.
Scott: sometimes I'm not you know you're not alone in that, but if you take a step back, and you say oh my god This is dude making dudes heads explode.
Scott: It's twice as good It's.
Scott: so I think I've discovered this use for hentai that was previously unknown to me in that It's basically ultra comedy if you take a step back from it and look at it from afar.
Scott: some of it some of it That's true.
Scott: There is some hentai that is so horrible that you can't make it comedic.
Rym: It's just horrible in all through and through, but it really helps if you're not even watching it.
Rym: There's this someone describing it in a very deadpan kind of but deadpan with foreshadowing and proper pausing.
Rym: like so the guy comes home, and he walks into the basement.
Rym: and What does he see, but the girl and a penis?
Rym: Second and then he's like now you might be asking yourself.
Rym: Are there any other people in the room besides this girl?
Rym: Now no there aren't.
Rym: you know where that penis is you know exactly where it is, and you know it's coming for him.
Rym: Oh, and watch out obviously he doesn't escape Otherwise it wouldn't be any fun.
Rym: Okay That's the kind of thing that that I don't know.
Rym: if I can do it justice.
Rym: I'm not that guy.
Scott: Yeah, I do think that the the only other thing I had to say about hentai at least maybe Rym has something else to say Is that it's sort of problematic for us in a way in that?
Scott: It's sort of because of hentai's popularity, and it's being brought over to the US and stuff There's sort of in manga and anime.
Scott: It's sort of a trap in a way.
Scott: It's like I think freedom of speech and all that stuff in freedom of the press.
Scott: We should you know expression We should have hentai.
Scott: it should be available to people who want it as long as it's not harmful which it isn't because it's all drawings right and That that's a good for them.
Scott: You know let those people have their thing.
Scott: But it's sort of because of its sort of spread.
Scott: There are people who get the improve.
Scott: there are some people out there who actually think that anime is just like naked porn Ultraviolet anime from Japan which is part of because of old marketing, but I had a teacher in high school.
Rym: He was a really cool guy.
Rym: He was a communist straight-up like red communist, but he was otherwise.
Rym: well, I guess.
Rym: otherwise he was a really cool guy, but He one day we're talking about Japan and he brings up the topic of moggings, and he basically said manga is this Ultraviolet form of comic book that is found in Japan Uh-huh, and I was like uh it's not all ultraviolet.
Rym: He was like yes, it is.
Rym: It's cathartic.
Rym: That's why there's no violence in Japan.
Rym: and the next day.
Rym: I brought in some tenchi muyo manga, and I was like ah You saying this is ultraviolet.
Scott: Yeah, yeah But that's sort of like those people who you know.
Scott: a lot of people think wrong things about foreign countries.
Scott: They're they haven't studied them enough.
Scott: You know that's just how it is.
Scott: but Regardless there's this sort of another catch with the yaois and stuff.
Scott: all these yaoi manga and the BL mangas are coming over Which is great for those BL fans.
Scott: let him let him do their thing.
Scott: I'm not I'm not into that.
Rym: obviously you all realize that there is going to come a day.
Rym: I don't know when it might be tomorrow.
Rym: It might be next year, but one day Somewhere out there in the
Scott: US
Rym: Someone's mom is gonna go into their 14 year old daughter's bedroom and pick up one of those you know picture books that she always gives her money for and See Sephiroth making a cast of his own penis in order to impregnate himself.
Scott: Like I did that one you made a cast of your penis to impregnate yourself.
Rym: Well now It was that time when we you remember right?
Rym: yes Yeah, you're making fun of me, but seriously not.
Rym: we were at a friend's house And for some reason a friend who had many yaoi doujins the topic something like that came up in conversation.
Scott: I think we were at a friend.
Scott: We're at a friend's house.
Scott: There are many people.
Scott: there was a semi party and the friend of the hat the friend who lived in that house one of the Friends who lived in that house had a large or semi large yaoi doujin collection Which is fine because they were a cool person whatever.
Scott: I didn't care what they did in behind their bedroom right and somehow making a cast of a penis came up in conversation.
Scott: So she runs into her bedroom goes under her bed Brings back a yaoi doujin of Sephiroth making a cast of his penis and then impregnating himself with it And then I don't know what was birthed from that, but that's all I saw.
Scott: that's all I needed to see.
Scott: in fact I saw too much but Someone's mom is gonna find out what the word yaoi means and there's gonna be ramifications in the u.s Yeah, it's really I mean I really personally I'm not so bothered by if you know BL.
Scott: Stop being printed in the u.s I mean I do think it should be allowed to be printed.
Scott: freedom of speech.
Scott: But because I don't care about it personally it won't bother me if it goes away.
Scott: What will bother me is the fact that it'll it might hurt Manga as a whole in the u.s.. If people start getting this wrong impression.
Scott: You know like one second You know some girl.
Scott: she goes and buys Naruto But she also goes and buys boys kissing and then mom finds the boys kissing and then no more Naruto.
Scott: sales Go down, but that's not good, but they love each other.
Scott: I'm sure I'm sure.
Scott: So yeah, there is that danger aspect of hentai And I think it would.
Scott: it's right now the industry seems to be sort of like being hush-hush And I think they really need to be more out with it.
Scott: It's like if you come out with it first You know and just warn people and then make it clear and instead of having you know sort of twisted and spun up stories out of the media from you know some Hype and outrage as opposed to stories from the industry about itself putting out the truth.
Scott: Yeah, I think it'd be better to do some preemptive defense here But no one seems to want to do that because that would be the end.
Scott: people would suddenly you'd be you know It'd be immediately opening the can of worms rather than keeping it closed for as long as possible.
Rym: So I guess have you actually ever seen a hentai and not just a clip from a hentai?
Scott: I don't think I've ever and I've never sat through an entire episode or movie of hentai anime And I've never.
Scott: I guess if you count Maiko 2010 is the most perverted entire volume of manga I've read.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: I have in fact seen a hentai.
Scott: What hentai did you see?
Rym: I watched the the famous.
Rym: This is probably Hiroshi Yamakawa's seminal work I actually don't know if he's ever done anything else put out by studio pink pineapple released in 1995. it is none other than Erufuno Waka Okusama, which is elven bride.
Scott: Oh that one.
Scott: you've told me about that one.
Rym: now I watched elven bride kind of by accident Because I like like elves a lot.
Scott: Rym really likes elves if you don't know that elves dragons.
Scott: Yeah, Rym really likes elves.
Rym: So I see you know on my goddess and it's great.
Rym: and then I see in the blockbuster Elvin bride and I read the back and it's some dude marries an elf but then hi jinx ensue and I think oh Man, this is gonna be all like oh my goddess, but also all like slayers.
Rym: I'm all about this.
Scott: Hey good.
Rym: It is funny And you know what?
Rym: It is really funny.
Rym: the one thing I can say about this is that of All of all the hentai I've seen in terms of you know Someone's showing me a music video or someone describing it to me.
Rym: It's actually really tame and it's actually kind of funny.
Rym: and but Regardless the plot is basically there's this dude and he marries an elf On their wedding night, they're gonna fuck they're gonna They're going to consummate the marriage, but they discover that there is an inherent Incompatibility between humans and elves.
Scott: I thought humans and elves had the same parts.
Rym: Well, apparently not.
Rym: it is there.
Rym: there's a problem and Something will not fit into something else.
Scott: Is it because one thing is too big or the other thing's too small?
Rym: It might be a little bit from column a a little bit from column B because they don't actually show.
Rym: it Makes me very happy.
Scott: It's not a hentai then is it?
Rym: Well, I would consider it a hint.
Scott: Okay, but but does that mean that elf guys have really small ones?
Rym: Actually, I know the answer to that because I did watch it to the end.
Rym: Oh god, but So as a kid, I'm watching this and now I'm thinking this isn't what I expected.
Rym: I wonder how this is going to continue, but I kept watching of course except I hope my mom didn't walk in.
Rym: and it goes on and he Decides that he has to go on a quest a quest to find the famed harpy ooze.
Rym: Harpy ooze That doesn't sound good the most lubricitious Substance in the known world Uh-huh, and now I'm thinking all right.
Rym: This definitely isn't what I expected.
Scott: See that's a it.
Scott: That's definitely.
Scott: I don't know if that's a hentai.
Scott: It's more of an erotic comedy in a way.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it would be but the thing is the when I got to the end I discovered that Oh, it's just a whole bunch of sex scenes.
Scott: You know, I remember there was some college.
Scott: it might even been in right it wasn't RIT, but it might have been U of R I'm not sure.
Scott: but I definitely heard a story of a college that every year would they would have an event where they took a Porn an actual porn put it up on like a giant screen and everyone would go and watch it and they wouldn't watch it seriously, they'd watch it ironically like You know like that and maybe it might be fun sometime to like get a one of the tamer Not gonna vomit hentai's and sort of watch it in a party lull setting.
Rym: I think elven bride is the thing It might work.
Scott: I think it is Something similar.
Scott: Does anyone know anything similar to that?
Rym: Elvin bride - oh god now I never actually saw elvin bride - but I will say this double harpy ooze.
Rym: I found the box and then I read online and I discovered what the plot is.
Rym: Now the plot in the first one was he has to go.
Rym: he could not get the harpy ooze and I just remember It was.
Rym: it was kind of funny.
Rym: But anyway, so elvin bride - The plot is the problem was half resolved.
Rym: to fully resolve it the elvin bride goes to a gynecologist who happens to be an incubus and Then a dragon and a werewolf come great.
Scott: Yeah, you have to fight them with harpy ooze.
Rym: I don't know if the harpy ooze comes back.
Scott: I Just think harpy is pretty funny.
Rym: It's even funnier when he finds out what harpies are.
Scott: Yeah, all right, do we got anything else to say about hentai's?
Rym: Not really.
Rym: I don't really plan to watch hentai in the future unless I have a large group of people.
Scott: Yeah, and all that Wow, this yeah, maybe Plan to watch porn with a large group of people, you know It wouldn't be that bad of an event if we were to say Otakon.
Rym: and we did the same, you know, Saturday night OMG 18 plus and we got.
Rym: we showed elvin bride and we got us and some other people maybe Dave and Joel or anime world Order and as you do MST 3k MST 3k a hentai.
Rym: that might actually be really funny.
Scott: I wonder someone's gotta have done that already.
Rym: Yeah, I think we could do it pretty well Especially if we also do mystery anime theater.
Scott: if we could just do mystery hentai I think someone had to do mystery hentai.
Scott: But if we did not be a new idea we did it.
Rym: and furthermore if we got the happy house a hentai guy Yeah to come and do it with an Arizona the Lord cows, you know, I'd be willing to fly him out for that.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: So yes, we finally talked about it.
Rym: Pray.
Rym: We never speak of it further.
Scott: Well, definitely not gonna watch any.
Rym: so This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit.
Scott: don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.