Scott: It's Monday August 13th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: anonymity's on to Internet's.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I realized something just now that I never really thought about before.
Rym: you know We always have you know an anecdote or something interesting at the start of the show.
Rym: well This weekend we mostly just relaxed and last weekend.
Rym: We also just kind of relaxed.
Rym: so nothing crazy happened.
Rym: We didn't go anywhere, and we kind of didn't do anything interesting enough to warrant this sort of leader.
Rym: Hey, how's your day bit?
Scott: I got a haircut.
Scott: my hair is they're shorter and more comfortable.
Rym: You also got your bike.
Rym: well you tried to get your bike fixed.
Scott: well basically my bike You know it's in perfect working order except There's a crack in the frame and the guy at the bike shop was really like There's a tiny crack in the frame.
Scott: you probably shouldn't ride that at all.
Scott: and he's kind of right.
Scott: kind of.
Rym: He's right in the sense that if it weren't Scott.
Rym: I'd say you should throw that bike away.
Rym: It's dangerous, but Scott rides really leisurely, and he doesn't really push the bike.
Rym: It's not like he's gonna suddenly worst case the bike.
Rym: you just kind of sag down and Scott would come to a stop and go oh Yep, so and everything else works.
Scott: You know the gears and the brakes and all that business and the guy was like yeah If you want me to you know I want.
Scott: basically it was out in the in in the winter Outside because we don't remember to put it inside and I had it under a tarp which wasn't good enough apparently And that's how I got sort of rusty and slightly damaged.
Scott: and all I need is you know to like replace the brake and the gear Cables and tighten them up and whatever.
Scott: and the grips the hand grips on the handlebars are all sticky So you just need to replace those with ones that aren't sticky.
Rym: yep now I mean, I'm kind of a bike guy, and I could do this for Scott, but One thing I learned as a kid is that while
Scott: it is
Rym: very Simple to do these things in terms of you know what you have to manipulate It really sucks to do it just in general.
Scott: It's also very difficult to get it in done in such a way where it's like new.
Scott: it's always slightly ghetto.
Rym: Well partly because I don't have all the right tools like I don't have the mount for the bike so I can just mount it Up and spin the gears and twist the little calibrate you bid.
Rym: so it's kind of like I know how to change my oil.
Rym: It's not worth the time it takes to change my oil to change my oil.
Rym: I'll pay the valvoline guy yep.
Scott: So he was like yeah something something And I think he he said it was gonna be $100 just for the tune-up and stuff just to discourage me from using the bike.
Scott: Anymore that is possibly to try to sell me a new one.
Rym: that is almost certainly true because the last time I was there I was charged like 40 bucks for exactly what you asked for on a much more complicated bike.
Scott: Yeah, so I figure what I'll do is all you know.
Scott: I don't ride that much.
Scott: I'll ride this thing around whatever not too hard and Maybe I'll take it to Wildwood put it out to pasture.
Scott: Maybe I'll sell it buy a new one.
Rym: Wildwood I think is a good place to put it.
Rym: It'll have a good retirement thing.
Scott: Yeah, maybe I could get a hundred bucks for it.
Scott: Maybe I mean every other part on it is fine.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'd be leery about selling that to anyone even telling them that there's something wrong with it because No one who know understands how dangerous that is would buy it and the only people who are left are people who don't really understand That that's dangerous.
Scott: Yeah, maybe like next year.
Scott: I'll just bring it to Wildwood leave it there Use it there cuz that's just the thing is.
Scott: like it Wildwood I have a desire to bike a lot.
Scott: Like if I had it there, I'd probably bike up and down the boardwalk with it all the time.
Rym: god I remember I biked up and down the boardwalk once or twice in all these years, and it was fantastic.
Scott: Yeah, it's straight flat Slightly bumpy good traction lots of things to die.
Rym: Well what it was?
Rym: it was that mom go real fast way back when I lived there with Scott for that month.
Rym: Not this Scott the other Scott those Scott.
Rym: you were here there for what like two weeks or so a while a while but it was just me and Scojo and his dad.
Rym: and we just lived there at the beach house for a while and I had All of my worldly possessions except my furniture in my car all of them as in You could only see out of half of the windshield and part of the driver's side window.
Rym: That was it.
Rym: The car was totally full and I had stuff on the roof and I had stuff on the back and I had my bike with Me on a bike carrier barely hanging on.
Rym: So, of course, I rode that bike as much as I could in Wildwood because I never brought a bike there again.
Scott: Yeah, I just wonder how I'm gonna get it there.
Scott: Basically, we'd have to go to Wildwood with only two people and my car and not so much other stuff besides my bike.
Rym: We could do it with three people if we disassembled your bike the rest of the way It's still.
Scott: it's a pain in the ass.
Rym: then if like you mean Emily go down later and like at the end of summer we Could do it then very difficult and or we could just bite the bullet and buy a bike carrier That isn't shitty or take two cars.
Rym: That would.
Rym: my car is not going anywhere.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, let me put it this way selling my car to anyone because Emily actually asked a while ago Hey, I need a car when you get a new car.
Rym: I'll buy your old car.
Rym: I Would feel about as comfortable selling my car to anyone as Scott should feel selling his bike to anyone.
Scott: Yeah, what do you do?
Scott: The bike was cheap.
Scott: I bought it cheap and I got a whole bunch of use out of it when it was new.
Scott: it
Rym: does say something though in That if you are serious about something and you want to buy a piece of equipment that lasts Spend the money and get exactly what you want because I've been using and
Scott: if you're not serious about something And you're gonna leave it out in the winter You probably shouldn't spend too much money on it because you're not gonna take care of it because you don't care as much and it's Gonna break.
Rym: Yeah, I mean think you spent a couple hundred bucks on that.
Rym: Imagine if you'd spent eight hundred bucks on it and then it broke like that.
Scott: if I spent eight hundred bucks on it I would never have left it outside even in the greatest summer day in the universe.
Rym: So, but I mean look I spent that much money on my boy I didn't.
Scott: my sort of a two-way deal.
Scott: Whereas if you care more you should spend more but also if you spend more if you care about money And you're not just a stupidly rich person with money to burn You're going to care more as a result of your spending more.
Rym: man I was so careful with that bike when I was a kid and I first got it, but you know 13 years later I just leave it outside.
Rym: I haven't.
Rym: I've never replaced the chain.
Scott: I think your deal is the same deal you had with your DS.
Scott: is you wanted a DS light?
Scott: So you let you.
Scott: you treated the DS like shit till it broke.
Scott: and you know, you want a new bike.
Scott: So you're waiting for your bike to die.
Scott: So you have an excuse to buy a new one.
Rym: See the thing is I don't I actually take care of that bike.
Rym: It's one of the few things I really take care of.
Rym: not like my car.
Scott: Yeah, I take you're much more expensive car that you finally paid off.
Rym: I've spent a lot more time working on and repairing my bike than even mechanics have spent on my car.
Scott: Yeah, but think about the the trouble you've had with that car.
Rym: It was repoed and had nothing to do with the car.
Scott: that I do with the back went through all that shit for that car And now you're just like ah, fuck it.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I didn't go through that for the car.
Rym: I went through that because society requires that I own a car.
Rym: Yeah The car I mean, you know, you could say oh everything has a spirit and I I should love my car.
Rym: I put effort into that carpet.
Rym: No fuck.
Scott: No, you shouldn't you're crazy.
Scott: It has no feelings Right.
Rym: Wow, I guess that boring thing about your bike was actually a pretty good opening bit.
Scott: well You know, there was nothing else happened this.
Rym: what else do we do?
Scott: Nothing we.
Rym: I played some vidya game.
Scott: I beat like two levels in Paper Mario.
Rym: I caught Some Pokemon played some Mario strikers.
Scott: I Watched some FPS with Emily Alex and Scott the next Horatio hornblower The next one that I've never seen.
Rym: God the short story here is simply that we like Horatio hornblower And we watch it kind of like as this event among the group You know yelling and screaming and cheering and just enjoying it.
Rym: And all these years I've only seen up to a certain point and I've never five episodes Yeah, and no one in our crew was seen past that point.
Scott: So we got to watch the sixth episode.
Scott: Let's watch it today.
Rym: I don't know I got stuff to do.
Rym: We know you don't.
Rym: I gotta watch gang kotsuo But you could find out what happens.
Rym: I know but I kind of want to hold off.
Scott: What do you want to hold off for laudanum?
Scott: See there are situations in lives where you can't hold out a lot of addiction you'll go crazy.
Rym: I'm not gonna give a specific start thinking lamps have feelings.
Rym: There is one kind of thing one action you can take in life Occasionally something I enjoy.
Rym: that if you build up and build up and just let the event as they build it up for years Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I've learned that there's no limit to how much.
Scott: there is a limit.
Scott: certain things pretty much built up to The max.
Rym: no because it was built up to the man charge.
Scott: If you push the button again, it will be released.
Scott: You cannot charge it up anymore.
Rym: I think I can charge it up a little more.
Scott: You can't charge it up ten more.
Rym: if we watched the last episode that we just watched again with a group of people Then we would enhance the experience by bringing more people in a folder.
Scott: that would just create another feeling of frustration.
Rym: It would fill up a different meter if you couldn't tell I was trying to make a sexual metaphor here.
Scott: god too bad.
Scott: Let's talk about technologies.
Rym: Alright, I'll do my news first because I don't have much to say about it And Scott's news is much more important.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So there's this article on slash shot that was actually in PC world about how OMG vista takes your high-quality HD content and fucks it.
Scott: and oh this is so terrible.
Scott: Oh vista the worst thing ever You know, I used Vista for two weeks because it came with my laptop And of course, I don't use it anymore.
Scott: But when I used it, it was just normal windows with some fancy stuff on it.
Scott: There wasn't anything weird going on that.
Scott: I noticed it was just windows.
Rym: Well, the thing is I'm not going to speak from a point of authority because I don't know a lot about Vista.
Rym: I don't really care about it.
Rym: I only use XP because it's easier to install XP with my legitimate license than it is to install Windows 2000 with my also legitimate license that certain people Accidentally stole from me and never gave back.
Scott: Yeah, and meanwhile As much as we're super Linux users, we have a 2000 license and an XP license and a vista license and they're all legitimate.
Rym: We're just not pirates anymore.
Rym: What can I say?
Rym: Yeah, I like to play steam games.
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't quite work.
Scott: I've suddenly been playing a lot of steam suddenly.
Rym: We'll talk about that tomorrow, but yeah, oh, man.
Rym: But this article as far as I can tell is pretty much just FUD fear uncertainty and doubt.
Rym: It's just bullshit.
Rym: I mean while it is true that Vista has a bunch of DRM stuff in it and HD content that is flagged in a certain way or in a certain format Will be downgraded if you put it over an interface like DVI that isn't set up for encryption.
Scott: Yeah You need the HDMI that has the.
Scott: so that way basically what they're trying to prevent with this DRM technology is it's Technologically feasible for someone to say put a DRM DVD in their DVD player play it But then take the video output cable from the DVD player Put it into another the input on a recording device and record it at that point.
Scott: So what they do is that's why HDMI exists.
Scott: HDMI isn't really any better than component video or DVI But DVI plus bullshit.
Rym: It's kind of like if you had a standard like I don't know the little headphone jack used for audio And then you just put a little bit of feces on the end of it.
Rym: Yeah doesn't enhance this.
Rym: all it does is cause trouble.
Scott: It just encrypt it makes it encrypted so that if you have a DVD player and you use the HDMI cable It's actually sort of impossible because of encryption without some sort of you know decrypting key.
Scott: Of course, we have those but to record from the HDMI cable.
Scott: The only way it works is if you plug it into an HDMI Compatible monitor and then it will play at the full HD resolution.
Scott: Otherwise if the player recognizes that you're not using HDMI, it won't do HD.
Scott: It'll do some lower quality because that way you can't steal the HD content.
Scott: You can only steal the low res content.
Rym: now This guy seems to be making the point that all HD content is hurt in this way by Vista.
Rym: But I'm generally of the impression now, correct me if I'm wrong internet but I think that the only time Vista will downgrade the quality is if the content you were trying to play is In some way encrypted in DRM by the person who made it in the first place.
Rym: yeah,
Scott: I mean if I download an x-vid that's at a ludicrous resolution and I play it with like VLC or M player or maybe even Windows Media Player and I have the right codex and I full screen it On my HD screen or my computer monitor and I have just a VGA cable or a DVI cable It's gonna be HD.
Scott: I think yes, I think so.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that this guy's full of crap.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh Well, yeah, so just as much as I am generally indifferent to Windows and now I generally prefer Linux It does bother me sometimes that people who are pro Linux or pro open source get a little bit Sensationalistic about oh my god Microsoft is how evil.
Rym: so evil and it's not always true.
Rym: Granted they did bow down and let this DRM stuff get into Windows But at the same time there's a very easy way to circumvent all of this DRM.
Rym: It's very simple.
Rym: And in fact all of you can do it no matter what your technological skill.
Rym: don't buy DRM content.
Rym: if something's DRM and you want to watch it don't watch something that isn't DRM or go on the bit torrents and get the same thing without DRM on it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Okay, right.
Rym: So, uh in the big news.
Scott: So back in what year?
Scott: 2003?
Rym: I think we were still at RIT.
Rym: It was a long Time ago, I hadn't even worked at IBM.
Rym: yet
Scott: back in the days before dig way back back in the day Slashdot was synonymous with technology news and we would basically We just reload slash dot like 20 times a day Maybe 20 times an hour if you're really bored because that was the only place where the news was
Rym: at.
Rym: I really only went to two websites back then slash dot and Fark and penny arcade.
Rym: Well, I don't have webcomics as websites.
Scott: Penny arcade is different.
Scott: But anyway, yes It was all about slash dot in those days and slash dot had a lot of news stories that would recur.
Scott: They would come up often as new developments came out and one of these news stories was about SCO a company called SEO and I'm not gonna tell you all the details because you can get every detail down to every single thing that ever happened in the court at Grok law as well as other websites, but basically SEO is a company.
Scott: It was a company that made some Unix's kind of and the company really didn't do that much other than Make some business deals and sue people.
Scott: so
Rym: in addition to all that what I mean the real crux of the issue was that a lot of people contributed a lot to Unix back in the day and the actual State of who contributed what and who had rights over what was really kind of murky Yep, and as a result opportunist idiots like yet.
Rym: Well, maybe not idiots because I think a lot of them made a lot of money off of this Decided that hey because of this murky legal crap Let's sue people who use Linux which is based on Unix for a lot of money.
Scott: It's not even based on Unix.
Rym: Well, the thing is what they actually sued over was hey, you're using Linux.
Rym: Well that infringes on all of our Unix stuff.
Scott: That's not really what they sued over so much.
Rym: I what specifically did they sue over?
Scott: They basically said, you know back in the day they licensed Unix right from I guess no valor AT&T or someone or Bell lab Who knows?
Scott: I guess no one's really sure who owns the Unix really.
Scott: and that's what this court case is all about.
Scott: So they said we own Unix.
Scott: Anyone Unixing?
Scott: we own you.
Scott: You can't be Unixing.
Scott: We're Unixing and they sued like, you know, no val and IBM and such.
Scott: and How many years later?
Scott: but at least four years possibly more than four years later.
Scott: the court.
Scott: This is the news by the way the court finally said Novell owns Unix not you.
Scott: they just licensed Unix to you.
Scott: you you're allowed to use Unix.
Scott: Well, the thing is you anyone.
Rym: it got really more weird because SEO I mean the people there must have known that this was a crap fraudulent case Because they basically sued but had no evidence and then over the course of the court case.
Rym: They kept trying to force IBM to provide evidence to them.
Rym: So they'd say like yes somewhere in their code is our code.
Rym: Tell them to give us all their code so we can find it.
Scott: Yeah, how do you know it's there if you haven't seen it?
Rym: and they'd say oh we know we know it's there.
Rym: Yeah, and it just got crazier and crazier and crazier.
Rym: They were talking about suing everyone who's ever used a Star nix or anything and they were just going all over the place.
Rym: Everyone's getting nutty anything with nix in it and even worse the the I mean the amount of money that they sued IBM for was Staggering.
Scott: well the amount of money they were attempting to sue I've.
Rym: well they did sue.
Rym: they just lost.
Scott: Yeah, they very much the amount of money you're suing for determined after this winner or loser.
Scott: Nah.
Rym: No, it's kind of like how Bill Clinton was impeached, but he was not kicked out of office.
Rym: He was impeached.
Rym: However, all right, but the thing is when the news first broke way back They were like SEO is suing IBM.
Rym: Ha this isn't gonna last long because anyone who knew anything about technology knew pretty much immediately That it was completely fraudulent and not true and that there's no way they could win.
Scott: No, none of it was true pretty much at all.
Scott: and over the years there was so many different FUD stories about this court case like oh Well, if this hat this is just Microsoft trying to make people feel Unsafe about using Linux to make it sort of a legal gray area.
Rym: A lot of people thought that Microsoft was secretly funding SEO and while they might have been it doesn't really matter.
Scott: Yeah, and Basically this tiny little shit court case by this crazy back-of-the-middle-of-nowhere company turned into like this huge thing for the whole open-source world and it went on for years and people kept paying attention to it until People stopped reading slash dot and then people stopped caring about it because they stopped paying attention to it.
Rym: because I've forgotten about it.
Scott: The only reason people paid attention to it is because slash dot wouldn't shut up about it and everyone read slash dot.
Rym: Well, the funny thing was in the real world like people every now and then the news would come off and people would care.
Rym: but the only reason this case took as long as it did was that Everyone who knew about technology knew it was crap and could just snap their fingers and say wow I'm done with that.
Rym: But the legal system had not a single person involved in it who knew enough to succinctly explain what was going on to a judge.
Scott: Yeah I remember how people used to talk about SEOs just trying to get bought by IBM and then IBM didn't buy them IBM, to their credit And they wanted to like maybe like, you know What's it called?
Scott: They wanted to Settle?
Scott: Yeah, settle and not.
Scott: that didn't happen either.
Rym: See, luckily they miscalculated because I did work at IBM for a while and I liked working there.
Rym: and all I really want to say Is that IBM does not take shit lying down and as a corporation if someone causes them grief And it's big enough and it's malicious I get the impression that IBM would actually spend more money to destroy them.
Rym: Then they would have to spend settling with them.
Rym: They would rather destroy their enemies than pacify them.
Rym: Haha, and when SEO went up and bit their toe IBM just stomped on them.
Scott: Yep, so basically this bullshit where for years and years and years and years and years we've known that It's all bullshit.
Scott: Finally the court said SEO you got nothing and they got nothing.
Rym: now the thing is I think a lot of people made a lot of money off of this because the Stock and SEO went up and up and up when they first made these lawsuits and then anyway down and down and down and down.
Rym: But it kind of leveled off and every now and then it would get a surge as SEO would say something people who didn't know About technology would say oh they're gonna win that case now and then they're gonna be gigantic.
Rym: But now down the shitter pretty much the day as soon as the announcement was made in the courts SEO stock dropped almost nothing.
Rym: Yeah, it just plummeted straight down.
Rym: I'd laugh but I don't care anymore.
Rym: It's kind of like finding out that Carthage finally fell 20 years after it happened and not caring.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I knew it's like.
Scott: I knew that this was bullshit five four or five years ago And now it's just finally proven me right and that's that's it.
Scott: So I'm sure you can read all the actual details of this on grok law and Wikipedia And if you just search on slash that for SEO or a billion other sites and get all the details.
Scott: But like there's a crazy guy who's in charge of SEO who is involved in a bunch of other like, you know Sue companies that exist only for suing.
Scott: he has said some interesting things Crazy Mormon or something or a scientist.
Scott: I'm not sure which one I don't know.
Rym: I'd make a penny arcade kind of joke about dogs and orgasm.
Scott: He's a crazy guy and he had some crazy people with him.
Rym: and I think the funniest part is when I worked at IBM one day I was like so I SEO haha and No one in the company that I had talked to and I talked to a lot of people Had any idea that the case even existed.
Rym: that's how little IBM cared.
Rym: like no one even knew it was happening except their legal department Yep,
Scott: but yeah What it comes down to is just that you know people paid attention in the geek Tech community to this story so much that all these crazy details and speculations things came out of it most of which are just black Speculation speculation and so now this story sort of inflated to this giant monster because all the details were Exposed and they went down to the very last grain of salt.
Scott: and now it's over and we never had to think about it again Let alone, you know talk about it again.
Rym: Well, I do know this that this is proven one thing Duke Nukem forever is going to come out as is Team Fortress 2 Supposedly.
Scott: well, I know Team Fortress 2 is coming.
Scott: Okay, right.
Rym: Well, yeah, there's all that marketing video and they keep saying it's coming.
Rym: but they they had a lot of marketing videos a long time ago.
Rym: They said it was coming things of the day.
Rym: So way way back we did a show about shaving and the fact that Scott and I both shave not with you know Modern crap, whatever Gillette whatever razors, but we shave with 1950s style safety razors.
Rym: You know the big T things with an actual razor blade in it and a badger hair brush and the little.
Scott: not a straight razor Not a ledge razor.
Rym: The thing is I mean I don't same thing.
Scott: John Wayne shaved with it was good enough for him.
Scott: It's good enough for you.
Rym: cuz about we don't do this for any like Oh I like the antique way of doing things or any nostalgia for the past because straight razors Really suck to use and are really hard and really dangerous.
Rym: But the Mach 3 and all that shave pretty craftily and they're stupidly expensive.
Scott: Even more important than the razor is the the cream and the method of applying the cream.
Scott: Yeah, we're not gonna do another shaving it.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: But all I want to say is once we started shaving I guess the old-fashioned way with an actual brush and hot water and lather.
Rym: It was like night and day.
Scott: go listen to the old shaving episode.
Rym: I think it's a pretty good show.
Rym: it was a good show, but Finally I was poking around and I noticed a video of called the joy of shaving.
Rym: and If any of you still doubt our method of shaving and the way we do it and how it's so awesome Just watch this video and if you like the idea of what that guy did if you can imagine What shaving via that method felt like?
Rym: I'll just leave it at that All right, so so Hulk Hogan.
Scott: Hulk Hogan was my man Back when I was a kid.
Scott: He was the man now.
Rym: He's alright.
Scott: He's not so bad I mean, he took a bunch of Royds.
Scott: He knows he took a bunch of Royds.
Scott: He doesn't take him anymore.
Rym: I remember he's not a you with him on channel 1 TV that propaganda ad machine for middle schools.
Rym: And I remember that they only asked him one question if you went bald Would you wear a wig?
Rym: and he said no, I would not.
Rym: I think wigs are stupid.
Scott: Yeah, and now he knows it bald and he only has hair growing in the sides in the back and stuff.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is it makes him look a little bit majestic.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's his.
Scott: that's that's the Hulk style Hulkamania.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So anyway, he's an alright guy, you know He's better than the macho man Randy Savage or the ultimate warrior.
Scott: He's much better than the ultimate warrior.
Scott: Randy Savage is also kind of cool, but not as cool as Hulk Hogan.
Scott: No, not as cool as all.
Scott: good, you know, he's not insane.
Scott: He's not a genius, but he's alright.
Scott: He's not evil or anything and he I guess he does good things and he wasn't stupid and he didn't waste all his money.
Rym: Yeah, he's not on the Magic Johnson level but he's definitely a pretty good guy.
Scott: all things considered Yeah, he's alright as far as famous people go, especially pro wrestlers.
Scott: Anyway, it's all Kogan Not too bright when it comes to the computers.
Scott: not not a man of machines never would have guessed.
Scott: No, so this is a video of it.
Scott: I guess his son trying to teach him how to use the old AOL instant messenger.
Scott: Pretty funny.
Scott: I the only question is like how does he like he types with like one finger, right?
Scott: But it's sort of like how does he do that?
Scott: I mean, it's like how does strong bad type with boxing glasses.
Scott: fingers are so big They must need like a special Hulk keyboard.
Scott: I don't know how he does it, but he's doing it.
Rym: You know I just.
Rym: that's actually kind of a valid question because when I did meet Magic Johnson, he could have picked me up by my head Easily.
Rym: his fingers were gigantic.
Rym: I can't imagine him typing.
Rym: I'm looking at my keyboard.
Rym: His finger is bigger than a key.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know how it's done.
Scott: So watch this video and look closely at his Hulk hands and see how he types on a laptop keyboard.
Rym: So a while ago as you all know, we were at Otakon the anime convention.
Rym: We're not going to talk about that today because it's not anime day None of you probably care, but at that convention our friends Pete and James James having a fancy video camera he wanted to play with and Pete being well reckless and crazy decided that they wanted to go to the 4chan panel and Record a little documentary kind of as a joke about these, you know weirdos in 4chan.
Scott: Oh, that's a smart move.
Rym: Well Pete came back a little bit shaken like actually a little bit shaken not jokingly and then he showed us the video and We basically as a group came to the conclusion that you couldn't.
Rym: I mean it's not quite as funny and just oh, haha Look at those guys.
Rym: there's actually kind of a serious point here about the future of the internet and anonymity and internet culture and people culture and hive-minds and emergent behavior and all these things.
Rym: and it was kind of frightening.
Rym: the fact that 4chan just a bunch of weird kids yelling stuff at an anime convention when viewed through the eyes of the researcher Actually illustrates a lot of very important points about socialization.
Scott: Yeah, I kind of wish I was some sort of Anthropologist or something because then I'd go there and it'd be like, oh see this is you know Like that and this is like that but sadly some nerd.
Rym: the only things we can really say are words We learned in ghost in the shell we can talk about second-order simulacra.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I know what that is.
Rym: It's actually pretty simple.
Rym: It happens in almost in both ghost in the shell standalone complex.
Scott: I probably understand the concept.
Scott: I just don't know what concept it is that those words represent.
Rym: Well think about the plot.
Rym: but anyway.
Rym: So we want to talk a little bit about anonymity and places like 4chan or whatever exchange.
Scott: Well, there's.
Scott: there's two things you got to take into account here.
Scott: There's the.
Scott: there's the technology of anonymity, you know.
Scott: and then there's the sort of psychology of anonymity both on the internet because I don't know how to deal with anonymity elsewhere other than the Internet's because well you Can wear a mask all the time and not carry ID, I guess I guess.
Scott: but when it comes to the technology of anonymity There's pretty much two different levels.
Scott: There's are you a hundred percent guaranteed anonymous?
Scott: there is no way anyone could possibly find out who you are who did that.
Scott: and then there's you're basically anonymous where Sure, they could technically find out if they jump through a lot of technological hoops But they effectively no way of proving who you are now what they basically break down to.
Rym: I mean you can call these Absolute anonymity and trust-based anonymity.
Rym: Yeah now trust-based we should talk about first because that is the vast majority of anonymity on the internet.
Rym: Yeah, like, you know all those places where you can go through an anonymizer So people can't see where you're coming from on a website or you go through a proxy just so people can't track you or you Log into a site like FARC, but you didn't link your real name or anything to it.
Rym: So it's just like jahar 4 7 8 and no one knows that is actually Rym from GeekNights.
Rym: While you're anonymous Functionally as far as anyone who accesses that site or whatever is concerned You had to trust someone along the way Because you can't really get anywhere on the internet without an IP address.
Rym: and while there are varying Levels of how close they could track you down the fact remains that there is a point along the way where you had to trust someone Enough to use them as your anonymity broker.
Scott: pretty much the way it works Right is let's say you're on the internet and your computer has a real IP address.
Scott: right one computer one IP address.
Scott: You're on the real internet, right?
Scott: So you go to a website.
Scott: that website knows your IP address, even if you encrypt all the traffic You're not encrypting the IP addresses.
Scott: The router needs to read those so it can send your packets the right way.
Rym: So if you want to go through one of those anonymizers, all right.
Rym: Now the website doesn't know but the anonymizer knows.
Rym: they know where you went and who you are Things.
Scott: the way those things work is basically there's a computer out there and you connect to that computer and so to like a hundred other people or a thousand other people and then that computer goes to the website for you and then gives you the website.
Scott: so now You basically you can be effectively anonymous.
Scott: because if the website says hey who posted that they go and they find the IP address of Some computer somewhere and they say we don't know it could have been any of these thousands of people We have no idea.
Rym: granted You have to trust that person perfectly.
Scott: because yeah that computer in the middle of nowhere Might just you know be logging your IP address and it might tell them.
Rym: and then all you know That things being run by the FBI.
Rym: It's really no way to know.
Scott: There's no way to know at all Absolutely none.
Rym: and with websites or anything.
Rym: It's the same way.
Rym: You know, I set up for an account on slash dot infarct, but they know what IP addresses I come from.
Rym: In fact over time they probably have a list of all the different IP addresses I've come from.
Rym: they could probably figure out Just by looking at the history of me accessing FARC with my account where I work where I live where I go on vacation.
Scott: You might be thinking you're real clever.
Scott: You might go to like a public library or some other publicly accessible computer log in and post stuff on the internet somewhere.
Rym: Alright, well one.
Rym: a lot of those places make you log in with a student ID or a library card ID Or there's a camera and they can say this is posted this around this time.
Scott: Let's see who is sitting there at this time.
Scott: Look it was Scott.
Rym: There he is on the camera and you think oh, I'm behind a net in a big corporation.
Rym: They can't find me.
Rym: Well, guess what?
Rym: They can figure out the corporation and from there they can say Alright corporation who has who is accessing this site?
Rym: We know you keep logs to prevent porn.
Scott: So unless you know that you are behind something where there is sufficiently a large number of other people and That the thing you are behind is You trustworthy and actually making you anonymous and that along the way There is at least one point at which no logs are kept and there is no way to recover any logs and no one will talk It's really hard to actually be for real a hundred percent anonymous because if someone goes through all the trouble They can retrace every step and find you because you need and or that at least they can find Your real IP address and then at that point it's not too hard to find you from there.
Rym: now.
Rym: the few ways to get effectively true Anonymity are to either compromise someone else's computer and do it very well To the point that you erase all traces of you being there or at least all the logs of where you came from.
Scott: Yeah, so I hack into someone else's Windows crap computer.
Scott: I use that as my go-between and then I Leave and I make sure that even if someone gets a hold of that crap computer or someone at the ISP takes a look There's no way absolutely no way they can figure out.
Scott: I was the one who did it.
Rym: another way is to compromise on a more broad sense Jen certain parts of the Network internet talking protocols.
Rym: I'm not gonna go into tech detail at all about this.
Rym: Yeah If you
Scott: own some if you own some big router or
Rym: not Even that if you can compromise or there's shady things you can do at various levels depending on What you're trying to access where you can spoof or make it look like you're coming from somewhere else than you really are.
Rym: But even then that's very difficult doesn't always work very well.
Rym: And even then you might leave traces behind.
Rym: Currently the the best way for normal people to get.
Rym: true anonymity is to use someone else's unsecured wireless access point While you're on it to not do anything that could link back to you.
Rym: So don't check your email.
Rym: Don't visit the websites.
Rym: You normally visit.
Rym: don't log into your myspace.
Rym: Don't look at your friends myspace.
Rym: Don't google for anything that in any way could link back to you.
Scott: Don't run any services on your machine that someone might be able to detect and find out what computer you are using.
Rym: and Make sure that there's no cameras around and no one can see you accessing that thing.
Rym: So
Scott: it's pretty hard to be actually anonymous, but you can be pretty much anonymous because like if I just go to 4chan and I post something or if I just go To slash that make an account and post something No one fucking knows and no one's gonna bother to look.
Scott: I could I could go on Slashdot or dig and make up an account and post something.
Scott: That's like fuck fuck fuckity.
Scott: Fuck your mother sucks and No one's gonna know what.
Scott: they're not gonna know who posted that.
Scott: they have no idea that Scott from GeekNights.
Scott: no clue and they're never gonna because it'd be so much effort to figure that out and Dig.
Scott: it probably figured out pretty easily, but they're not even gonna bother.
Scott: It's just not gonna happen now.
Rym: I have a lot of things to say about Absolute anonymity particularly if it were ubiquitous and easy and things related to along those lines terrorism and Global nations that have nothing to do with.
Rym: I don't know location or anything like that But I think that's really beyond the scope of this right now.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I think what we have to go venture into is John Gabriel territory here now socially.
Rym: We'll leave all the tech aside.
Rym: We could go into more specifics another show someday, but Generally, there's a lot of writing and literature about the idea of anonymity and a lot of this came out in the early days of the Internet when Sociologists were looking at how people react and how people write and how people interact with each other When they're anonymous or when they can be anonymous.
Scott: Well think about back in the day before the Internet's what anonymity was all about usually when someone Wanted to write like a book that they might get in trouble for or when someone wanted to do something without getting any recognition, you know.
Scott: or when someone Maybe did like did something great, but they didn't want to get all the credit for it.
Scott: They wanted to stay you know hiding and they didn't want any attention from anybody.
Rym: or in like small group theory and collaboration Theory in these social situations and studies where they looked at ideas of if people are collaborating Openly versus if people are collaborating in a way where you can't know who proposed what idea.
Rym: And there's a lot of effects where some people who might have been more reluctant to voice their opinions will suddenly voice them more often And some people might say less because they don't want to do something They won't get credit for.
Rym: and there's a fascinating field of study that again is a little bit beyond the scope of this show.
Scott: The point is is that people?
Scott: Mostly want to be anonymous when they don't want.
Scott: they want to avoid positive or negative Attention they want to send things out and they want to avoid things coming back to them.
Rym: Now a lot of times this just ends up being something like trolling or unpopular opinions.
Scott: Yes, but other times it can actually be serious like I want to make a charitable donation But I do not want anyone to know it was me or I am posting from North Korea.
Scott: Get me out of here house But I don't want to be killed within the next 10 minutes.
Scott: Seriously.
Rym: It sucks.
Scott: Yes, it does.
Scott: All right So you get on this internet where suddenly even it's pretty hard to become not anonymous.
Scott: I mean, you're always gonna be not technically a hundred percent, you know anonymous, but it's pretty hard to avoid the effective anonymousness.
Scott: as far as you know socializing and Communicating on the internet is concerned in a practical everyday sort of sense.
Rym: In fact, I think for this discussion, we actually have to break it up into three terms.
Rym: I mean on one hand there's absolute anonymity and on the other hand, there's verifiable identity, but then there's the middle ground.
Rym: I don't know what I call it.
Rym: I don't know Attributed anonymity where you are not linked to your persona.
Rym: No one knows that shez are is Rym from GeekNights.
Rym: But at the same time on Farker slashdot shez are is a valid account.
Rym: And if someone posts from shez are people are 99% sure that that was actually that guy talking.
Rym: So they don't know who it is.
Rym: But they can link all the things that one person says together and as a result that online identity can have its own Opinions and its own view from other people.
Scott: Well, I think what that is Is that when you say you write a book say by anonymous, right?
Scott: That's sort of like, okay We don't have no idea who wrote this book.
Scott: We have no clue.
Scott: It could have been you know there even if there's another book also by anonymous.
Scott: We don't know.
Scott: it's the same person.
Scott: We have absolutely no clue.
Scott: We can't do anything.
Scott: All we can do is guess based on the contents of the book itself.
Scott: But if a book is say by I don't know shez are that's like a pen name?
Scott: No one knows your physical real-world identity.
Scott: But you have created this new proxy identity that instead of you personally You know Rym were receiving the credits or the negative impact and you know Feedback from whatever you've put out.
Scott: You're able to put out through a proxy sort of in the same way.
Scott: you use an internet proxy to put out and the receiving goes to the proxy and you can sort of choose to when stuff is received by the proxy whether to Take it to yourself or to leave it out.
Rym: There's on the proxy level now even here I think there's a lot of fascinating discussion about how a lot of people have very different online Personas from what they have in real life.
Scott: or people have multiple online personas in different places Like on Facebook, they have sort of like a nice guy and on Craigslist They have a wheeler dealer and on eBay.
Rym: They have a wheeler dealer Yeah, and then on slash dot they're just sort of a nerd or well in the realm I had you know, my main guy Alison Dar who was an elf and he was all cool or whatever.
Rym: But then I had a cute who was a girl who existed solely to scam pimply nerds out of valuable magical items Uh-huh, and then give them to the guy.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Yeah That's sort of sexist but whatever.
Rym: well the thing is it was mostly guys playing that game.
Scott: Yes, it was mostly practical.
Rym: I mean even World of Warcraft is pretty popular today.
Rym: It's really popular and it's kind of.
Rym: it's a lot of women playing Yeah, but back in the day like in the first couple MMOs there were like five girls total Yeah, but or like on Fark.
Rym: I'm an asshole on Fark pretty much a hundred percent.
Rym: I post only when I'm going to anger someone.
Scott: Yeah, that's a whole nother topic of discussion of Anonymous.
Scott: missus you gender and race and all those sorts of things just sort of go away.
Rym: Yeah In fact, I know multiple women who post with generic gender neutral or even masculine screen names Just to avoid all the crap that comes when OMG a girl is in our forums.
Rym: I shall hit on her
Scott: but at the same time it sort of Perpetuates the impression that there's not so many women and I think if more of them posted, you know, like yeah We're a whole bunch of women people would say oh there are a whole bunch of women like, you know about half the Internet's.
Scott: Stop their bullshit.
Rym: in general I mean people treat the things that men say and women say oftentimes differently and the internet is an exception to that in that you can't really know if someone's actually a woman or a man and a lot of times someone with a neutral or Opposite screen name will be treated very differently from how they might have been treated in real life.
Rym: Mmm be interesting I have noticed that because I once used a screen name that was kind of gender on gender neutral.
Rym: But I learned from talking to people in South America of all things This is back in the ICQ days that a lot of people thought it was a feminine name and a lot of people thought I was A girl, uh-huh, and there I wasn't intending that there was no way.
Rym: I mean, it's not like I use.
Scott: a lot of people think you're a girl anyway, so it's not.
Rym: you know Well now that I got rid of the mustache, I guess and the neck beard.
Rym: But I think that is again a whole topic for another show.
Scott: It seems like this whole show is just saying wow, look at all these really interesting, you know Intellectual discussions you can have about anonymity.
Scott: It is such a vast and complicated thing.
Rym: Look at it Ooh, hence I want to narrow it down to a very specific kind of anonymity the kind that Pete and James saw with their own eyes at Otakon the 4chan world.
Rym: I mean, I'm gonna explain very briefly how 4chan works because I know a lot of people hear about it.
Rym: It's kind of like this murky part of the internet that they avoid Full of penis girls and scariness if they even know that and not that many people go there except the people who are kind of into It.
Rym: basically it is a site where not only are you anonymous in the sense that your screen name is not Actually linked to your real identity in any way that users can get to.
Rym: it goes one step further than that.
Rym: You cannot prove that you are you and you can post as anyone.
Rym: people who post and put their name or something are generally looked down upon and they even have a system that was built in where you can use a hash to prove that you were The same person and those people are universally despised.
Scott: Yeah generally the way 4chan works is you can type in any username you want just about every time you post and That's the username that'll show up and no one knows who's who.
Scott: and that's sort of the way they like it.
Scott: They don't want anyone to know who it was.
Scott: So, you know all those dick girls could be one guy.
Scott: It could also be a thousand people.
Scott: You have no idea.
Rym: So think about.
Scott: they don't want to know.
Rym: This is a community where people are contributing content and interacting.
Scott: They could just one guy, but no, it's probably not.
Rym: We know it's at least two guys.
Rym: Yeah but think about it.
Rym: people are talking to each other submitting content creating content creating meta content based on that content having Social relations all these things and yet they've removed any sort of anchor point into as to personality.
Rym: There's no more.
Rym: I am an individual talking to this individual and this third individual is commenting.
Rym: It is I am throwing with no possible chance of attribution.
Rym: No one will ever know what works.
Rym: Retribution Attribution also, I've had attribution.
Rym: but I guess retribution is also true.
Scott: Yeah any sort of asterix fusion.
Rym: There aren't so many.
Rym: I don't know if you get ablution.
Scott: That's not uh That's blue.
Scott: It's not view.
Rym: Ah, I guess you're right.
Scott: It has to be fusion.
Rym: No butions Anyway, so you throw these ideas out there and people respond to them But you can't know who's actually responding and you're basically stripped of all sense of identity and kind of subsumed by this Massive anonymous blob that ends up having almost emergent behavior.
Rym: Like it almost has a mind of its own.
Rym: You're not a person anymore.
Rym: You're just a neuron in the 4chan brain.
Scott: Well, I think what it is is that you know when people You know act normally in life when they're not anonymous in any way they have Inhibitions that prevent them from doing certain things.
Scott: they have filters on things they intake and things they put out and they're not just gonna Do whatever.
Scott: but when you're somewhere like 4chan and this is no chance of anything everyone just lets a hundred percent completely loose and it's a hundred percent honest and No one gives a shit about anything.
Scott: So you're gonna get like the most natural of instinctual reactions and Such, you know biological urges and things all coming out in Writing and imagery and sometimes audio and maybe even video but rarely now as we started thinking about this looking at 4chan.
Rym: 4chan because it's 4 channel.
Rym: It's not like 4chan like a little cute thing.
Rym: At least that's what I've been told.
Rym: It kind of puts it in a frightening new light because if that is the emergent behavior of the collected Unconscious or the collected unbridled inhibitions of the people on the internet That kind of says a lot about humanity
Scott: or at least the humanity that speaks English and is on the Internet.
Rym: So or at least at least the humanity that has decided that they want to be a part of this.
Rym: anonymous.
Scott: I'd like we'd have to set up fortunes and like get I guess other people on them.
Scott: because even though right 4chan is anonymous We kind of know that it's mostly You know anime fans high school young college type people Mostly males in the US granted.
Rym: I think a lot of that is just due to the fact that older people Just aren't hip to it.
Rym: I mean, I think I'm above the age where I could have gotten into 4chan.
Scott: I 4chan is good for you know, occasionally like it's sort of like this world where I kind of understand what goes on there But I don't enjoy going there and occasionally funny pictures pop out of it and I enjoy looking at them and Sometimes not so funny pictures pop out and I don't want to look at those
Rym: I look at kind of like the the high culture in France where they have like the super fancy fashion show where women wear like boat anchors and like crazy things that no human being could possibly wear as high fashion.
Rym: and then People who are more reasonable see hey, huh?
Rym: They're inspired by that and they make something and then that becomes the high fashion for normal people and then it filters down and filters Down and filters down and eventually a knockoff of a knockoff of a knockoff is in Walmart for $5.95.
Rym: Yeah, and I fee.
Rym: I see a lot of internet jokes and internet me shirt with a picture of an anchor on it.
Rym: Yeah But you see a lot of these internet memes that get big if you trace back their origins.
Rym: a lot of them came from 4chan.
Scott: Yeah, I mean lolcats.
Scott: And if they didn't completely originate in 4chan, 4chan made them big.
Rym: and while not just 4chan I mean something awful is kind of like the exact opposite of 4chan in that regard.
Rym: It's kind of like if 4chan is evolution then something awful is intelligent design Something like that.
Scott: I mean something awful.
Scott: people sort of know who you are, you know, it's not.
Scott: it's not super anonymous.
Scott: It's just as anonymous as every other site.
Rym: people there take attribution and they try to make memes.
Scott: 4chan it just happens Yeah And it's sort of tough because something awful does seem like when they produce product like.
Scott: it is more amusing more often.
Scott: but 4chan is sort of like this pit where there's a whole bunch of excess stuff in there and Sometimes interesting things can come out of the excess stuff.
Scott: Even if the excess stuff itself is not what you're looking for.
Scott: It's almost like I bet there's something awful.
Scott: people go and look at the 4chan and then they make their stuff based on what they You know.
Scott: see there it's like you go and you wait in a pool for a while.
Scott: you come back and you pick some leeches off and then You find you got a quarter stuck in your toe and you're like, ah, there it is.
Rym: Ah, got it See the.
Rym: I mean the really fascinating thing to me is that 4chan very often illustrates the principle of emergent behavior Very directly and if you think about it when you're when someone's on 4chan They're not engaging in a continuous thread of conversation as one being.
Rym: What they're doing is they're seeing the current state of the 4chan world as a snapshot and they are basically making a one-off Decision of what to contribute to that exact snapshot or what to take away.
Rym: Ah true yeah, and as a result this kind of emergent behavior where things become popular or not popular or morph or become Self-referential not based on the decision of any one person but based on the collective Unconscious and undecided decision of the masses like people don't decide Seeking fuck.
Rym: Yeah is gonna become our thing.
Rym: It just happens.
Rym: No one person thought that's gonna become the thing.
Scott: Yeah It's like undig right.
Scott: you actually have a system of voting where technically everyone votes and if enough people dig something it comes and rise to the top and that's supposed to be.
Scott: that's sort of like institutionalized what you what what you know.
Scott: 4chan is without any sort of software to back it up and dig.
Scott: You know someone with a bunch of friends dig something and then all those friends see it on their RSS feeds and they dig it And then it gets a little boost so it gets a little bit of exposure.
Scott: So enough other people see it and they dig it and then it's on the front page Whether it's actually something the community really likes or not.
Scott: You should see how many things get to the front page and then get a zillion berries because once it's on the front page all These other people see it and then they all get rid of it.
Rym: like me Yeah, Barry's like ten times the things he digs.
Scott: Yes, but meanwhile and fortune There's no software backing up.
Scott: What's popular?
Scott: What's not?
Scott: there is no, you know person with a bunch of friends getting all their friends to do Something there's no scheming.
Scott: It's some guy puts a picture up of seeking and it says fuck.
Scott: Yeah on it.
Scott: Okay, a guy put a picture up then some other guy says seeking fuck.
Scott: Yeah, was it the same guy or was it a different?
Scott: Guy, I don't know.
Scott: There's no way to know.
Scott: it could have been one guy saying seeking fuck Yeah the whole time but it's it's on there a lot a lot of people or you.
Scott: supposedly more than one person is saying seeking fuck Yeah and a lot of threads all of a sudden.
Scott: and Then you realize when you go to the 4chan panel at Otakon when a hundred people or more are chanting Seeking fuck.
Scott: Yeah seeking fuck.
Scott: Yeah seeking fuck Yeah, that it became popular on its own without any software or anything like that.
Scott: It just did it.
Scott: was it caught on like fire catching on wood?
Rym: I mean once James and Pete get this documentary fully together I'm sure we're gonna figure out a way to get it out to you people Because you can probably some sort of YouTube and the experimental feed.
Rym: I imagine you can see this happening in real time.
Rym: because remember the people going to the 4chan panel.
Rym: they're all 4chan people or people like Pete, but most of them are 4chan people and They don't know each other.
Rym: They can't know each other.
Rym: Well,
Scott: some of the people know each other, you know, like if you bring your friends at the 4chan
Rym: Well, yeah, but at the same time like they don't know each other on 4chan No
Scott: I mean the person sitting next to you in that line could be like the guy who posts every penis girl on all of 4chan.
Rym: you have no way of knowing and These people and Pete said this and watching the video I start to agree with it They don't.
Rym: a lot of them don't just go to 4chan and these things because it's funny or they like to look at these penis girls or whatever.
Rym: They go because they almost worship the idea of anonymity and they they're serious about it.
Rym: The idea of being anonymous is so liberating that and I'm dead serious.
Rym: It's like religion for some of these people.
Rym: Yeah, and when I say some I mean a significant number.
Scott: Well, I mean you look at the way they behave in the line, right and basically there's a lot of mumbling.
Scott: Well, it's not mumbling, but it sounds like mumbling.
Scott: it's a lot of talking and people are saying things to each other and Occasionally someone says something that catches fire and before you know it half the line is chanting it Right and then it sort of dies out as people get tired of it And then everyone's talking and eventually someone says something that catches on and everyone chants it and then they get bored of it.
Rym: No one was directing this.
Scott: No one knows who started it.
Scott: No one.
Scott: No one was directing it saying, okay guys Let's do this chant now because you if you did that people just like boo sit down, you know But everyone's talking to each other.
Scott: There's a lot of talking, you know, probably don't ever even met the people you're talking to.
Scott: They're all strangers.
Scott: You don't know who they are.
Scott: Really you might recognize them if you see them again.
Scott: some of them are in costume guy wearing a v-mask.
Scott: a lot of people wearing v-masks a guy with a v-mask and he has Bracelets that say epic fail on them.
Scott: You don't know who that is.
Scott: That could be me It's not me, but it could have been.
Rym: but you know, they're a four-channel, you know who.
Rym: it isn't me, but that's a Clever cover story.
Scott: Yes, but I mean Shit like that goes down.
Scott: they behave in the line the same way.
Scott: the website works And I the thing is they don't even say alright guys We're gonna go to the line for 4chan panel or we're gonna go to the 4chan panel and behave The way we're gonna mimic 4chan.
Scott: They don't think that.
Scott: it just happens.
Scott: That's just the way it is.
Rym: There was no pre meditation and any other crowd of people even if they have a sink a like purpose Like if you went to a fart party or whatever and lined up or a slash-dot gathering or a lug.
Rym: It'd be really hard to get a group of people standing in line for an event like that to yell anything without some sort of Active director some sort of Mover that pushes the crowd into a direction and the crowd being willing to submit to that.
Rym: in this no one was moving No one was pushing and ideas just coalesced Independently and I think the anonymity and the fact that these people are so into it caused I mean this crowd because of who they were and what they cared about even though they didn't all know each other and in any real Capacity things could catch on and die out so much more quickly than they do among normal people because these people totally give themselves up to the anonymity.
Scott: and while You know on a community like 4chan these things happen and in a community like slash-dot or dig these things don't happen so much.
Scott: If you look at the internet as a whole the internet as a whole is just like the 4chan.
Scott: It's the macrocosms and the microcosm.
Rym: I think 4chan is just a lot faster.
Rym: It converges quicker onto an ideal, but then it discards that ideal just as quickly.
Scott: But you know if you have a microcosm of anything, that's what happens.
Scott: It's just a lot more efficient.
Scott: You know if you had a universe in a jar You could probably see the beginning and the end of the universe of that little tiny universe Within the beginning and the ending of the universe that we live in true.
Scott: So if you have a 4chan in a bottle and you're living in a giant 4chan that's bigger and slower.
Scott: You can sort of see the past in the future in your little jar.
Rym: I just find it fascinating how absolutely quickly a crowd of 4chaners can come to a consensus as to what?
Rym: Obscenity to scream at any given moment?
Scott: yeah, I mean plus if you look here look at the internet as a whole.
Scott: right the internet Is a whole.
Scott: rumble rumble rumble rumble slash.
Scott: no news groups rumble rumble rumble rumble slash.
Scott: peer-to-peer rumble rumble rumble rumble.
Scott: dig YouTube myspace rumble rumble and it'll be something else.
Scott: it just stuff comes and goes.
Scott: just the same way.
Scott: People are chanting stuff, and then they're not chanting stuff.
Scott: Everyone's anonymous and this big internet see and different things come and go and yep, that's how it goes down 4chan.
Rym: It's just lower level.
Rym: It's the next step.
Rym: beyond that it's kind of the next progression, and I I don't know I really can't let myself be subsumed by this kind of anonymous idea.
Scott: Maybe I have better things to do.
Rym: well not even that even if it were on a more philosophical or larger scale.
Rym: I'm too proud of a person, and I'm too self-determined to let myself be subsumed by that.
Rym: yeah But at the same time Peter the guy who was there recording all this with James he ended up joining in and yelling with them and Afterward he said that he really couldn't help it, and he is just as strong-willed as we are.
Scott: yeah Well, I mean I probably would have yelled like see King fuck.
Scott: Yeah, I mean back in the high school days We used to have some fun chanting action.
Scott: You know chanting is fun.
Scott: You go to baseball game.
Scott: You say you know let's go ahead.
Rym: It's like that scene in a dead Poets aside Walking he tells.
Rym: he tells the class just walk around in the courtyard.
Rym: That's your assignment And they're all just kind of walking around and over time they end up kind of walking in a line And then they start marching in a line, and then they start marching in a circle very militaristic And then he's like.
Rym: I think you've learned the lesson.
Scott: So anything else we got to say about this besides an obligatory John Gabriel mention?
Rym: I think that's pretty much it mainly just because we're gonna have to do more shows about this in the future.
Rym: We've already gone a little long Shitcock so penny arcade has summed up one of the biggest failings of anonymity in all the world and Fortune-chan we
Scott: talked about this before we have I'm sure fortune
Rym: mitigates this by being so anonymous that it doesn't matter and Other things don't deal with it very well.
Rym: counter-strike does not deal with it very well.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Rym: but basically penny arcade made a comic entitled John Gabriel's greater internet fuckwad theory and I Proposed that this is internet fuckwad law.
Rym: That's what I was about to say.
Rym: This is not a theory.
Rym: This is a law of the interaction of human beings.
Rym: yep normal person plus anonymity plus audience equals Total fuckwad, and it's a picture of a nice guy.
Scott: fuck water, so I forget these.
Rym: total fuck wad is a total fuck.
Rym: It's a picture of a nice guy plus You know a question mark anonymity plus an audience, you know an audience and the total fuck wad image It's just a guy yelling shit cock and his face is all mangled.
Rym: And if you've ever played counter-strike while no one may have actually said the word shit cock to you You know exactly what that word means.
Rym: you know what shit cocking is.
Rym: if someone says someone was shit cocking me You can imagine what kinds of words they were saying.
Scott: yep Basically someone's anonymous.
Scott: So they can say something to you, and you'll have no idea who said it.
Scott: They're gonna say something shit cocky.
Scott: That's that's how people are Except for very few people.
Rym: yep.
Rym: I will.
Rym: while I don't shit cock I have on occasion anonymously trolled people on some websites.
Rym: while I am NOT a regular shit cockery I've done it in an ironic sense.
Scott: I'll admit that I have Shat cocks in the past, and I probably will shit more cocks in the future mostly playing counter-strike Maybe maybe playing some other games or possibly not even playing games at all.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.