Rym: It's Monday June 4th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we make our triumphant return with my new computer and media playing software.
Rym: Let's do this Back in business coming to you live from the depths of my brand new computer that finally freaking works.
Rym: I'm I'm really pleased with this thing.
Rym: It's I Don't think I can really describe it in any terms other than stupidly fast.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I had that core to do at work.
Scott: That's still stupidly faster than any computer.
Scott: I've ever used and this computer is even faster ran into a few problems Getting it going.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about those in any great detail.
Rym: eventually I'll try to a show about the ordeal of the new computer and the things that are taking us off about the computer industry right now.
Rym: But suffice to say the last problem that we had to resolve was that a lot of Podcasts use out there use a lot of different programs to make their little podcasts And I'm of the opinion that most of those programs suck.
Scott: Well, they suck for pod.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they're great.
Rym: If you want to make techno you want to mix or master music you want to make an audio drama?
Rym: You want to make a music video anything like that?
Rym: They're great.
Rym: yeah, if you want to record one or two channels of Talking and then process then yes And then process them directly and edit them directly and filter them and cut them up into you know Remove coughs and things like that.
Rym: now in that case there those programs are still okay.
Rym: They do those things, but if you also want to do it often and in a timely fashion They're not good at that.
Rym: There's really only one program that's worth a dick and that's resound and are cool at it Or the old cool at it, but I guess audition cuz it is cool it yeah, but maybe that's so anything we've never used.
Rym: actually I When I in first installed windows I got a bunch of wares.
Rym: is just to look at all those proprietary Expensive audio things and the new versions of audition are kind of I don't like him.
Rym: Yeah audition 1.5.
Rym: I liked a lot better, but it had less functionality than cool at it.
Rym: They took some stuff out.
Rym: Granted they took out some things that weren't so useful too.
Rym: So it wasn't just Yeah, I'm not gonna pretend that cool that it was like the end-all be-all but cool that it was a really good program.
Scott: the thing With resound is like, okay.
Scott: It's like the only program that does what we need, but it's an old and busted program.
Scott: It just barely works.
Scott: It's funny works enough that it beats everything else.
Rym: Yep I mean, it's kind of cluttered and it definitely looks old.
Scott: It looks like a piece of shit.
Rym: But because I think because the person who makes it it's maintained as far as I can tell by this one, dude He updated in January who's really into audio.
Rym: So this guy makes this kind of for fun and there's a lot of algorithms and filters and things That are in here.
Rym: just because he's playing around with audio and a lot of his experiments have ended up being very useful to me I think it just needs to be rewritten which I might do one day.
Rym: Yeah, I like to talk to this guy.
Rym: Actually, I should try to bother him.
Scott: You should try to contact him.
Scott: get him on the show.
Rym: I'd love to get him on the show.
Rym: I'd be like, I'm probably the only dude using your program Now.
Rym: I know other people are but I don't think anyone is podcast.
Scott: it's like no one's respecting the program.
Scott: It's like because I don't know if there must because remember we complained so much in that garage band episode.
Scott: We got the Mac how garage band sucked.
Scott: Well, apparently I'm checking out these other programs and that are similar in their functionality That a lot of people are using like Joe kosher and audacity and all such.
Scott: they're all the same as a garage band.
Scott: It's not garage band like.
Scott: maybe it is garage bands fault because maybe they're copying garage band.
Scott: But how do people consider that to be a good way?
Rym: I mean it is a good way if you're making one thing or you're making music.
Rym: But if you're recording, you know I should like say you did a show every night you did something constantly over and over and over again.
Rym: those those interfaces at their fundamental level are not as efficient as resound and cool edit.
Rym: in fact resounds even beaten cool edit in a lot of ways because you know It's had I don't know another eight years of development and it's free.
Rym: Yeah free helps a lot.
Rym: freeze good I don't know.
Rym: I think now that I have the new computer.
Rym: I'm probably going to make videos of Me editing the show in resound Compared to me editing the show in garage band and audacity and all these other programs.
Scott: Yeah, get the eggs vid cap go.
Rym: Yeah I want to make like a comparison and put it on YouTube and see if there's something I'm missing or maybe Everyone else in the world is.
Rym: The rest of the world was gonna make a Napoleonic war analogy, but never mind I think the rest of the world just sucks it doing podcast editing and such.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Rym: Anyway, the computer's badass the heart.
Rym: I love it.
Rym: That's all I can say took goddamn long enough.
Scott: It took me a while to figure I actually think there's the last thing Did.
Rym: The only thing that I had trouble with really like the biggest thing was that I mean when I name a computer It's always a big deal because I don't buy new computers often
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: and I didn't actually think about what I was going to name it for when I built the first computer I decided what to name it like six months before I bought it.
Rym: this one I'm sitting at the Windows install prop and it's what do you want to call your computer?
Rym: and I go?
Scott: crap Yeah, and basically we sort of we sort of fell into because you know You have to have a theme for naming like this computer lab is gonna be all Thundercats So this computer lab is gonna be all Douglas Adams.
Scott: So this computer lab is gonna be all Star Wars, right?
Scott: Yeah, well with our house.
Scott: We sort of didn't pick a theme and we just called our computers by our screen names and that was it.
Rym: Well, we'll go in order.
Rym: My computer was Chazar and Scott's was a fresh.
Rym: Yep, and our server was server Yep, and then we got the media PC.
Scott: We got them.
Scott: Oh, yeah the media PC.
Scott: What do we call that?
Rym: We called that div as well.
Scott: Oh, yeah, we called it div as in the little DVD player in penny arcade.
Scott: So that was an accurate name.
Scott: That is why we chose that name because it was accurate to the function Yep.
Rym: Also, we like penny arcade.
Rym: So yeah, and since the Mac Mini is in the living room now, we call that div Yep, and then we got another computer That's little and boxy and looks like a character from Ghost in the Shell and we had just been watching Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: So we called it Jameson.
Scott: Yep, just like CEO Jameson.
Rym: Yeah, who's my second favorite character in Ghost in the Shell?
Scott: and then I got a laptop recently.
Scott: So I called it Robita and I said I'm gonna start a Tezuka theme Yep, and I was gonna.
Scott: I was gonna name some other computers like denouba and hallelujah and all that stuff Yep.
Scott: But then now that kind of breaks because we have div and we have all these other things and we realize that the theme of our computers is machines and robots from anime and manga and comics and Whatever video games.
Rym: so I thought about what I wanted to name this one and I put a lot of thought into it because I Didn't want to break from this theme because I like this theme.
Scott: Yeah, it's got to be some sort of robot or machine from something geeky if it's a video game anime Whatever.
Rym: and then I realized well Scott mentioned about he was saying a bunch.
Scott: I was just going through every frickin computer and robot from anime manga and comics Games I could think of.
Rym: and the one that stuck the one that I think was perfect is a character from an anime that a lot of people out there haven't seen.
Rym: and just so happens that that character was a normal guy who Ended up transferring his intelligence or his soul into a ship.
Rym: Yep, and it works even better because he has a little sidekick that I can now name my iPod.
Rym: that oh That's clever, however, I had to look up what that sidekicks name was.
Rym: it wasn't as cool as I thought it was.
Rym: no It's not no no cuz I didn't know what its name was.
Rym: So I looked it up, but I'm kind of I used to do that.
Scott: I used to know the name and then I forgot it, but if you say it, I'll remember it again.
Rym: Yeah I'm gonna save that for anime day because no one today cares.
Rym: no Suffice to say it is a character from an anime.
Rym: if anyone out there can guess based on the nothing I've given you I'm pretty sure someone's gonna know it right away.
Rym: I hope so.
Rym: cuz we gave him pretty much.
Scott: Gerald knows it.
Rym: of course Gerald knows it.
Rym: Of course germs, but I thinking no it can't be that obvious.
Rym: No, it is that obvious.
Scott: Yeah, maybe If you you either know it or you don't it's either gonna be.
Scott: oh, that's what it is.
Scott: There's no one else who transferred their mind into into a ship.
Scott: Well, there are but it couldn't be that because whatever there's this one that's above all others.
Rym: Anyway, that's my news because nothing else in the world really happened as far as tech is concerned in my book because I haven't been On the internet.
Rym: I spent the last four days on this computer working on it and not reading Fark.
Scott: Yeah, well there are bigger tech news is than my tech news But this is the one that I can talk the most about even though I've talked about it on the show before.
Scott: Basically, there are some lobbyists out there in Washington.
Scott: I'm not sure if they're in Washington DC or in state.
Rym: There's lobbyists.
Scott: Yes in DC, I guess but they're good lobbyists for us.
Scott: Anyway, because what they want to do is they're trying to push laws in many states that will Mandate the use of open document format and other similar formats for Government stuff.
Scott: what this means is let's say you are I don't know the town clerk and You have the.
Scott: I don't know the Application for zoning change and it's a Microsoft document file.
Scott: that means if somebody wants to access their government and Their democratic government and apply for a zoning change they need Microsoft Office a Proprietary for-profit paid-for program that you have to go out and get and pay money for.
Scott: that's basically the same As saying if you want to drive on the road that your tax money paid for you have to drive a Ford.
Scott: There's no other car will go on the road.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I don't think we really need to explain to all of you why this is a big deal.
Scott: So the people who are pushing open document format are saying hey you need to make all sure all government digital Documents are in a format that anyone can use Freely without having to buy shit and also that the advantage of having a be in an open format is you know It's probably not gonna happen but on paper, you know the government Microsoft could like hold the government by the balls.
Scott: or you know in the future if Microsoft doesn't, you know make certain software then government documents will be lost or not unable to be accessed.
Rym: There's also a much more simple Motivation here once the government is using Microsoft Office stuff.
Rym: They're tied to that.
Rym: So whenever a new version of Microsoft Office comes out once anyone upgrades Everyone has to upgrade because you all know that Microsoft Office very much likes to be incompatible with older versions of Microsoft Office.
Scott: Yep, so now the government has to keep spending money on Microsoft Office and give money to Microsoft forever.
Scott: and blabbity blabbity blah.
Scott: So this lobbyists that are on our side and they're pushing to get ODF pat that laws mandating open document format in many states.
Scott: meanwhile Microsoft and IBM have some lobbyists pushing from the other side and So far we've lost in six states.
Rym: Well, I think it doesn't help that we don't have as much money as them.
Scott: Well, we got something we're actually lobbying which is good.
Scott: We got a lot.
Scott: We got a bill written.
Scott: That's a step We got somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of bills get written and a lot of bills appear out there.
Rym: It doesn't mean Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Anyway, there's one line from this little slash top blurb that I think is pretty funny.
Scott: It says there was heavy lobbying being done in private on both sides with one problem being the jargon laden Disinformation.
Scott: that committee members felt they were being fed by lobbyists for both IBM and Microsoft.
Scott: Although lobbyists would tell the committee one thing in private They got cold feet when asked to verify that information publicly under oath, huh?
Scott: In other words these IBM and Microsoft guys are basically lying lying and bullshitting to the congressman.
Scott: The congressman are smart enough to see through it, but they're still voting now.
Rym: There's the problem.
Rym: They're smart enough to see through that but they still don't understand the underlying issue.
Scott: I think that's the problem is.
Rym: I doubt that any congressman involved actually has any idea of what the issue really is.
Scott: No, I think that there was one guy.
Scott: I remember watching a Like.
Scott: it was like a c-span video from like a congrats US congressional committee meeting About like digital radio and HD radio stuff and the DRM and all that jazz.
Scott: and of course, you know The Ted Stevens was there and whatever.
Scott: but there was one guy One congressman on the side and he would like.
Scott: he was just sitting on the side somewhere and no one else was saying anything Except him Ted Ted Stevens and the people before the committee Talking about radio.
Scott: and this guy kept chiming in and he knew what was up and he was some congressman in the US government.
Scott: I don't know who he is.
Rym: But I think the question the operative question is how old is he?
Scott: He wasn't too old.
Scott: He was 40 something maybe 30 something 40 something.
Scott: Ah Relatively young.
Scott: Yeah relatively not gray hair Yeah, but so if there's one in the federal government there's got to be at least one in each state.
Rym: I guess see the reason that one is not enough though I mean on one hand I this always bothers me and when I was younger I was always more and more outraged about this sort of thing than I am now.
Rym: and If I look back through history It seems like every bad thing our government in the United States does every time there's a problem with the government not Understanding something or not dealing with something properly the problem especially when it comes to social issues though.
Rym: I think technology is also right up there.
Rym: Regardless of whatever happens or what lobbying is done or whatever laws anything the problem gets resolved as a direct correlation.
Rym: With old congressman dying and new congressman coming in and the generations changing hands It seems like every generation that gets into Congress fixes the problems that they cared about The previous generation when they were kids and Congress was bothering them.
Rym: They don't care about the new kids issues Mm-hmm.
Scott: I think that's gonna be a bigger.
Scott: It was a big problem, you know, pretty much always.
Scott: but I think it's a bigger problem now because Things change so freakin fast and the government is just as slow as it was in 18.
Rym: Oh, yeah a long time ago.
Rym: in some ways I think it was a benefit because it did keep.
Rym: the one nice thing about our government is that it's slow enough to keep bad Things from happening in a hurry.
Rym: Yeah, it keeps good things from happening in a hurry But as the world learned from Rome and the Byzantine Empire The more good things can happen in a hurry the more bad things can happen in a hurry.
Scott: That is good.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: However, now bad things that are you know, of course bad things that aren't a result of laws But a result of the nature of the world are happening a lot faster than we can ever stop them.
Scott: So While We are not making bad things happen with Making bad laws and we're not making good things happen very quickly by making good laws and it's just going at the steady pace Bad things are happening and we're just on their own and not too many good things are happening on their own.
Rym: relative Well plus look how fast technology is advancing.
Rym: think about how different the world is and the internet is technologically From two years ago even two years ago.
Rym: The internet was a different place.
Scott: There was no YouTube.
Rym: In fact think of this.
Rym: the internet has changed more in the last two years than it did in like eight years before that and the 16 years before that.
Scott: Yep, and the old fogies in Congress can't keep up and Eventually, it's gonna fuck us all.
Rym: and it's not even really a question of the old fogies It's a question of society is getting to the point where?
Rym: Things change so rapidly that people you fall out of the loop like that in an instant.
Scott: I really think there's gonna be a point maybe later in our lives where There are gonna be people who can't keep up and people who can't.
Scott: and the people who can't are gonna start to look a lot Like cavemen to the people who can.
Scott: and we're really gonna.
Scott: it's sort of gonna be like Gundam with like new types and not New types in or you know, what do they call it?
Rym: Well, I guess one thing yeah that normals humans.
Rym: Yeah, humans and you didn't know the word for human.
Rym: No.
Scott: No the other word the the one that you don't call it New typing Gundam seed they call it a Coordinator.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's really gonna be like that.
Scott: where it's like there are people that are just Below others because they're in the society because they just can't interact with it because they don't know how.
Rym: well I think it's going to be exactly the same as it is with literacy, you know At least in the Western world where currently being illiterate is a crippling handicap
Scott: Yeah, and worse than not having any legs
Rym: and being Technologically incompetent or technologically out of the loop while bad and causes a lot of problems Does not remove you from society the way illiteracy does but it will yes I really think within I don't even say within our lifetime I think within the decade maybe maybe two decades,
Scott: but I think it's actually gonna be worse you see because Illiterate people can't read or write but you can still talk to them.
Scott: They speak English.
Scott: We're gonna get to the point.
Scott: or they speak whatever language from whatever country they're from they can speak in here.
Scott: I think it's gonna get to a point and maybe like, you know when we're 70 or 80 where you just can't even talk to them They're just they cannot communicate.
Rym: I'm starting to see that now.
Rym: I mean sadly, I don't talk to my family nearly as much as I would like to Because I just don't think to pick up a phone.
Rym: I'm just online all the time.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Pete my grandma keeps complaining like why don't you call me and then she IM is me?
Scott: But I hate to instant message her because she sucks at instant messaging.
Scott: It's painful.
Rym: or like look at businesses.
Rym: Here's a big example in my life.
Rym: as far as I can see if a place of business doesn't have a web presence if I Can't find them on the internet and I don't happen to pass by them on my way to somewhere else that I did find on The internet it doesn't exist.
Rym: there could be the best restaurant in the world in my town and I would never know it was there if it wasn't on the Internet or if I did.
Rym: I mean it's right now geeks like us.
Rym: You know the.
Rym: you know There's the the curve of innovators early adopters and all that the long tail of people pick it up later the earliest adopters and the innovators right now that like the uber geeks and the people well beyond us because there are people well Beyond us in terms of adopting new technology super
Scott: beyond us mostly people with money.
Rym: They look at us the way we look at people who don't own computers.
Rym: Yep But people like us are starting to semi voluntarily cut ourselves off from a lot of the world Just by nature of the way we communicate and the way we interact and the way we live and What the way it works is.
Rym: society eventually always follows the early adopters.
Rym: It just takes time.
Rym: Eventually most of society is gonna be where we are and we'll be off somewhere stupid doing our own whatever technology crap.
Scott: But I think that the society always catches up with the early adopters at the same rate the rate of which people learn things.
Scott: But the early adopters are gonna go faster and faster and faster to accelerate faster and faster.
Scott: So
Rym: I think what's gonna happen is we're gonna have a longer and a longer tail for a long time for at least the next decade where there's gonna be this long long gradient and Society is gonna keep getting more connected Until a point where I think what Scott brought up is gonna happen and I don't know where the line will be But there's eventually going to be a line where people are just outside of society.
Scott: Yeah, we sort of like, you know I don't know people walking around Like hooked into cyberspace and then people walking around in the meat world and it's actually different.
Rym: What was it called?
Rym: Emily just told me about an anime that just came out that we got to check out Where.
Rym: the idea is that the internet is everywhere now that there goes in the show not even not like that But there's transponders everywhere, right?
Rym: And if you put on glasses, you can just interact with this and see it so you can have a virtual Follows you around or yeah stuff like that.
Rym: They live.
Rym: so people who are in with this and where the glasses live in the same physical world as people who do not But actually live in an entirely different Effective world.
Rym: they're in a world that is completely alien to people who don't use this technology.
Scott: Yeah, and of course this all assumes that nothing crazy happens.
Rym: Yes, as long as there's no global thermonuclear war or a similar event.
Rym: Now my fear is that a lot of people might fall out of the loop just because the leaders of their countries are Holding them back.
Rym: I mean, it's not any given North Koreans fault that they're out of the loop technologically.
Rym: No, it's not but there's no way they can get in the loop.
Scott: But what might happen is their whole country will fall out of the world loop And it that's the end of the whole country right there or like large parts of Africa or even South America.
Rym: that's why I really it seems like education and the spreading of technology and Information and connectivity is the best thing we can do for nations that are having trouble outside of you know.
Scott: First obviously food and security and that's why they're doing that stuff for like the ol PCs and all that stuff Yep, or even Ubuntu.
Scott: Yeah, but they're not it's not they're not doing it.
Rym: So well, well, it's hard to do.
Rym: I mean How do you convince someone who is trying to get food to eat to live one more day that they should be on the internet?
Scott: Because if they learn how to use the computer they can you know right now They'll go five days hungry and then every other day for the rest of their lives They'll get twice as much food as they've had before.
Rym: the problem is I still think the immediate Maslow Opportunity cost is too great.
Rym: for a lot of people.
Rym: it is and I can't blame anyone but the leaders of their countries at this Point.
Rym: Yep, but that that To talk anymore about.
Scott: then you could say that people in there in a country the population.
Scott: You can't blame the leaders.
Scott: may even if the leaders like some monarch is the people could rise up and do something.
Rym: But and then if you go full circle the people can't rise up unless they're connected.
Rym: Otherwise, there's no way to organize but they can't.
Scott: people have done it.
Scott: You know there was rising up going on hundreds of years ago.
Rym: Rising ups were always due to people having some measure of secure connection to where they could organize it.
Rym: Yeah And that's actually being harder to do because a long time ago when there are revolutions in the US or in France or wherever The world there wasn't so much surveillance and it wasn't that hard to secretly put something together.
Rym: But now people who are in power have so much more power relative to people who aren't in power that it's so much more difficult to rise up against them except Geeks and people in the modern world because we have encryption that the government's can't keep up with.
Scott: Yep Yeah I guess if the actual leader of the country does is like.
Scott: I was kind of assuming the whole country was technology Technologically deficient, but if you're a king with mad computers and all your people are peasants They're pretty much permanently oppressed I mean unless they physically run away and you didn't catch them.
Rym: from what I read I am sure that the elite and the aristocracy and the government of North Korea are connected to the Internet.
Rym: Yeah, probably and know about the world, but because they have that power.
Rym: There's no way anyone in their country could do anything.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I think we're done things of the day.
Rym: So we were talking over the weekend.
Rym: I'll get to it I'll get to it.
Rym: scotch is a chin to bring this one up because this is a good thing of the day.
Rym: We were joking about the tally of people we know who give us things of the day and the frontrunners are like Idaho gives us a lot and actually Emily gives us a lot and a few of the listeners send us some and we've got a General idea of who gives us good things of the day.
Scott: Most of them come from dig.
Scott: dig gives us Yes, but in terms of not actually humans who give us stuff Yeah, most of the time though it's us finding it on the internet but there are.
Scott: we do get them from people
Rym: and luckily the ones we get from people are usually the good ones because they're not on dig or and
Scott: also because if someone gives them to us like that and it's something it's Either we've already seen that or those are the aren't people who spend all day on the internet.
Scott: So when they find something it's because that's something kind of came around to them and their specific way which matters a lot.
Rym: because while?
Rym: We're connected to the slash-dot dig, you know the technorati of the world and all that?
Rym: We're not can?
Rym: there are two communities on the internet that we are not connected to every other community.
Scott: We're not connected to who.
Rym: I'm connected to a lot
Scott: Yeah, we're not connected to every community on the internet But to well,
Rym: but the ones that matter to us the ones that would give us things of the day Yeah, and and also the ones that are big Okay, and of the big ones we're not connected to the live journal community, which is like this insular Closed community of
Scott: people.
Scott: It's not really inserting clothes.
Rym: Yes It's the God.
Rym: Go in there the the inside jokes that spark.
Rym: like every now and then a joke pops out a live journal and it's usually really Funny or it's some kind of lolcat thing or whatever.
Rym: but they circulate in live journal for a long time before they ever make it to dig.
Rym: hmm and We miss out on a lot of those too long after the fact.
Rym: so Corbin Showed us this and I just come to get right to it.
Rym: Should I just play the whole thing?
Scott: I don't know if you need to play the whole thing.
Rym: All right, uh, I'll sum it up.
Rym: a guy Made a little song for his daughter who was frustrated with people She has to deal with at work and the song goes a little something like this About to whip somebody's ass.
Rym: About to whip somebody's ass.
Rym: Oh If you don't leave me alone You're gonna have to send me home cuz I'm about to whip somebody's ass.
Rym: Really like it.
Rym: I just it fits.
Rym: I feel good about that song.
Scott: I feel real good about that song.
Scott: Awesome song.
Scott: the guy's a musical talent and he recorded it pretty high quality.
Rym: Now that made me laugh a little bit of lolcat in me Yeah.
Rym: Then one thing led to another and an unrelated human being elsewhere in the world Took that and made a techno remix.
Rym: That is actually pretty badass.
Rym: I'm not gonna play an example here.
Rym: Just listen to it.
Rym: It's really worth listening to.
Rym: I also know that's really.
Rym: That's the kind of dance music.
Rym: I like I like to dance to that stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it's good music Alright, so I want to.
Scott: I want to get this straight here cuz this is how Corbin tells me the story.
Scott: you ready Guy makes song for daughter, right?
Scott: Probably heard that she was frustrated at work over the telephone Records.
Scott: song with microphone into computer.
Scott: put song on internet.
Scott: People on internet find song.
Scott: some guy who makes a video podcast Found the song and played it on his show.
Scott: people who listen who watch that video podcast Right all over the world made remixes of the song and sent them back to the video podcast guy.
Scott: The video podcast guy then asked if they could find out where the original singing guy was.
Scott: They found him.
Rym: in two days.
Scott: two days The video podcast guy went to the guy who sang the song with a CD full of the remixes Interviewed him on the video podcast.
Scott: They put the remixes up on the website.
Scott: Some guy named Corbin saw it showed it to some people named Rym and Scott.
Scott: people named Rym and Scott got it made an audio Podcast right put that on the internet and whoever you are is now listening to that.
Rym: and when you tell someone about this That how many layers is that?
Rym: the meta levels of this are astounding.
Rym: This is the world we live in.
Scott: It's basically almost Godlike omniscience.
Rym: I say this a lot.
Rym: This has been one of the.
Rym: I have a few kicks lately and a bit but lately I really think about the fact that compared to the vast majority of Human beings that have ever existed as far as we know in the history of the planet Earth We right now myself and Scott and all of you listening are Gods.
Rym: compared to them we live out what we just did.
Scott: think about it for real.
Scott: Look at the bigness of it.
Scott: Like you look at the stars in space and you see you like you think about how it Ludicrously large it is with these stars billions of light-years apart and the light that took a billion years to shine down on you.
Scott: This is like one.
Scott: This is half a step under that.
Rym: Grock.
Rym: the home is here grock the fullness.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: I mean, what kind of world do we live in?
Rym: There's a good chance that at some point along that chain That audio went into space and came back from a satellite.
Scott: Think of that.
Rym: Yeah So that is my thing of the day that we are at this moment compared to the vast host of humanity that has ever existed Living unto likened unto gods.
Scott: and you know, we use that godlike power for singing about whipping people's asses About a do thing of the day.
Rym: Okay, that wasn't so great.
Rym: Damn it.
Scott: So We talked about encryptions before one or two times.
Rym: I think we did a whole show on it semi recently David me.
Scott: I don't really remember.
Scott: I don't remember if I've even talked about this thing on the show before but I searched and I'm pretty sure it wasn't a thing Of the day.
Rym: we did do a show on how encryption works on a basic level, right?
Rym: there is a Firefox
Scott: extension that I've been using for a while called fire GPG and GPG is basically can do privacy Guard I don't know exactly
Rym: as the open source equivalent of PGP,
Scott: which is pretty good privacy and That allowed GPG is basically a program that lets you manage keys and encrypt things very strongly.
Rym: Yep, and by encrypting this member that also includes Signing and signing.
Rym: so verify.
Rym: even if you don't encrypt you can still verify.
Rym: I am the person who sent this within such an astronomical mathematical certainty that you can be guaranteed It's me or someone held the gun to my head and forced me to sign it for him, right?
Scott: Fire GPG is a Firefox extension that incorporates into GPG that allows you to encrypt decrypt sign and verify Text in any text box in your browser and also it integrates with Gmail.
Scott: So what I can do is very easily in my Gmail I can write a Gmail I can click Encrypt and send and it will encrypt my Gmail and send it and then if the person on the other end has fire GPG and I encrypted it with their private key and their put they get it their public key and their fire GPG will automatically Decrypt it and if Google tries to read that email, they'll be like up.
Scott: It's a garbled mess.
Rym: Oh, well now anytime someone takes encryption and makes it trivial to use.
Rym: That makes me happy because I am I used to be a proponent of open internet Mostly because I was in school and every time I had to deal with debugging a problem with an encrypted protocol It sucked.
Rym: but in the real world, I want everyone to encrypt everything when at all possible.
Rym: Yep at least when it's in transit not so much on your own computer because I could go on and on about.
Rym: I'd like there to be archives of email for the future for generations to study and read and I could do a whole show on that.
Rym: but suffice to say I think it's a good idea for everyone to encrypt because encryption will always stay ahead of I guess Decryption that is not authorized barring
Scott: the technological discovery Yes
Rym: but if everyone encrypts even if the encryption is broken or breakable it makes it that much harder for Anyone with malicious intent or any government to put forth the effort to decrypt everything and snoop on all your data.
Rym: Yep They're really.
Rym: regardless whether or not you believe there's a right to privacy in the United States The fact remains that regardless of whether that right exists anywhere it is your duty to protect your privacy whenever you can by whatever legal means you have available
Scott: and Encryption is one of those means that is legally available to you and it up until very recently managing keys and encrypting and decrypting and signing and these things weren't easy to do.
Scott: like Sometimes they're easier than others and there are tools you could buy to make it easy.
Rym: Yeah but the easiest it was in high school.
Rym: the best I got it was where I could tell it to automate I could encrypt whatever was In my clipboard, so I typed something put it in the clipboard run the program paste it back out send it.
Rym: Yeah, I sent it to had to copy it into the clipboard decrypt it paste it back out.
Scott: Generally, it's a pain in the ass unless someone else sets it up for you.
Scott: now with fire GPG It's pretty freakin easy like damn easy.
Scott: So if you're thinking about you know, you know, I don't encrypt or sign all my emails, but sometimes they do.
Rym: Yeah, and actually the only I used to always and the only reason I haven't is that my computer was kind of crappy And I didn't like compiling anything on it.
Rym: And now that I have a new computer I'm going to go full-on with my permanent.
Rym: Well semi-permanent GPG signatures of varying lengths.
Scott: Sounds good.
Scott: So fire GPG worth installing and setting up.
Rym: So we were inspired to do this show after a conversation Scott had with our friend drag-and-drop over at anime world order a little while ago, yes, you see Someone was complaining.
Scott: Well, actually I they were saying, uh, don't use VLC.
Scott: It sucks.
Scott: and I Went and I told them well, yeah, I don't like VLC either I'm not a fan, but there's no reason it shouldn't work unless you fuck up.
Rym: Yeah, VLC while it does use a lot of resources it'll play just about any video with almost no effort.
Scott: Yep, it'll just might be slow and the interface is kind of cruddy, but it's not that bad.
Rym: I don't mind VLC at all.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not a fan.
Scott: so I realized that there's a lot of different media playing softwares out there and you know You go and I use people's computers or I see people using their computers and everyone's using something different.
Scott: some people using iTunes People using QuickTime People using Winamp people using widows media player.
Scott: It's people using them play man.
Rym: There was a time when Winamp was the people and all.
Scott: yeah, there's people using foobar whatnot right?
Scott: and all everyone uses something different and a lot of 90% of media playing programs suck and People got to learn not to use these crappy ones that they insist on using for whatever reason.
Rym: Well first the brief 30-second history of media playing.
Rym: Alright, there was nothing for the longest time.
Rym: There was nothing.
Rym: you just couldn't play media If you could.
Rym: it was some proprietary like a program that made media appear.
Rym: Yep, then We had multimedia PCs.
Rym: media started appearing everywhere.
Scott: Your computer usually would come with a program or two and those programs would be able to play maybe an AVI Which is there was a QuickTime and Windows Media.
Scott: AVI's were sort of these competing formats.
Rym: Yeah, basically nothing was compatible.
Rym: It was almost and you could maybe play a wav file.
Scott: That was really short or an eighth file and that was about it.
Rym: Yeah, not that it mattered because you couldn't get any miles anyway.
Rym: Midi yes, I'm doing a show on MIDI.
Scott: Yep, and then win it.
Rym: Yep, basically mp3s came about and huh mp3s.
Rym: I wonder how I can play these.
Rym: and then Nelsoft and Winamp.
Scott: There was also real but real sigh.
Rym: Oh god Yeah, I guess I skipped over that on a subconsciously on purpose.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Real basically real player the original real player.
Scott: the idea of it was hey, let's stream video over 14 for modems So it would compress the hell out of video and audio.
Scott: So the quality was Stupidly low.
Scott: I mean worse than any podcast you've listened to so bad and You could watch like a tiny tiny video of CNN headline news.
Scott: That was all jerky and low resolution.
Rym: I remember watching 30 seconds of Les Miserables and like a 60 by 60 window.
Rym: Yes, and that was awesome.
Scott: Well, I was in a 640 by 480 monitor.
Scott: So it wasn't so bad.
Rym: It looked bigger Yeah, but it was still only 60 pixels.
Rym: How much information is there in 60 pixels of video?
Scott: Yeah, and that's how it was.
Rym: So, uh, well real just kind of that company was evil back then like they're.
Rym: oh, they're not as bad now But that was bad now.
Rym: They were actually evil and we're trying to take over media on computers But we're not gonna get into that either.
Scott: No, we're not.
Rym: Winamp pretty much became the gold standard for a long time in media playing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it could play pretty much any audio file and then it started playing video really?
Scott: Well, yeah I mean even when when it was playing video there were other players to use as well.
Scott: But Winamp was just as good as the others because in those days like the early days of Divx and MPEG-4 Pretty much, you know, you had trouble with any player you chose and you know Winamp was just as good as the others.
Rym: Yeah, there were competing codecs competing formats.
Rym: They still are but back then there was no easy way to install them.
Scott: No, it wasn't obvious at least.
Scott: Yeah, like I actually installed I think for a long time I used the Divx player from Divx.com.
Scott: Yeah, which is terrible.
Rym: It is pretty terrible.
Rym: I gotta say it's horrendous.
Scott: No one should use it.
Rym: So now recently it's not as big a deal anymore And it's pretty easy to get media playing to work as long as you know what programs to use and how to set them up.
Scott: Yeah, I mean a lot of people.
Scott: they use just Windows Media Player, which I guess it's.
Scott: it's actually not bad.
Rym: Yeah, I will admit if you're using Vista or modern XP Windows Media Player is not that bad for playing video.
Scott: Yeah, and they use you know QuickTime iTunes on a Mac and then they install you know codecs like directly into their operating system that you know all the different players can take advantage of.
Scott: they get like the CCCP thing they get all the codecs on Windows or whatever and VLC can also just play every freaking video and that works on Windows Mac or Linux.
Scott: so a lot of people use VLC, which I don't like.
Scott: it is it's a cry.
Scott: think it's a bad interface and Generally an inefficient program, but it does work and can play it just about any video you've got.
Rym: I don't really worry about efficiency unless I'm near the end of the life cycle of a computer.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, plus I mean my old computer M player couldn't even play most things properly just because it was so old and slow.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, basically.
Scott: I want to talk a bit about M player.
Scott: M-player is the video player the media player.
Scott: actually as far as I'm concerned and far as many people are concerned M-player is primarily a Linux app, but it does go on.
Scott: we use it on the Mac and you can use it at Windows.
Scott: also.
Scott: M-player can fucking play anything.
Scott: god damn it can play anything.
Rym: not only that but it actually it's pretty simple to make it work.
Rym: It's not as complicated as you might expect But there's a lot of functionality just under the surface if you decide you actually want it But it's not in your way if you don't want it.
Scott: Yep It's like with M player.
Scott: you can.
Scott: you have the ability to like adjust the timing of subtitles if you want to But you don't have to and you won't even know.
Scott: you can do that If you want to just watch videos and listen to music and player does that very easily and it does it with such Clockwork and perfect efficiency that just always works.
Scott: It's amazing.
Rym: So Scott say you've got a Windows PC.
Rym: How would you go about installing M player and getting it to play commonly found things on the Pirates Bay or anime ski?
Scott: Well first I would go to the M player website.
Rym: Isn't it M player org?
Scott: It's M player HQ HU.
Rym: Oh Yeah, I've never actually been there.
Scott: I just go in the repositories Yes, and then I would go to the download page and the download page here says description M player 1.0 RC 1 Windows GUI.
Scott: So I download that and I do the usual business just like it's a program.
Rym: I'd install it now notice GUI It's not like.
Rym: it's some weird Linux.
Rym: Oh, you gotta type commands to make it.
Scott: well You can also download M player 1 RC Windows, which does not have the goo.
Rym: Yeah, I'd recommend getting the GUI because I'm a Windows user.
Rym: Yeah, or if you're anyone it's nice to have.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is I actually like it better without the GUI because it's really simple.
Scott: All I do is I find the file.
Scott: I want to play and I say M player Space the file and I push enter and it plays.
Scott: That's all I got to do.
Scott: It can even play DVDs.
Scott: I watch DVDs on the train with M player on my laptop.
Scott: M player space DVD colon slash slash Chapter number.
Scott: so chapter 4 and it plays.
Scott: chapter 4 the DVD ba-bam.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: So then how do I go about getting the codecs?
Rym: I heard that nothing works unless I get all the like.
Rym: fancy new Divx codecs.
Scott: well on the same page where you can download M player if you scroll down a bit, it says Binary codec packages, huh?
Scott: And there's a little thing there You can download the binary codec packages and install them and that will allow you to play 99.9% of videos and audios ever.
Rym: So, uh, how do people have problems with this?
Scott: because people don't use M player and they use some other crazy video program or They have problems with their computer in general outside of their media player.
Rym: And since a media player is sort of a finicky app in general Screwing up your computer with spyware or DRM or other is what I was waiting for you to say because most of the time when someone comes to us with a Windows media playing problem.
Rym: It is probably actually a Windows spyware or Windows DLL or Windows broken problem?
Rym: Yep, Macs are different But I don't know enough about doing all that on the Mac to really talk about it.
Scott: The most reason the most problem with Macs is that so many Mac programs just use QuickTime.
Scott: So you kind of have to put stuff into QuickTime to make it do what you want, which is not obvious.
Scott: Like you get to go put some stuff in some library files somewhere and all that kind of jazz.
Rym: But you can always just run M player on the Mac.
Scott: The way we watch Anime on the Mac is I have M player and a little dock thing and I just find a video file and I drag it Onto the M player icon and let go and it plays every time.
Rym: well nine every now and then.
Rym: well the one or two times It didn't work.
Rym: Usually the file was actually broken or corrupt.
Scott: Yeah, it wouldn't play in anything on any computer.
Scott: The thing about M player that you gotta understand is actually one of the things I like the most about it Is that if you're not using the GUI version, it's all.
Scott: it's all keyboard shortcuts.
Scott: But the keyboard shortcuts are obvious.
Scott: Like if you want to skip forward like one 30 seconds in the video You push the right arrow.
Scott: if you want to go back you push the left arrow.
Scott: If you want to go like a minute ahead or back you push the up and down arrows.
Scott: You cannot.
Scott: you can do all this stuff to like go forward and back like with page up and page down like ten minutes.
Scott: and Unlike other, you know video programs.
Scott: So like you'll drag the little thing left and right and it sort of lags and You know, it skips around a bit.
Rym: It's instant.
Rym: It's just BAM BAM BAM player is instant.
Scott: It's like BAM BAM BAM.
Scott: It just immediately jumps ahead and it's perfect with no skips.
Rym: That's not just fast computer It's BAM BAM BAM for the most part even on my old computer.
Scott: Yeah that if you've got an old computer and like you're watching videos and it skips around a lot To try using like M player on Linux.
Scott: I can get a Pentium 3 450 450 megahertz people to play Brand-new high quality videos with M player.
Scott: It's it'll work without a lot of skipping at all.
Scott: It'd be very watchable because I used to watch anime on a computer exactly like that back in the day When videos were actually even worse than they are now.
Rym: So I should have no problem now and Sadly, well, I guess not sadly.
Rym: That's really all we have to say about that.
Scott: It's pretty straightforward use M player use M player and yeah video players is sort of a troubled thing.
Scott: You know, there's like so many different ones and there's a lot of spyware ones out there and yeah It's not as bad as it used to be.
Scott: It's like everyone has these different preferences, you know for what software they use to play their media and I think there's really not too many of them that are actually good and I don't know why people are all using different things.
Rym: I think part of it is people don't know and part of it is that there are a lot of Websites out there that trick you or try to make you think that you need their player to play certain things or that some things Are incompatible.
Rym: there's a lot of fun about media players.
Scott: There is indeed a lot of fun.
Scott: Yep people like oh, yeah If you're having trouble.
Scott: so because it'll generally happen is someone will find a file they can't play and they'll go somewhere and they'll say Hey, I can't play this file.
Scott: What should I do?
Scott: And someone always says oh use this player.
Scott: Oh use this player I don't have any problems with this one.
Scott: Yeah, and they keep switching player.
Rym: But here's the thing.
Scott: All right I have a problem on different codec packs.
Rym: I'm Wendy and I have my Windows PC and it's full of spyware and I can't play some video I downloaded.
Rym: so I go and ask hey guys, I can't play this video.
Rym: I'm using Windows Media Player and they say oh, well, it works fine if I play it in blah blah blah.
Rym: So I download blah blah blah and it still doesn't play.
Rym: now the reason it doesn't play?
Rym: because my computer's messed up.
Rym: There's nothing to do with what video player I'm using.
Scott: Yeah I notice a lot of people have like a whole bunch of different video players and audio players installed on the same computer and it's We do.
Rym: but that's just because we never bothered to delete all the ones we experimented with.
Scott: Yeah No, I really only have well on the Mac.
Rym: Yeah, we have the QuickTime.
Rym: We have the VLC We have the end player.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but you can't get rid of the QuickTime juice.
Scott: There's an immediate.
Scott: I know.
Rym: I just laugh about juice because I'm thinking about uninstalling it.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, the other thing though is Nowadays people actually back in the day.
Scott: You didn't have a lot of media.
Scott: You only had like a folder full of it.
Scott: So using directories and your file system as a way to organize your media was not a big deal because it actually worked.
Scott: You only had like a thousand songs.
Scott: Maybe just organize them into folders and you're good to go.
Scott: nowadays it's really necessary to have something that sort of manages your music or video library because you have so much stuff with such these giant hard Drives and there's not too many applications that do that very well at all.
Rym: Yeah, I mean iTunes does it better than most I'd say but I still it's not.
Scott: it does it it.
Scott: iTunes does it in a way that actually works which is better than most.
Rym: see that's the thing.
Rym: iTunes doesn't do it in a Like but iTunes works and doesn't just crash halfway through.
Scott: Yes on Linux pretty much like banshee can do it But banshee if you add more than like a hundred things to the library It becomes unstable and crashes and slows to the all the shit no matter what computer using I mean.
Rym: sadly It's to the point where while I recognize that I need to organize my music in a better way because the way I do it Now is fine, but it's starting to be outstripped just by the sheer amount of media I have but I continue to put my new music into the same directory structure Which is fairly robust, but it's gonna run It's not.
Rym: it's not gonna extend forever because there's no better way for me to do it.
Rym: I have too many songs Yep, and Linux.
Scott: the only thing that actually I think does a good job of it is Amarok mostly because it just doesn't crash and It actually is good.
Scott: management uses real relational databases to tell her that stuff.
Scott: But it's like a Katie EF and it's it's a little you know, it's not perfect.
Scott: But the other problem is the best you can get.
Rym: a lot of people have a large Legacy collection of music that they've gotten from way back in the day.
Rym: There's no ID threes in that file names are wrong things are spelled wrong all sorts of.
Rym: it's very hard to take an old set of mp3s and Without a lot of effort or crying put them into a new way of organizing them.
Scott: Yep I mean there are things that'll help you out with that like music brains.
Scott: But music brains isn't perfect and it basically it's.
Scott: it's a tool that makes it easier to Like corral all your mp3s and such.
Scott: But it still requires a lot of manual labor and data entry and dragging and dropping and typing It just requires a lot less than doing every single song one at a time.
Rym: so I think as a result a lot of people end up continuing to use their old structures just because They like like my mp3 collection.
Rym: if I import that into iTunes I can't find anything easily because I know where all the files are.
Rym: They're organized in a way that makes sense to me, you know, this gigantic nested collection of folders based on different whatever's.
Rym: But in iTunes because there's no ID 3 data or anything The songs are just in this mishmash and without the file name structure and the directory structure I can't find the files.
Rym: So as a result, I don't use iTunes to organize my old music But I'd like to use it to organize my new music.
Rym: But then now I'm gonna have two different collection to music.
Rym: I think the only answer is to keep your legacy music separate and start fresh with your new music and wait and eventually You'll probably replace all your old music with better modern mp3s of the new stuff with all the data in the right places and once you reach that point just delete your old mp3 collection.
Scott: But yeah There aren't too many programs besides iTunes and maybe I'd ever tried to do it with Windows Media Player and WinAmp does it now And when I'm
Rym: did it, okay, actually
Scott: Yeah When it does it does it an okay way and that it is really not too many programs that are good at managing a media Library, which is becoming a huge need of many people.
Scott: that is not satisfied nearly as well as it should.
Rym: plus media library alone one thing cross-platform media library or media library on SAN or NAS.
Rym: But then I want to access it from iTunes from my iPod and I also want to access it from my media player downstairs and my zoom.
Rym: At that point you got to use the directory structure to just so everything will work and then you're right back where you started.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, it pretty much sucks.
Scott: Like because you've got an iPod.
Scott: You've got a computer a desktop You've got a laptop and you've got the music stored.
Scott: and you know You don't want to copy every single song and every single video to every single one of those.
Rym: Yeah hard drives aren't that cheap.
Scott: Yeah, so you want to have them all probably on the desktop or on maybe a server somewhere But you want to be able to search and play anything from the library from your laptop no matter where you are.
Scott: You want to be able to sync anything to your iPod no matter which computer you plug the iPod into.
Scott: you want to be able To you know, listen to any song and watch any video from any computer and there's really not too many solutions for that.
Scott: I mean, there's a pro there's a thing on Linux the MPD the music player demon, but that's sorta.
Scott: It has the right design to do something like that, but it's not perfect.
Scott: It doesn't solve all the needs.
Scott: There really isn't anything that solves all these needs now.
Rym: I mean for now I'm just gonna keep my directory structure which is half based on artist and then album but also half based on genre.
Rym: Yep, which is kind of annoying but luckily I'm weird so I'm used to it.
Scott: But once you find whatever file you want to play and player plays it.
Scott: Yep And that's all.
Scott: I think that's all we got to say.
Scott: media players are crazy and Don't use a stupid one.
Rym: Yeah, and in terms of just playing audio on Linux, I use xmm s.
Scott: Xms is old and busted.
Rym: I know it's old but it still kind of works.
Rym: It works Okay, and it's it feels like Winamp which I'm used to.
Scott: I use Amarok because my media library is in it So I don't have to you know export or anything like.
Rym: the only reason I'm not currently using Amarok is because I didn't have a computer that I could easily install it on until now.
Rym: I think xmm s is gonna go the way of all the other things I was on installing.
Scott: thing is those guys are working on.
Scott: there used to be beat media player But now they're actually working on BMP X and it looks like it's going to become the shit awesome.
Scott: But it's not there yet.
Scott: So you got to wait until BMP X is ready and then we can go to BMP X. Cuz I think in the end that will be the best choice But it's not right now.
Rym: and on that note I want to finish here Mostly because I want to get the show done on the new computer.
Rym: See how long it takes to edit which I think is gonna be a really pleasant experience.
Scott: Gotta bet a lot earlier there.
Rym: Not at all.
Rym: No, cuz I think I'm gonna reboot and play steam.
Rym: I installed Def Con.
Rym: Steam is bad because I can just click on games that I don't own and the games appear and the only thing that changes is A number goes up on my credit card.
Scott: You can even get game demos without making the number go up.
Rym: I know I know but I can get games and also I can play counter-strike.
Rym: And I guess I forgot that counter-strike is still a pretty damn good game.
Rym: all things are not full ads Yeah, but luckily I can as long as I don't play on the most popular maps in the game.
Rym: I won't see the ads.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.