Scott: There's so much going on.
Scott: I mean I got new parts of my laptop.
Rym: I've got like eight new things of the day.
Scott: There's like bunch of things of the day and newsies and it all everything's so great.
Scott: We got loads of show material, but we're not gonna use any of it.
Rym: No, not at all.
Scott: No, we're holding on to everything.
Scott: All the cards are firmly planted against the chest.
Scott: Today is yet another day of ask Grim and Scott week.
Rym: Listen to I don't know Tuesday October 16th or Monday October 15th.
Rym: And even if you don't like I don't know computers or video games or any of that I'd say listen to them anyway, because we've been getting more feedback about these episodes than from frickin anything else.
Scott: Yep, all this week and perhaps even another week in the future.
Scott: We are going to just answer listener questions, and that's all we're gonna do and Basically some of the the rules about this.
Scott: first of all We are not going to give credit to who asked the question so none of that.
Rym: Joey Jojo Shabbat who writes.
Scott: first of all that takes up a lot of time and second of all that really can affect the psychology of how we answer the question, so we just got rid of that.
Scott: and Second of all, we're just gonna I don't know answer the questions perfectly literally like well, that's been Scott's thing Yeah, but I mean a lot of people ask questions, you know, and it's obvious what they really asking.
Scott: But if I answer the question literally is just yes or no, and then that's not what they want.
Rym: So now also we're doing this from pieces of paper.
Rym: We don't have any like screens open in front of us.
Rym: We're.
Rym: we're kind of running it like it's a radio talk show and people just called in and asked these questions other than Going through quickly to make sure everything in the list was actually a question.
Rym: We didn't even read him ahead of time.
Scott: Nope So shall we begin because all yesterday and the day before it was like we only got through half the questions And I believe we're going to get through half the questions.
Rym: if that because there's a lot of them here, okay Well, let's get started.
Rym: All right, so do you torrent any comics?
Rym: I have torrented one comic in my life and that was death note.
Scott: I didn't torrent death note.
Scott: I guess I'm gonna direct.
Rym: I'm not gonna say I mean Obviously.
Rym: they're using torrent in the generic sense of download of scans lation.
Scott: I never use bit.
Scott: Well, actually they could be specifically referring to torrents because I know that every week They put out torrents that had for example every Marvel and DC comic that came out this week and stuff like that.
Scott: So no, I do not torrent any comics.
Scott: I buy comics with money on paper and I read webcomics that are supposed to be free online.
Scott: and that's it.
Scott: The only I read the scans lations of death note back in the day, but I own all of death note now.
Rym: so I guess part of it was that one.
Rym: I E-readers aren't there yet and physical media are still better for reading comics.
Rym: in my opinion and to Scans lations are often inaccurate kind of crappy in many times.
Rym: three It's not like manga.
Rym: is that much money for?
Rym: I haven't been excited enough about a manga since death note To actually want to go through the effort of reading it ahead of time instead of just waiting.
Scott: Yep All right This one is only to Rym but I think I'm gonna outlaw that and say everyone we both answer every quest.
Scott: How come for Wednesday?
Rym: a lot of our listeners asked questions just to us because I noticed the next one's the same way.
Scott: Yeah, I think that was might have been the same person asking both questions might have been anyway Rym, even though it's spelled wrong.
Rym: How can you spell that wrong?
Rym: It's in the feed It's rims thing of the day.
Rym: every day people email me.
Scott: Anyway, who is your favorite character in all of comics including manga what you know, whatever all the comics?
Rym: I would say that's kind of a crap question.
Rym: Yeah That's like asking who's your favorite character in a movie ever or in a novel ever?
Rym: where in that case?
Rym: It's a cross between Horatio hornblower and the Count of Monte Cristo, but I digress In comics, I don't know.
Rym: I I'd have to say it's a cross between Ozzie Mandias and Rasha.
Scott: It's also a good one It's.
Rym: that kind of question is really hard to answer.
Rym: I can just say characters.
Rym: I mean what?
Rym: a character that I identified with the most a character that I thought was an interesting character Even though oftentimes I don't identify with at all or sometimes hate characters that I think are great.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even have ryuk sure There whatever.
Rym: so Scott if you were married with a child obviously a hypothetical question what?
Rym: what anime character Would you be proud to name your child after?
Scott: I'm not a freak so I wouldn't name my kid after an anime character.
Rym: I think my answer is that if I had a child their middle name would be get her beam.
Scott: get her beam Hurricane John.
Rym: get her beam to cost her.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I don't know Scott rust hurricane Ruben I don't know.
Rym: when I was younger in my teens I often thought yeah if I ever have a kid their middle name is totally gonna be something from literature and I Guess you could include anime manga comics in that and I think you could draw a name from that sort of thing.
Rym: Well,
Scott: yeah, if I interpret this question differently into where I didn't actually have to name my child after an anime character But sort of an anime character that has qualities that I would like you know that I think are good and I would be proud if my Offspring grew up to be like that character Roger
Rym: Smith.
Scott: Roger Smith's a good one.
Rym: Togusa is pretty good Misato, I just really like Misato.
Scott: talk to me.
Rym: Yeah, cuz talk to me.
Rym: He learns he gets better Those kinds of characters.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: All right, let's move on.
Scott: If you had to pick up an underwear pervert title, which one would it be?
Rym: I would be just be the amazing Rym.
Scott: the amazing Rym I can't.
Rym: I mean, I don't know.
Rym: if I was a superhero my name would just be Rym I wouldn't put anything in front of it.
Scott: Well, I'm currently purchasing.
Scott: I think the only underwear pervert title I'm purchasing right now is Marvel Comics presents, which is a brand new series And it's one of those ones where it's not actually like a continuing thing.
Scott: It's like an anthology.
Scott: so it's like you get four random stories in it each each month and I always buy all those things because They never sell and they always go out of print and then they come up with a new one every few years and I'm the Only one who likes them apparently, but I love those things.
Scott: There's random stories hit or miss random artists random writers.
Scott: It's like whoo.
Scott: It's like a total grab bag and I love that action.
Rym: So I guess of all the underwear pervert literature in the known world it's either, you know Watchmen or Batman the animated series.
Rym: Yeah, because they didn't say they said title.
Rym: so I'm going with Batman.
Scott: Yeah, what they really mean is that like a title that's currently coming out and you know, which yeah I don't care Batman the animated series is like the best underwear pervert thing ever.
Scott: It is and I tried to buy an issue of Batman strikes Which is sort of like the Batman the animated series a comic equivalent.
Scott: It does.
Scott: it doesn't measure up.
Scott: Okay, have either of you seen the anime desert punk?
Scott: I've heard of it, but I've never seen it.
Rym: I've also heard of it and not seen it.
Rym: I thought for a second it was this other anime, but I don't think that's the one I'm thinking of.
Scott: Nope Do you have any interest in any anime coming out next season?
Scott: How about the season just passed?
Rym: Let's talk about just I don't know very very recent anime that we were excited about cuz I'd have to go with baccano.
Scott: It's a good one.
Rym: I'm really excited about.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So last season I would say baccano and this season I have yet to watch the first episode.
Scott: but Gundam double-o might be the second coming of Gundam wings.
Scott: So that could be good.
Rym: or you're excited about it because you haven't seen it yet.
Rym: That's happened before Show and then I don't know it's.
Scott: I mean it's a Gundam show I haven't seen and it's not Gundam.
Scott: see destiny.
Scott: So there's a chance it could be good.
Scott: And if there's a good Gundam show, hooray, if it's not, I'll just won't watch it.
Rym: What was that show?
Rym: we were all excited about because we didn't listen to Emily and we didn't realize it was the same show And it started out all Aboardage and samurai pirate fighting on the high seas and politics and then it turned into gay samurai and nothing more.
Rym: Yeah, I was excited about that for the first five minutes and then it turned out to be like some BL thing.
Scott: Yeah guy harem instead of a girl harem.
Rym: It was a guy harem with all guys who like all guys.
Scott: All right What do you think of controversial or taboo subject?
Scott: anime for example?
Scott: kohikaze Or konomo no jinkan, which I've never heard of?
Rym: I think I am all.
Rym: when it comes to any controversial media I'm always of the mind that one freedom speech people unless they actually harm people in the making of media, you know, like Then there's no it's a snuff film.
Rym: Yeah, then there is nothing wrong with making it no matter what it is.
Rym: I don't think that any subject it that could possibly be conceived of it should be taboo in terms of Writing about it or expressing feelings or thoughts or ideas about it but at the same
Scott: time has nothing to do with whether I'm going to like it or not or whether I think that other people Should watch it or not
Rym: at the same time.
Rym: I feel free to form opinions about people who enjoy such media.
Scott: I do as well.
Scott: so it pretty much comes down to.
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: it's like you could even pick any taboo subject like you know murder or genocide or something and you could you you could have genocide be the focus of a comic or an anime or a video game or movie or any any art form that you know story a narrative art form and You could do it tastefully or Tastelessly.
Scott: and if you do it tastefully then it might be enjoyable.
Scott: and if you do it tastelessly Then it's crap and I think anyone who you know enjoys it is a pretty terrible person.
Rym: Sometimes that goes over the line into hilarity.
Scott: It sometimes does.
Scott: so it pretty much comes down to whether you do it tastefully or not and that is sort of subjective.
Scott: But there seems to be some sort of societal agreement on what's tasteful and what's not for you know like you can have.
Scott: you know you go to the art movie the art theater and you see a movie that happens to have a Sex scene in it and then you go to the porn theater and you just see you know hardcore banging.
Scott: There's a difference.
Scott: They're both sex.
Scott: They're both rated X or whatever, but one of them's tasteful one of them's not.
Rym: So, uh, what anime is your latest favorite?
Rym: I'll assume that means just any anime not just new stuff.
Rym: Well latest favorite my latest favorite right now is I'm finally finishing up Master Keaton And I'm finally finishing up gone kotsuo and they're both the business.
Scott: I Haven't watched anime in a month or two.
Scott: I don't think.
Rym: in fact actually I'm.
Rym: I mean I've only got four episodes left of Master Keaton and I'm really sad because I really really like that show.
Scott: Yeah, I'm probably gonna watch it on the train sooner or later.
Scott: I beat the Zelda.
Rym: the only problem with Master Keaton is that I feel as though it peaked early or may.
Rym: I'm not sure we were.
Rym: the seasons broke up in Japan But there's one episode called the Cali man of the desert and it happens about two-thirds the way through.
Rym: I think it's episode 25 or 26.
Rym: I don't remember but Good God was that that could have been the Master Keaton movie.
Rym: as far as I was concerned That was everything that makes that show awesome.
Scott: Uh-huh, but moving on Let's see, oh what are your opinions of theatrical releases of anime in the US or elsewhere?
Scott: Uh, you know, I like it.
Scott: when they put anime in a movie theater.
Scott: It's one of the few times I'll actually get off my ass and maybe go to the movie theater depending on the end.
Rym: I've caught almost every major anime release in the last several years.
Rym: I missed one in particular, but I caught it.
Scott: I didn't even I got to tell you I didn't even realize the concept of anime in the theater until I think 1992 thousand when I was in Israel and Princess Mononoke was in the theater there with you know Like English with Hebrew subtitles or something like that.
Scott: I didn't actually go see it there.
Scott: but I saw the movie poster and I was like, oh and some other guy on the trip had seen it and he was raving about it the whole time.
Scott: and Yeah, I like it when they put anime in the theater.
Scott: I go see it.
Scott: What what other opinion do you want?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I mean, it's great seeing I think.
Scott: Yeah, I think that they should market it more heavily and put it in more theaters and they're like, oh No one goes to see it.
Scott: The theaters is in our pact.
Scott: You just had to push it out more and then more people will see it.
Scott: It's like come on Yeah, I mean you take the sales in the theaters It's in and multiply them by you know, the number of theaters in a wide release.
Rym: That's a lot more money than they actually make especially considering that they don't promote anime in theaters for shit And it wouldn't cost that much to do it.
Scott: and I and it's not like oh I just want you gotta do is put like the ad in the newspaper Right in the you know in the movie section that says come see this movie.
Scott: What a bunch of awards Yeah, and you buy show time you buy a couple of reviews and local papers That's really cheap and then you freaking put like a commercial on TV during like the local news at night like for a week I don't know.
Rym: I don't want to get into our opinions on the anime industry in general, but I just think that I Get the impression that most of the American anime industry is won by old school anime fans or new school anime fans And they don't seem to have much business sense at all.
Rym: and while maybe oh, it's a labor of love They just want this stuff to come out at the same time They're not really doing anything to spread the genre.
Rym: well not the genre the medium yep Alright.
Rym: Oh, this is a good one for Scott.
Rym: What comic publishing company.
Rym: Do you believe most reliably produces the best content?
Scott: This is a hard question right here because there are a lot of things like I could say vertigo.
Scott: But the problem is vertigo is not a publishing company.
Scott: vertigo is actually an imprint which means it's DC Comics.
Scott: They just put a different label to separate those from the DC Comics.
Scott: so pretty much most vertigo comics are awesome.
Scott: But that's not a publishing company.
Scott: It's an imprint.
Scott: so publishing company if you're talking about reliability We have to go by percentage.
Scott: like the percentage of the stuff They put out that's quality.
Scott: so if a company came out with one comic, and it was high quality Then they're the winner.
Scott: they got a hundred percent versus someone other company that puts out a hundred things and 99 of them are good.
Scott: Then they're not the most reliable even though they put out more good stuff.
Scott: So most reliably produces the best content.
Scott: well the one that I know for sure is Reliable is vertical not vertigo.
Scott: vertical incorporated, which is actually not strictly a comic publisher.
Scott: They are a book.
Scott: basically they publish Japanese books in English But they're putting out all the Tezuka and the keiko Takami, and they never put out anything bad ever.
Scott: It's a hundred percent across the board so vertical incorporated.
Scott: But there's a chance that red five comics could be the second hundred percent comic publisher.
Scott: they are putting out the atom robo and such you know by the Brian clevenger of 8-bit theater fame, so you should buy that at the style of that.
Scott: I mean It's already in the stores now if you want it But it's coming for me at the end of the month, and I liked 8-bit theater a lot.
Rym: But goddamn is that comic exactly what I want?
Scott: imagine like Indiana Jones more badass and a robot a cool robot But not not wise kraken robot.
Rym: you're imagining a robot, and you're not imagining the right kind of row.
Rym: And this is pretty much almost the same spider-man plus, Indiana Jones plus robot.
Rym: Which comic book author is most reliably involved in the best project?
Rym: so Samu Tezuka.
Scott: some with Tezuka, but he's dead.
Scott: so living Brian cave on Brian cave on he can write no wrong all right good now.
Rym: You can do this really long one.
Scott: During the last 10 years the rate at which comic books are being adapted to an audio visual media is increased in the audience.
Scott: consumption is grown.
Scott: EG spider-man x-men to prevent that etc.
Rym: correct use of eg good job.
Scott: Do you think this signifies a change on the product side of audio-visual?
Scott: Entertainment on the consumption side of it.
Scott: if those in charge of audio-visual entertainment keep producing comic book movies Well the audience keep watching it.
Scott: or will they get bored and move on to the next fag?
Rym: well.
Rym: I point out that spider-man 3 and x-men 3 didn't do so.
Rym: well and we're crap.
Scott: I Want to point out that the only thing the only thing that is to be learned from all these comic book movies Is that you know we used to think we used to joke about like all Hollywood's run out of ideas They keep putting out.
Scott: see no they've really run out of ideas.
Scott: They're basically.
Scott: Hollywood has no writers left.
Scott: They can't come up with a single Interesting or new movie plot or script.
Scott: or you know whether they call it screenplay.
Scott: I mean you don't have any of them.
Scott: there are exceptions I think very few compared to what it used to be.
Rym: I think the I mean I wouldn't go quite that far.
Rym: But I would say that I think the general problem is that the Hollywood industry is as it has been at many points in its Existence very risk-averse right now.
Scott: Yep, so they're just.
Scott: you know it's.
Scott: it's relatively easy to Adapt say a comic to a movie than it is to adapt say a book to a movie because you already sort of have like these Storyboards done for you and stuff like that and you could even do like a Sin City job where it's like a direct translation.
Scott: You know so it's.
Scott: it's very you know Hollywood people.
Scott: They like to turn comics into movies and they're optioning comics to turn into movies all the time And it's proven to be a success in the past.
Scott: So if it's proven to be a success in the past they want to take a risk on doing something else like writing a brand New screenplay.
Scott: they'll do something that they at least know has kind of worked in the past.
Rym: plus remember Normal like most people out there the audiences.
Rym: They don't know that V for Vendetta was a comic.
Rym: They don't know that yeah, he was a comic.
Rym: No one knows that 300 was a comic.
Scott: yeah They might say you know on the the movie poster like based on the graphic novel.
Rym: or no one looks at that.
Scott: They might you know in the bookstore people might see it.
Scott: But the vast majority of people have no idea Like even if you put it right in front of their face like what to say V for Vendetta.
Scott: right right at the beginning of V for Vendetta it says DC Comics.
Scott: most people you say hey V for Vendetta like oh, yeah, that was a good movie.
Scott: They don't even know this fucking comic.
Scott: They don't know Alan Morris.
Scott: They don't know anything.
Scott: so Hollywood people are just gonna milk it.
Rym: So anime in the HD DVD blu-ray versus the DVD format worthwhile or not?
Scott: Well first of all I mean, I'm not I'm asking a question here I don't know, but how many anime were actually made in HD?
Scott: I mean if the anime is not made in HD like I don't know Akira.
Scott: well Akira was made on film so you could transfer that to HD, but Say what an old anime that wasn't made on film for the movie theater say initial D Initial D is not gonna do any bad.
Rym: initial D would look like shit in HD.
Rym: Well, I mean I like initial D.
Scott: Hey Eric, how I bebop can I bebop wouldn't do so well in HD.
Scott: It's made for a TV screen.
Scott: It's not widescreen.
Scott: It's not HD.
Scott: It's it's just normal Resolution whatever.
Scott: well putting it on an HD DVD isn't gonna help it out.
Rym: I watched some of the Bandai visual like.
Rym: check out how high quality this stuff is.
Scott: oh yeah, see that was freedom They were showing.
Scott: What I'm saying is what is made in age.
Rym: what I'm saying before you interrupted me is that yeah I watched some of that stuff, and you know what it didn't really look much better than.
Rym: There's no reason to buy anime on an HD DVD.
Scott: I mean we watched freedom right the first episode on a downloaded fan sub so even less than DVD quality and still look pretty Fucking amazing.
Scott: I mean it was more amazing admittedly on the HD TV from the you know at Otakon But not worth the price of an HD DVD player an HD.
Rym: Well look at this an HD TV.
Rym: unless you had them side by side You would not be able to tell.
Rym: and it's just for anime of course I don't think it's even worthwhile for movies me there let alone for and then the price comes way down.
Rym: Yeah, especially since anime attempts to be a lot simpler.
Rym: You know cell shading that sort of thing It's not.
Rym: it's not the kind of thing that's gonna be benefited in any way.
Scott: Yep, except well freedom is actually like one of the.
Scott: you know If there's an anime that's gonna benefit that's gonna be.
Rym: yeah, but what I was saying was that didn't really.
Rym: yep.
Scott: Okay Why is the melancholy of Haruhi Suzumiya is so popular.
Rym: and what is Haruism all right for the first part?
Rym: It's.
Rym: I haven't seen it yet, but a lot of my friends have and I've read about it.
Rym: I want to see it.
Rym: It's just a really clever funny good show that's well animated
Scott: And I think it's a show from what I've heard that is sort of you know made to like target the fans Right at the core the same way that you know a lot of video games like just they.
Scott: they know their audience And they go straight for it with everything.
Scott: They've got.
Scott: you know.
Scott: this show is like we know what otaku like.
Scott: let's stroke Every part of them that likes to be stroked and this show does it.
Rym: so in terms of what is hurry ism?
Rym: And I've also seen it written as Haruhi ism now the same as Naruto ism only for Haruhi.
Rym: I mean I've seen a lot of people trying to make it out to be something more, but and Unless there's some academic dissertation.
Rym: I'm missing from what I can gather It's just one of those memes yeah where people kind of worship Haruhi in this kind of funny way And it looks very 4chan-y, and that's all I really have to say about that.
Rym: So can you actually get caught torrenting anime?
Scott: Well the first question is a technological question for Monday, which is yeah, you actually get caught torrenting anything which Technologically?
Scott: yes, there are things you can do to make it harder for anyone to to create reasonable doubt as to whether you were Torrenting or not and what you were torrenting and stuff like that including encryption and proxies and who knows what or even just reason.
Rym: I mean getting caught is not the thing.
Rym: what I think you really mean is could there be any Consequences?
Rym: and it depends on if you were torrenting something that has been released in the United States yet Or not and it depends who is watching.
Scott: for example there have been in the past.
Scott: I think the closest people have come to dangerous situations is when Bandai Japan said do not pirate solid-state society.
Scott: We will come get you.
Rym: do not fansub it but even then there's not much they could have done because being sued by a Japanese company when you're US citizen and Getting get them getting to the point where they can identify you from an IP and all that.
Rym: I'm not a lawyer, but it seems highly unlikely it is.
Scott: there is not nothing.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: I can't say there's nothing to worry about, but if you just pay attention to anime news a Come at least the current the current situation Companies will make a threat before they do anything.
Rym: I'm just saying there's.
Rym: I'm pretty sure there's nothing to worry about at all.
Rym: the only time you would need to worry is if you Were torrenting or pirating things that have been released in the u.s..
Scott: Straight torrent fansubs and anime ski.
Scott: I would say you're 99% safe if you're torrenting trigon.
Rym: well one you shouldn't be torrenting trigon and two.
Rym: Well yeah, that's it.
Scott: Yeah, you deserve what you get.
Scott: all right does the definition of anime include made in Japan?
Scott: I can something be made in the US and be accepted as an anime?
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I don't care about this anymore because there's there's two camps, and they're mutually exclusive and on one side They're the anime world order types who say by definition It is anime if it is animated and from the nation of Japan.
Rym: and on the other side There's people who say yeah, it's just anything animated that looks like that or it's just anything animated at all.
Scott: But then what if some?
Scott: there's a lot of things that are made you know for Japan like look crayon Shin-chan doesn't look like anime style But that's an anime or even even better.
Rym: the word anime or anime is a French word that just means animation.
Scott: Well and also the word is you know animation and they just shorten it to anime.
Rym: But even better.
Rym: in Japan from what I gather they call a lot pretty much anything animated.
Scott: Yeah, the Simpsons.
Scott: if you go to Japan and you say is the Simpsons an anime?
Scott: They would say yes, the Simpsons is an anime because they don't have a different word for something from their country and something from another Country.
Scott: they just use the word anime for all Animation whether it's movies or TV or from whatever country.
Scott: the only reason we use the word anime is because we like to make a Difference between things that come from our country and things that come from.
Rym: well actually no I was going to say because I noticed that this didn't really happen with French animation It's just with Japanese stuff.
Rym: And I think the reason is that for most anime fans when they saw anime It was just in general what they saw was very very different from American media.
Rym: the stories were just very different and a lot anime seemed like a genre to a lot of early fans just because The storytelling was a lot different the visualization was a lot different.
Rym: It was.
Rym: it was better in a lot of people's eyes And they kind of associated all those things that they saw in anime as this kind of Overarching genre and this is why these people became anime fans rather than fans of animation from around the world in general.
Rym: So the real answer is that it doesn't matter at all And if you ever argue with someone over whether something is anime or not you really need to get a life.
Scott: Yeah, I mean just if you want call everything animation or start calling the Simpsons anime if you want to be really Japanese.
Scott: but I guess the only thing I have to say is that as As I like words to be useful, and if we have words You know I like to give them the definition that makes the most sense in terms of using them in ways that make Conversation easier and allow communication to be you know facilitated.
Rym: for example the argument over.
Rym: You know they decided that Pluto is no longer a planet and there were people who?
Rym: Protested this and I think all of those people are categorically stupid.
Rym: yeah, because the reason Pluto is no longer a planet is because we've realized that there's a bit a bunch of things that are Bigger than Pluto or the same size as Pluto out there.
Rym: And if we call Pluto a planet then we either have to call all those things planets too or the word planet now means dick Yep, so I like words to have to be useful.
Scott: so speaking that we speak the English language and not the Japanese language I think in English.
Scott: You know we've taken a lot of foreign words like croissant.
Scott: right We don't say hooked roll or something like that.
Scott: You know it's much easier to say croissant.
Scott: so we can take words from other countries like Anime and use them for our own purposes, and I think for the purposes of usefulness in language.
Scott: I think it is good to use the word anime to mean Animation from Japan or for Japanese audience is the most useful way to use the term and that's what I use it for.
Scott: but whatever Like if someone says I'm not gonna get hung up about it and go crazy.
Rym: Well like a lot of people say oh avatar is very anime isher.
Rym: It's very much like anime.
Rym: You know what that's kind of true?
Rym: It's a lot of the elements of avatar are very similar to a lot of elements commonly seen in Japanese animation.
Rym: Yeah, so there in fact.
Rym: I ran into a kid while I was at work, and he was playing the Naruto game And I just started to talk to him.
Rym: He's a little kid, and I was like.
Rym: so uh what other cartoons he like?
Rym: he's like yeah, Naruto and One Piece and Avatar and he considered all three of those to be anime from Japan.
Rym: and when I told him that avatar was made in the US He didn't believe me.
Rym: He's like Americans.
Rym: Can't do something that good.
Rym: Yeah, I just found that funny.
Rym: Yep, all right, so if more anime could go in the direction that music has been ie Downloadable for a fee.
Rym: again good use of ie correct mm-hmm?
Rym: What do you believe would be the most profitable price per episode?
Rym: well?
Rym: Let's see 26 episodes in an average series 2 bucks It's close.
Scott: I think right now I'm willing to pay like 40 bucks for a thin pack of a 26 episode thing, but I'm getting DVDs.
Scott: So it's gotta be less than 40 bucks for 26 episodes I don't know.
Rym: I'd almost be willing to pay a little bit more for the convenience and the fact that I can watch it as it comes out And I don't have to deal with physical media, which I'm getting more and more sick of.
Scott: I don't like.
Scott: I see I would like see.
Scott: actually here you go ready per episode basis.
Scott: I say five bucks an episode.
Scott: right, but first episode is always free and you can pay 40 bucks to get the whole season.
Rym: well I'll go one step further and say I'll say that I don't buy anime and it's.
Scott: and I'm yeah Netflix it all right That's the thing.
Rym: I'm fee.
Rym: I'm getting to the point.
Rym: and it's not just anime It's all media other than video games because it doesn't really work with video games, but for all like movies and of any kind I have no desire to buy anything ever.
Rym: and the idea of buying a DVD is Kind of important to me because it's just like I don't like face.
Scott: Yeah I don't like owning things you know taking up physical space in my house not even that even Digitally.
Scott: if I'm gonna watch it once why should I pay to keep it around on a hard drive somewhere?
Rym: You know I'm just.
Rym: I'm of the mind that I would I would pay to be able to rent digitally anime.
Rym: The problem is renting is the same as owning unless you add DRM, but you know what if anime were digital?
Rym: I'd probably buy it if it was cheap enough and then delete it.
Scott: Yeah So it's got to be the basically this the equivalent price of Netflix in the series and then Watch him and then delete them.
Rym: I mean I only buy anything.
Scott: well any you know DVD if it's but I do want to be able to download if I'm.
Scott: if They're technically saying that I own them I won't be able to download it again Whenever I want in case I want to show a friend or something or in the very least if it's no DRM So I can back it up.
Rym: However.
Rym: I want yep, okay?
Scott: Why do anime?
Scott: opening song lyrics never make any sense?
Rym: All right well part of that is that most of what you're thinking about is either Engrish II kind of openings like the opener to Nana Which is just any time.
Rym: a lot of Japanese songs Just kind of do that and a lot of times the lyrics don't make any sense particularly in just you know pop music and Sadly a lot of j-rock.
Scott: wait listen think about some songs in the u.s.. Right like some Britney Spears song.
Scott: no No, no like songs that really they're.
Scott: they're concentrating on the.
Scott: what the lyrics are is is the primary thing in the music Comes second right like for example Christian music or you know things like that.
Scott: where they really want to put they already figured out the words first and the music Second.
Scott: so what ends up happening is the music sort of suffers and the the words they have to sort of gimmick the words around And like add in like syllables here and there to make it sound right and not be stupid or impossible to sing Anime music.
Scott: what they tend to do is rather than worry about what they're saying first and foremost They actually worry about the music first and foremost and as a result the lyrics often.
Rym: Actually, I was going to say that a lot of anime put out in the late 80s and 90s had openers that were basically just pop Songs sometimes semi-popular pop song.
Rym: that also or song is that they were trying to then make popular and like for example The opener to Dominion Tank Police in Japan is crap pop nothing.
Rym: I kind of like the song since every move I like the song actually like it's kind of a guy could listen to it, but How did you know?
Scott: it's that I was also a problem of Japanese people writing a song in English because the English sounds cool Not because they know what the English means all the time, but there are a lot of Anime songs openers and closers where the lyrics like for example gone kotsuo.
Scott: That's written by a French guy.
Rym: Yeah, but even Jean-Jacques.
Rym: What's his name Jean-Jacques?
Scott: better now?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes But listen to that song and the lyrics are basically here's the plot of the count of Monte Cristo.
Scott: Yeah, but he's a he's a very famous song.
Rym: Yes, our Utena is an example or it doesn't matter not so much the opener because actually the openings a day But the opening song to Utena.
Rym: actually the lyrics like they kind of fit.
Rym: They don't fit perfectly But they kind of make sense in the way that most pop kind of songs make sense.
Rym: and the dual music Usually doesn't mean much but at the same time it sounds really cool.
Rym: All right, I don't have anything else to say.
Rym: What is the average production value of an anime movie and series per episode?
Scott: No idea if I know millions of dollars.
Scott: it depends on the show.
Scott: I mean some shows are stupidly cheap and they spend nothing on them.
Scott: and some shows they spend a zillion dollars on like goes In the shell.
Scott: and some shows some movies are stupidly cheap and some cost a zillion dollars.
Rym: It's and that's not even getting into the cost of you know, releasing things in America where no one ever says anything The cost of marketing or producing merchandise or all the.
Scott: you know millions of dollars.
Scott: There you go five bucks.
Scott: Why is CG used in anime?
Scott: anything that is CG seems that it can be drawn.
Scott: instead you say that about anything.
Scott: Okay, first of all, right You know, you look you're watching an anime and you'll you'll say oh that looks like CG, you know Cuz it'll be like some 3d battleship or something like that.
Scott: Do you realize that?
Scott: no no anime that you watch nowadays except for Sazae-san is Animated on cells.
Scott: everything is done entirely with computers full metal alchemist whole things computers Hara hey, Susan, man whole thing is computers.
Scott: It's all CG.
Scott: The 2d is CG.
Scott: Everything is CG.
Scott: So I think what you're all you're noticing is the 3d stuff that looks different than the 2d.
Rym: So and there are two reasons.
Rym: one a lot of times especially in a lower budget show It's a lot if something's three-dimensional or has to move three-dimensionally like really three-dimensionally.
Rym: It's a lot cheaper to make some CG than it is to animate that.
Scott: Yep But if you watch some of the higher production value shows say goes in the shell The 3d looks 2d.
Scott: You won't even notice that this 3d there.
Scott: It's so subtle because they spend a lot more money on their technology.
Scott: So the real thing you basically you're saying is I don't like it when they don't spend enough money on their 3d.
Scott: And I agree if someone's gonna put 3d in their anime Why you know?
Scott: you should just spend more money on it to make it look right and not stand out like a sore thumb like A Scooby-doo, it's bet you're better off doing a 2d.
Scott: if you don't, you know, huh right along those lines.
Rym: What is your opinion on CG animation in an anime?
Scott: aesthetic wise I like it when it doesn't Scooby-doo.
Rym: Yeah, I mean some shows use it really well.
Rym: some shows are initially some yeah PlayStation 1 graphics for the win All right.
Scott: In what ways is a manga better or worse than a novel counterpart?
Scott: on the same note?
Scott: What are the dis and advantages of an anime versus live-action?
Rym: You know, I could give a long complicated answer and I have a lot to say but it really just comes down to.
Rym: It's a different medium and different me.
Scott: It's like saying how's this painting?
Scott: How would this painting do in sculpture?
Rym: How would this painting do in scrimshaw?
Scott: Yeah, how would this?
Rym: needle point do in a live-action Musical with children's choir?
Scott: exactly.
Scott: It's like there's different mediums of art.
Scott: You can express yourself in different ways, you know with with ink on paper with oil on canvas with Limestone on chisel whatever and There's different things to know about each medium and they're all different.
Scott: and there's a dissident Advantages to all of them and there's.
Scott: none of them are better or worse.
Scott: I did any other.
Rym: I mean I could say cuz I there's a lot of things to say.
Rym: just papercraft I just think it.
Rym: it wouldn't be interesting to go through all the.
Rym: well in manga you get to Visually make the frame and make the scene but in a novel you have to describe it and leave it up to the imagination Whatever and not going to go and describe the difference of every artistic medium ever.
Scott: there's a lot of them.
Rym: Why do you think people generally look down on cartoons anime, whatever?
Rym: In Japan, I mean, it's not like everyone watches the ghost in the shell anime or anything But it's generally kind of an American thing where cartoons are kind of looked down upon.
Scott: Yeah in Scandinavian countries Donald Duck is the business.
Rym: I should live in Scandinavia.
Rym: Everything's telling me to move there.
Scott: I know.
Scott: however, you know, it's pretty much in America.
Scott: we have had a culture and because of things like the Comics Code Authority and censorship on television.
Scott: and you know animation and comics and those sorts of things were generally relegated and Culturally assumed to be mediums of art in which you could only create art For the enjoyment of by children and not for any other demographics.
Scott: and of course, that's false Completely.
Scott: you can mix you can appeal to any target demographic in any artistic medium.
Scott: You can make paper craft for one-year-olds paper craft for million-year-olds.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: but because that was the way it was for so long and because that was the you know, The impression people had and sort of the the dogma of the society it stuck around.
Scott: and now the old people Pretty much anyone 30 and older and even people younger than that even little kids Nowadays, you know, they think that cartoons are for kids and some things are breaking that like Adult Swim, you know.
Rym: But at the same time that's why a lot of your 13 year old girls are reading scary hardcore reality and their mom has no idea.
Scott: Yep, so Yeah, as soon as you know Pretty much when the old people die that will be a thing of the past.
Rym: I just there's a related question right here How do you how would you change cartoons anime whatever so that they would be taken more seriously?
Rym: One I wouldn't I wouldn't even bother to.
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: The only way you could do it is with a massive expensive PR campaign.
Rym: Well, no, I think it's the question really hits upon this.
Rym: a lot of people who have like a we It's almost like a lot of we and anime people have this almost inferiority complex of my thing is serious business and the world's got to take my business seriously.
Rym: and I got to get people to Respect.
Rym: and you know what if I like something I don't care if other people respect it or not.
Rym: I like it because I like it.
Scott: Yeah And yeah short of a massive PR campaign.
Scott: You got to wait till all the old people die.
Scott: That's pretty much all you got.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Okay, I just read what the next question is.
Rym: Okay, you can read it.
Scott: Let me find it.
Scott: Hold on Do you?
Scott: you have been given an arbitrary large amount of money to create an anime manga.
Rym: Oh, I guess I skipped about.
Rym: I was looking at a different question anyway.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Oh wait.
Scott: Oh Cuz I was okay.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: Good.
Scott: What is the main purpose of hentai?
Scott: to beat off?
Scott: That is is it just something funny at all?
Scott: watch with friends who are most people actually getting off.
Rym: Most people are actually getting off to it.
Rym: Good God now hentai.
Scott: see the main.
Scott: you're asking What is the main purpose of hentai which is for perverts?
Scott: hentai means pervert in Japanese for perverts to get off?
Scott: That's the main purpose.
Scott: however a side effect is that you can use something that perverts get off to in an ironic fashion to entertain yourself if you Put it in the right context for a side effect.
Scott: That's not the main purpose.
Rym: I mean the good thing is if you go to you can always tell you go to an anime con and every big one there'll be some sort of hentai showing or something somewhere.
Rym: and Sometimes especially if it's a bigger crowd if you go into that room It's mostly people like us and they're laughing hysterically and MST3K the whole thing.
Rym: But every now and then you go to a small con you walk into the hentai room.
Rym: There's five guys and they're just watching it and that's super creepy super creepy All right.
Scott: So here's the reason I messed up and picking the right question.
Scott: The next question is Do anime manga comics need to be taken more seriously?
Scott: That is lack of respect for anime manga comics a major problem with those media for you.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: All right All right.
Scott: Now here's the question I started to read.
Scott: you have been given an arbitrarily large amount of money to create an anime manga Comic or to hire someone to create it for you.
Scott: What is created?
Rym: That's a really difficult to answer open question.
Rym: I Couldn't say it all what I do.
Scott: I couldn't pick just one But I'll just pick something that happens to be on my mind lately.
Scott: I would take the plot of a shounen fighting show but make the fighting actual choreographed fighting like cowboy bebop and not stupid.
Scott: I will use this technique.
Scott: I was this technique and it only.
Scott: it would be less than 39 episodes and it'd be the best show ever.
Scott: You know what I would do?
Rym: I don't I can't say what the creative direction would be But I would try to get together the talent of the world to create a new good serious Not really science fiction but fantasy anime because there aren't a lot of really good like straight-up.
Scott: Would it be more like a slayers or more like more like eska flown a?
Rym: I think something kind like that robot in there.
Scott: Throw a little bit of school in there appeals to the wide audience.
Rym: something like that.
Rym: I quality music as component is one of my favorite shows ever.
Rym: the other thing is just out of the blue.
Rym: I just thought of this because I've always thought about this.
Rym: I'd either make a movie adaptation of the plot of Final Fantasy 4 or an OAV adaptation of the plot of Final Fantasy 6.
Scott: I might do also do something like an Akira television series to actually sort of adapt the manga.
Scott: That might be tough the correct way, but if you had money, yeah, it says arbitrarily large amount of money.
Rym: Alright, the next question is what is the next step for anime?
Rym: Where is the medium going?
Scott: It's not going anywhere.
Rym: Well, I think there are two answers.
Rym: there's what's the next step as it should be and what's the next step as it is because as it should be is the anime industry in America kind of coming together to try to mass-market this stuff and where I see it going is Nowhere,
Scott: it's not gonna keep going as it's
Rym: going.
Rym: I feel like it's kind of stagnating in the US and it.
Rym: it doesn't worry me yet, but it's not a good.
Rym: It's not growing.
Rym: It's kind of like it's treading water.
Rym: That's all it's been able to do for a long time Yep, and I feel like it wouldn't be that hard to start swimming, but no one seems to try.
Rym: I mean no one.
Rym: when was the last time an anime company took a risk.
Rym: That wasn't a stupid risk.
Rym: No.
Rym: Yeah, I rest my case.
Scott: What's the next step for comics?
Scott: Where is the medium going both artistically and financially?
Rym: this one's easy trades all the way and I think issues are gonna disappear.
Scott: I think it'll take a while because as the you know Again, all these people are holding on to it fiercely and there's like a big tradition of it.
Scott: But I think as time goes on the issues are gonna go down and down and the trades are gonna go up and up.
Rym: I also think the traditional idea of a superhero is going not disappear because nothing disappears, but spider-man will always be there Don't worry.
Rym: I just think that on average that sort of aesthetic of you know The costume wearing superhero will disappear except in ironic senses nostalgic senses and Watchmen style sense.
Scott: It might take a long time because you were gonna have to.
Scott: you know Cuz.
Scott: basically things are being kept the way they are Because the existing fan base which is not really growing or shrinking so much is sort of Maintaining a status quo and holding on to it for dear life.
Scott: But the only thing that's gonna slow that down is When those people who have been underwear pervert fans since the Stan Lee days and continue to collect now and forever When they actually again start dying or you know Start stop collecting or whatever and the people of this crazy collector's mentality stop doing it then Marvel and DC and all them will be forced to abandon their superhero ways and try to do something new or Let the medium go by the wayside and become super niche and it'll be just.
Rym: you know indie stuff because it's happening that the traditional comic industry is not doing well and You know so-called indie comics and all these kind of doing better than it did it after the crash in the nine.
Rym: But that's not saying much.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not like some super mega bucks thing.
Scott: It's just doing what it's always been doing.
Rym: So, uh, how do you make a good webcomic?
Rym: What do you look for in one a penny arcade?
Scott: Okay How do you make a good webcomic?
Rym: I think it there's.
Scott: no it's really easy.
Rym: All you have curious if you'll say the same thing.
Scott: I say all right you use.
Scott: you need to have some sort of artistic talent or find someone with artistic talent, right?
Scott: But it doesn't matter if your talent level is low as long as your potential is high and You know, you need to find someone with some writing talent.
Scott: But it doesn't matter if it's currently low as long as has a high potential and then you just need to keep making Webcomics keep making them don't stop and whatever you do improve yourself in art and writing in Every comic.
Scott: as long as you constantly improve you will eventually have a great comic case in point.
Rym: Look at the first year of penny arcade.
Scott: look it go by go to the store and look at the penny arcade books.
Scott: Look at the first one and look at the current one.
Scott: They improved.
Scott: That's why they're gods now.
Rym: Look at something else like You're trying not to name a certain comic.
Rym: I know which one you're thinking of.
Rym: All right, fine mega Tokyo, okay That's not the one I was thinking.
Scott: it's improved some but largely it's unchanged.
Scott: The writing is just as bad as it's always been and the art really hasn't improved.
Rym: that means if you know what mega Tokyo started going and I thought a really good direction and then it I'm not sure where it went in the last couple weeks Yeah, I got any other ones that haven't improved at all.
Scott: What about that one you read like CR college roomies from hell one that looks the same now as it always did.
Rym: No, he actually looks super better compared to how it does it.
Rym: you own the first I don't know year of that.
Scott: Bob and George never got never improved.
Rym: Bob and George was never good.
Scott: Well, he was it was.
Scott: no it was when they made Joe about flash man and quick man And wood man.
Scott: then it was downhill.
Scott: guy there.
Rym: those are the three examples you always give.
Scott: did they ever make a fourth joke Flashman quick man wood man eat man.
Rym: Did they ever make a fifth Joe airman?
Scott: No, they didn't know.
Scott: Snake man, that was dumb.
Scott: No see Beginning of the comic.
Scott: it was all downhill from there.
Scott: Luckily the comics over now.
Rym: Oh god, that was a bad guy.
Rym: but in terms of specifics, I think a Lot of people approach the webcomic world I think in the wrong way and that You can't.
Rym: you can tell a serious story You can do a comedy you can do whatever you want.
Rym: But the thing with a webcomic is that whatever your update schedule is one It has to update consistently or people won't read it to.
Rym: When you put something up whatever unit you update in whether it's a page of volume a panel.
Rym: It doesn't matter That in and of itself has to be enjoyable.
Rym: I mean you can't have like just The Wednesday comic this week doesn't go anywhere because it's just set up for the Friday comic.
Rym: That'll kill a webcomic.
Rym: every single one while it can tell it can take you a story and while it can be consistent Has to have something.
Rym: one thing that happens like one unit of progression one unit of enjoyment Something that makes it stand at least somewhat on its own.
Scott: if you want to learn How to do that very well look at order the stick because he knows when all that is like the best web.
Scott: He knows when he doesn't have enough in his single page to really do anything on its own.
Scott: and he'll do these multi-page Releases so that every update has stands on its own as something enjoyable.
Rym: like look every order of the stick Advances the plot a little bit has a joke at like one main joke probably a side joke and some foreshadowing Almost every single one.
Scott: It's a great comic.
Rym: Oh, it's definitely one of the top two.
Scott: Okay, will Naruto ever die?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't watch the show.
Scott: I don't read the model.
Scott: I know if the character will not die permanently ever.
Rym: I'm certain of that at best and I don't think this will happen They would kill him at the end to save everyone.
Rym: He'd probably kill himself, but that's beside the point.
Rym: The show Naruto the idea of Naruto the reruns of Naruto the Phantom of Naruto Much like old generals and much like Dragon Ball will never die.
Rym: It will just fade away and then always exist at this baseline level forever.
Rym: Not that there's anything wrong with that.
Rym: All right, if you could ask Alan Moore one question, what would it be?
Scott: I don't really have a question for Alan Moore.
Scott: That's like, you know, I'm dying to ask him So I'll probably just ask him like hey, why are you so crazy?
Rym: Down a bit who's your barber?
Scott: Yeah, who's not your barber?
Rym: All right I know what I'd ask the next one because they listed a bunch of people Kazuo Koike and my question would be are you for serious?
Rym: Yeah, you just are you just playing?
Scott: Cuz something like that.
Rym: I really don't know if the things he like some of the things he did Like if he knew how crazy and I ran stupid they were well not stupid, but you know just weird and scary.
Rym: But I wonder if he understood what he was making when he made it or if he was just crazy Stanley.
Rym: actually, I gotta answer this.
Scott: I know what you're gonna answer how I say the same thing But we saw actually at the New York comic-con.
Scott: We saw him from like a hundred we did.
Scott: He was surrounded by this throng of courtiers Yeah, and I was just like hey I think that's Stanley.
Scott: and it was.
Scott: and then he hobbled away like an old man Which is what he is.
Rym: and my question for you Stanley what the fuck was up with you bolding random words?
Rym: It's not like you bolded words that should have been in because you've bolded random words just randomly.
Scott: what the fuck.
Scott: I would actually you know sort of have a bigger question that includes the random bowling.
Rym: Oh, there's the other question with me.
Rym: Why did you use words?
Rym: You didn't understand?
Scott: Well, I basically asked him in general You know, do you looking back now?
Scott: Do you honestly think that that you know, your writing was high quality or do you think it was you know terrible?
Rym: He would say yes it was.
Scott: Yeah, all right Osamu Tezuka, uh, I don't even know what to ask.
Scott: I couldn't.
Rym: I wouldn't feel okay asking him.
Rym: I'd ask him out for a drink because I think he's one of the He's.
Rym: I have so much respect for the late Osamu Tezuka.
Rym: I mean, I just finished Apollo's song a little while ago and god damn.
Rym: Also as an aside, I just would like to say that I know a lot of you are listening now Probably also listen to anime world order and they recently reviewed Apollo's song and I'm not gonna you know rip into them or anything But you're
Scott: gonna wait until we review Apollo's song to do that.
Rym: What I would like to say is that I don't think they got it at all.
Rym: And I just I really don't think they got it and as a result, I think their review really didn't do that comic justice.
Scott: Well, I would basically as Tezuka, you know greedily like hey What was gonna be happening in the rest of Phoenix?
Scott: because he didn't finish it.
Rym: I Just finished reading what was created and uh, yeah, actually I'd ask him if I'm right about Apollo's song Though I'm pretty sure I am because yeah, I don't want to spoil that comic.
Scott: Why isn't Tezuka more popular in the USA?
Rym: one Americans by and large don't like comics like any kind of comic.
Rym: I mean manga is popular but it's not like the average Joe reads manga and comics and like So less popular than and Tezuka being black and white and being so different looking than even anime, you know Manga style comics also.
Rym: Tezuka is really disarming.
Rym: you read Tezuka like Oh to carry hedo or Apollo's song or Phoenix and it looks goonian light-hearted But and there's jokes like every third panel But it was kind of random and bleh.
Rym: those comics hit on issues Really hard that make a lot of people especially in the u.s.
Rym: Really uncomfortable.
Scott: And I think the biggest thing is that really the it's sort of inaccessible.
Scott: I mean most of his stuff.
Scott: I mean he's got Phoenix's published by Viz.
Scott: he's got a few things published by Dark Horse Which are kind of hard to get and the rest is published by vertical ink.
Scott: These are not easy things to get at.
Scott: these are not things that are marketed widely or advertised.
Scott: Most people in the country don't even know who Tezuka is.
Scott: I think if people knew who Tezuka was and they were like, you know They they hyped him up.
Scott: as you know with again a PR campaign like Tezuka is as good as Walt Disney.
Scott: Oh my god, his stuff is amazing.
Scott: It's so crazily popular.
Scott: We're putting it everywhere and if you give people the impression that it is already popular then it will become pop, you know It's funny.
Rym: I was gonna interrupt you but I didn't because I had to sniff and I would have said the exact same thing if there was just a marketing campaign of Osamu Tezuka the Japanese Walt Disney the greatest comic author ever and they just pumped it.
Rym: Yeah, does it do greatly?
Scott: Also, they're gonna.
Scott: they're starting to colorize all of Tezuka's manga that the Tezuka.
Scott: Actually, I I'm kind of really looking forward to How much it's gonna cost when it comes out here, but maybe that'll help a little bit.
Scott: I don't know I don't know.
Scott: All right crossover question.
Rym: Oh, I can read this one cuz it's long.
Rym: Okay, you've expressed distaste for underwear pervert comics But what do you think of underwear pervert video games?
Rym: Did they suffer the same stigma as licensed branded movie video games?
Rym: Have you paid?
Rym: I guess he means played any of the Marvel titles like X-men legends or Marvel?
Rym: Let me answer I want to answer to but you can do it.
Rym: All right, you can go.
Scott: Okay, so There there's nothing inherently good or bad about an underwear pervert video game.
Scott: I mean you make a good spider-man video game.
Scott: you sadly almost no one did.
Scott: you can make a bad spider-man video game like the Attar.
Rym: actually, I think the Atari 2600 is one of the better spider-man.
Scott: the Sega Genesis one We have to take pictures of the bosses is actually a really good.
Rym: That's coming from me.
Rym: I hated the Sega, but you know what?
Rym: That was a damn good spider-man game.
Scott: X-men arcade good game.
Rym: the walk across the side smashing things won.
Rym: Yeah, Captain America nothing moves the blob except Cyclops.
Rym: the Captain America arcade game also quite good But uh that x-men legends game that that game was crap.
Scott: It's just gauntlet our world of Warcraft.
Rym: one of our friends hyped it up like man.
Rym: This game is awesome.
Rym: Check it out Oh my god, and we finally played it and I was like, it's just gauntlet.
Rym: It's better than gauntlet at being gauntlet.
Rym: But that's like saying world of Warcraft is better than the realm.
Rym: Yeah in world over here play gauntlet.
Scott: if you like gauntlet and you like the the under x-men Then you'll like x-men legends cuz it's just gauntlet with x-men instead of green wizard and red warrior.
Rym: I think the worst thing is that the game has this leveling mechanic that was kind of cool.
Rym: grind aside Like.
Rym: it was really cool except half the powers didn't do Jack and it just wasn't fun.
Scott: and it also didn't matter.
Scott: It's like you get skill points.
Scott: It doesn't matter what you put the skill points in You just you can automatically spend them.
Scott: You'll do just fine.
Scott: You can't lose.
Scott: It's gauntlet Alright.
Rym: Yeah, you really can't lose it.
Scott: Nothing inherently good or bad about a game that uses an underwear pervert license to try to sell itself.
Scott: The thing is is that you know, you can make a good game and you can make a bad game Whatever.
Scott: Okay, would you guys be okay?
Scott: If someone would continue the Phoenix story from the two pages the testicle left before he died?
Scott: Probably not.
Rym: I say yeah, you know why that sort of thing happens all the time and While it's effectively a glorified fanfic at the same time if someone's a good writer and they
Scott: well I guess I guess anyone's allowed to try it go go nuts, you know, do whatever you want.
Scott: But I think the odds of someone doing it well enough to the point where I would respect it and consider it to be the actual continuation of Phoenix Nothing.
Rym: I would consider that to be a work in and of itself kind of a. they took this core story and Everything that they knew about it and they just wrote something based on it.
Rym: I think it's like an adaptation.
Scott: Yeah, let anyone try go nuts.
Scott: You're free to do so.
Scott: All right expression.
Rym: But what would it take to get anime quote mainstream unquote recognition in the
Rym: u.s.?
Rym: Why hasn't this been done yet real?
Rym: simply it wouldn't take much and the American anime industry is run by morons And they all that.
Scott: the other problem is that they have to take a big risk and spend a lot of money on Marketing in PR.
Scott: They're not.
Rym: I mean they take risks on stupid things, but they don't take and also they're so secret It.
Rym: uh, yeah, we talked about that a lot.
Rym: Okay, I'll ask this one because I we both have a lot to say about this one.
Rym: Why do DVDs cost so freaking much in?
Scott: Japan People in Japan are dumb and they're willing to pay a lot for DVDs.
Rym: I think the Japanese anime industry Well, really just media in Japan.
Rym: They kind of for a long time took advantage of the Japanese people and I don't know if it I mean I think there's a lot of reasons.
Rym: but it ended up that They price things very high and people were willing to pay it and as a result The prices stayed really high.
Rym: and then Japan tried to sell stuff in the US and the US said $40 for a DVD.
Rym: So Japan started selling, you know, they'd license it so that DVDs would be cheap in America.
Rym: but then Japanese people started Re-importing because they're like how come that DVDs?
Rym: 20 American dollars in America and 80 American dollars here?
Rym: Yeah, so as a result, they don't license stuff to America right away, which hurts the American industry Which makes the licenses worth.
Rym: it's like this cycle of crap.
Scott: Another thing is that in America you realize, you know DVDs sell a lot maybe because they have lower prices, but also I guess because Americans watch a lot of things.
Rym: I think the total output of Shows that are then put on DVD in America is a lot higher than Japan total just because there's a lot more TV in America.
Scott: I also I get the feeling also that you know The anime is on TV in Japan and I get the feeling that most people just watch it on TV and that only Sort of otaku were likely to buy it on DVD.
Scott: Yeah a lot of the time A lot less people purchasing so and they're they're crazy fans and crazy fans are willing to pay more because they're crazed fans.
Scott: Yeah, the kind of people who are gonna buy Bandai visual DVDs in the u.s So When are you going to do final thoughts episodes when I rewatch anime series?
Rym: Actually, we're going to do one either next week or the week after because there is one show if we don't do it.
Rym: Oh, no there is one show that we both remember enough to give our full final thoughts on and Scott just has to watch Ava again and eska flown a again.
Scott: And I'll tell you what as soon as I finish Phantom hourglass.
Scott: I'll start watching Evangelion on the train.
Rym: Ah, see at the same time I was kind of waiting.
Rym: cuz I kind of want to watch it again, too And we have a couple friends who have never seen it.
Rym: Oh, but at the same time, what are we gonna get together in marathon anime?
Rym: We don't have time for that.
Scott: No, it's not gonna happen.
Rym: But yeah, I'm not.
Rym: should I say the title we're gonna do final thoughts on.
Scott: it's up to you.
Rym: I think I should.
Rym: just if you're listening We're very likely going to do a final thoughts on Trigon All right in the near future because I think a light kind of like Apollo song.
Rym: I think a lot of people misinterpret what it was saying.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Do you think that nonfiction graphic novels?
Scott: Eg also a correct use of again the 9/11 report a graphic adaptation will ever be a major force in the American comic book market.
Rym: You know, I don't know.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I think if comics became more mainstream than things like that would become equally mainstream.
Scott: Yeah, I guess you know.
Scott: there there's another graphic non-fiction graphic novel the plot by will Eisner which is sort of the the true history of the.
Scott: What's the stupid conspiracy?
Scott: Jew book the brother the elders is ion?
Scott: Yeah, ever book.
Scott: Yeah, I have that and it's pretty good.
Scott: Yes, there just really aren't that many Non-fiction graphic novels out there and I think if someone you know came out with one with good timing, you know They hit on an issue that was like, you know Very big at the time and they did a very good job of it and they market it properly that they could you know Really make a big hit.
Scott: there is definitely a potential there.
Scott: Have I seen any examples?
Scott: No, I haven't really seen anything.
Scott: that's that you know is gonna make it happen.
Scott: I don't think this 9/11 report graphic adaptation did that?
Scott: Well, I never heard of it before.
Rym: I've heard of it because it was all over FARC.
Rym: Okay, but along the same lines.
Rym: Uh, how common are nonfiction manga in the Asian comic book market?
Rym: I vaguely recall you guys mentioning something about a manga history of ramen.
Scott: I think they are more common than nonfiction I think is in the American comics.
Rym: broader answer is just that Manga isn't like this special thing in Japan.
Scott: It's just another medium Yeah, and there's nonfiction in it as well as fiction.
Scott: I mean, I already already know they have like business manga which tells stories about businesses and I imagine is Historical manga which tell like, you know stories from history pretty accurately.
Scott: I you know, I'm sure they had lots of drama to really get people going on it and stuff.
Scott: But I'm sure it exists.
Scott: everything else exists.
Scott: Why wouldn't you know nonfiction exists?
Scott: Okay, so this one is actually a Thunderdome.
Scott: we should do another Thunderdome episode.
Rym: Oh, so you're skipping those other two questions.
Scott: Okay Now everyone's thinking.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: I want that.
Scott: Yeah, I'm skipping them.
Rym: Yeah, they're kind of crap.
Rym: Not that I look at him.
Rym: Okay, I'll answer.
Rym: I'll do this one real quick.
Rym: All right What's the most you've ever paid for a comic anime manga and the biggest steel deal ever scored?
Rym: We bought all of master Keaton for like freaking nothing.
Scott: Yeah, that was pretty damn cheap.
Rym: That was so worth it.
Rym: And the most was just in the early days.
Rym: I paid like Some stupid amount of money for the VHS box set of the original Tenchi Muyo OAVs.
Rym: It was like thirty five forty dollars of VHS.
Scott: I think for all six volumes of Akira.
Scott: I paid full retail price For anime, I bought all the gassaraki on dubbed VHS and for a single comic I never really five bucks.
Scott: I paid for like x-men number one, I guess but I Don't know.
Scott: I guess I spent Like 30 bucks to get like a hardcover, you know, like come in a book like a graphic novel.
Scott: But I you know, I guess those big red stars the volumes.
Rym: I paid a lot for those I guess one I could say if you talk most expensive in terms of dollars spent per unit quality.
Rym: I forget what it was called but there's a picture of it in a picture I got from my mom of my bedroom when I was younger and It's a comic I think it was by Margaret Weiss and it was something about dragons, so, of course I bought it and Effectively I paid infinity for it because there was zero content worthwhile in it and I paid some amount of money.
Rym: Good God was that horrible.
Rym: and I even like Lied to myself and said I liked it because I didn't want to admit that I'd spent that money.
Scott: All right, the other question that we skipped.
Scott: I'm just gonna ignore cuz it's so generic.
Rym: Oh it is All right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So back to the Thunderdome gonna read the whole thing.
Scott: Who would win in a battle?
Scott: spike Spiegel and the swordfish or a starbuck in the Viper?
Rym: I don't know who starbuck star is is a character from Battlestar Galactica Who in the modern Battlestar Galactica is a woman, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: I think it's kind of cool.
Rym: They did that but in both Starbuck is a badass one of the best fighter in space pilots in the known human world.
Scott: What kind of weapons does that thing have?
Rym: actually the Viper is fairly equivalent to the swordfish really?
Scott: Doesn't really have that many weapons other than the big Of it and which is kind of unwieldy.
Scott: It's not really a gunship.
Rym: So let me put it this way So she's flying and she's lying in the equivalent of an a-wing with extra weapons.
Rym: That's a x-wing.
Scott: an x-wing Oh x-wing frickin wedge antilles could own spike in an x-wing.
Scott: I mean spike is a good pilot, but the swordfish really isn't that powerful as as a fighter.
Scott: It's it's you know, it has fighter abilities and it shoots its laser But it that's really all it has and an x-wing which is actually a military vehicle.
Scott: He'd be owned he'd be toast but at the same time you take him out.
Rym: my answer I think is much more clever and I hope everyone agrees All right So and I'm not gonna ruin cowboy bebop.
Rym: But it is.
Rym: they kind of make reference to this in the first episode and they bring it up a lot and the movie Brings it up like super.
Rym: but spike Spiegel the only way he could possibly die is in a very specific situation because Spike Spiegel doesn't say he has to die.
Scott: He just loses.
Rym: He can't win a battle.
Rym: He cannot lose.
Rym: I am up cuz it's a space battle.
Rym: You can't lose a battle like that and not die.
Scott: He can.
Scott: now your ship is damaged.
Scott: You're floating in space.
Scott: Then someone picks you up and goes.
Rym: I don't think that could happen.
Scott: I think I'm gonna gun them all the time.
Rym: Well Gundam is different in the real world.
Rym: I'm pretty sure your cabin would depress your eyes and you die immediately.
Scott: Well, you're wearing a spacesuit.
Rym: How does spike wear a spacesuit when he's in his?
Rym: uh swordfish sometimes?
Rym: Does he think back sometimes?
Scott: He's puts on a space suit a few times.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah, I just don't think spike could lose because of various plot.
Rym: I think that spike would just win due to some crazy thing.
Rym: Starbuck would just go insane or something I don't know.
Scott: Here's an easy question What are the good and bad parts of Naruto?
Rym: good parts funny ninja school.
Scott: funny ninja school and the characters are really awesome At least most of them.
Scott: bad parts everything else.
Scott: Seriously, all right What point in your lives did you go from OMG all cartoons from Japan are awesome to anime jadedness?
Rym: Well, it's you know, people say oh you're jaded about anime.
Rym: It's more than when I first found out about Japan cartoons, you know Japanimation anime on the sci-fi channel.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Me too It was different and that alone made it amazing because it wasn't like things I'd seen.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I was.
Scott: it's all relative you see.
Scott: so when I was watching even though some of the things I watched were amazing Like say galaxy express 3 9 on sci-fi channel.
Scott: I was also watching Like fatal fury on the sci-fi channel and it was relative to what I had already Experienced in my life and at that point in my life the things that I had experienced in terms of animation We're not nearly even close to being as amazing as fatal fury even so.
Scott: that's why everything was so awesome to me early on.
Scott: But as I watched more and more anime and more and more amazing anime like the works of Satoshi khan Otomo and Miyazaki and reading manga of Tezuka They you can start to see when things are not so amazing because you've seen something even better than that.
Scott: And that's when you start getting jaded.
Rym: It's kind of like once you ride the Millennium Force the super bad rollercoaster.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you.
Rym: if you're not gonna have fun on the blue streak anymore because it just it pales by comparison Exactly.
Scott: You go to the amusement park.
Scott: You've never ridden a roller coaster in your life.
Scott: You ride the hundred-foot Twinkie and it's awesome.
Scott: Then you ride the 200 foot and you go, holy shit, then you ride the hundred foot again you go man That's how it goes.
Scott: so when I first watched anime it was it was the hundred footer.
Rym: All right Should we end on this one?
Scott: pick whatever you want?
Rym: Cuz it we've gone about an hour as always right and this one's this one's aid.
Rym: and what are your opinions on?
Rym: Otak in?
Scott: what are Otak in our otaku kin?
Scott: What are otaku kids?
Rym: Oh, you didn't read that thread.
Scott: No, I didn't All right.
Rym: Well, uh, you know other kin theory entropes no People who think they're vampires or dragons or werewolves or anything like that.
Scott: Yeah those scary people.
Rym: well Otakin and this is a self-made term, but there seem to be a lot.
Rym: I read a few serious business writings from these people.
Rym: They see manga or comics or sometimes it's something else and it's not like they identify with the character.
Rym: It's not like they like see parallels to the character.
Rym: It's not like they feel a spiritual connection to like the story from the book.
Rym: It's that they believe somehow That they are that character or that their soul is that character and that book existed just to show them or that book Was written by someone who was channeled into their past life.
Scott: And they're not jobs with psychological problems.
Scott: Go see a shrink.
Scott: end of story.
Rym: No, I think it's a much more interesting phenomenon because I don't think it's any different than all these other You know, but the theory entropes and the people are also not jobs.
Scott: Well,
Rym: no what I think it is is that a lot of people when they're young and they're going through puberty and just you know young becoming Adults becoming like adult sentient people they have feelings that they don't quite understand or explain and a lot of people attribute these to various Things but I think a lot of people attribute these to mystical experiences or to supernatural experiences or things along those lines.
Rym: and I think at that point when you're a very impressionable person and you have experiences like that Your experiences tend to be shaped by the things that you think about a lot or the things that are going on in your life.
Rym: and I think this new phenomenon is coming out just because the primary audience of a lot of manga and comics these days are people who are in that time period and all these kind of subcultures are Psychologically almost identical.
Rym: and I think it's just what you've come across.
Scott: in my armchair psychologist kind of way I always viewed the people who think they're like You know a furry or they they sort of you know live in a fan.
Rym: Well, it's not.
Rym: it's not hard to be a furry.
Rym: You just have to like furry.
Scott: I know People actually think like I am a sea otter, you know, and like they you know that that's really what gets them.
Scott: I think that with those my armchair psychologist opinion is that those people have a very poor Self-image.
Scott: So what they do is they replace the shitty self-image which in many cases is there's.
Scott: they are a poor self-image.
Scott: I look down on that.
Scott: what they really are as well, you know, they're usually you know Kind of in people you don't want to hang around and they replace their own self-image with this.
Scott: You know.
Scott: other image that they like say that their favorite character from you know Some anime and they say I'm not this shitty disgusting smelly stupid person that I am.
Scott: I'm actually that other person that I really like and they replace their horrible self-image with a better self-image and then they sort of get Self-esteem, but it's not self-esteem for themselves It's self-esteem for what they wish they were.
Scott: and this is why it's a problem.
Rym: You know, I would say that for I don't know I couldn't give a percentage but I maybe half of them.
Rym: I think that that is probably a somewhat valid assessment.
Rym: But I think what I said is I think that I say we're both not psychologists.
Scott: So this is just woo.
Scott: Yeah, that's our guess.
Rym: This is what makes sense to us what I will say because that's my opinions and not my opinions.
Scott: Yeah, you have an opinion here.
Scott: I'm not a psycho.
Scott: My
Rym: opinion straight up is that it's it's almost more sad and I think I was talking to Emily about this and she brought this up a lot to that if someone's gonna have this kind of mystical experience or this like super like this thing in their life the spiritual idea and They base it on a Japanese comic they read as opposed to on something that just sprang from their creative consciousness It's like it's just like a one level down in terms of less sad.
Scott: Yeah, it.
Rym: I'd much rather someone believed something interesting that they made up than believe something That was just in a comic that some guy wrote to make money.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: I mean I Would ask to one of these people so, uh, I'm actually Superman from Superman.
Rym: And if they think that's stupid well mirrors and such.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: All right, maybe we could do one or two more.
Rym: I don't want a black maybe but my kettle is black.
Scott: Do it do whatever you want go you wanna do another one.
Scott: do whatever you want It's up to you.
Rym: Where do I get a good supply of one-shot Western comics along the lines of DMZ?
Scott: Amazon calm or in stock trades calm.
Rym: next Why is it that the uglier the person the more sexual the cosplay costume they wear?
Rym: That's not true at all.
Rym: That's just what stands out.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there are hot people wearing hot costumes ugly people wearing cover-up costumes.
Scott: is there's all sorts of stuff going on.
Scott: It's a totally mixed up across the board.
Scott: It's just that when someone ugly or someone scary is wearing a particularly revealing and unattractive Costume it stands out like a little freaking don't know?
Rym: Don't forget that there's a large subculture of the ironically bad cosplay.
Rym: You know a big fat guy who dresses like Sailor Moon, but that guy's cool.
Rym: Yeah, that's the thing It's you can't.
Rym: don't just because you see someone in it like a scary cosplay Don't judge him based on that.
Rym: now.
Rym: if they also smell and tell you about their D&D character Then yeah, but if if you see Sailor Bubba Sailor Bubba is an awesome, dude.
Scott: Seriously, there's another question on here that has the same answer Which is why are the vast majority of cosplayers people that would never want to see naked?
Scott: That's because those are the people that stand out like a sore thumb.
Scott: You don't notice all the completely average looking cosplayers because they don't stand out very much.
Scott: They're just mixing in with the herd.
Scott: You only notice the really hot ones and the really ugly ones.
Rym: now hot not isn't sexually attractive, but hot isn't.
Rym: damn.
Rym: That's a good cosplay exactly all right.
Rym: Let's end on this cuz I like this question all right as of today.
Rym: What is your?
Scott: I like the one above it want to do both, okay?
Rym: All right, I'll ask this one, and then you do the other one.
Rym: okay as of today What is your favorite AMV and what makes it so?
Rym: I Have to say two because one is a hit me baby one more time set to utana.
Rym: It's not the Britney Spears cover.
Rym: well not really cover, but original.
Rym: It's a cover by a rock band.
Rym: And I think that video aside from one comedic insertion is just amazing on levels that I really can't get into without Derailing the show.
Rym: it's technically excellent the concept is solid the song fits perfectly and it's funny.
Rym: But if you've seen the show it's also really serious and really meaningful.
Rym: It's just like the best AMV.
Scott: I will pick the Mambo Leo.
Rym: the Mambo Leo is just one of those perfectly executed.
Rym: Pump you up.
Rym: so well done.
Rym: It's painful AMVs.
Rym: Yep In fact that was the last thing the last AMV.
Rym: I ever showed at the RIT anime club.
Scott: all right Here's the question.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: I got.
Rym: I got to say one more.
Rym: I got to jump in 25 25.
Scott: that's okay.
Rym: I think that is also one of the best anime music videos ever made.
Rym: It's a good one.
Scott: I think it's one of the best.
Scott: I think it is anyway all right.
Scott: Here's a question that I could actually take up a whole episode with.
Scott: If you could have any anime manga or video game mecha Which would you take now?
Scott: This is a very difficult question because do not be deceived if you're gonna ask which is the strongest you could say Voltron.
Scott: But that might not be what I want with Voltron.
Scott: I need four other people.
Scott: what a pain in the ass.
Rym: Not only that, but you know it's relative because I would say that the only thing that could match Voltron would be I don't know the Ava.
Scott: Yeah, so yeah in an Ava.
Scott: You don't want that either.
Scott: That's not practical for everyone.
Rym: use Ava's great, and I'd love an Ava.
Rym: Here's my problem with an Ava.
Rym: that is not a world with Ava's is not a world you want to live in right.
Scott: so We're assuming that we're gonna live in the current existing world.
Scott: only I'm gonna have this robot So you know or mecha of some sort.
Rym: so in that case oh, I almost said bokurano, but then I remembered right.
Scott: so You want to pick something that's incredibly practical and would make your life better like a Gundam would be a good choice.
Scott: You know cuz a Gundam is very practical.
Scott: for the normal world.
Scott: It's usually no power especially something like the Zeta Gundam right or or freedom Gundam You know which can fly into and out of outer space and it can power itself and maintain itself.
Scott: You know I might a punk kid.
Scott: It's so easy.
Scott: a punk kid can fly.
Rym: I might go with a guy my left from Escaflowne because they just run on my soul or whatever.
Rym: so they just work forever.
Scott: Anything that requires too many people is right out and anything that is you know sort of requires a power source.
Scott: It runs out of energy is sort of right out.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: there's an obvious answer.
Scott: No, I have the obvious answer.
Scott: Oh no the big O is not so good.
Scott: Yes, it is not sort of in your full control all the time exactly.
Scott: You know what.
Rym: it doesn't matter.
Rym: It's so cool that I take it anyway.
Scott: all right I have the perfect answer.
Scott: now the the first answer obviously is the most practical of all mecha Which is the Valkyrie from Macross.
Scott: you know it turns to do a plane perfectly.
Scott: You know jet plane or a robot or the in-between right.
Scott: the problem is just it's just little old Valkyrie.
Scott: It's not that powerful.
Scott: I mean f-16s or f-22s could come and take you out.
Scott: So you're not really king of the world which is why the obvious answer is the entire Sdf-1 Macross which comes with a whole fleet of Valkyries, so you have no problems there.
Rym: You complain about needing four people.
Rym: now you need like.
Scott: there's the sdf-1 macross.
Scott: see that's.
Scott: if you want to fly it around in Space and stuff you need a whole crew and a whole fleet of people and everything right.
Scott: But if you're just sitting on the ground it's gonna get full of dust.
Rym: you're not gonna mop that thing.
Scott: You don't need to mop the thing.
Scott: It's self-repairing.
Scott: It's self powering.
Rym: is it self mopping?
Rym: Yes, where does it say that?
Scott: it's little robots that go around the ground and they clean it up.
Rym: and who maintains those?
Scott: They maintain themselves.
Scott: oh, I'm sure it doesn't matter because you get power.
Scott: It does it itself.
Scott: does it has?
Scott: it has an power plant.
Scott: It doesn't matter because I get a few of that just sitting on the ground.
Scott: on its own It's like a city just sitting there.
Scott: It's like so lame.
Rym: you know what you just said.
Rym: if I could have any robot in the world it would be New York City But just me exactly.
Rym: That's lame.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: It's not as New York City with me Just me.
Scott: if New York City with just me in it and two aircraft carries full of f-22s that transform You know what then I'll take my big oh, and I'll punch your city up.
Rym: What are you gonna do about it big?
Scott: Oh is like not even as big as like the pinky finger But you know what.
Rym: what are you gonna?
Rym: Do you can't pilot that thing by yourself?
Rym: You can't even make it move.
Scott: I can go up to the bridge and fire the main gun.
Rym: Are you gonna point that at me?
Rym: you need a gunnery person?
Scott: No you can that all in from one spot.
Rym: No, you can't.
Rym: you can't watch those shows.
Scott: This is why this would take a whole episode to answer this.
Scott: Sdf1 macross is the perfect choice.
Scott: either that or super stardestroyer.
Rym: That's not a robot.
Scott: It's a mecha.
Rym: How is that a mecha?
Scott: That's a Shit, it's a mecha.
Rym: It's a space shit.
Scott: It's a mecha.
Rym: I think I think the definition of mecha is has arms superstar has arms.
Scott: Hi Death Star.
Scott: All right, we're done.
Scott: this could take a whole episode.
Rym: Yeah, suffice to say we.
Rym: there's another hour of questions that we'll do at some point.
Rym: You'll hear it someday in the future.
Rym: Good night This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.