Scott: It's Wednesday January 17th.
Rym: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discuss our favoritest manga ever sanctuary.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we've been talking a lot about the upcoming Katsucon and how we're going to be having a GeekNights' extravaganza.
Scott: Yeah, when is this Katsucon?
Rym: Why?
Rym: it's February 16th through 18th 2007 2007 what?
Scott: Where is it?
Rym: Well, it's at the Omni Shore hotel in Washington DC.
Scott: Oh, so anyone who is on the East Coast can come to Katsucon pretty easily.
Rym: now as we've said before I've been to Katsucon for many years and it's one of my favorite cons.
Rym: I have a good time there.
Rym: I always have.
Scott: I've heard many stories of Katsucon and I know all about it, but I never been.
Rym: yes You've heard some very high-class stories from Scott Johnson and mines adventures.
Scott: Oh, oh, I must say Definitely is very ritzy.
Scott: It would be the words you describe.
Rym: Well, actually the thing is they moved from Crystal City to this Omni Shore hotel.
Rym: So the Crystal City was okay, but Compared to what most hotels that host anime cons look like the Omni Shore Um is actually pretty ritzy and when I first walked in Thursday night last year All I could think was there are about a thousand breakable expensive things within reach right now.
Rym: There's shit low-hanging chandeliers, there's vases on mantles everywhere Fancy stuff all over the place really expensive-looking leather couches everywhere.
Scott: You know if you want to know about last year's Katsucon both us and anime world order have episodes about it.
Rym: in fact last year's Katsucon was probably one of the most important moments in anime podcasting history for that is when I Rym of GeekNights met Darryl Sarat of Darryl Sarat Incorporated.
Rym: and Isn't it Sarat, you know, he says Sarat.
Rym: everyone else says Sarat.
Rym: I take that as a sign, huh?
Rym: Strange, I mean no one calls me de Castor because it doesn't.
Rym: oh, yeah, I know but no one might call you de coaster.
Rym: No, no one's ever mispronounced my last name.
Scott: Yeah That's because it's pronounced the way it looks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: Once I was asked if I was Hispanic to which I said no That's da Costa.
Rym: Yeah No, I think I'm kidding now.
Rym: They were trying to guess what Hispanic country I was from and I was like, I'm Belgian.
Rym: But anyway, we met and as a result, we know about anime world order and they know about us.
Scott: Yeah Well, I knew about animal order before but I didn't listen to it cuz I didn't trust any of those anime podcasts.
Rym: I thought I still don't trust most anime podcast.
Scott: Yeah, totally but I trust them.
Scott: now I get kinda And I trust some other people, you know our people everywhere.
Scott: all our people know who they are.
Rym: Yeah, but regardless Katsucon is a great con.
Rym: believe me We were probably going to have some sort of pregame for Katsucon since we're going in force this year.
Scott: Yeah, we'll try to one and a half to two episodes on plus.
Rym: there's a good chance We'll be putting up some content throughout the weekend since we'll basically have all of our equipment set up in the gaming room for the Entire con.
Scott: also if all goes well, we'll probably be creating content like for Katsucon.
Rym: Yes, we may be running our famous anime match game, which was very much well received at city con.
Scott: So if you want the the full GeekNights action You pretty much have to go to Katsucon because if they're gonna let us go all out We're gonna go all out.
Rym: We may even have some of the earliest earliest vestiges of swag in the tiniest of quantities Which you will only be able to get if you see us at Katsucon.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Rym: Yeah Granted every word I said should be taken literally Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now also the news here is not that we're gonna be doing crazy stuff at Katsucon or that Katsucon is awesome Or that you should go.
Rym: the news here Which is nothing to do with any of you is that despite the fact that they've said that the Omni Shore Motel where Katsucon Is situated has been sold out for quite a while now Either that is not true or I'm the luckiest Goddamn guy in the world because I was able to acquire through various means a room at this hotel throughout the entire convention.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: now as a result The rest of the front row crew may indeed have to find their own accommodations because I'm not cramming 20 or 30 people into a one-bed room.
Scott: Yeah Plus we're gonna bring a lot of shit with us and we're gonna have a lot of stuff to do and not so much time To hang out.
Rym: So yeah see in the front row crew generally for conventions We tend to plan it all.
Rym: we tend to get the hotel take all the money make the reservations make the travel plans Wake everyone up take make everyone get out of the room collect the keys dole the keys out blah blah blah.
Rym: and You know This is probably gonna be the first con where a lot of people are going where I'm just tossing my hands in the air and I'm Taking care of me and GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, we just have too much GeekNights stuff to do that.
Scott: We can't take care of anyone else besides ourselves at this convention.
Scott: Yeah, I mean not only that but other conventions where we do a lot less we can help other people out.
Rym: We might not even have a chance to actually hang out much in the traditional way We do cuz we're pretty much gonna be running events the whole con.
Scott: Oh unless you know people come to our events, which I'm sure they will or yeah come hang out in the video game room.
Scott: But yeah, I just hope there aren't too many real.
Scott: Yeah, I hope that Kazuka doesn't have too many good events that I want to go to.
Scott: Oh, no Yes, I won't be able to go to them.
Scott: I'll probably end up going to like the dealer's room.
Scott: Maybe like once late Sunday.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Their dealer's room.
Scott: Isn't that amazing?
Rym: Anyway, I imagine Scott and I will be pulling shifts where one of us will be wacky radio guy in the gaming room while the Other one goes and does, you know con stuff.
Scott: Yeah We'll see how it goes.
Scott: It should be fun.
Rym: Yeah, though speaking of anime news that isn't related to Katsucon There was an article recently that got dig up about how some anime clubs of aimed at teenagers high school kids and communities are Flourishing in libraries now.
Scott: This is something we've known about for a long time.
Rym: Yes, the new is not news that this is happening that anime clubs are springing up all over.
Scott: It is news that someone wrote a newspaper article.
Rym: Yes The mainstream news has picked this up.
Rym: anime clubs at local libraries and Alex lodges and whatnot are starting to get noticed by normal people.
Rym: in fact It's getting to the point that many libraries because most libraries now have a wide selection of older DVDs for people to check out I think is wonderful.
Rym: They're adding anime To the libraries because there is such a demand and it draws a lot of kids.
Rym: In fact, it draws a lot of people in in general and there are stories about libraries that have Practically doubled their takeout rate just by adding a mildly extensive anime library.
Scott: There are also a lot of libraries adding manga.
Scott: I mean, you know those posters they read on them Well, they constantly make more of those and they get more famous people to make them and such one of them has art from of Things Cantarella on it.
Scott: that was on anime news network a week few weeks.
Rym: Wow, if you're going for the 14 to 22 year old female shoujo demographic Mm-hmm.
Scott: Just get a big ol read poster with a picture that cantarella guy.
Rym: Yeah, Cesare Borgia Yeah, my favorite Pope and you can put that.
Scott: you can actually buy that poster at the library Association website.
Scott: Yeah, but I think they also have bookmarks.
Rym: I guess this is.
Rym: I mean, this is definitely not a sign to say that anime is now 100% mainstream.
Scott: blah No, it's a sign that libraries are suffering and anime and manga are a way to help the libraries out.
Scott: Well, I
Rym: think it's also a sign that Anime while it is not mainstream This is definitely one of those tiny junctures where if you tanning 20 years from now you look at the history of anime in America We're in one of the eras where one of those tiny little junctures one of those little boosts before another plateau comes.
Rym: I think if this trend continues, we're gonna see a lot more Anime.
Rym: anime related Banga Japanese related things being used in educational capacities.
Scott: I think what it is is that libraries have been places where people can get access to information to entertainment, you know for free.
Scott: and Anime and manga are like, you know of all the possible types of entertainment we have now, you know We have pop music and movies and all this stuff.
Scott: Anime and manga are sort of a little more intellectual than you know, the other types of entertainment don't get us wrong.
Rym: I mean that is definitely a generalization.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there's plenty of dumbass mug Naruto and Dragon Ball if I know means intellectual.
Scott: but on the whole, you know, there tends to be sort of this, you know Like culture about it, you know It's like if you read anime and manga while you're cultured and libraries are all about making people more cultured.
Scott: So and you know kids like it and libraries are all about getting kids into the library as much as possible.
Scott: So anime and manga the libraries like it the kids like it.
Scott: It all works out good.
Scott: Everyone saves money.
Scott: Everyone's happy.
Rym: I think it's also a sign of generally a trend that despite how the anime industry is doing which for many reports not so well Anime in terms of popularity.
Rym: I think is doing wonderfully.
Rym: In fact, it's growing rapidly.
Scott: And yeah, I mean, there's a lot of people who aren't necessarily in our anime fan group But like, you know, they'll just be some guy, you know, he watches sports.
Scott: He watches, you know, the the non anime and Adult Swim and you know, maybe watches some.
Scott: You know some spike TV once in a while, you know, he's looking through the channels.
Scott: He'll stop on an anime.
Scott: You know, it's there.
Scott: not a lot of people out There aren't anime fans now like we are we're you know, we watch the anime.
Scott: we know about them.
Scott: You watch old giant robot shows.
Scott: they don't care about watching whole series.
Scott: I don't care about watching every anime there is or knowing about all of them, but Anime isn't some scary thing.
Scott: They're not gonna watch anymore.
Scott: It's like hey, there's an anime cool.
Rym: Yeah, plus I mean these clubs are sprouting up and I know anime world order talked a lot about how they think anime clubs seem to be dying, but I Guess it's a regional thing because up here these clubs are springing up practically everywhere at a fairly rapid clip.
Scott: I think it's just these style of anime clubs that is.
Scott: you know, we're dying.
Scott: It's like the old style of anime club is going away.
Scott: The new style is doing well.
Rym: Yeah, well I'm cuz up here I mean for the last five to ten years actually.
Rym: Yeah About the last ten years now a lot of the big anime clubs are definitely not Like the old big anime clubs used to be but as a result due to the fact that the fan base is bigger These clubs are even bigger.
Scott: Yeah, it's tough to have a special interest club for something that is widely available.
Scott: It's like you can't have I don't know a Harry Potter Club on campus because only the crazy Harry Potter fans will come.
Scott: And what are you gonna do there?
Scott: Hey, you got to have a club about something.
Scott: That's you know, if it's just a club of consumption and nothing else you need to have that club.
Scott: You know do something besides the consuming.
Scott: if everyone can consume it or the thing they're consuming has to be rare Yep, or if it's not rare you can also add rarity or add.
Rym: I hate to use business terms But there's a value add.
Rym: I mean if you're just say clubs just shows anime and that's it every week that show some anime Great, you can get anime anywhere.
Rym: So all you got to do is have the value add of watching anime in a crowd is always better than watching it alone Especially if it's a funny anime or a giant robot anime.
Scott: You're reading Harry Potter, you know doesn't add anything when there's some fangirl next to you.
Rym: however also reading Harry if you like Harry Potter and you get a bunch of people who love Harry Potter and you all go to watch a Harry Potter movie together.
Rym: That's a value add now.
Rym: You'll all yell and scream when Snape does something wonderful.
Scott: I guess all right.
Rym: What do you mean you guess?
Rym: Don't pretend that your like of Japanese cartoons is somehow superior to someone else's like of American movies.
Scott: You're allowed to not like Harry Potter, I'm just yeah, I'm just saying I don't like Harry Potter.
Rym: I know see here's the thing.
Rym: I like the story of Harry Potter a lot.
Scott: No, I really kind of don't know.
Rym: I like the story.
Rym: I like the characters.
Rym: I think the movies are kind of lame and I really absolutely hate the novels because the writing to me is just Horrible.
Rym: I can't stand the way that I just think the whole idea is sort of it's like.
Scott: it's a good idea.
Scott: It's like a kid in the wizard school.
Scott: Just like Naruto is a good idea kid in the ninja school.
Scott: Ah, so genius.
Scott: then we need to make kid in the pirate school next but it's just so played out that sort of story That I'm just kind of yeah, I don't think it's that played out especially in cinema.
Scott: I think it's played out for me.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I agree in movies is not played out But for me it is.
Scott: we had the same argument the other day about how I just read so many books like that when I Was a kid that I'm just like whatever.
Rym: Well, we were arguing over the weekend about dragons.
Rym: It's like Oh dragons are totally played out in fantasy.
Rym: And then the answer was maybe in fans.
Scott: I guess I wasn't there for that.
Rym: I know you weren't okay, but not in fantasy movies.
Rym: How many dragon movies have there been in recent memory that it?
Scott: that is true.
Scott: There are not enough dragons and movies except for Dragonheart yeah and rain of fire.
Scott: Oh, that doesn't count.
Rym: that movie can die in a fire.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Anyway, so I got a news.
Scott: Everyone knows that in Japan, you know The manga typically comes in the big foam books every week and they they're like two bucks and it's awesome Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well get and that's pretty sad because in this country, you know, you can get a comic book Which is maybe 32 pages and eight of those pages are ads and it's three dollars and change and it comes once a month.
Rym: Yeah, but they'll argue it's all shiny and glossy and has 16 million colors Right.
Scott: Well, that's not what they say.
Scott: that what they actually say is not.
Scott: you know?
Scott: Oh our comics are better and worth this money because they're in color.
Scott: what they say is no one would buy it if it wasn't in color.
Scott: That's what they say Wow.
Scott: Anyway In Japan get ready for some sadness because well sadness for the u.s.
Scott: There's going to be a new manga magazine called comic ganbo ganbo and it's going to be Distributed at 30 different Tokyo area train stations and there's gonna be a hundred thousand copies and they're gonna be free.
Scott: ha now I imagine it's not gonna be as big as like a big fat shonen jump and I imagine it'll be loaded with ads and It'll probably be on cheap paper and black and white and all that.
Scott: But it's gonna have more than 24 pages of comic content.
Scott: That's I mean, it doesn't.
Scott: I'd haven't read that anywhere It's just a guess but it's got it.
Scott: this because no one else had even bother picking it up.
Rym: Yeah, putting out that small amount of content.
Rym: I mean I could distribute a one-page flyer around beacon, but yeah exactly.
Scott: So it's gonna.
Scott: it's they're giving away things that are have more content than American comics Which cost three dollars or maybe even four dollars for free in Japan.
Rym: You know Japan just gets all the breaks except for DVD prices, I think yes it evens out.
Scott: I think this is just.
Scott: you know, I mean if there wasn't a wake-up call to the American comics industry before this is it?
Scott: I mean, come on You're trying to compete not with piracy free but with legitimate free And you're losing and you're charging more.
Scott: you have a worse product for more money than what someone else is doing for free Legally.
Scott: yeah,
Rym: I mean I remember a while ago We had the news of you know top selling books and top selling print items and manga sells real freakin well, that's
Scott: like if I was trying to sell a DVD for $30 that had a half-hour single episode of a TV show on it and Some other guy was selling a VHS with a five-hour movie for $2, which one am I gonna buy?
Rym: Yeah, meanwhile it could be.
Rym: I mean it's like there's the reverse wake-up call in Japan of just the fact that DVDs there cost more than my soul.
Scott: and yeah, it's totally backwards.
Rym: They wonder.
Scott: they wonder movies and TV over here the wind and in Japan comics of the wind.
Scott: I think we need to trade.
Scott: we'll give you all our cheap DVDs and you give us all your cheap comics.
Rym: Yeah, I'm real down with that.
Scott: I need a big old cultural exchange going on Things of the day.
Scott: Actually found this thing just recently and it's pretty damn awesome.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: So there's a guy in a DJ competition and well, I think we've said before what we think about the two turntable DJs.
Rym: Yeah in general.
Rym: I'm not that impressed with most to tear turn to turn tabling.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I'd much rather hear Pre-created well done techno.
Scott: I mean the thing is, you know to turntable mastering is quite a skill that takes a you know Great deal of effort and time and it is respectable skill.
Scott: However, it's not really useful skill because you can accomplish generating the same sound or better with a lot less effort.
Scott: It's like people are doing things the hard old-school way just to be cool.
Rym: I mean of all the clubs or dances or whatnot I've gone to pretty much the best one is just played good techno that I already knew about or even techno I didn't.
Rym: just basically albums.
Rym: they beat mix them together.
Scott: Yeah instead of having some records with some It's not really necessary to you know, mix things live between two turntables.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: now there's the video DJ.
Scott: It's a skill that I can respect but it's not really.
Scott: it's like you can just mix it up at home on your computer and play It for me and I'd like that just as much because it would sound better.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, this guy though demonstrates his mad DJ skills.
Scott: He's got you know, he's got two discs - not discs.
Scott: He's got two vinyls spinning around playing this nice hip-hop beat and he's do.
Scott: he's in a DJ competition.
Scott: He's got a win right?
Scott: So he's got 30 seconds left.
Scott: He takes off one of the you know, the vinyls.
Scott: He's got the other ones still going.
Scott: he puts a new one on there.
Scott: He gets them all lined up without making anything sound stupid.
Scott: If you listen to both of these records going around It's just a really good hip-hop beat.
Scott: Groovin to it.
Scott: then he stops him and he kind of alternates between the two on like these few notes and he Basically plays the Imperial March.
Scott: If you don't know what the Imperial March is get the hell by alternating and you know scratching between notes on these two different records and everyone in the whole club or wherever he is starts going.
Rym: It's pretty well done it's pretty good.
Scott: I mean I was just watching it and I knew what it was and Ram is on the other side of the room not looking and he says is that the Imperial mark?
Scott: Yeah, that's what that is.
Scott: And hey, let's go with the records and the hip-hop beat comes back and you're like, whoa You found a hip-hop beat that contains the notes at the Imperial March.
Scott: That's pretty cool.
Rym: Well, there aren't so many notes in the Imperial March.
Scott: I know really analyze it I know but it's still.
Scott: it took some practice and it took some Foresight to even think to do that in the first place.
Rym: Well, anyway, as I promised I have a rather Japanese thing of the day Definitely better than the thing of the day from two days ago, even though those competitions in Japan are now my favorite sport.
Rym: Second only to hockey.
Scott: I was gonna say what the fuck hockey?
Rym: Well, see when I say favorite sport and I don't say hockey.
Rym: I think the hockey's implied.
Scott: Well, some people you know, maybe this is the first episode they don't know.
Rym: no No, I'm just talking about in general in life in the world.
Rym: The hockey is implied.
Rym: You just you don't even have to mention the hockey.
Rym: it is understood.
Scott: There's a lot of people who don't understand hockey.
Rym: No people in their hearts.
Rym: They know and they're lying to everyone and themselves.
Scott: Okay Yeah, or maybe they're just from below the Messier line.
Scott: They don't know what hockey is.
Rym: so a while ago Scott had a thing of the day which was a Japanese prank from some Japanese TV show where To to summarize very briefly people would go into what looked like a public restroom a porta-potty an attempt to urinate.
Rym: While this happening a little countdown would start next to him and there's a hidden camera and they turn and look and think wow I wonder what those green lights mean.
Rym: I wonder where it'll happen when that red one lights up and then the roof would open and the entire thing would Launch up and put them on display for all the world to see.
Scott: It was pretty hilarious.
Scott: it was so hilarious I couldn't believe it and it's the kind of awesome prank you can't do in the United States because it just gets sued.
Rym: Yeah in the America.
Rym: if you did that the first thing people say was I'm suing whoever's responsible for this in Japan?
Rym: People's first priority is getting their pants on.
Scott: Hey, yep.
Scott: So we thought what could possibly be better than that?
Rym: Well, let's say you're at a ski lodge You know, you're at a ski resort.
Rym: you're skiing.
Rym: you're out on the mountain way out in the middle of nowhere up at the top.
Rym: You've been skiing all day.
Rym: Now, let's say you see a nice wooden spa and you wonder what it is.
Rym: you go in it's free.
Rym: It has a little room where you can take off all your stuff.
Rym: It's really warm and heated inside.
Rym: There's massage chairs Inside of it.
Rym: You can put a little money in and they'll massage you.
Rym: there's a steam, you know, nice little thing.
Rym: So, oh, that'd be great.
Rym: I think now if I was skiing I would love something like that.
Rym: So, you know, you sit down and you don't know.
Rym: there's a hidden camera and you sit in this little chair and you're ready to go Turn on a little massage and you lay back.
Rym: You've just got a towel over your naughty bit, if anything And a little countdown goes down to your right, but you don't even notice it.
Rym: And then suddenly without warning the wall behind you opens up and the chair Catapults you out naked into the snow.
Rym: the chair then immediately retracts into the building.
Rym: the wall seals back up and you there is no Evidence that it ever opened.
Rym: you're now naked in front of a crowd of people in a pile of snow on the top of a mountain.
Scott: oh shit.
Scott: Even though I've watched seems that all these pranks are pretty much taking people in the situations Which they would comfortably get naked and then launching them outside of those situations without putting their clothes on.
Rym: now It was funny on its own But then they had to go like they do with the previous thing one step further.
Scott: So went one step further.
Rym: now the one step further is perhaps one of the funniest things I've ever seen.
Rym: It's I'd say top 50 mostly because there's so much build up.
Rym: so the guys sitting there and then his friends watching him and then the cherries and just starts turning around like rotating to face the wall and you see he's saying something to his friend and his friends like her and they're both like what's Going on and then before they can react that the thing he had a rocket lights off on it And it launches him on.
Rym: effectively a snowmobile sled naked down the mountain at incredibly high speed Naked in a chair with a rocket on it.
Scott: Well.
Scott: What looks like a rocket.
Scott: I don't think it's actually rocket propel.
Rym: No, I think it's just.
Scott: I think it's just like propelled by.
Scott: you know some sort of Tires or something.
Rym: it's still going pretty fast.
Scott: It's going pretty fast.
Scott: It's got to be dangerous.
Rym: Oh, you should have seen the absolute look of horror and terror on the guy's face.
Scott: Yeah, they must have tested that a couple times to make sure it wouldn't kill anybody.
Rym: of course the worst thing was the one where The chair would like flip out and dump you in the snow and then flip back in.
Rym: one guy was laying over the towel.
Rym: So it flips him out and he falls into the snow and his towels kind of laying on the corner of it.
Rym: He turns around and his first instinct is to grab the towel.
Rym: the moment he reaches for it the chair goes back up with His towel and takes it back into the building Wanted.
Rym: So if you were a fan of pranks or naked people or Japan or snow I can't recommend this thing of the day enough.
Rym: So speaking of things that we can't recommend enough we have delayed Reviewing this manga for a long time Partly due to the fact that we didn't feel we could do it justice in the early days of GeekNights Partly because as soon as I looked at this manga again I had a burning desire to read it which is bad because I have more important things to be doing than rereading things I've already read.
Rym: Yeah, it's part of the reason why I haven't read it again Despite a great desire, of course now that I've got a bunch of it piled up in front of me I've been reading random pages and I can't stop.
Rym: I might end up reading some of this tonight.
Rym: Oh No tonight.
Rym: We're going to talk about in both of our opinions.
Rym: Probably one of our favorite manga ever.
Scott: Also, it's arguable one of the best manga ever one of at least one of the best ones that we have access.
Rym: Yes, I mean I could never say that any one manga was the best manga But this is this is not on the Kira Phoenix level.
Scott: It's like on the level right under that It is definitely in the running.
Rym: It is in the top ten in my easily.
Rym: So we are going to talk about Sanctuary.
Scott: now, I don't think it's really fair for us to talk about sanctuary without saying it's out of print bitches.
Rym: We got it all and you don't you know how hard it was to get all of this How many years we searched.
Scott: well, I think what it was is someone mentioned sanctuary.
Scott: they said hey, you know There's this manga out there where one guy's a yakuza and one guy's a politician, you know.
Scott: And we all we knew is hey, there's a manga where that's the story and for years We never really came across it or anything, you know.
Scott: And then it's sort of boiled up into the spotlight and we eventually got issue one.
Scott: Where do we get issue one?
Rym: for the thing is the year before we got it?
Rym: I had read issue one in the manga library of a convention And that is all that they had had.
Scott: and then that's how I discovered Phoenix in the Otakon Manga library.
Rym: Yeah, so to anime cons keep the manga libraries.
Rym: They definitely serve a purpose.
Rym: Yeah, so I'd read it and it was amazing and I didn't know there was 12 volumes of it.
Rym: I thought it was gonna be like a two or three volume little thing because it didn't seem like it could go.
Scott: aren't there nine?
Scott: How many are there 12?
Scott: Oh, wow.
Rym: There are 12 volumes of sanctuary, okay.
Rym: So we all we became desperate Scott and I and the rest of the front row crew and started trying to get a hold of the other 11 volumes.
Scott: We eventually got a couple of the volumes.
Rym: It was not easy.
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: and you know, they belong to Rym, which I guess sir.
Rym: Yeah, I own Sanctuary and you and all the good board games.
Rym: I owe a lot of the good manga.
Scott: Yeah I own lots of good manga - you do anyway, we.
Scott: Eventually when I was working in the city I started going to Midtown Comics every day and I noticed that Midtown Comics on the wall of manga They had sanctuary.
Rym: Yeah, they host all of it.
Scott: They had almost all the sanctuary that we didn't already have except for what volume?
Rym: for volume three.
Scott: It was like volume three.
Scott: So me and Rym in red.
Scott: one and two.
Scott: Rym had bought four through twelve and we didn't have three.
Rym: I wouldn't even look at the covers of them.
Rym: I was so afraid of ruining something also me.
Rym: and then finally We got a whole and it was through Alex of the missing one.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know how or who got it, but someone I'm pretty sure Alex got issue three.
Rym: Scott ended up paying for it.
Rym: Even though I own it.
Rym: the deal was because he paid for it.
Rym: The only thing that he I had to do was let him read it first.
Scott: Is that what I really do that?
Scott: Yeah, because you paid for it.
Rym: No You did because then you read all the rest of sanctuary and you were pretty much one volume ahead of me the whole time.
Scott: Three is mine bitch.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: You said it was mine.
Scott: Remember that you trade.
Rym: you said very clearly.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even remember paying for.
Scott: I remember you paying for.
Scott: you said I mean I remember just me reading it first.
Rym: I may have paid for it, but I but Whatever.
Scott: I just remember reading it first.
Scott: I don't remember paying but whatever.
Rym: Yeah, you you paid for it and you read it before me and then you just you have no idea.
Rym: You have no idea.
Scott: Yeah, I remember I was desperate to read it first.
Scott: So I read number three first and then I burn through the rest of it because I didn't want Rym to hold me back by Holding on to an issue that I need.
Rym: in fact you read it at the shore to the exclusion of shore activities.
Scott: Oh, no that I think sanctuary and it can beat shore activities or is the least equivalent.
Rym: Yes So before we talk, I mean we're gonna review sanctuary.
Scott: Let's talk about.
Scott: let's not before we talk about what's in the manga Let's talk about some of the meta information.
Rym: Yes, because sanctuary is kind of the tip of the iceberg of this whole other world of manga that many of you have probably never Seen yes.
Scott: Well, the first thing you have to know about sanctuary is That there is also an OAV and that is not what you want.
Rym: Yes, if you see a VHS tape of sanctuary avoid it like a lens.
Rym: min.
Scott: Well, we have it and it's actually a pretty faithful Animation of the first couple volumes.
Rym: Yeah, but it's like every OAV from a manga.
Rym: It's a bunch of scenes that you'd like to see animated animated.
Rym: Okay, and if you haven't read the manga, it's totally useless.
Scott: it is pretty useless if The only purpose of the OAV is people who have read and enjoy the manga can now see the beginning of it animated.
Scott: That's all it does.
Scott: Yeah, there's really no point in watching it at all.
Rym: And in fact, the voices are pretty bad.
Scott: Yes, the second thing you have to know about sanctuary is that there are a lot of things out there especially comics called sanctuary.
Scott: I think there's even a Jesus comic called sanctuary.
Scott: There is an American Jesus comic.
Scott: That's not what you want that that's really not what you want.
Scott: What you want will be a black book with a picture of a guy on it.
Scott: You're probably pointing a gun at you or wearing a white suit or you know looking all badass.
Rym: Yeah, these things are big and black.
Scott: Yeah, they're bigger than your old than the current manga because they're so old.
Scott: I mean when were the one of these things published?
Scott: freaking.
Scott: so the first printing of these things was in 1995. that's pretty crazy when you think about it.
Rym: Yeah back then I had never seen a manga.
Scott: Yeah, and Apparently there were printings as late as 2003, you know, what was that?
Scott: the seventh printing in 2003?
Rym: Yeah, I mean this thing was wildly popular.
Scott: Yeah, the fourth printing was in 99.
Scott: So I'm guessing they had a printing a year, you know, maybe they skipped a year or two.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, it doesn't look like other mommy open it up and there's no magical things fighting what it doesn't read right to left Because it was printed before Americans decided they wanted to read manga right to left, but that doesn't matter.
Scott: What else about it?
Scott: Oh, yes now Sanctuary is written by a man of many names.
Scott: His real name is Yoshiyuki Okamura.
Scott: The name that you will see on the cover of sanctuary at least the printings that we have is show Fumi Mura But the name he mostly goes by is but on son, which is the name he gave himself.
Scott: He named himself after Charles Bronson, I know Charles Bronson is a famous guy, but I don't know anything about him.
Scott: What do you know about Charles Bronson?
Rym: Well Charles Bronson's way of growing in a mustache was imitated by Okamura according to the trivia on Wikipedia.
Scott: Oh really?
Rym: But anyway, you might remember this man from such wonderful works as Hokuto no Ken Fist of the North Star.
Scott: Yes, this is the guy who wrote Fist of the North Star the guy who wrote strain Which is pretty similar to sanctuary You know, this guy is written all sorts of good action stuff.
Rym: Fist of the Blue Sky.
Scott: Well, I don't think he actually wrote the Fist of the Blue Sky manga.
Scott: He advised on it.
Rym: Yeah, well it is listed as one of his works.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Now the artist for sanctuary is Ryoichi Ikigami who is one of my favorite artists.
Scott: now Ryoichi got Ikigami also did the art for strain, which I just mentioned Samurai Crusader and Crying Freeman.
Scott: Crying Freeman as you know was written by Kazuo Koike.
Rym: See it all comes together.
Scott: It all comes together.
Scott: This is big chain of these same, you know, Bronson, Kazuo Koike Ikigami and some other guys and they all work together to create this body of manga Which is all the good stuff.
Scott: the stuff that we like was all made by these same group of guys.
Scott: Yep Different combination.
Rym: There are a lot of different ways to categorize this.
Rym: a word You might hear a lot to refer to this kind of manga would be Seinen Which generally means manga targeted to men our age.
Rym: It's kind of I mean, there's Jose which I got a hold of some crappy Jose a long time ago and learn what the word meant.
Rym: I guess you could kind of say that shoujo and shounen are Kind of the lesser not really lesser but the younger equivalents of Jose and Seinen.
Scott: Yeah, Seinen is the manga that Riven's got like.
Rym: yes if it were made in America They would probably call it adult manga or something along those lines.
Scott: Yeah, I mean whereas shounen usually involves like little kids with superpowers fighting Seinen usually involves yakuza and politicians Being awesome and killing and raping.
Rym: Well, I mean, let me here's how sanctuary is built in the first volume Sanctuary an Erotically charged saga of political corruption the yakuza underworld and two handsome ruthless men.
Scott: That sounds awesome.
Rym: That is exactly what sanctuary is all about.
Rym: That is exactly what GeekNights is all about.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's a lot of manga out there in this same sort of genre But because of the anime culture United States not too much of this comes over here.
Rym: I mean, I guess in anime more than manga.
Rym: I don't know why but it seems like the manga market has been generally run by the generally generic Shoujo type stuff and the very, you know million volumes of fighting whatever manga.
Scott: Yeah I mean, this is the kind of stuff that they tried to bring over when manga was still new in this country.
Scott: I mean 95 people.
Scott: this is over 10 years ago that this stuff was coming over, you know No one cared about flipping or anything.
Scott: and well, it was the awesome stuff and then it didn't sell.
Scott: so well back then Because the timing is wrong not because the content was wrong.
Rym: Yeah, we could go into great detail about the anime and manga industry back there.
Scott: Yeah, they changed the timing and the content and they thought that the content was so they haven't gone back to the old content Whatever.
Rym: Well, there have been a lot of forays back into this territory bit by bit and I think we're gonna see a lot more of this stuff coming over in the next.
Scott: Well dark horse has always been good about bringing over the good stuff.
Scott: I mean, they're bringing over MPD psycho pretty soon.
Rym: Yeah, there's all you know, like the Viz signature series.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what?
Scott: Is sanctuary actually about?
Rym: well the plot the basic plot and once again We are not going to spoil anything because woe betide anyone who spoils this manga for anyone.
Rym: Mm-hmm is about two men One of whom has taken the high road and one of whom has taken the low road and their goal is to change the world And remake Japan.
Scott: Yes, one of them is named Hojo.
Rym: He has taken the low road.
Rym: He has decided to join the Yakuza.
Rym: join the underworld.
Rym: He's a criminal.
Scott: He's not just joining.
Scott: The underworld is gonna take over the underworld.
Scott: He's got to be on top of the bottom.
Rym: There is probably one of the best scenes in this entire manga.
Rym: Well, that's hard a heady statement considering how many so many good see it's.
Scott: every volume is like five of them.
Rym: It's one of the best scenes in the early part of the manga Where one of the older Yakuza guys flashes back to when Hojo tried to join the Yakuza.
Scott: That's my favorite scene.
Rym: I think I can spoil this one scene.
Rym: Okay, just just to express to you how absolutely badass this character and his manga is.
Rym: This is a punk kid out of high school.
Rym: He's dropped out of high school and he's come to this Yakuza guy Asking him to join his little gang.
Rym: The Yakuza guy is a hardcore criminal.
Rym: He looks at this kid and laughs.
Rym: What the hell you think you could just join the Yakuza out of school.
Rym: blah blah blah You're not tough.
Rym: and he takes out a knife and puts it on the table.
Rym: And he says if you're serious take that knife and stab it through your hand.
Rym: now This is all part of a flashback where in the modern time the same Yakuza guy is doing the same thing to some punk kid off the street and the kids scared like.
Rym: And he doesn't do it.
Rym: But then he thinks to himself there was only one man whoever and it cuts back to this and Hojo without blinking grabs the knife and stabs it through his hand and into the table.
Scott: and he goes and Seeing no one has ever done that before because you're not really supposed to stab your hand You know, it's just a scary punk kids away from joining the Yakuza, you know, the guy goes.
Scott: doesn't that hurt?
Scott: He's like it hurts like hell.
Rym: He says quote it hurts so much I could cry and he's looking up.
Rym: This is like the signature thing of this manga is no one ever looks right at someone if they're a badass.
Rym: They always kind of look down but then their eyes are up and you get a full page spread of this.
Scott: It's so badass Ever.
Rym: I mean everything is so absolutely dramatic in this manga, but yet it's not cheesily dramatic It's intensely dramatic.
Scott: It's like every time one of those full pagers comes along.
Scott: You just like.
Rym: yeah I mean I tend to just blow through manga But sanctuary is one of those few things that gives me pause and when I come to one of those spreads I just kind of admire it for a while.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I tend to rush through just to get to the next one and then it I stop.
Scott: It's like a speed.
Scott: It's sort of like this little way for it's like oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god Oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Here's comes the climax BAM.
Scott: But the thing is I started speeding up again in more.
Rym: in typical manga The climax would be like they beat the guy in the fight or a thing happens.
Rym: But a lot of the climaxes in this aren't a thing happens.
Rym: They're like someone decided to do something or Conversation and like.
Rym: it's hard to explain without reading it But there'll be a climax an absolutely intense climactic moment where nothing happens.
Scott: And but usually it's something nothing physical happens.
Scott: Yes, someone decided something Yes, or like.
Scott: there'll be you know some large Physical thing like on the verge of half.
Rym: Oh, I know exactly what you're thinking about
Scott: and you'll be like, oh my god It's like of a bomb is falling towards the ground right and you're like, oh my god Oh my god is a bomb coming towards the ground and instead of having the explosion be the great the great like finishing move It's actually there's not an explosion and that's the finishing move and you go.
Scott: Oh my god, there wasn't an explosion.
Rym: Now I remember first president of Japan did that pretty well in one particular scene.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they give you the explosion of you know Finalizing suspense without having it the explosion in the story.
Scott: It would be like if if you were watching a fight in Naruto and then all of a sudden Naruto and whoever he was fighting said, alright, let's let's chill and let's make a little let's just make peace and Duke it out.
Scott: You know, we'll we'll just agree to.
Scott: you know disagree agree to now.
Rym: that might sound lame just oh whatever But you've got to read this manga.
Scott: Holy shit, if you can find it.
Rym: Well, if you happen to live near us and you're really really nice to us We might be willing to let you read it under supervision.
Rym: This stuff doesn't leave my house.
Rym: This are Eagle.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well Eagle we can get it's not Eagles out of print also, but you can get copies of it.
Rym: Yeah, well you especially if you go for the non super volumes.
Rym: Yeah sanctuary is pretty difficult to get but anyway You've got this Yakuza guy whose goal is to take over the Yakuza become the dawn of all the Yakuza in Japan And not just that but all of East Asia.
Scott: now, you've got this other guy.
Scott: his friend Asami Asami is a politician.
Rym: He stayed in school.
Rym: He became a political advisor.
Scott: He works for a member of the diet yep, and his goal is to become the Prime Minister of Japan.
Rym: and The funny thing is there's a really really good scene where he has to do something horrible Not horrible like shoot somebody cuz he's not a criminal but you want to spoil him.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil this okay, but he has to do something pretty horrible in order to get the favor of this senator.
Scott: Well, yeah, basically he's talking to this other D It was much more important than he is like a senior guy and he's just a junior whatnot?
Rym: He's not even on the D. He's just an advisor.
Scott: Yeah, and he's trying to move up in the ranks.
Scott: So the guy says, you know the senior guy who controls his fate says do this horrible thing.
Scott: and he says You know normally you wouldn't do such a thing.
Scott: It's it's so horrible.
Scott: but he says This isn't even close to anything as horrible as anything Hojo has had to do in the Yakuza.
Scott: and he does it without Hesitation.
Rym: and then that's an awesome scene.
Rym: then it cuts to Hojo right after that Living it up as the Yakuza awesome dude with wine and women.
Scott: It's quite the hilarity.
Rym: Now you might wonder you know Why would this be considered adult if it's just some Yakuza story?
Rym: I've read Yakuza stories before.
Rym: this is just a particularly well-done one.
Rym: Aside from the fact that sanctuary pulls no punches and does not like the camera never leaves the action.
Rym: if something happens You see it no matter how horrible it may be but not in the fist of the North Star people exploding way, but in a very realistic and Disturbing because it could be real way.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there are lots of scenes of sex or rape or Murder and all sorts of very adult and serious things But they're not portrayed in a perverted way or a pornographic way.
Rym: They're not even in a gratuitous way.
Rym: Yeah Mr.
Scott: Tokai, okay, they don't put extra blood and guts in there to make you go Oh, and they don't put you know extra hot women's to make you get off or anything like that.
Rym: It's that was an interesting way of putting that.
Scott: Yeah, it's just Normal, it's like wow.
Scott: Yeah, that's what they would look like if they did it.
Scott: That's what it would look like if that guy got shot.
Rym: That's what would happen if you smash you guys face in with a glass bottle and then beat him Yeah, and Yakuza smash people with glass bottles and beat them.
Scott: It's not any sort of you know, like extreme unnecessary violence with chainsaws or anything silly like that.
Rym: Yeah, there's perhaps only one gratuitous thing in the entire manga and it's almost a running gag but yet on the grander scale when you read the manga you kind of realize near the end that it really isn't and you realize What that character was actually all about and then it's almost touching.
Rym: However, I say almost because he's still raping people God, there's just one character.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Tokai.
Scott: Tokai Is so awesome now also so horrible.
Rym: you will not approve of what he does.
Rym: He is a despicable horrible person and yet at the same time It's almost funny the way he leads his life and I really don't want to ruin it.
Scott: Anyone that can make me like any manga in which there's a horrible rapist that I pretty much recognize as a bad guy.
Scott: Yet I'm on his side.
Scott: You got they got to be doing some magic there.
Rym: see this is a manga where you're on the good guys's side the whole time.
Rym: There's well, I guess relatively the good guys.
Rym: There is never a doubt in your mind that they are right and you're with them a hundred percent and yet at the same time You feel for everyone they're up against because every time they're up against someone.
Rym: They're not just some faceless villain They're not just some stupid.
Rym: I would rule the world or I will stop these people for no good reason.
Rym: They all have very good reasons for what they're doing well at least very justifiable reasons for what they're doing.
Scott: That's one thing that a lot of these manga by all these guys have in common.
Scott: that is really beginning to bother me and a Lot of other media maybe because I've been spoiled by reading things like sanctuary, you know It is really made apparent to me when I recently Watch.
Scott: I went to my parents house and there was happened to be this old movie on TV a great movie called M It's.
Scott: it's a very old awesome movie by Fritz Lang.
Scott: But the one thing wrong with the movie is that it was like, why don't you do this?
Scott: Why don't you do that?
Scott: It's like people didn't do the smartest thing They possibly could.
Scott: the same thing happened to me when I was playing Resident Evil 4.
Scott: I was like, why didn't you just shoot the guy right there?
Scott: You you know, where was that helicopter hours ago?
Scott: You know, this is really no one is doing the smart thing.
Rym: Yeah, I mean forget the president's daughter.
Rym: You just nuke this place from orbit.
Scott: Exactly, you know people were not making smart decisions.
Scott: people were not acting in their own best interest or in the very lot of things People did and that were totally did not make sense at all.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if you're watching a character that's dumber than you and you figure something out that they could have done better That's one thing.
Rym: But if the character is portrayed as smart and then they just do a stupid thing because that's the only way the plots gonna work.
Rym: I can't deal with that.
Scott: Yeah, I think another manga that recently that gets this right is Death Note.
Scott: Yes Where every character who is smart there aren't really any stupid people, you know.
Scott: And if they are stupid they pretty much their stupidity is exposed immediately and they just die.
Scott: They're probably they're probably a henchman.
Rym: Yeah, actually if you like Death Note, I think you'll really like sanctuary because it's the same deal.
Rym: There's a lot of talking a lot of planning ahead a lot of very smart people at odds.
Scott: Yeah, and you have all these really smart badass people and they just get more smarter more smarter.
Scott: They just get smarter and more badass as the manga goes along.
Scott: and they're.
Scott: some of them are in conflict and some of them are you know in cooperation and all of them do the smartest thing and the best thing they possibly can at any one moment to achieve their goals and Repeat repeat repeat repeat and the excitement is all about seeing how it goes down
Rym: even better.
Rym: And I love this so much about this manga is that not only do they always do the smart thing but many times Characters did something I didn't even think of.
Rym: they outsmarted me.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that's why I like it so much.
Scott: Is that I'm so outsmarted.
Scott: It's like what's he gonna do now?
Rym: Oh shit, and it's not like oh shit Kamehameha, man, man, man, the super double attack.
Rym: It's like oh shit He just put a bunch of Yakuza on a boat and sent him there.
Scott: There's one part in the manga where You don't know which part I'm gonna say.
Rym: I think I know what part you're gonna say.
Scott: Well, there's one part cuz it does deal a lot with politics in addition to the Yakuza.
Scott: and there's one part where this lady beset Who's some American?
Scott: She's some American like foreign policy lady or something?
Scott: I forget exactly what she is and she comes over and she's pissed that Japan won't let America sell American cars in Japan.
Scott: and She gets dealt with in a way.
Scott: Yes I don't want to spoil how she's dealt with but Almost everyone gets dealt with.
Rym: but then the other thing is People lose and people win and while everyone's smart someone still has to win and characters die.
Rym: people die all the time.
Rym: It's as realistic I mean.
Rym: if this world were realistic a world where Yakuza are like this and politicians are like this Then the events here are effectively a documentary.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the other thing is not everything always turns out in a predictable way.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: There's a Yakuza boss and he's infringing on some territory.
Scott: I'm just making shit up right now.
Scott: I don't remember this in the manga.
Scott: Yeah, and you know normally would and aha He killed the other Yakuza boss and took his territory killed the other Yakuza boss took his turn.
Scott: well sometimes that are.
Scott: the Yakuza boss makes an alliance and sometimes the you know The other politician decides to go along with it and maybe sometimes the guy decides to go along with it But he's secretly against it.
Scott: any you know Agrees to an alliance and then does some evil or maybe the guy acts like he's against it But he's really for it, and they keep surprising you left and right.
Scott: But it always makes sense and whenever anyone does something out of the ordinary or unexpected It's always explained and the motivation always works and the decision always works.
Rym: There's never a point where you think why did that character do that?
Rym: Yeah, or you think why did he do that?
Rym: and then you realize oh because he's smarter than I am.
Scott: yep What else is there to say about sanctuary besides how awesome it is?
Rym: yeah like in terms of the understated climax.
Rym: I was just flipping through the second volume again And there's a really important scene where this politician comes home to his house.
Rym: He sees his wife and blah blah blah And then he walks into the dining room after his wife said there's a guest and there's a two-page spread Which they usually reserved for like huge huge huge moments and all it is is Hojo and his assistant Sitting very quietly at a day on a dining table.
Scott: Well because what that what that two-page spread is really saying is hey you have a guest.
Scott: I wonder who my guest is the Yakuza boss.
Rym: not only that but this Yakuza boss is here Not as any gesture of goodwill, but to show me that he could come and do anything He wanted to my family if I crossed him.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: He knows where I live.
Scott: He knows who I am.
Scott: He knows everything about me in my in my house Already kills my wife and my family drinking my juice.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: He's in your base right now.
Scott: He's saying hello And you're still alive.
Rym: and of course not to this won't ruin anything by saying names.
Rym: But if you read this manga and get a hold of it Isao is a name that you will know very well and Ichijima is a name that will be dear to your heart for the rest of your life.
Scott: Ichijima is perhaps the best character in there except for Hojo who's just awesome.
Rym: Yeah, not to discount Tokai or the police chief who is as awesome as you call the police chief for the police woman both of them.
Rym: Yeah Pretty much every character.
Rym: Yeah, except this guy.
Rym: I'm looking at right now.
Rym: We just got killed.
Scott: Oh and Toshiro.
Rym: Oh Toshiro is my favorite character just for the fact that there's one scene early on where he he joined the Yakuza and He's a young guy.
Rym: He has a young beautiful wife and he has a kid.
Rym: and one day Hojo just asks him Why do you want this life?
Rym: What do you want for your kids?
Rym: and he looks out the window and there's all these?
Rym: Businessmen normal businessmen walking through the streets and he basically says I want him to live a life unlike them.
Rym: Their eyes are dead.
Rym: They've got one foot in the grave.
Rym: How could anyone become that way?
Rym: and there's this beautiful conversation that encapsulates everything that I think is awesome about anything ever.
Scott: You know that line in Snow crash that's like every 20 year old guy wants to be a badass.
Scott: If only he could go to a monastery and you know study kung-fu and become a badass If only something he could become the you know, the biggest badass in the whole world.
Scott: Reading sanctuary for 20 something year old guys is the realization of that fantasy.
Scott: Yeah That's what it is.
Scott: It's like look at these guys They're the badasses.
Rym: and he's reading about badasses and you go Even worse despite the fact that you know The Yakuza aren't really like this and you know that politics doesn't work like this.
Rym: When you listen to listen to when you read these speeches that these characters give and the things that happen You think for every now and then for a second?
Rym: Why don't we just do that?
Rym: Why doesn't someone just do that?
Rym: That's the way the world should be.
Scott: Well, I think a lot of the moral of sanctuary that appeals so much to us young kids is like, you know something they say very often throughout the manga is like, you know, 99% of you know, everyone in the diet is over the age of 50 something something They're all a bunch of old geezers run in the country blah blah blah.
Rym: They hold power only so that they can continue to hold power.
Scott: Yeah, it's like we're young people.
Scott: We want to change something.
Scott: Here's all our awesomeness, etc, etc.
Scott: You know and that stuff that anyone who's 20 something years old or even teenager can get way behind In like yeah, fuck those old people.
Rym: But there's a lot more to it than that and we really can't say more without ruining this.
Rym: I don't want to ruin a. there a lot of.
Scott: there are a lot of morals of the story that come in at the end.
Rym: Yeah, and and we say morals because I guess like eska flown a is a good example of an anime That is this there is not just one moral or one theme.
Rym: This manga is about a lot.
Scott: Yeah, it's like each volume is like each segment of the story comes around you'll learn something new or they'll try to tell you something new and then at the end There is an ending at the end that ties everything together.
Rym: a very well executed one.
Scott: I might add an unexpected one alright, so Sanctuary is one of our favorite manga ever.
Scott: if you are a human being who enjoys reading manga You probably should read it if you can get a copy of it, which is not easy.
Scott: it was published by Viz by the way, I don't think I mentioned that before.
Scott: and Holy shit, is it freaking awesome?
Rym: If you can't get ahold of sanctuary At least check out.
Rym: Eagle Eagle is much more readily attainable.
Rym: It's only five volumes.
Rym: It's much less mature and adult but yet at the same time It is very very good and very similar in many ways.
Scott: Also first president of Japan is in the same vein.
Scott: strain is made by the exact same guys is Similar in plot structure, but I don't like it as much.
Scott: It's just kind of different.
Scott: It's the story about a guy in like Southeast Asia doing some stuff.
Scott: I'm not gonna talk about it much now But yeah, there's a lot of manga like this and they're all awesome.
Scott: But sanctuary I think is by far the number one.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.