Scott: It's Monday January 22nd.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discuss text editing.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I'm super super super bored at work lately.
Rym: How bored could you be more bored than usual?
Rym: I think the amount of work we do at any given time is inversely proportional Because I've actually been doing a lot of work at work.
Rym: In fact tomorrow.
Rym: I'm gonna be working late.
Scott: Yeah, I'm trying to actually find I'm putting more effort into finding new work, you know, all right.
Scott: Yeah, not it doesn't look like I go to the postings and stuff and there's a few good things and I send applications But you know, it's there's not.
Scott: it's not like.
Scott: there's a plethora of awesomeness.
Scott: mostly it's because I'm too picky.
Scott: I'm like, no not that one.
Scott: Not that one.
Scott: No, no Yeah, actually what I'm doing more at work than programming is building furniture.
Rym: Well, if they're paying you a programmer's salary to build furniture Well, you know It's just.
Scott: they brought all this furniture to the office and a lot of it's not built.
Scott: So I just kind of when I got nothing better to do.
Scott: I build a piece of furniture.
Rym: I just would have built it all in like one week and been done with it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I could have done that but I'm pretty good at but building together Three file rolling cabinets.
Scott: This is one bitch though because the bottom drawer has a wheel on the bottom of it because it could The way it works and it's really a bitch to get that wheel on there.
Rym: Well, why don't you subcontract this out?
Scott: All right, come to my office and we'll put together furniture.
Rym: I'll do it for 98% of your salary No Of your salary to me.
Scott: Yeah sure for the privilege of being allowed to put together the furniture.
Rym: Yeah, now you might be wondering rims working late tomorrow.
Rym: What happened to his philosophy of 40 hours?
Rym: and I can say very simply that by working late that one day I will in turn get an extra vacation day with which I could go to Katsucon.
Scott: Whoo-hoo, so it's kind of a profit because you're not gonna be working eight hours late.
Rym: Plus I'm going to get two days worth of work done for one day's commute.
Scott: Mmm, that's a good deal.
Rym: Yeah, not too bad at all.
Rym: I should do this more often.
Rym: I wish I could work holidays cuz my company crazily reimburses me.
Rym: if I work a holiday I'll work not.
Scott: let you work a holiday when you want it to they never let me work holidays?
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: no we don't want to pay you that money.
Rym: Yes, even though I'm salaried I get time and a half and an extra vacation day and all this other stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta ask for Katsucon off.
Rym: All right, you'd better do that cuz we're slated to be there.
Scott: It's not really like I ask.
Scott: it's I tell I'm not going to be there these days.
Scott: See ya, yep, right.
Rym: so being science and tech day which also includes internet stuff in the news Wikipedia is Changing one of their policies regarding links and from now on any link going out of Wikipedia will be no-follow.
Scott: Don't know now?
Rym: if you don't know what that means very simply I'll know.
Rym: follow link is a link that search engines know to ignore.
Scott: Yeah, what happened is a lot people have blogs and you can post comments on blogs.
Scott: now the way Google works is if there Are a lot of websites out in the world that link to your website Your website goes up in Google.
Rym: so and the higher up those websites that link to you are the more booze They give to you when they link to you, right?
Scott: So let's say in the olden days I would go to a popular blog a very popular blog with a high page rank and many visitors and I would post a comment And in that comment, I would link to my website.
Scott: now Maybe no one will click on that link.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: Because now if people search for certain things on Google My website will be much higher up possibly on the front page.
Scott: now Imagine if I post comments on lots of blogs now, we got trouble.
Scott: So they invented this thing called rel equals no follow and what they do is in your blog software You make it so that when anyone posts a comment to your blog that it's a no-follow link Which means the search engine ignores it in terms of ranking.
Scott: So no matter how many no-follow blogs you put comments with links to your website on it's not gonna help you out.
Rym: Now this isn't like a mandatory Technological thing.
Rym: It's just data that our search engine can use.
Rym: I mean if Google really wanted they could ignore this.
Scott: Yeah, they could.
Scott: it's actually something they invented.
Scott: Yes, hence to help out blog spam It basically says hey blog spammers come spam all you want It's not gonna help you because there's no follow.
Rym: Yeah, it's not like anyone actually follows those spam links and blogs.
Scott: Yeah, and there's actually a program a kismet which for WordPress at least I don't know if it works in other blog software that filters out blog spam very effectively.
Rym: Yeah, now the issue with Wikipedia was that I mean if you just tried to stick links to your crap Anywhere normal, yeah,
Scott: like let's say I had a website about Pharmaceutical drugs, I'd go to like the Wikipedia page for the disease That's related to those drugs and put links to my crap drugstore.
Rym: Well now you like in general just you could just put links in high-traffic areas to get traffic.
Rym: But Wikipedia mods are smart and those links disappear immediately.
Scott: Yeah, they disappear pretty quickly, but you know almost immediately.
Rym: There's very rarely in high-traffic areas.
Rym: Is there any vandalism like that for any length of time?
Rym: links are looked at much more readily than small changes
Scott: yep,
Rym: but the problem was people were going to not often visited web pages in Wikipedia or discussion pages or Areas where there wouldn't be people and they would just post link after link after link to their stupid Bullshit website trying to get to click through money, whatever.
Rym: and they do this to raise their page rank.
Rym: So now this won't work.
Rym: So those people can keep doing that.
Rym: It doesn't hurt Wikipedia because no one really goes to those parts of Wikipedia yet.
Rym: Anyway, but now those people are just wasting their time.
Rym: their links do absolutely nothing.
Scott: Oh, I guess it sucks for them.
Rym: now there are people on the internet complaining saying that this is somehow bad of Wikipedia or evil or wrong or hurts them in some way and I submit that the vast majority of people of those people are Scumbags who were profiting from this in some way and are now mad about it.
Rym: I mean we get what we got Quite a bit of page rank from Wikipedia.
Rym: We're linked to on Wikipedia in several places because we have relevant interviews and content But we're not complaining about this at all because this is definitely what I think Wikipedia should do.
Rym: There should be no incentive to be linked to from Wikipedia Independent of the merit of your information.
Scott: Yeah There are just too many people out there who try to do things like to increase their traffic to their websites and to their podcasts and to their blogs by means of simply creating content and Waiting for people to come.
Rym: by the same token the only people that use these services are people who either don't know better or Honestly, probably don't have content that deserves to be at the top of Google.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: It seems to me like I look at it from two perspectives.
Scott: Is that like there's the sort of field of dreams model where you build it and they will come and it seems like any other Model you follow other than that Seems sort of illegitimate on the web.
Scott: Like the only way to go without people looking down upon you is to make a website and just hope people show up but at the same time it's like You can't do anything at all without people looking down on you except you really shouldn't be.
Rym: I mean buying ads somewhere is Different from that because that's straight up and while I don't look at ads at least it's a straight-up and open business transaction.
Rym: Nothing wrong with that.
Rym: The problems when people try to game the system say Google doesn't rank your page highly That means that either no one else likes your page or your page has problems or your contents.
Scott: But what if just no one's discovered your page yet?
Scott: And it's actually really good and they never gonna discover it because it's so low on Google.
Scott: blabbity blabbity blah Argument that some asshole makes blah blah blah.
Rym: Well, my argument against that is that almost every major website out there now That's worth a damn grew entirely by random word-of-mouth.
Scott: Yeah, you didn't see dig doing any of this search engine optimization crap.
Scott: Yeah that you didn't see YouTube doing any of this search engine optimization.
Rym: that GeekNights podcast never did any of that.
Scott: Yeah, it's the.
Scott: simply by the merit of what they offered on their website They became popular.
Rym: Remember there are people who will troll around the bottom of Google looking for cool stuff to try to be the first one to dig.
Rym: If your content is out there and is worth a damn odds are people are gonna find it one way or another.
Rym: it might take a While but people will find it.
Scott: Yeah, and it's a good way to start is just it's okay to just tell your friends to go To your website.
Rym: Yeah, I mean God the front row crew going to our website was our only listenership for the first week.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Oh Okay, so I got two news's but I'm gonna combine them sort of uh-huh.
Scott: The first they're both news's about new versions of software.
Scott: the first version of software that came out is Xfce 4.4.
Scott: It just came out.
Scott: for those of you don't know on Linux There are many many different desktops you can choose from but Xfce is the third most popular for good reason.
Rym: I prefer gnome.
Scott: Yeah gnome is you know GTK?
Scott: It's based on the GTK GUI library and KDE is based on the QT GUI library And QT can die in respective fires.
Rym: Well, I'll admit I have not used KDE in about two years.
Scott: I used to use KDE and now I'm still probably not gonna use KDE but I'm realizing a lot of KDE Applications are pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, but I use though.
Rym: I just have QT install.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, me too.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Anyway Xfce Uses the same library as gnome, but it's light.
Scott: It's sort of like no it's you know, people would get pissed if you called it gnome light But that's kind of what it is.
Scott: It's it's light It's fast but it has all the desktop II features that you need and none of the ones you don't.
Scott: and if you want to try out Xfce a Good way to do it is to use Zubuntu XUBUNTU, you know as opposed to kubuntu.
Scott: or Yes, ubuntu uses gnome Kubuntu uses KDE and Zubuntu with an X uses XFCE.
Scott: Now if you're already have like ubuntu installed you can apt-get install KDE desktop or oh I mean you can apt-get install kubuntu - desktop or Zubuntu - desktop.
Scott: So you can actually have all three of these things on one computer without having three separate operating systems.
Scott: Anyway in the new version of XFCE 4.4.
Scott: They added some new stuff.
Scott: First thing they added a new text editor, which is relevant to our show today Called mousepad and I haven't tried it so I can't say anything about it, but it looks pretty fun.
Scott: The other thing they added is they made this is funny because Rym just had a panel with a problem with this two seconds ago.
Scott: Is they made their panel more stable?
Scott: Goddamn, basically The way the panel used to work is like if a part of the panel would crash the whole thing would crash.
Scott: Now every part of the panel gets its own separate process and everything.
Scott: So if like you install a panel applet that kind of sucks and it crashes It'll just disappear and your panel will still be there and it'll be more stable and awesome.
Rym: It wasn't just my panel that crashed though.
Rym: It was pretty much everything.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what happened I just within your known panel.
Scott: Well, we got this.
Rym: I mean, it's the computer that with the $20 motherboard and just now before we did the show I booted it and Instead of booting like normal It's just one by one.
Rym: every single thing that started on boot crashed And I think if I'd let it keep going eventually everything would have crashed maybe.
Scott: But anyway, XFCE 4.4 is an awesome new version.
Scott: It has a lot of new features and bug fixes that I don't want to mention and You should definitely try.
Scott: if you're trying Linux.
Scott: You should at least try XFCE gnome and KDE to see which one you like best.
Scott: There are others out there, but Odds are if you are not a super nerd and super Linux master You're going to have a hard time using them because you won't have a clue what to do.
Rym: Actually, if you want to make a very customized but very not pretty One really really quickly and learn a lot about text editing config files Yeah, ice WM is a great way to go.
Scott: Yeah, I said, I don't know if that's still maintained.
Scott: I should go look that up.
Rym: I don't know either but I Before I left IBM I standardized them on that.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good one, especially when you need stability and users don't need to do too much.
Rym: Yeah good one.
Rym: I mean, honestly, I would still recommend ice WM if you're gonna make a grandma PC because it's just I don't know about that.
Scott: XFCE is pretty good for a grandma PC.
Rym: I mean remember cuz grandma if she's ever used a computer before then you can make it look exactly like Windows 98.
Scott: There's actually another desktop environment that looks exactly like Windows, but I forget what it's called.
Rym: Yeah, well, I mean you can make it look like it with the start menu But just don't add anything else to it.
Rym: So the start menu just has internet email.
Scott: Yeah, and mp3 player Yeah, anyway, the other big software release that just happened minutes ago is WordPress 2.1.
Scott: Oh, baby, you know what they got in this.
Scott: Oh, you're gonna like this.
Rym: What are they at?
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: I didn't even look at the changelog ready.
Scott: I'm not installing it on our servers yet.
Rym: install it on the test server.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna but you're gonna have to wait for the real server.
Scott: But anyway, you ready wanted to be in production.
Scott: now You're ready for this.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: first auto saving of drafts.
Rym: I will note that in the last year or give or take I have probably lost maybe 30 posts To timeouts or internet blips or whatnot.
Scott: So this is hotness with the Ajax number two better image upload Handling.
Scott: we don't do that too often But if you if you're the kind of person who makes blog posts with pictures in them It's real easy to just upload them from the WordPress interface without having to upload them manually by some other means and Something like that.
Scott: It can also like thumbnail them and all kinds of stuff for you.
Rym: You don't have to do much Depending on how we change up the website when we eventually update it.
Scott: Yep They've got a new Migrator thing.
Scott: So if you're upgrading from an old version of WordPress, it's easier to get to this new version.
Scott: Old plugins are might not work.
Rym: Oh, that's a great feature.
Scott: They're no longer supporting MySQL 3.23.
Scott: You have to use MySQL 4 or higher, which is probably something you should be doing.
Scott: Anyway, yeah The visual editing interface the rich text editor no longer sucks.
Rym: We'll see about that.
Scott: They've actually got two tabs visual and code instead of having the HTML code pop up.
Scott: Yeah, they it supposedly sucks.
Rym: now not I wonder if it'll work because I noticed something really weird about WordPress editing in that Box currently.
Rym: Mm-hmm if I use opera versus new Firefox versus old Firefox it behaves completely differently.
Scott: Yeah, it uses a thing right now.
Scott: It uses a thing called Tiny MCE and I don't know much about that thing, but it doesn't work.
Scott: Well, and they've they've updated the rich text editor significantly.
Scott: We'll test it on the test server to see how much better it is.
Scott: I actually become so frustrated with the old rich text editor that I stopped using it And I put the I turned off rich text editing in my options.
Rym: Yeah, I never did that just because it works as long as I use the one version of Firefox.
Rym: It seems to work.
Scott: Okay, you know, here's a big deal change already.
Scott: They've merged links and categories because they realize that Links are really only being used for like blog roles and that sort of silliness And there's not really a point.
Scott: so they just made links and categories the same kind of thing Uh-huh.
Scott: So what happens if you upgrade from an old WordPress?
Scott: They put all your links into the bra into the blog role category and that's it All right, then.
Scott: Yeah, so now it you know, there's no longer this weird.
Scott: Just you can't just make big lists of links for no reason you put them in categories.
Scott: there might be posts in those categories too and I think that's actually makes a lot more sense.
Scott: and can You could do a lot more interesting things.
Rym: Yeah, that's something I might want to poke around with just to see how they've done it and how we could make use of it.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty sure that's what we want.
Scott: Anyway, plus I really don't like a lot all those WordPress blogs that have just piles of links on the side.
Scott: Yeah, that's always such a like a low-class style.
Scott: It's like what are you doing, man?
Scott: I don't want that.
Rym: I mean what I don't mind.
Rym: and one of the ideas I've been tossing around and sketching for the site is You know some sites like penny arcade has the main thing and then each person can has but mega Tokyo is a good example.
Rym: Each person has like a little box where they say stuff.
Scott: Oh, it's a good idea.
Rym: Yeah, I'll show you the design I've been working on.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I had some idle time today.
Scott: I didn't think about that.
Scott: I can go for that.
Rym: Yeah, well big changes coming possibly.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see how well our ideas actually work on a website.
Rym: But in a situation like that, I see nothing wrong with each person having like a box in their box.
Rym: It's like my current hot link or whatever.
Rym: I've seen people do that too.
Scott: Okay effect Yeah, but I'm not a fan of like the links on their own.
Scott: like.
Scott: here's some sites You should check out.
Scott: then like ten links I like the ones where if you're gonna send me a link to something, right?
Scott: You should write a post and then link the words in the post like, you know, you're saying something.
Rym: Well, I mean it does depend on what you're doing.
Scott: Like if you're a webcomic and you are like affiliated or friends with ten other webcomics and you all put like an affiliate section I would just see in that kind of case What you would do is let's say you were all the same kind of webcomic, right?
Scott: You would make up something make a web ring.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, you don't make a web ring.
Scott: That's the old style.
Scott: what you do now for example a lot of podcasters are doing this is they say we're part of the so and so podcast network and then they set up another website for the podcast network and Everyone on their own podcast websites puts like a little badge.
Scott: I'll admit though that and in their podcast They say we're a member of the such-and-such podcast network.
Rym: a lot of people who do that.
Rym: if you google for their podcast You get the network page first and it's just confusing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that's I'm not notice how we haven't joined any podcast networks.
Rym: Well also because we dislike the vast majority of podcast.
Rym: I know but I mean pretty much the podcast we like are mostly the podcasts that we're friends with the people who do this.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know if it's if one causes the other or if it's just a coincidence or or what.
Rym: but
Scott: yeah another thing that WordPress has come out with in for in the newest version that someone might care about is There's a lot of privacy features where you can easily without, you know Editing robots dot text files make your blog private and keep it out of search engines and directories and all sorts of stuff.
Scott: So if you want to make a blog just for your family or just for your friends or you know Keep at the whole world from looking at it.
Scott: You can do that now with WordPress very easily Huh.
Scott: or as before that was slightly more difficult because you know anyone could read the blog but you know Only certain people could get into the posting interface now.
Scott: You can just keep everyone out of your blog.
Scott: make a private blog.
Rym: I Don't I don't.
Rym: I don't see many people doing that.
Rym: I don't think I don't see.
Scott: it says it even says pro bloggers Will not find this useful nor will most bloggers who desire expose.
Rym: Well, I mean there aren't many people out there who do a blog for any reason other than to get the word out to people They don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I guess other than the live journal types.
Scott: Mm-hmm But even useful though, like if you want like a shared Journal among.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I agree entirely, but I don't think many people think to do things like that.
Scott: No, this isn't gonna be a very widely used feature.
Scott: It's just an interesting fee.
Rym: Well, like the front row crew look at us we have I mean, no no, you can see it But you know, our forums are pretty cool.
Rym: inside of there.
Rym: We have our own private forums that we just use for our internal friendly business Mm-hmm, and we had a wiki for a while, but no one used it.
Scott: Yeah The other thing is there's some other changes to stuff under the hood for people who make plugins and themes and all that.
Scott: But you don't care about that stuff.
Rym: Not at all.
Scott: But yeah WordPress 2.1 the hotness.
Scott: if you're blogging you should jump on this because it came out just now two seconds ago.
Rym: Now before we get to the things today and all that one quick little meta bit of information for all you out there I see once again A lot of people are joining the forums and I noticed that a lot of the people who joined the forums never posted.
Rym: There's a good chance Like with many of the people who joined our forums that if you use hotmail or pretty much any non good email That our confirmation hotmail.
Rym: Yes our confirmation slash acceptance email that we sent to you was not received.
Rym: I can tell you all that I have not denied a single person entrance to the forums in the last two months.
Rym: Yeah, so if you didn't hear back from us if I log it into your account, it probably just works Yep, and you can start posting.
Scott: I remember I would be on the forums.
Scott: Someone would apply for membership.
Scott: I would approve it before they had even left the forums.
Scott: They were still there.
Scott: They just registered.
Scott: I can still see their name on the left side of the page.
Rym: Yeah, the only people I've ever denied access to were flaming geek 3.0 through 6.0.
Rym: Yeah Yeah Things of the day.
Rym: now, I might be a psychic.
Rym: So I'm gonna have to call Randy on this one.
Rym: You'll have to back me up on this.
Rym: I predict that Sylvia Brown is a fraud.
Scott: Well, that doesn't really count.
Scott: You're not predicting the future.
Scott: You're stating a fact about the present.
Rym: fine She will continue to be a fraud in the future.
Scott: Oh You know what gravity will Continue to function.
Rym: Well, you see the difference between these two claims is that the laws of thermodynamics will remain true.
Rym: No, the difference between these two claims is that we're not entirely sure if gravity will always work But we do know that Sylvia Brown will always be a fraud.
Rym: Now my news isn't that Sylvia Brown is a fraud.
Rym: nor is my thing of the day the fact that Sylvia Brown is a fraud.
Rym: That is common knowledge.
Rym: At least I wish it was common knowledge.
Rym: I pray every day that it would become common knowledge.
Scott: I don't think the pranks gonna help.
Rym: Well, no, I pray to the Sun and Joe Pesci.
Rym: Okay, but no the news that my thing of the day here is very simply probably the best debunking video of her.
Rym: yet You see she's been a consummate jackass for a long time.
Rym: A lot of people believe in this including Montel Williams.
Scott: I don't think he actually.
Scott: I don't know if he actually believes.
Scott: I think you know.
Scott: I just has nothing better to put in his boring ass daytime.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I submit that whether or not he believes has no bearing on the fact that he acts like he does in a public forum and Openly supports this BS.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: He's not a good dude in my book, but not at all.
Scott: No daytime talk people are good in my book.
Scott: unless somehow I got a daytime talk gig Then I would have the best daytime talk show ever.
Rym: You know, I think back to that old penny arcade where they gave gave a morning show.
Rym: Fuck you, it's early.
Scott: Fuck.
Rym: Yeah And then they can just like that just like that.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So she did some particularly assheadish things lately and this CNN bit is basically a compilation of the Consummate douchebag that is Sylvia Brown.
Scott: Yeah your kid that's missing.
Scott: Yeah, he died as Hispanic.
Scott: I killed him in the woods.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah now let's have the rescue workers search these woods for now.
Scott: What hours?
Scott: one based on some lady's guess.
Rym: I blame Sylvia Brown for you know, whatever I blame the police for even listening to this woman.
Rym: What the hell is wrong with that police department.
Scott: a lot of stupid police departments are there.
Scott: police are just people.
Scott: They're no smarter or dumber than anyone.
Rym: Yeah, all detectives are smarter, but the police should know better and if he doesn't he shouldn't be a police chief anymore.
Scott: Yeah, that really police chief.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I mean It's one thing a police chief might disagree on whether or not the drug war is a good thing or a police chief might disagree.
Rym: What constitutes a good interrogation of a suspect?
Rym: But there shouldn't be any debate among police chiefs as to whether or not psychics can find kidnap people.
Rym: Yeah, the answer is no.
Scott: Hey, I could find one better.
Scott: You know, I'll do.
Rym: I guess I'm sensing a triangle like some kind of triangle shape near where you're going to find the body some kind of tall maybe.
Rym: a tree Starts with a T triangle trapezoid train tracks Something with a T like that.
Rym: see where I'm going.
Scott: trap.
Scott: Yeah, so this is actually a pretty cool video.
Scott: You ever been on an airplane need to look out the window and you look at the wing and the wing just kind of goes Wobble wobble wobble wobble, you know and you go whoa, it's sometimes in this turbulence The wing goes wobble wobble wobble wobble wobble wobble wobble and you go Whoa, look at that wing flapping around like that.
Rym: I remember the first time I flew with Cessna and the whole plane did that.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, no But like the first few times I flew and I'd look out at the wing and I would see it flapping and be like whoa Is the way you know?
Scott: Cuz you look at a wing on a big commercial jet.
Scott: when it's on the ground and it's a big metal wing You're like if you jumped and like tried to hang on it with your hands.
Scott: It wouldn't move.
Scott: It's like a big piece of metal with a bajillion bolts in it.
Scott: It ain't going anywhere.
Scott: Well, apparently turbulence and jet engine speeds are fast enough to make a wing bounce around.
Scott: Well, just how much can that wing bounce around?
Scott: What if the turbulence is so crazy, you know The wings got a break sometime now, I guess.
Rym: more importantly How do you figure out the point at which the wing will break?
Rym: and apparently the answer is the same answer that?
Rym: Calvin's dad gives to him as to how they figure out how much weight a bridge can hold.
Scott: Yep So they made a Boeing 777 and they tied a bunch of cables and shit to the wing and they bent the wing until it broke.
Scott: and They had a prediction for when they thought the wing would break.
Scott: and they discovered the reality for when the ring would break.
Scott: I will leave those to be a mystery.
Scott: You can watch the video.
Scott: You can watch them.
Scott: bend this wing until it breaks and then you will probably have a lot of confidence about flying Unless you're one of those stupid people who are afraid of flying in commercial jets.
Scott: cuz you're the pussy I don't know.
Scott: There's nothing to be afraid of.
Scott: freaking flying Goddamn depends on what airline.
Rym: if I'm flying out of I don't know Mogadishu.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah Okay, the only airline you have to worry about is oh, what's that come?
Scott: What's that country in Dilbert?
Scott: Oh albonia albonian Airlines you have to worry but a Commercial jet in the United States.
Scott: I Worry about it.
Rym: No, is it just me?
Rym: or is Dilbert not been funny for the last like five years?
Scott: Dilbert is funny once every four months.
Scott: I've discovered.
Rym: Ah, so that's the current period.
Scott: Well, actually since I have like a Dilbert tear-off calendar and I read Dilbert on the website.
Scott: It's funny once every other month until you get repeats But it's a you don't remember Dilbert.
Scott: So it's if it's a reef.
Rym: I remember all the Dilbert I read.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: well the thing is I remember how they remember the memorable ones.
Rym: I remember each archetypical joke.
Rym: Just like I know.
Rym: I remember every single Garfield ever.
Scott: Oh, well Garfield.
Scott: It's the same thing Isn't it?
Scott: It's time again one day.
Rym: I'm tired.
Rym: I like lasagna But dog off the table, there's normal.
Rym: John Arbuckle is gay.
Scott: You can't get a woman.
Rym: They got that guy?
Scott: Yeah, yeah Right.
Rym: So this might sound like a strange topic But it's something that a lot of people don't actually have much experience with and also we're tired.
Rym: So this is a nice quick one.
Rym: You see a lot of people edit text very often yet They never really think about what kind of text editor they use or they never think about what?
Rym: Text editing really means or how certain tasks in text editing could possibly be done more efficiently.
Scott: Yeah, there are many many things that do a text editing.
Scott: So we're just gonna talk about text editing now at first.
Rym: before anything we really have to clarify that text editing and Layout and design are entirely different things.
Scott: Well word processing desktop publishing text editing These are all very different things, even though to the layman they might seem to be the same thing.
Rym: Yeah cuz I mean you use Microsoft Word and what does it show?
Rym: you shows you a piece of paper with a cursor on it and It shows you what font you're using and how big that font is and some margins and all this business.
Rym: So you're you're creating your content your text Simultaneously you're creating your layout you're creating your style You're creating every aspect of that document in real time all at the same time.
Rym: Yep, now a lot of people have complained that.
Rym: you know, sometimes it's confusing, you know I want to just write my essay But I spend 10 minutes looking at fonts and then I think about the word art I want to put in and and then I hit enter and it doesn't.
Rym: it makes a weird paragraph.
Rym: I didn't want it to and I have to back up and try to make it.
Rym: undo that.
Rym: That's because you're trying to make text in something that is designed to do something far different than just make text.
Scott: Yeah, well, actually if you're writing a paper, you should be using a word processor.
Scott: You should just also learn how to use it.
Scott: So that doesn't happen to you More and more.
Rym: I prefer to write documents just straight-up text demarcated by paragraph and then I formatted later.
Scott: Yeah, that's alright.
Scott: But anyway a text editor is something very different from word processor.
Scott: All it does is write text files.
Scott: a text file is basically just a big long string of characters.
Scott: Some of those characters are the new line character.
Scott: so that's how you get multiple lines of text, but it's really just a big long line of letters and spaces and Punctuation marks and new lines and carriage returns and all those sorts of things
Rym: all encoded in like ASCII or Unicode But you don't need to care about that.
Scott: Yeah, you know that that's not important.
Scott: So Basically, hey if you're not trying to you know, make margins or italics or bold sir or anything like that You need to put text into a file a text file for which there are many many uses that you will discuss.
Scott: There's a lot of ways to do that.
Rym: Yeah for most of you who use Windows probably the the text editor you have the most experience with is Notepad dot exe.
Scott: Yeah, notepad dot exe is.
Scott: There's a lot of notepad clones out there.
Rym: Yes there every program like that is the same.
Scott: Yeah I mean it works like a word processor.
Scott: So if you're used to using a word processor, you're used to using notepad.
Scott: It just doesn't let you do anything.
Scott: that is text files can't do.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you think about.
Rym: you can set word wrap in the text editor But that doesn't actually do anything to your document.
Scott: All that does is wrap the text around in your window in real time So that you can see all the letters without them going off the edge.
Rym: Yeah Because anything other than the letters you're typing and the punctuation you're typing all of that is basically metadata.
Rym: That's kind of irrelevant to the actual data you're putting in the actual content of the words.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, so there's notepad.
Scott: Nope, there's a lot of other notepad clones out there too.
Rym: now the reason this matters in one big respect aside from you know semantics and aside from not distracting yourself from your task at hand is very simply that if you're writing a dot like a File that a computer is going to read a text file is just that.
Rym: what you are typing is exactly what is in that text file Encoded but in something like I don't know write dot exe or Microsoft Word or open office.
Rym: if you're typing and you save a file It doesn't just save the string of text It saves all of this other information in that file saying, you know, all the formatting all the fonts all the whatever.
Rym: So if a computer tries to read that it has to know exactly how that file was created in order to get the data out of it.
Rym: This is a problem.
Scott: if you want to edit say your operating systems hosts dot text And you use Microsoft Office Yeah, I mean technically Microsoft Word can edit and create text files and things But it does them like a word processor.
Scott: It doesn't do them.
Rym: It's very easy to mess up a text document and make it not just a text.
Scott: Just opening it and then saving it again with Word will probably screw it up Depending on older versions of Word are more notorious for that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what other kind could there possibly be another text editor that isn't notepad or doesn't work exactly like notepad?
Scott: Why would you use something that doesn't work like notepad?
Scott: notepad is just fine.
Scott: Well, there are two major other ones.
Scott: There is the Emacs ones and the VI ones mostly vim vi Improved which is vim.
Rym: Yeah, but most people just refer to all of those just VI.
Rym: Yes, the differences are not noticeable to the average person.
Rym: No, they're not even noticeable really to me.
Scott: I noticed there's a VI in vim, but I would never use VI.
Scott: so it doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, I use VI once when I was fixing on some terrible old Unix system.
Scott: Yeah, so what is Emacs?
Scott: Well Emacs does kind of work like notepad, you know it's.
Scott: you type things in a box and you push enter and you a normal person could open Emacs and start typing in it, however Emacs they often joke about it.
Scott: It's like It's a great operating system with a bad text editor.
Scott: I mean Emacs is so is full of all sorts of commands and it it's basically so loaded with fancy features for Open-source people and such that it could do anything.
Scott: You can play Tetris in Emacs.
Scott: I kid you not.
Rym: Yes I was I will say from my perspective Unless you if you were the kind of person who would need Emacs you probably already know about Emacs.
Rym: Yeah, if you don't know what we're talking about, you probably don't need Emacs ever.
Scott: Emacs is very popular among those people that we often don't like who are like super open-source.
Scott: It's also popular among the people who are open-source and don't like VI.
Rym: Yep Yeah, it is not popular among Rym.
Scott: Yes I used to use it, but I know you used to use it.
Scott: I don't use it anymore.
Rym: I used to poke fun at it.
Scott: Yeah Emacs, you know, I don't know what it is about Emacs.
Scott: It seems like it has its place and it is an eternal battle between Emacs users and VI users.
Scott: you know that I remember a funny comic where there were like Two guys on the beach and there was you know, it was the classic, you know surf dudes you have big muscles and you know hot girls and bikinis on the beach and It's a two-frame comic and there's even a one-frame comic I don't remember.
Scott: but one guy Punches the other guy right in the face and he says take that you Emacs user and the hot girl on the beach goes.
Scott: John I always knew you were real VI man.
Rym: But anyway, we don't really.
Rym: I mean VI for most of you is the same kind of things.
Rym: you look at it and think wow This has got a lot of stuff in it that I don't understand.
Scott: Well, the thing about VI is it is fundamentally different from every other text editor that I know of in Every way imaginable.
Scott: if a normal person opened up VI they wouldn't even know how to begin typing because let alone how to turn it.
Scott: Yeah, you they wouldn't know how to save and quit.
Scott: You wouldn't know how to do anything.
Rym: Yeah I mean just in examples you realize here say you want to type something you hit I and then you start typing.
Rym: Say you want it.
Scott: also hit a row or capital.
Rym: O now say any other letters, but those all do slightly different things.
Scott: They do they do.
Rym: indeed now Let's say you want to save your file and exit you hit escape.
Rym: you hit shift colon then you type Wq, then you hit enter Yeah, that will write your file out W and then quit Q. Yeah, now that might sound obtuse but it's actually a very Highly useful and highly sophisticated system if you're willing to put forth the time to learn it.
Scott: Yes, VI is what we call a modal editor Which means it has more than one mode.
Scott: by when you open VI it's in command mode.
Scott: when you're in command mode Every button on the entire keyboard is a command.
Scott: so I isn't the letter I it's the insert command.
Scott: You know P will be the paste command.
Scott: X is delete the current character and I shouldn't talk so much.
Rym: I actually haven't used VI since I left IBM.
Scott: Yeah, why?
Scott: why is copy?
Scott: Why?
Scott: 5y is copy five lines, you know.
Scott: and DD is delete the current line.
Scott: There's all like.
Scott: d5d is delete from here five lines down.
Scott: and that's when you type commands in command mode Which is the mode you enter when you first turn on VI.
Rym: now the commands can get incredibly complex.
Rym: I mean you can use expressions to do such things as find every instance of a certain expression and modify it slightly.
Scott: Yeah there you can do almost anything in command mode of VI that you would ever want to do to a text file.
Scott: now Certain commands will bring you into Insert mode or typing mode or whatever you want to call it, which is where you type.
Scott: So if you push I to insert then wherever the cursor is right now It'll turn into a little stick and you could just start typing now But typing your document and now you want to enter a command so you have to go back to command mode.
Scott: So you push escape.
Scott: you see how there's two modes of VI.
Scott: in one mode Every button on the entire keyboard is a special command and in the other mode You just type like you're typing and you push escape and then a bunch of commands.
Scott: all you know.
Scott: Escape will get you back to command mode and there are a bunch of commands that will bring you back to typing mode.
Scott: Now who in their right mind would use something like this when you could just use notepad which is so much easier?
Scott: now It might seem I want to get this.
Scott: I want to make sure everyone understands what I'm about to say.
Rym: Complexity and simple versus that whole thing.
Scott: I want to talk about how VI is actually Easier.
Scott: as long as you interpret easy in the correct way.
Scott: VI is not easier to learn than notepad.
Scott: VI is Easier to use than notepad if you have learned it.
Scott: Let's say you know nothing about VI at all.
Scott: Well notepad you'll be able to type and VI you won't so you'll want to kill yourself if you ever have to use VI.
Scott: Now let's say you do know how to use VI and you do know how to use notepad.
Scott: Notepad is now a nightmare because there are things in VI which you would be able to do With like pushing three buttons whereas in notepad you would have to like press a bajillion buttons And it would take you forever.
Rym: Yep, and some things you might want to do.
Rym: a notepad There's just no way to do it automatically.
Rym: You would have to you know, like copy and paste and copy and paste and copy.
Scott: Have you ever been editing a document ever where you have had to go copy paste copy paste copy paste like a bunch of times And then edit each different like Pasting like a little bit like you paste change a number paste change a number in that one paste change a number.
Scott: if you ever Done anything like that?
Scott: Guess what if you knew how to use VI You could have done all that and saved an hour of work by typing one line of text and pushing enter.
Rym: now This might not be something you'd care about.
Rym: I mean Let's say you occasionally have to do this for like five little things like you have to do a weird copy paste backspace 12345 thing five times on a document every now and then.
Rym: then yeah It's still probably not worth your time to learn VI and use it.
Rym: But let's say you have to do that to a thousand page document or you have to do it to a five page document every day for an hour.
Rym: That's when VI really starts to shine.
Rym: you can do extremely powerful things with just a few quick commands.
Scott: Here's an example of something I did with VI just yesterday.
Scott: actually you said also, but that's not the point I was making a metador.
Scott: I was working on the DVD for the podcast and there's gonna be a little website on the DVD to let you browse the DVD.
Rym: Yeah, it's really cool-looking.
Scott: Yeah, and I had to make links to all the episodes.
Scott: now I made links to all the episodes by writing a little program that outputted the.
Scott: you know the links now.
Scott: I forgot that the episodes are numbered.
Scott: 2-0-0 Number number number number number there.
Rym: Yep, so he'd put them in as all Number number number number number number.
Rym: the 2-0 in the year 2-0-0-7 was left out of the version he was working.
Scott: Yeah, so for example at what's today's episode?
Scott: today's episode is oh six.
Rym: Oh seven.
Rym: All right Oh 7-0-1-2-2.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So today's episode is oh 7-0-1-2-2.
Scott: I hit and the mp3.
Scott: the file name of the mp3 will be 2007. oh 7-0-1-2-2. so I in VI I needed to add a 20 to the beginning of every file name of an mp3.
Scott: So I told VI hey VI look through and every time you see six digits followed by a dot followed by mp3 take whatever that is.
Scott: take those six digits that dot in that mp3 and put a 20 before them.
Scott: and That was I don't know like a very very small command.
Scott: It wasn't even like a line as maybe 20 characters and I typed it in and I pushed enter and it went through Not just my document, but all the documents that I had to change this in.
Scott: and boom immediately They were all changed and fixed the end because I took the time to learn VI.
Scott: Now we're gonna tell we're not just talking about VI We're gonna talk about text editors as a whole.
Rym: but so then the real question is very simply why would you even want to bother?
Rym: Writing flat text files like this ever when you could just do all the layout and everything at once and We'll ignore the argument of you're not distracted by the layout because some people might not be distracted by the layout stuff in Word.
Rym: Well, we have.
Rym: we have many more arguments than just that.
Scott: Yes There are many times where text editing is the only way to go.
Scott: most of them involve When you're writing something that a computer is going to read and not something that a human is going to read like I think.
Rym: earlier I mentioned that ice WM.
Rym: you can modify it very heavily with just editing text files.
Rym: The way ice WM works is when widgets get loaded or whatever, you know A thing appears on the screen.
Rym: all the instructions as to how those things appear on the screen are contained in text files.
Rym: so you can go into a text file that would define what icons are used on your start menu and Change the values in the text file.
Rym: and then when you restart ice WM It'll change those things in your thing because it'll look at the text file see icon dots as whatever And it'll use that instead of the one he was doing before.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it mostly in Linux but also in other operating systems including Windows, you know You're used.
Scott: you're probably used to using programs with graphical user interfaces where when you want to change the options you go edit preferences or tools options and there's all your options and you check boxes and radio buttons and text boxes.
Scott: and that's how you Configure your programs and change the settings on various things.
Scott: you go to your control panel or whatever.
Scott: Well, a lot of programs out there in fact, probably most programs out there if they have options at all Those options are just in text files like Apache.
Scott: if you want to change the web server, you know, there's no GUI.
Scott: I mean, there's some GUIs you can install that will basically allow you to you know Change the settings on Apache with you know, some buttons and some text boxes.
Scott: But all those really do is they're just programs which convert the GUI things that you do Into the text file and if you really want to do whatever Apache wants you to do and configure it properly You need to open the Apache configuration files with a text editor and edit them.
Rym: now There are a lot of reasons programs do this.
Rym: I mean one.
Rym: a text file is very easily read Very easy.
Rym: It's a very simple thing.
Rym: It's a commonly known standard.
Rym: Anyone can edit one without any trouble.
Rym: To say it's a program that has thousands and thousands of possible options.
Rym: Your GUI would now have thousands and thousands of little lines with little radio boxes next to them.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you really think about all the possible Configurations of an Apache web server.
Scott: It's basically infinity.
Scott: You can configure the thing to do anything and as a complex language That's in order to configure it.
Scott: You know, you have little curly braces and there's all sorts of different commands you can give to it and stuff You could configure it to just provide a Java Tetris game no matter what.
Rym: Yeah Nothing else.
Scott: you could configure the Apache web server in so many different ways and that is because instead of having some simple GUI Preferences window they have a text file.
Scott: you edit the text file and that's it And you could put anything you want in there according to the documentation.
Scott: That's something actually a lot of people who are new to Linux ever don't understand.
Scott: is Yeah, if you want to configure that you have to edit a text file.
Rym: I mean even back in RIT when I was taking early IT classes and there would be people in a class who the lab would say like Build a simple Samba server and then go to the config and configure it to do X. now Not only did they not know to look in ETC Samba Which might have been the first problem.
Rym: Yeah, but they were asking questions like so, where's the configuration program?
Rym: Or how do I open the configurator or the?
Rym: how do I open the thing?
Rym: That'll configure it and the professor's really had a hard time explaining.
Rym: No, you just edit it Like what do you mean edit it?
Scott: There's a text file with all the options in it and it actually in that text file has comments which explain the options.
Rym: Yeah, I mean most open source programs that are worth a hill of beans will give you a sample configuration file that includes in it like commented out instructions like if you want this kind of widget then uncomment the following line.
Rym: if you want this kind of widget uncomment the following line and Change your value here to the value you want things like that.
Rym: They're usually very easy to work with.
Rym: the problem is you have to actually read Which a lot of people either aren't willing to do or don't realize they have to do.
Scott: Yeah if you're planning on using Linux even if you're using a nice easy Linux like Ubuntu or something and you're never gonna have to Edit a configuration file in your life.
Scott: You should still learn how to edit the X dot X or configuration file Even if you never have to do it because eventually you're gonna have to do it.
Scott: You might have to do it and if you don't it could be devastating if you don't know what to do.
Scott: So you should learn that no matter what even if you never run into it You'll it'll be.
Scott: it's worth it to know and also just to learn how to edit configuration files.
Scott: The other time you probably want to use text editor.
Scott: besides editing configuration files is writing source code.
Scott: I mean, you don't see people writing programs, you know, if I'm writing code in C I'm not writing C code in Microsoft Word.
Scott: that doesn't work.
Scott: You write it in a text editor.
Scott: and if that text editor has lots of advanced features like VI or an editor emac or like Ultra edit.
Scott: Yeah, all those things or any of those fancy text editors.
Scott: It suddenly becomes a lot easier to write source code.
Rym: Yeah, I mean imagine you're writing code.
Rym: So you you know, you have open parens all over the place, you know open parentheses and open carrots things like that.
Rym: what if you had a text editor that would look and see if Every open you had had an equivalent closed and it would mark in red any that weren't closed.
Rym: It'd be real easy to track down that missing semicolon then.
Scott: Yeah, it's like and when I type a closed parenthesis There's a little.
Scott: it lights up the parenthesis the open parenthesis that I just closed so I can make sure that I'm still going straight.
Scott: Also a lot of languages have you know.
Scott: indentation.
Scott: that's important like Python Where indentation is the most important thing and if the text editor is smart and not crappy as notepad It'll keep that indentation correct for you automatically.
Scott: You won't have to be like enter tab tab tab enter tab tab tab, you know it'll.
Scott: just when you push enter that's in the tabs in the right spot and languages that indent based on curly brace like you'll put the closed curly brace and it'll Untab it for you and put it back where it belongs.
Scott: and when you push enter you'll be on the next line in the correct Spot and it's all happy times.
Rym: so the very least I hope.
Rym: in the future if you're ever writing a document and you're using Microsoft Word at least think a minute and Consider the possibility that maybe there's a better tool for what you're trying to do at the moment.
Scott: yeah, also if you're happen to be learning Linux or anything or you know using any sort of application that might have a text Configuration file or maybe you just want to learn something about computers because you don't know anything You should learn how to edit a text configuration file.
Scott: Yeah for some sort of programming in every program the configuration files look different But that's an essential skill of computing and it probably always will be.
Scott: Oh You should learn VI even if it's hard and it seems annoying and there's no point to it Even if you don't learn the advanced stuff.
Rym: I mean even people who use VI all the time don't know everything about VI.
Rym: I know like half the stuff about VI but in the very least Partly because you might someday run into an old computer or a computer where X isn't working and VI is the only thing on there.
Scott: Yeah, that's one thing that's true is VI will run on any computer ever pretty much, you know.
Scott: Even if you come across the oldest most broken computer in the entire universe You'll be able to use VI.
Scott: and if you can use VI you can do anything.
Rym: and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.