Rym: It's Tuesday February 20th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: We're back from Katsucon and boy are our voices tired.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: ah We're finally back from Katsucon.
Rym: god damn It was a fantastic con.
Rym: We're totally exhausted.
Rym: Expect my voice to sound weird for the next couple days as I recover.
Scott: Yeah, we finally figured out those roads near northern Jersey right you know west of New York City.
Scott: How all they all work.
Rym: yeah in other words We figured out how to get out of Jersey Quickly the quickest way possible as opposed to the slow and inefficient way, but no the con was great.
Rym: We're absolutely exhausted.
Rym: We missed last night's show as we'll talk about later, but more importantly Welcome to all of our new listeners.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder how many new people are actually gonna start listening who met us at Katsucon so very interested.
Rym: So of course we're not gonna do this really ever again.
Rym: But we figured since we know we have a lot of new listeners We should at least go over a little bit of what this business all is in case they couldn't figure it out from the CDs Which we ran out of immediately yeah?
Scott: Well anyone who picked up the flyer instead of the CD is probably gonna need some help.
Scott: the CD had help on it.
Rym: well It's Tuesday night, so it is a gaming day where we talk about games.
Scott: You know video games board games all that sort of stuff role-playing games Not really so much card games, but yeah, whatever we're playing at the time is usually what we're gonna talk about.
Rym: yeah But GeekNights in general is four different nights with four effectively different shows every night Just with the same format about a different topic.
Scott: yep, so if you listen to the show tomorrow night It's gonna be about anime manga or comics.
Rym: and more importantly if you listen to it tomorrow because it's about anime manga and comics We're going to actually cover Katsucon tonight.
Rym: We're just talking about the gaming at Katsucon.
Scott: yep Thursday You never know what it's gonna be and Monday.
Scott: It's usually computers and technology and slash that type of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, and of course It's a podcast so no one's forcing you to listen on any particular day.
Scott: So even though we make the video game show on Tuesday night You might listen to it on Saturday or Monday or who knows when.
Rym: yep now We're not gonna explain how podcasts work because you got this far, so you've obviously figured something out.
Rym: But in general tonight is going to be not mostly a standard episode just because we are tired.
Rym: I threw the equipment back together hastily after getting back from the con and instead of doing our normal topical thing We're just gonna kind of talk about the con until we get tired of talking about it.
Rym: That sounds kind of fun Yeah, so I'd recommend if you're new to the show Search for a topic you're interested in or browse through the archives.
Rym: I almost guarantee you'll find an episode about something you care about.
Scott: yeah There's like two more almost 300 episodes in there.
Scott: There has to be an episode that we've done That you'll be interested in and then you can decide if you like the show or not.
Rym: based on that yeah And starting either probably Thursday, or maybe next week.
Rym: We'll get back into our normal nightly groove
Scott: yep,
Rym: but anyway We'll be really quick about the news because I still want to go to bed and rest my throat for one more night And because I don't know how long we're gonna talk about Katsucon gaming since it was totally awesome, and I have a lot of awesome things to say about it.
Scott: Yeah, we don't want the episode to go too long, so let's do the news real quick ready go all right.
Rym: So real real real briefly as I can expound and go on and trade.
Rym: No so apparently Nintendo has said that they have not entirely ruled out the possibility of releasing.
Rym: Translated Japanese were only games on the virtual console in the United States.
Rym: earthbound Not just earthbound.
Rym: there's a lot of games I want Desperately.
Scott: well, I'm gonna use one talk about something as my thing today, but it's not really a Nintendo game.
Scott: So don't expect it on the virtual account.
Rym: yeah, so obviously this isn't news that it's happened yet.
Rym: But the fact that Nintendo didn't come out and say no is kind of significant because Nintendo is one of the few gaming companies where?
Rym: They say exactly What they mean.
Scott: yeah if they're.
Scott: if it's no They'll just say no.
Rym: Yep, like the when the GameCube came out or that not the GameCube the Wii the Wii they were talking about.
Rym: you know How much is gonna cost and way back they said it will cost no more than two hundred and fifty dollars.
Scott: And guess how much it cost.
Rym: it cost exactly two hundred and fifty dollars.
Scott: I think it cost maybe two forty nine ninety nine.
Rym: I'm not something like that.
Rym: So like that when Nintendo when they don't lie they they might be deceitful by saying something that is perfectly true But might mislead you, but they whatever they say is always exactly what they said.
Rym: yep, which shouldn't be an issue.
Rym: But there are companies like Sony out there, so we got it.
Scott: They're like us.
Scott: They say what they mean anyway.
Scott: So for anyone who's worried that Capcom may or may not release more Phoenix, right in the United States You should probably be less worried.
Scott: They're having a contest.
Scott: It's on the official Capcom forums in the United States.
Scott: one of the administrators posted rules for a contest full official rules and the contest basically says Convince Capcom to release Phoenix Wright 3 in the US and win a prize.
Scott: I didn't really read all the details of the contest because I have no interest in entering But it gives hope that Phoenix Wright is more of it is on the way.
Rym: if I had a video camera I would be very interested in entering.
Rym: I imagine we could put forth some sort of Horrid video that would force them to recognize the awesomeness of us and of this game coming out here.
Scott: That could very well be true.
Scott: But yeah, I mean the fourth Phoenix Wright, which doesn't actually have Phoenix Wright in it.
Scott: They changed the main character is coming out in Japan pretty much right now.
Scott: So if we get the third one, we're just about caught up.
Rym: Yeah I mean I'm playing through the second one.
Rym: finally now and I actually had to spend most of Katsucon Surrounded by cool people who are cooler than me because they've already played the game Pretty much just gushing about it while I had to sit there and go.
Scott: Whose fault is that?
Scott: I played it real quick.
Scott: You could have played it just as quick as me and been done already.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I have a job.
Scott: Oh, right Not working until March 1st, right?
Rym: Yeah, see I can't even use the dig if yeah captain jobless.
Rym: But the only reason you don't have a job is because you quit your job to get a better job.
Rym: that doesn't start right away.
Scott: It's good times in the life of Scott right now.
Rym: things of the day Now there's not much in this world I like more than Mario and Mario related paraphernalia, but there's not much more in this world I dislike than Dragon Ball Z GT.
Scott: whatever Man, like Dragon Ball Z. I mean it's one of the most popular anime in the US but Popularity is so far away from what isn't even still that popular.
Rym: I wonder how popular it actually is.
Scott: It's a good question because it was super pop.
Scott: It was Naruto popular maybe Five to ten years ago, I don't know back when the only anime on TV was that and Sailor Moon Yeah, but the current popularity of Dragon Ball Z that's tough.
Scott: It's real tough to say.
Rym: Regardless someone decided to take Mario and Dragon Ball Z and kind of mash them together in that way I like to do on the internet.
Rym: So, uh, I'm not gonna talk much about it because I want to get right into Katsu Kan.
Rym: But I suggest you watch this video and I will say that while it is parodying Dragon Ball Z It does distill about 12 episodes worth of this into about a minute and a half.
Scott: Yeah, the video Rym is linking to is like sort of a trailer thing for Mario Ball Z.
Rym: don't actually watch Mario Ball Z. It's not funny.
Scott: They've actually made episodes of Mario Ball Z like they've made episode 1 so far, but Scott tried to sell me on.
Rym: I'm like check them out.
Rym: They're an awesome funny parody.
Scott: Well, no, I wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't that funny But it's the.
Rym: the production quality of the animations and the effort put into it is obviously more than other mashups that involve sprites Yeah, but all they had to do was make this trailer and it was good enough by actually going through with the project.
Rym: It's almost a minus minus in my book.
Scott: Yeah I think the problem with going through with the project is that they actually copied Dragon Ball Z too well and the problems of Dragon Ball Z show through in the final work.
Rym: Well, they also just go really really slowly But without any dialogue or anything and there's no voice acting per se.
Rym: so it's really just kind of a slow Plotting boring thing to watch.
Rym: at least Dragon Ball is music and people yelling This had it.
Scott: You just didn't see those parts, but that doesn't know cuz it was all just text.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: It is slow boring text that was on the screen way too long All right.
Scott: Anyway, there was a Sega Saturn game that I heard of a while ago and I you know, totally forgot about it.
Scott: But the reason I heard of it is because Famitsu, which is pretty much the number one gaming magazine in all of Japan It's like the gaming authority in Japan.
Scott: They had sort of a reader's poll on best games ever.
Scott: I think it might have been in 2005 or something.
Rym: Yeah, we were actually looking at this at Katsu Con.
Scott: Yeah, well cuz I was reminded of it at Katsu Con.
Scott: So I looked it up because we had internets there, which was lucky.
Scott: and Yeah, this game was like I can't remember exactly which how it was ranked But it was like the number three game ever in Japan according to readers voting on Famitsu.
Rym: now considering that we'd heard of all These other games like yeah Dragon Quest whatever Final Fantasy, whatever this game never heard of that.
Scott: Yeah Imagine if the number three game ever was not in the US was not available in Japan Like you couldn't buy Zelda 1 in Japan only in US.
Rym: So what the hell is this game?
Scott: It's apparently a game called machi and It's for the Sega Saturn in Japan only god damn it text heavy.
Scott: I assume
Rym: how many Sega Saturn games are there that we'll never get to play
Scott: plenty and it's sort of Can't really tell exactly what kind of game it is, but I'm pretty sure it's an adventure Story kind of game that
Rym: would
Scott: probably be right up our alley possibly with Yakuza action Although I can't really tell so,
Rym: you know at this point because I know I can't ever play the game.
Rym: I'm just going to assume that there's Yakuza action because it seems to me that Japan is this Conspiracy to prevent Yakuza action from getting into my hands.
Scott: Yeah, you know what else?
Scott: I recently discovered that this game machi had a re-release on the PSP in Japan.
Scott: making owning a PSP in Japan worth it if you know Japanese.
Rym: So maybe if I get a PSP and then I mod it and then I get this game in Japan And then I sit there with Emily and make her translate it all for me I might get some Yakuza action.
Scott: You could play what is quite possibly one of the top 10 games ever made that will never ever ever be available in English barring Someone crazy with a lot of money.
Scott: see the thing very nice.
Rym: There are people out there who translated the utenna game for the Sega Saturn.
Rym: We just haven't bothered to actually try to emulate it.
Scott: It's all you.
Rym: hey, I'm all about that so far.
Rym: now There's two reasons for me to learn enough Japanese to play Sega Saturn games.
Scott: well Go for it.
Scott: And if you succeed, let's play some machi because I really want to play this goddamn game.
Rym: But that's enough thing of the day because we have plenty to talk about in the actual show since as you all should know we Were at Katsucon over the weekend.
Rym: Well, it's the lack of a Monday show.
Scott: Yeah, well we were planning on doing a Monday show But then we realized that would have meant we had to unpack all the equipment and set it up again Which I only set back up less than an hour ago.
Rym: Yeah it takes a while to plug in all those wires and clean up the mess and move shit around and not to mention the fact that Scott's voice was a little scratchy and mine was about ten times more scratchy than it is now.
Scott: Yeah, I think mine is pretty much back to the way it was but yours is still a little a yeah I need another day of recovery.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, well, of course.
Rym: I shot.
Scott: it's not Otakon bed.
Scott: So we're alright.
Rym: I shouted a lot more than you.
Rym: my rampart tournament ended up being quite competitive with a lot of people in it.
Rym: Yeah, my Street Fighter tournament was mighty quick Partly cuz Street Fighter was broken and two because it's a really really really bad game.
Scott: I know that's why I had a tournament in it cuz it's so bad.
Rym: Yeah, we'll talk about that though.
Rym: But firstly well tonight We were talking just about the Katsucon game room game katsu and all things related to that.
Rym: tomorrow We will be talking about Katsucon as a whole our actual experiences at the con Outside of the gaming room since today's gaming day and tomorrow is anime manga comics day.
Rym: Yep Well
Scott: for those of you don't know Katsucon sort of weird with its gaming compared to other At least other anime conventions and that they have a sort of section It's like half of the convention almost called game katsu and it's sort of like its own gaming Convention within the bigger Katsucon convention.
Rym: Well, the thing is most other large cons are run generally like that where they'll have a department head for each area and they're largely Autonomous and they interface with each other to get stuff done.
Rym: Katsucon isn't special in that regard.
Rym: It's just special in that it seems as though the head of the game department has as much Discretion as an entire convention where at some other cons.
Rym: I don't think it's quite to that scale.
Scott: yeah, it's almost as if there's these different conventions going on like.
Scott: each department is its own convention and They only work with each other, you know when it's absolutely necessary like a super confederate Convention which is perfectly fine because it is perfectly fun.
Rym: Katsucon is a great con.
Rym: It's what it's probably my second or third favorite con period.
Scott: yeah after going to it I can definitely say it was a pretty awesome despite a few shortcomings here and there.
Scott: but you know, no one's perfect.
Rym: But yeah, Aaron the head of game katsu who basically set us up in the front of the video game room Well, it was broken him in two.
Rym: We'll talk about all that in a bit.
Rym: How was actually set up?
Rym: but we were set up at a table in the front and we basically were hooked into the PA System through this crazy mixer configuration.
Scott: with are we gonna even talk about how?
Scott: with
Rym: the live DJ next to us and all the music and some of the video games spliced in and We basically whenever the DJ wasn't, you know, actually mixing live with this awesome digital vinyl mixing system We were just playing music talking to the crowd and generally hanging out for most of the con.
Scott: Yep We also spent a lot of time sitting there promoting GeekNights and running tournaments and giving away prizes and talking to people.
Rym: We didn't really do much to promote GeekNights.
Scott: Well, we try.
Scott: we gave away those CDs.
Scott: The thing is they ran out so fast.
Scott: as soon as I fixed our free CD sign to be more prominent Those things flew.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And once we got our friend I know to draw us a funny little.
Rym: hey come up and take stuff.
Rym: Pretty much everything disappeared.
Scott: Yeah, and then we put a sign that said come to the match game and that totally worked also.
Scott: So people are definitely paying attention to what we were doing.
Rym: Yeah so basically we just sat there and it was Kind of like how we would go at other cons if we had an artist alley table and we could just kind of park behind it whenever there's nothing else to do.
Rym: but Because Katsucon we were so prominent and too because the video game room was so happening 24/7 throughout the whole con we were basically in the thick of it at all times.
Scott: Yeah Imagine if instead of your artist alley table being in the middle of artist alley with everyone else's table You certainly had like your own special table out there.
Scott: It was pretty cool.
Rym: It was totally awesome.
Rym: But before we you know go off on all that business because a lot of funny things happen to us while we were sitting up There.
Rym: Yep, but the game room at katsu is Really really neat and unique compared to most other cons for one main reason Instead of having just a big game room like most cons have they split it up into exactly two rooms of roughly equal size.
Scott: Well to video game rooms.
Scott: They also have other gaming rooms.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but we'll get to all that.
Rym: Yeah Now the first half of the room on the other side that you get through through our game room Was the same as Otakon and anime central and everything else a giant room full of TVs with Wiis and PlayStations And Xbox's and DDR and Guitar Heroes and everything just kind of strewn about everywhere.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: one thing I thought was pretty cool actually about that room was I don't know where they rented the TVs from but every TV Was identical and they were laid out, you know in a very nice and even fashion and everything seemed to you know Been working at least every time I went in there.
Scott: It was working Yeah, and you could always you know, you might not get the game you wanted right away But there was always somewhere to sit and play a game, you know without much weight.
Rym: Yep Well plus I mean it looked like every single game there was getting play.
Rym: They had a very good selection.
Rym: Well Otakon had some trouble with that where there were areas where no one was and you thought oh I can play a game And then you find out why no one was over there.
Scott: Yeah, another thing was.
Scott: I noticed that the staff would often say hey that games not getting played much that games getting played a lot You know and they would set up new stations of games that were getting played a lot and they would get rid of Station.
Scott: it would change games out where they weren't being played.
Scott: now, you know.
Scott: Actually changing what games are out there during the convention is pretty cool I think.
Scott: Otakon they set it up and then it is let it sit there.
Scott: They don't care.
Rym: I think a lot of that had to do with the fact that Aaron who was running the game room and all of his staff This was the most highly staffed game room of any con I've ever been to yet
Scott: quality staffed Also, like the worst guy on the staff was still a cool guy.
Rym: Yeah, well above our line of tolerance, which as you all know is pretty high.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But no I mean This time not only did they have more staff per game and more staff per person in the room But they had probably more staff total than most anime cons.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they had a staff meeting which we were kind of at cuz.
Scott: we were semi staff in a way Yeah Basically by staff.
Rym: all that meant was we could MC our half of the game room and basically do whatever we wanted in that room At all times.
Scott: Yeah we did a few staff things like I handled giving out some wireless controllers for a little bit and People would come up and ask us questions because we were sitting at the head of the room and I would answer them the best I could.
Rym: the answer was always either No The tournament is for that Street Fighter arcade game right there or the answer you're looking for is in the other room at the other Identical table.
Scott: Yeah, well semi identical table, but more authoritative table.
Rym: Well partly because that's where all the I guess official con sponsored tournaments were in the act the normal gaming room with the normal Xboxes
Scott: Yep,
Rym: but the other half of the con or the gaming con in katsucon where we were sitting They had like they did last year classic arcade cabinets.
Scott: Yeah Apparently there's some video game museum rental company place that they know and pay I guess called video topia and they will Provide your event with old-school arcade machines that are usually working and well maintained.
Rym: Well, the guy who runs it is really cool and knows his stuff and there was a guy there for the whole con Constantly fixing any game that broke to the best of his ability as fast as possible.
Rym: He was on top of that.
Rym: now that alone I mean they had that last year too, and they had a good selection of games.
Rym: I talked about it almost one year ago today But this year due to the specific requesting of the staff They had a slightly different loadout and I'm not gonna name all the games Notable.
Scott: I could probably remember them all if I had to though.
Scott: notables included dig-dug Ram dog where the left pump button was broken in the right pump button was working.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: Yeah rampart, which is one of my favorite games.
Rym: Rampart was pretty big which I have much to say about in a bit.
Rym: Yeah, we had a spy hunter.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't even realize the spy hunter was there for a while.
Rym: No one did.
Scott: actually we're some guy came up to us.
Rym: Yeah, we were playing some random OC remix.
Rym: This guy's like what's this music from?
Rym: and one thing led to another and then he says man Spy hunter was my favorite game ever and I'm like dude spy hunters sitting over in that other corner of the room.
Scott: He's like really where I'm like over there go play it.
Rym: He ran over and we didn't see him again for like an hour.
Scott: Yeah That was pretty good.
Rym: They had stun runner which while it's a pretty piss-poor game I have a lot of history and memories with that game.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: What was that game the road blasters?
Scott: I think yeah.
Scott: Yeah, well we'll talk about more of the specific game plays later.
Rym: Yeah, they also had marble madness and not only that moral madness.
Rym: But there was a guy at the con who is one of the registered champions of Marvel.
Rym: bad.
Scott: Yeah, he's like a third best marble madness player ever and I watched him just beat marble madness.
Scott: Yeah, I mean he died a few times and that shows you how hard that game is in it.
Scott: but right before they packed up the machine I watched him beat it and Holy shit.
Rym: Granted marble madness is probably one of the hardest games I've ever played and the fact that I got to the second and a half stage of the game Totally impressed these three fangirls who were standing around the machine.
Scott: Yeah, it was surprising like how many people I watched play these games.
Scott: They just didn't know what to do or sucked or I saw some girls put quarters in the dig-dug machine.
Rym: But there was also Tetris miss pac-man and of course zookeeper and root beer tapper zookeeper.
Rym: now the sad thing is our friend I do and actually I'm out from Apple.
Rym: geeks were both staying in our room and I do Tells me you know, I said, oh they got zookeeper in there.
Rym: She says I love zookeeper and I'm really good at it.
Rym: So I think wow She's more hardcore and old-school than I could ever have imagined.
Rym: So then we get there and I'm like, let's go play zookeeper.
Rym: and I start to play and she's staring at it with this.
Rym: The fuck is this your child's look?
Rym: she was thinking of zookeeper this flash game that she played on the internets.
Rym: Ah I was thinking of zookeeper this somewhat poorly coded game from before probably before I was born.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, granted.
Rym: I rocked zookeeper and had the high score by the end of the con.
Scott: Yeah zookeeper was a game that I played once at a roller skater rink as a child and I remembered it as being this Old-school arcade game that didn't get any memory or respect.
Scott: So when the machine showed up, I was like, holy shits But that level where you got to jump up to the top.
Scott: I just didn't like that at all.
Rym: Oh, I love that because I could get pretty much like 60 or 70 thousand points in there without even blinking.
Scott: Yeah, they also had the old at asteroids and centipede and Star Wars.
Rym: Yeah, they're Tron but that game sucks wrong sucks bad.
Scott: Oh and the paper boy with the bike handlebars that sucks also.
Rym: Oh, you mean the game that's 10,000 times harder than any other version of paper boy ever.
Scott: Oh and track and field which also sucks.
Scott: Yeah, it's an NBA game and as you already mentioned Street Fighter one.
Rym: Essentially they had an entire arcade from the early days of my childhood.
Scott: They had more games than most arcades in the early days of my childhood.
Scott: It was like two arcades.
Scott: really Well, I guess there were a few arcades that had more games than that But they had like it was like two or three roller rinks worth real.
Rym: every arcade I lived nearby had at least that many games if not twice as many.
Scott: I think there were only two arcades I remember that had that many games.
Rym: Oh, well now the only small arcade I went to was in the Gibraltar Trade Center and it had stun runner and like two other games Hence I played stun runner a lot.
Scott: It was more than a timeouts worth.
Scott: That's all I'm gonna say.
Rym: That's not saying much?
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: but no the cool thing is that in this room I mean we had the normal video game room where the normal con people playing their normal con games were hanging out and that room Was pretty much packed 24/7 throughout the entire con.
Rym: Mm-hmm our room which had the old-school games was just as packed and the people in there range from people younger than us staring at These games just trying to fathom anyone enjoying them at all.
Rym: But also equal numbers of people our age Practically just on the verge of ecstasy playing games from their youth.
Scott: You can place both of us clearly within the ecstasy group.
Rym: God I spent probably all told about six hours that this con playing root beer tapper.
Scott: I Didn't play that root beer tapper that much but I did play quite a bit of a few other games Yeah, so in terms of the con itself though, the room was rocking.
Rym: We were playing our music which was mostly Psychedelic trance OC remixes and mock and I supremacy.
Rym: It's all I could fit on my little 4 gig I thought well intermixed with some para para maxes and whatever else we could take up from my iPod and from the Mac Yep, and whenever we weren't this awesome guy next to us was DJing with LA.
Rym: He's got this really cool kind of digital vinyl setup.
Scott: Yeah, it's this thing called Serato.
Scott: I don't want to talk about it a lot But all I'll say is that I heard about it previously, but I didn't think it was like that advanced.
Scott: Apparently it's super advanced and it's super awesome.
Scott: And even though I have no interest in being a DJ whatsoever I kind of want this equipment.
Scott: Anyway, it's that awesome.
Rym: Now the best part was whenever he wasn't around and we were people would come up and look at him like hey Dude, you guys DJ's and I was so tempted to say yeah, I'm totally a rockin DJ.
Rym: Check out my set.
Scott: Yeah, too bad.
Scott: You're not.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm not at all.
Rym: God.
Scott: I I wouldn't even know how to use that thing.
Rym: Yeah well it looked pretty simple until he actually started using it and it was actually far more complex than I would ever have the effort or Energy or time to put forth?
Scott: Yeah, I think it's pretty simple.
Scott: If all you want to do is play a record scratch switch the next record that kind of thing.
Scott: But anything advanced like actually making music by combining two records and all kinds of stuff would be difficult.
Rym: But yeah, this kind.
Rym: they had the normal loadout of you know convention tournaments that a halo tournament.
Rym: They had a Wii Sports tournament which had mixed results due to the fact that golf is kind of a broken game.
Rym: Oh Yeah, but the tournaments went over really well and we were in charge of the prizes.
Rym: So basically whenever someone won they come into our room all nervous and you know, we'd shake their hand.
Rym: Hey, congratulations.
Rym: You want to be interviewed?
Rym: You want us to announce your name blah blah blah, and they almost universally say no I just want to get my prize and skulk away.
Rym: Yep, we had a box of prizes.
Scott: Yeah, the box of prizes was because Aaron the guy who ran the the whole game katsu thing.
Scott: He worked at EB.
Scott: So we had all the you know, the pre-order incentives from EB that didn't get given out.
Rym: Yeah, basically he told us that anyone who ever worked in an EB would see that pile and say wow who worked at EB at this con?
Scott: Yeah, we looted some good stuff from there.
Scott: We gave away most of it.
Scott: Some of our friends took a few things.
Rym: well someone stole the three the three best prizes there other than the Wii Sports Reggie t-shirts that we gave away at our game show and the Phoenix Wright stylus, which I took.
Rym: bastard.
Rym: Yeah But yeah There were these little harvest moon sheep and they were really cute little plushie dolls and people Doesn't?
Scott: no one pre-ordered harvest moon?
Rym: yeah, but people were constantly looking at him and asking about him and pointing to him and referencing them and so at some point during the Con someone somehow stole one of them from us Basted.
Rym: now luckily they didn't steal the Tachi Koma or the dragon from brave story that I also had and we're sitting on the table Prominently because you totally would have found them out and gotten them.
Rym: Oh if someone installed one there was only one of those dragons the entire con and I scoured the con.
Rym: if that had disappeared Believe you me.
Rym: I would have been prowling around with that black mag light until I found it.
Scott: Yeah, so the only way someone could have gotten away with is they hid it in their room and then didn't let it out.
Rym: Yeah, oh well But in our room, we pretty much had discretion to do what we wanted.
Rym: So aside from playing our music I decided and Scott agreed with me that we should run a rampart tournament.
Rym: However, we didn't want to commit to being there at any particular time.
Rym: So we decided to make it at 1 a.m.
Rym: Let me tell you the combination of having a rampart tournament Coupled with having a rampart tournament at 1 in the morning is like this cool dude distillery.
Rym: Because of all the people in the con it seems like the coolest dude showed up for this tournament.
Rym: Because one all the people who showed up were either rampart fans and when I say rampart fans I'll get into that in a minute as to what that entails or there are people who just discovered rampart and loved it.
Rym: Yep, and between those two groups of people you have an awesome group of people.
Rym: now couple that with people who are up at 1 in The morning and willing to give up their rave time or their sleep time to come and play in a rampart tournament.
Rym: Only cool people need apply and we ended up having exactly nine people in the tournament and even Scott Johnson was one of them.
Scott: Well, of course guy Johnson He wasn't gonna miss out, you know Because if I can't play in it and you can't play in it He's like, ooh the people I know who are better than me are not playing.
Scott: I think I will enter this tournament seeing as I own the game of rampart?
Rym: Yeah, even though he owns it on a GameCube and it's really not the same.
Rym: I mean, I'm not undefeated on the GameCube version.
Rym: In fact me Scott and the other Scott win in fairly equal amounts just because we play the game I can constantly.
Rym: But on the arcade machine the actual physical arcade machine I am to this day undefeated.
Scott: Yeah, well, I think what it is real close though.
Scott: Well, see cuz that's what it comes down to is when I used to play rampart way back on the machine only I sucked bad then playing on the GameCube.
Scott: I got really good.
Scott: Yeah Now I went back to the arcade machine for the first time in years and I I was still really good But not as good as the GameCube like.
Scott: I could do the trackball now But I would still get a flub once in a while and that flub would always do me in Rym wouldn't get any flubs because he likes the track.
Rym: because for me the GameCube controller is so inadequate for rampart and by using That giant heavy trackball I can lay down pieces two or three times faster than I can on the GameCube.
Scott: See I want to play rampart with a mouse and then I can use the scroll wheel to rotate the pieces and Click to shoot the cannonballs, then that would be the best rampart ever.
Rym: See that would actually throw off my strategy.
Rym: I think I do better with the trackball than I ever could with them Because other people can't do the trackball.
Scott: if other people could use the trackball as well as I could use a mouse Then you'd be in for.
Rym: but it's not just that because remember the game where you were winning for a while.
Rym: You're like, oh shit I'm gonna beat rims undefeated streak and he'll have to shut up about that forever.
Rym: And you were ahead by points and you were all excited.
Rym: and then right at the end When it's coming down to the final wire, it had nothing to do with you making a flub of positioning anything.
Rym: You just put two cannons in really stupid places and that alone caused you to lose.
Rym: Yeah, even so if I had a man I had there was a flub I had earlier in that entire series of Battles, it wouldn't have mattered because you still would have put the cannons in those stupid places and then two rounds later I finally exploited it.
Scott: No, that's alright.
Rym: Anyway, I mean what it but any the level of thought we put into rampart as our group of friends the front row crew is Probably frightening to keep average normal boggle type human beings.
Rym: But I think part of we argue about like, you know kung-fu fighters would talk about he uses the crane stance.
Rym: Well, he uses the crab technique.
Rym: We're just like that when it comes to rampart.
Scott: I think part of it is that rampart is is a very playable old-school arcade game that has a very Direct me versus you directly damaging the other guy game style Which other old-school arcade games tend to not have.
Rym: it also has the three player simultaneous Which gives you this?
Rym: You know player versus player versus player and then you don't have to just worry about doing as best as you can.
Rym: You have to worry about who to attack and when.
Rym: Yeah, when to gang up on someone when to form an alliance when to just totally screw someone at the last second with a final Well-placed cannonball.
Scott: All right shows not on rampart.
Rym: Yeah, however getting these people in at the 1 a.m Tournament the nine people in that actually joined the tournament.
Rym: They were so hardcore about the game.
Rym: It was totally awesome.
Scott: Yep I had a Street Fighter 1 tournament because I thought it'd be humorous to see if I could get people to actually play this Terrible terrible game because Street Fighter 1 if you've never played it is ass.
Scott: Well, I I was playing Street Fighter 1 and I could get you know to do the hurricane kick But I couldn't do the uppercut or the fireball.
Rym: Well, the hurricane kick was hit up and fears kick.
Scott: No, you actually had to do the hurricane kick.
Scott: No, you didn't.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you did.
Scott: We'll look it up.
Rym: I just hit up and kick and it did it.
Scott: I did the hurricane kick maneuver to do it, but we'll check that out on the Internet's.
Rym: doesn't the hurricane kick maneuver eventually involve?
Rym: Going up and kick.
Scott: No, it's down down and away.
Scott: It's down down and away away kick.
Rym: Well, no up and kick did it and me and Scott Johnson were up and up and kicking each other for a while, huh?
Scott: I'll have to go look into that.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, I doubt anyone wrote a fact on that game.
Scott: Yep so I got five people to five or six people to play in a Street Fighter 1 tournament and the guys who made it to the End were actually a lot pretty good and they were using fireballs all over the place and I was like, holy shit How the hell they get this shitty old game to do that?
Scott: It was pretty entertaining for me.
Scott: At least I got what I wanted out of it.
Rym: My favorite part was throughout the day ever since Scott put up the sign about the tournament people kept coming up and asking What version of Street Fighter alpha double X beta?
Scott: And I would say that one and I'd point at Street Fighter 1 the machine sitting right there if you like.
Rym: Oh see this is what you could tell another just like the rampart thing the cool people from the not cool people.
Rym: because when you when Scott Pointed the cool people were to go bad ass and put their name down and not cool.
Rym: People would go and walk away.
Scott: Yeah, I think I've learned something about running video game tournaments because I haven't really run that many in my life.
Scott: Is that if you have a sign-up sheet You need to start out with a name on it because a lot of people like at least three or four people came up Saw that the sheet was empty and they wouldn't sign up because the sheet was empty.
Scott: Personally, I would sign up if the sheet was empty because that might mean an automatic prize without having to do anything.
Scott: But people don't like to sign up for tournaments if they see it's unpopular.
Scott: So if you're ever running a video game tournament Don't put out a sign-up sheet Until you have one name on it and that way as soon as the sheet goes out people actually start signing on.
Rym: actually What worked well for the Saturday 3 a.m.
Rym: Rampart tournament was saying no sign-up necessary.
Rym: Just be here at 3 will find you.
Rym: yeah, the problem is there was a security incident where they had to close the front door for a little bit and Scott and I use this as an excuse to get the hell out of there and go to bed.
Scott: That was a good time.
Rym: Yeah, oh well those in all day ever since the 1 a.m.
Rym: Rampart tournament all day people kept seeing me and saying Dude, there's another rampart tournament today, right?
Rym: Right?
Rym: It's gonna be continues instead of last man standing, right?
Rym: I want to fight for points instead of sudden death.
Scott: Yeah, and there are also people who wanted to have like Marvel Madness and joust tournaments and I was like, yeah We'll do that.
Scott: Sunday didn't happen.
Rym: Yeah, let's see.
Rym: I would have been more inclined to do it except the PA system wasn't so great.
Rym: So it was actually really hard to announce anything to the room.
Scott: Yes, that's cuz.
Scott: they had those video games on there which made it more to know.
Rym: it was more because the full PA system wasn't That.
Rym: also there weren't any speakers on the other side of the room.
Scott: Yeah We had to turn it up pretty like we had to turn it in order to hear our audio on the on the other side Of the room.
Scott: we had to turn it up so loud that it hurt you on our side of the room.
Rym: So on the right side of the room is from our perspective.
Rym: They had two projectors on either side of us.
Rym: for most of the time They had some Xbox 360 action go in there but next year I'm gonna petition for them to put some sort of old-school multiplayer game there instead or Anything cool in multiplayer instead of just watching someone kill zombies.
Scott: Yeah, they had a zombie game and then they had steel battalion, which didn't work.
Scott: So well, well the Xbox 360 kept crashing Yeah, and then they put guitar hero up there.
Rym: Which guitar hero was great?
Rym: Sunday when I didn't want to play music anymore because it provided music to the room.
Scott: Yeah, it was good, but I wouldn't want it there while I want to play music.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, just you know because of me not because guitar is bad.
Rym: now to the left of us.
Rym: Well, I'm just gonna play this clip.
Rym: We recorded at the con All right.
Scott: So this is game.
Scott: This is Video game called pop and music and it's a beat.
Scott: It's a konami be money rhythm game.
Scott: Just like DDR and What else is be money beat mania, of course with the name.
Rym: be money all that crap.
Scott: Yeah, guitar heroes not actually konami.
Scott: So it's not be money even though it's also a rhythm game.
Rym: same kind of game Those are freaks is be money or you interact with a game in some sort of rhythmic manner.
Scott: Yeah, so pop and music is a game.
Scott: I've heard the name and I knew it was a rhythm game, but I never actually seen it.
Scott: Well now I see it right in front of me a guy's playing it.
Scott: He's basically got these nine hand-sized buttons.
Scott: they're real big like big bubbles to pop and There's five in the bottom row and four in the top row and they're different colors.
Scott: There's like blue yellow green red clear and On the screen there's these little lines that are falling at the different colors really quickly and he's got to hit the buttons At the right time.
Rym: Yeah But the thing is it's not like a drumming game or a piano playing game or anything and that the buttons other than being rhythmic Don't seem to have anything to do with the music.
Scott: It's sort of arbitrary like you're not playing an instrument.
Scott: You're not simulating playing an instrument.
Scott: You're not simulating dancing.
Scott: I mean at least in beat mania.
Scott: You're technically simulating being a DJ even though it's not even close to what really DJing is like this game.
Scott: It's simulating Hitting a bunch of buttons that are real big real fast like it's simulating itself.
Scott: I Don't know what the hell is.
Rym: Last year it was set up in the exact same spot and because I wasn't staffed at the video game room I just kind of ignored it like I saw it.
Rym: I was like, oh, it's that thing.
Rym: I've seen that before whatever and I totally didn't even think about it.
Rym: But now here there's a little dispute because they wanted to you know Have their game and use the sound system for the room to play it and we want to use the sound system to play Derek the bandit sound Republic.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But no people kept coming up and asking like when this game was gonna be here and stuff and now that it's here You know these like five or six guys who asked about her all lined up gathering around it Like it's the greatest thing ever.
Rym: No The thing is I'm pretty sure that it was almost the exact same group of people from last year Maybe but it seems like it's.
Scott: it's a very niche game and I think personally think it's kind of a sad game.
Rym: Yeah, I just I don't know I guess because it looks impressive like they let him set it up on the big projector.
Rym: if I ran this con I do what Otakon does and just stick it on a TV in.
Scott: this is definitely a game that Only deserves to be on a TV.
Rym: anything.
Rym: guitar heroes should be out here on the big thing.
Scott: I know it really doesn't make sense which games they've chosen to go on the projectors and which one they've chosen to go.
Rym: like this Games, no one plays this game who doesn't already play this game?
Rym: Like there's no newbie who walks up like oh this looks cool and tries to play it.
Scott: Yep Plus guitar hero is probably the number one game of this con by far.
Rym: Yeah, I mean honestly if you had a video game room that had like ten guitar heroes They would all see constant action through an entire con.
Scott: pretty much The game
Rym: is as popular as DDR was when it hit its peak
Scott: Yep, plus also what I would do is since these two projectors are in this old-school
Scott: room
Scott: Personally, I would have plugged in main cabinets to both of them
Scott: Yeah, and I would have kept
Scott: all the other gate the newer games in the other room
Rym: or something I don't I would have used.
Rym: I would've done something differently.
Scott: I would have like an NES plugged into one of them That's a good call an Atari.
Scott: We could have had our Atari plugged into one if we brought it.
Rym: Yeah, but we didn't bring.
Scott: right now What do they have on the other one dead rising?
Scott: No one's playing it.
Rym: However, no one's playing it.
Rym: So maybe we'll hook something up to it.
Rym: Maybe we'll go steal a system like guitar heroes and slip it in here.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know cuz I don't want.
Scott: no no I don't think a music game works well when we're trying to play music and it depends like I'm thinking late at night.
Scott: Late at night anything goes of course because no one will be.
Rym: yeah in general.
Rym: I guess I would segregate more.
Rym: I mean Otakon is the problem in their video game room where it's so loud.
Rym: You can't talk to anyone You can't do anything like we walked in with Jess and all them We couldn't even communicate among ourselves as to which game we wanted to play.
Rym: We had to point and nod and pick up controllers and gesture.
Rym: Here we're really trying to keep it quiet enough to where people can play and it seems like a good mix.
Rym: and the other room is doing this similar thing only with different music and They really should put all the music games either like on the far end of the room away from the DJ front of the room Or something.
Scott: I don't know they dated other.
Scott: the problem is that the all their PA equipment didn't show up because someone sucks.
Rym: Yeah, I think one of our plans might be later tonight when the room comes more of a cool vibe.
Rym: We'll get that to shut down.
Rym: We'll play music and we'll make this like a happening room like we'll do stop.
Scott: I think it's a good idea.
Rym: It will make this kind of like the late-night party with Rym and Scott.
Scott: Yeah, just some advice for anyone running a con.
Scott: if you need something like desperately like you need X equipment for your con to function like let's say you need a PA system and Joe one of the staff or someone says I have a PA system.
Scott: I'll bring it and say good.
Scott: Can you bring it on Friday?
Scott: Yes, I'll bring it on Friday.
Scott: Make sure you get them to sign a contract that says they will bring it on Friday and then sue them if they don't.
Scott: otherwise You need to go and find a real place and rent a system or else your con will probably not end up with the system They need.
Rym: you really just have to be smart about it.
Rym: I mean we didn't make our friend text sign anything when he's all we did his life.
Rym: But the thing
Scott: is because we know
Scott: he was reliable in text
Rym: was rock-solid.
Rym: He'd always show up like two hours late But we planned on that and he planned on that just like everyone involved planned on him being two hours late and everything still worked On time, but if there is any doubt about you know your stuff not showing up.
Scott: You need to have the backup plan and You know because we didn't have the backup plan.
Scott: I mean stuff is working, but it's working sub optimally here.
Scott: So yeah, all you convention organizers piece of advice.
Rym: well I think the main issue is simply that they planned everything out well, but they didn't plan on Sounds.
Rym: I mean I haven't gone into the other room yet to check out the sound here But even if the equipment weren't different You got to make sure that the rhythm games are far away from the music sources and from the other rhythm games.
Scott: Well it's really tough when rhythm games are the most popular thing now.
Scott: Also in the console room a lot of the TVs are turned up kind of loud.
Scott: It's like I don't know.
Scott: I didn't really know what you do about it.
Scott: It's kind of tough.
Rym: Yeah, because no con has done it better.
Rym: I mean, this is just as good as any other cons video game room in fact.
Rym: It's a little better because we're here All right cool.
Rym: So now that I've had more time to reflect on it pop and music in my opinion And if anyone disagrees with me, I would love to hear from you is a totally lame game.
Scott: You know what I'm adding to that because I actually went over there And I played pop and music and I actually also played beat mania Which I've seen but never played before.
Scott: and my opinion now after trying both of them Is that both of them are totally lame games.
Scott: beat mania and pop and music are equally lame and crappy.
Rym: however Because I mean there's such a novelty I think they're a good thing to have at a con in Retrospect because they always drew a crowd of people who would at least stare at it for a while and go wow That's really weird.
Rym: I've never seen that before.
Rym: they tried to play it once and lose and they'd have a good time And then they'd leave.
Rym: The only bad thing was that the same three guys were pretty much playing at the rest of the time 24/7 throughout the entire con.
Scott: it didn't help that their music was loud and annoying over our music.
Rym: We had this huge conundrum now because people would come up to us and complain that the pop and music music was annoying them.
Rym: but if we turn that down the pop and music people would come up and complain that they couldn't hear their music and play their Game and there was no way for us to resolve that situation other than to just kind of keep messing with the volume whenever no one was looking or Say I would change it then not and eventually people stopped complaining.
Scott: there was a great period of relief where no one is playing pop music and That's all I'll say about that now.
Rym: My solution here is very simple.
Rym: what they should do next year is we'll take the all these rhythm games and put them in the same Room, but on the opposite side of the room, you know, two rhythm games should be near each other at all.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: I mean guitar heroes can be near DDR and it works because the the type of music is just so different that I don't think it Causes any.
Scott: you can also have a bunch of DDR is near each other because people are used to that.
Rym: Yeah, mostly from arcades Yeah but in the main room all they have to do is take these rhythm games from the other side of the room and Half the room is rhythm game music and then the other half of the room is live DJ and OC remixes.
Scott: Oh, well Let's talk very quickly because you didn't spend much time over there about the non video game rooms at kazukan Which are also part of game katsu.
Rym: Yes I gotta give props again to the people who ran the video gaming at kazukan for a great freakin job.
Scott: Yep Well at kazukan, what do they have?
Scott: They had a larp room.
Scott: They had a Bored Tabletop fish card room and I think another room just maybe a role-playing room.
Rym: I think it doesn't matter.
Rym: We walked by.
Rym: Yeah, we walked by a couple times and peeked in Larp-room tick typical scary anime larp same as every other anime cut though Actually by walked by it a few more times looking for people and doing things.
Rym: It wasn't as scary as Otakon's larp.
Scott: That's good It was.
Rym: the people seemed to be into it in the way that we were into it when we larped that Cthulhu game way back.
Scott: Yeah, actually saw some people, you know, the larp traveling around the con a couple times.
Scott: I saw a rock-paper-scissors go down in the artists alley.
Rym: Yeah Which of course we were hanging out with Tex who was running the artist alley and we basically as a group just made fun Of them for like five minutes.
Scott: Yeah, it was pretty good.
Scott: the car the other gaming rooms they were either empty or Kind of sad or one of them was super smelly Super smelly.
Rym: Yeah, I can't blame Katsucon for that because every anime con I've gone to except ConnectiCon if they've had a like a normal tabletop gaming or card gaming room It has always been smelly.
Scott: It's always smelly unless it's big because ConnectiCon a big gaming rooms because they were big on gaming.
Scott: But like anime next had the super small gaming room super smelly god.
Rym: That was the worst smelling room.
Rym: I've ever been in.
Scott: It's like you might have enough physical space for you whatever card or board games are gonna play But you should always have double the space.
Scott: I'm saying from now on is my standard because if you don't the smell will come out.
Rym: guarantee or just strict rules.
Rym: I mean remember anime next had the problem with the smell.
Rym: we came back an hour later and a certain person was Conspicuously missing from the room and the room did not smell anymore.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Rym: they put a sign on the thing and they they put a sign up and they left some Lysol out and the fat smelly guy had disappeared.
Scott: Yeah, Oh Gaming rooms tend to smell the ones that Katsucon smelled also.
Rym: the thing is video gaming rooms tend to not smell so badly.
Rym: I wonder if it's the demographics.
Scott: Well, it depends on the video gaming room.
Scott: Like if you have a bunch of DDRs in a small room smell is gonna happen.
Rym: true plus a Katsucon.
Rym: At least.
Rym: there was the one DDR with two quality pads a good hard pad and then a typical, you know Octane ignition pad.
Rym: enough people were in line at all times that no one smelly Dude could play DDR more than a few minutes at a time.
Scott: Yeah, I mean even late at night at 2 a.m.
Scott: You had to wait in line at least a couple.
Scott: get a couple songs to play DDR.
Rym: god, it was nuts.
Rym: This this is why I have such props in this video game room.
Rym: I mean one.
Rym: the con was alright.
Rym: We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Rym: But there wasn't a lot going on at the con and it other than the like the cosplay lobby The video game area of Katsucon was like the hot shit and that is where everyone went all the time.
Rym: That's where all the action was at this time.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the con.
Scott: the programming was sort of.
Scott: it wasn't bad But it was light.
Scott: so there would be many hours of the day in which you'd be spending all your time in this hotel Where you wouldn't have anything that you really wanted to do.
Scott: So your options were go to the dealers room go the artists alley and once you've done those is not really point doing them again Except on Sunday to get a discount in the dealers room.
Scott: You know go see anything you haven't seen already like the art show which you can go see once.
Scott: But the only thing that you could always revert to besides sit in the hallway and do nothing Was go to the video game room.
Scott: So a lot of people would keep coming back to the game room when the other stuff, you know Wasn't up to snuff and there was nothing exciting to going on.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So despite the fact that we went to the rave at like 1 and dance for an hour and we come back to the video Game room thinking.
Rym: All right, we're sweaty.
Rym: Anyway, let's play some DDR and some guitar heroes and go to bed And then we have to wait a half hour to play more DDR And then we just couldn't even get into anywhere near the guitar heroes machine.
Scott: Yeah, I mean other than the artists alley which you know while it was open 24/7 not all the artists sat there 24/7.
Rym: Yeah, the artist alley was definitely this quiet subdued area at night Like there were people hanging out there.
Rym: It was mostly hush conversations and giggling or I saw 13 year olds making out at one point.
Rym: That is not how you react to 13 year olds making out.
Scott: I Just kind of reacted to the making out without processing the 13 year old fart.
Rym: Great.
Scott: Yeah, there was a Mostly watching those 13 year olds.
Rym: There was a preponderance of 13 year olds making out at this con as was reported to us by our reporters in the field as they Went around the con.
Scott: I didn't really notice so much.
Scott: Actually the con did feel older than other con.
Rym: That's what I was saying.
Scott: Like there were high school kids there But they tended to be mostly older high school kids and there were less middle.
Scott: there were like almost no middle school kids.
Rym: See, that's what I love about Katsucon And I've said this last year too and even the year before.
Rym: before we did GeekNights But I still said it that Katsucon's demographic is very much targeted more people our age.
Rym: And as a result, there's a lot more, you know drinking but not you know, stupid drinking except for a few occasions We ran into that.
Rym: We'll talk about tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, but seriously with it the con is older and the crowd is generally more subdued and more I don't want to say intellectual because that's definitely not the case.
Rym: But there was a lot more, you know, cool people hanging around in the bar cool people Just kind of hanging around talking to each other.
Rym: There wasn't so much kids running around screaming Yeah, almost no middle school kids.
Scott: So definitely a plus I guess for us but other people who knows what they care about.
Rym: now an interesting thing that I never thought of but became an issue this year with This con and probably with other cons too.
Rym: Was that now?
Rym: Wireless controllers are becoming the thing more and more.
Scott: Yeah, you got wiimotes you got 360 wireless controllers.
Scott: You know, I aren't the six axis controllers wireless.
Rym: I guess so.
Scott: I think they are not sure.
Rym: not like anyone wants a ps3.
Rym: It's not like they even have a ps3 there.
Rym: What game would they put on it?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't think they had any anyway.
Scott: But yeah, you have a wireless controller.
Scott: So okay someone comes up.
Scott: They want to play a game.
Scott: You give them a wireless controller.
Scott: now, they get up and walk away.
Rym: Oops So the way katsu got handle this was basically to set up a bag check at the entrance to the video game room.
Rym: you had to check your bag in order to get in.
Rym: you could claim it.
Rym: when you went out and Despite the chaos of the fact that a lot of people were trying to go in and out of this room constantly at all hours They had their shit together and that bag check worked as well as it could possibly work.
Scott: Well on Friday the bag check worked kind of a but then they realized that it was a problem which is a good thing.
Scott: You know most cons.
Scott: they have a problem and the problem stays for the whole con.
Scott: and yet you just go Uh, and they fix it.
Scott: next year katsu-kan.
Scott: They shut down the game room at Friday at midnight for an hour and fix the bag check the best they could with the available Resource.
Rym: Yeah, they called all the staff over including us and they're like, alright How do we make this work better?
Rym: and we gave we put forth an idea that worked well enough.
Rym: Yep, I got some better ideas for next year that they play if we can plan ahead a little bit Yeah, and immediately now they're already thinking about how to streamline it or eliminate it for next year.
Scott: So awesome props.
Rym: and seriously as far as I saw One bag was lost in the entire con and they found it in fairly short order.
Scott: Awesome Yeah, but how do you what else they do about this wireless controller problem?
Scott: It was pretty simple.
Scott: They would keep the wireless controllers at a desk and if you wanted one you had to give up your badge.
Scott: So if you walked off with the controller, all right, you're gonna get caught without your badge and then you're screwed.
Rym: of course you could buy another replacement badge if you lost it for $10 and It probably wouldn't filter back right away because eventually they would probably figure out.
Rym: Hey, I've got this kid's badge.
Rym: He just bought a replacement badge.
Rym: I see what's going on here.
Rym: I don't think you thought your cover plan all the way through.
Scott: I mean, they all had walkie-talkies.
Scott: So it would probably the con had a whole loss prevention department.
Scott: I'm sure they had their stuff together and if someone wanted to buy a replacement badge They had probably just walkie-talkie.
Scott: the video game room like hey Did so-and-so take a wireless controller and doesn't matter because no one tried to pull that shit.
Scott: Cuz it's really so difficult to get away with it.
Scott: The risk is high and the reward is low.
Scott: You don't have to be an idiot to even try.
Rym: I don't know when it comes to the wiimotes though.
Scott: It's true.
Rym: We most are valuable commodity.
Scott: They had.
Scott: they had the Wii area sort of cordoned off with tables.
Scott: It's like you had to get into the Wii area mostly because people in there would be swinging around.
Rym: Yeah Apparently there was one incident where some poor girl lost her grip on her remote and being one of the staffers in the face.
Scott: Oh, I don't know how true that is, but I guess I'll pretend it's true because it's funny.
Rym: Well, it was in the staff email list and I read it like 10 minutes ago.
Scott: Well, it could have been just a joke But anyway, yeah, the Wii area was sort of cordoned off and I think they had staff watching it at all times.
Scott: So you'd have to be real slick to make off with a wiimote.
Rym: and the other side They also.
Rym: a nice thing they had was in the normal video game room.
Rym: on the other room They had a bunch of couches kind of lined up in the corner and it was half a crash area.
Rym: You know relax chill a bit half a bust out your DS's and play DS games area.
Scott: Yeah at first I thought it was just a cool sit-down and rest area.
Scott: You know cuz they had all these couches covered in sheets so that no one messed them up.
Scott: Cuz there were really fancy couches and they didn't want scuzzy gamers messing up the couches.
Scott: But then I saw people with their DS's there and I was like, oh that's what those couches are for clever
Rym: Granted in the video game room at one point we wrote on one of our white boards channel B picto chat whoo, and we just stayed in picture chat to see what happened and Immediately someone joined and typed yo /b/ which I immediately recognized as some sort of 4chan glyph
Scott: and we stopped picture chatting.
Rym: Yeah, we pretty much ended that right away.
Scott: Apparently now picture chat is no longer for drawing penises But what you do is you're greeting.
Scott: instead of saying hi or yo, you just draw a penis to announce here I am what's up God?
Rym: when we had it open pretty much anyone who joins us drew a penis and left.
Rym: It was so I don't know expected.
Scott: I should mod my DS change the firmwares that it's his penis chance that it picked up?
Scott: shit.
Scott: Alright what else went down at the game?
Scott: katsu?
Rym: anything else for the most part?
Rym: We just kind of emceed the room and hung out playing music and hanging out with cool people.
Scott: Yep, giving away CDs giving away flyers telling people about podcasting meeting people Playing video games playing a lot of video games.
Rym: I had a bunch of little and I just chat.
Rym: I went up to random people in the video game room and challenged them to games.
Rym: Granted I was being kind of a jerk about it cuz I only challenged people to zookeeper root beer tapper Rampart and Marvel Madness.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Well, you could have challenged that one guy to Marvel Madness.
Rym: Yeah, actually people kept trying to get me to play against him But it never came to be and I wanted to.
Rym: I wanted to watch him win while I lost.
Scott: That would have been funny.
Rym: that would have just been great plus.
Rym: I could have tried to get in his way.
Scott: Maybe that would have been cool truck.
Scott: Can you prevent this guy from winning Marvel Madness?
Rym: I don't think I could have because I mean I play with my whole arms like we go we go.
Rym: we got on that trackball.
Rym: He plays with his whole body, you know, and he played with two hands.
Scott: He's like whoo-shoo-shoo-shoo-shoo.
Rym: I did two hands, but I was kind of just padding at it.
Rym: this guy like, you know How you know in a Katana fight samurai like they'll move their ankle and that's like the tell.
Rym: this guy was like that about Marvel Madness.
Scott: he was full out.
Scott: He put his full energy into it like he could.
Scott: if there were more levels in Marvel Madness He'd need to take a rest after like a few more good thing.
Scott: The game's only what five levels?
Rym: Yeah, something like that I I once in my entire life.
Rym: I got to the last level and proceeded to lose horribly.
Rym: I never got there again.
Scott: Yeah, this guy beats it every time.
Scott: so We're suck We suck.
Rym: Well, yeah, that was our cursory You know.
Rym: early presentation of Katsucon's video gaming.
Rym: Tomorrow we're gonna have the actual full coverage of the con because we'll finally be fully rested and we'll finally remember all the stuff We wanted to talk about.
Scott: Yeah, Oh Katsucon the awesome gaming at Katsucon big and awesome.
Rym: Yeah, Katsucon is totally badass.
Rym: And if you ever want to go to an anime con, you know I recommend going to Otakon and I recommend going to Katsucon and happily they're both right next to each other.
Rym: Yeah, so you can start con season with Katsucon and ended on Otakon and have a damn good summer.
Scott: Yeah, Katsucon I think is actually a great con if you've never been to cons before and because if the programming remains light You know, you're not stressed all you know, you're not all stressed out.
Scott: You gotta you can feel your way around a con without having to do a big serious one right away.
Rym: OMG It's also not as difficult to navigate as Otakon.
Rym: I mean the hotel layout is a little confusing, but you'll figure out where stuff is pretty much right away.
Scott: It's basically a stick with a Y on one end and a T on the other end.
Rym: Also the fact that it's in a hotel meaning most of the people that are staying at the hotel Really really sets it apart from because pretty much all the cons bigger than this aren't in hotels anymore.
Rym: They're all in convention centers.
Rym: They can't go 24/7.
Rym: You don't get the 3 a.m.
Rym: Rampart tournament or the 4 30 in the morning guitar heroes.
Scott: Yeah, plus it's 24/7.
Scott: So you have a lot of time to get the lay of the land By after an hour or two on Friday.
Scott: if you actually bother to walk around, you know where the hell everything is And they have really good signs.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.