Scott: It's Wednesday January 24th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight We review the anime movie.
Scott: brave story.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So my work today.
Rym: usually I don't really worry about this sort of thing But they realize that it would actually be a good idea to listen to me for a change and I needed a you know a toner like a little thing that networking people use to Plug it into one hole and then find the wire that connects to that hole somewhere else in a building.
Scott: Yeah Basically the way it works is you have a wire and this wire goes through the walls and it goes Through pipes and you have no idea.
Scott: So you have one end of a wire in your hand and you go to the other end where there's some computer and you have Another end of a wire, but how do you know if that end is actually the same wire as the other end?
Scott: You're holding you have no idea.
Rym: Well, I'm not gonna go into the details because it's not Monday night Suffice to say.
Rym: the interesting bit is that at IBM?
Rym: I often needed such a piece of equipment But I was in a situation where the company was trying not to spend a lot of money.
Rym: as a result I tended to be denied whenever I asked for anything more expensive than a plastic screwdriver.
Scott: Wow, unless it was not even a metal screwdriver Well a plastic handled crap screwdriver.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I just brought my own stuff in for all that.
Rym: But anyway, so here at my new job, I'm thinking you know I need a toner and they say yes, we agree.
Rym: You need a toner.
Rym: So normally I expect them to just order the cheapest toner like I'm just give it to me.
Scott: No, they got a fancy one.
Scott: Even better they got you one of the the things that what's it called the flukes?
Rym: Yeah, well they come back to me and they say well tell us what kind of toner you want.
Scott: And what do you say?
Scott: immediately fluke?
Rym: Well first I thought you know what?
Rym: No one's ever actually asked me I'll get back to you.
Rym: and I did some research and I found two.
Rym: I Suggested that I wanted a fluke and a land test Pro which isn't really a toner but is all is just as good.
Rym: practically Yeah, and I expected them to say we're not buying you a fluke.
Rym: But no the flukes gonna be here next week.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: It's so weird to ask for something and a company just says oh, yeah, I'll buy that.
Rym: Yeah, how much money whatever.
Scott: for anyone who doesn't know a fluke fluke is a brand.
Rym: Well, this is not right.
Rym: This is not the fluke you're thinking of.
Rym: Yeah, it is not the $10,000.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: that'll tell you like how whose mom it was of the guy who made the cable.
Scott: Exactly, but for anyone who doesn't know fluke is a brand.
Scott: They're a company that makes network Testing and electron its equipment for computer guys to test things and it's the best stuff ever.
Rym: I mean like Brady pretty much makes the labelers that professionals use for industrial applications and Fluke tends to make all the things that networking professionals use for the networking business.
Scott: Yeah, they're they're really expensive them.
Rym: Yeah, well at least on terms of meta tools, I mean or Tronics make them.
Rym: I won't get into that.
Rym: Yeah, you know we should do Monday on that.
Scott: It sounds good to me.
Scott: But today's not Monday.
Rym: It's Wednesday though since it's not terribly related.
Rym: But since there seems to be the most overlap of any of our days between Tuesday and Wednesday I would like to note that we have finally played and beaten Warioware smooth moves and we've worked.
Scott: Well, I think I need the last elephant whatever Unless that unlocks real multiplayer.
Scott: Well, we'll talk about that next week.
Rym: Yes I'm somewhat disappointed with Warioware smooth moves and that is despite the fact that the actual micro games are 99% utterly brilliant.
Scott: Yeah, and only 1% of them are crap, which is the opposite of monkey ball.
Rym: And even the ones that are crap, it's not that they're broken.
Rym: It's just that the control.
Scott: There are a couple that are broken.
Rym: Did you try them in the regular mode until you figure it out?
Rym: because every one that's been broken for me if I sit Down and try it.
Rym: I realized that I just wasn't doing the right kind of motion or I didn't get the game fully All right.
Scott: Well, I'll try it with the one that's super broken tomorrow the flaggy one.
Scott: Yes, the what the raising of flag?
Rym: I only tried it once I don't know.
Rym: Yeah But yeah in actual anime news a lot of people have been talking about this movie paprika including us.
Rym: now paprika Looks to be absolutely amazing And the reason we say that is because it is by the the one the only Satoshi khan who is the current?
Scott: It's a modern master of animation.
Rym: I mean aside from I mean, there's Miyazaki movies.
Rym: I mean you see a movie.
Scott: I think Miyazaki is going down and Satoshi khan's coming up.
Rym: What I think that's the current status that the point I was gonna make is just that you look at a Miyazaki movie You go wow, that's a Miyazaki movie.
Scott: You look at a Disney movie and you go goddamn.
Scott: That's a Disney movie.
Rym: Well, if you look at a Satoshi khan movie, you know exactly even if you don't know his name You know that the same guy did all of let's see perfect blue Millennium actress Tokyo Godfather's paranoia agent.
Rym: These are all grade-a anime.
Scott: They are the a-plus anime.
Scott: So he has never stepped wrong.
Scott: It's like people used to talk about blizzard.
Scott: You know the company that makes Warcraft and Starcraft and Diablo and everything.
Scott: and they used to talk about how blizzard Never made a bad game.
Scott: They were all hits You know.
Scott: and they would talk about valve.
Scott: I guess valve has made some non-hit games But I don't know if that's technically correct, but we talked about it for a while.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, Satoshi khan all hits.
Scott: I predict all hits for years to come granted.
Rym: We have never seen dolos I guess that's true, but I really want to see it because I imagine it's good.
Scott: I imagine it might be.
Rym: well paprika It looks to be a very interesting movie.
Rym: You can see the trailers and all sorts of promotional material online.
Rym: It looks exactly like you'd expect only better just because technology has improved.
Scott: Yeah, and I just want to point out one thing is that?
Scott: The movie was it's animated by madhouse and it's directed by Satoshi khan.
Scott: It's being brought over to the u.s.
Scott: Produced and distributed by Sony Pictures Entertainment.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Sony classics is the Sony entire in a giant company.
Scott: It just proves that no matter how big crappy your company is if it's big enough You'll do at least one thing right.
Rym: so to the dude or dudette.
Rym: I can't believe.
Rym: I just said the word dudette.
Rym: who?
Rym: Decided that Sony should do this?
Rym: you are the man?
Scott: well No, well any someone was gonna do it no matter what?
Scott: No, it's they're not the man.
Scott: all right It doesn't take the man to do this.
Rym: what it means is that you are the only person who it doesn't suck in that giant Company because he was smart enough to end Charismatic enough to convince the people who actually make decisions somewhere in Sony That this was the thing you should pick up.
Scott: Maybe maybe who knows how that crazy stuff works?
Rym: it was since Sony classics is picking up.
Rym: It is going to be in America in theaters on May 25th now to most of our listeners who seem to live in bumblefuck.
Rym: That's really not gonna help you, but if you live in any metro area I practically guarantee you can see this movie.
Scott: if you live in bumblefuck you're gonna have to wait probably till late 2007 maybe even early 2008 when the DVD inevitably comes out and you'll buy it on Amazon if there isn't a best buy.
Scott: But yeah the movie came out in Japan on November 25th.
Rym: Oh six and actually it aired in the u.s.
Rym: Once in one theater in LA last year solely so that it would be eligible for an Oscar Which it was not nominated.
Scott: no instead three crap movies are nominated.
Scott: Yeah People don't know shit.
Scott: Sometimes they do yeah sometimes not not usually not.
Scott: in this case I haven't even seen this but I know what is nominated in that category And I can guarantee none of them are gonna beat it.
Rym: Quality seeing what I've seen of this movie sets me on fire in the way that few anime have in my entire life.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's rare where I see a show and it's coming, and I don't know anything about the show But I know it's gonna be good.
Rym: eskaflowne was one of those I knew.
Rym: eskaflowne was good before I saw a single frame of Animation.
Scott: well it's something I realized just a few minutes ago about Satoshi con and why his stuff is so awesome Is cuz.
Scott: I think he might be the only person still left Making anime in the old way not the super old way of the ancient times But the old way of like the 80s and the early 90s when I got in when we all got into anime.
Rym: now We're not talking so much about technique, but more.
Rym: I think it's more about like how he approaches his anime.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know when you back in the day when I would watch first watch anime I was watching stuff like Akira and Galaxy Express vampire hunter D. Yeah all these sort of sci-fi fantasy surreal epic kind of things and they all gave you this feeling inside when you watch them.
Scott: and Satoshi con stuff is the only things that come out now that give that same feeling and I think that's What anime needs to concentrate on more.
Scott: well?
Scott: He's seen the United States.
Rym: I think there's a lot to that.
Rym: I mean his anime tends to be very while not realistic.
Rym: it's the.
Rym: the character designs are stylized in a realistic way and Motion tends to be complex, and there's always a lot going on on the screen, and it's it's.
Rym: it's wonderful.
Rym: Yeah, I really maybe we should just do a show on Satoshi con.
Scott: I think we just did.
Rym: he's awesome Yeah, so if you have any way to see this movie in a theater on May 25th I highly recommend let you know again around May 25th when we do a show on the movie after seeing.
Scott: yes
Rym: We'll probably have a Friday night special
Scott: Yeah, but anyway if there's an indie theater near you And you know you should go to it now and maybe write them a letter saying hey get this movie Yeah,
Rym: or if you live in New York just go to one of the many theaters the shows anime
Scott: Yeah, or any other major city will probably have it all right.
Scott: my news There is a comic series by Garth Enix and Garth Ennis never heard of them.
Scott: Garth Ennis is the guy who did preacher.
Scott: no and Derek Robertson who's just the artist I guess It's called the boys never heard of it.
Scott: Yeah, and The tagline when they came out with this thing was that it was going to out preacher.
Scott: preacher.
Scott: That was the thing they said about it.
Scott: That was how they tried to sell it.
Rym: that doesn't seem like the best plan anyway.
Scott: Well, I haven't read any of it, but they came out with six issues, and I said all right I'll order the trade of all the first six issues.
Scott: It's only gonna cost me like five bucks at the discount and everything and you know I'll see what this is about.
Scott: Well DC decided well, it's not.
Scott: actually it's.
Scott: it's wild storm Which is the same people who print ex machina, but it's a wild storm.
Scott: is DC?
Scott: DC just decided to Cancel it just up.
Scott: It's canceled the trades not coming out.
Scott: issues 7 through 10 aren't coming out.
Rym: Sorry, did they give any reason why?
Scott: no, but the they didn't say anything.
Scott: They didn't even confirm that they canceled it because they solicited the trade and issues 7 through 10.
Scott: But you know apparently it is canceled according to everybody except DC itself, huh?
Rym: I wonder did they realize it wasn't gonna sell was there?
Scott: no it was actually the third best-selling Wildstorm comic.
Scott: there are only two.
Scott: well what the hell was so better than X?
Rym: was there an issue with the IP?
Scott: No, the actually here.
Scott: Here's how it goes down.
Scott: ready.
Scott: the suspicion Is that DC canceled it because it was - it was like over the line with its violence and such-and-such.
Rym: Okay, wait, so if that's true, which we don't know I'm pretty sure it is.
Scott: they were trying to out preacher preacher.
Scott: Well, it's gonna be over the line.
Scott: Well one if you draw lines They're gonna cross them just for the sake of it with this thing.
Rym: What little I read.
Rym: a preacher did not impress me.
Rym: yeah, but - if a comic company like that decides to cancel things that are popular based on some Arbitrary moral or whatever line.
Rym: I don't think that's gonna go well for them in the long run.
Scott: Really this is just more evidence for me that the comic companies at least Marvel and DC, you know, they're comic divisions because those both DC is owned by Warner Brothers, right and Marvel makes all their money on movies and shit and toys.
Scott: So these companies obviously still have their comic divisions.
Scott: But I don't think they actually care about making their comic divisions profitable and this is just more evidence of that.
Scott: All they care about is for as far as comics are concerned is not pissing off a bunch of fanboys who give them money in other departments and Research and development for other things.
Scott: I mean look how many comics they make just to turn into movies or Writers that they have their writers practice writing on some comic books to figure out who's the best to write for their new TV show.
Rym: Well, there is another possibility.
Rym: We complain a lot about how the anime companies in the US do a lot of things poorly or secretively.
Rym: We complain about all the anime companies in Japan.
Rym: Kind of rip off everyone.
Rym: they can as much as possible at every step of the way.
Rym: It's possible that the US comic companies are just less in touch with the world than even the Japanese anime companies.
Rym: They might just not know.
Scott: no I definitely think they know because they're basically selling to fanboys who communicate with them more than anyone.
Scott: and comic creators are like outspoken on the internet like they're all blogging and talking to everyone and There's lots of.
Scott: There's a lot more interaction between The comic fans in the US and the end in the comic industry in the US than any other art industry.
Rym: No, but see that could be the problem.
Rym: It could be a feedback loop where the comic industry does something.
Rym: the fans react a certain way.
Rym: The comic industry reacts to what the fans did and it Spirals into the abyss in this feedback loop while the rest of us are standing at the edge looking down going.
Scott: Whoa It could be.
Rym: that's what happened with tribes - on a very tiny scale it is it is true.
Scott: But anyway, the comic was luckily I guess Creator owned.
Scott: so they're taking luckily it was creator owned.
Scott: Yes so they're taking their ball and going home to get it printed somewhere else and Maybe then I'll buy the first trade if it's eventually printed.
Rym: Well I got to say now that I think this is gonna be a hot commodity because whoever picks it up got a pile of free publicity.
Rym: they get a pile more free publicity when they say they pick it up when Especially if they try to allude at all to maybe why it was canceled ball.
Scott: No, because they market it from the beginning as being this ultra-violent gory line crossing thing.
Rym: Yeah, so they could market and everyone.
Rym: this is the comic that they refuse to even carry.
Rym: This is so bad.
Scott: Your mom will cry now looking at trends of comic sales.
Scott: It's really not gonna help.
Scott: What will help is if when they come out with it again They start again with number one.
Scott: that'll help them out because number one always sells a lot more than every other number.
Rym: Well, that's how they used to try to sell anime a long time ago in the u.s.
Rym: Check out these ultra violent horribly perverted cartoons.
Scott: Yeah doesn't work anymore.
Rym: Well, it does on a very small subset of the population probably the same subset it worked on 10 and 20 years ago.
Scott: Yeah, I just think anyone who is actually reading this car who was going to read this is already reading it.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: so you know you watch all those police chase videos where the guy always gets caught because they really never show you the time for the Guy gets away.
Scott: Well the times the guy gets away are not exciting because those are the times and the police didn't try to get him.
Scott: You know if the police really try they can get just about anyone though.
Rym: There have been cases where people got away despite being chase.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: But I mean it all depends on the amount of effort like if they don't send the helicopter Or if they don't send the helicopter before you get away that you know There's certain tricks you can do or if the guy is clever at all.
Scott: Yeah, it depends.
Scott: It also depends on where you are.
Rym: Well, the cool thing is whenever there's an actual police chase and they need to take the person down or catch them as opposed to Let them go there's a common procedure wherein a police officer will bring their car up behind the suspect's car and Then in a motion kind of strafe them to the side at the rear with the front end of their car Thus putting most drivers into a spin that will result in their cars stopping or possibly hitting an obstacle
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: This is common trained police procedure.
Rym: It's used all over the world.
Rym: You can find all sorts of videos of how to do it how it works, whatever.
Rym: This is a chase video from a news helicopter where they try this on a car.
Rym: and well this guy must know how to drive.
Scott: Well, I think part of it is number one.
Scott: this guy's driving a pretty nice stolen Mustang, you know, it's rear-wheel drive.
Scott: It's pretty fast and the guy knows how to drive.
Scott: He's also got a lot of room on this highway.
Scott: It's like four or five lanes and there's not so many cars around.
Scott: so he's doing he's doing alright.
Rym: So the cop comes up and he does it and the reporters are like, yeah That's the end of this guy.
Rym: and the guy just immediately recovers and keeps going like nothing happened.
Scott: good driving skills.
Rym: So you see the cop back off of it then come up again and he just tries it again.
Scott: And it's like three different cops try the same trick.
Rym: The reporters are like, yeah, he just got lucky.
Rym: Yeah, you'll get him now and he keeps recovering.
Rym: Finally they get him and just for dumb luck He was close enough to the wall to where he hits the wall and that stops his car.
Scott: Well, see it wouldn't have even stopped him hitting the wall if the car had been front or all-wheel drive.
Scott: It just so happens that the rear wheels went up on the wall and it was a Mustang.
Scott: if that was a like a front Car he probably would have kept going.
Rym: granted the video doesn't end there and he keeps going.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: It was great.
Scott: So basically the cop pushes him into the grass.
Rym: Yeah, while this guy may I don't I don't know if he was like a child murderer or whatever he did I think he stole a Mustang.
Scott: I think that's it.
Rym: That's all he did.
Rym: then You know what?
Rym: I at least give this guy props for knowing how to drive.
Scott: Yeah, I kind of feel like he deserved to get away because his driving skills are so good.
Rym: Maybe it's like the old days where if you're gonna hang someone and the noose brakes they let you go because they figure hey That was enough.
Rym: Yeah Yeah of course see the thing is I give him props for being able to drive mostly because I Talk about how my commute sucks mostly due to the fact that people just don't know how to drive.
Rym: But today today I witnessed an accident Immediately in front of me to where I had to swerve between two cars that had just struck each other in fantastic fashion Law and Someone else was right there and they stopped to be a witness.
Rym: So I didn't bother stopping partly because I had no idea who caused it.
Rym: it was just two jackasses and like I think one guy was trying to Go up real fast and then cut around before a lane ended.
Scott: Oh not good.
Rym: and these cars hit each other side by side and then exploded in opposite directions in a sea of debris.
Rym: And I drove straight through that debris.
Rym: good move.
Rym: We were all going about 75 at the time.
Rym: Awesome and Everyone just kept going.
Rym: so now there's this line of cars going 75 through this debris field.
Rym: just kind of did it.
Rym: and Then on either side of it is a smash car.
Rym: the people looked okay, but there's a cop actually right there Dealing with another accident on the other side of the road.
Scott: So if the city was sitting there dealing with an accident also done the other side of the road Accident.
Rym: I mean, I don't I didn't see the cops face because I was going fast, but I imagine he had a look of.
Scott: But at least how do you do the paperwork on that shit?
Rym: At least if these people were hurt the ambulance was probably already on its way Maybe and the guy could get more cops more quickly than 911 could I am thing is I was zoned out listening to movies.
Rym: You should see so I didn't really pay attention.
Rym: But if I had seen who caused the accident I would have stopped until the police guy came over so I could have Made sure the person who caused it got whatever ticket was coming to him.
Scott: Yeah, and then you know, you'd have an excuse for being a few minutes late to work.
Rym: I was on my way home.
Scott: Okay I would have gone straight home.
Rym: I'll always stop if I witness an accident.
Rym: that was obviously one person's fault and I saw it.
Scott: I might depending on the situation almost depends on if I have time.
Rym: Well, like if I was on my way to have lunch with Miyamoto and then dinner with Satoshi khan, I would probably keep going probably Regardless of how many pedestrians were hanging from my grill.
Scott: Yeah Alright, so, you know how sometimes in the world there are things you want real bad.
Rym: I can list at least five or six.
Scott: Yeah, and sometimes there are things you don't want at all.
Scott: You go who the hell would want that like a PlayStation 3?
Scott: Oh And sometimes there's things that you go.
Scott: Wow, that would be useful.
Scott: I would kind of like to have that but I don't know if it's worth the money, you know And you know, you never actually buy it.
Scott: but you kind of have this slight desire like hey if you got one It would be cool, but you're not gonna spend money on it.
Rym: Yeah, like I'd love to have a Lotus Elis and I think it'd be an awesome car to have but it's not worth that money.
Rym: I would never buy one.
Scott: It's not that expensive compared to other cars of that caliber.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's more expensive than a car.
Rym: You could get let me put this way a car of that caliber is While it would be awesome is not something I'm willing to spend that much money on.
Scott: Yeah Well, what if someone took two things that you kind of wanted, you know a little bit and then combine them now?
Scott: All of a sudden it's like uh, I kind of want that a little bit But I never bought it because it was too much money and I kind of want that.
Scott: But I never bought it cuz eh and now I can get both of them for the price of one.
Rym: somehow I picture a PlayStation 3 with a puppy duct tape to it.
Scott: well Apparently Takara if anyone doesn't know Takara is a Japanese company that makes high quality awesome toys.
Scott: They most of all.
Scott: I think their biggest deal is that they make all Transformers toys in Japan men in some of which I have and they're fun.
Scott: Well, Takara is making a combination optimus prime aka convoy and iPod dock.
Rym: So no, wait, is this just an iPod dock or does have speakers in it or what?
Scott: no, it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: basically the front part is a transforming optimus prime and the truck that the trailer that he pulls around is an iPod dock where you put the iPod in it and it has two shitty speakers.
Scott: Well, they look shitty.
Scott: We don't actually know how they sound.
Scott: two shitty speakers to your optimus prime Two allegedly shitty speakers.
Scott: Oh, they look shitty.
Scott: They're so small and they look like the same shitty speakers that every other iPod boombox thing has.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: But now, you know, I kind of wanted optimus prime But I was never gonna pay a hundred bucks for one and I kind of want an iPod dock.
Scott: But I was never gonna pay a hundred bucks.
Scott: and well now for a hundred and forty four dollars You can get a white optimus prime that can drive your iPod around and Keep playing music.
Rym: Well, that might be kind of useful at katsucon to have on our little table.
Scott: I think it would definitely be a big hit at convention tables.
Scott: I must agree.
Scott: It has its uses.
Rym: See we are slowly Accumulating all the things we need because cinecon was the first time we went to an anime con and had an area.
Rym: You know, we were guests.
Rym: we had our whole area set up for the whole con.
Rym: We could put stuff on it and we've got the pirate flag and we had the apples which we eventually got rid of all Of them and bit by bit.
Rym: We're accumulating all that stuff and cruft that you see on long-standing whatever tables.
Rym: Yep, maybe you should get the optimus prime to pan that out.
Scott: Wait me.
Scott: I should get the optimus prime.
Rym: Well, I'll admit and this might come as a shock to many people that while I enjoy a great many at the old TV shows from my youth I Never really enjoyed transformers that much you suck now.
Rym: the transformers movie was pretty badass.
Rym: I once skipped on a project to stay up late at night with a friend watching the transformers movie.
Scott: It's a good move.
Rym: Despite the fact that I also had to be up early the next day.
Rym: Yeah I didn't.
Rym: it did.
Rym: the rest of that week sucked because of that but it was totally worth it.
Rym: Yeah, but the rest of transformer is not so great.
Scott: Transforms is awesome.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I I much preferred not as good.
Scott: It's not as good as say Voltron But it's better than say he meant.
Rym: what about Exo squad?
Scott: Exo squad is I think better than transformers quality speaking and I don't know.
Scott: I guess they're about equal if you average all their components.
Rym: what well we could do a Thunderdome with that Star Blazers compared to Exo squad.
Scott: I never saw Star Blazers Because I'm not that old, all right, right.
Rym: So way back Emily saw Brave Story long before it was a twinkle in any of our Gaijin American.
Scott: Well, I knew that it was the name of a movie that was coming out.
Scott: Yes I also knew that and I saw the official Japanese website that had a picture of the movie poster.
Rym: Oh, I hadn't even seen that.
Rym: I knew nothing about Brave Story.
Scott: That's all I knew was what the movie poster looked like.
Rym: So Emily saw it way back and she told us no, it was pretty good It wasn't the greatest thing in the world.
Rym: It was definitely in some ways maybe aimed at a younger audience or was it was a simple story?
Rym: But yet it was good.
Rym: and now through the magic of the Internet We have finally seen Brave Story and her assessment was pretty much a hundred percent dead on.
Scott: Yeah Brave Story is a full-length Anime feature film that is a hundred and twelve minutes long made by get ready Gonzo.
Rym: oh You might remember Gonzo from the fame of being really good at making episode ones and really a bit shit at making episodes 13s or 26 is yeah, but wait, here's some hope.
Scott: the director of this movie also directed gatekeepers.
Scott: last exile Let's see.
Scott: What else we got.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: So so far two shows that started out awesome and went nowhere.
Rym: At least though to its credit.
Rym: last exile I really liked because while the end was kind of meh and while it did the Gonzo fall off at the end it Waited until so far back to fall off that the rest of the show stood on its own.
Scott: Yeah Let's see.
Scott: What else he directed.
Scott: Oh, wait.
Scott: Oh, why never?
Scott: and I it's a movie I don't.
Rym: yeah, whatever.
Rym: I looked at a couple of these things Tokyo Babylon.
Scott: He directed also Tokyo Babylon - that's pretty much the big ones.
Scott: and He directed this movie.
Scott: brave story.
Rym: now brave story.
Scott: Oh, his name is Koichi Chigita.
Rym: Yeah, I'd never heard of him before either.
Rym: I'm sure anime world order will have something to say about him and I'm sir Bass karate for the gentleman will have something funny to say about the fact that anime world order had something to say about him.
Rym: Yeah, and we'll stay aloof of that whole thing.
Rym: Okay, I don't play promos.
Rym: I just say the names of podcasts.
Scott: I like all right the same ones every time.
Rym: I don't listen to many podcasts.
Scott: You should you know, look for a few new ones.
Rym: I have I've added and then deleted more than 40 podcasts in the last four months.
Rym: Good job Good God, oh, there's a bad five.
Scott: Alright brave story is a standard child Fantasy movie.
Rym: Yes is basically the story of this kid Wataru and he's living his normal life.
Rym: He's a punk kid.
Rym: He's definitely got all of the cool aspects of a young punk protagonist kid in a story.
Rym: Hmm And at school, there's this supposedly haunted building, whatever.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: but at some point he sees this kid this really be shown in looking kid and he's there and Apparently this kid is a wizard which is kind of weird because there's no magic up to this point.
Rym: But this this guy can summon demons.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a normal Japan.
Scott: He's 10 years old.
Scott: So what middle school?
Scott: Yeah, there's a bully.
Rym: Oh my god, the bully's beaten up the kid.
Rym: I'll save him.
Scott: Yeah, there's six creators who are bullies, you know, and all of a sudden magic.
Scott: It's like WTF where this magic come from.
Rym: Yep, but this is right away.
Rym: I mean, this is basically just the lead-in to get you into the.
Scott: it's like the first five minutes of the movie.
Scott: You will quickly be transported to a cliche fantasy world.
Scott: Do not worry.
Rym: Yes now before we go any further I would like to stress that cliche does not necessarily mean bad.
Rym: in fact you can take a cliche and use it and there's nothing wrong with that and you can execute a cliche wonderfully and This movie definitely does that.
Rym: it is super cliche, but at the same time it's really really freakin Well done, huh?
Scott: It's pretty well done.
Rym: I think it was really really well done.
Rym: I really enjoyed this movie.
Scott: I enjoyed it slightly above average.
Rym: Well, not super super awesome Well, but anyway, he sees this kid and this kid can cast spells.
Rym: You get the impression that this kid is somewhat bad because the spells he casts summon demons and the demons do things.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, he tries to get rid of the bullies with the magic but the magic is like this horrible black Magic witch thing demon scariness.
Scott: Yeah, and it eats him.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm like, huh that kids seems to be a good kid.
Scott: He got rid of bullies, but he seems to be a bad kid.
Scott: summoning demons Yeah.
Rym: So anyway that the kid leaves and he goes through this door like this magical door at the top of the stairway and then it disappears.
Rym: Cut back to this kid's normal life the main character and his dad.
Rym: his father Just walks out on him and his mom and this is kind of traumatic for him.
Rym: fast forward to a little bit later and unrelatedly his mom Has some sort of medical problem and is now in the hospital and he is alone and his life is as far as he knows Ending.
Rym: everything is falling apart around it.
Rym: one thing leads to another and he ends up going through this door because through this door is the Power to change the world and he wants to change the world His family back because I didn't even realize till halfway through the movie.
Scott: It's like okay his dad left the family and his mom is sick in the hospital All right, and then halfway through the movie.
Scott: I'm like, oh wait, he has nobody.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I'm like, he's all right.
Scott: He's old.
Scott: He's like, oh wait No, see now.
Rym: this is why I say this movie is particularly well executed.
Rym: It starts out as a mundane normal story about some kid in school in his family.
Rym: it then gets weird and magical and within a short span he is now in a Magical magical world with a hero apprentices sword and a little helmet and a wizard telling him where to go and Cute little ducks and a cat girl and an awesome lizard man, and he's off on an adventure.
Rym: Yeah, and you buy this hook line and sinker face value with no question.
Scott: Well, I think part of the reason why I bought it so easily was because it played out Just like a video game that I also buy now.
Rym: I know that last exile kind of did the same thing in a more subdued way.
Scott: It did.
Scott: it did have that same kind of feeling that hey This is the plot of an RPG not the plot of a movie, but you're animating it.
Scott: But you still left in a lot of this stuff that you normally take out when you make a movie.
Scott: So I can tell this is a video game.
Rym: But at the same time leaving that stuff in Makes me realize it's a video game and I get real excited about that for some reason.
Scott: Yeah makes me think, you know Gonzo I think they got their roots making cutscenes for video games, right?
Scott: So maybe this guy needs to go back and do the video direct video game cutscenes again.
Rym: See, I think it works.
Rym: Well, because there's something fun about watching an anime that kind of goes along on its own terms like this.
Rym: And while it feels like a video game you kind of feel like you're playing it.
Scott: I don't really feel like I was playing I did with last night.
Scott: No, I was just kind of pissed at the character for not doing what I want him to do.
Rym: The character was as smart as a kid that age would be.
Scott: yeah Yeah, but if I'm playing an RPG, he'd be as smart as I am.
Rym: what he does exactly what he should do.
Rym: He follows the plot points.
Rym: Does thou love me?
Scott: No, but thou must Yeah, but you can tell some things about it that are totally video game are like.
Rym: well that the stats.
Rym: yeah, that was the best part.
Scott: And also he has to like collect a certain number of gems to fill his magic sword and every time he gets a new gem And the sword the sword gets a new ability that he can use to.
Rym: you know Do-harder and more difficult situations now also now cliche enough He gets the sword the sword has the five holes for the five things and like every game He gets the first one right away.
Rym: Like here's the first one the rest will be difficult to get.
Rym: mmm now.
Rym: So he's going around this world and he meets this awesome lizard guy who's really funny and he meets this adorable cat girl Who is who becomes a character?
Rym: I'm really trying not to spoil it.
Scott: It gets like a pet dragon.
Rym: There's all my god the pet dragon.
Rym: Yeah that now you might wonder, you know How could they make a pet dragon?
Rym: that isn't stupid.
Rym: and the answer is they make it really really cute But at the same time more badass than you would have expected.
Scott: Yeah, it's a little tiny thing that breathes lots of fire There's.
Rym: but there's one of the funniest scenes this entire anime because the anime is serious But at the same time it's really funny and it's a good balance.
Rym: But he gets arrested for attempting to steal this baby dragon because the cat girl lies about something.
Rym: So he's in jail and he's all mad and the dragons really cute.
Rym: and then the next day they let him go.
Rym: and the reason They let him go is that apparently during the night someone kidnapped the baby dragon.
Rym: So obviously you weren't the one.
Rym: and then it cuts to this three-second scene of these two evil shady guys Running out of the circus holding the baby dragon up at arm's length and it's breathing fire and screaming above their heads into the distance.
Rym: It's just this scene is classic gold.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that's good stuff.
Scott: It's also this the funny scene where they're eating food at the inn and his baby.
Scott: It totally reminded me of slayers.
Scott: I did.
Scott: I was like this it is totally going to explode She gets angry.
Scott: only thing it was totally opposite is the guy didn't want to eat whereas in slayers It's you know that food to be gone so fast.
Rym: Well, he did want to eat but then something happened.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, anyway, but yeah The reason I said the show like you buy it at face value was that almost immediately Once he's in this world and you know He's trying to get the power to change his own life back home you forget about that world back home.
Rym: You totally forget that this show started as a normal show and you're just totally in this fantasy world.
Scott: You're like, oh wait, this is a show about a kid with no parents.
Scott: It's like suddenly alone in the world.
Rym: Yeah and he's doing these quests and he's living this life and he's saving people and he's being a hero.
Rym: and Forget that.
Rym: he's doing all this just to save his mom and then bring his dad back and then every now and then they remind You that.
Rym: no, this is what this anime is actually about.
Rym: just in case you forgot in very very well done scenes Yeah, it's usually just like flashbacks like oh shit mom in the hospital or the cool thing with the priest and the quote-unquote burn victim.
Rym: true is that that got me a little bit just like the Golem scene and stand alone and the second innocence Ghost in the Shell movie got me.
Rym: Mm-hmm Cuz.
Rym: I for a second was like what's going on?
Rym: Who's the bad guy here?
Scott: Yeah, you knew Sutton was going on because Admiral Ackbar was there.
Rym: But yeah that in general the most the vast majority of this movie.
Rym: I would use the word romp.
Rym: It is just a fun romp through a fantasy world with a kid and his venturing companions.
Rym: at one point The anime even stops showing you everything and basically does an adventuring montage.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's you know, it definitely feels to me like You have to kind of fill in the blanks to enjoy this thing.
Scott: I mean, it's obvious what that goes in those blanks if you've ever played an RPG in your life.
Scott: So it's not so bad that they cut out all the stuff.
Scott: That's just obvious and say yeah We did what every other RPG in the whole world does.
Scott: Don't worry that we didn't flesh out these characters to the fullest or don't worry that we just montage that whole bit because you frickin Know what happened there?
Rym: You don't need to see that Yeah and actually the months due to the nature of a montage they could show a little vignettes and little scenes that Might not have been able to have been pulled off.
Rym: Well, if the whole thing had been shown if you knew what was going on But just showing the one funny bit where they're running away from the thing or the one little whatever It just.
Rym: it's almost charming the way it's executed like you get all this character development and all this camaraderie building Without having to spend half your movie doing that which a lot of movies seem to get wrong.
Scott: Yeah, it does seem like It feels like they originally wrote like a few episode OAV and then get wet a movie, you know.
Scott: So a lot of the OAV stuff is you know I don't know if they actually wrote stuff and didn't put it in or if they just realized that you know the stuff that they The idea that they had couldn't be squished into.
Scott: you know, that small amount of time I don't know.
Rym: I think it might have been for stylistic reasons just for the fact that the movie does play out like a video game.
Rym: Yeah, and it has this feel of get right to the business.
Rym: follow the plot.
Rym: The plot is always there.
Scott: I also think there's a lot of simplification on that end because it's targeted towards children more than it is targeted towards us.
Scott: Yes Now despite the definitely a good one for the kiddies if you got kiddies who like the animes Or you want them to like the anime this is what they're gonna like this action.
Rym: Yes granted.
Rym: I also like this action a lot.
Rym: Now the thing is the show's a straight-up fantasy Whatever.
Rym: the kids got stats in the beginning.
Rym: They give him stats and then they give him appropriate equipment and there are a lot of tongue-in-cheek moments, but they're executed.
Rym: Well Towards the end as the actual real plot starts actually coming out and you start to find out about this other kid and these other things going on This movie really takes a turn toward the dark.
Rym: I mean it eludes at it.
Rym: it hints at it bit by bit that Maybe all is not fun and games for kids in Adventureland And in fact, it's kind of hard.
Rym: I mean you get you know that that other kid there.
Rym: He has some sort of dark past.
Rym: There's something that made him the way he is and I'll admit that when I found out what actually happened to that kid And then they showed what happened to him.
Rym: I was taken aback.
Rym: I didn't expect it to be that bad.
Rym: Yeah, I really didn't exactly.
Rym: they showed me that's you know.
Scott: The stuff like that is definitely what separates the kids anime in Japan from the kids movies in the u.s.
Rym: Oh god, this movie would have been rated pg-13 in America at least.
Scott: Yeah, but probably it's appropriate for like eight-year-olds.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but really there's despite the fact that this is very much a silly tongue-in-cheek.
Rym: Hooray.
Rym: I'm on an adventure movie.
Rym: It's really well done serious at the end and I think it's really good.
Rym: And while the moral behind this anime, which I'm not gonna ruin cuz saying the moral could in some in many ways ruin the anime It is a very simple thing.
Rym: It's not like eska flown.
Rym: It has a thousand morals.
Rym: It has one very direct very clear can be expressed in one sentence with a colon moral.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's good enough.
Scott: It's definitely worth watching but I'd say it's definitely like a B in my book You know, it's not like oh man's this is so amazing.
Scott: It's like up.
Scott: This is a nice shallow fun movie.
Scott: It's worth your hundred and twelve minutes of time.
Scott: Don't expect something, you know jaw-dropping and life-changing But expect an anime that will be entertaining for an hour or so.
Rym: see now I would give it.
Rym: I put it on the low End of the A's instead of the high end of the B's.
Scott: The B's not even the high of the B's.
Rym: see my reasoning.
Rym: I'd put it above initial D. No, I like initial D, but it is not the best.
Scott: Oh, but see could I could watch initial D more than one time?
Scott: I can't.
Scott: I probably couldn't watch this again.
Scott: I could watch this at least one more time Because I don't think it has anything to offer.
Scott: on a second view plus.
Rym: I can't watch much of initial D more than once.
Rym: I can only watch certain scenes.
Scott: again depends which initial D. I've seen the first season of initial D.
Rym: like all of their vibe time They're very few entire episodes of initial D that I could stand to watch again.
Rym: I can stand to watch a lot of initial D But my reasoning is that aside from the fact that you know It's a fun movie and it has a fairly serious and good plot and the characters are pretty cool The animation is really really good.
Scott: It's it's it's gonzo plus more money And they actually put in the full gonzo effort on the whole thing as opposed to just the first few episodes and not the later Episodes.
Rym: the music is really really good and atmospheric.
Rym: I really liked it.
Scott: Yeah The music is apparently by Juno reactor at least according to anime news network.
Rym: the character designs are really cool and that like a video game there are a lot of Peripheral inside characters that have zero development.
Rym: They may be only be on screen once or twice but all of these characters have very well-defined character designs.
Rym: They're very distinctive and they're very neat and there's a lot of atmosphere to this show.
Rym: Well this movie beyond the plot itself There's a lot of background characters that are animated.
Rym: Well, there's a lot of.
Rym: there's this little fox boy who you see twice But he's still really funny.
Scott: This is circus scene.
Scott: That's just really cool Like, you know.
Scott: and there's some really cute and like just.
Scott: it's just animation.
Scott: there isn't even really talking during the circus part But it's just whoa.
Scott: you watch it.
Scott: You're like, ooh.
Rym: Yeah, like if I was at that circus.
Scott: Yeah, baby, really like that.
Scott: I think that might be my favorite scene in the whole thing because when I was watching it, I was just like whoa.
Scott: This is like they combined fantasy and a circus in a way like yeah circuses would be that amazing and awesome.
Scott: Not only that, you know.
Scott: It's not just that they made a circus that was as awesome as the circus would be in a fantasy world But I kind of felt like I was at the circus.
Rym: I got to admit I I was impressed with the fact that I was impressed with the circus routine because I know on an Intellectual level that it's animated.
Rym: Yeah, there's no danger involved.
Rym: They can draw a character doing whatever they want and yet at the same time a couple times.
Rym: I was like, whoa Don't you do that?
Scott: Look at that circus thing going on there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I also like circuses.
Rym: if you don't like circuses it might not work for you But there are a lot of moments like that where you'll just step back and go.
Rym: wow That was pretty cool.
Rym: Like there's the baby dragon, which is adorable comic relief.
Rym: throughout much of the show.
Rym: There is also the adult dragons and when they come by they are given the due level of respect and largeness.
Scott: Yeah That's not a. it's not a major spoiler because you know that this is baby dragon and that someday the big dragons are gonna come.
Scott: It's just obvious.
Scott: You can't have a fantasy movie for kids where the big dragons don't come.
Rym: but I was surprised As to the scale of the big dragons.
Rym: Yes, and I was also.
Scott: I was thinking every time I saw the little dragon I thought about man.
Scott: What did the big dragons look like?
Scott: and I kept trying to grow.
Scott: the baby dragon in my mind didn't work out, right?
Rym: No, the dragons looked exactly like a straight-up well executed large silent powerful dragon.
Rym: Yep, and and Honestly, I thought that the riding the dragon scene was pretty cool.
Rym: the way it was done Mmm, and of course the dragons fighting the thing and And how the thing was given appropriate due respect as well.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's enough of that.
Scott: We don't spoil the whole thing.
Scott: then there really no reason.
Rym: Oh a thing happens.
Rym: the character accomplishes one thing.
Rym: There is a content point of contention near the end of the of the movie.
Scott: Yeah I don't want to say what the ending was, but I actually kind of like the ending.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta admit I like what it's like.
Scott: the ending has like this kind of catch to it And as soon as you realize it, you're like, oh I get it.
Scott: Oh nice one.
Rym: Yeah, suffice to say if a character makes a wish pay attention to what the character said.
Rym: Yeah, that's it That's an important thing.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I Thought of and the ending I mean this anime could have ended in a totally saccharine stereotypical.
Rym: Well, that's how a movie like this ends.
Rym: But it gives it a couple of twists and it's really a not terribly predictable and fairly well done ending.
Scott: Mm-hmm, I kind of why I was.
Scott: I was rooting for a slightly different ending, but I didn't get didn't get my way.
Rym: Yeah, there's also a lot that is left unsaid.
Rym: It's not just in the end, but in terms of characters made obvious mistakes.
Rym: Yep, a one character in particular made a very obvious mistake And he could have done something a lot easier than he ended up doing it.
Scott: and there are a lot of loose threads hanging.
Scott: Also, it's just like they're like the.
Scott: there are a couple threads in the movie that they start and then they might use them But they never seal them up.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time I didn't feel unsatisfied with them.
Scott: Yeah, because they weren't things I really cared about because they're all side threads and the side threads never develop enough for you to care About them.
Rym: Well, also there's the fact that this fantasy world that the kid is in kind of doesn't really feel like a dream.
Rym: But every time you're reminded of the real world you get this sense of oh, none of this actually matters.
Rym: He doesn't know.
Scott: I actually had the exact opposite once the fantasy world was rolling I was like fuck the real world.
Rym: Well, no Personally, I was like, yeah, whatever I would stay in this world.
Rym: This is so much better than being a high school kid someday and having some sort of I don't know anime relationship angst, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, plus I mean he had a cute cat girl and an awesome lizard guy and he he was a member of a prestigious Order of Knights.
Rym: Yep, and he was 10.
Rym: I mean if I'd accomplished that much by the time I was 10.
Scott: Oh man Especially if you know the real world has for you a dad who left you and a mom in the hospital.
Rym: Yeah, of course compared to the dark past of the other character.
Rym: That's nothing.
Scott: No, that's nothing at all.
Scott: That's yeah All right, anything else you got to say about this movie?
Rym: Not really I mean, I really liked brave story and I highly recommend everyone watch it.
Rym: It's not the most amazing movie in the world, but it's really really good.
Rym: It's worth the price of buying the DVD.
Scott: Is there a DVD?
Rym: there will be a English language.
Scott: Apparently the region 2 DVD is any as an English subtitle on it.
Scott: Uh-huh Yeah.
Scott: So if you buy the DVD from Japan and you have a method of watching region 2 DVDs you can watch this and also on UMD HD DVD and blu-ray UMD a. uh, is it gonna be a four disc collector's edition with 391 minutes of bonus material?
Rym: I can't imagine what that would be.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: Maybe it's all the stuff that I was talking about that didn't make it watch.
Rym: They made a whole OAV and then they edited it down to a movie.
Scott: Oh, man, the OAV then would probably be much better than the movie.
Scott: It's like I would get that feel.
Scott: I get that feeling a lot like hey if they actually you know Split this thing up into four episodes or five episodes.
Scott: This would be awesome stuff.
Scott: See I disagree.
Scott: That's about how long Gonzo shows usually go for before they suck as four or five episodes.
Rym: But I think this movie by being a movie and by using the montage and by cutting out all The build like all the things that lead you to the actual thing you care about and just having a series of all the things You care about.
Rym: I think that style at least for this story worked really really well and kept the energy and the excitement And my investment in the movie at a maximum all the way to the end.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely avoided the typical Gonzo letdown but at the same time it made the end result shallower instead of deeper.
Rym: See the thing is it wasn't that shallow and most of the anime I watched.
Scott: it wasn't that shallow, but it was like twice the depth of gatekeepers.
Rym: You know more than that gatekeepers.
Rym: god You couldn't even drown in a pool of gatekeepers Even if you couldn't drown a baby in a pool of gay if you took gatekeepers and put it up on its edge.
Rym: So all of the depth got into one corner.
Rym: You still couldn't be.
Rym: it Gatekeepers is not a good show.
Rym: watch one episode.
Rym: That's all you need.
Scott: Well you can watch.
Scott: I think there's some good stuff in the third episode of gatekeepers, but other than that I don't remember.
Rym: Yeah, you don't watch any one episode.
Rym: It doesn't have to be the first one.
Rym: You just need to see a guy go yokai edges And and I see the school open up and that the da storm and see someone open a gate got to see the bus transform and the Red Hat Linux.
Scott: yeah Okay, but not brave stars.
Rym: a really good movie and see it any way you can.
Rym: It's on BitTorrent right now, and it'll probably eventually be in the US on a DVD or something But not right now and of course if you're going to be in the DC area during Katsucon Which is coming up in the middle of February February what?
Rym: 16 17 18th I believe but I'm not currently looking at the Katsucon site.
Scott: I'm about to look at the cuts.
Rym: I should know since I have a hotel room there and we're gonna be guests there in the Omni Shoreham Hotel and Washington DC.
Scott: February 16th 17th and 18th 2007. we will be at Katsucon.
Rym: Yes, we will not just be at Katsucon.
Rym: We are at many many cons every year.
Rym: We are going to be at Katsucon.
Rym: We're gonna be running shows running game shows doing live whatever and pretty much carrying on in a semi-official Capacity for the entire weekend.
Scott: Yes anything that is going on at Katsucon.
Scott: We will be rocking with the full Power of our rocks.
Rym: Yes, which may or may not include a squealy and mealy And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.