Rym: It's Thursday March 22nd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Cthulhu photography.
Scott: Let's do this All right, so last Friday.
Scott: We had a little problem.
Scott: We were out of bread, and we didn't have any.
Scott: there was run out of juice.
Scott: We didn't have much to eat for dinner.
Rym: well other than the infinite litany of Frozen meat and frozen vegetables and bits of food that lasts forever that we'd bought a long time ago.
Rym: And the apocalypse never came the zombie apocalypse, so we never used it.
Scott: Yeah Well what happened was is there was huge snow fuck fuck and we didn't want to go anywhere and the grocery store here sucks Anyway, so we didn't mind not going to it and as a result we haven't been to the grocery store in a longer time than usual and We've had to eat the stuff that we had around the house all week Instead of going to get more stuff to eat as we usually do.
Rym: I found frozen meats And I wasn't sure what they were but when I thought them they were tasty I Bought a loaf of bread on the way home from the city and then French toasted it to eat.
Rym: God we ate a lot of French toast that night.
Scott: We did cuz.
Scott: I just cuz the thing with French toast is you know you make the little egg stuff And you put the bread in it And then you put the bread in a pan until it's edible.
Rym: now when I make French toast the next step There's no pain.
Rym: I usually just eat the French toast immediately as I make it until I'm full and then I continue making French toast until I'm out Of egg.
Scott: yeah, well I just kept making French toast And I couldn't stop.
Scott: cuz once you get going you just keep French toast in and French toast and until you as long as you Have bread and egg you can just keep going forever, so I made way too much for two people.
Scott: I think I hate like five slices.
Scott: It was out of control.
Rym: Yeah I guess we got too used to have an Emily around and making a bunch of food or having Alex over and making a bunch of food.
Scott: yeah, and today I ate the One of the last two frozen pizzas.
Rym: I ate like a pound of rice.
Rym: That was my dinner.
Rym: I just filled the rice cooker up, and then I ate all the rice in it.
Scott: That's a pretty bad dinner.
Rym: It's a pretty good dinner was jasmine rice with some sesame oil.
Scott: What do you say tomorrow?
Scott: We like go out to eat somewhere for awesome.
Rym: Wow that'll hold it off even one more day.
Rym: I know right we might have to go tomorrow anyway.
Rym: We got people coming over for D&D of all things.
Rym: no great Yeah, which means now that our house is clean.
Rym: Every bit of the house is clean everything's nice and tidy and all the fridges empty Relatively and all the snacks are cleaned up.
Scott: the freezers real more empty than it's been since we moved in.
Rym: Then the visigoths are gonna come.
Rym: they're gonna eat all the food that's left like rats.
Rym: Then they're gonna dirty up every single dish in the house.
Rym: I don't know how they manage it well.
Scott: That's all well and good, but Saturday at 10 a.m.. I'm finally going to get rid of those goddamn game pro magazines.
Rym: Oh the ones you wanted to sell on eBay, but we're too lazy so you try to give away.
Scott: the only reason I didn't sell them on eBay is because Think about I've got basically almost every game pro magazine.
Scott: I think there's a couple missing.
Scott: who knows what happened to him?
Scott: who cares?
Scott: from 1995 through 2005?
Scott: that's like 10 years of magazines 120 magazines some thick something But the pages are very thin paper, and they weigh a lot.
Scott: You know one magazine doesn't weigh much.
Rym: I remember when you had him stacked up and the ones on the bottom had kind of compressed into thinner entities.
Rym: They were barely magazine.
Scott: They're very very heavy when combined.
Scott: so even if I sold them on eBay the shipping cost Would it be like hundreds of dollars more than the magazines are worth?
Scott: I don't imagine that anyone would want to pay that and It would be also very difficult for me to calculate it and a miscalculation could result in actually losing money Instead of gaining money.
Rym: well in that case you just back out of the eBay deal and take your negative feedback and not care.
Scott: Yeah, I'm actually thinking about selling things that aren't a hundred pounds honey Bay though, so it's not the greatest idea.
Scott: Or maybe I'll sell them on some other options.
Rym: I just make another account.
Scott: Yeah, it's tied to your credit card.
Scott: They know whatever.
Rym: I have multiple credit cards whatever.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: The point is is that I was.
Scott: I decided I'll just give them away to someone who lives around here on Craigslist and a lot of people said they wanted him But no one had the balls to actually come and get him.
Scott: so I finally found a guy And he's gonna meet me at the post-off.
Rym: You're behind the post office where the parking lot is.
Rym: yeah Yeah, I just have a vision.
Rym: at like 2 in the morning Scott's gonna meet this shady.
Scott: I can read him.
Scott: at 10 a.m..
Rym: Behind the post office where I have he's gonna get sodomized.
Scott: Yeah, I had to go to the post office anyway by an easy like figure.
Scott: I had to bite as well.
Rym: some game pro.
Scott: Give this guy these game pros.
Rym: He's smart cuz.
Rym: he saw that Scott's giving away game pro.
Rym: So he's obviously some sort of nerd or geek.
Rym: so you won't be able to fight back from the vicious sodomy that awaits.
Scott: So we know Rym psychology is.
Scott: But yeah this guy, I think he's an art teacher nearby, so he will probably give these to kids which will be awesome.
Rym: This is actually kind of cool.
Rym: now you want to hear my crazy scheme.
Rym: Get him.
Rym: just get make up a receipt.
Rym: don't know any numbers on it.
Rym: Just have it.
Rym: basically say the number of magazines and what they are uh-huh and get him to sign it.
Rym: Especially if he's an educator is gonna use it in the school.
Rym: doesn't hurt him to sign it.
Rym: now You can through various means as say the value of said game pros, and it is now a charitable deduction.
Scott: Here's the problem.
Scott: I just did my taxes.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Rym: This is for next year.
Scott: Scott I know I know I'm not talking.
Scott: I'm not done yet.
Scott: I I just did my taxes just now right and You know I'm gonna get a nice return because I gave the government too much goddamn money Which I'm not gonna make that mistake again.
Rym: I still haven't done my taxes yet.
Scott: I refilled my w-2 when I got the new job, so there's no way I'm giving the government too much money this year.
Scott: Regardless I tried to you know actually itemize all my deductions and everything And it never adds up to more than the default deduct.
Rym: Um you do realize that charitable things can be put in separately depending on how you fill it out.
Scott: Well, I filled it out.
Scott: I just went along and I filled everything out and I included my $20 for child's play and it didn't do anything for me.
Rym: that well what you realize that all charity does is For every dollar you give to charity it removes that dollar that you gave to charity from your tax burden.
Scott: Yep I know that it didn't help though.
Rym: Well cuz you only donated $20.
Scott: well Duh cuz I never donate enough for it to do anything.
Rym: So how many game pros do you think are in that pile of game pros?
Scott: over 100 easily all right over 100 now?
Rym: What is the?
Rym: retail value?
Rym: if you had bought them new Game Pro on average I had a subscription Which is what would they cost if it wasn't a subscription?
Rym: if you're buying them in the store?
Scott: well I don't have the whole parts of the magazines like.
Scott: I tore a lot of shit off of them and why why?
Scott: Well you know they used to have like ads attached to them and some of them had CDs in them that are gone.
Scott: And uh a lot of them had like.
Rym: alright.
Rym: So anyway you take the add the value and then maybe make deductions for wear and tear But then increases for value over time and all.
Scott: there's no value over time.
Rym: there might be.
Rym: it's a shitty-ass man.
Scott: Even you can buy game pro number one on eBay for like 10 bucks alright, so then take all those adjusted values.
Scott: So they're worth the paper They're printed on but less because they're already printed on.
Rym: and what you do is you deduct it.
Rym: You could probably get five or six hundred dollars all told if you played it right and you documented it properly.
Scott: How about?
Scott: no because that's BS?
Rym: I'm the one who gets the gigantic tax return every year though.
Scott: actually that's bad.
Scott: You don't want a tax return.
Scott: that means you gave the government too much.
Rym: no No, I get the jet again a tax return because I pay the right amount.
Rym: But then I do something weird with my taxes.
Scott: why gonna laugh one day when the IRS comes looking for you?
Rym: Well the thing is they were all legitimate.
Rym: the problem is this year's the first year I don't have anything.
Rym: I donated 50 bucks to the RIT anime club And I donated some money But not much money to the local.
Rym: let poor people have electricity fund and that's it.
Rym: I don't have any moving expenses.
Rym: I don't have any special tuition stuff to deduct because remember I paid tuition.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I always I can always detect my awesome Student loan interest payments, oh I could deduct that but it's nothing.
Scott: that's my biggest deduction.
Scott: is the the student loan interest.
Scott: really Yeah, I paid like.
Scott: I paid like thousands of dollars in student loan interest.
Rym: this what I paid like 300 bucks total and that included that crazy 12% loan that I got rid of.
Scott: I paid a lot of student loan interest according to the piece of paper I got.
Rym: Wow I Didn't realize you had that much student debt.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: That's just what the number said.
Rym: yeah Well I take care of mine manually so I pay up ahead and I let it all go automatic.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: it'll be paid off eventually.
Scott: It's not that bad.
Rym: Yeah Plus what really helped me last year was memory moved to your way back when we moved here.
Scott: That was counted.
Scott: everything is moving expenses.
Rym: Well a lot of it was moving expenses like the thousand some dollars we spent on that stupid truck.
Scott: Yeah, that was a moving expense.
Rym: Yeah, especially all the diesel.
Scott: Yeah, I remember when you had to fill that thing up and take a taxi back, and you that was horrible.
Rym: I deducted the taxi though.
Rym: That was a moving expense.
Scott: good job.
Rym: Actually it was.
Rym: I followed all the rules I didn't have to do anything shady, and I still have the receipts.
Rym: Okay You I got that file cabinet there.
Rym: I keep track of all that stuff.
Rym: That's why I keep paperwork around.
Scott: I keep paperwork around, but only the absolutely every piece of paper.
Scott: I say.
Scott: will I ever look at this piece of paper again?
Scott: if the answer is yes I keep it.
Rym: well you realize that you're suppose you have to keep X years of all your tax documents.
Scott: I keep all tax documents for sure?
Rym: yeah, well those are tax documents.
Rym: They're the receipts that back up the deductions.
Rym: I made uh That's the only reason I keep them.
Scott: I don't keep.
Rym: I'm gonna throw them away in two more years.
Scott: Yeah, taking standard deduction.
Scott: You know I don't really have to keep so many receipts around.
Rym: god I file a manual 1040 a every year.
Scott: I use turbo tax.
Scott: It's easy.
Rym: actually one year I had to file a 1040 because the a wouldn't cut it.
Scott: actually though This was the first year where I made so much money that I couldn't do it for free.
Scott: I had to actually give turbo tax money instead of not giving them any money.
Scott: Just using their website for free.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I think you're also above the line where you can't use the easy form anymore.
Scott: No no easy form Just a normal whatever.
Rym: I never actually got to use the easy form.
Scott: I've used the easy form almost every year did I?
Scott: I don't think I used it last year But I definitely I never could.
Rym: when I was in college I had to do.
Rym: I spent a bunch of bonds to pay for stuff and the bonds had weird business.
Rym: So I had to use a 1040 a. then the next year I had a bunch of other weird business.
Rym: then the next year I made too much money, and then from that point on I made too much.
Rym: I never got to use one.
Scott: They're awesome.
Scott: It takes like five minutes.
Scott: Yeah, you just say how much money Did you make?
Scott: do you?
Scott: are you allowed to use the easy form?
Scott: if the answer is yes do this man?
Rym: Wait a minute, but I thought according to the Internet's that you don't have to pay the income tax because technically Ohio wasn't a state when they voted for the Federal Reserve and the IRS and all that business.
Scott: All right you try that.
Scott: yeah, see what happens.
Rym: I just remember my dad knew a guy who tried that all the time, and he always said yeah You don't have to pay tax pay taxes.
Rym: dude went to jail one day, and I was the end of him.
Scott: They do.
Rym: Anyway in the news the American Postal Service has decided in the United States Postal Service.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I'm gonna say I'm gonna be all ethnocentric and say American here.
Scott: Oh that good.
Rym: Yeah We don't have so many listeners in South America compared to the rest of except for the listeners in South America who are going.
Rym: Yeah, you know what if you're in South America.
Rym: Let us know.
Rym: That'd be cool.
Scott: There was a guy.
Scott: He does let us know constantly.
Rym: I know are there any more Areas?
Scott: probably I've seen some preppers.
Rym: Anyway the United States Postal Service the USPTO Has decided to raise the price of stamps see in America every few years.
Rym: for generally semi-random reasons.
Rym: They decide to raise the price of stamps, and they'll raise.
Scott: um USPTO is the patented trademark?
Rym: Yeah, it is anyway.
Scott: It's the USPS.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: They raised the price of stamps like three cents And then they sell three cent stamps, so you don't have to waste all your old stamps.
Rym: Yep, even though I'd be fine if they just raised it to 50 cents ten years ago, and just left it there So it was easier.
Rym: I don't send that much mail.
Scott: Yeah, not only do I not send that much mail, but think about it.
Scott: even if stamps were 50 cents 75 cents even if they were a dollar right what can I get for a dollar?
Scott: I can get a bagel.
Scott: I can Get not a bagel with cream cheese.
Rym: Just a bagel.
Scott: I can get a bagel with butter for a dollar Yeah, but not cream.
Scott: I can get a couple packs of gum.
Rym: Yeah crappy gum.
Scott: Oh good gum.
Scott: you can get some double mint for a dollar.
Rym: Yeah, not so much.
Rym: double me.
Rym: you can get a lot of fruit by the foot for a dollar plenty packs are like a little Over a dollar.
Rym: so get a lot of bubble tape for a dollar plenty pack with a few sticks missing.
Scott: You know.
Scott: now think about this.
Scott: the Postal Service for one first-class stamp will take a piece of paper and perhaps some other things and Transport them to anywhere else in the United States very quickly.
Scott: You don't even have to bring it to them.
Scott: They'll take it out of your house, and then bring it to someone else's house right to the door.
Scott: That's worth a dollar and they're only charging what 30 something cents now, and they're gonna charge 40 something cents.
Scott: Yeah It's still a steal.
Scott: what the hell are you complaining about?
Scott: The only people who lose from this are people who send lots of mail and the only people send lots of mail are junk mailers.
Rym: Yep now the best part is they've added this thing called the forever stamp, which you can buy for I believe the 41 cent.
Rym: Yep, 41 cents, but unlike normal stamps.
Rym: They don't have an amount on them.
Rym: They are worth one first-class postage.
Rym: No matter what forever.
Scott: Oh, that's a good idea.
Scott: You can buy a whole bunch of them.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna.
Rym: they don't sell them on sheets because they don't want people who send a lot of junk mail out But don't send enough junk mail to use the junk mail rate to use them.
Rym: They're just gonna sell them in small quantities to normal people.
Scott: Yeah, I'll go buy it.
Scott: Can you get him like in a roll?
Rym: Yeah, you just can't get him in the crazy gigantic sheets.
Scott: Yeah I'd go and get a roll of them and then I'd never need freaking stamps again.
Scott: cuz that's something as I always tend to buy Stamps like as I need them like I have to mail a bunch of stuff.
Scott: I just bought stamps for the first time in like six months like when I need to mail one letter I buy one stamp and what I need to mail like a few letters I buy one book of stamps, and I always know don't have stamps.
Scott: the next time I need them Let's see this time.
Scott: I'm gonna go to the post office.
Scott: I'm gonna buy a bunch of them.
Rym: I send about seven letters a year.
Scott: I don't send too many.
Scott: I send the rent.
Rym: Oh, yeah the rent.
Rym: so I send like 12 and I send electric bill.
Rym: I do.
Scott: Yep, not much.
Scott: I pay most of every bill online.
Rym: So yeah, so I don't have much more to say about that.
Rym: I just thought I'd bring it up.
Rym: I thought it was interesting.
Rym: the internet lost its shit over this.
Rym: as they lose their shit over everything People are gonna forget and then the rate change will happen and people will grumble and then they'll forget and then it won't matter.
Scott: Yep Anyway, there's been a lot of RIAA news is lately.
Scott: So it's time to talk about those assholes again.
Scott: Now there's quite a few news is there's news is about them suing people.
Scott: There's news is about them interfering with schools.
Scott: some more like these things tried to sue a bunch more college students.
Rym: There's a bunch of schools who are fighting back and saying we can't map IPs to people.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that was like think that was Wisconsin was like RIPs keep changing all the time.
Scott: This is BS.
Scott: Leave us alone.
Scott: You're wasting our time.
Rym: more power to them.
Scott: there was a story about a guy who they the school has like a DMCA guy and he went to this guy and the guy was an asshole and Apparently everyone goes to.
Scott: the guy then caves in and since he didn't cave in the guy was super assholish And it's a whole.
Scott: it's a pretty good greed Anyway, the story I want to talk about is CD music sales down in quarter one 2007. guess how much they're down 20 percent 20 percent, huh?
Rym: Fancy me knowing what Scott was gonna talk about ahead of time.
Rym: It's almost like we planned this almost.
Scott: I mean CD sales have been going down quite a bit over the past few years.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, this is a huge Drop, isn't it interesting that I mean aren't?
Rym: don't the numbers show that online music sales are going up?
Scott: Yeah, but online music sales, you know compared to the times in say the 90s We were CD stuff.
Scott: sales were crazy.
Scott: Even if you add the online sales and the real sales together It's not even close to what the sales used to be.
Rym: now people might say yeah Piracy is the reason CD sales are down like they always say.
Rym: but I point out that way way back in the day When you know, there was no Napster there weren't even mp3s.
Rym: You couldn't easily pirate music at all.
Rym: Even then I thought that 15 bucks for a CD was a total ripoff and I bought maybe four CDs Over the course of I don't know seven years.
Scott: Yeah, I think the real reason that CD sales are going down is you know way back when recorded music started selling a whole lot.
Scott: You had people like Elvis.
Scott: It was just so big what you know.
Scott: few artists that were just so incredibly huge.
Scott: Yeah, the Beatles they were just so huge, you know, the Rolling Stones are so huge.
Scott: And then the 90s you had a lot of you know pop stars that were so huge.
Scott: now There aren't really huge pop stars Music stars so much anymore.
Scott: If you look at like the Grammys they tend to be people who are famous a long time ago.
Scott: Where are the new famous musicians that are super popular everywhere, huh?
Rym: Maybe it's more of a balkanization where people in local areas like local bands or people all over the world like one little band and then another set of people all over like one
Scott: other little or because people finally have access to Lots of different genres of music instead of just pop and rock The they can find the genre that they like.
Scott: that was never in the store on the internets and they don't need the record companies That sell vanilla music anymore.
Rym: Also the fact that there is a lot of actually free not illegal music all over the internet and a lot of it's really good.
Scott: Yeah, if anything hurt record sales more, you know, it wasn't Napster.
Scott: It was ocremix.org.
Scott: But yeah, they're down 20%.
Scott: now, let me give you an idea of how big I hit.
Scott: this is right.
Scott: There was a CD recently the.
Scott: it was a movie soundtrack to some movie I've never heard of called dream girls, right it hit number one.
Scott: It was the number one CD.
Scott: it sold 60,000 CDs in a week.
Scott: Aha in 2005 it wouldn't have been in the top 30, huh?
Scott: But in 2007, it's number one.
Rym: I wonder if this sudden drop has a lot to do with the industry and what music is available or if maybe all this Time I was geeks been bitching about the RIAA has started to leak into the masses now that the RIAA is being Well, probably the biggest set of jackasses in the world at this point outside of actual jackasses like North Korea and Iran.
Rym: But I digress.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, there's an anecdotal evidence.
Scott: I recently read some guy who is a super music CD collecting guy, you know.
Scott: He's the kind of guy who bought everything.
Scott: he had a zillion vinyls and then he bought a zillion CDs and he goes to all sorts of record shops everywhere and loves buying CDs as tons of them.
Scott: He recently started buying some iTunes and it you know, of course the DRM got in his way big time got in his way Basically, he paid for music and then he couldn't play it.
Scott: So he wrote this big rant about how he super pissed and now he doesn't buy music so much anymore.
Scott: Nah.
Rym: Oh Way to kill probably one of the biggest sources of your income people like that.
Rym: Yep, I mean DVDs.
Rym: I get the impression that the primary buyers of DVDs in America are Hoarders and collectors and people who have this whatever need they feel like.
Rym: yeah I gotta own all these DVDs and they want to have this giant rack of DVDs next to their hi-fi system.
Scott: I see a lot of people, you know I've been to their houses and they've got like all their favorite movies on DVD like just crap tons of them big racks.
Rym: I have all my favorite movies at my disposal any time.
Rym: I want through Netflix.
Scott: Yeah orbit torrents.
Scott: Yes Hey, I buy DVDs but not many.
Rym: they have to be either really cheap or they have to be something that I plan on watching a lot or Showing to other people or lending to other people.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much what it's got to be.
Rym: I mean when I bought Firefly, it's not like I needed to buy it.
Rym: I know like 10 people I could have borrowed it from and I'd seen most of it already.
Rym: I bought Firefly mostly to lend to yet more people.
Scott: Yeah, I mean and think about this though.
Scott: If you buy a CD, what are you gonna do with it?
Scott: You rip the mp3s and so throw the CD away and then if you don't lend it to people you give it to people here.
Scott: Here's the mp3s.
Scott: go have fun.
Scott: Yeah, so what's the point of paying for the CD?
Scott: I mean, it's kind of silly not like buying a DVD where there's actually sort of a point to buying it.
Rym: now There's still.
Rym: I guess the only the fun thing is that I don't even pirate any RIA music anymore either.
Rym: Well part of that's that I've already got all the old good music.
Rym: I like.
Scott: Yeah, all this all the music from like the 70s the 80s in the 90s That was actually good that I like.
Scott: or you know 60s and 50s.
Scott: Also, I've got it all already.
Scott: I got it a long time ago and I sort of rightfully own it because some of it I bought on CD for real.
Rym: Oh, I don't rightfully own any of it some of it.
Scott: I rightfully own but not much, you know, but There you go.
Scott: What else?
Scott: there's no new music.
Scott: I want from them.
Rym: well all the new music I like is either indie stuff or already free stuff or foreign stuff where While it may technically be illegal to pirate Japanese CDs.
Rym: I'm not going to pay $30 for a CD.
Scott: No, I'm not going to pay 30 or 40 dollars for a CD Especially when they make it incredibly difficult for me to buy it.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: Well, it's not that you're in New York City It's pretty easy to buy it.
Scott: actually I got yeah, but I got to go find it I don't know, you know how to look for it in a Japanese store.
Rym: you go in and you ask and they point at it Yeah, it's no good.
Rym: My issue is more with the fact that well, maybe not my issue But there is an interesting argument that it may not Technically be illegal to pirate foreign media simply in certain circumstances.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Well, it's whether it is or whether it isn't.
Scott: I don't think it should be.
Scott: if something is not available in the place where you live
Rym: But you said it is you can order it on the internet for a lot of money
Scott: But it's not a bit like if some if it is if there's a movie and it's only available on region 3 DVD and you live in region 1.
Scott: I See no reason that you shouldn't just be allowed to just take it if they don't want to sell it to you.
Scott: But see you can take it without harming anyone.
Rym: but CDs aren't region and they are available.
Rym: You can buy any Japanese CD online.
Rym: Yeah, it just cost a lot of money from a company in Japan.
Scott: That's far away.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, you're just rationalizing.
Rym: at least I come out with it.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not licensed for distribution in your country.
Scott: So so it's legally not available in your country Even though someone over there will sell it to you and send it to you.
Rym: But you know, I like my rationalization a lot more whatever.
Scott: It's it's cool.
Scott: So the RA is sucking even more.
Scott: I predict what do they got?
Scott: How many years do you think they got left?
Scott: if they're at 60,000 CDs now for number one hit?
Scott: Right, uh at 60,000 CDs a week and you go 20% in a year.
Scott: So next year It'll be what 40,000 something CDs in a week.
Rym: well, it really depends on a lot of factors and rates and that sort of thing because the Hardcore inner circle of CD buyers might hold out to the bitter end or something.
Scott: I give it three years until we see this actually Harming their business in a very in a such a way that they go Oh shits and they have to fire people and all sorts of stuff.
Rym: I'll bet that within five years the organization known as the RIAA Well, I'll make it seven years will not exist as it does today.
Scott: I think what's gonna happen.
Scott: Is that other media companies?
Scott: That are gonna start just buying the old record companies taking all their stuff and doing better things with all that stuff?
Scott: I think that's what's gonna happen.
Scott: all the new media companies like Google and Google are Gonna buy all the record companies And do something better with the music.
Rym: Wow You know I just imagine if a philanthropist just bought because those these companies don't make that much money anymore.
Rym: What if a philanthropist just bought one of these record companies and just public domain everything?
Scott: they would be awesome.
Scott: That's what I would do if I could afford it.
Rym: Yeah Maybe we should put together a fund to make a little shell company from pure donations nonprofit And all it does is buy intellectual property and then public domain.
Scott: it sounds good But how do we decide what to buy first?
Scott: start with the cheapest the low-hanging fruit or go for the big ones.
Rym: first We could set up some sort.
Scott: if you get too many low-hanging fruits You might not be able to get a big thing that actually matters.
Rym: you set up some sort of moderation system where people who?
Rym: contribute can vote based on how much money they put in.
Rym: or maybe we just get people to donate and then I Personally decide.
Scott: I think what we should do is we put up a list of things that we want to buy and how and then You can put your money towards a specific thing Especially if it was a pledge system as opposed to a give us money now system.
Rym: because give us money now is Actually rimspeak for total scam to steal your money.
Scott: It sounds good to me.
Scott: Let's do both.
Rym: Yeah But no we did a pledge system.
Rym: Then there's no way we're scamming because we don't get the money unless we actually have enough to do it.
Rym: It's like you have to pledge and if we get the ten grand we need or whatever amount of money it is Then you got to give us the money.
Scott: No you give us a credit card.
Scott: We just don't charge it until the time come.
Rym: yeah Something like that.
Rym: or we gather every geek on the Internet's credit card, and we spend the rest of our lives in Fiji things of the day.
Rym: Now this may be a total cop-out But I was actually surprised by how funny this was.
Rym: you know all those compilation things people put on YouTube like yeah Oh the funniest moments of the creepy pedophile from Family Guy.
Rym: or Oh Homer Simpson's best top 10 funny bits.
Scott: Yeah, someone goes and you know they takes their Simpsons DVD collection.
Scott: They cut out all the Ralph Wiggum's they paste them together They put it on YouTube, and they hope that you know.
Scott: then they make their blog link to it And then they put some Google ads on their blog and then they dig their own blog with the route You know and then they try to get some money from the Google ads.
Scott: people do this all the time.
Rym: luckily Dig video is kind of prevented that from happening because now all the links go right to the video.
Scott: Yep, it's good stuff.
Rym: Yeah every now And then they go to one of those crap non YouTube video sites though some of them are okay like College Humor is alright.
Rym: Oh College Humor is the only one that isn't crap cuz.
Rym: College Humor has its own good content.
Scott: Yeah, the meta cafe isn't so bad if you have proper ad blockages But it's still not as good as YouTube or I shouldn't need to add block that much.
Rym: I know I know Granite It's no underdogs even though people in our forums seem to have had trouble downloading xcom from last night.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: Let's download star control 2 instead Which is much easier to get.
Rym: but anyway?
Rym: I saw this one that claimed to be the funniest moments of Homer Simpson and while it is not probably all Of the funniest moments of Homer Simpson it is a laugh-out-loud Confilation of some of Homer's better moments.
Scott: It is quite a good Homer compilation video.
Rym: I must say it starts with one I'd never seen with the spider, which was probably one of the funniest one.
Scott: Well, I think that one got me going because it reminded me of one of my favorite penny arcade comics.
Scott: We're at the hobo spy the hobo spy engage hobo spy.
Rym: I'm confident that this box contains engages contain cell phones.
Rym: Anyway, this is actually Surprisingly worth watching and I'll leave it at that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right I had a bunch of things of the day to choose from and I decided to go with this one because I was a random decision completely arbitrary.
Scott: So this is what you get.
Scott: So there was some sort of sand castle Competition of some sort.
Scott: I don't know I don't really care either But people made awesome sand castles the kind of sand castles that you can't possibly make unless you're a sand castle master.
Rym: I'm surprised you didn't say it.
Rym: Wait for it.
Rym: You can't make ten sack assholes.
Rym: Oh I was reminded of our inside joke when Dave and Joel who apparently discovered the video much later than I started making Reference to it.
Scott: That's kind of weird because it started out back.
Scott: I remember months ago.
Scott: Everyone was like, yeah Dave and Joel That's that podcast that small time but hilarious and all the other Podcasts is steal their jokes from it.
Scott: And now Dave and Joel stealing jokes from us.
Scott: Haha, yeah, we stole from some kids in Brooklyn who are on YouTube.
Rym: we should find those kids.
Scott: We should find those kids and we could interview them for a whole episode interview.
Scott: I just want to hang out with them That's but we don't know enough about Pokemon to hang out with them.
Rym: We'll play some Pokemon puzzle league.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Anyway, saying castles that are too awesome You can't possibly make them and what do you do with the same castle?
Scott: when you're done making it that it's so awesome You blow it up surround castle to stay alive.
Scott: Now what if you take a video of the sand castle blowing up that's pretty damn cool.
Rym: Yeah, now you can watch it over and over again in slow motion.
Rym: You can watch sand castles blow up that you were never physically near.
Scott: What if you play that video backwards?
Rym: That's probably pretty cool to watch.
Scott: It's really freaking cool because you basically see sand Everywhere a bunch of tiny flecks of sand and they come together as if by match to make a sand castle.
Rym: You know, you're actually seeing how a wizard would make a sand castle.
Scott: that's pretty much Yeah, what it would look like if a wizard made a sand castle with his magic powers.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: I say you should watch it and go.
Scott: Ooh, and then in five minutes later, you'll never need to watch it again.
Rym: So that is not dead which can eternal lie and with strange eons even death may die.
Scott: Why do you have to be all like?
Rym: because that is probably one of the most famous quotes from horror fiction ever short only of?
Rym: Cthulhu photography.
Rym: Yeah See tonight geek culture seems to have been suffused by Cthulhu.
Rym: Cthulhu is Ubiquitous.
Rym: it is everywhere.
Rym: any geek has at least heard of Cthulhu.
Rym: They know it's that green guy with the tentacles.
Rym: There's Cthulhu plushies Cthulhu's in like every webcomic at least once or twice.
Rym: Cthulhu is an inside joke to every geek social group out there.
Scott: just about I mean, I didn't even know Anything about Cthulhu or anything until I got to college, but once I did it sorta exploded.
Rym: Yeah, I mean even despite this everyone knows about Cthulhu.
Rym: They see him all the time.
Rym: yet I've noticed over the years that very few geeks relatively have Actually read any of the literature from which kook through Lou derives.
Scott: It'd be like if everyone was a fan of Darth Vader.
Scott: You saw Darth Vader everywhere.
Scott: You saw lightsabers.
Scott: You dressed up as Darth Vader.
Scott: You made jokes about where the ambassadors are and choking.
Scott: You know admirals and things but you never saw Empire Strikes Back or Star Wars or return of the Jedi.
Scott: you just never saw them.
Scott: But you loved Darth Vader and you talked about him all the time.
Scott: That's what it's like.
Scott: Yeah, people are talking about Cthulhu never read.
Scott: call a Cthulhu.
Scott: It's not even a book It's a short story and you can get it online for free.
Scott: Yeah, what the hell.
Rym: and despite I mean even with all this there's a lot of things In geek culture and video games out there that derive heavily from the Cthulhu mythos or the Cthulhu stories eternal darkness for the GameCube is so Lovecraftian that well obviously
Scott: the people making that wanted to make a Cthulhu game and couldn't get the Cthulhu license So they just made a game that was so close instead.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty obvious.
Rym: There was also the call of Cthulhu game.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think any of the actual Cthulhu license games were any good as far as I heard.
Rym: that's what I've heard.
Rym: I don't actually know but in case you couldn't tell we're not actually talking about Cthulhu.
Rym: Cthulhu is in fact a minor part of a greater body of works written by a man named HP Lovecraft.
Rym: don't worry about what is actual, you know what the H&P stand for.
Rym: it's kind of like JRR Tolkien.
Rym: Everyone knows him as HP Lovecraft and that's all that matters.
Rym: I'm not gonna go into his biography even though Howard Phillips Lovecraft.
Rym: Yeah Yeah Even though his life is actually pretty interesting his father went insane and died in an asylum.
Rym: His mother went insane and died in an asylum.
Scott: That makes a lot of sense.
Rym: He was a nerdly angry little man.
Rym: He had a lot of friends through correspondence because he lived mostly as a hermit and and he was a super anglophile.
Rym: There's a lot of evidence that he was a super anti-semite.
Rym: All keeps making sense all sorts of interesting stuff, but I'm not gonna get into that.
Rym: But when I was a young child, my mother was very much into horror fiction.
Rym: She read Stephen King and I think Dean Cook is never get all those.
Scott: my mom also liked the horror type stuff You know like the Anne Rises and the Stephen Kings.
Scott: and right I know but it's not hard It's not.
Scott: but as a kid I didn't like horror stuff.
Scott: cuz I was scared and then for some I don't know how I went for being scared of like Anything that was the slightest bit scary like the boogity man to not being scared of pretty much anything.
Rym: When I was really really young I was afraid of the dark and I was afraid of skeletons.
Scott: Oh, I was never afraid of skeletons.
Rym: I was when I was a little kid.
Rym: if you would put me next to a dead body That was freshly killed with like knives in it or put me next to a cleanly Like a skeleton a bleached white skeleton.
Rym: The skeleton would have disturbed me more.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: now I think skeletons are awesome.
Rym: skills are the best Skellingtons are today.
Scott: I love Well, not the anorexic guide.
Rym: I was very much.
Rym: I liked horror stories and I had a lot of Children's horror story books and I read a bunch of Stephen King when I was really really probably too young.
Rym: I remember reading skeleton crew when I was a little kid.
Scott: I didn't even read goosebumps.
Rym: I read all the goosebumps and I found them trite.
Scott: Yeah I didn't read any.
Scott: my brother read him.
Rym: But still like a lot of this stuff was really kind of scary and I would talk about it a lot.
Rym: and one day my mother Basically said I think you're old enough to read real horror and I said what that wasn't horror.
Rym: I've been reading all the Stephen King.
Rym: that's scary, right.
Rym: and she hands me tales of horror and the macabre a collection of HP Lovecraft's works followed by tales of terror and death.
Rym: It's a scary stuff right there and I was introduced to this world of horror fiction That is so different from all of the other horror fiction out there.
Rym: That is almost its own genre.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: It's just you know, you read a horror story, right?
Scott: And what it?
Scott: what?
Scott: what's the typical horror story?
Scott: Oh, there's someone who's in a tough situation.
Scott: So the suspense of are they?
Scott: you know, they're gonna get hurt.
Scott: the monsters after them the wall.
Scott: He's calling from the phone upstairs The Dracula or the Frankenstein or whatever it is coming.
Rym: put the money on the collection plate and the finger bone stuck to his hand.
Scott: Yeah something, you know.
Scott: and crazy stuff happens.
Scott: and it's always about the crazy thing that hey vampires Zombie comes out of the ground and goes boo Rice is not horror.
Scott: Something is so gross that you're gonna bargo, right?
Scott: Yeah and it's all about what actually Really happens or what you think is going to happen in the possible near future.
Scott: because the current situation is all HP Lovecraft, he doesn't really tell you so much right out what happens.
Scott: It's always about the Unspeakable and the unnamables and the.
Scott: you know He kind of it's.
Scott: it's weird and that he doesn't lay it out on the table for you.
Scott: But in the same way you get the idea in your head or close enough that you don't go insane and die.
Rym: Yes, I mean the.
Rym: the stories that HP Lovecraft work are wrote are very varied.
Rym: They're not like this long story arc of a mythos.
Rym: They're not this collection of stories that all piece together into something big.
Rym: there are a lot of generally disconnected stories.
Rym: that kind of reference each other or give Nods to other works and that sort of thing and you can really take each one pretty much independently and it's still a good story.
Rym: There's no reason to try to find all the connections between this world that HP Lovecraft was making.
Rym: It's not about his stories as in terms of what they are.
Rym: It's more about the way he wrote his stories and the themes he used and the way he would describe events.
Rym: That was it's not you know, oh my god boo scary.
Rym: It's a lot more of this unnerving disturbing kind of you of horror where as Opposed to say a zombie story where the zombies are chasing the guy or at the end the zombie grabs his leg and oh my god.
Rym: There are a lot of stories HP Lovecraft wrote where there is some sort of monster some sort of horrible beyond time and space beyond life and death Being and it's coming after someone but he'll never actually describe it.
Rym: In fact, it won't even show up until the end and even then it doesn't really show up.
Rym: The story is mostly the person thinking about how afraid of it He is or trying to deal with it or trying to get away Despite the fact that the character himself hasn't even seen it let alone as HP Lovecraft describing it to you.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of the stories seem to follow a you know a similar pattern especially Call of Cthulhu where there's a guy and Something maybe slightly strange happens or maybe nothing strange happens at all.
Scott: But you know someone discovers something and they want to know more about it like a book or an item or something and they start researching or investigating or they get involved in something and they learn more and more.
Scott: and the more they learn the more they can't stop learning.
Scott: but at the same time the more they wish they never started in the first place and Eventually they get to the end of the road and it's just worse on from here on out.
Rym: I don't think anything HP Lovecraft ever wrote has.
Rym: I wouldn't even bother with a happy ending.
Rym: I don't think he even has melancholy endings pretty much.
Rym: Everyone's fucked.
Scott: Yeah I mean the whole world of HP Lovecraft.
Scott: every single story is pretty much saying a Similar thing in one way or another in that you are just a useless nothing.
Scott: You're your human being.
Scott: your life is worthless and meaningless.
Scott: They're crazy things out beyond the stars and also on earth that are way more important than you and you are totally Insignificant if you try to even learn a little bit about the things that are significant in the universe You'll probably just go insane and die.
Scott: It's the only kid.
Scott: pretty much your choices are stay in the shitter that you're in or Try to get out and end up in a worse shitter.
Rym: Yes the general overriding theme of most of HP Lovecraft works revolve around this idea that The true nature of reality.
Rym: What's actually going on is so utterly alien and horrifying that mankind does not have the physical capacity to deal with it to understand it or to even Grasp it for a moment and that the world and earth and everything were at one time under the domain of Horrible eldritch beings from beyond the stars and beyond death.
Rym: and that the world is this thing far greater than we could ever understand.
Rym: but now the stars aren't right and all those beings and all those things are asleep or waiting or hiding.
Rym: and for this tiny microsecond of history mankind has evolved and comes to exist on earth totally oblivious to the true reality of the world and the idea that the worst thing that could ever happen to a person is if they put together all the If humans figure it out.
Rym: if humans put the puzzle together and step back and actually see The end result of everything they have discovered.
Rym: it is so horrible that death is not even an escape.
Rym: Yeah, I mean this is heavy horror here.
Rym: This is not light reading.
Scott: No, it is not.
Scott: It's actually sometimes if you don't read it carefully hard to figure out what exactly is going on.
Rym: Yes Well, he writes in a very archaic style.
Rym: He was definitely an angle.
Scott: I mean this stuff is from like the 20s.
Rym: Well, not only that his writing was archaic for the 20s.
Rym: He uses a lot of old interesting words.
Rym: He describes things in very strange ways in a lot of ways.
Scott: It's the writing itself.
Scott: That is scary.
Scott: It's like you have all these old words that he uses all the time and it doesn't matter what the words are saying.
Scott: The words themselves are frightening.
Rym: eldritch Cyclopean horrors claw at my squamous flesh.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Kwame's is is the famous That we like to remember quite often.
Rym: I don't know I like the word eldritch even though I use that in D&D long before I knew about Cthulhu and all that squamous is my favorite one.
Scott: It's like oh squamous.
Scott: It just yeah, you know You don't want to run into anything that squam is pretty much ever.
Rym: now.
Rym: the interesting thing about These writings is that the way he presents the works and the way they're written.
Rym: if you don't say you don't know anything about Hp Lovecraft or the mythos or you don't even know that it's fiction.
Rym: You just have this literature and you start reading it You'll get the sense that it's based on something you always feel like there's some maybe not truth to it Not like.
Rym: well, it's actually based on the ancient writings of the blah blah But it really reads like it's based on some real mythology somewhere or it's based on some actual Tablets that we found long ago or some old culture even though it's entirely fabricated.
Rym: In fact, there are a lot of feet like.
Rym: the Necronomicon is a good example.
Rym: The Necronomicon was invented by Hp Lovecraft.
Scott: Well, it's not really.
Scott: I don't think he wrote the Necronomicon.
Rym: No, no, but he made up the idea of the Necronomicon.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: He called it the Necronomicon.
Scott: yeah in many of his stories.
Scott: He refers to a book called the Necronomicon.
Rym: It is a a grimoire of the most horrible knowledge.
Scott: It's a grimoire.
Rym: Whatever captain didn't read much Hp Lovecraft at all.
Scott: I read enough.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I've read like a whole bunch of books on my shelf over there, and I've read most of them All right for the ones I brought recently, but anyway It's a grimoire and it's written by my favorite fictional person ever.
Scott: well I guess the fifth best name the mad Arab Abdul al-hazred.
Scott: ha ha That's just awesome to say the mad arab because they always capitalize mad and arab like he's the mad arab.
Rym: Yeah, definite article.
Scott: if you get definite article and mad in your name That's quite a thing yeah, so he wrote this book fictional book written by a fictional guy written in a work of fiction Called the Necronomicon which is the book that has basically all the horrible stuff in it.
Scott: And if you read it you go insane and die and crazy stuff happens.
Rym: now.
Rym: a lot of people over the years have published Necronomicon or acted like it was real.
Rym: a lot of people today believe that the Necronomicon was a real book and that they use this mythology and all these horrors.
Scott: If you go to borders or whatever and go to the Durandi bullshit section you can see copies of the Necronomicon there the written by who knows who.
Scott: I'm sure you could find out But it didn't exist when HP Lovecraft was writing about it.
Rym: now Not only do his writings really almost lend this sense of legitimacy to them But a lot of people attribute things that they think were written by HP Lovecraft him when in fact they weren't.
Rym: in fact most of The Cthulhu mythos the so-called mythos around this and the outer gods and the elder gods and how they're at war and all the Kind of pieced together stuff wasn't written by HP Lovecraft at all.
Rym: It's written by all his friends long after his death.
Rym: Yeah, or the yellow sign or the king in yellow.
Rym: that was actually written by a man named Robert Chambers Who was also a pretty good writer, but it wasn't HP Lovecraft.
Rym: the two were friends, but not the same guy.
Scott: Yeah, Lovecraft.
Scott: You know he wrote some stories that introduced a lot of the Creatures and monsters and horrors that are present in.
Scott: you know games like Call of Cthulhu and the general Cthulhu mythos But he never really you know established like alright.
Scott: Well.
Scott: This is how it works.
Scott: There's elder gods and outer gods and old ones and this and that.
Scott: and you know the other thing.
Scott: He just kind of threw the monsters in there And then it was after he was done that people collected all these things and made them work in the same universe in some sort of Systematic fashion ready for RPGing and further writings and fan fictions,
Rym: so why are these so scary?
Rym: we've already talked about the fact that the way it's written and the way everything is described is so just odd and almost realistic that it's bothersome to read it because you feel like you're missing something or that there's something just.
Rym: But there's also this idea that there's really no escape for these characters.
Rym: there are stories I think the thing on the doorstep.
Rym: when I was a kid this scared me more than just about anything I'd ever read because not to really ruin it, but the main character the guy Dies he loses.
Rym: It's over right.
Rym: It's that you lose you die.
Rym: That's the end you might have lost, but now you're dead.
Rym: Death was no escape and the story doesn't end.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: if you were up against something that you don't understand you can't see and yet even if you die You can't get away.
Rym: What what could you do?
Scott: Yeah, I mean you watch a normal horror movie Let's say right in the mod the zombies chasing you right.
Scott: so it's a little bit scary because you have the suspense of trying To get away from the horrible situation, but in the end usually some of the characters probably the main character gets away.
Scott: There's a way that you know.
Scott: they can run away from the zombie.
Scott: they can kill the zombie.
Scott: they can they could do something.
Scott: You know one guy might die over there a guy might die over there, but someone's going to escape.
Scott: There's a terrible situation with horrible scary things and someone's gonna live somehow an HP Lovecraft.
Scott: I mean the things that in a normal horror story would help you survive such as learning more about the zombies Acquiring weapons and actually trying to fight the zombies of some sort.
Scott: those things are only gonna make it worse and not better.
Rym: I mean if you want to take a nod from the Cthulhu based role-playing games The idea is not to win or to figure it out or to kill Cthulhu.
Rym: The idea is pretty much to stave off insanity for as long as possible Assuming full well that any character you play will go insane and or die possibly at the same exact moment a combination in the famous Lovecraftian insane and dead Finishing move.
Scott: I Guess we'll call it.
Rym: Yes So lately we've been reviewing or talking about a lot of things we like and this is also something that will we gush about because HP Lovecraft works are some of my favorite writings I've ever read.
Scott: yeah I mean I like some of them better than others.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but like the dream quest of unknown cadence That's a freaking awesome super awesome.
Rym: I think my favorite work of HP Lovecraft's is the color out of space.
Scott: It's a good one.
Scott: I forget which one it is.
Scott: It's the one with Antarctica and the old ones in the Shagat.
Scott: What's that one called?
Scott: I forget.
Rym: I actually forget the names of a lot of them because I read him in giant anthologies Just one after another.
Scott: yeah It's like you buy since they're all short stories you tend to like buy like these books that have a whole bunch of short stories In them.
Scott: Oh at the mountains of madness.
Scott: That's the one.
Scott: yeah, and You just read a bunch of short stories in a row and you forget which one is which and like.
Scott: you'll remember the name Of a story, but you remember which story that was And some of them are a lot scarier or memorable than others.
Scott: These things are written in pulp magazines and that sort of stuff way back when.
Scott: so it's not like you know.
Scott: Everyone was a masterpiece kind of deal.
Rym: Yeah In general if you want to get an idea of what these works are like I'd recommend the color out of space.
Rym: The shadow out of time is really good.
Rym: The thing on the doorstep is pretty creepy I must say and that might be one of the scarier ones.
Rym: as a little kid I mean it was pretty scary all the way through but then at the end I Actually stopped reading HP Lovecraft for a while after that.
Rym: that was a little too much for my young mind.
Rym: Herbert West reanimator and of course the call of Cthulhu which I wouldn't recommend reading first.
Rym: But I recommend reading it because it's probably the most well-known work And it has probably my well another one of my favorite quotes from.
Rym: I have to read this quote because it's just it too Perfectly sums up just about everything that Lovecraft wrote about.
Rym: the most merciful thing in the world I think is the inability of the human mind to correlate all of its contents.
Rym: someday the piecing together of Disassociated knowledge will open up such terrifying vistas of reality and our frightful position They're in that we shall either go mad from the revelation or flee from the light into the peace and safety of a new dark age.
Scott: All right, if we're gonna keep doing this reading game, I want to read something here.
Rym: Oh, what are you gonna read?
Scott: I'm gonna read the description of the shoggoth, which is my one of the best monsters ready.
Scott: So they hear this is how I'm gonna demonstrate how he describes something without really describing it.
Scott: you ready It was a terrible indescribable thing Vast er than any subway train a shapeless conjure.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: I actually don't know this word c-o-n-g-e-r-i-e.
Scott: conjury.
Rym: conjury.
Scott: conjury of Protoplasmic bubbles faintly self-luminous and with myriads of temporary eyes forming and unforming as pustules of greenish light all over the tunnel Filling front that bore down upon us crushing the frantic penguins and Shiltering over the glistening floor for that and its kind had swept so evilly free of all litter.
Rym: Yeah, try to try to draw that.
Scott: Yeah, try to think of what a shoggoth looks like from that considering he uses the words Indescribable shapeless and conjury.
Rym: see another word that you'll really have to be familiar with is non-euclidean.
Scott: Yeah, well if you know anything about geometry, you know, there's a guy named Euclid.
Scott: He was Greek right keep going Yeah, and he pretty much invented modern basic geometry and his geometry is a geometry of three dimensions.
Rym: Well, I think I think I can sum it up better non-euclidean geometry.
Rym: You can have line You can do things that you can't do in normal geometry.
Rym: You can have parallel lines that cross each other or you can have a right triangle that has seven hundred and twenty degrees within it.
Scott: All kinds of crazy.
Rym: imagine things that not only are they did they're not just difficult to describe.
Rym: It's not like the person who saw this shoggoth or saw this city of real.
Rym: Yeah, just had trouble describing it.
Rym: It's that he could not fathom what he was seeing.
Rym: that it is something so alien That it cannot be described.
Rym: It cannot be understood.
Scott: Yeah, I mean think about this for a second, right?
Scott: You have a triangle one of the three corner.
Scott: The triangle has three corners and three sides.
Scott: one of the corners is 90 degrees.
Scott: if you add up the degrees of all three corners, it is like 700 degrees.
Scott: Think about that for a second.
Scott: try to get a picture of that in your brain.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: that's why he can't even use words to tell you what it looks like, but it's scary as hell.
Scott: You don't want to run into that triangle, especially if it's part of a monster that's gonna eat you Man.
Rym: I talked more about the Cthulhu role-playing game, but we should do that on a Tuesday.
Scott: Yeah, the Cthulhu role-playing game is basically role-playing in a universe with all these indescribable things.
Rym: There's also Arkham horror which you've played.
Rym: I have yet to play it.
Scott: Arkham horror is one of those Teamwork beat the game board games.
Scott: I think I like it better than that Lord of the Rings board game, huh?
Scott: But It's it takes a lot more time than it's worth.
Scott: basically.
Scott: Yeah, there's lots of Cthulhu stuff out there.
Scott: If you like you through loose stuff Go for it.
Scott: There's more than you can handle.
Rym: Scott's got a stuffed Cthulhu.
Rym: Alex has a Cthulhu finger puppet our friend Greg.
Rym: I think he had a shoggoth and a star spawn.
Scott: There's a lot of stuff out there.
Scott: I think I got to go get a gnarly thotep one day.
Rym: Gnarly thotep is my man.
Scott: I must say he is the crawling chaos.
Rym: So Event essentially check out HP Lovecraft and all of the related works.
Rym: I think you're really gonna like it Unless you're a wuss.
Rym: now.
Rym: before we go I'd also like to note that the deadline is now as of this podcast over for the worst podcast in the world Contest those naps.
Rym: unless you have what you think is the most awesome entry in the world I'll accept him up until tomorrow at midnight if you think you've got the best freaking entry.
Rym: But I must say there's some stiff competition.
Rym: people have sent us some pretty bad Podcasts that I'm going on quite a bit longer than you might have expected.
Scott: Yeah, even before listening I've narrowed this down to like three or four and as soon as I go back and listen to what all the rules were We might have a winner.
Rym: I think yeah granted We're going to read many of the entries because I find this hilarious and some people ragged on some pretty popular podcasts.
Scott: Yeah, I was expecting people to find these obscure podcasts made by like one ten-year-old nerd in his closet or something.
Scott: granted some of Them did some of them did but that's what I was expecting.
Scott: Then some people came out and they were like, yeah, this popular podcast is the worst podcast and I'm like.
Scott: I listen to that.
Rym: I'm friends with that podcaster.
Scott: Yeah, it's like hey, I've heard of them.
Scott: They're just normal.
Scott: What do you?
Scott: Great, but not the worst podcast.
Rym: Yep, so and it will take us.
Rym: probably I think the week after next we're actually gonna announce the winners cuz I want to spend The time to thoroughly listen to each and every one of these perhaps to get relevant audio to put into our show.
Scott: Do you really want to make a her podcast so terrible by putting the worst podcast ever in it?
Rym: possibly?
Rym: Possibly.
Scott: Well, if anything it'll help people understand how great our podcast is Placed in such stark and abrupt contrast with a the worst podcast there ever was.
Rym: Oh By the way, you should listen to anime world order.
Rym: It's a good anime podcast.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.