Rym: So you might notice the lack of music.
Rym: we just started talking right here.
Scott: Yeah, cuz we have a special treat for you today.
Rym: Yes It is quite the special occasion and not only.
Scott: this isn't one of those episodes where we say Yeah, it's special because it's not a normal episode.
Scott: Well, it is not a normal episode, but this episode is actually really special in a good way.
Rym: Yep starting last year We began a tradition of every year when we go to Otakon having Probably some of our favorite podcast friends do a special episode for us a guest host.
Rym: where it's our show.
Rym: It's GeekNights, but they're the hosts straight up and This year we present to you.
Scott: I don't know it.
Scott: This is so great.
Scott: I can't even Got them.
Rym: I had a hard time editing it because I kept cracking up.
Scott: I I just listened to the beginning part and I was cracking up.
Scott: I like I felt like it didn't even need editing.
Rym: Yeah, I know I like.
Rym: I would have just put it in our feed straight up But I figured I should at least give the appearance of this being in the GeekNights format.
Scott: I mean the best part about it.
Scott: Is that like?
Scott: I was listening to and I was like, wow, this is really good.
Scott: And then at the end they were like, wow, this is double-a-plus material.
Scott: We should be giving it to GeekNights and I was like you shouldn't have but you did all man's yep.
Rym: But of course the reason we're doing this intro before the actual show is just that I like to point out.
Rym: I know we have a lot of new listeners from ConnectiCon and Otakon Perhaps and I need you to know that we're all out of town.
Rym: So this is not a normal episode of GeekNights.
Rym: if you couldn't gather in fact all this week They're not going to be any normal episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: Feel free to listen But don't get the wrong impression.
Rym: listen to any episode that does not have the special tag on it to hear what we're really about.
Scott: Yes if you see the word special in the title that is not a normal episode and if you're new to the show you should listen to Some other episode that just says like, you know GeekNights episode something something.
Scott: that way You know what the show is actually about.
Scott: you can decide whether to be a fan or a listener or not.
Scott: Don't judge by this episode Of course, I actually wouldn't mind if you judged by this episode because this episode is damn high quality.
Rym: Yes If you like the what you're about to hear at all I highly suggest you check out Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentleman outside of the 12 Byzantine rulers.
Rym: I think they're my favorite podcast.
Scott: Dave and Joelle calm J.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and on that note, I think I'll let the boys take over.
Guest 0: Oh, man It's GeekNights.
Guest 0: Hi, I'm Dave and I'm Joel and tonight we're gonna talk about MD guys episode 2 the death force Don't Okay, so now we're doing The intro part where we're just Gavin.
Guest 0: It's free flow.
Guest 1: This is free flow.
Guest 0: Yes.
Guest 0: So Joel I Went downstairs to check out my laundry as you know, I did.
Guest 0: but for the internet they should also know.
Guest 0: and I'm thinking I should check out the lint trap on this dryer because Nobody in this apartment ever empties the lint trap and you gotta empty the lint trap.
Guest 1: for is it one of those humane lint rats where they allow it to Humane back out into the?
Guest 1: yeah humane lint trap where you just trap it and then you let it back out into the wild?
Guest 1: You know lint's natural habitat.
Guest 0: I think lint's natural habitat is in the lint trap.
Guest 0: Anyway, that little entrap is not the story.
Guest 0: So I flip open the lid for the lint trap and there is a tooth in it.
Guest 0: It's a human tooth.
Guest 1: I Pray to God you didn't try to reach your hand into it because you know how that got there.
Guest 1: the lint trap It's oh my god It's like an owl.
Guest 0: It can't I just it was more remarkably clean.
Guest 0: It wasn't at all like when Bruce Willis tore the tooth out and army of the twelve monkeys and was all bloody and stuff I think.
Guest 1: cuz he just tore it out.
Guest 0: Well somebody I think somebody purposely put that tooth in there.
Guest 0: just fuck with me.
Guest 1: But now be there's some kind of a.
Guest 0: cleaned it up and buffed it a little.
Guest 1: maybe they were hiding it there.
Guest 1: Maybe there's some kind of weird - I mean, there's a lot of different Customs cultures that live in your apartment building.
Guest 1: Yeah, it's true We have a lot of African immigrants where we put our tooth under our pillow.
Guest 1: Maybe somebody else they put in the laundry.
Guest 0: But yeah, I don't know.
Guest 0: this is what you get living in an apartment that uh Thousand bucks a month for five bedrooms.
Guest 0: This is the kind of stuff you deal with.
Guest 0: It's wild and crazy times.
Guest 1: It's an accident.
Guest 1: Still that's freaking awesome.
Guest 0: I I'm still not entirely sure it happened to me.
Guest 0: It's just like that Queen song.
Guest 0: Is this the real life?
Guest 0: Is this just fantasy?
Guest 0: that Queen song the Queen song?
Guest 0: Yeah, the Queen song everybody knows.
Guest 0: So Joel, I guess we're talking about the news.
Guest 0: and what's in the news?
Guest 0: Shall I lead?
Guest 0: I think I shall.
Guest 0: so this is a bit of a self-serving news thing, but maybe this will be a bit of a self-serving podcast.
Guest 0: You may you guys may have heard of that otaku USA magazine that's rounding the store shelves.
Guest 0: The next issue should be coming out next week.
Guest 0: it comes out in August and you know Most likely I'm featured in it, but I haven't really gotten any mail back.
Guest 0: So I think you guys should pick it up because it's the second issue.
Guest 0: We want this thing to keep going and you get to read stuff by me.
Guest 0: I'm making the funny jokes about Odin sphere and guitar hero and how Playing guitar hero actually makes you cooler than starting your own band and it's a lot easier to do.
Guest 0: It's a good article.
Guest 0: I hope it makes it in there because I was actually pretty proud of it.
Guest 0: It has that ironic lilt that I'm known for.
Guest 1: Wait, so that's the news like we can pay to get your free opinions that we read on the Internet's.
Guest 0: Yeah, but now that it's gonna be on glossy pages.
Guest 0: We're talking about 80 perhaps 100 pound paper.
Guest 1: Wow Wow, that's weighty.
Guest 1: What does the pound in paper mean?
Guest 0: For with it per 500 sheets, it's how much of 500 sheets of paper away.
Guest 0: So a hundred pounds is Okay, isn't a ream 500 sheets.
Guest 0: Maybe I don't know.
Guest 1: There's no way of ream of paper.
Guest 1: It's 500 pounds.
Guest 0: Well, that's not a hundred pound paper.
Guest 1: Okay, I guess that's true.
Guest 0: Wait, maybe it's a pound.
Guest 0: Maybe it's per 500 sheets.
Guest 0: That's what I said, right?
Guest 0: Yeah Well, that's probably that stuff's like you just print stuff on that.
Guest 0: Whatever Joel continue talk about your news item.
Guest 1: My news eat an item.
Guest 1: I know it was about how to measure pounds of paper.
Guest 1: I had no idea know.
Guest 1: my news item is drawn from the the headlines that were on anime news network and I chose it because it's a pun.
Guest 1: Apparently the chars attack DVD players that were coming out are being recalled.
Guest 1: get this because they're a fire hazard.
Guest 1: I don't know if that's a recall or and I told you so Should they just mail everyone a letter?
Guest 1: that said we just said it was a char DVD player.
Guest 1: We didn't say it was in reference to chars counter-attack.
Guest 0: You guys should read the frying friend.
Guest 0: You should check that listening board They have at the local target.
Guest 0: that says all the stuff that went bad this week.
Guest 1: How was a DVD player a fire hazard?
Guest 1: How much power do you have to draw to play a DVD?
Guest 0: I remember the ps2 the.
Guest 0: when they remade the ps2 it could burn through discs because the laser was poorly Calibrated or something.
Guest 1: What do you just like?
Guest 1: hold it up to an attacker?
Guest 1: It shoots through the top and kills.
Guest 0: Careful man, I think loaded for DVD ain't nobody gonna try and rob my place ever again.
Guest 1: got a circle right in your chest.
Guest 0: Oh, man, but now I ruined.
Guest 0: Zone of the Enders - why did I?
Guest 0: I couldn't think of any video game titles.
Guest 0: I have like a hundred PlayStation games.
Guest 1: They're all too good.
Guest 1: You couldn't think of a crack you were thinking about.
Guest 0: what's that one with the steampunk robots?
Guest 0: Oh Ring of red.
Guest 0: that's the one I wanted to talk about.
Guest 0: ring of red.
Guest 0: Yeah, it's the the strategy game with oh That even come out.
Guest 1: that was a Dreamcast game dude.
Guest 0: no no that was ps2.
Guest 0: It's the one where you had a robot and you fight like another robot And you had like little ground crew that would fight other ground crew.
Guest 0: it wasn't that good But mostly because the missions were like 45 minutes long yeah, and you couldn't save during them.
Guest 0: I thought you were talking about that bumpy trot game that was terrible, and that was also on the ps2.
Guest 0: I know I was ridiculously awful.
Guest 0: Joel shall we move on?
Guest 0: I guess.
Guest 0: is the things of the day the things of the day?
Guest 1: What is this category even about?
Guest 0: it's about posting wacky wild things you find on the internet such as people might post on dig Or the slash dot mostly videos of a humorous nature.
Guest 0: okay, and to that extent.
Guest 0: I'm going to cheat.
Guest 0: I know this is anime day, but my video is in reference to a vidya game But it's a Mega Man and Mega Man had many animes.
Guest 0: Mega Man powered up.
Guest 0: no wait that was a game.
Guest 0: Well, so there's somebody made a Mega Man anime.
Guest 0: at some point.
Guest 1: It was hot TV.
Guest 1: take don't be a jerk take faith in that.
Guest 0: and this is maybe the best song that was ever made on the internet, and it's called oku Sen Mon and it is the story of one man's life as told to the tune
Guest 1: of
Guest 0: Wiley's Castle from Mega Man 2 which is Possibly the greatest song ever recorded during the 8-bit
Guest 1: era there.
Guest 0: Okay, during the 8-bit era during ever during the history of man's music Mozart B.
Guest 1: Take that Ave Maria.
Guest 0: Ave Maria Ave.
Guest 0: That's what I'm talking about.
Guest 0: so what you got here is a guy.
Guest 1: It would be better if they had a shrieking japanese man overdub it.
Guest 0: they could do that.
Guest 0: They should do that.
Guest 1: they should.
Guest 0: they were so close when they put Ave Maria into Cowboy Bebop.
Guest 0: You could have taken that extra step yoko kano.
Guest 0: you could have tried you could have believed in yourself.
Guest 0: But Joel, please take the floor.
Guest 1: uh My video clip is actually something that's probably going around on the internet forever But it's something I've sort of recently become aware of and that is if you go to YouTube and Google Kanye West The first video that comes up is a the video he made with daft Punk
Guest 0: for
Guest 1: I guess it's bigger stronger better faster.
Guest 0: It's the it's stronger.
Guest 0: You're thinking of the original Daft Punk song.
Guest 1: Yeah, well unfortunately.
Guest 1: Yeah, sorry I'm aware of daft Punk too, but yeah, Kanye Basically the entire theme of the video is straight out of Akira.
Guest 0: well He reenacts scenes directly from Akira and wears a pink shirt Which is well.
Guest 0: Kanye was doing that before, but you like to think he got inspired by Kinada.
Guest 0: There's so many things to talk about.
Guest 0: Kanye West re anime.
Guest 0: I think the most.
Guest 0: well This is not directly related to anime, but I think the most important thing to note here Is that Kanye West is sampling a band who?
Guest 0: Uses excessive sampling already?
Guest 1: yeah, you can't really sample electronic is weird.
Guest 1: Yeah, I feel like it was more of a collaboration than it was a sampling though because daft Punk appears in the video and It really is just their song with Kanye West in the lyrics, so it's more like a remix than a new song.
Guest 0: I don't know.
Guest 0: This is like when P. Diddy did The song about Biggie Smalls.
Guest 1: oh yeah every step you take.
Guest 0: But I don't know.
Guest 0: Kanye West may be a secret anime fan.
Guest 0: What's the secret?
Guest 1: He's just a nerd.
Guest 0: well he yeah.
Guest 0: But uh what's the song?
Guest 1: Are you thinking a fly guy?
Guest 0: Yeah?
Guest 0: That's the sky where the the guy on it?
Guest 0: Yes, loop on the third.
Guest 0: So there might be more than meets the eye here, but there is a storied history of hip hip-hop artists Enjoying Japanese culture as evidenced by say tell the funky homo sapiens protoculture song.
Guest 0: yeah Where he talks about playing sega games and how he's got to get xeno gears That's the type of game that relieves his fears.
Guest 1: get it from overseas to here way to go del I'm glad you're making enough money to buy video games and get totally baked out of your mind.
Guest 1: When is the album with the automator coming out again?
Guest 0: Yeah, you wish?
Guest 0: Okay, now on to the matter at hand.
Guest 0: Are you a regular listener a fast karate for the gentleman?
Guest 0: We hope you are.
Guest 0: you probably are because?
Guest 0: you know the internet is one big incestuous pile of Spreading stuff around like this.
Guest 0: so if if you listen to our show you probably listen to GeekNights and vice versa I Doubt that GeekNights has a much broader.
Guest 0: Yeah nice has a much bigger audience than us, but that's okay.
Guest 0: We're a little baby podcast.
Guest 0: we we got our couple three four five listeners, and that's all we need.
Guest 0: So if you listen to our podcast on the previous Saturday you heard all about the trials and tribulations of a man Who is not only dangerous?
Guest 0: He wasn't more dangerous He was most dangerous, and now we will continue the continuing saga of most dangerous guys with this.
Guest 0: talking about most dangerous guys to the death force and I know what you're thinking.
Guest 1: in fact most dangerous guys to the death force is Not a reference to the DVD itself causing you want to want to kill yourself though It should be.
Guest 1: it's actually a reference to the death force within the MD.
Guest 1: guys storyline.
Guest 0: well Joel There's nothing saying it can't be both.
Guest 1: This is a man skill actness on the soul of humanity.
Guest 0: many skilled authors will include Multiple meanings behind things.
Guest 1: so you're saying Koichi Ohada was like I should name this death force Because people are gonna want to kill themselves after they watch it or maybe they'll die during the middle like they'll just have a seizure.
Guest 0: How great would that have been then?
Guest 0: you wouldn't have had to watch the end.
Guest 0: what for the last ten minutes when everything turns black And white just like the atomic bomb?
Guest 0: shoot man.
Guest 0: That is so deep.
Guest 0: Wow I'm not sure if the atomic bomb did that but they set off a bomb in the movie I'm gonna.
Guest 1: turns everything black and white and atomizes.
Guest 0: it atomizes it.
Guest 1: This is a bomb capable of atomizing everything within four meters.
Guest 1: I hope that doesn't go off because it atomizes any part of the planet.
Guest 1: We're in trouble.
Guest 0: what I like is they say the bomb has a range of It can atomize anything within four kilometers, and then when they're setting it up They're like are you sure we're far enough away, and the guy's like we're five kilometers away We won't even feel it.
Guest 0: that I was like.
Guest 0: really it goes from atomization to nothing.
Guest 0: in one kilometer Cuz that's only like a third of a mile.
Guest 1: Are you sure?
Guest 1: we won't feel anything?
Guest 1: well you might want to put on this sunscreen.
Guest 1: This will protect you from atomization.
Guest 0: it take these goggles crybaby if you need them if you're a sissy, but whatever that's.
Guest 1: yeah I'm just gonna stand here.
Guest 0: so MD Geist has already been defined as the most dangerous soldier and when last we saw him he was releasing the cloud of deadly robots upon all human civilization.
Guest 1: Well on Jera not on all human.
Guest 1: all human civilization Stretches to the far reaches of the stars because we've successfully managed to colonize several planets.
Guest 1: and on Jera They were fighting a war to decide who would dominate the the gerunds themselves, or you know Earth because Earth was sort of the locus of power and they were throwing off the shackles of those oppressors 3,000 light-years away.
Guest 1: was it 3,000 light-years away?
Guest 1: I was just making a reference to the American Revolution because they said 3,000 miles away.
Guest 0: Hey, that's cool Because this is a lot like the American Revolution except with Bug robots that explode your head and eat you.
Guest 0: This is why does a robot eat a person?
Guest 1: That's what I'm saying.
Guest 0: is it Are they born that way or do they learn it?
Guest 1: Just to recap the death force was released by MD Geist But it was created by the regular army of Jera in case they were to lose the war and decided that it wasn't worth having Anybody alive on the planet if they weren't in charge.
Guest 1: as Joel described in the last episodes sour grapes And apparently to make it like ultimate sour grapes, they didn't just make.
Guest 1: you know, it wasn't a nuclear bomb already.
Guest 1: It's kind of weird sour grapes because you have robots that hunt people down and ostensibly shoot them with the enormous cannons that are on their arms.
Guest 1: But no what they do in fact is shoot other robots that are centipedes then eat people That's Slowly and With mandibles.
Guest 0: Yeah, which is like.
Guest 0: that's not how you want to die.
Guest 1: Like.
Guest 1: what if you?
Guest 1: if the only way to make this worse is if like you invented robots They killed people by exploding their reproductive organs So everybody came within like 30 yards of these robots would just have their testicles or ovaries burst.
Guest 0: I can make it and I die.
Guest 0: the robots rape you then eat you Or they eat you while they're raping you.
Guest 1: I think if they raped you then ate you it would.
Guest 1: I feel like if it was if both were happening at once you might Be dead before fast.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: Well, you might go.
Guest 1: I wouldn't want to have both of those things happening consecutively.
Guest 1: That's like a concurrent jail sentence.
Guest 1: I'm really hoping for the ten years concurrent as opposed to the a hundred years consecutive like, you know, I'd rather serve my Ten year ten ten year sentences concurrently as opposed to my ten ten year sentences Consecutively Which means you're gonna be in jail forever.
Guest 0: Yeah, except in this jail.
Guest 0: It's a metal robot penis Yeah, and it's invading your rectum, which is not where that's supposed to go.
Guest 0: But really I don't think a metal robot penis is really supposed to go anywhere at least not in a perfect world.
Guest 1: Well, they don't just to let you know that doesn't actually happen in MD guys But the robots do eat you in a most gory fashion - these robots have not learned table manners.
Guest 1: No, they're chewing with their mouth open stripping the flesh off Leaving the skull hanging.
Guest 1: I don't understand how they bite somebody.
Guest 1: and you know, these robots are big and they're metal.
Guest 1: How do you manage to bite somebody and just pull off their face?
Guest 1: Because that happens at least ten times.
Guest 1: somebody gets bitten.
Guest 0: that's what they just precision the precision only an Automaton could aspire to.
Guest 0: I feel like that.
Guest 1: they designed it just you know.
Guest 1: going back to the sour grapes theory It's like like they were doing a spitballing session and they're.
Guest 1: they're thinking what would the end of the world?
Guest 1: How would the end of the world be worse?
Guest 1: Nuclear bomb.
Guest 1: Yeah, I mean sure you've got you know.
Guest 1: explosion and then nothingness, but how we went to drag us out?
Guest 1: We don't want to destroy the planet.
Guest 1: We want to kill all the people.
Guest 0: The on it's fine.
Guest 0: If I could do whatever robots that hunt them down.
Guest 1: Okay, but how are they gonna hunt them down?
Guest 1: I don't know with guns.
Guest 1: That's a good idea.
Guest 1: Wait, wait, wait, what if they're centipedes centipedes that eat them?
Guest 1: What if they're centipedes that when they bite them they cause their face to explode off so that everybody else has to watch them Getting eaten with their face torn off and they only kill one at a time.
Guest 1: Give that man a raise even though he's gonna die because he's part of the regular army and by the time this goes off we're all dead anyway or Soon will be.
Guest 1: shouldn't we be investing money in other soldiers Johnson.
Guest 0: That's why we put you in the hallway.
Guest 0: So where is MD guys during this whole struggle?
Guest 0: why he's fighting the death force as was his original intent But not for any altruistic reason.
Guest 0: He just really likes fighting stuff.
Guest 0: But what he really likes is putting homeless people on cars and then driving them around.
Guest 0: So all the death force guys come in and he can shoot him.
Guest 1: Well, he doesn't even drive around.
Guest 1: I think the plan was to crash the car into the death force.
Guest 1: I never really got it.
Guest 0: I don't.
Guest 0: I don't even know why there was a car because where else would he put the homeless guy?
Guest 1: Yeah, or also why was the car underneath a pile of garbage?
Guest 1: Did you know MD guy spent 30 hours hauling debris onto the top of the car to camouflage it?
Guest 0: Yes, so you can wait there for seven days until just the right homeless guy came along sits on it.
Guest 1: Then he would drive it and stand on top of the.
Guest 0: he's got a thing of malt liquor hanging on the string.
Guest 0: Fortran I love that stuff and it's conspicuously out in the open.
Guest 0: the worst thing.
Guest 0: This is I shall drink it.
Guest 0: Oh, no now I'm in a car and there's robots pursuing me.
Guest 0: I Was gonna die anyway quick.
Guest 0: Let me Exposite the story of this show for 45 seconds while the credits were whole.
Guest 1: Yeah, you maniac you I'll leave these monsters and now we're gonna have them.
Guest 0: you get eaten well enough, but you're just killing stuff.
Guest 0: Are you crazy?
Guest 0: and so on and so forth.
Guest 0: the homeless people not really known for their coherency?
Guest 1: The worst part is after the car chase scene where he's driving around running away from the death force.
Guest 1: You know how he kills it.
Guest 1: He stands on top of another death force and shoots it with two guns Not even two big guns.
Guest 1: two guns that you could probably appropriately hold in two hands.
Guest 0: You could purchase them at the gun store.
Guest 0: You wouldn't even need a permit.
Guest 1: how tough for the death force.
Guest 1: if all he's got to do is have two guns.
Guest 0: They were gonna believe that they were intimidated by his most dangerous aura.
Guest 0: It works even on robots apparently being most dangerous.
Guest 1: It's just realizing you can shoot stuff.
Guest 1: I don't really see anything.
Guest 0: Nobody else seems to have figured it out.
Guest 1: You know what else?
Guest 1: nobody else figured out?
Guest 1: what's happening in this movie?
Guest 1: MD guys the first one had enough plot gaps.
Guest 1: This one stuff just happens literally.
Guest 1: You're you're watching it shoot to black Different scene.
Guest 0: something happened.
Guest 0: one of my favorite parts is where?
Guest 0: They figure out that MD guys is still alive.
Guest 0: the story As much as you can call it bad is that after this death force got released?
Guest 0: Another most dangerous soldier MD the first most dangerous old Andy Krause Krauser.
Guest 0: he builds this mobile city fortress where he's gonna save humanity because he's got a real god complex thing going on and You know he's rescuing people, but he's sort of doing it to further his own ego.
Guest 0: So they figure out that guys is still alive and They want to take out guys.
Guest 0: cuz Krauser's got some unfinished business with him or something.
Guest 0: He's not too.
Guest 0: Happy with that guys fella and What do they do?
Guest 0: it cuts to black and then it opens up.
Guest 0: on the next scene?
Guest 0: There's a scientist sitting next to a delivered cyborg, and he says hey You're a cyborg.
Guest 0: remember when you were working on that most dangerous project.
Guest 0: now go find my MD guys.
Guest 0: Well, then the next scene is he finds MD guys.
Guest 0: well, and he has a robot suit on.
Guest 1: What's even worse is like the entire story that I mean cuz it kind of follows that where the the I guess the cyborgs name is Eagle Did not catch that.
Guest 1: well, that's cuz they said it once.
Guest 1: he says Eagle you're especially dirty.
Guest 1: you come do this job, and you're thinking who the hell is Eagle and why is he dirty?
Guest 0: and He's a dirty girl.
Guest 1: dirty, but anyway dirty white boy.
Guest 1: all you see is Empty guys like walking through a swamp and then Eagle pops out and attacks him with
Guest 0: this super sweet robot suit
Guest 1: nothing After that like I mean or MD guys also, but they they explode out of water at each other multiple times But you don't know who's killing who?
Guest 1: Apparently.
Guest 1: and but while this is happening they then flash back and tell the entire Backstory, but also the current story in still frame animation with a voiceover mm-hmm.
Guest 1: How weak is that?
Guest 0: Well with 45 minutes you kind of got a budget your time Joel more like without enough money You kind of have to budget your animation.
Guest 0: I can't believe they got this thing made.
Guest 0: I'm pretty sure CPM at least in part funded the second episode really because they really wanted to get that made.
Guest 0: well MD guys was a big-ticket item back in like the 90s when there was nothing else out exactly.
Guest 1: Yeah the other I don't know.
Guest 1: this one was really weird cuz they have a bunch.
Guest 1: There's really one montage, but because the movies only 45 minutes long and the montage is you know probably like six minutes long.
Guest 1: It's about you know a tenth of the movie like.
Guest 0: It's more than a tenth.
Guest 0: It's this is worse than rocky five That's rocky four and those were great.
Guest 1: the whole movie is a montage.
Guest 0: I wish they would make a rocky movie like that.
Guest 0: I watch it every day.
Guest 1: It was all.
Guest 1: it's all just cut flashbacks to other rocky movies.
Guest 1: Part of this movie I could dig it MD guys - has flashbacks to Montages that were an empty guys.
Guest 1: Well.
Guest 1: They just got the montage straight out and pasted it into this movie.
Guest 0: Well, that's what we want all being efficient.
Guest 1: the montage is already a shortcut But how can we make it even more of a shortcut?
Guest 1: What if we include a montage from another movie?
Guest 0: Brilliant give that man a gold star Bust some caps.
Guest 0: god I love that movie.
Guest 0: that movie was much better than MD guys But we're not talking about the big hit starring Mark Wahlberg and Avery Brooks.
Guest 1: the worst part is the only end we've done in Phillips that this movie makes a foreshadowing is a Eagle first finds MD guys after he's finished fighting a death force.
Guest 1: You know how I know that because Eagle says that afterwards because there's no other indication.
Guest 0: Yeah, he says thank God That guy was fighting the death force otherwise I wouldn't have had a shot.
Guest 0: but we learned from this.
Guest 0: if you're willing to dig a little deeper that Eagle is a bit of a braggart and maybe not very self-confident because When the soldiers who apparently were not helping him, but we're kind of just hanging out in the helicopter until he got back They asked him hey, buddy.
Guest 0: How'd you get that most dangerous soldier?
Guest 0: He says I took him out in one blow.
Guest 0: That's all it took was one blow, and I'm not gonna reference all that other stuff I said about how.
Guest 0: don't worry about the fact that I'm missing both a leg and an arm Or both legs and both are now.
Guest 0: I'm pretty sure they strip him of his robot gear.
Guest 1: No, he cuz.
Guest 1: the way he beats guys is that he tases him from his chest.
Guest 1: Yeah after having his arm, and which is a pretty useful pose pretty funny.
Guest 0: I wish I could shoot the taser when his chest when his legs are from food.
Guest 1: There's this hilarious scene where he's in water, and he's floating up, and then his legs float up in front of him And he shouts ah my legs.
Guest 1: You know it's kind of like a cyborg would say it not like you or I would say Yeah, we're screaming out of pain like oh my legs.
Guest 0: He's like.
Guest 1: Oh, man.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: He's sort of like ah this is not optimal time-consuming and pricey.
Guest 1: But yeah, well they attempt foreshadowing.
Guest 1: because before they get before they get on the helicopter the Driver the robot driver of the death force because the death force is a giant robot But it can't drive itself it also has a robot driver.
Guest 1: The robot driver slinks out of the canopy and falls to the ground.
Guest 1: yeah And you see that happen and you think okay, so he destroyed the death force.
Guest 1: That's what that's referencing.
Guest 1: Wrong that?
Guest 0: what it's really referencing is the fact that jump all up on that soldier chicken pop her head like a grape while they're in the fortress Inexplicably.
Guest 1: how did it follow him?
Guest 1: How did it get on the helicopter?
Guest 1: did the helicopter even land?
Guest 0: Of course I don't know.
Guest 0: landed long enough to see Eagle Eagle's got The best name for a cyborg.
Guest 0: that's in like the top five eagle.
Guest 1: Yeah, if that's even his name.
Guest 1: It could be like weevil.
Guest 0: We like.
Guest 1: I just couldn't stand it.
Guest 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Guest 1: said he was dirty weevil See hanging out in bedsheets.
Guest 1: in this case you must choose the lesser of two weevils come on Master and commander other side of the world.
Guest 1: I saw it.
Guest 1: I didn't get that one.
Guest 1: I'm sorry Russell Crowe makes a joke about two weevils.
Guest 1: It was stupid.
Guest 0: so they bring him back to the city where Krauser who in my notes I have as Krauser equals blue asshole Because he's blue, and he's also an asshole.
Guest 1: well Krauser's not even that bad though like compared to MD Geist I would much rather have Krauser Krauser's got this whole Deity complex yeah, but at least he's not a deity bent on destroying you.
Guest 1: well
Guest 0: what I like is that the scientist when he's Analyzing Geist after they have him captured and this is the scientist that created the MD project as we find out he's talking about how Krauser is the imperfect soldier because Once he made Geist Geist has no ambition in life But to kill stuff and how Krauser is fundamentally flawed because he doesn't have that drive to constantly kill bigger and bigger
Guest 1: things.
Guest 1: Well, I think that part of the justification was that Geist's thirst for battle helps him regenerate because Krauser has to undergo this process that keeps him alive.
Guest 0: I guess yeah, they put him in this capsule and like shoot him with gas like in spider-man 3 But only.
Guest 1: but Geist is self-perpetuating because the thirst to murder Helps his cells regenerate.
Guest 0: so all we know we're in a satellite in space And he would eventually die.
Guest 1: or would he know because he would conserve energy by not growing a beard.
Guest 0: That's where all that cellular death happens.
Guest 0: all those lost skin cells it takes it never mind.
Guest 1: What the hell was he eating up there?
Guest 1: Maybe they shouldn't have put a life support system on a satellite?
Guest 1: I don't know.
Guest 1: These are just ideas that I'm thinking about out loud.
Guest 1: The other thing that's really stupid is Krauser is apparently the only one who can fight the death force even though humanity has developed a technology that makes them effectively Invisible to the death force, but they couldn't make enough of them.
Guest 0: It's like the ps3 cell process exactly.
Guest 1: they came out with this great product.
Guest 1: everybody wanted it for Christmas, but they under-produced and Everybody went out and bought.
Guest 1: I don't know like a hand grenade.
Guest 0: So now everybody's trying to buy the limited vibration Maskers on eBay for five times their retail value and then people are getting all Disheartened because they're like man.
Guest 0: nobody standing in this line wants to use the vibration maskers to fight the death force.
Guest 0: They just want to turn a quick buck.
Guest 1: Yeah, well what doesn't make any sense is they?
Guest 1: they only have enough to give it to The wing commandos.
Guest 1: well why don't you focus more energy on making those cuz?
Guest 1: then you don't need wing commandos.
Guest 1: The people on Jara have this problem with resource allocation.
Guest 1: first they build a death force First they build a death force then they build wing commandos And they just ignore.
Guest 1: like really like I don't know.
Guest 1: for death force or bomb one bomb destroys the planet.
Guest 1: Nine hundred and ninety nine thousand nine hundred ninety nine row or nine thousand robots.
Guest 1: I don't know how many you know.
Guest 0: it was nine thousand Ninety nine.
Guest 0: yeah, that was the maximum number, and it's not like like if there's no one another one would come back.
Guest 0: But for some reason they could only have nine thousand and ninety nine.
Guest 1: I don't know.
Guest 1: I guess that was like the Computer limit.
Guest 0: yeah, but what's stupid is it's like in Zelda how you could only have 255 rupees.
Guest 1: Yeah, well all you have to do is like.
Guest 1: you can just sort of have these.
Guest 1: you know death force located late locator blocking devices And if you gave one of those to me I could then wander the earth and kill all the blowing up death forces.
Guest 1: as a regular guy Well it seems to me if I could walk into them stand right in front of them and like feed them explosives or something.
Guest 0: They'd be like a little puppy.
Guest 0: You could just hold them in there your lap.
Guest 1: They like snuggle up and curl and then it would turn off and they bite your face off Because that's what they do.
Guest 0: even they just they like to bite.
Guest 1: What do you think?
Guest 1: what?
Guest 1: if?
Guest 1: I bet it would be even better if they just had a device that you could have like insect Camouflage where you just paint eyes on other things.
Guest 1: So they're kind of bite the face off of that like hold up a dummy.
Guest 0: you got like a scare.
Guest 1: Everybody walks around with a head attached to their shoulder like two of them on each side like I've got it.
Guest 0: Stop by quantum indecision.
Guest 1: Yeah, I now have a 60% greater chance of surviving 66%.
Guest 1: oh, yeah It's like zebras.
Guest 1: I can't tell which one to bite which is like the dumbest camouflage ever.
Guest 1: It's like okay, so all you stand right next to me And then the line will only get one of us, and it's like how would I just fucking run?
Guest 0: You will after all gets bit.
Guest 0: I Don't know.
Guest 0: I'm just figuring if they have these wing commandos, and it's shown that while there are death force that have guns.
Guest 0: They're not particularly adept at using them as my favorite seed of the movie is when okay?
Guest 0: So they have.
Guest 0: Krauser makes the plan that they're gonna use the jingo bomb.
Guest 1: No wait.
Guest 1: What is it?
Guest 1: What is it actually called?
Guest 1: Let's look?
Guest 1: I wrote it down because it was so stupid.
Guest 1: I thought the jig nix.
Guest 0: Get jig nix with it.
Guest 0: Is it that game where you build the tower out of wooden blocks, and then you don't want to knock it over?
Guest 0: I don't know.
Guest 0: You just pull out one block of Jenga.
Guest 0: I'm pretty sure it's jig nix.
Guest 1: That's a Jenga clone who came up with the jig nix bomb.
Guest 0: so right they're gonna take this.
Guest 1: Professor jig nix his theory of particle atomization.
Guest 1: who's professor jig nix.
Guest 1: I don't know.
Guest 1: he's that dude over there.
Guest 1: They flashed him.
Guest 1: He's like in a lavender coat with star glasses.
Guest 0: I'm like hey It's got the white boy afro Bitches.
Guest 1: better have my money shut up professor jig nix.
Guest 1: You've served your purpose.
Guest 0: platform shoes So right?
Guest 0: So they decide that they're gonna blow up all the death force at once.
Guest 0: cuz they're gonna.
Guest 0: They're gonna have the opposite of death force masking device.
Guest 0: It's gonna be the death force attracting device, and it's gonna simulate that they've got these things on a string.
Guest 0: How are you getting killed?
Guest 0: Basically you can put them wherever you do or do not want them to be.
Guest 0: But yet humankind is still in peril, and there's only one city left on earth.
Guest 1: We are retarded.
Guest 0: so yeah, so guys figures this out Thanks to the help of Eagle who has now decided that he doesn't much care for his human captors anymore But only down here cleaning up trash, but he only has a brief moment of indecision before he starts helping with humans again.
Guest 0: So Geist gets out of his captivity Rushes to where the the jig nix bomb is and Stops them from setting it off.
Guest 1: well.
Guest 1: No he doesn't stop him from setting it off.
Guest 1: What he does is he tears out the what was it called the like?
Guest 0: Of the attractor thing.
Guest 1: yeah, he tears it off of.
Guest 1: He just breaks it and then leads the death.
Guest 0: yes That's my favorite scene.
Guest 0: so after a brief respite with Krauser where they have a little battle and throw a couple words around mostly Krauser Geist is kind of strong sullen.
Guest 0: He's very passive.
Guest 0: stoic is a good word to describe guys.
Guest 1: Yeah, that's exactly yeah, so what I go killer is one of my favorite scenes of the OVA.
Guest 0: It's all 100 verse is when he's flying across the desert because now his football armor from the first episode has wings.
Guest 1: That was the upgrade that happened mid-season upgrade.
Guest 0: He's flying across the desert and all the death force are just placidly following him.
Guest 0: It's like total carrot on a stick.
Guest 0: Nobody shoot.
Guest 0: we've got to get closer.
Guest 0: We gotta get into biting range.
Guest 0: Yeah, we well to be fair They don't have a human head on my table.
Guest 1: They're not guns.
Guest 1: They shoot centipedes.
Guest 0: Are you gonna shoot somebody down with centipede?
Guest 0: You can shoot a centipede at him, and then he could bite him.
Guest 0: Yeah, I guess maybe listen centipedes only attack from the ground.
Guest 0: They're insects a very terrestrial base They know.
Guest 0: But if they were used if they were in midair
Guest 1: the guns do work because the the human city sees them coming and apparently The device that had protected their identity from the death forces or from the death force which I assume like these devices are all Over this fortress.
Guest 0: No.
Guest 0: No they only work on a personal level.
Guest 1: well, whatever.
Guest 1: That's another dumb thing.
Guest 1: then Maybe you should just build a really big one.
Guest 0: Maybe if you put them all together.
Guest 1: Yeah, but so then the death forces show up and They shoot him with like cannons and stuff, but it doesn't do anything.
Guest 1: Yeah And I'm thinking back to the beginning when guys took him out with two machine guns or I I remember now correctly.
Guest 1: He didn't actually kill the death force He just shot it.
Guest 1: it failed to shoot him and then crashed into the death force.
Guest 1: guys was standing.
Guest 1: How you don't even know.
Guest 0: they spent all their programming routines on the head biting stuff.
Guest 0: Navigation was a far second unfortunately.
Guest 1: well if they can just infinitely reproduce why not have them crashing into each other?
Guest 0: who cares Thousands of these nine nine thousand ninety nine to be specific, but wait Let's not leave out one of the most important parts of the movie, which is it's a very brief scene.
Guest 0: It's only a couple seconds, but when Geist is heading to where they're gonna set off the bomb He walks by the head of the Statue of Liberty Which in case you're not familiar is on earth?
Guest 0: Not on Jara not on the planet.
Guest 0: They're on in this movie.
Guest 1: Well, what's even dumber is the chick is back in this movie, too But she doesn't remember anything.
Guest 1: when do they make that clear?
Guest 1: they say it like maybe we'll cure you of your amnesia.
Guest 1: And I'm sitting there, and I pause.
Guest 0: well Joe you missed the line where she's like.
Guest 0: I feel like I've seen those dog tags before.
Guest 1: well Yeah But the problem is they never explain that she doesn't know who guys is because when she sees Krauser and she sees the dog tags she flashes back to Geist.
Guest 1: But that's how does she not remember?
Guest 1: it's like you just showed me a picture of him.
Guest 1: And then I'm thinking am I'm amnesiac?
Guest 1: has this movie killed some part of my brain metaphysical?
Guest 0: And I have to say it's breaking the fourth wall here, man.
Guest 0: This is crazy.
Guest 1: Yeah, it did kill a part of my brain.
Guest 0: Yeah, I wish it would kill all my brain.
Guest 0: Now my damaged brain Celeste's soldier on with the knowledge like why?
Guest 0: why couldn't it kill the MD Geist part of my brain?
Guest 0: You think it would least have?
Guest 1: that courtesy part is like the showdown between Krauser and guys to where Krauser throws Geist out a window, and then doesn't track him down.
Guest 0: and yeah, I like.
Guest 0: it's like Especially since guys girlfriend now Krauser's girlfriend cuz you know pitch sleeps around.
Guest 1: She's totally banging everybody on the home team.
Guest 0: yeah She's like he ain't dead Krauser, and he's like.
Guest 0: I'm pretty sure he's dead.
Guest 0: I threw him.
Guest 1: did you see cuz I had him.
Guest 1: I had him in the air, and then I threw him down.
Guest 0: I just I really.
Guest 0: I mean I think it's okay.
Guest 1: There's nothing we could possibly do.
Guest 1: I've only got a fortress full of soldiers that follow my every command And what do you want me to do?
Guest 1: devote them to finding the one guy who could destroy everything?
Guest 0: We've built Wasting resources on these stupid vibration maskers vibration amplifiers We got if only we can make one that made vibrations appear as they normally do.
Guest 0: I Put two of them together.
Guest 0: The next scene guys is sitting probably exactly where he was thrown down.
Guest 0: He didn't even bother to move.
Guest 0: and that's when Eagle comes in with all the guns which he calls by the way fire sticks Cuz.
Guest 0: apparently he's native american.
Guest 1: Yeah, I'm Jara native america.
Guest 1: That's why they named him Eagle.
Guest 0: You know well shouldn't he be like?
Guest 1: Well see when humans first arrived on Jara there was a very rich indigenous population of cyborgs.
Guest 0: He does have face paint.
Guest 0: He's got like a blue eye and a white face.
Guest 1: Yeah, I don't even know.
Guest 0: later on Eagle gets his arms and legs back.
Guest 0: We're not sure why but he does.
Guest 0: maybe that was his reward for bringing guys to him.
Guest 1: well No, they chained him up to.
Guest 1: they were gonna take you out because the doctor sent Eagle to get Geist.
Guest 1: Krauser didn't want him to bring guys back to the city.
Guest 0: Krauser was trying to kill him but Krauser failed even though apparently Krauser is so strong that he can grab guys vibrating saw And not really have any problems with that while it's vibrating.
Guest 0: He's like just holding it.
Guest 0: He's like yo stop with the vibrating saw.
Guest 1: enough already.
Guest 0: Geist with his ridiculous like 1985 Japanese street punk visor with like the one slit in it like he's Geordie LaForge And His half nate easily is wearing like his underoos and like this all these cables coming out of me.
Guest 0: He's like I killed.
Guest 0: well.
Guest 0: He doesn't even kill the doctor does he?
Guest 0: maybe he does?
Guest 1: it doesn't matter none of this matter.
Guest 0: Eventually they get they set off the jignix bomb.
Guest 0: because though like three death force that didn't decide to follow guys Everyone already killed the soldiers who are totally ineffective.
Guest 0: because oh my god robots I'm like what?
Guest 1: Quick, what do we do?
Guest 1: throw your guns at it?
Guest 0: I think let's do something else.
Guest 0: No.
Guest 0: We I'm pulling the trigger.
Guest 0: Somebody give me a spear, but fortunately the last death or the last wing commando to die Falls.
Guest 0: so the detonator lands perfectly on the three screws sticking out of the destroyed eye beam That's gonna set off the bomb like this bomb.
Guest 0: the apparently the detonation mechanism is.
Guest 0: you push three buttons So they're just happen to be these three screws sticking up and kaboom.
Guest 0: And that's when everything goes black and white except for the characters eyes, and maybe I'm thinking here I'm thinking Koichi's getting a little creative right and Guy sighs are blue and Krauser's eyes are red, but who's the bad guy?
Guest 0: As we soon find out it may also be Krauser as he kills a little kid for no reason.
Guest 1: well.
Guest 1: No he freaks out First.
Guest 1: no, that's the this that that scene Perfectly exemplifies everything that's going on in MD guys because when it happens They don't show it happening.
Guest 1: It's not like a little kid dives in front of guy.
Guest 1: Yeah, you don't even know how the little kid was there.
Guest 0: He could have been impaled on that spear when Krauser picked it up.
Guest 0: So you're telling me this crime happened before the fact.
Guest 0: you know Joel.
Guest 1: There's no evidence to come Contradicted.
Guest 0: well in criminal law if you shoot somebody who jumped off a building.
Guest 0: You're still guilty of murder.
Guest 1: That's how gogo 13 gets paid.
Guest 1: I murdered him.
Guest 0: Hell's yeah, I murdered him.
Guest 0: I don't care.
Guest 0: We jumped off the building.
Guest 0: Well, it's over there now because he doesn't have a head anymore But still the bullet is in the vicinity of his head, and that is a kill.
Guest 0: a million dollars Please plus expenses, and I went to cozy three times.
Guest 1: You signed the contract for incidentals, okay, I love the bread.
Guest 0: I love those breakfast sandwiches.
Guest 0: Sometimes I get them with him sometimes.
Guest 0: I'd like to go with turkey.
Guest 0: It's not really much, but yeah, don't usually eat turkey as a breakfast made, but I do.
Guest 0: I'm go go 13 Who's?
Guest 1: you're trying to wake up not go to sleep, but whatever.
Guest 1: but yeah like When that's that scene happens and all you know is that Krauser Apparently stab some kid in the guys, but guys is okay, even though he's just been stabbed He's been.
Guest 0: they got them all the way through.
Guest 1: It's a clean wound and you know, but that's like the end.
Guest 1: That's when the movie just ends.
Guest 1: Yeah, just ends Krauser's like oh, no The whole city blows up and guys survive.
Guest 0: Maybe?
Guest 1: no he does.
Guest 1: it shows him standing there doesn't it?
Guest 0: no no remember.
Guest 0: it shows a picture of his helmet.
Guest 0: It's all busted up and in the rubble.
Guest 0: I hope he's freaking to be continued dot dot dot question mark.
Guest 0: No, let's hope so.
Guest 0: it took him about 10 years to get the second OVA out.
Guest 0: I think we might be do MD guys three death force?
Guest 0: err They don't know.
Guest 0: none of it is dangerous or sir.
Guest 1: It's actually most dangerous.
Guest 1: Yeah, most dangerous Most dangerous or forced death.
Guest 0: oh Man I can't wait till that comes out.
Guest 0: Maybe they'll have MD Krauser part two.
Guest 0: Maybe it'll be green this time.
Guest 1: Who knows it?
Guest 0: Oh man this show.
Guest 1: It's so dumb.
Guest 1: This is one of those shows.
Guest 1: It's so bad.
Guest 1: It's almost worth watching cuz it's so stupid.
Guest 1: It's not bad like ikitosan or where you just get pissed off.
Guest 0: You're just watching this and you're like oh That's the thumbs up cuz you know somebody gave it the double thumbs up.
Guest 0: Go for it and Koichi Ohada is like fuck man.
Guest 0: I'm gonna do this.
Guest 0: I'm gonna make jenno cyber.
Guest 0: That's gonna be worse.
Guest 0: Koichi Ohada, I hate you.
Guest 1: he made both of them.
Guest 0: is it getting Ohada in here?
Guest 0: I?
Guest 0: Somebody give that man a medal.
Guest 0: somebody give that man a million dollars so it can make bottom of an ocean.
Guest 0: The metal will be made of concrete and attached to his feet.
Guest 1: I think that that about covers it.
Guest 0: I need a map.
Guest 1: did we stay on target?
Guest 1: is this good enough for GeekNights.
Guest 1: Did we follow the format?
Guest 0: I think so.
Guest 0: we tried.
Guest 0: Oh wait.
Guest 1: I forgot to mention.
Guest 1: I'm following the ikitosan rant someone actually talked about a great disciple Koichi.
Guest 1: or yeah, it's disciple Koichi.
Guest 1: That's not a good show.
Guest 0: It's not.
Guest 1: I've seen episodes of it.
Guest 1: It's pretty bad.
Guest 0: It's no master Keaton then.
Guest 0: well something.
Guest 1: Well, it's another like shonen show, but it's all stupid.
Guest 0: It's definitely Construction worker or something that's.
Guest 1: No, it's about some kid who's a loser, and he's like learning all kinds of different martial arts, but it's everybody's goofy and silly and the goofy and silly stuff.
Guest 0: You can only make fun of that for so long.
Guest 0: I wish there were more shows out there like MD guys and in fact People should point them out to us because this is a lot more fun to make fun of than ikitosan.
Guest 0: ikitosan We've seen like a hundred ikitosans.
Guest 0: Actually, there's two MD guys.
Guest 0: we discussed them both at length.
Guest 0: Yeah, MD guys to thumbs down thumbs super up because seriously I'm regretting giving this podcast the GeekNights because this is triple-a material.
Guest 1: We gave you our best GeekNights.
Guest 0: Well, we gave you our best to make up for what is probably a very awkward and shabby sounding recording.
Guest 1: so Our bad you get what you pay for.
Guest 0: yeah, well you knew what were you again coming into this?
Guest 0: we're fast karate accessible at www.daveandjoel.com.
Guest 0: we're like this every week.
Guest 0: seriously Good night internet man doing stuff with the format is hard.
Guest 0: Did you see that guy's email that said we should be groomsmen at his wedding?
Guest 0: yeah, did you see the reply I gave him?
Guest 1: No, did you copy me on it?
Guest 0: Well?
Guest 0: I mean it's in the email account.
Guest 0: I told him we would do it, but only if we can walk down the aisle to the Robocop theme or If we could be lowered by chain to the altar with the Terminator 2 theme.
Guest 0: I figured I'm never gonna get married so I might as well use it up on somebody.
Guest 0: good And I said the the vat of molten steel was optional.
Guest 0: But really if you're gonna go all out you might as well right.
Guest 1: so it's worth it.
Guest 0: He only gets married once Hopefully in this modern-day world Joel who knows divorce rates being what they are.
Guest 0: Yeah, you want to talk about?
Guest 0: uh whatever I will say that for when.
Guest 0: we're talking about that video, okay So you like a fish.
Guest 0: so we're doing introduction leader news news to music thing.
Guest 0: Wait what what we're not doing?
Guest 0: they'll do the post-production.
Guest 1: well no, but do we have to follow that format?
Guest 1: well Yeah, this is gonna be crazy.
Guest 1: We don't do formats.
Guest 0: That's what I just said.
Guest 1: I think that should be the news item.
Guest 1: fast karate has a format.
Guest 0: Yeah, right.
Guest 0: We're gonna try.
Guest 0: We're gonna give us our best shot GeekNights.
Guest 1: You need to make me a copy of that.
Guest 0: This isn't gonna work.
Guest 0: I'm just.
Guest 0: I'll be the moderator.
Guest 0: Okay So what we're gonna.
Guest 0: Do is.
Guest 0: we're gonna say I'm I'm Dave and I'm Joel and this is fast karate for the GeekNights on Whatever day, this is supposed to come out July 25th, and then we're gonna say you know hey Joel.
Guest 0: How's your day going today, and then we'll figure that.
Guest 1: okay Do I have to talk like I'm a like?
Guest 1: erudite slack-jawed 49er from San Francisco circa 1850?
Guest 0: well you don't Nugget still got my tooth though tooth Joel.
Guest 0: Complain how topical that you would bring up teeth.
Guest 0: Maybe I'm over exaggerating this laundry story, but I think it's pretty good.
Guest 0: It's a thing that you would not expect normally to happen, but anyway Shit how's it go to you?
Guest 0: I remember how the music goes.
Guest 0: do you do do do do do do do do do do do?
Guest 1: Okay, you have to do the entire podcast with me gesturing at you threateningly with this knife.
Guest 0: You're right that knife can't cut shit.
Guest 0: Give me the girl To hand this knife tonight on.
Guest 0: you know it's fat Aussie.
Guest 0: we act like we're gonna talk about anime But we talk about commando instead shut up.
Guest 1: You know you like it all right.