Rym:
Rym: It's Thursday September 6th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is big night tonight.
Rym: air hockey.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Warm today Super warm today even though it wasn't warm outside.
Scott: It was warm inside.
Scott: cuz the air conditioner my office doesn't work.
Rym: Wow, I would have just gone home.
Scott: Yeah, it's the IT guy who's also sort of like you know the manage all the physical things in the office guy.
Scott: It's his job to get that fixed.
Scott: he called in and put in the guest work order whatever.
Scott: they came yesterday They didn't have parts.
Scott: they came today with the parts Still not working.
Rym: Wow and it was actually pretty warm today unexpectedly.
Scott: Yeah, so I've been.
Scott: we've been melting in the office all week.
Scott: I'm totally leaving early tomorrow.
Scott: There's no way.
Scott: I'm staying there all day in the melting.
Rym: see the last time that happened to me at my company has happened twice Both times in like the first couple days of August.
Rym: where be sitting there working on something.
Rym: suddenly the power goes out.
Rym: Great, no computers.
Rym: What am I gonna do in an IT job?
Scott: Don't they have UPS's?
Rym: Yeah, and the data center not on like my office.
Rym: so then all right power comes back on AC doesn't come back on and It's Yonkers, and it's hot and that building is an old converted warehouse.
Rym: I mean, it's nice office space now, but it got mighty warm mighty quick, and I went home along with everyone else.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not spending a lot of time at work tomorrow.
Rym: That's for sure though It was particularly miserably hot today.
Rym: Just because uh I didn't get a chance to shower this morning.
Rym: I wonder why I didn't get a chance to shower.
Scott: It's not my fault.
Rym: You could know my fault that Scott spent an hour in the shower doing an hour in there.
Rym: Well, I mean because he tried to buy those shoes back at Otakon.
Rym: They didn't match.
Rym: So he spends forever in there, you know am I gonna put the hair up?
Rym: and I can put the hair down maybe in a bow.
Rym: And so I wake up at like six and I look and Scott Scott.
Scott: So I don't think you're up at six because I remember waking up at six But I also remember waking up at six thirty Are you sure?
Scott: Because I definitely got out of the shower at seven because I was awake by the yes seven.
Scott: when we usually all leave for the Train station when we're usually all already it seems like any day when I shave you always yell at me for being in there too Long.
Scott: so I think I just can't shave during the week without you yelling at well You gotta stop putting on all that makeup and you gotta stop putting your hair up actually about shaving.
Scott: Finally, how long have we been shaving the old-school way?
Rym: Uh God a couple years now, right?
Scott: I was still on my first tub of cream.
Scott: Well, it's unlike all you other people I don't use an inordinate amount of it.
Rym: I don't use the tubs.
Rym: Don't talk to me I'm just.
Scott: I'm just saying like my dad also he uses way too much.
Scott: He already be burned through a tub in like a few months and I'm like you're using too much.
Rym: Not really I think.
Rym: the thing is you don't shave that often and your hair is actually not.
Rym: It's not quite the Brillo pad.
Rym: you'd expect it to be like.
Rym: it seems.
Scott: it's a pretty Bad, but the point is that even though I shave less often.
Scott: I also use less cream.
Scott: Anyway, I finally I mostly ran out.
Scott: I ran out.
Scott: There's still some in there.
Rym: I got to the point where it's just kind of crappy to use it.
Scott: Yeah, I could probably shave with it But you know not and also recently I have been noticing that.
Scott: you know Like I remember when I first started shaving the awesome way that it was like wiping my face of the sponge and it I Realized it hasn't been like that in a while.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I opening up the new tub I realized why I've been using the dregs of some tub of.
Scott: So now using the new tub, it's back to the sponge on face hair goes away action.
Scott: It's good times.
Rym: actually now that I've gone with the puck a full-size pocket shaving soap Even if you use like stupid amounts of it lasts for over a year.
Scott: Didn't last you a year.
Scott: You're already on your second puck.
Scott: No He's only doing it for a few months.
Rym: that first puck was a half-sized puck and the second puck is twice as big Because it's a normal sized puck.
Rym: and so far.
Rym: It hasn't changed in size at all.
Scott: I'm not a fan of your puck.
Rym: I like my pocket sandalwood.
Rym: I really like sandalwood.
Scott: your puck sucks.
Rym: I had lavender before but also sex.
Rym: But anyway speaking of all that I don't really have a segue here at all.
Rym: But I'm gonna do something crazy.
Rym: I got a geek back.
Rym: Oh, no Yeah, we got an email from a guy named Walt from Canada.
Rym: didn't say where in Canada somewhere up there.
Rym: Hey You know, I can't really make fun of Canadians because where I grew up in Michigan There wasn't that much of a cultural divide between us.
Rym: and I'm Terry.
Scott: I'm not making fun of Canadians.
Scott: I like Canada like Canadians.
Scott: I like hockey.
Scott: I like all sorts of Canadian things.
Scott: It's just they do say hey, they don't say it.
Scott: as much as people making fun of them Depends in parts of Ontario they do yeah, but I have met Canadians and they say it it.
Scott: that's what they do It's it's true.
Rym: Honestly, there is only one Accent of English that is ever.
Rym: it doesn't bother me.
Rym: I do like.
Rym: I don't think ah that person but I can't help.
Rym: but Chuck a little bit and I feel bad about it.
Rym: But I cannot talk to anyone from Minnesota Yeah, anytime.
Scott: so it's sort of like talking to Swedish people.
Rym: I don't mind that that doesn't bother me.
Scott: No, it doesn't bother me either one.
Scott: but they both make me laugh because they're so silly.
Rym: The only accent that makes me laugh is a Minnesotan and only if it's like the crazy Stereotypical like.
Rym: I can't believe this person actually talks this way.
Rym: I thought that was only in the movies, Minnesota Yeah, they also say a in Minnesota a. What was that stupid joke that someone told us we were playing D&D at RIT and someone was like, yeah Minnesotans That's what you get when Canadians get lost in the woods something like that.
Rym: Something might have been vice versa I don't know.
Rym: I don't know but I got I'm.
Rym: Well, I'm glad you listen to the show, but I might rip in your email a little bit here.
Scott: Oh, you're gonna tear a listener a new one.
Rym: You know, I almost did that Dave and Joel voice.
Rym: I don't even know why.
Rym: yeah Basted right.
Rym: So hi guys really enjoy the show.
Rym: You're informative in the topic of anime and highly entertaining when you go on tangents and talk about off the topic stuff Then swing back to the topic reminds me myself and my old friend from high school college You do sound like two buds just talking over a soda or a beer.
Rym: I don't know why I suddenly started doing.
Scott: I don't drink soda or beer.
Rym: Yeah, I drink.
Rym: I don't really drink soda anymore either.
Rym: I drink soda water.
Rym: Anyway, now, uh, here's the part that I'm kind of curious about.
Rym: Hopefully women will not come in and mess this up Huh?
Rym: Parentheses.
Rym: Hey, I like women.
Rym: comma good for cooking cleaning sex Etc.
Scott: Yeah, if you're making a silly joke like hey get back in the kitchen Lowell But not like seriously.
Scott: get back in the kitchen.
Rym: When my buddy got married our fun came to an end.
Rym: We have seen you needed a semi-colon there, dude.
Rym: We have seen or spoken for eight years.
Rym: Dave and Joe.
Rym: That's all one sentence.
Rym: God Dave and Joel have a similar conversation style, but you can tell.
Rym: now I want to point out that Walt is obviously mixed up.
Rym: Dave and Joe.
Scott: Yeah, you can tell Dave is Joel and Joel is Dave.
Rym: granted a lot of people originally thought I was Scott and Scott was Rym.
Scott: That's why we started doing that thing at the beginning of the show.
Rym: Of course people also thought I was Hispanic.
Rym: Yeah, well one person, okay.
Rym: All right God is one long sentence.
Rym: blah blah blah blah.
Rym: You can tell Dave's senses forward slash sharpness have been slightly dulled by marriage.
Scott: Well, Joel's married and Dave is not married.
Rym: Women will do that to you.
Rym: dame them and their sex as Joel might say.
Rym: now that was Dave But I must admit I too have fallen for the wilds I believe you meant wilds of women and I am now married.
Rym: so guys stay strong and keep on Podcasting.
Rym: all the bells.
Rym: all the best.
Rym: What Walt's from somewhere in Canada?
Rym: now up I'm not gonna just come out right and say that was kind of sexist.
Rym: I don't think I need to get into anything like that.
Scott: That was pretty sexist.
Rym: The point I would like to make because I see a lot of people say things like this like ah, yeah Women will screw up your geekery.
Rym: They won't let you play your board games and they won't you know.
Rym: A lot of people say things like this and that's really people you worked with at IBM.
Rym: God Not all of them just a few of them.
Rym: Yeah, but that's really kind of not true at all.
Rym: and One I'll note the fact that Emily and I have been dating for like three years and she is just as geeky if not more so than me All the other girls that all our friends date just as geeky.
Rym: no problems there.
Rym: And I think the thing you see where like a girl drags down the guys geekery and makes him kind of lame That's that has nothing to do with gender.
Rym: guys do that to girls just as often as we've seen in our group of friends before.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen plenty of geeky girls, you know They.
Scott: they get with some guy who's not so geeky and they never hang out with us and they never do anything cool Even though they're all into the coolness and then as soon as they dump that loser guy They're back hanging out with us doing all sorts geek stuff.
Rym: So essentially now also I'd like to say that David I don't know how you mixed up Dave and Joel because they actually refer to each other by name all the time Which we don't yep, and I don't know.
Rym: I don't really see that either.
Rym: I mean Dave's relationship before.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into that though I think he was a little bit bitter about the breakup.
Rym: if you from the show you could kind of get that.
Rym: but This has nothing to do with sex.
Rym: It just has to do with people dating people who don't have similar interests and then dealing with it.
Scott: It also has to do with people sort of can you know going out with someone for whatever reason and then sort of?
Scott: Controlling them or allowing themselves to be controlled by the other person.
Scott: if you marry someone and you like to work on cars Why if if they're demanding that you give up your enjoyment of working on cars to be with them?
Scott: Why do you want to be with this person and do they really?
Scott: Love you and respect you if they want you to stop doing the other things you enjoy in order to be.
Scott: what kind of Relationship is that yeah?
Scott: I mean it has nothing to do with men and women.
Scott: it could be gay people were one like a gay guy And then a gay guy who's not geeky and they get together and the non geeky gay guy makes the geeky Romantic relationship.
Rym: it could just be friends where it could just be friend.
Rym: friend is really kind of like that god that calm.
Scott: It could be any sort of relationship between people.
Scott: you know friends are more than friends or family even where you know you have Kids and then you know because you have kids your kids tell you to stop doing something.
Scott: Then you do it or something like that Your parents.
Scott: you let them tell you what to do and what not to do.
Scott: do what you want.
Scott: Don't let anyone tell you you can't do what you want.
Scott: And if they do tell you to do something other than what you want They obviously don't care about you or they care about you less than you think they do or you need to tell them hey listen This is what I like.
Scott: learn to deal with it or else I don't need you, and if you think that somehow a woman or anyone.
Rym: I mean people seem to think we're gay.
Rym: so a guy whatever an alien a furry.
Rym: I don't know if anything could stop the geekery in the front row crew.
Rym: I would just like to point out that every girl in the front row crew and gasps.
Rym: There's a lot of them Actually I think almost now they don't quite outnumber now another, but there's still a lot too many penises.
Rym: They're all just as geeky if not more geeky than us without exception And they definitely do the opposite of slowing down the geekery.
Rym: yes for sure Right that's all I got.
Rym: so we're glad you listen.
Rym: That's all cool, but a little sexist there.
Rym: Yeah, you might want to Loosen up, and I will say I often Kind of suspect anyone who's sexist like that of being latently homosexual, but I'm not gonna get into that slide.
Rym: I'm not gonna make an ad hominem or anything.
Rym: I'm not.
Scott: that's all you.
Rym: not that there's anything wrong with that.
Scott: That's all you.
Scott: All right, I got a real news now.
Scott: Okay, man.
Scott: All right with you.
Scott: Not really all right.
Scott: So I'm not gonna.
Scott: the actual news itself is gonna be quick.
Scott: Is that some guy who's a chemist at Cambridge Cambridge is the right way to say it?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: He wrote a scientific paper of some sort and he put the old Creative Commons on there As a smart person does and it was published by Oxford University Press.
Rym: Did they follow the terms of the Creative Commons?
Scott: like no they blatantly violated the terms of the Creative Commons?
Scott: And they're charging like $48 for a copy of this thing double Oh, he even had to pay $48 to get a copy from them.
Scott: also There's a FUD group called the prism coalition that is going around sort of saying that open Scientific documentation is no good.
Scott: it prism stands for the partnership of research integrity in science and medicine and FUD stands for fear Uncertainty and doubt.
Scott: right that's the news.
Scott: someone violated Creative Commons license.
Scott: fuck them, but the actual thing I want to say is this of all the things that people publish in the world don't you think that?
Scott: scientific research Done in an academic setting paid for in part or whole by taxpayer dollars Should be freely and publicly available to all.
Scott: Nothing in the world I think makes more sense to be freely and publicly available and not copyrighted or restricted in any way.
Scott: then scientific research Which everyone can get the benefit of learning and expanding their knowledge from that they partially or wholly paid for.
Rym: yeah I mean, I can't add to that.
Rym: I agree 100%.
Rym: now We're not saying you know if a private company does private research And they want to.
Scott: yeah, if you're a drug company, and you invent some wonder drug You know patents last X years whatever and you patent it because that you don't copyright things like that you patent it Which means you tell everyone what you did?
Scott: But they're not allowed to do it at least not in a country where the law is enforced.
Scott: That's how patents work and they also.
Scott: if you have some sort of trade secret Then the patent office keeps your patent a secret also, so no one can actually find out until the patents over either.
Rym: Well actually I believe the way that works is you just don't patent it.
Rym: It's just a trade secret.
Rym: if someone steals it from you.
Rym: You're fucked.
Scott: it depends on the situation on the lawyer.
Rym: It depends on the country.
Scott: yes But if someone paid for their own research, and they invent something and they want to keep how it works a secret.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: Because I'm not I can't take a black and white information should be free position on it because it's a complicated issue.
Rym: Yes, even though I do Jen.
Scott: I'm not talking.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I'm not taking the greater state.
Scott: I'm not talking about the greater issue here, which I still might say something.
Scott: what I'm talking about is When a teacher a professor had a college, what was it?
Rym: a private or public college?
Rym: Oh, it was Cambridge.
Rym: That's right Never mind.
Rym: I wasn't listening to you at all.
Scott: no if you write a paper and You're getting paid in some way by tax money Especially if you're getting paid in some way of a tax money And you thought up something new and you want to share it or you should be sharing it with the whole world Shouldn't people be able to read that shit for free.
Rym: I mean forget all that.
Rym: even The professor put this out under the Creative Commons, so uh get a lawyer and sue the shit out of that journal You should you should freakin sue the mighty all hell out of Oxford for doing this.
Scott: I would get mad lawyers on them.
Rym: So yeah granted unless he licenses under the Creative Commons in Contradiction to previous agreements he may have signed regarding said research.
Scott: who knows about that?
Rym: because as you know internet Tends too often not do a lot of research.
Scott: yep, but just be warned anything the prism coalition says is probably BS and It really sucks that all scientific most scientific research is published in scientific journals Which are fine except that they're not free.
Scott: they cost a lot of money And if you go to like a college you can read them because the college library buys them or you hope they buy them
Rym: alright, otherwise
Scott: They're not free and a scientific information is Secret even if your tax money paid for it, which it probably did and it sucks balls
Rym: things of the day.
Rym: So we've never gone to the Burning Man festival.
Rym: I'm not really gonna get into what the Burning Man festival is other than I go one day I'd love to but it's not like a con where you can just like show up for a weekend and then leave.
Rym: It's not the kind of thing where you just kind of go in and look at everything.
Rym: It's uh There are pros and cons to it.
Rym: It's an interesting exercise.
Rym: I think a lot of the people who do it make it out to be a lot more than it is But at the same time I think a lot of people don't understand just how much it actually is.
Rym: but one thing that is always a staple of Burning Man other than the Burning Man is The amazing crazy art and music and things that people do there just for the ever-living fuck of it.
Scott: Well, you get a bunch of hippies together arts gonna pop out that.
Rym: that's how it works Especially because the crowd that goes to Burning Man tends to be the fairly technological hippies.
Rym: They're not anarcho primitivists.
Scott: Well, there's techno hippies in this sort.
Scott: It's also anarcho primitivists.
Scott: There's all time all kind.
Rym: However, it's I think I'm general a lot of the people there.
Rym: the impression I get are the kinds who read all the blogs And they all blog about their experience and they really yeah.
Scott: But anyway, there's a lot of hipsters there.
Rym: check out these pictures of this art installation.
Rym: That's some hippies made.
Rym: I'm.
Rym: I can't believe they made something this cool.
Scott: Well, you got like.
Scott: how long is Burning Man?
Scott: like?
Scott: a week or two?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: you got a lot of time on your hands.
Scott: You don't have much to do.
Scott: There's a lot of cool people hanging around.
Scott: What's gonna happen?
Scott: Making cool stuff?
Rym: just seriously check out these pictures.
Scott: plus a lot of people go in with a plan to make cool stuff.
Scott: So, you know they must.
Scott: it's not like they spur.
Scott: the moment came made something awesome.
Scott: They probably planned it out got there and just did the deed.
Scott: Is that it?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: All right So this here is a video of two dudes one dude.
Scott: It's playing the violin.
Scott: quite well He's not like the greatest violin player ever, but he's better than me better than I'll ever be probably.
Scott: Considering I'm probably never gonna even try.
Scott: I read an article about how hard it is to play the violin and why and yeah I'm never gonna be able to play the violin But he's good at playing the violin.
Scott: and behind him you have a guy who is rocking the two turntables and he is okay Using his two turntables spit making some beat beats of various kinds that are enjoyable and these two men combine their music in a fashion, which is most pleasing to the ear of Scott.
Scott: it Reminds me many times of say a samurai Champloo soundtrack having sex with the noir soundtrack Maybe.
Rym: ah, it is quite hot.
Scott: I must say this is the kind of music that I want to listen to but it's also the kind of music that Is only available from two guys on YouTube in one video, did you even do any research?
Rym: maybe that cuz they have a website.
Scott: Maybe I did not do research.
Rym: So you didn't look at for all, you know, they have CDs in the stars.
Scott: Maybe they do and if they do I might buy it for the first time in how many years I might buy a CD?
Rym: I have to agree.
Rym: I mean, this is pretty amazing.
Scott: I Generally like things like this anyway, but got that anyone who says again that you know the record companies They're sucking because of this that and the other thing they're sucking because this is not the music that they are making and this is The music that I want.
Scott: and if they made all their music as cool as this I would be mighty broke mighty broke.
Rym: So in the grand scheme of life There are a lot of different ways you can compete with your fellow human beings for fame and glory and pure Dominance over one another like boxing.
Rym: Yeah boxing or sports or board or anything like that tickle fights baseball Oratory podcasting podcasting.
Rym: but there's one that is near and dear to both myself and Scott independently of one another and the fact that we came together and Have had epic epic battles in this arena as made us realize that we really need to do a show about air hockey.
Scott: Well, I was arguing previously that perhaps air hockey should be a Tuesday show because it is sort of a game and it is mostly played in the video arcades Even though it is not a video game.
Rym: However, as you might well know Scott has been saying lately that it is video game season and I looked at the GeekNights calendar.
Rym: We have Tuesday shows booked for like the next two months So we'll just.
Scott: I guess I do consider air hockey a sport as well as a game.
Scott: So we'll throw it on Thursday.
Scott: cuz Sports that that doesn't fit into any other days.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Why not now?
Rym: I don't think there's anyone out there who is unaware.
Scott: but very briefly You know, I don't know do they have air hockey in other countries?
Scott: It was I mean air hockey was invented in the u.s.
Scott: In like the 70s.
Scott: So it's you know, I really not sure how much it spread to around the world.
Rym: Yeah, it also doesn't help that the majority of air hockey tables out there are really shitty, but we'll get into that.
Scott: Yeah, we will.
Rym: so air hockey is a sport where it's kind of like a basement parlor sport.
Rym: You got a big table.
Rym: It's like about the size of a pool table billiards if you have a real air hockey table Yeah, and it's flat and it's polished and there are a million little holes in the surface.
Scott: There's a motor that generates air Air compressor which attached to a motor.
Rym: it pushes air out of all of these holes evenly Hopefully if it's a good table, so air is coming out of the top.
Rym: two sides have goals.
Rym: I have two people.
Rym: each have a paddle that you put down.
Rym: kind of looks like according to Wikipedia a sombrero.
Scott: It does kind of look like a sombrero.
Rym: However, I just got to say that the Wikipedia article links to the article on sombreros And I've edited a lot for Wikipedia in the past.
Rym: But that is the saddest article I've ever seen and that is the saddest picture of a sombrero.
Rym: I think the sombrero article be bigger.
Scott: talking about the origin of the sombrero and you know where it came from Maybe some famous people who wore sombreros just so sad.
Rym: sombreros gained Popularity and that picture is just so.
Rym: I weep for it.
Rym: I feel like that sombrero was crying.
Scott: It's like the long-lost Wikipedia article.
Scott: someone please research sombreros and fill the article in.
Scott: I feel bad for it.
Rym: Yeah, they got like a bird without a wing-a-ling But anyway, so the object you have a little puck that floats on the air So it is effectively almost friction-free.
Rym: It's a lot like an ice hockey puck on ice only it's a plastic disc on air And your goal is through sheer force of manliness or womanliness because I've known some women who are really super good at this game.
Rym: And it's not like the game is.
Scott: it can't favor him is like his geek back Not that guy.
Rym: No But it's awesome and I love it and it's one of my favorite sport slash games in the world.
Scott: Yeah, you have a plastics disc and you're whacking it back and forth and it has almost no friction.
Scott: So it goes really fast and the other person is trying to hit it back at you and you're hitting a piece of plastic back And forth ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha and you're trying to get it in a goal and that it's pretty cool right there.
Rym: Now I've been super into air hockey since I was a little kid.
Scott: Well when I was a little kid even before air hockey we had knock hockey Which you basically have this wooden board with a wooden puck and a little tiny red hockey stick And you sort of sit on one side and your friend sits on the other side And you take turns hitting the wooden puck back and forth.
Scott: it usually devolved into hitting your friend Sometimes but me and my friends we actually sort of played knock hockey pretty seriously Like.
Scott: we even had the the real boards that had little nets behind them.
Scott: so air hockey was just sort of a Grown-up version of knock hockey in a way so bad.
Rym: You know when I was a kid arcades kind of still existed and weren't so bad yet.
Rym: So I went to the arcade a lot and there was a really good air hockey table there.
Scott: So I played it whenever I went to an arcade as a kid.
Scott: They always had air hockey.
Scott: It was just a staple.
Rym: every single arcade had it no matter what and I played it so much that one time for Christmas my Parents got us an air hockey table.
Scott: I never actually got.
Rym: it wasn't a good air hockey table But it was bad.
Rym: I mean it was better than nothing and I played it every day every single day for God like eight or nine years straight.
Scott: Yeah, you can get air hockey tables really cheaply like for a few hundred bucks.
Scott: They also you know they double as other things like little miniature pool tables and things But they're always small and crappy.
Scott: it really the eight-foot full-size Real-deal air hockey tables are the only thing that really count and everything else is sort of crap and doesn't work.
Rym: So in way as a kid in middle school.
Rym: in high school This is my sad story of Rym learned a lesson and grew up and he became an adult and learned about the real world.
Rym: So I played air hockey a lot, and I'm not gonna like be humble about this.
Rym: I was super freakin good at air hockey and Up until college.
Rym: I was absolutely undefeated And I played against people in the arcade.
Rym: I played against my brother against my family people who cared about the game Little mini ad hoc tournaments we'd set up.
Rym: No one could beat me.
Rym: I just I think part of it was that I was probably the only kid in the entirety of the state who actually Practiced air hockey.
Scott: well I mean you think about it.
Scott: air hockey is not something that a great number of people think or care about.
Scott: so if you Spend it You know just a minimal amount of time Trying to practice it or you know think about it on any deeper level you're gonna beat the vast majority of people at air Hockey.
Rym: yep That's one thing we learn.
Scott: later is Scott and I both like imagine if there was a fighting game And you were the only person who actually learned all the moves.
Scott: even if you sucked at it You'd probably win a lot beating the vast majority of people in the world just because no one else has bothered to look at it.
Rym: Yep, I mean if two people who've never played air hockey before play the outcome is almost entirely random.
Rym: But it's I mean if one of those people is even played air hockey a few more times.
Rym: They're probably win yep But you know super undefeated, and I remember I went to RIT and one time the topic of air hockey came up And I was like yeah, I'm super fucking good seriously, and I was.
Rym: we played a bunch.
Rym: I still remained undefeated for a little while and then Our friend Luke one day.
Rym: You know it came up.
Rym: I'm in his presence, and he was like oh well I'm super good at air hockey too.
Rym: now at this point I know that I'd never really played outside of my environment And I'd never played against a skilled person like someone who had also cared about air hockey as much as I did
Scott: or at least a little bit yeah
Rym: a little bit and He absolutely smoked me.
Rym: I was crushed.
Rym: my undefeated record was gone forever.
Rym: I felt like a dumbass.
Scott: well because see what he did is It's pretty much you go through your whole life playing a game against people who don't even think about the game at all and you Think about it a little bit.
Scott: So you play against someone who thinks about it a little bit also and Luke's basic idea was that he would defend.
Scott: He just defended no matter what he put his full concentration on defense.
Scott: He actually cared about it.
Scott: He thought about defending he concentrated on defending and he never let you score and then when he got the puck Sometimes he would hit it really hard in the same way every time and maybe a slightly different way And he would go in after you know an amount of time.
Scott: He would just endure until he got all the goals and he would defend no matter what.
Scott: so it was really hard to score.
Rym: It was even worse than that because his defense He'd basically sit there defending hoping that you get frustrated and start scoring on yourself, which often happens.
Scott: Yeah, I still score on myself.
Rym: Yeah, but that was it.
Rym: I realized that wait a minute crap there are other people who are also good at this game and I started practicing and playing a lot and then Scott also got into it.
Rym: the two of us played against each other Pretty much at every opportunity.
Scott: Yeah, if there's a real air hockey table, we will play it like nuts.
Scott: However, if there is no real air hockey table, we don't play it.
Rym: So it's gotten to the point now where I know there are people out there.
Scott: I pray and I'm sure there are people out there who are better at air high possibly this list of air hockey Champions, they might be better than you I think.
Rym: but I would say of the all the people in the world who have ever played air hockey or ever will play air Hockey, I think we're in the top 1%.
Scott: what happens if suddenly there's a huge burst in air hockey popularity?
Scott: It would be fucking awesome I know but then we wouldn't be anywhere close to the top 1%.
Rym: No Cuz if there was a sudden boom we have a head start and you can guarantee we'd be practicing every single day and join in All the time, yeah, but the problem with that is it's sort of like baseball where baseball is a solved sport.
Scott: now We're back in the day when it was new and on and sort of you know Yeah I'll totally solvable and it'll come down to just pure reaction times and math.
Scott: and but air hockey is currently unsolved I I think and it's it's very so it's it doesn't?
Scott: they've made a lot of progress but it's still unsolved and people haven't you know put the full effort of human ingenuity into figuring out the Absolute best possible air hockey.
Rym: probably because most human beings don't give a rat's ass.
Scott: but if air hockey becomes suddenly populated popular the game will be solved and it I imagine that many people currently good at air hockey will be left behind by the newcomers playing in their new fancy way.
Rym: but now Scott and I are in kind of a predicament because we play against each other all the time and To be honest, we don't know a single human being who can even come close to beating either.
Rym: Yeah, I
Scott: don't personally know anyone but I imagine that these people on this list of champions But one
Rym: if you listen to our show and you're out there I'll say right now if if you are ever in our presence and there is an air hockey table within a reasonable distance We'll play against you.
Rym: No question.
Rym: We'll even pay cuz good guy.
Scott: It's a dollar big deal.
Rym: at most It's a dollar but it said because none of our friends will play with us.
Rym: so I can only play air hockey if Scott's there and he can only play air hockey if I'm there because No one else will even consider playing with this.
Rym: in fact, they actively avoid playing with us.
Rym: that totally sucks All.
Scott: right now let's let's talk about air hockey the game itself for a second.
Scott: in the 70s some guy made a game where there's like a table and there were two mallets and there was a disc and you hit it back and forth or whatever and it was like a low friction surface and something like that.
Scott: and Basically from
Rym: that spawned
Scott: air hockey which is created by Brunswick Which is a company that makes you know pool tables and stuff like that and to this day Valley dynamo slash which is I guess is a division of Brunswick, I think right it's still the same company that invented the game is the only company that makes air hockey tables that are worth a damn and They're the only cut the only air hockey tables that are like, you know approved for you know, real tournament play that counts.
Rym: I mean, I'll be honest I generally just will not play on a table that is not made by them because it's not worth it.
Scott: when you see their tables And you go, oh that's a table that counts and you look at all the other tables around you go Oh, yeah, I guess that is the only table that counts and it makes perfect sense.
Scott: I mean They make perfectly rectangular tables that are flat that have even air where there's no gimmicks or anything on the table.
Scott: There's no distracting colors.
Scott: The pucks are uniform and they actually work.
Scott: the goals actually work.
Scott: the the puck things actually, you know, it's Everything about them is standard and perfect.
Rym: The puck is the right size and shape.
Scott: They're great.
Scott: So if you see an air hockey table that says photon or pro style or Something like that, then it counts.
Scott: if you see a table that says hot flash to Hot flash to sort of counts because hot flash is also a table They make that is in the same style as the other tables and it's the same.
Scott: It's the right shape and size and everything, but it's all covered in neon lights and shit.
Scott: So those neon lights are sort of distracting.
Scott: so the table doesn't really count.
Rym: So playing air hockey itself because we really get into it.
Rym: I kind of almost look at it.
Rym: I'm not gonna say like I'm not being serious here But it's kind of like a martial art in that every time you run a foul of someone who actually cares about the game People all kind of have different styles of play and different grips and different techniques and different shots.
Rym: like Scott has this one kind of shot and I have this one or two.
Rym: like it's my special move.
Rym: and like Like if I'm playing against someone who sucks, it's like I'm gonna score now.
Rym: and Scott is the same thing.
Rym: He does this one thing.
Scott: when I'm playing against people who suck All I do is hit the puck straight at the goal every time.
Scott: because think about when most people play air hockey They just try to hit the puck at you not really trying to aim or not knowing how to aim.
Scott: So very often they'll hit the puck in a way that doesn't go.
Scott: that wouldn't go in the goal Even if you just had your hands in the air.
Rym: That's the reason I lost my first game ever to Luke because I had never played against someone who could shoot worth of shit And I never defended because the puck never even hit my goal.
Scott: So all I do and I play against someone who sucks is aim at the goal every time and the pucks coming at the goal and they have to defend defend defend defend defend defend constantly and Even if they can do it successfully, they probably can't do it for a very long time, but it's gonna go in.
Rym: Yep, the other thing I do against people who can't play very well is I just I hit it Absolutely as hard as I can and as fast as I can every time and it just totally throws them off and they freak out
Scott: As long as you don't mess up and accidentally get it in your own goal.
Scott: because that's the only reason that I don't always Hit it as hard as I can because sometimes you know it the way the angles work out it ends up in my own goal Which yeah, well, that's why for the last two years.
Rym: I've been a little bit above Scott in terms of wins.
Rym: I've been I've won every set of games.
Scott: We've played not every set again.
Rym: Yeah In the very least you can't deny that it.
Rym: while would.
Rym: this year I beat you Quite a few more times than you beat me a handful of more times.
Rym: Maybe I beat you eight times.
Scott: I don't think it was eight.
Rym: you beat me three times.
Rym: I think it was more than that and all the times you beat me were tied game And then you won by one.
Scott: all the times you beat me were tied game.
Scott: who know?
Rym: two of the games I won by two Whatever.
Scott: It's pretty close.
Scott: Stop acting like you're something, you know way better or anything.
Rym: I think I am.
Scott: No, I don't think you are fine.
Rym: That's a challenge.
Rym: We should next next time we find an air hockey table.
Rym: Let's film our match and we'll see we will.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, you'll get a camera.
Rym: In fact, I'm willing to put money on it.
Scott: I'll pay some money.
Rym: Maybe I'll put a hundred bucks up on our next two out of three game of air hockey on a professional table.
Scott: We'll see about it.
Rym: Oh, you're not taking the challenge.
Scott: I just I'm not a betting person.
Rym: Oh, so you're not confident your ability to win.
Scott: No, yeah, I just don't bet on things.
Scott: If I was as to be a hundred percent sure thing for me to bet on oh so it's not a hundred percent sure thing.
Scott: No, it's just ninety nine point nine percent sure.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah, I'm willing to put up a hundred bucks.
Scott: I'm not a betting person.
Scott: You know that.
Scott: and just because someone refuses to bet on something isn't some sort of evidence that I know what?
Rym: I'll put a hundred Bucks up if you beat me, I'll give you a hundred bucks if I beat you.
Rym: You don't owe me shit.
Scott: That's fine We'll do that.
Scott: I Could do that.
Rym: Sure, but against a skilled player you can't do that because they If you shoot at their goal, they just block it.
Rym: you have to be subtle about.
Rym: you know fast slow fast slow twiddle it up.
Rym: You make two shots that are kind of part of a three-shot combo
Scott: where
Rym: the first two missed their goal on purpose But bounced back to you in such a way that when it bounces back at the right angle you then hit it and the banking Shots gonna go in and
Scott: you can also like add power to pucks that you know, you hit it really hard.
Scott: It bounces around it comes back.
Scott: It's going slower than when you hit it.
Scott: But if you hit it again now it's going faster than your original hit and you can get the puck going pretty fast if by hitting it a whole lot
Rym: and Much like ping-pong but to a much less degree you can put in English on the puck But thinking that that will have a significant effect on your game is not going to get you very far.
Scott: No, I mean it has a slight effect.
Scott: But because there's so little friction between the puck and the table whether the puck is spinning or not barely affects how it moves.
Scott: It does slightly affect how it might bounce off the wall because that's when it's actually gonna hit something.
Scott: But usually when it hits the wall, it sort of stops spinning.
Rym: Yeah a much better strategy if you're playing against someone who's good but doesn't know a lot about air hockey is to Act like you're putting English on it and talk about how you're putting English on it and they'll totally just freak out and lose.
Scott: Yeah, so according to Wikipedia Someone apparently wrote in all sorts of air hockey strategies and things which I must admit these are things I do not do.
Scott: They show like some grips for the puck for the for the paddle that I do not personally use.
Scott: I just sort of grip it like it's you know in my fist.
Rym: So I'm 50/50 on those because on one hand because I use the same grip Scott does though I think I hold my hand up a little higher Kind of like a claw coming down.
Scott: Yeah, something like that dragons claw.
Rym: Yeah, I Used to try all these other ways of holding it like with the fist out Like I tried some defensive offensive things and eventually I realized that they were all shit compared to one of them.
Rym: Yep, but it's got me.
Rym: I'm 50/50 because on one hand that might just be Wikipedia BS or People who are too into air hockey just kind of over analyzing it.
Rym: but at the same time There's the same thing in table tennis.
Rym: I used to play a lot of table tennis and I actually switched to a Chinese grip and it was far superior.
Scott: Yeah, it's just.
Scott: you know, I I've never actually played in tournaments or with professionals, you know I'm basically like it's sort of like being the best person in your town to pick up basketball.
Scott: You don't have NBA skills.
Scott: You're not even close to NBA skills.
Scott: You don't know anything about real basketball.
Scott: But you're better than everyone, you know.
Scott: And you're better than everyone in your town because they're just a bunch of schmucks who'd also don't know about NBA basketball.
Scott: So this stuff on Wikipedia that says air hockey strategy, I imagine someone who's actually practiced professional You know quote professional air hockey because even professional air hockey is amateur.
Scott: I'd probably lose but I'm also considering practicing these things so that maybe I won't lose.
Scott: You don't have a basement.
Rym: I mean I almost would put it in the living room because I'd be okay with that being in the way and the only reason I decided Well, we decided not to was just that we can't even play DDR in there because the floor is not supported So well.
Scott: an air hockey table is a big eight foot long by like four or five foot long table.
Scott: It's big as a motor in it.
Scott: It's heavy as all hell.
Scott: It's huge.
Rym: I mean space wise.
Scott: I would turn a loud motor.
Rym: I would totally consider putting it like in that space behind the piano like in piano, but I could put it there.
Rym: But I'm afraid it would make the floor sag.
Scott: I'm afraid it would fall through the floor eventually.
Rym: Also the fact that I don't think anyone would appreciate tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech tech Tech tech tech tech.
Rym: four hours a day every single goddamn day.
Scott: No, I don't think they'd appreciate that either.
Scott: But if I owned a house with a basement I would go immediately to Valley Dynamo.
Scott: the only makers of worthwhile air hockey tables and purchase an air hockey table are pretty much immediately.
Rym: I Guess the moral of this is just if you have never played air hockey.
Rym: It's a great sport.
Rym: It's really really fun.
Rym: You don't need to be super athletic or anything.
Rym: You just need good eye hand coordination.
Rym: You got to be quick.
Scott: You gotta use your hands in your arm and your wrist.
Rym: Yep, you see you probably got to be able to stand up or something to that effect.
Scott: Yeah, it really sucks cuz it's it's.
Scott: it should be a handicap accessible game.
Scott: It's a game where you just sort of use your arms But you got to be able to reach sort of deep into the table.
Scott: So I guess they'd need some sort of chair to like sit them up or something.
Rym: I also kind of rock back and forth and get up on my toes a lot and kind of shift my weight around and I can't say exactly when or why but I do that a lot.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes I lean down just because the tables eight feet long So you need to be able to reach four feet out into the table on occasion.
Rym: Well, plus really to be good You need to be able to lean back and lean forward and change your angle and view depending on what's going on.
Rym: I mean if you're really on the offensive you kind of want to lean forward and get like the Momentum in the offensive, but if you're on the defensive you want to lay back and stay low so you can see everything more clearly.
Rym: Mmm, yeah stuff like that.
Rym: We take this game way too seriously possibly, but yeah, well, I remember it's sort of like taking skee-ball seriously.
Scott: Yeah, only versus if those versus skee-ball.
Rym: It's kind of like that fascination game Sort of sort of yeah, but if any of you ever want to play air hockey against us, we're totally up for it.
Scott: Yep, air hockey is awesome.
Scott: Everyone should play air hockey.
Scott: It's still.
Scott: it's one of the few things you'll still find in every arcade.
Scott: So if you see an air hockey, you should play it especially if it's made by Valley Dynamo.
Scott: also don't play air hockey's that are not made by Valley Dynamo because they'll just ruin you because they're not right.
Rym: and Remember the if for no other reason the reason you want to play air hockey is that in your town if you practice at all You'll be better than everyone in your town and you can just declare yourself the almighty air hockey god of your town.
Rym: No one will be able to beat you and you can hustle everyone.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I always thought I would do that and I try like I wanted to try.
Rym: I can't.
Rym: I can't hustle because but Some people call me egotistical maybe arrogant big-headed sometimes.
Rym: I don't know why But any time I think like oh I could totally hustle this dude I start to try to make myself lose and then suddenly I think what the fuck I can't lose to this guy and then I win.
Rym: Haha, I just can't do it All right.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: I really want to eat some tacos.
Rym: It's about taco time.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.