Rym: It's Thursday October 25th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm goth and this is goth night tonight.
Rym: We got the goth goth goth goth.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So Rym did I get home at my usual time today?
Rym: Uh no you got home a little bit late.
Scott: Oh, why do you think that might be?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: maybe because I lost all track of time not being at work today.
Scott: No, no that wasn't it.
Scott: I actually did get home late in usual.
Rym: It's hard to say I mean It feels like it was I don't know years ago that you went to work And I've just been living in this house all this time.
Scott: Yeah, that's what it feels like when I'm home sick.
Scott: It's except.
Rym: I'm not sick.
Rym: It's great.
Scott: Yeah, it won't be great in another week or so.
Rym: Yeah, you gotta go back to work, but I gotta keep going back to a job.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but anyway I leave work and as usual I go down in the subway, and I wait for the choo-choo.
Scott: So I'm waiting and I'm waiting and sometime.
Scott: you know some days you go wait longer than others.
Scott: But this day I had waited about the usual waiting time you know and it sort of passed And it's like huh, I've never had to wait this long.
Scott: I realized not only was my train not coming the uptown six train I hadn't seen a single four or five or six train go by in either direction.
Scott: That's not good, and the platform was getting mighty full.
Scott: and since I was not at a major Express stop There weren't so many announcements going on.
Scott: and usually if the already Didn't you think it would matter?
Rym: the last time I heard an announcement on the subway?
Scott: it was attention passengers Delay In some places.
Scott: you can hear the announcements if we're at Grand Central at 14th Street.
Scott: You can hear the announcement.
Rym: I don't know where else.
Scott: So it also depends a lot on the person using the intercom.
Scott: you know and how well how good they are at it.
Rym: I love the guys on the subway itself.
Rym: like that.
Rym: the actual trains who they'd make stop burger burger next up.
Rym: We're so little effort in.
Rym: they're like next opposite next up is gonna.
Scott: Yep, anyway Eventually the train comes.
Rym: so did you fight your way onto it?
Scott: No, it actually what.
Scott: it was pretty crowded, but wasn't that crowded?
Scott: some people just didn't get on wusses Which is good, and it takes me to 14th Street.
Scott: basically They're like announcement announcement something something something and what I gathered from the garbled announcements was that there was some sort of criminal investigation at 125th Street and That they had to turn the power off at 125th Street Which can only mean that there was something involving someone getting pushed on the third rail and police had to go down into the track Probably
Rym: just a bum jump.
Scott: It could have been a bum jump.
Scott: It could have been a bum push.
Scott: who knows what it was?
Scott: All I know is that whatever it was Basically caused the four or five and six trains in both directions.
Rym: now for those of you who aren't New Yorkers or Americans or anything?
Rym: The four five six is pretty much the most important subway in Manhattan.
Scott: Yeah, it caused it to stop completely pretty much in both directions for a long time.
Scott: And you know someone asked us last week during questions week about what we thought about Mandatory minimum sentencing kind of stuff and we said that stuff sucks.
Scott: well on the other hand You know obviously there was some sort of crime involved because there's a police investigation right now What the crime was?
Scott: it could have been pushing it could have been killing it could have been who knows right?
Scott: It could have been who knows.
Scott: but when you sentence someone right you know you take the crime into account.
Scott: someone You know robbed a bank, okay?
Scott: I really think that they need to take into account more than they already do.
Scott: well Damages caused by your well example.
Rym: well I'm gonna say there's been legislation Pending or come up periodically in a lot of places and I read an article a couple years ago where there was one part of Texas where they actually passed a law to this effect where if you're in a car accident yeah, and it's shown that you caused it and like fully like it's your fault and You delay people like they're they're statutory fines to make up for the delays You have caused to the economy as a result of blocking like rush hour traffic.
Scott: Yeah, and this is the thing that I think is good.
Scott: actually because you know you can't figure out I mean I guess in an ideal world right you would figure out Every person who is delayed because of the problem you caused and exactly how much Damage it did to each individual person and make you pay them all right.
Rym: the thing is you can't do that.
Rym: the thing is then There's these that that almost brings up the problem of the stupid mistake lottery where you know a lot of people drive poorly But not poorly enough to crash every day, but just pretty poorly where you know they're not paying attention And they run a red light or they're not paying attention And they take a turn too fast and usually they're lucky enough like there isn't a car in the other lane.
Scott: They and also our traffic system has enough safety buffer is built into it where you can kind of drive shittily and still get Away with it, but a lot of people they they're not driving extra shittily.
Rym: one day They just the buffer isn't there and they end up hitting someone and whoa betide You caused the accident the day that Bill Gates is trying to drive through Yonkers.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: so I think you know a good solution is just okay since we can't figure out everyone you have to pay Right exactly how much damage you did to each and every one of them.
Scott: We'll just take a bunch of your money, and we'll give it to the state and that I guess will alleviate taxes.
Rym: I'm of the model the people all their unit of damages should go to the state no matter what.
Rym: yeah even better They should go into a specific fund that can only be used for civil infrastructure improvements.
Scott: Well, I guess you know if it's traffic related.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and if there are other things then anytime there's punitive damages.
Rym: They should somehow be set up where they can only be put toward fixing the problem that caused the crime in the first place.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean basically all I'm trying to say is that if you commit a crime You know and you know there's the direct harm.
Scott: your crime does you know?
Scott: you?
Scott: you robbed a bank you took a thousand dollars in The bank.
Scott: well you go to jail for robbing a bank, and the bank gets a thousand dollars back Whatever, but if that caused like you know the bank to close down and now a bunch of small business people couldn't do their Business at the bank all day and that caused all this other trouble.
Scott: But you got to take that other trouble into account.
Scott: usually it's traffic You know subways and cars because that's the easiest place for this kind of thing to have.
Scott: well I thought it happens in other places And I think when you do that we got to let you know.
Scott: look you look at all the trouble you Actually caused.
Scott: doing your bullshit.
Rym: Well is the thing I mean you pay for it.
Scott: cuz.
Rym: then the flip side of that is the no harm No foul side of what if you?
Rym: Committed a big crime, but the actual damage you it did just by a by chance were very very low.
Scott: well then I Actually think if you know that the something should only be a crime if you're infringing on someone's rights or causing harm And I think well well well well here's the problem with that.
Rym: Yeah, if you if you allow no harm no foul in the legal system, then if you Attempt a crime and fail it there's nothing to stop you from attempting it again, and you're not punished in any way.
Scott: But you see I think actually Attempting a crime right I guess failing You could.
Scott: you could just say okay?
Scott: You're you're you know we have to you don't punish them in terms of financial damages like we're taking money.
Scott: Oh, I say look you're a danger to society.
Scott: We need to put you in a jail.
Rym: so a low example for I run a red light And I don't hit anyone.
Rym: well.
Rym: I didn't hit anyone.
Rym: no ticket great I'm gonna always run red lights.
Rym: cuz the odds are I'm not gonna hit it because now you're a danger to society.
Rym: So dangerous society, but you were saying before that oh, we just go after the actual damages you caused.
Rym: What if you haven't caught energy?
Scott: I didn't say I mean having.
Scott: I didn't say just go after the damage you caused.
Scott: I said make sure that people know The damage they caused.
Scott: that normally isn't paid attention to okay.
Rym: so you want an asymmetric system where you have the fines and punishments for crimes and if you happen to cause a problem for someone else unforeseen like You're in a minor car accident, but because you're in a tiny minor car accident Someone rich behind you has
Scott: nothing to do with someone rich behind you.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: you got to make the person realize.
Scott: look you know you you because of your negligence You caused this incredibly large amount of traffic to be packed up for hours.
Scott: They'll care and you have to get to make them realize that if someone caused all that trouble You know make them pay some money to the state.
Rym: But then you set up a system where if you're in an accident in rush hour you ever cause a problem that has unforeseen consequences.
Rym: Freak accidents could.
Scott: it's not an unforeseen consequence.
Scott: It's totally for a scene.
Scott: You know that if you get an accident in rush hour You'll cause a lot of traffic compared to getting in an accident.
Rym: Are you going to pay our fine?
Rym: representative of the problems you have caused?
Scott: Not represent, but you know they should just make them realize look We're adding on this extra thing because of all the trouble you cause all you're really bad and sort of encourage.
Scott: You know safer driving during rush hour because make it worse to get an accent or you know stuff like that.
Rym: I think the best way around that would be if the police officers who respond to accidents once they know whose fault It was we're just not polite or maybe yelled at him laid into a little bit.
Scott: Maybe I know you don't actually just got to play weeaboo with everyone who I got a.
Rym: here's a great way around this.
Rym: if you Cause an accident and the police are able to determine that you cause the accident Which is a science by the way Then you have to appear for whatever length of time at the place where you caused the accident.
Rym: So people driving by can see you with one of those puritan signs like the scarlet letter.
Rym: That's fine, or you have to wear a badge some kind of yellow badge on your shoulder.
Rym: that with a picture of a car I don't know.
Scott: I delayed like take those police in.
Scott: was it Taiwan or Thailand?
Rym: China Like See I'd wear the Hello Kitty.
Scott: I like bots Mars.
Rym: I was about to say liking Hello Kitty is just a side effect of liking bots Maru.
Scott: Yeah, I like but tomorrow Hello Kitty sex.
Rym: Hello Kitty is kind of awesome though.
Rym: Not really can't really underestimate yellow Hello Kitty.
Scott: Well, there's that other guy that the pachaco.
Scott: I thought you would like him.
Rym: So speaking of Underestimating people the federal government in the United States set up something called the terror watch list You know because Americans are deathly afraid of terrorism.
Rym: terror watch this like Osama bin Laden Despite the fact that there really has been almost zero terrorism in the history of the United States.
Rym: and you know Oh, there's terrorists everywhere and we got a yeah But yet there hasn't been a terror attack since September 11th, and it's really easy All those terror attacks.
Scott: and weren't there terror attacks in other countries?
Rym: Oh, yeah Cuz remember we arrested those kids who were on vacation and then we looked at their vacation footage and said yeah They were filming Disneyland so they could blow it up, but it's just films of them laughing and running around Disney anyway.
Rym: So we've set up this terror list where people who were suspected terrorists are on the list and we like give them extra scrutiny and if they try to fly we don't let him.
Rym: and Well, there's almost a million people on that list.
Rym: Now.
Scott: There's a million terrorists.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: We're in big trouble the curt.
Rym: There are seven hundred and fifty five thousand people on the terror watch list.
Rym: They've adding an average of two hundred thousand people per year.
Rym: 548 people every day as far as our government concerned become terror suspects.
Rym: uh-huh, uh And even better all the studies they've been doing lately.
Scott: So when is everyone gonna be a terrorist?
Scott: what year?
Rym: I think I think it's kind of like when I was in high school and they had student of the week.
Rym: and I remember I was like, oh great student of the week cuz someone cool was student of the week The first week of school.
Rym: but then Some and they someone else was student of the week and someone else was student of the week.
Rym: And then I discovered that they've set it up to where effectively Every single person in the school will be student of the week at some point in their four years.
Rym: They keep track everyone gets it.
Rym: Everyone gets it once.
Rym: Yeah, so this terror watch list.
Rym: I Don't know what else I can say about this news.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's staggering to me that it still exists and even better.
Rym: It doesn't even work.
Rym: They do a bunch of studies and they show the people on the list can just get on planes anytime They want.
Scott: the answer to this is obvious, right?
Scott: They date.
Scott: somebody decided that it was a good idea to come with this list.
Scott: some politician You know would would use this list like I made this list as part of their campaign to show how tough they were in terrorism.
Scott: Whatever right politics generated this list.
Scott: someone in the government It's their job to manage this list and then I want to lose their job.
Scott: So they're just constantly adding people to list and that that explains the whole thing.
Scott: It's just bureaucracy.
Rym: What's great is the list is really poorly done like there are so many cases you can see these on FARC all the time where like an Infant will be denied from flying because it happens to have the same name as some guy who might be a suspected terrorist.
Rym: Yeah Awesome, yeah, the u.s.
Rym: Is really kind of great right now, but luckily I Think it's gonna come to an end because I'm not.
Rym: I wanted to talk about politics for my news But Scott didn't want me to for some reason.
Scott: I'm just kind of tired of it all but in the u.s That the Republican everyone knows it sucks GeekNights.
Scott: talking about it isn't telling anyone anything new.
Rym: I'll enlighten everyone out there who may not be a u.s citizen.
Rym: the Republicans in the United States are currently almost unelectable and don't have any candidates.
Rym: so Their reign is over and it's pretty much for the presidency coming down between Hillary Clinton and Barack Obama.
Scott: And you know be awesome like if like if Hillary gets like Democratic nomination or something like Obama goes Republicans something like that.
Rym: I don't think that's gonna happen.
Scott: No, but that'd be crazy cool.
Rym: Yeah But but I but I thought Ron Paul was gonna save the day.
Scott: Yeah, I think Ralph Nader and Ross Perot win before Ron Paul.
Rym: god Ralph Nader.
Rym: yeah, you were cool in the 80s.
Scott: He's really tall.
Scott: Someone is freakishly tall.
Scott: I saw Ralph Nader once.
Scott: he could like fucking play.
Scott: He's like Michael Jordan.
Rym: He's really thin though like really kind of gangly and skeletal like Michael Jordan like Skeletor.
Scott: Yeah, he's also old.
Scott: He's like 60 something.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's all we have to say holding tall.
Rym: so this guy in 1955 named Homer Jacobson You know you said Homer Jay and the fact that you didn't say Simpson through my brain for a loop.
Scott: Jacobson not Jake Simpson, but Homer Jay.
Rym: the Simpson comes next anyway.
Scott: He was a chemistry professor in Brooklyn, and he wrote a scientific paper entitled information reproduction in the origin of life.
Rym: and The paper may or may not have been so great.
Rym: It wasn't so great actually.
Scott: well.
Scott: He's in the paper He's speculated on the chemical qualities of Earth in the hedean time which is billions of years ago, and such-and-such.
Scott: right regardless.
Scott: Some creationist nutjobs saw his paper written in 1955 and they decided that because of this one scientific paper That creationism is true, and here's the evidence this one scientific paper.
Scott: now I Don't want to go into the usual Creationist you know stuff of why they're wrong.
Scott: because they're wrong they're wrong, but I do want to say one thing here, right?
Scott: If the creationist right it's it.
Scott: This is so backwards.
Scott: There they say the science is wrong And then you use a scientific paper to say that science is wrong.
Scott: you if you say the scientific paper is right because it's scientific Then all the other things that you disagree with are right because they're scientific.
Scott: It's like you can't have it both ways.
Scott: you can't use some scientific papers as evidence and some are just bullshit.
Rym: You know it's a course like the less like Lesson we learned in the new game from valve called portal where you can't have your cake and eat it, too.
Scott: It's much less.
Rym: you have a portal gun.
Scott: well It's sort of like how you know they treat their Bible.
Scott: they sort of pick and choose the parts they want and they think they Can do the same thing with science, and they don't realize it's it's sort of an all-or-nothing.
Scott: you either You know you don't have to be here to every scientific paper is all true.
Scott: But you the fundamental tenets of science and the scientific you know process you either go by them, or you don't.
Scott: You can't really.
Rym: so why did he?
Rym: why specifically did he retract the paper?
Scott: I didn't actually say retracted the paper yet, but he retracted the paper.
Rym: So why Scott did he I mean did he do it just because the creationists were using it?
Rym: did he do it because the paper?
Rym: Was old and incorrect?
Scott: well it actually says here that Dr.. Jacobson's retraction is the noblest is in the noblest tradition of science.
Scott: This is according to the editor of American scientist.
Scott: They said that his letter shows The distinction between a scientist who cannot let errors stand no matter the embarrassment or of public correction.
Rym: All right, well I people who cling to dogma I've actually been reading more about this and yes the paper has many wrong assertions in it and the scientist who wrote it basically said You know what I mean.
Scott: it was written in 1955 and contrary to a creationist would have you believe Older information is not more correct.
Scott: You know it's like they always act like this is older.
Scott: It's ancient wisdom therefore.
Rym: It's more correct if we go find how older religion is then Christianity's got Some competition from the Jews.
Scott: it's got the Jews a competition from like.
Rym: I guess you know cyclopeans Zeus might have something to say.
Scott: yeah this paper.
Scott: I guess in 1955 was you know legitimate science, but since then We've learned better than that and we realize it's not so right.
Scott: and since it's being used in a bad way This guy was was smart and he got rid of it.
Rym: But I think is I don't think it was that noble of him because he's old enough to where he's not going to lose any Fame or any prestige by retracting a fan.
Scott: actually I think the problem of him Retracting the paper is now that creationists go.
Rym: Oh look.
Scott: Yeah, they had some science.
Scott: That was that was proven us us right and now they were attracting it.
Scott: yeah look at that.
Scott: Yeah, and it's sort of giving them more ammo with their crazy conspiracy logic even though real logic.
Scott: that doesn't work out.
Scott: Yep It's funny.
Scott: I like the crazy conspiracy nuts right and the creationist sort of disagree.
Scott: usually I mean you know they're they're sort of like you know you did.
Scott: it seems like the the people on dig who are saying that 9/11 was you know a controlled 9/11 was caused by the fake Apollo moon landing.
Scott: exactly and Ron Paul I didn't seem like being covered up by the media.
Scott: It doesn't seem to me like there's a big overlap between those people and the creationists, but their logic is the same.
Rym: Anyway things of the day.
Rym: So I'm gonna paraphrase this story because I read it on FARC a couple weeks ago And I just found a link to it again, and you can read for all the juicy details.
Rym: It's very Cathartic to read.
Rym: this is one.
Rym: This is an inspirational story for our time.
Rym: This is something that you should hold your head high and just look upon it as an example of how you should live your life Mmm, so basically what happened was a kid.
Rym: some teenager went to a convenience store Bought a bottle of malt vinegar.
Scott: I'm all.
Scott: Is he gonna cook something what's?
Rym: he tried to drink it to get drunk God's sake Vomited all over himself.
Scott: That's that's what's gonna happen.
Scott: Don't drink malt vinegar.
Scott: I mean you can't.
Scott: you barely drink regular vinegar.
Scott: How you gonna drink?
Scott: Oh my god, so I just don't drink malt cider vinegar at least it won't take Or red wine vinegar.
Rym: Okay so The mother of this kid drags the kid into the convenience store and Demands an apology from the clerk who happened to be working there that day for selling her kid this dangerous substance.
Rym: clerk says Vinegar no law says I can't sell it to a kid.
Rym: I Didn't think he'd drink it.
Rym: I'm sorry your kids stupid.
Scott: Yeah, tell him.
Rym: so woman goes off and makes complaints and gets the management of the store and they're like did the kid told my kid that he could have them all vinegar and that if you drank it he'd get drunk and that it'd be okay to drink.
Rym: and The manager says to the clerk.
Rym: Well, uh, since you told the kid to drink it.
Rym: You should apologize to the kid and The mother's standing there with the kid.
Rym: and the clerk says Apologize.
Rym: I didn't say that the kids making shit up Alright.
Rym: now at this point we would have been at an impasse because we wouldn't know exactly what occurred on that day.
Rym: But luckily it luckily in store the convenience store had security tech tapes and these tapes recorded audio and video 24/7 nice.
Rym: So like the manager of the store and like the big manager like the to the boss and the boss's boss of this clerk Are pretty much like demanding that this guy apologize.
Rym: So he's like fine Let's watch the tape and if on the tape you see me it I tell this kid he can drink it.
Rym: Not only will I quit my job But I will donate the last months of my salary to this kid and his mom and I'll give a written formal apology and everything alright, so they go and get the tapes and they watch him and Kid walks up.
Rym: Hi Hi, that'll be four dollars.
Rym: Thanks walks out.
Scott: Is it is this story like confirmed true or is this like just a tale?
Rym: I've seen multiple sources for it.
Rym: So it's very likely true at least most.
Scott: it could be a little souped up.
Rym: maybe if it's apocryphal It doesn't matter because the moral of the story stands regardless.
Scott: Yeah, it's like an ace up.
Scott: think of it as like an ace of spable.
Scott: It's whether you know, the lion and the mouse didn't really talk, but you still learn a lesson from it.
Scott: That's still true.
Rym: So then the mom comes back in with a dad who's a lion *Laughter*.
Rym: So now the manager like the manager watch this thing and they see what the clerk saw and what the mom saw and they all saw it.
Rym: and The manager says apologize.
Rym: He just kind of acts like he didn't see what he just saw.
Scott: He says apologize to this kid this kid and his mom and he says no Yeah, you tell him it's only a convenience store job, what's the worst you can happen?
Rym: yeah Well, I mean, it's kind of a small town.
Rym: Like it's a pretty good job for that kind of place.
Rym: I guess you were a teenager, especially if you don't have you know a degree or anything or a Cisco cert.
Rym: Well, actually if Cisco cert that probably a good job for you.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what?
Scott: I bet this kid wasn't even supposed to work that day.
Rym: Well, the mother then starts claiming.
Rym: The mother starts claiming that the tapes were doctored doctored by the store to cover up the gross malfeasance.
Rym: So the manager again is like kid apologize to this mother or we're firing you and the kids like fuck this Your kid's stupid and he leaves.
Rym: Yeah Now it would have ended at that.
Rym: the manager apparently kept calling the guy Leaving him messages like you're a shitty person for quitting this job on such short notice.
Rym: You're terrible and and you shouldn't have you're made my business suck because you ruin this.
Rym: The Luckily and I never thought I'd say this.
Rym: Luckily.
Rym: There was a union and Was a union and for the convenience store clerk and also the owner of the whole chain of like convenience stores.
Rym: and one thing led to another and it ends with the kid getting his job back and a retroactive raise the Manager being fired the managers manager being demoted and docked a bunch of pay the woman never getting her apology And I assume the kid is still a dumbass.
Scott: But finally a story with a correct ending now on FARC.
Rym: It was funny because half the comments were yeah yeah, yeah, yeah and The other half were Jesus all this trouble and the police getting involved in all this.
Rym: when the kid could he just Apologized swallowed his pride and everything would have worked out and they could just continue down their way.
Rym: And my response to that is very simply What kind of life do you live that you lack the simple dignity to stand up for?
Rym: what little pride you have For when someone is lying about your character outright to swallow your pride and accept that?
Rym: That makes you a sad person.
Scott: This is how to get ahead in life.
Scott: You find these people who would rather, you know lie and and you know and and You know deprecate themselves and I believe you mean degredate degredate themselves prostate themselves before people and you know and take blame for things that is undeserved.
Scott: and and You know have no pride in themselves and no self-respect.
Scott: if you find these people take advantage of them.
Scott: That's how you get rich.
Scott: You find these people who won't stand up for themselves No matter what because there's they just don't want to ruffle any feathers because they'd rather just apologize.
Scott: and and you say You crack use crack you scratch my car.
Scott: No, I didn't.
Scott: Yes You did give me a hundred dollars to pay for the damages and they'll give it to you cuz I'd rather not ruffle any feathers.
Scott: And that's how you get rich.
Rym: that I skipped over a lot of the details.
Rym: if you want to read the story You can find all the links to it.
Rym: I'll link to one of the accounts.
Rym: and yeah, I felt good about that.
Scott: Yeah, I think the moral of the story is it shows you the difference between dignity in dignity and no dignity.
Rym: It's like no lack of dignity is the default.
Rym: by default.
Rym: You don't have no dignity except for the basic dignity inherent in being a living thing and being a sentient living thing.
Scott: No, no dignity are is the boss and the people on FARC who don't want to ruffle feathers.
Scott: Those people have no dignity.
Scott: They don't care about themselves.
Scott: They just don't want to ruffle any feathers.
Scott: Now.
Scott: The clerk has dignity.
Rym: the clerk straight up dignified.
Rym: He is dignified.
Scott: He's double dignified.
Rym: He is he is replete with dignity.
Scott: Yep, and the mom and the kid are.
Scott: well, maybe not the kid the kids just stupid.
Scott: But the mom is indignant.
Rym: I I note that the kid while stupid about the malt vinegar is probably smart in terms of lying about the clerk Because he knows his mom.
Rym: He of course knows how his mom's gonna react and also Apple not falling far from tree.
Scott: I Just want to point out the kid.
Scott: bargo bargo bargo bargo.
Rym: You know, why'd you bargo?
Rym: everywhere kid drank malt vinegar.
Rym: mom who?
Rym: why the fuck kid?
Rym: That guy told me to yeah knowing that the mom's anger would be redirected at the guy.
Scott: It's so weird right the way parents like most parents least that I've seen right if their kid is lot is is You know lying about something they did like, you know, the mom comes like did you spill that all over the floor?
Scott: No, yes, you did.
Scott: you're lying to me.
Scott: But when it's like, you know The kid blames it on someone else the parent will defend their kid Even if you know, it's like you believe your kid a hundred percent.
Scott: when you think someone else is to blame I think but you'll know your kid is lying immediately.
Rym: man, if I come home and drank a bottle of malt vinegar and thrown up all over my house and My tried to say that some guy told me to do it My dad would have just laughed and told me to clean it up pretty much.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah I asked.
Scott: I actually looked up the definition of you know To make sure because we've been using that word a lot lately.
Rym: Yeah, I think we use it in the very specific sense in The the best way to see it is fat indignant woman.
Rym: Yeah, you've met her she's out there.
Scott: Yeah, but the actual definition the dictionary is sort of like, you know, if someone's angry about injustice Then they are indignant.
Scott: and you know If you take that right then we're often angry about injustice.
Scott: I mean if in this story like, you know The mom and the and the managers had won then we us complaining about that would be technically indignant.
Rym: when we complain about Indignance what we are actually complaining about are people who are indignant yet are lacking the initial dignity to give them cause.
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: it's certainly people who are falsely indignant, you know, it's like this righteous indignation.
Scott: We're just sort of like what we have where you know We're in this.
Scott: we're righteous exactly, but our indignity is righteous.
Scott: Whereas this lady she was indignant She was upset about what she viewed as injustice.
Scott: The problem was is she was on the side against justice.
Scott: So it's sort of this false indignation that makes us so indignant.
Rym: I think falsely indignant people see just they seek perverse justice in order to Justify to themselves their inflated and undeserved sense of dignity.
Scott: Yes, whereas people actually have dignity They don't really get upset because they know they're right.
Rym: So I assume your thing of the day is something about a car.
Scott: good because that I told you before.
Rym: well Not only that but you've been talking about this a lot.
Scott: I've done this I think twice as a thing of the day before but now it's the real deal.
Rym: It doesn't matter what your actual thing of the day is I think your real thing of the day is just the same as the previous ones which is the thing I'm about to talk about is awesome pretty much.
Scott: the Tokyo Motor Show is Happening very recently maybe a day ago, maybe still now.
Scott: I'm not quite sure what the dates are but it basically happened as far as you're concerned and at the Tokyo Motor Show They revealed many cars many many cars all the cars that matter.
Scott: basically One of those cars is long-awaited.
Scott: One of those cars is perhaps the most intimidating Motor vehicle that is street-legal in any country and that car is of course the Nissan GTR.
Rym: You know, I'm not like.
Rym: I like cars But I'm not like a car nut.
Rym: and but there are a few cars that I picture myself driving and I imagine just this Immensely enjoyable like somewhat transcendent experience.
Rym: Yeah, and it pretty much comes down to the RX7 and the GT.
Scott: are X7 is not so exciting in real life.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Rym: I've been in it.
Rym: It's crazy fast.
Rym: It's really scary to be in an rx-7 that's being driven by a competent driver at high speed.
Scott: It's scary to do that in any car, but the GTR.
Scott: I'm not gonna tell you everything there is to know about this.
Rym: I'll sum it up.
Rym: It's a robot car.
Rym: It basically drives for you.
Scott: Well specifically, right?
Scott: this is the first ever car to have an Independent transaxle four-wheel-drive system.
Scott: now the original GTR which was you know Semi four-wheel-drive had the Atessa ETS system which is basically a Computer that does traction control to make it so easy to drive the car that you can basically just floor it and turn the wheel Like you're playing grant trees, but
Rym: if you start to slip, it'll just correct on its own.
Scott: Yeah This independent transaxle four-wheel-drive system, so each individual wheel It's not its own thing and they all wheels have power going to them in varying degrees.
Scott: That that's like.
Scott: that's the technology they ban in f1.
Scott: That's what we're talking about here.
Scott: You can literally get in this car being a shitty driver Floor it and just turn the wheel when you get to turns and not even look at the brake.
Scott: You know unless you're going downhill or something crazy and you'll probably beat a guy in a Porsche most likely it is that crazy.
Scott: The car is I think $70,000 which is not bad.
Rym: I could yeah, you know, I'm not gonna.
Scott: of course It's Japan only right now, but who knows the car is not pretty but it does.
Scott: it is very intimidating looking.
Scott: It is a scary motherfucker.
Rym: I like the way GTR.
Rym: slow cuz they look just powerful.
Scott: Yeah, it looks like it doesn't look like it like a Ferrari like oh man like there's a beautiful work of art.
Scott: It looks like you know, it's the personality of the car, which is.
Scott: I'm going to fuck you up.
Scott: And like the original GTR there was like a video screen.
Scott: Not really like a video screen to watch movies on but like a screen in the car that we would let you show.
Scott: like all These different displays like g-forces and you know different meters and things.
Scott: The new one has the same kind of screen only updated for modern times and that screen Not unintentionally.
Scott: all the user interface of that screen was designed by the developers of Gran Turismo, huh?
Scott: Anything else I had to say about this car?
Scott: you can just read on the website, but Be on the lookout for GTR's and if you don't really understand the craziness That is the GTR and you know the aura of this beast Scott.
Rym: You want to buy one?
Rym: We could easily afford it.
Scott: we could.
Rym: we could share a GTR.
Scott: you what am I gonna do with it?
Rym: drive it to Otakon?
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna fit our stuff in it.
Rym: We wouldn't need to bring anything.
Rym: We'd have a GTR.
Scott: We just saw a car drive.
Scott: you drive my car to Otakon all this stuff and I'll drive the GTR to Otakon and then I'll be there before.
Rym: actually I got a better idea.
Rym: You drive your car to Otakon with all the stuff in it, and I'll drive the GTR.
Scott: Yeah, okay fine But then I'll drive the GTR from Otakon to Wildwood, and I'll be there in like a half hour.
Rym: But speaking of GTR's tonight We're gonna talk about something that I've always found fascinating because as you all know has nothing to do with GTR's.
Rym: obviously You know I've been doing that a lot.
Rym: I do a segue.
Rym: That's just a complete non sequitur, but like speaking of fire water I've had a few that were actually clever, but not many.
Rym: uh-huh right but As you know we were really into the 12 Byzantine emperors podcast and as Many of you should know part of what happened at the with the West the Western Roman Empire fell was that The Visigoths moved in and not getting into all the history, but tonight.
Rym: We were talking about the Visigothic invasions of Beacon, New York.
Scott: ah What what century did they come here?
Scott: Uh the aughts before or after George, Washington?
Rym: You See there's kind of an inside joke in the crew well in between me and Scott and Emily But we often entertain guests because where we live you know Scott And I have always been kind of the center of the front row crew and while some of you out there friends May be listening might balk you can't pretend that wasn't true as long as we were in college.
Rym: Where did anyone ever gather, but our apartment?
Rym: where did anyone ever get together, but around us?
Rym: Where did anyone ever go to a con, but if we went yep?
Scott: You know and it's like I remember that time.
Scott: if anything proves it remember that time We wanted to go to the city, and we said all right This is what we got to do and the people didn't do it, and then they were like blaming it on us.
Rym: I think what proved it more than anything was at the Otakon.
Rym: the first time Scott And I did a panel together, and we lost our voices just from all the GeekNights stuff we were doing at Otakon.
Rym: so we could not talk and the whole crew was gonna go to Wildwood after the con and Scott and I were waiting for Yuko because she had some stuff to do and we were giving her a ride.
Rym: So that was gonna take a couple hours.
Rym: the rest of the crew could have left at any time.
Rym: They were waiting for us, and they just kind of stood around like waiting for us to make a move.
Rym: They were hungry, but they wouldn't go eat.
Rym: They wanted to leave, but they just wouldn't.
Rym: they waited for us to give them direction because we didn't.
Rym: they just stood there.
Rym: Yep, it was beautiful, but all that aside we often entertain large quantities of our Visigothic friends.
Rym: We call them Visigoths because we have never had our friends at our house without them permanently damaging large swatches of our house.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you no matter what you do unless you mean It's it's easy to have like a few people come over to your house for like you know a quiet evening and not have anything You know damaged or not have a hard time to clean up Pretty much no matter who you invite even if you invite like a bunch of grandmas over to your house You know if there's a lot of people coming to your house They're gonna fuck shit up.
Scott: so you know and the longer they stay there and the more they stay there the more people They
Rym: are
Scott: the more you're gonna need to feed them the more they're gonna need to go to the bathroom the more they're gonna need To shower the more stuff they're gonna bring and the more they're gonna fuck up your shit
Rym: stop wonderfully They're coming tomorrow for another weekend.
Scott: I wonder how many of them will listen this episode before coming.
Rym: I wonder if any of them will be angry.
Scott: Oh tough.
Rym: Yeah, luckily They've gotten better, but I guess well We'll start at the beginning like before cuz they've gotten better.
Scott: anyone complains Let's do it at their house partly because we've been jerks about it, but yeah, we kind of had to be jerks about it.
Scott: How long were we not jerks about it?
Scott: years?
Rym: well one thing we did notice is that in colony?
Rym: We didn't care cuz that apartment was in a trash state all the time.
Rym: pretty much It was.
Scott: it was a college apartment on campus tiny And in.
Rym: it was a dungeon and we'd crammed like 20 people into a building a little room That barely had enough space for two people to live in.
Rym: yeah Those were good times.
Scott: then again people weren't sleeping in it besides us.
Scott: so much Yeah But it wasn't.
Scott: it was never a lot of people sleeping in it.
Scott: Maybe like one or two.
Scott: remember those two drunk girls wandered in randomly and played DDR with us And they didn't even mess anything up, but not even spilling a drop of beer.
Rym: They were probably some of the best houseguests.
Rym: We've ever had.
Scott: maybe.
Rym: Well, I forgot about that until just now, but I didn't I digraph right.
Rym: so We let in addition all that we live central to the front row crew the fruit.
Rym: the crew lives up in Albany and out in Philly and down and and dirt, but we're at that like epicenter of the front row crew.
Rym: so of course Geographically speaking we host Dungeons & Dragons monthly.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean if we did it in Albany well Then some people would have to drive like three hours, and we would have to drive one.
Scott: ever you know.
Scott: But if we had it down in Philly the Albany people have to drive like four hours And we would have to drive like you know an hour.
Scott: so having it in the middle is the least.
Scott: No one has to make an incredibly long trip.
Scott: We sort of get the best average trip time.
Scott: You know keep it low as possible.
Rym: We also have the biggest house.
Rym: well except for ugly Fred.
Rym: But that house is inhabited by other people too that might not take kindly to pre-hab.
Rym: is a god.
Scott: Have a house that is most conducive.
Scott: I mean even our house is not conducive to D&D playing.
Scott: if we had a basement It would be so much better.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: our house would be perfectly conducive to it if people did not also spend the night
Scott: That's true, but yeah our house is not so conducive to it You know, but it's the most conducive house We have that only geeks live in and we can make a ruckus and all that stuff where you know we couldn't really do that.
Scott: It's say my parents house You know which is only about an hour from here because well my parents live there, and there's no really big Actually considered because it wouldn't be that much money Just getting a ballroom at one of the hotels near us.
Rym: every time we have D&D Yeah, for like you know like half a day and just charge everyone You don't split up the cost and just ready during yeah get catered.
Rym: that we're thinking about doing that in the future.
Scott: It's not a bad idea.
Scott: so yeah I mean we pay a lot of money when people come over.
Scott: it's just sort of invisible because it's you know you don't realize.
Scott: Oh, you spend a lot more at the grocery store And you had to buy like you know cups and plates and things and the damages.
Rym: But the thing is our friends We know they're capable of not being Visigoths because when we go to say Wildwood and stay at our friend's Gojo's house and the beach There that place is immaculate.
Scott: when they leave it Is a jerk to everybody and makes everyone clean up.
Rym: And I guess we learned her lesson.
Scott: because sort of threat She sort of threatens because she's like I'm letting you stay at this wonderful beach house.
Scott: And just because you're staying at this wonderful beach house You know for free where normally would cost a fortune you sort of feel you know obligated like I'm not paying anything to be here.
Scott: I'm gonna be as nice as I can and be as clean as I can and you know what.
Rym: that's what you should do except for Captain Hugh shall not be named who sat in the couch Clipping his toenails into the couch, okay, okay?
Scott: Yeah, but that's what you should do is what I just said and that's what we do do.
Scott: But when people come here you know because you know we're not someone's mom We're you know their friends and not their friend's mom, and we're also just really laid-back.
Rym: I mean we sound kind of like her on the show because we're opinionated, but in terms of actually living our lives.
Rym: We're pretty laid-back Very laid-back.
Scott: we care a lot less about the cleanliness than our friend's mom does.
Scott: and because our house isn't you know it doesn't feel Like a privilege to come to our house.
Scott: You know it's not like you're getting to stay on the beach for nothing.
Scott: It's like you just go into your friend's house.
Scott: It doesn't feel like a privilege.
Rym: granted Were I not here?
Rym: Scott would live in abject filth Rym we're not here.
Scott: I would live in.
Scott: No, you would live in abject filth, and that wasn't here.
Rym: Yeah Well, I sadly our third opinion is out getting food currently so we can't Quarry.
Scott: just as actual evidence though I want to say that back in the days when we were in colony right County is pretty much always a mess.
Scott: But whenever any one of us either one of us was out like you know going home or something like that for it Spotless thousand ago, so if any one of us was alone the house is spotless But the two of us together be a mess.
Rym: well part of that was whenever one of us was alone.
Scott: It also meant that the rest of the visigoths weren't around either Usually and usually meant we had time to clean and I think if either of us left lived alone.
Rym: We would have time to clean you know and then stuff would be clean, but yeah I just remember that like the first few times we had you know the majority the front row crew over.
Rym: We're not talking about a crazy party like our Slightly famous New Year's parties that are kind of epic, but a mess is expected after a party, but just playing D&D That people broke like five glasses and just hit him like and to this day No one ever admitted to it, but we found broken glasses.
Scott: There was a broken glass in the sink.
Rym: someone broke it.
Scott: no one fessed up.
Rym: There was another broken glass behind the couch.
Rym: I wasn't sure how it got there.
Rym: things were knocked over.
Rym: there were spills Everywhere dirty dishes everywhere half-eaten food.
Rym: ever.
Rym: I found more half full cans of soda than I found empty cans.
Scott: That's something that you know.
Scott: people sort of fight with me on this.
Scott: But you know the way I drink beverages Scott is a freaking weirdo.
Scott: people say is weird And it is different from everyone else, so I'll just let that go for now.
Scott: and when I drink something I either use a cup right out, and if I do use a cup I fill the cup with beverage and then I hold it in my hand until it is done And that usually doesn't take very long.
Scott: I usually drink the whole thing in one go or two goes at the most you know.
Scott: like if it's something particularly difficult to drink I guess hot chocolate takes me a while to drink because I don't to burn my see.
Rym: you're just weird real.
Rym: people Have a glass and they like to nurse a drink.
Rym: you set it down on a coaster somewhere And you just you drink it while you're being social right?
Rym: But I like beverages.
Scott: people when they come over they seem to have a it's not just you know nursing a drink or What it is they want unattended, and they never go back to it.
Rym: one is that I have a well Extensive collection of liquor right like I basically have a fully stocked bar and I really I can make any normal drink.
Rym: The only drinks I can't make are drinks that only old men like really old men make a Harvey Wallbanger.
Rym: Yeah Harvey Wallbanger is not good But I can make all normal drinks.
Rym: I can't make stupid frat boy drinks because those drinks are stupid And I can't make frou-frou drinks because those drinks are also stupid.
Rym: I can make normal drinks and everyone seems to want to drink and that's fine.
Rym: But everyone will like want to drink something different and everyone will make like a weird drink And then they'll only drink like a little bit of that drink.
Rym: then they'll want to make another weird drink And then I'll find like eight half-finished drinks, and that's a lot of liquor that people wasted.
Scott: Yeah, and not only that but it's like the thing that bothers me the most is not that you don't finish your drink right It's if you don't finish your drink at least you know even if it's expensive liquor And you feel bad just dump it down the sink and wash the glass or something you know.
Scott: yeah They take this glass they leave glasses and cans Half full or mostly full or even untouched and then they walk away from them.
Scott: at least if you're good Gonna hold on to it and drink it pick it up Carry it with you where you're going and set it down someplace new and don't set it in a precarious position.
Scott: I mean how many times has there been like a half full can of soda?
Scott: someone just leaves it on the floor And then it tips eventually?
Scott: yeah, and it's like you don't know especially with an aluminum can if it's full or empty.
Scott: There's no way to know.
Rym: Yeah, the other fun thing was that until we just luckily we don't eat or we actually don't eat or drink What the rest of the visigoths eat or drink anymore?
Rym: Which has kind of saved us a lot of money because we really in our fridge is just juice and seltzer water and Very and Red Bull and pretty much nothing else.
Scott: because they drink all those $2 Red Bulls and don't even think you know it's like You go to a restaurant with someone right.
Scott: they actually think you know Oh, we should you know split if you share something.
Scott: they feel like they should split it.
Scott: You know you buy someone something I feel like they should pay you back.
Scott: But if they drink a Red Bull out of your fridge Which is $2 the Red Bull is more expensive than most of the liquor.
Scott: I own I know.
Scott: it's like you know.
Scott: it's so weird.
Scott: It's like they feel like like if we have a bag of cookies.
Scott: They feel like oh, we can eat their cookies, and they just eat them.
Scott: What if those are like $10 cookies?
Rym: well if I'm just if I'm at someone's house And I want to drink I usually ask the host or the person like could I have something to drink unless it's a house that?
Rym: I you know family and even then I can say like yeah, I drank some of your orange juice or usually I just drink water.
Scott: well.
Rym: That's cuz you're weird Whatever.
Rym: I drink other things as most people do but luckily we don't drink soda anymore like crap soda High fructose corn syrup water yeah, and even worse the lot of them drink diet soda Which I still I don't get that times a million.
Scott: Yeah, it's just fucked up.
Rym: And I remember that they once we stopped having things that like I just don't keep dr.
Rym: Pepper or anything around anymore And I actually hide my Red Bull and all my fancy boiling sodas and things whenever they come and as a result they always open the fridge Stare and the fridge is fully stocked.
Rym: There's a lot to drink But nothing they like.
Rym: they need high fructose corn syrup water and then they go out and buy a bunch And then they drink it all warm.
Scott: and now we know that if we see a high fructose corn syrup undrunken It wasn't us.
Rym: I think they drink about half of what they buy and they leave the rest in unfinished cans all over the house.
Scott: maybe maybe All right.
Scott: anyway on the show we're gonna tell you I guess the rest of the time we have gonna We already do.
Scott: we have time left.
Scott: Yeah, we got time all right.
Scott: I'm gonna tell you some tips.
Scott: if you want to have Goths come over to your house how to Keep your house from getting totally destroyed.
Scott: rule
Rym: number one While I mean I'd like to drink especially real drinks like alcohol I like
Scott: how most of it is just involving drinks But there's a lot more than that
Rym: out of glass glasses like nice tumblers or you know wine glasses or whatever And if you're having a nice party you should do that.
Rym: if you have a few friends over you should do that But if you can't if your friends can't be trusted to return glasses to the kitchen or to not break them.
Rym: Red solo cups yep give every one of the start one red solo cup write their name on it, and that's it.
Scott: Yeah And say you're not getting another one and they have to clean that one out or they have to at least like show you like I'm throwing this away.
Rym: I want to drink something different.
Rym: Hey, I have another red solo.
Scott: I think the first rule though is is only be as mean and jerkish as you have to be.
Scott: it's like you know if they Keep it relatively clean, and you don't have to jerk them around.
Scott: don't jerk them around.
Scott: But it's sort of like wait, and then you know as their level of you know gothicness goes up.
Scott: You know increase your level of Jerusalem is to counteract.
Rym: We'll give you the levels.
Rym: level one your real glasses.
Rym: level two your crappy plastic glasses that are only used when friends come over.
Rym: level three pile of red solo cups.
Rym: level four named red solo cups.
Scott: Yeah, level five you treat everyone like children.
Rym: Sippy cups sippy cups god.
Rym: We should buy sippy cups.
Scott: good not a bad idea All right.
Scott: next thing you got to do when the gods come over is sort of like you know you You got to make people realize you know how much money it you know they're costing.
Scott: I mean
Rym: when we first the first time we had D&D at our house And we said like we'll provide all the snacks and everything we provided literally like $300 worth of snacks and drinks all told for the weekend,
Scott: and then we said you know we expect that when you guys come here Next we're not gonna provide snacks and drinks you will provide your own.
Scott: So what do they bring next time?
Scott: look at the level that we have provided and you will get an idea of the level we?
Scott: Expect you to provide.
Rym: we provided breakfast lunch dinner snacks drinks everything yep for the whole even got the high quality brand of Hot dogs and blankets instead of the low quality store brand, and I made hors d'oeuvres, and it was.
Rym: it was a nice time.
Rym: So uh the next time People cooked something and made a big mess and didn't clean up after it, but that's a whole separate problem Yep, but it wasn't that much money worth of and it wasn't enough food for everyone so we had to supplement.
Rym: So we basically ended up spending about a hundred dollars worth of our snacks anyway.
Rym: Yep, fast forward to the third time no one brought anything, and they ate all our food.
Rym: yeah, fast forward to the foot the next time people came and we didn't.
Rym: we made sure that all our food was hidden and Everyone was super hungry the whole time and no one they brought like crappy like you know those really cheap like sour cream rumple whatever Potato chips.
Scott: I hate any of those.
Scott: like I like snack food.
Scott: You know don't get me wrong You know as much as I rag on fast food and unhealthy snack foods and shit.
Scott: Yeah, I like me a pretzel or a potato chip.
Scott: You know I've changed chips.
Scott: when
Rym: I was in high school I could eat like a whole bag of Cheetos Yeah,
Scott: but any of that stuff that has like the flavoring like if it's a real potato chip I'm down, but if it's like one of those flavor potato chips I mean is what is a difference?
Scott: like like you have some actual like onion dip.
Scott: that's good stuff.
Scott: But like the fake flavor powder is really what bothers me the most.
Scott: even if it's a flavor I like it's like I can't eat fake flavor powder.
Scott: all tastes like combos.
Scott: It's disgusting.
Rym: Oh god Well, I think our issue was and of course this is just turned into awesome bitch about our friends for an hour.
Rym: awesome So easy episode.
Rym: something potato chips right we provided the dark russets like the nice fancy awesome potato chips And then when it's their turn they brought the cheapest.
Rym: well I guess the second cheapest potato chips you can buy.
Rym: yeah Basically the store-brand stuff yeah, and we provided like dr.
Rym: Pet like real soda.
Rym: They brought like dr.
Scott: W Dr.. W. Actually, you know Wegmans had a great selection of store brands even though I never drank it.
Scott: they had a wide selection of store brand stuff.
Scott: shop right does not have that?
Rym: no It doesn't.
Scott: it does not really like a dr.
Scott: S. You know they don't have Mr..
Rym: Pibb, but even then that Wegmans stuff wasn't as good as actual soda.
Rym: But then again none of that is good as you know like boiling soda, but that stuff's expensive And no one's gonna bring that to our house, so there's no way I'm gonna provide that to my friends anymore.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, what else you do?
Scott: I guess if you really have to you can like duct tape your like fridge and your cupboards shut.
Scott: you know to sort of be Like.
Scott: you know cuz someone walks up You know they don't even think.
Rym: you know we did that and one of our friends Came up to me in my room like Friday night and says hey Rym.
Rym: I was looking for glasses, and there was tape I don't know where it came from on your cupboard, so I cut it all and yeah And I was like oh god Like didn't you think maybe that tape was for you.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like.
Scott: you know you put the.
Scott: What you had to do if you're hosting anything is you put the stuff out that people are.
Scott: so you want people to eat.
Scott: you Put it out and anything hidden you keep it hidden and like if you got malamar's you gotta lock that shit up and like your bedroom closet, they'll eat Everything.
Rym: we started finally and now they all bring their own food, and I don't like any of their food.
Rym: It's really crappy usually, but we just we let them bring.
Scott: I also don't like their food, and we eat from our hidden food.
Rym: That's like hidden up in our rooms throughout the time yeah, but ah I forgot where I was going with that.
Rym: I had something I wanted to say, but I don't care anymore.
Rym: Yeah, but like Figure out how much food you're gonna provide and I guess as long as other people will either pay or reciprocate then yeah go for it, but if Money becomes a problem just stop providing food, and they'll deal with it on their own.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's one thing.
Scott: if you're hosting you know like a Christmas party that you invited people to you know.
Scott: Then you're like a host and you invited people to a party at your house like our New Year's party.
Rym: We just we buy catering every year.
Rym: We don't charge people money.
Rym: We just cater here We got a bunch of food or hosting a party.
Scott: But if just if it's people just come into your house for an event you know and they're sort of make it you know I mean it's you want to be hospitable and set.
Scott: let people make themselves at home.
Scott: You know you don't want them to feel like they're they're at some event, and they can't you know be relaxed and whatever.
Rym: But but I've seen their apartments.
Scott: Yeah, but if they make themselves at home and their home is it's like not good.
Scott: like you don't want a homeless person making Themselves at home in your house.
Scott: I mean well most homeless people who are you know dirty and you know?
Scott: But stabbin con not saying yeah exactly the stabbin kind They make themselves at home in your clean house your home is gonna be a big sty.
Rym: Yeah, well like food.
Rym: Actually one one of our other friends had the same Takes the same issue with all of our friends because she does the same thing that we like to do But we kind of stopped doing because no one seems to appreciate her care.
Rym: but like we'll actually make like nice hors d'oeuvres and fancy things and bring out like a Tray of cheese and crackers and nuts and fruit.
Rym: like food nice food here you go.
Rym: And she does the same thing when people come over and the rest of our friends pretty much look at it and go Eat it all and that's it.
Rym: nope no no Thank you know anything.
Rym: just they eat it all and then they're still hungry, and then they bitch about all.
Rym: they're still hungry.
Scott: I don't even need to thank you because I don't really care about matters.
Scott: I just need okay Thank me by not fucking up my house Or I don't know.
Rym: bring some hors d'oeuvres next time so I don't have to.
Scott: yeah It's like.
Scott: I don't need you to say thank you.
Scott: I need you to act.
Scott: thankful I just need you to not do things that suck.
Scott: Luckily it feels like I'm paying you.
Scott: you know stuff I'm giving you things and then you're you're taking more things away.
Rym: luckily There's one saving grace.
Rym: very few of our friends actually drink wine so I can always open a bottle of the wine and do all The nice and but in the end everyone gets like a small glass.
Rym: They don't even finish it, and then I just get to drink most of the bottle.
Scott: Way to go yeah, I know I like.
Scott: why you should do is you should take some Hobo wine?
Scott: Right you should you finish a bottle of real wine.
Scott: take Hobo wine.
Scott: take a funnel.
Scott: fill the real wine with the Hobo wine.
Scott: Right well I did that be like who wants a wine.
Scott: here's some wine for you, and you pour it from your fancy wine bottle But it's Hobo wine.
Scott: you don't have everyone Hobo wine that they're not gonna finish.
Scott: I think you drink your nice one.
Rym: I think what I'm gonna do Maybe not this time, but yeah, I'll.
Rym: probably if I can't I'll get time.
Rym: I'll prepare it.
Rym: I'll set it up to where I'll have some crap wine that is actually crap like bad wine nitrate And this.
Rym: so anyone who any of our friends who listen to this episode before they come tomorrow We'll we'll know and be ready for this, but let's go like tomorrow.
Scott: Let's go down to the to the and get some Thunderbird hell.
Scott: I'll buy some on the way home from work.
Rym: Yeah, do it.
Rym: I'm gonna get red red whatever wine.
Rym: I'm gonna get the the Hobo wine basically and I got some nice wine bottles And I let's be a test not even at the Visigoth thing.
Rym: I'll just find out.
Scott: try what we could try with beer - I can go get some steel reserve.
Rym: I'm just gonna find out which of our friends cuz I you know whenever I pour wine people I was like Oh, this is a good Chianti.
Rym: I like the taste of.
Rym: it's very duh And I can tell to a degree like I think a lot of people take wine way too seriously and make a lot of shit Up, but there is good wine and there's bad wine.
Rym: I have drank wine that was terrible and I've had wine that was good.
Rym: But I think a lot of our friends just say things that they don't actually know and they can't tell.
Rym: and if I gave him Hobo wine they'd probably say oh, this is good.
Rym: It's sweet.
Scott: It's sweet.
Scott: It tastes like grape juice.
Scott: I mean I've tasted it even though.
Scott: I don't like it.
Scott: Hey Rym.
Scott: What's the word Thunderbird?
Scott: has it sold good and cold?
Scott: What's the jive birds alive?
Scott: What's the price?
Scott: 30 twice?
Scott: I got some pictures of us drinking the Hobo wine and while that was MD 2020 That's hope I think Thunderbird will be more convincing because it's like a white wine and not like you know It doesn't look like grape juice.
Rym: I got a really nice Riesling that I finished a while ago and I still have the bottle.
Rym: I'll refill that Riesling bottle with Thunderbird.
Scott: The thing is if just one person knows listens to this episode They'll tell everyone else only if they're jerks.
Rym: it will serve two purposes.
Rym: one We'll find out who among our friends are traitors And two we'll find out if no one is a traitor who among our friends is a tool when it comes to saying wine tastes good.
Scott: Hahaha Cuz I feel like oh, yeah, you should hype it up be like, oh, this is a fancy jury.
Rym: Oh French wine I know I'll go straight up like this is like a gorgeous war winner.
Rym: Like this is one of my like fancy spice wines that I really like.
Scott: cuz I drink it.
Scott: they say oh wow This is really great.
Scott: That's Thunderbird.
Rym: I'll be like, this is an Alsatian wine.
Rym: Can you taste the spices?
Rym: Yeah, I can.
Rym: that's that's mad train.
Rym: The only spice is in there Hobo P.
Scott: Well, this show has turned into a lot more of a beverage show.
Scott: such a please.
Scott: you people are always arguing for food shows.
Rym: Yeah, the real thing is we've mostly solved the Visigoth problem and they're better even though the last time they came over They broke our screen door.
Rym: Wow, like just ripped it and none of them will admit to have done it.
Rym: But we know one of them did it.
Scott: So the thing is I can kind of sympathize that a little bit because sometimes you break something you don't realize, you know It's.
Scott: it's like you break a glass, you know, you're like if you just drop it, you know You broke it.
Scott: There's no question, right?
Scott: But sometimes like you put a glass in the sink and then you're trying to do dishes You know like something might fall onto the glass and cry which means you were doing the dishes wrong But you might not realize that it actually happened, you know, like you might be walking, you know You bump into the screen door.
Scott: You just keep walking.
Scott: You don't even realize that you just broke it, you know Anything can happen has happened to me.
Rym: I don't think it can.
Rym: well Just I'm.
Scott: it's happened to me in the past where I've broken something not realized it.
Scott: But then later when it was pointed out, I would say oh I remember I must have broke it when this happened I don't know.
Rym: but then again we pointed out and no one
Scott: I know
Rym: Yeah plus I just can't imagine being so unaware of my body that I would just crash into things and knock things because that's the other people knock things over like well
Scott: it is it is crowded and people are
Rym: Move around
Scott: a lot in a very crowded.
Rym: Point out that neither Scott nor I have ever knocked something over during a session of Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: Well, the only argument I can make as to why that would be the case Like, you know devil's advocate we're really skinny Is that you know you.
Scott: you can sort of walk through your own house in the dark without looking You know and into our house even though they come here often is still a Slightly stranger place and they don't have the the sort of muscle reflex of going around the house.
Scott: Like if it was dark, they might fall over in our house.
Rym: Oh, but to play the anti devil's advocate the things they knock over are things that are like like they're trying to maneuver around the table to sit back down at the D&D table and they just slam into the table and knock everything over.
Scott: I think also we a few of our friends are generally clumsier than we are.
Rym: Oh, yeah, definitely.
Scott: Yeah Anything else?
Rym: Well, I think the real what it came down to in the end was like a few times ago.
Rym: We just were jerks about it straight up and we pissed off all our friends by basically saying Don't trash our house or we're not playing games here.
Rym: In fact, we even said, you know, we're gonna play D&D Sunday morning and the house was an absolute disaster.
Rym: So we just said no D&D is being played until the house is back to the way it was before.
Scott: When I was trying to enforce that decision you were not really backing me up.
Rym: so cuz you were being crazy about it.
Rym: You went a little beyond.
Scott: you got it.
Scott: You got to back me up or else.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Scott: They'll just be like, yeah, whatever we're playing but the thing is we didn't play.
Scott: we waited cuz I wouldn't I backed you up Yeah, but they didn't clean up as much as they could.
Scott: it, you know, it wasn't a hundred percent clean.
Rym: Yeah well part of the problem was that there were a bunch of messes and we went to each one and we're like Look at this pile of crap.
Rym: who made this pile?
Rym: and no one would fess up Who did that?
Rym: and everyone would say it wasn't me.
Scott: don't get mad Because it isn't any individual person for any individual mess.
Scott: if any one of our friends came over they would make no mess basic.
Rym: well except Scott Johnson.
Scott: Guys make it fun.
Scott: Scott Johnson is too easy.
Rym: But Scott actively is funny because he makes a big mess whenever he arrives anywhere But the mess contracts and disappears the moment he leaves cuz he keeps track of all his stuff.
Scott: cuz bit Yeah, cuz basically what does?
Scott: he just brings a bunch of unnecessary shit over his thing?
Rym: Well, but some of it is very very necessary.
Rym: It is like the GameCube games.
Rym: Yeah, and the DVDs.
Scott: So basically I think another thing you can do to help unless you have a lot.
Scott: It's like when we go when I go over go to my relatives house, right?
Scott: But we just always been like no one even thinks about it.
Scott: right is When I go and all of our family does this right we go to my aunts any aunts any uncle any grandma anything?
Scott: When you walk in the door They be person.
Scott: the people who live in the house Sort of take all the coats and things right all the coats and all the bags and everything and they bring it up and they Put it in someone's bedroom.
Scott: The thing is no one's sleeping over.
Scott: So it's like, you know, if you're staying for dinner and then going home No one's going in the bedrooms, you know.
Scott: So they put all the stuff on like a bed in one of the bedrooms and then when everyone leaves they all take it out.
Rym: That's what all civilized people do exactly.
Scott: but you know because people are staying the night.
Scott: We can't have a system like that and we need to sort of force people like keep as much as their stuff out as possible In their cars or and stuff.
Rym: Well, I think the real problem there too is that people bring a lot of stuff and they just let it get everywhere.
Scott: And every every Sunday when people leave a lot of stuff by everyone leaves stuff behind constantly.
Rym: We've started just throwing a lot of it away without saying anything.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I just the socks left behind every time that aren't mine and aren't rims.
Scott: Just throw them out.
Rym: Yeah people leave bathrooms our bathroom every time they leave.
Rym: we have like four new conditioners and two new shampoos and we have two loofahs.
Scott: we Have loofahs.
Scott: that the loofahs are?
Scott: they left the loofahs on the stairway?
Scott: I'm hanging on the railing to the stairs outside the bathroom.
Scott: who even puts a loofah there to begin with?
Scott: Perhaps you do not know what it is.
Scott: Do you hang the loofahs on the stair railing in your house?
Rym: I just like saying loofah loofah loofah.
Scott: You know what loofah is backwards aloof a fool Yeah, but it just came down to.
Rym: we had to be jerks about it and it kind of an episode.
Rym: yeah Well, it kind of worked and they don't mess up our house nearly as badly as they used to.
Rym: and now we just have to Teach them things like people always say oh and they'll like they do the dishes like.
Scott: one time Someone did the dishes with the bathroom sponge.
Scott: Yes It's partially my fault for leaving that sponge there in the first place But it was pretty obvious.
Scott: one was a dish sponge and one was a horrible.
Scott: one was covered in hairs Or just I don't know.
Rym: we just had to be jerks.
Scott: and having a dishwasher does also give us a big disadvantage.
Rym: Yeah, not having dishwasher I mean, I think the only real complaint I have now is that people bring way too much stuff and they leave it all over The place and they just I mean I go to their house.
Scott: I bring basically two bags like, you know The bag I carry every day with like my laptop my DS and stuff and a tiny duffel bag and that's it.
Scott: And or even if I bring people come to our house with freaking luggage for a weekend.
Scott: What the hell like.
Rym: this is what we do at cons to and it works So well when I show up at a hotel room and this is why we don't stay with anyone anymore our hotel room for cons.
Rym: Now it's pretty much like just me and Scott.
Rym: Yeah, and I'm never getting hotel rooms for people again.
Rym: Good God, but We all like go find a little area in the hotel room or the house or whatever and all my stuff will be Compacted into that tiny little area except for the bathroom stuff, which I compact into an area in the bathroom.
Rym: Yep, or usually actually I leave all my bathroom stuff in my area.
Rym: if I go bring it back and forth to the bathroom I carry it all to the bathroom that I carry it all out sometime.
Scott: Actually, I have a little toiletry bag that I use, you know.
Scott: But for a while, I didn't have the toiletry bag because my brother stole it.
Scott: But my mom bought me a new one from LL Bean.
Scott: I'll link to it.
Scott: if anyone asked in the forum, I'll link to the ultimate toiletry bag.
Rym: Yeah, there's not much moral other than that.
Rym: we just kind of we talked about doing this episode right after they came the last time and it took us about a month to Get around to actually doing it.
Scott: So I want people for this episode in the forums.
Scott: I want you to give stories of either When you went to someone's house and you super messed it up or it got super messed up and then they complained or When you had a bunch of people come to your house and they super messed it up.
Rym: That could be good.
Scott: Yeah, so tell all those kinds of stories and anything that's even anyway related and it will entertain everyone.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Scott: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.