Rym: It's Thursday August 23rd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is you know what fuck it?
Rym: I just don't even care.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah despite the fact that both Scott and myself had plans to not be around last night We ended up both being around and we were so lazy that not only did we not do the show But we didn't even do the Rym and Emily special.
Scott: We didn't do Jack or shit.
Scott: last night I played some of that system shock game.
Scott: You know what I did and I played some paper Mario.
Rym: I washed my pants and then I proceeded to play natural selection until way too late.
Scott: Wow Yeah, if I was booted into windows, this is the problem in video game season.
Scott: Is that I?
Scott: you know game.
Scott: video games that don't take a long time to play are generally DS games.
Scott: So I played them on the train.
Scott: So when it's video game season, I play video games at home.
Scott: I actually play them.
Scott: not much else goes on.
Scott: I'll be sitting there for like an hour Or two at each game.
Scott: Yeah, and I'm casting takes a backseat.
Rym: No, it doesn't really take it back
Scott: It doesn't but you know what I'm saying,
Rym: though I was playing natural selection pretty much from the moment I came home from work until Scott came into my room and said hey, we're gonna do the show
Scott: And then we didn't do the show
Rym: for like another half hour
Scott: At all yesterday.
Rym: Oh, yes.
Rym: I'm talking about today.
Scott: Oh, yeah today.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Scott: Well, actually today I got home and I started playing paper Mario and I stopped a bit like eventually when I said hey, I should do the show.
Rym: Yeah, my video game cue is really backed up right now.
Rym: Even worse is there's a deep.
Rym: we have a Netflix movie that I really want to watch but Scott doesn't seem to care about Mutiny on the bounty the original and I'm all excited about it, but I just don't have time to watch.
Rym: He's just like two hours long.
Scott: So watch on the train.
Rym: I don't have a laptop.
Rym: I guess I could borrow Emily's but you should get one of those.
Scott: I'm thinking about a bull DVD.
Rym: The only reason I haven't bought one of those portable DVD dealies is that I'm currently reading books on the train.
Scott: And I know actually just today I was reading a book on the train.
Rym: and the worst thing is I don't have enough time to Even read.
Rym: I have an hour on the train and I get to work and I think crap.
Rym: I want to keep reading.
Scott: I have a weird relationship.
Scott: I love to read books.
Scott: the kind that I've were only words read a book.
Scott: But I get a box full of books of pictures every month.
Scott: So and for some reason I read those really quick as fast as I can.
Rym: Scott You should not a sports page not amazing.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a sports page or mag not a one-piece not no Naruto But a book anyway, but so I don't actually like start reading novels often But whenever I start reading one, I can't stop reading it and I read it stupidly fast.
Rym: Yeah, that was the problem.
Rym: I mean I did a geek bite about it not too long ago but Alex Got me hooked on these prints of nothing books and I read all of them pretty much as fast as he could give them to.
Rym: And now I'm reading Plutarch's histories and they're super awesome All right.
Rym: I feel a little more erudite though because Scott's reading comic books and I'm reading ancient historians works on even a more ancient Personalities in Rome.
Scott: Yeah, but the comic books I read are literary.
Scott: I don't read those underwear perfect comp books.
Rym: So what comic book you're reading right now?
Scott: I'm not reading any comic books right now.
Rym: Ah, so what's the last comic book you read?
Scott: I read Will Eisner edge of genius.
Rym: All right, I can't make funnier for that.
Scott: Okay, right?
Rym: So I got a news tonight and it's not really a new news.
Rym: In fact, this is news that was news ten years ago.
Rym: But I've realized in reading what people say about this issue on the internet that most people out there have Absolutely, no idea what this issue actually is.
Scott: Well, I have an inside scoop on this.
Scott: is that on the most recent episode of twit last week an inside scoop I know is that a guy was talking about it.
Scott: Hence if you go to sites like slash dot and dig where there are many twit listeners the conversation is carrying on from that.
Rym: Man, you know, I haven't listened to twit in like three months ever since I stopped.
Rym: I got to get some earbuds.
Rym: So when I'm playing Pokemon, I can also listen to podcasts.
Scott: I know I just actually sent my earbuds in for RMA because the right the wire to the right ear got loose.
Scott: So it's like I had to keep jiggling it.
Scott: So I sent him in and if you know at the very worst I could get a replacement pair for like half price.
Scott: So why not?
Scott: but now I need to go and buy some like shit $5 earbuds to hold me over until they come back.
Rym: Thing is I just never drive anywhere anymore.
Rym: And also actually of all awesomes this morning I get to work and I got to drive to this hospital and I get in my car and I'm driving a couple co-workers over there And I hit the ignition and nothing happens.
Rym: Not like digga digga digga digga, but just nothing Uh-huh, so I poke around in your car had that exploding ignition problem that you did.
Rym: so I'm thinking huh?
Rym: Here's the car now on fire.
Rym: what's going on?
Rym: So I go out and I turn the lights on the batteries.
Rym: fine as far as I can tell and I don't have time to deal With this.
Rym: so I just get a cab to the hospital and we deal with our work and I get back and I'm gonna take The train home and I figure all right.
Rym: Damn it.
Rym: You'll see what's wrong with my car.
Rym: There's a mechanic like a block away.
Rym: So I was just gonna push my car over there.
Rym: Yeah pushing the car and the car starts fine.
Rym: Yeah, no problem weather.
Rym: I bet it that Betty was like the car for the last year said well actually for as long as I've owned it as I'd trouble with Rain when it's wet out.
Rym: the car just doesn't like to do things.
Rym: Thing is it's a beater.
Rym: I'm driving it into the ground.
Rym: I figure probably winter time ish.
Rym: I'm gonna buy a new car.
Rym: Maybe I want to hold out until next summer.
Rym: I'm really looking at a used Miata.
Scott: Get whatever you want.
Rym: I want a little zoomy car.
Scott: Yeah, everyone does.
Scott: Yeah They're coming out with new DeLorean's that are only gonna be like fifty nine thousand dollars.
Scott: Yeah $59,000.
Rym: that's what I'm gonna spend on the car because I'm so flush with cash and my diamond shoes are too tight.
Scott: DeLorean It's not so much.
Scott: Ferrari's also coming out with a car.
Scott: That's only like 130.
Rym: I spent 10 grand on my current car and you know what?
Rym: It's it's been worth well more than 10 grand worth of driving.
Rym: I'm not spending more than 30 grand on a car unless I'm rich and I'm not rich.
Scott: yet They're coming out with like a half-price Ferrari.
Scott: How can ya half-price?
Rym: Yeah, it's like yeah 80% off this house in the Florida Keys.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Scott: Anyway, I don't see what your problem is.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: I guess my news turned into another leader bit.
Rym: Okay, anyway The issue at stake that twit talked about that sent us on this tangent is the quote loudness war unquote in music.
Rym: and The heart of the issue is dynamic range compression.
Rym: Now I got to stop you all right here because most idiots on the internet when they are compression think Oh, you mean like turning it into an mp3 or an aug or whatever and that is absolutely nothing to do with this at all.
Scott: It's a different kind of compression.
Scott: This is more like the compression where I squish your head than the compression where I take away your bits.
Rym: now The deal is that one different mediums especially back before digital distribution had different limitations as to how loud music could be and what dynamic range you could have.
Rym: and a lot of people like to Say yes.
Rym: and vinyl records because they're analog have perfect dynamic range and that's a load of horseshit.
Rym: Don't even get me started about.
Scott: the dynamic range of a vinyl record is the depth of the little pits in the vinyl and not Only that but records had all sorts of special problems.
Rym: If you tried to put too much bass in there you could knock the needle out of the track And you couldn't put high-pitched things in.
Scott: so that's why they have those lasers that read your vinyl records now instead of needles Yeah, but even then that's.
Scott: but then it's a CD.
Rym: Well, no, it's it's better and worse than a CD.
Rym: the thing does.
Rym: there's too many issues for me to talk about.
Scott: I know isn't it all right?
Rym: I'm gonna solve all of these issues up one.
Rym: Records only sound better to people who like warm audio sound and by warm audio I mean different kinds of distortion and different kinds of audio.
Rym: It's not higher fidelity The distortion just sounds better to some people mostly people who grew up listening to records.
Rym: Yes CDs sound harsh to them because the CDs in many ways more accurately Reproduced the audio and as a result, you don't get that nice distortion they had and they liked.
Rym: But anyway This issue specifically is that and it's something that talk radio and we at GeekNights do Actually more so than most radio stations do we compress the audio?
Rym: Dynamically whereby the louder our audio gets above a threshold the more it is compressed the less loud it can get.
Rym: So up to four decibels, let's say nothing happens.
Rym: But for every decibel above four decibels that our audio is gonna sound to you We have to get say three decibels louder.
Rym: So it decreases the dynamic range of the audio and as a result if I start yelling or if Scott and I talk at The same time or if I lean back from the microphone or anything weird happens or I talk quieter It all gets kind of smoothed out and as a result the talking you hear tends to be very uniform.
Rym: it doesn't get super loud and super quiet like pretty much every other goddamn podcast and radio show out there.
Scott: the advantage of this is that if you're in your car or In the end, you know, you can hear us.
Scott: if you're listening on your iPod, you can hear us.
Scott: You can hear every word we're saying no matter what we do and no matter what you do And that is good for a talk show.
Rym: if you want to hear audio that doesn't do this.
Rym: I don't want to make fun of them because I love their podcasts But listen to like any of the first 30 or 40 episodes that Dave and Joel's fast karate.
Rym: for the gentleman That is what uncompressed and unprocessed audio sounds like folks.
Rym: You don't want that.
Scott: It's very difficult to hear sometimes because it'll be so quiet and sometimes it's so loud It hurts your ears.
Scott: You know you ever listen to a podcast and the music suddenly comes in really loud a lot louder than the talking kind of like How early GeekNights was and then the talking comes in and it's too quiet and you can't hear it.
Scott: You have to keep adjusting your volume knobs that you can hear what's going on in the podcast.
Scott: We have a thing over here a little machine that does that.
Rym: and then furthermore I apply many additional dynamic filters on the audio after the fact in post-production.
Rym: But anyway, they do the same thing in music.
Rym: and the effect the net effect of compression Is that the average volume of a song is increased?
Rym: Because say you can only hold I don't know 10 decibels of audio in say a CD.
Rym: I'm totally making up numbers just so you can understand this.
Rym: so a CD or a tape can hold 10 total decibels meaning the most difference between the loudest part of the audio and Silence is 10 decibels.
Rym: So say I record some audio and I got a drummer on a snare drum Just banging that snare drum every now and then.
Rym: so pak pak pak and then I got a guy kind of mumble rap.
Rym: So the snare drum is like nine decibels and the shocker own guy is like two decibels.
Rym: As a result when I do the final post-production without doing any compression The snare drum is 10 decibels and the dude talking maybe is like three or four decibels and you can't hear shit with the guys Saying and the drum hurts your ears.
Rym: Yeah, so the only way around that is to use dynamic range compression.
Rym: So as a result, the snare drum is still loud and it sounds loud but you compress the audio and as a result the shocker own guys at like seven decibels and the snare drums at like eight decibels and You do some other stuff to it and you really can't tell the difference in most situations.
Scott: Yeah I mean I like to you know Play but a lot of people that like I don't like the sound of that like the sound of that.
Scott: get these people in some Double-blind tests or in some real-world situations where you know They'd be having to fiddle with the volume knob constantly and let's see which one they pick when they don't know What's what.
Rym: now the real issue would say because as I keep saying that the real issue would stake here the root of the issue It's the real deal, I guess there's a lot of roots.
Rym: Here's the bottom line with no more No more techno jump.
Rym: Oh, I got this already black.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: The crux if I may.
Rym: the issue is that as a result of people doing this, you know You can make audio sound louder.
Rym: Generally pop music and music that people listen to in the world Particularly in the United States in Europe has been dynamically compressed to the point that there is no more dynamic range.
Rym: They try to make the sound more and more apparently louder and some subgenres of music Take this one step further and try to make the bass sound super loud and all that sort of thing.
Rym: And a lot of music purists seem to be of the mind that without dynamic range Music is somehow bad.
Rym: and while I will say that dynamic range can be put to great effect and Wonderfulness in music if you're listening to music in the way that 90% of Americans are people in the world record Music recorded music.
Rym: Yeah, so you're not listening to it in a soundstage You're not listening to it on your $200.
Rym: not, you know, $10,000 audiophile bullshit headphones But like $200 absolute real monitor headphones You don't sit there in the listening room with a blindfold on listening to music and listening to the subtle Differences between the quiet part of the symphony and the loud part of the symphony.
Rym: You're listening on the train you're listening in the car You're listening with a bunch of people at a party and if you've ever tried to listen to classical music in a car It totally sucks because you have to have to turn it up whenever it's quiet and turn it down whenever it's loud
Scott: Or else you can't hear over the noise of your engine in your car, even if your car is an electric car.
Scott: So
Rym: I guess while dynamic range can be used to great effect in music This whole loudness war is kind of BS because that is what people want and a lot of people and a lot of music players Will do this after the fact so that you can listen to music that isn't dynamically controlled.
Scott: This is why that people write programs like mp3 gain and normalize so that you you don't have to keep fiddling with your volume knob Constantly to be able to hear all your music.
Scott: It just makes all your music the same volume level.
Scott: so and then Automatically changes the volume based on the song that happens to come up in your playlist so that you can hear it.
Rym: So the issue is just a lot more complex than the people who are so loud about this want to make it out.
Scott: Most of the people are allowed about.
Scott: it are crazy audio files who believe in bullshit.
Rym: anyway I think we need to get some sort of dynamic internet compression for those guys.
Rym: Oh, I don't know.
Rym: the crazier you are the less digs you get Too bad.
Rym: It's the exact opposite.
Rym: We have some sort of crazy expander on dick right now, but I'm done with the audio analogies.
Scott: Okay today.
Scott: I couldn't find any news.
Scott: I can do a geek back Bringing back the geek back.
Rym: Oh the geek back.
Rym: We had a geek bite a little while ago now.
Scott: a geek back Yep, so the fayed guy, you know th a ED whatever is that every we want people to say his name?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He basically sent me an email and he said wait, basically like he could have done something else He could have.
Rym: he could have.
Scott: it's a very short email.
Scott: It could.
Scott: it could have been an instant message Oh, but it says so.
Scott: have you guys ever thought about creating a podcasting channel or network?
Scott: If anyone could do it you could and I'm like, okay, that's all he said.
Scott: I gave him a big little response, but I saw the response.
Scott: I think this bears Talking about on the show.
Rym: Let's start with podcast channel and then move into five.
Scott: Okay well I think the difference between a podcast channel and a podcast network is sort of hard to define because people I don't know.
Rym: Well, I think it's pretty easy.
Rym: a Podcast channel is either, you know some sort of cross syndication with feed so you can subscribe to one feed.
Rym: that's just got all the different stuff the different people do like.
Rym: if there's Yeah,
Scott: if you're gonna make it a direct to television analogy then yes That would be a channel where you you'd program some sort of podcast, you know You take a feed and we would choose podcasts to go into the feed thus creating a larger feed of programming Which is what a TV channel is.
Rym: And I think the only other thing a podcast channel could be is just some sort of live streaming screaming Streaming.
Rym: I said a bunch of words that weren't the word Yeah, you did but some sort of live streaming thing which as we talked about recently is really dumb I don't think that's what I say.
Scott: or a podcast network, which depending on what you think about podcast network There are a lot of existing podcast network.
Scott: Like for example, it network.
Scott: Well, it's sort of different than the others but like the sci-fi podcast network or the comic podcast network or one of those, right?
Rym: Then there's those loose affiliations or I mean These are.
Scott: is that basically a bunch of people who already have their separate podcasts, right?
Scott: They're completely unreal.
Scott: They're not unrelated podcasts, but they're podcasts on the same thing like a pseudopod and escape pod.
Scott: Well, no, like look at the comics podcast network, right?
Scott: Okay, every podcast and the comms podcast network is made by someone different somewhere else in the world.
Scott: They don't like work together.
Scott: Really.
Scott: There's no like that.
Scott: You know, they're they're friends I guess on the internet, but they're not you know friends in real life Or at least they weren't friends in real life before.
Scott: they don't produce their shows together.
Scott: they just have an affiliation under a common label and the fact is that some of the individual podcasts under that label are actually bigger than the label itself and I really don't see the point of Grouping a bunch of podcasts under a label like this.
Rym: the only rate reason you would ever do that is if in your group of friends or Just group of podcasters or whatever that may or may not have been formed directly by you One is really popular and the rest aren't and you want to make the rest popular and have them tag along on your coattails.
Scott: Yeah, and I really I think that's kind of a dumb idea because the way to get more listeners for your podcast is to be Like Nintendo and get people who aren't listening to pod the blue ocean.
Scott: people are already listening to podcasts.
Scott: if they're gonna find you They'll find you.
Rym: don't worry In fact, I know how it works.
Rym: This is kind of a big indictment against a lot of our podcast friends because I'll be very blunt Most of the friend podcasters we have are very incestuous in terms of Podcasting and they all cross promote each other and they all play like when we went to Otakon, right?
Rym: We did a podcasting panel that a bunch of people recorded.
Rym: Every one of the podcasters we know put the exact same audio from the same panel up in their show Except us.
Rym: obviously we actually gave The Ninja Consultants five the best recording of that thing because we gave them our recording that we didn't actually use for anything.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: from the fancy-pants Marines,
Scott: but you know, they're all promo each other and stuff and it's sort of like Podcasters associate with each other for no other reason than other to share listeners And I don't know how many listeners actually get shared because of these networks, but I imagine it's not making a significant difference.
Scott: Well, all except for the really small podcast that attaches on to the really big one gets a good head start.
Scott: But that's about it in the end.
Rym: All it does is eventually I see a lot of listeners seem to consolidate Like they'll start listening to a bunch of shows because of you know cross-promotion But then they end up only listening to one or two of the original ones that cross-promote and just stop listening to the rest.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: I think in the end the only kind of podcast network that's good is one like to it because to it is different in that All it to it is a lot more like GeekNights in which we have like four different podcasts We do effectively and to it has like 10.
Scott: Yeah, they got like.
Scott: there's the headline show to it.
Scott: But then there's like the free open-source one and the law one and but they're all Twit shows made by twit.
Scott: Leo Laporte has something to do with all of them.
Scott: They're all made by twit.
Scott: It's not like all these people making separate shows and slapping a twit label on them.
Scott: They're actually all Produced by the same crew.
Rym: basically now if there was anything like that that we would do that is it?
Scott: Yeah, and I mean we're doing that already as far as I'm concerned The only thing we're not nice is for podcasts and twit is a lot more than for the only reason we don't do more.
Rym: It's just a lack of time because we both have day jobs.
Rym: Imagine if I didn't have a job I could just make like two podcasts every day and I could see in the future Especially like if we had as many listeners as twit, I can guarantee there'd be a lot more GeekNights out there.
Scott: There sure would be.
Rym: I mean if my job were to do this eight hours a day I'd probably do it 12 hours a day.
Scott: I don't know if I do it 12 hours.
Rym: Well by doing I mean not just talking for 12 hours a day But 12 hours worth of stuff.
Rym: because remember playing video games counts as working on GeekNights.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: So does playing D&D playing board games watching anime?
Scott: I guess the point is is that I think
Rym: that
Scott: podcast networks as they stand today Most of them are pretty stupid and pointless and I think they're kind of lame and I don't really want to have anything to do With any of
Rym: notice that we stopped playing promos pretty much right away.
Scott: Yeah, we played promos because other people were doing it and then we realized why we doing this.
Scott: Jesus other people are doing it.
Scott: It's stupid.
Rym: Yep It doesn't help that all promos are bad including ours.
Scott: if you're gonna make a net some sort of label to apply to multiple Separate podcasts that label should have some meaning.
Scott: other than we all talk about similar things or we all like each other.
Rym: Yep I mean Like these shows are all produced in the same studio Like we have the GeekNights experimental feed which in the winter or early fall is gonna start seeing a lot more use.
Scott: It should see some use pretty soon.
Rym: I think they will but it's gonna see a lot more use.
Scott: Mostly our lips in limitation.
Scott: It's not seen more use.
Rym: Yeah that and we have actually been really busy lately.
Rym: Yep, but I could see us expanding with a couple more hosts and more shows and that sort of thing And I could see the front row crew as a whole busting out But I don't see many of our front row crew friends actually podcasting.
Rym: No, at least not unless they podcast through us.
Scott: Yeah, oh well podcast networks and kind of lame very lame.
Rym: So things of the day whatever screwing around we seem to be doing with geek bites and geek backs and newses.
Rym: I think the things of the day are gonna stay.
Rym: everyone seems to like him.
Scott: Yeah Can't get rid of the thing of the day.
Rym: I mean I'm gonna be quick about this.
Rym: cuz all I hate to do everything I do is on dig and if I don't if it's not On dig it's on dig by the time I do the show.
Rym: so I stopped caring.
Rym: This is a little old but a little old meaning a couple days ago.
Rym: It's a comedy sketch.
Rym: It's either Australian or British and It's about the front falling off.
Rym: and I don't want to say anymore just watch it.
Scott: It's really Monty Python esque and really it's not Monty Python, but it is very much like Monty Python.
Rym: The thing is it's that whole kind of very witty very dry style of British humor.
Rym: It's it had a little bit of the pell you.
Rym: well, well the fun fell off.
Rym: Yes, right, right.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Anyway, that's all I thought it was funny.
Scott: Here's another funny thing I found here.
Scott: Basically you ever seen the Street Fighter live-action movie in the US actually know that my mom did.
Scott: Oh, I saw it.
Rym: Anyway, it's My mom really liked the Mortal Kombat movie Mortal Kombat movies a lot better than the Street Fighter movie But she kept trying to like hide it.
Rym: She always be like, yeah, I just like it for the special effects But she totally just dug that movie.
Scott: It wasn't as that bad.
Scott: It was bad, but not as bad as Street Fighter movie.
Scott: Anyway, Korea at one point South Korea I assume tried to make a Street Fighter movie as well Street Fighter 2 movie.
Scott: Actually that was live-action.
Rym: All right, is this better or worse than all those like Filipino spider-man movies?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Why don't you watch this eight minutes of live-action footage and decide for yourself?
Scott: The best part of this is just watching all the character introductions at the beginning.
Scott: Zangief priceless Priceless.
Rym: you say it's a priceless Zangief because I know what Zangief looks like and I mean, I know exactly what a Korean guy Dressing up as Zangief.
Rym: I can't imagine that that's impossible.
Scott: Well, I'm gonna show it to you after the shows.
Rym: that is there is no way a person of Korean descent Full-blooded Korean descent could look anything like Zangief.
Scott: well, we'll watch this when the show's over and everyone else listening will watch it also and be entertained.
Rym: I mean the College humor has a perfect Zangief.
Scott: Oh not that hard to find a guy like that Street Fighter at the later years on college humor is like the hot shit I hope they finish making as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: That is the live-action Street Fighter movie.
Scott: Oh there it.
Scott: of course definitely but this is uh So is this?
Rym: this is interesting in the same way that Japanese spider-man who put my claws in the sink, you know You can't do the gonna rise Right, so, uh, if you haven't noticed Scott and I are a little bit jaded about a lot of things.
Rym: Jaded like Jade monkey but jaded like, you know That doesn't work because you can't.
Rym: something can't be jaded in the same way that it's bronze.
Rym: You can't coat something in jade very easily No, but yeah, what I don't know.
Scott: I was just trying to make fun of the the material Jade
Rym: I know I really like Jade though because it protects you from the what's-it-in-uh,
Scott: it doesn't protect you
Rym: l5r
Scott: It doesn't protect you
Rym: know in l5r if you're out into those accursed lands for the only and everything Are you better?
Rym: had you best have some Jade on you?
Scott: I guess Jade and l5r is sort of like cold iron with our demons.
Scott: and yeah granted captain.
Rym: Oh, so that's the kaiju wall.
Rym: Eh, I go outside and roll around in the dirt.
Scott: The setting was not thoroughly explained enough to me.
Rym: So rather setting All right wall a cursed land beyond the wall.
Rym: Don't go out there.
Scott: Okay, I go on right around in the door because I was like exactly how you know Where it's like.
Scott: I look over the edge of the wall.
Scott: Is it a curse it down there?
Scott: I'm like how far away is the accursed miss?
Rym: They're like how a curse it.
Rym: is it?
Rym: on a scale of one to ten?
Scott: Yeah, I was.
Scott: I was trying to curse is gonna get on.
Scott: I was trying to get a complete picture of what evil would lurk beyond the wall and it wasn't offered to me out of Characters.
Scott: so I had to go in character and find out What if I eat the dirt?
Rym: is the dirt cursed?
Rym: What if I only eat like a handful of dirt when I just lick a lick a rock or something?
Rym: What's that gonna do?
Scott: That's what I did.
Scott: Anyway, I'm fine ninja for the win.
Rym: I do want to preface this by saying that however jaded I may be Scott is entirely immune to the accursed effects beyond the kaiju wall.
Rym: Scott is made of Jade Scott that I could say that 80% of the time.
Rym: with no exaggeration if I say anything to Scott his response will range from Nothing to yeah.
Rym: Yeah, it's pretty good as far as I go and I'm talking things like oh my god Scott Russia just invaded Britain and they nuke France and Scott.
Rym: to be like it doesn't affect me.
Scott: yet Yeah, I don't know what happened.
Scott: I mean, I know I wasn't always this way and I know I am this way.
Rym: But yet you get super excited about the stupidest little things like what like I remember back We were watching Ozamanga died.
Rym: You'd sit there like oh shit.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: I was like, oh my god I was a while ago.
Scott: Wasn't that long hated then?
Scott: that was years ago.
Scott: That was like four years ago Not even long time four years.
Rym: you sat and watched that screen saver.
Rym: There was nothing more than an Osaka.
Scott: That was like four years ago.
Rym: It wasn't that long ago long ago.
Scott: but I think it's mostly in the past two years ish that I've been super jaded where I Just go on the stupid RSS feeds and I see so much shit every day Constantly that it takes so much to make me get any sort of reaction.
Scott: I mean, it's like if I sit there watching coat see for a whole day.
Scott: What are you gonna show me?
Scott: That's gonna make me go and nothing.
Rym: yeah, see there's a secondary issue that actually Jess and a few other people brought up when we were talking about this exact same thing when Everyone in the crew except Scott went mountain climbing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well rock climbing.
Rym: It wasn't actually a mountain.
Rym: It was a hill.
Rym: I'm not gonna pretend that breakneck rage is a mountain but nonetheless We were rock climbing and we were talking about how jaded Scott is and an issue came up.
Rym: But I'll get to that at the end.
Rym: Let's focus just on the internet right now Because People send us things of the day all the time.
Rym: It seems like ever since we started saying who sent us a thing of the day We get so many emails of oh my god, check this out.
Rym: Oh my god Check this out.
Scott: and I'd say about 75% of them are things I've already seen.
Scott: 15% of the rest are things that are just man and then the remainder some people actually do send us things We haven't seen that are awesome there what it really comes down to on the internet as opposed to maybe other issues.
Rym: It's just that We've seen a lot on the internet and I've already seen a video of a guy putting on a banana suit and then lighting it On fire and then saying that was a bad idea in front of the camera after the fact after he was horribly burned.
Scott: So when I watched the video of an idiot You know lighting a train track on fire then lighting his jeans on fire with gasoline from the train Or to just break
Rym: that up any video of someone doing something really stupid I just I've already seen a video of someone doing the stupidest thing.
Rym: They're all just really the same thing and I'm not yeah, it's like you watch this owned compilation.
Scott: It's like every like a hundred owned videos just tied together.
Scott: How are you possibly gonna show me another owned video?
Rym: I already saw a guy Parasail into a cliff.
Rym: I've seen that there's nothing worse that I could see in Paris.
Rym: All right If a shark jumped out of the water and grabbed a guy in the air who was parasailing That would make me go.
Rym: I would I would take pause at that for a second maybe but then Once you've seen that the shark jumped the guy it's over.
Scott: but I mean once you've seen that video though, what's next?
Scott: I mean the guy is diving into the water and eat coming out with the shark.
Rym: now I don't just want not just owned videos That was just the example that came to mind but anything like flash animations.
Rym: I have seen some of the most amazing animations online and in film festivals and everything and 99% of the stuff on the internet is crab flash whatever that I've seen.
Scott: a million things better Even even things that aren't in the internet.
Scott: anime back in the day.
Scott: There wasn't so much anime.
Scott: It was hard to get.
Scott: I didn't see a lot of it.
Scott: Well, not only though even a bad anime was awesome because it's like oh my god an anime Holy shit, and it didn't matter to me what it was.
Scott: It was an anime.
Scott: That's all that mattered.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I watch so much anime that it's like wow, it's crap.
Scott: That's crap.
Scott: That's crap because I've seen the best of the best of the best.
Scott: So if you don't show me something that's on that level I mean you might show me something that's pretty damn good like a but I've seen 30 a plus anime.
Scott: So compared to those your anime have no chance your B Anime has no chance and your a anime is only gonna get watched if I'm really bored and I have this mountain of a plus Stuff to look at.
Scott: the a stuff just isn't gonna happen people.
Scott: I'm too busy with my life.
Scott: I got to go to work I got to eat.
Scott: I got a do laundry.
Scott: I got to make a podcast.
Rym: It's like when I was a kid, I watched Tenchi Muyo and I love that show.
Rym: that show was just so funny and so clever.
Scott: I didn't like it even then but and so original and I thought it was great.
Rym: It was hilarious.
Rym: I love the character I love the movies and hey the original OAV has a lot of charm.
Scott: You got what you want to call it.
Rym: Have you seen the OA?
Rym: what?
Rym: what Tenchi?
Scott: have you seen the Cartoon Network?
Scott: random?
Rym: Whatever random whatever?
Rym: what?
Rym: because there's the original OAV and there's the.
Scott: I think I saw some episode where there was swimsuits.
Scott: It was obligatory.
Rym: So that doesn't narrow it down, but suffice to say Yeah, I've seen like a hundred anime since then.
Rym: that are the same kind of harem show whatever.
Rym: but not only are they all Just oh, I've seen a harem show I don't need to see another one.
Rym: and not only did none of them bring even one original thing to the table but they all were not as good as Tenchi like just not.
Rym: it's not just oh, it's just the same thing.
Rym: over again It was the same thing.
Scott: does that perhaps nostalgia?
Rym: No, you're like no good God If you watch love Hina that show.
Scott: I watched all of love He actually enough because back in the day before it was jaded.
Scott: you were stupid.
Scott: I downloaded all of love Hina because we watched episodes of it at anime club where every anime appears better than it is and everyone Was laughing their heads off after four episodes.
Scott: So I downloaded the rest.
Scott: went home over the summer.
Scott: There was no RIT internet connection.
Scott: There's just a 56 56 K modem and I watched all of love Hina goes nothing else to do that.
Rym: I can't make fun of you because what granted love Hina by the third episode.
Rym: I realized wait a minute They haven't.
Rym: it was like a Garfield comic.
Rym: They haven't made a new joke in several episodes pretty much.
Scott: But did you?
Scott: you watched all of Sailor Moon's.
Scott: he can't talk.
Rym: oh, no, I wasn't gonna make fun of that when I was living in the mountains with no internet and no cell phone and Nothing to do and I'd read every book I owned and I was buying but I had nothing to do.
Rym: and I was bored Super bored like I come home from work and I'd run for a couple hours and then I'd like make dinner And then I still had four more hours to kill.
Rym: I watched all of read or die TV and And I watched like 12 episodes of monster and monsters.
Rym: good though It was okay.
Rym: The the manga is so much better that the anime I just can't stand.
Scott: how much of the manga if you read like one issue.
Rym: I Got two volume.
Rym: I didn't like the anime.
Rym: It just it did it.
Rym: The pacing was really bad in my opinion.
Rym: All right I really watched enough the anime to say I like the first four or five.
Rym: then it just really started going down.
Rym: but Read or die TV was crap.
Rym: And then I watched about 17 episodes of brother dear brother.
Rym: And then finally I realized all right, this is crap.
Rym: I watched the last two and it was worth it.
Scott: But here's an example of how I am jaded.
Scott: if you still can't understand right?
Scott: I think look at movies, right?
Scott: I haven't been to the movie theater in forever.
Rym: No, we went once but we want to see paprika recently.
Scott: oh, yeah, that that's different but I Since before paprika before I went to see that I was not excited about a single movie since Lord of the Rings.
Scott: all three of them, right and Every time people would start yapping about oh, let's go see this movie all this.
Scott: even today people say oh this movie's great You got to go see it.
Scott: Oh this movie, right?
Scott: First of all, I got Netflix All right so I don't got time for your movie theater.
Scott: and second of all I think back and I think of Lord of the Rings and Paprika and I'm like, huh?
Scott: It's moot and like.
Scott: is this movie Lord of the Rings level?
Rym: But Scott as a whatever you uh, you miss some pretty damn good movies like but they're not a plus the Sean of the Dead.
Scott: But just I didn't miss that because I wasn't excited by.
Scott: I missed that just because I missed it, you know.
Scott: But you know even good movies that are out now They're they're not Lord of the Rings level.
Scott: so I don't pay attention or get excited or really care.
Scott: And I'll catch him like two years later on Netflix.
Scott: Well,
Rym: the root crux bottom whatever of the issue here is just that with the internet and all other media when we're talking just about consumable entertaining media
Scott: There is more
Rym: media being created than I can peruse Even if I spent 24 hours a day seven days a week watching it reading it Whatever.
Rym: as a result I have to be choosy not to mention the fact that there's all of the media.
Rym: that has been created and preserved throughout the history of Humanity that's been stacked up and between all is now becoming more and more easily available where it used to be.
Rym: Not like I like.
Rym: I have easily a hundred to two hundred books that I own That I haven't read and I really really want to write it on 200 books.
Scott: I haven't read.
Scott: Yeah, I Own like maybe 20 books.
Scott: Are you afraid I can tell you exactly how many books I own that I haven't read?
Rym: not only do I have stacks and stacks of unread books But my book collection is still in Arizona with my mom and I haven't read even half of those books and I wanted to read All of them and I think I still do so it gets to the point where I sit there and I look at all my books And I have to pick one of them to read and as a result I'm never gonna get to the books that don't immediately say Rym You have to read them
Scott: until I'm a retired old man.
Scott: A lot of stuff is just gonna go unwatched unread unseen on whatever.
Rym: That's one benefit of the modern culture.
Rym: as long as I somehow have enough money to retire Retirement doesn't seem as bad.
Rym: I mean I see a lot of people I know retired and grandparents of people who really lead boring like they.
Rym: just they don't do anything anymore and they sit around kind of bored all the time or watching TV or whatever.
Rym: and I know there's exceptions.
Rym: But I see a lot of people like this and I have enough entertainment.
Rym: now.
Rym: if no new Entertainment were created for the rest of my life I think there is enough entertainment in the world to keep me up until the age of 90 retired and Perfectly content and have something to do at all hours.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's a scary thought.
Rym: that means that I'm not gonna be able to read most of the books that I want to Read.
Rym: I'm not gonna be able to watch most of the movies.
Rym: I want to watch.
Rym: there's no way in hell.
Rym: I'm gonna play all the video games.
Scott: I want to play and hence Jadedness while it sucks because there are a lot of things that are quite enjoyable that for some reason I'm just not enjoying and other people think it's weird like, uh, why aren't you you know?
Scott: Loving up this movie that everyone loves so much.
Scott: It's not cuz it's bad It's just because I mean it if you eat steak every day and you eat it every day.
Scott: Eventually steak becomes not so interesting anymore.
Scott: But then when you go to eat a hamburger It doesn't taste so it tastes bad even worse than the steak.
Scott: It's sort of like being addicted to heroin.
Scott: and then you just need you know, if you go down to like morphine It doesn't do shit.
Scott: Nah, but actually more heroin doesn't help you either.
Scott: You need something bigger and badder all the time and eventually run out.
Rym: Emily was making fun of us just a little while ago out there like oh you guys you lead the good life.
Rym: And now you can't understand the simple pleasures.
Rym: and it reminded me of a somewhat sad anecdote that happened not too long ago.
Scott: All right Tell you sad anecdote.
Rym: well Scott and myself and a small portion of the front row crew went to try out a hibachi sushi Whatever chain called Izumi that opened a branch right near our house.
Rym: All right, so we thought oh great We don't have to drive up the road to the neko anymore, even though I really like the neko We'll check this place out and it was kind of mad.
Scott: It was okay.
Scott: It wasn't the greatest.
Scott: It wasn't the worst.
Rym: I would rather drive up the road to the neck.
Scott: Oh, I agree that I would rather drive up to the road to the neck Oh, but it wasn't like bad like.
Rym: ah bad about you don't go there It was just this better but there weren't enough of us to get a whole table So we ended up sharing a table with this couple and whatever.
Rym: We're just talking and they're just talking.
Rym: and I think we related a whole other story about how our conversation was crippled by the fact that they weren't really geeky and Almost everything we said weirded them out and they just couldn't deal with it and they kept talking to us and it kind of ruined Our dinner.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't want I really don't want strangers talking to me while I don't mind strangers talking to me But they could not engage us in any conversation that we wanted to have and they just kept.
Rym: it was weird.
Rym: But anyway, so we're just talking.
Rym: I'm looking at the menu and one thing this place has is you can't lobster In your hibachi.
Scott: Yeah, the neko does not offer that surprisingly enough Yeah, but I'm looking I'm thinking and I say to myself.
Rym: Oh, man lobster.
Rym: I'm all about that, but I just had lobster yesterday So maybe I shouldn't have lobster two nights in a row.
Rym: Then those people turn to us.
Rym: they're like, wow, aren't you guys the fancy spenders?
Rym: la di da?
Scott: and I'm like.
Rym: And I'm like, whoa.
Rym: Yeah, I did just have lobster.
Scott: But you look at the menu the lobsters like $15.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's not like it's some $50 deal.
Scott: It's it's 15 bucks.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: How is it?
Rym: So I kind of notice this in my life and it's not a matter of money.
Rym: It's just like because I used to really like eating at diners.
Rym: I used to eat them all the time But now we don't eat out so often.
Rym: So when will other than lunches?
Rym: so when do I eat out?
Rym: I always want to go to like the best possible restaurant at the time.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Rym: so as a result I don't go to the diner anymore Even though I really like the diner.
Rym: just if I'm gonna eat out I'd rather go to the cafe Maya.
Scott: I know it's.
Scott: I go to the cafe Maya I go to the Chipotle.
Scott: So what's the point of you know, Joe's Tex Mex?
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: I got Cafe Maya.
Scott: Joe's Tex Mex doesn't mean shit for me.
Rym: The thing is it's weird cuz I can still eat Taco Bell.
Rym: I fucking love Taco Bell.
Scott: I can't eat any fast food.
Scott: Really.
Scott: I eat it like when necessary and that's about it Taco Bell in White Castle.
Scott: I always get like some piece of chicken.
Scott: That's horrible.
Rym: So see, I'm not.
Rym: I'm not jaded about fast food It's more that I see.
Rym: I think there's a jaded.
Rym: we can't talk about it in such simple terms because People say someone's jaded about something and there's a whole slew of different reasons.
Rym: A person could have lost interest in something that has nothing to do with just he's so jaded.
Rym: He doesn't care doesn't give a carrot all about the world anymore blah blah.
Scott: Yeah, it's very difficult to tell.
Scott: sometimes also It's like I used to like that thing and now I don't.
Scott: why is it?
Scott: You know, is it?
Scott: am I not interested in movies anymore because DVDs and bit torrent?
Scott: Or is it actually because I'm jaded from seeing a zillion awesome to me.
Rym: I can do the movies thing very simply.
Rym: It's just time because I love watching movies.
Rym: I remember before we did GeekNights when we just lived in this house with our.
Rym: we had all this money and all this free Time and nothing to do.
Rym: we watch like every night.
Rym: We watched a movie.
Rym: Yeah, almost every single night We were Netflix.
Scott: send it back.
Scott: Netflix send it back.
Rym: Not only that but we were buying box sets like we bought a box set of old Hitchcock.
Scott: But it's not just not watching movies.
Scott: It's that you know, people will bring up movies They'll start talking about them and I'm just completely uninterested whatsoever.
Rym: Well, it's not so much movies that people bring that it's TV shows.
Rym: A lot of our friends watch TV and they're
Scott: always TV shows, you know I am somewhat interested in TV shows but only on DVD and I don't really care about them on television even though some of them might be good, but well,
Rym: they try to get the yell at us like.
Rym: I think Battlestar Galactica is Absolutely amazing.
Scott: I don't think it's so great.
Rym: That's cuz you're dumb, but I did say it I really freaking like it.
Rym: I think it's super awesome and I really want to see it.
Rym: but just in terms of all the media I have to consume and all the Non-media, I have to do like making media like this podcast and all the other things and my job.
Rym: I don't have time to watch Battlestar Galactica and it seems like a lot of our friends get really kind of indignant about it.
Rym: Like why aren't you watching it?
Rym: I keep telling you too And why don't you?
Rym: and I'm like because I have more important things to do.
Rym: I want to say it I agree with you that it's great.
Rym: I Have to make this podcast and then I have to cook a dinner and then I have to play this video game so I can Talk about it on the show and then I gotta go to sleep.
Scott: Yeah It's I don't know.
Scott: basically I do feel though in my in myself that I'm getting like less Enjoyment from things.
Rym: see I think that's just you.
Rym: that's the second issue.
Rym: I think we'll save this for another show.
Rym: Why is Scott so sad?
Scott: I'm not good.
Rym: No not sad But it's very rare that I see you Like really into something and really enjoying it and like seeing the joys sparkle in your eye.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I see that like you you have gotten to the point in like in Dungeons & Dragons Where I don't think there is anything other than playing burning wheel in a one-off with Luke Crane himself While being fell aided by a band of slave women or something.
Rym: I don't think you can enjoy role-playing anymore.
Scott: I Think I can because I have recently when our last D&D session we played lacuna at the shore.
Rym: That was fun But our last D&D sessions is evolved into the entire group yelling at you for basically Saying that you don't like settings anymore that you want only settingless games.
Scott: It doesn't have to be setting lists It's just I don't want.
Scott: I want to interact more with the other players than I interact with the setting.
Scott: That's what I was saying.
Rym: but anyway to get I don't well do another show about that sometime or special or whatever, but You can't confuse this with.
Rym: I don't want to say Getting better taste or anything pretentious like that But more of becoming more knowledge.
Scott: better taste would be a matter of.
Scott: I'm jaded.
Scott: I don't like those Tezuka's.
Scott: I'm gonna read my Naruto's.
Scott: that's needing better taste.
Rym: I think taste is subjective in many ways, but it is the idea that like.
Rym: let's take the example of fast food.
Rym: I used to eat a lot of fast food as a kid fast food.
Rym: Not because I know that's what I'm getting it.
Rym: I used to eat a lot of fast food as a kid.
Rym: I used to drink a lot of soda as a kid like Seven or eight cans of to use the vernacular in Michigan pop.
Rym: I drank a lot of pop soda.
Rym: I'm gonna start saying that word again cuz like 48% of Americans say pop.
Scott: They're all wrong.
Rym: It's pop.
Scott: That's how you can tell.
Rym: the thing is I say 48% because I don't count those cola people or those coke people.
Rym: They're not people.
Scott: Nope, but unless they say moxie Moxie is awesome.
Rym: I here's the thing Scott always yells at me for like liking things Like.
Rym: I only like the idea of liking it.
Scott: You just eat shields all the time.
Rym: I'll admit this.
Rym: I like the idea of moxie soda cuz it's old Like the idea of my soda as much as I would love to like moxie soda.
Rym: that shit tastes like battery acid.
Scott: I never taste not good.
Scott: I never tasted it, but I do really like the idea of moxie soda.
Rym: It is I wanna like it.
Rym: I want to be one of those guys.
Rym: He's like ha moxie, but it tastes like shit.
Scott: I know it's so bad.
Scott: What's?
Rym: it tastes like drinking burning phosphorus?
Scott: I'll just have to take a word for it.
Rym: I would rather drink battery acid cuz.
Scott: Actually, I don't think there's much of a difference But we should try to make a battery at a moxie.
Rym: I get a lot of crap from people mostly at my job and just kind of normal people about.
Rym: I won't eat fast food Like we'll be at a job and they're like, hey, we're working late.
Rym: I'll go get some McDonald's for everyone and I'm like, I'm not gonna eat McDonald's and I just don't eat anything.
Rym: And they think it's really weird.
Rym: Like why won't you McDonald's?
Rym: everybody's McDonald's like?
Rym: I don't like McDonald's.
Rym: Everyone likes McDonald's and they get into the stupid argument and I don't care about him.
Scott: So They get an argument about that.
Rym: They're like, why don't you eat McDonald's?
Rym: It's poison.
Rym: Why do you have a thing against McDonald's?
Rym: Oh, you're just some health food nut.
Rym: It's not a health food nut.
Scott: It's a difference between being a health food nut and not eating poison.
Scott: I mean a health food nut is someone who always shops, you know, like, you know The super organic granola II like Atkins.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, whatever get into that cuz I want to work.
Rym: You want to get into it either but cuz I want to Want to go eat some I'm hungry.
Rym: Just I want to make you're not an idiot.
Scott: It's like not smoking.
Rym: I'm saying is that I had a taste for that stuff right then.
Rym: then over time as I got to college and I started You know eating and drinking a much larger variety of things outside of the Midwest.
Rym: I Started not drinking so much soda and not eating so much fast food And then as time went on like once I stopped being accustomed to that food.
Rym: now The idea like biting into a McDonald's burger the taste of it makes me nauseous.
Scott: You still eat your freaking White Castle.
Rym: White Castle's different.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It is the same shit.
Rym: Cuz it's the White Castle smaller.
Rym: No, it's not because White Castle is just Greece.
Rym: They're not pretending it's me.
Rym: You don't bite into that and think oh man fake meat.
Rym: It's just Greece with onion paste.
Rym: It's so good.
Rym: Anyway, I only eat fast food when necessary and I actually if there is a White Castle within a half hour I would go get like 20 White Castle's depending on which fast food I get.
Scott: I actually like some of it.
Scott: like Arby's.
Scott: I love some Arby's.
Rym: I can eat those Arby's chicken fingers all day long.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: chicken fingers and curly fries from Arby's are awesome.
Rym: Well, those curly fries fries are awesome while also disgusting.
Scott: while my mouth loves them My stomach hates them and thus I am able to just not eat them.
Scott: and I don't really eat fast food Unless I absolutely have.
Rym: I think soda is a better example because soda in and of itself Well, that's cuz.
Rym: Scott can't deal with fizziness Even non fizzy soda.
Rym: Well, the thing is soda is not really bad for you.
Rym: Just a lot of people drink too much of it and it also ruins your teeth.
Rym: Not so much.
Rym: You don't ruins your teeth more than anything not brushing.
Rym: Well, brush your teeth not.
Rym: Actually in terms of drinks number one is lemonade.
Rym: lemonade is the worst possible thing you can drink other than I don't know What if it's not corn syrup lemonade though?
Rym: That's even worse uh-huh, because it's a combination of sucrose and Super acidic lemon and it sticks to your teeth and it just it's horrible for your teeth All right.
Rym: Number two is energy drinks.
Rym: Number three is soda.
Rym: Uh-huh only do lemonade and even then so does not that bad for your teeth in moderation, but Soda, especially in America is super super super sweet and that didn't bother me as a kid But as I started drinking and eating a lot of different things.
Rym: now if I drink normal soda It's so sweet that it's almost painful.
Rym: Like I feel sick drinking it like wow.
Rym: There's way too much sugar in this.
Rym: I can't deal with it.
Scott: Yeah I do feel sick like eating fast food and stuff like now like eating like I used to eat a Cinnabon and like mmm now I eat a Cinnabon and it's like oh my stomach.
Rym: Ah Did we tell the Cinnabon story on the show?
Scott: No, we're not gonna bother with it.
Scott: I'll save that but I think let's just end it.
Scott: and I'll say if there's anyone else out there who's like me where you just Can't enjoy things because you've seen so much shit on the internet that it takes something so crazy to interest you We should start like some jaded by the internet support group or something like that.
Rym: All that would be is an RS that you realize that that just devolves into Rome in the end.
Rym: is hedonism bot?
Rym: Yeah, because you get so jaded that the only thing left is you have to Summon one of the slaves and have him executed and then dipped in the finest of oils and creams.
Scott: But that doesn't even excite me.
Scott: What do you?
Scott: what do you?
Rym: what excite you?
Rym: I mean, are you gonna get so decadent that what?
Rym: what?
Rym: if you could have anything in the world right now?
Rym: What would instill joy in you Scott Rubin?
Scott: not possible not possible Right now.
Rym: anything infinite money.
Rym: You have the count of Monte Cristo's money and hedonism bots resources and million slaves.
Rym: What what are you gonna get?
Scott: make some Star Wars movies that don't suck?
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I think that's it.
Rym: Geeks like us you have to get together and be patrons of the arts like in the old days and commission great works.
Scott: That's that's.
Scott: that's worse than than our current copyright system For many reasons.
Scott: a reason we got rid of the patron system.
Scott: We went to the copyright systems.
Rym: fine if it's in parallel to another system within the system.
Rym: Well, I think the only way left to keep us from just killing ourselves is to commission great works.
Scott: I guess I'll have to go and commission some Sculptures or something.
Rym: but Emily's here.
Rym: She's an animator.
Rym: She went to NYU.
Rym: make us Star Wars.
Rym: That doesn't suck.
Scott: I don't know if she could do that.
Scott: She said no People have tried on the internet.
Scott: They haven't quite gotten.
Scott: cuz you're forgetting.
Rym: patrons need money.
Scott: We need to be rich first, but if I'm rich I'll just drive my Ferrari and I won't be jaded.
Rym: Yeah, you will you get you realize after like two weeks of driving that Ferrari.
Rym: You'll be like man.
Rym: I need a Bugatti.
Rym: I don't think that'll happen cuz I need a custom car.
Rym: and then man I need to fly my jet and man I need to fly my Star Destroyer.
Scott: I think once I had the space shuttle, I'd be alright.
Rym: the space shuttle sucks.
Scott: Well renew better space shuttle that piece of shit.
Rym: All right, we're done cuz I need me some white castles.
Scott: I need to be some space shuttles.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.