Scott: It's Tuesday January 30th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we review WarioWare smooth moves.
Rym: It's a wee Wario.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, I dutifully did my civic duty and reported to jury duty today.
Scott: Did you do any jury-ing?
Scott: Any nullifying?
Rym: Well, you see it was not as painful as I expected.
Rym: I'll tell the whole story on Thursday.
Rym: when we talk about jury duty Is that what we're talking about Thursday?
Scott: because they never had jury duty?
Scott: I don't know if it's a good for a whole show if I've never.
Rym: I've got quite a bit to say about how jury duty Went.
Rym: okay, and it's not over yet.
Rym: You see the trials that came up were large long trials.
Scott: So you didn't get to go to the nice traffic court.
Scott: you had to go to the serious criminal bad thing court.
Rym: So what what ended up happening?
Rym: was you know?
Rym: They have a thing where hey if you this would be a hardship to you.
Rym: fill out this form.
Rym: Sign a statement swearing that it'll be a hardship, and we'll figure something out.
Rym: So I told him what my job is and they said oh you can go home.
Scott: Yeah, all right What time was that?
Rym: well?
Rym: They might make me come back not tomorrow, but maybe Thursday for like.
Scott: are you gonna go to work tomorrow?
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna go to work tomorrow, and I will see but theoretically Just because of the line of work.
Rym: I'm in.
Rym: I can't be called up for jury duty.
Rym: No, that's good and apparently even if I don't have to go in the rest of the week I'm ineligible for jury duty for another six years from this point.
Scott: Oh six years is pretty good.
Rym: watch six years from now like immediately jury duty, and if I'm still an IT worker in Hospitals I probably just won't get to serve on a jury again.
Scott: Yeah, but if you're doing that in six years I don't know.
Scott: is that what you want to be doing in six years.
Scott: Hey if I'm the boss Alright, if you're the boss, that's cool, then yeah, I could deal with but if you still got your same job in six years It's no good.
Rym: I probably won't have my same job in a year and a half.
Scott: I might not have my same job in weeks.
Rym: Yeah, aren't you interviewing with Google?
Rym: No Yeah, barely you're talking to a Google guy.
Scott: It's this one person from Google who seems that it seems like this is person at Google and their job is to go around the Internets.
Scott: all right finding people who might be able to work at Google who haven't applied to work at Google.
Scott: Aha so they look for like.
Scott: they'll go to forums and look for people giving tech advice or they'll go to the look at resumes just posted in places and They'll look at open source projects and things and they'll say hey Here's someone.
Scott: have they applied to work at Google?
Scott: they haven't.
Scott: we should talk to them, huh?
Scott: And apparently she said it's.
Scott: it was like the subject line of the first email.
Scott: They send out a form letter.
Scott: because I searched for the form letter And I found this same person sending the same form letter to everyone.
Scott: She just changes the line that says where she found out about you.
Scott: yeah, and It was like Google is impressed with your resume, and it was my old resume.
Scott: So I sent the new one.
Rym: love Google's impressed with your old resume.
Rym: I know it's.
Scott: this is one person whose only job It is is to seek out people who haven't applied to Google.
Scott: I think you know.
Scott: of course they probably hire a few people this way.
Rym: no I can tell you what's going on.
Rym: I see what's going on here.
Scott: Google is amassing its resume database.
Rym: Google is getting basically dossiers on every single tech worker in the United States and possibly the world.
Rym: and Then when they build Skynet, that's why they want a million.
Scott: That's why a million people apply to work at Google and only five thousand actually get hired.
Rym: when they build Skynet They know exactly who needs to be on their side or gone.
Scott: It could be that's all it is.
Rym: you know it.
Scott: It's got something to do it.
Scott: But no she actually wants to talk to me on the phone and yeah, but yet I'm talking about other jobs, which are basically the same as my job only different places.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty much gonna go into those like all.
Scott: ass ish cuz I'll be like yeah, what are you gonna do for me?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I already got a job.
Scott: Offer me some shit.
Rym: I imagine cuz usually when I apply to a job I never really say like I don't demand a salary right away.
Scott: I usually just say oh, I never say like a specific salary or anything.
Rym: well But I rarely.
Rym: the most I ever did was say you'd have to pay me at least X Mmm.
Rym: If I were in your position.
Rym: I would probably say something like I need XY and Z alright or and if you can't tell me that that is a possibility.
Rym: There's no point in us continuing.
Scott: Yeah, well you know I always wait for them to ask.
Scott: you know I like cuz.
Scott: I even like if I just go in and say That and then leave.
Scott: that's kind of a waste of my time.
Scott: I'd like to at least you know find out about companies and see what I would probably do is I'd ask ahead of time.
Rym: You know before I interview whoever whatever recruiter I talked to I just asked him can this company offer me at minimum the following otherwise.
Rym: We're wasting both of our time.
Scott: Well, it's not a recruiter.
Scott: I'm actually talking to someone at the company.
Scott: Yeah, I like to go and see what companies are doing.
Rym: recruiter at the company.
Scott: Yeah, I just like to go see what companies are like.
Scott: you know walk around offices.
Scott: Oh,
Rym: yeah, but what if you talk to him ahead of time, and they say yeah Regardless we're not prepared to pay more than $70,000 a year for our position at that point You know if that's the salary you weren't looking for there's no point in talking to the people at the company
Scott: unless I want to go See what their company's like.
Rym: why would you want to do that if you already know?
Rym: They're not gonna.
Rym: Give you the job you want.
Scott: all corporate espionage.
Rym: What are you gonna?
Rym: Do after having seen the inside of some PR HR guys office?
Scott: I like.
Scott: I like offices uh-huh.
Rym: So you don't like urban exploration or crawling around in subways yet you like going to generic offices.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I like that's like.
Scott: I like going to staples What you?
Scott: are you looking at me funny?
Scott: I?
Rym: I don't get you sometimes weirdo.
Scott: You're weird.
Scott: anyway in the news We gotta talk about gaming for the rest of the show in the news.
Rym: There's news on the Wii now.
Scott: oh Right right right?
Scott: that the the news channel on the Wii.
Rym: yeah, it came out a day early Which I didn't notice or care.
Scott: I didn't even know it was coming into like a second before it showed up, and then it was like oh there It is.
Rym: well the thing is right away.
Rym: You notice that one it.
Rym: You can't really customize it.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like the Weather Channel where you say all right?
Rym: Oh, you mean the useless Weather Channel that always tells you the weather at midnight.
Scott: I know the Weather Channel be more useful if it would update the weather more often, but it doesn't.
Rym: it's not that it updates Infrequently it's that no matter when you look at it.
Rym: It only ever gives you the temperature for midnight.
Scott: Yeah, if you're looking for current temperature the weather thing is no good.
Scott: It's only good for like the five-day forecast, but even then it's kind of a see.
Rym: I only want the Wii to tell me the weather.
Rym: now.
Rym: if I'm looking for the forecast I'll be going to no a gov anyway.
Scott: Yeah, definitely more accurate than the weather that the Wii gets.
Rym: but the Wii news channel is basically just the AP wire.
Scott: yep It's just the Associated Press.
Scott: pretty much almost every story from the Associated Press in the past X-period of time like day or so and You know the only really cool thing about is you can go around the globe looking at news stories.
Scott: So you know it's like I don't you?
Scott: when I read my Google Reader in my RSS feeds I'm usually not getting the normal news, so this Wii news makes it pretty easy to read normal news story.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: the normal news like the news?
Scott: That's on TV and in newspapers like why opposed to on slash down on dig see I read Google news.
Rym: So I know what.
Scott: I also read Google news, but you know sometimes it doesn't give you like what what doesn't it?
Rym: Give you it all.
Scott: well the other thing is my Google news is customized to only give me like three stories In the like national international news section and only three stories in the national news section.
Rym: well Why don't you just expand that?
Scott: Because then it it's kind of annoying.
Rym: instead you're gonna go to the Wii every day.
Scott: Yeah, I don't go to the Wii every day But if you know from sitting at the Wii and I got nothing to do click on news channel see what's going on.
Rym: Well, I guess part of the problem is I never.
Rym: it's not like I have idle time ever.
Rym: It's not like I'm sitting in a living room thinking.
Rym: What could I do with my free hours?
Scott: Well, it's like you know.
Scott: sometimes you sit down you want to play a video game.
Scott: You're not sure which one.
Scott: while you're thinking about it.
Scott: You can read a couple news stories.
Scott: It's actually pretty fun the way you read news on there.
Scott: It's actually like it's decent to read and browse the news on the screen.
Scott: It's it's a good interface thing.
Rym: yeah, though I imagine if we get the Wiimote working exactly the way we want with the Mac It'll more and more eliminate the need to use the Wii for any of that.
Scott: yeah, yeah, oh well so check this out on.
Scott: I think next week or early in February the first week in February I'm pretty sure Diddy Kong raising DS is coming out all right.
Rym: I've never actually played a single Diddy Kong or game or a game that included any of those characters other than Donkey Kong.
Scott: Yeah, well Diddy Kong showed up in Donkey Kong Country remember.
Rym: I never played those games.
Scott: Donkey Kong Country was a good classic SNES game.
Rym: that was pretty much that in fact.
Rym: I remember specifically that game came out not too long after I had migrated almost entirely to PC gaming.
Scott: No, wow that was way long ago.
Rym: I was PC gaming.
Rym: wait I remember when I got Nintendo Power I still used to think that my PC was a better gaming platform.
Scott: anyway For the n64 there was a game called Diddy Kong racing, and you know it got played up You know bigger than anyone expected But it still wasn't.
Scott: you know it wasn't as big a smash as Mars at.
Rym: that game was like the boat and the airplane.
Scott: It's actually when you look at it with you know you take away the fact that the characters are characters that no one knows about Because they're Diddy Kong characters as opposed to Mario characters.
Scott: It's actually a better racing game than Mario Kart 64 ever was.
Scott: you know I was always.
Scott: I was skeptical when I first played it for the n64.
Scott: you know I'm like Diddy Kong racing.
Scott: Give me a break.
Scott: And then I played it and I'm like oh you can be a plane or a boat and a car and race them all against Each other.
Scott: that sounds ludicrous.
Scott: It's a. it's actually really works so well because it's even and it's actually a racing game even though it has the items.
Scott: It's more of a racing game whereas Mario Kart is more of a random item crap game.
Rym: well No Mario Kart for the DS.
Rym: There's pretty much no randomness in it.
Scott: there is the most the least random.
Scott: Mario Kart is the Game Boy Advance one.
Scott: But Diddy Kong Racing is actually a really good racing game.
Scott: the theme of it is just one No one knows about because no one cares about Diddy Kong, huh, but Diddy Kong Racing DS seems to be everything.
Scott: Diddy Kong Racing for the 64 was well.
Rym: I want more racing games for my DS.
Rym: I mean I like Mario Kart, but it's played out.
Rym: I beat it.
Rym: I'm done with it.
Scott: the Wi-Fi is dead Yep, but Diddy Kong Racing is gonna have one thing that Mario Kart DS Every racing game recently severely lacks and that is a custom track editor Uh-huh much better than the one in the original excite bike.
Rym: so wait Can I just?
Rym: I mean basically my dream editor would be I have a pallet a blank thing and I can just draw a track.
Scott: That's what you do got to.
Scott: just take the stylus and you draw.
Scott: You know let you draw the track the shape of it And then you race on it and there's a limit to how long the track can be.
Scott: and you know you can.
Scott: you might Accidentally draw an invalid track, and then it'll.
Scott: then it won't.
Scott: let you race it.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no your track is invalid.
Scott: fix it.
Rym: kind of like the other day when I was at the supermarket Self-checking out and I signed my name And it sat there for a while hung and it turned out that it couldn't figure out my signature And it didn't think that it was a real signature.
Scott: wait, but haven't?
Scott: we filled it in before and it's worked.
Rym: It depends on where you go.
Rym: some.
Rym: they actually look at it and apparently according to the cashier It was annoying because it rejects about 90% of signatures.
Scott: really where was this?
Rym: Some grocery store in yawkers.
Scott: Oh, they must have a weird new thing at that grocery store.
Rym: Well, I think they tried to up security.
Rym: I think they enabled some sort of secure bit.
Scott: No, they should turn that secure bit off.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so here's a video of the track editor and Diddy Kong Racing DS so you can see if you think it's cool and You know if you're someone who was playing Mario Kart DS And maybe you're done with it, or you know it's gone out of style Diddy Kong Racing DS.
Scott: I guarantee you at all the conventions this year This is gonna get some mad wireless multiplayer action.
Scott: It's better.
Scott: you might want to get yourself a cap.
Rym: well considering a DS is being sold every 60 seconds in the u.s.
Rym: Currently.
Scott: yeah, yeah things of the day.
Rym: So we all love Mortal Kombat.
Scott: What well about you?
Scott: But I only really like Mortal Kombat 2.
Scott: Mortal Kombat 1 is sometimes fun But it's not very good.
Rym: Mortal Kombat 1 was a was a good game only From the perspective of a 13 year old boy.
Scott: Yeah, and Mortal Kombat with numbers greater than 2 or just painful I mean God, but it is a 3d Mortal Kombat.
Scott: No one played.
Rym: you remember when Mortal Kombat 3 the arcade game came out Which is pretty much right at the like the ass end of the arcade era?
Scott: Yeah, I mean Mortal Kombat 2.
Scott: You know well even Mortal Kombat 1 had what they call.
Scott: is the That the palette swaps or whatever?
Scott: yeah, it's the same character.
Scott: Just a different color.
Rym: Oh scorpion.
Scott: ah Smart score yeah, and Mortal Kombat 2 took it a little bit further.
Scott: They had sub-zero Yeah, but Mortal Kombat 3 you think they would have learned their lesson.
Scott: No they went even crazier And there are just all these characters that were the same exact thing with a different color.
Rym: So what a rainbow coalition of scorpions, so they were different.
Scott: They had these spiky predator masks.
Rym: I don't know who they were But really I do remember that When I went to my old arcade tilt when I was a kid Mortal Kombat 3 was the hot hot hot game And there'd be this crazy crowd of people around it.
Rym: You could never play because it was that that was like the hot game and people.
Scott: where I was Mortal Kombat 3 was never The hot game was Mortal Kombat 2 was the hot game.
Scott: people would line up and one guy who knew to do how to do Some combos would stand there for a long time playing for free and everyone else's money.
Rym: well the arcade always had like the newest newest game to come out and A million super super old games that were actually also for sale.
Scott: Yeah, before arcades died you know when like Super Street Fighter 2 turbo was a new game and when Mortal Kombat 2 was a new Game the arcade was hopping really hopping like crazily the one in the mall.
Scott: They always had the greatest new games.
Scott: It was crazy.
Rym: Hey, at least we got Wildwood.
Rym: the arcades there on the boardwalk are more hopping than any other arcades I've ever been to.
Scott: Dave and Busters is and Jillian's and places are kind of hop.
Rym: Jillian's aren't happen.
Scott: No, it depends.
Rym: Jillian's are lame.
Scott: It depends on which one you go to but if you go there at the right times that there are people there.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, not like the boardwalk.
Scott: No, it's a different crowd.
Rym: But anyway, we also love Street Fighter 2 and Street fall the Street fighters except Street Fighter 1.
Scott: Yes, Street Fighter 1 is good for looking back on but you don't want to play that game.
Scott: There's nothing to it.
Rym: You realize when Street Fighter 2 came out I'd never heard of or even known that a Street Fighter 1 it exists.
Scott: I knew that one must have existed, but I never played it.
Scott: No, and I played it once.
Rym: I thought it was like Goonies - where there was?
Rym: there wasn't really a Goonies one I mean there was in the arcade and there might have been one for the NES But no one had ever played it Goonies - came out and that was the first Goonies game as far as anyone knew.
Scott: Yeah, I went.
Scott: I actually played Street Fighter 1 once in an arcade.
Scott: It was the version where there's just one button, you know and you depending on how hard you push the button It's either light or hard kicking and punching and it's not fun.
Scott: It's a bad game.
Rym: Well, uh, what if you were to combine these two and say have scorpion fight ryu?
Scott: Well, everyone's always wanted that but you know because those are the only two fighting game franchises We can't combine.
Scott: all we have is Capcom vs.
Scott: SNK and Marvel vs.
Scott: Capcom and stuff like that.
Rym: Well, not only did someone make a video that does it very well, but they made this video Cinematic quality.
Rym: this is an epic knockdown.
Rym: drag them out right out of they live Fight to the bitter end between ryu and scorpion and I got to say it's actually pretty cool and I'd recommend you watch it.
Rym: I'm not gonna ruin who wins But it plays out like any fighting scene in any movie you've ever seen where one guy's getting the crap kicked out of him but then the tide turns and the other guys getting the crack kicked out of him and then it comes down to the bitter wire and They both have and they know how to start
Scott: off using the wussy punches and then by the end it is using all special moves And fireball fireball fireball.
Rym: There's this one part where ryu throws like hadoken at an angle from the wall.
Rym: He's in the air then he drops down and throws another one in slow motion and it's really cool.
Scott: Yeah, it's good stuff.
Scott: You can actually do that in some of the newer street fighters.
Rym: Yeah See even they don't ask me how he was doing stuff that I'd never seen.
Rym: ryu do?
Rym: I know how to do a spinny Kick and an uppercut and a hadoken.
Scott: That's those are his basic three moves anyway, so You play board games and doesn't it kind of suck?
Scott: good board games take too long.
Rym: That is the primary reason I don't go to Mars on a regular basis.
Scott: Yeah Well, what if you played a board game for five hours, so that suck I'd kill myself.
Scott: What if it was ten hours?
Rym: I'm already dead.
Rym: So I guess I'd rot some.
Scott: what if it was 42 hours and 48 minutes such a thing could never be Well to win.
Scott: I guess winning it's not really a prize But to qualify for entry into the Guinness Book of World Records for longest board game ever played a longest board game marathon.
Scott: these German guys There are four of them they played Carcassonne for 42 hours and 48 minutes.
Scott: I don't know what expansions they had or what combination of expansions they had But they definitely had that.
Scott: there's no way.
Scott: when you look at the pictures of how big this board is at the end There's no way that they could have done.
Scott: It was just one set.
Scott: They definitely had multiple sets.
Scott: There's no other explanation for it but I don't know how many meeples they had each like.
Scott: did they modify that?
Scott: because Eventually, you're just gonna lay them all out as farmers or you just have to farm basically never because you know that eventually there's gonna Be a bigger farm somewhere.
Scott: So you just wait for it and eventually you'll put a guy in it.
Scott: See now it's not worth it for anyone to put two guys into it because they can always put two guys into two other farms that no One else can compete with.
Rym: you know what I would have done if I was there in this game Mm-hmm every tile I got I would have put on one side of the board in a long chain just to fuck it.
Scott: Oh That's if you can.
Scott: you might have to do like two separate chains just so that you'll always be.
Rym: Oh, yeah But I would just pick one side and whenever possible build as far as I can toward one player who was annoying me.
Rym: I've done that before in other games at Carcassonne.
Rym: if I'm winning or something I'll just start building towards Scott just to make him shift back a little.
Scott: yeah Yeah, it's a good move.
Scott: But no they made a giant Carcassonne board.
Rym: They played Carcassonne for 42 hours and 48 minutes, you know Normally if someone doesn't take their turn we get a little lacrosse.
Rym: if I was playing that Lay let level of board game and someone didn't make their turn in I don't know three seconds.
Rym: I'd probably just kill him.
Scott: Yeah, I would really want to know what the requirements were for this to qualify as the Guinness.
Scott: I mean, what if I took one turn and then Rym took an hour on his turn?
Scott: Yeah, we could.
Scott: does that count?
Scott: I mean, we're still playing.
Scott: just Rym, you know didn't take his turn.
Rym: Yeah, we're playing chess.
Scott: We've been playing chess for the last 10 years and Carcassonne is a game that can theoretically go on forever.
Scott: I mean, you know Did they just figure out like how many tiles per minute and then start with that many tiles in order to make the record time?
Scott: Or did they just keep adding tiles to the game when they really?
Rym: you know, I don't know.
Rym: Well, it's your thing of the day.
Scott: So the onus is it doesn't say anything and I can't find any information.
Scott: And if there is information, it's in German.
Scott: So it's not helping me out.
Rym: Oh, well, at least we just played a normal sane game of Carcassonne.
Scott: I thought I was gonna win but you built two giant castles.
Scott: one of them had the cloister not the cloister the Cathedral.
Rym: Yeah the suicide bit.
Rym: Yeah, see I will.
Rym: I always win Carcassonne Yeah, but usually I do with farming but this time because we're playing with three people and it's not like playing with a bunch Of our other friends who wall.
Rym: I mean, they're smart people.
Rym: They just don't play board games as much as we do.
Rym: I was playing against Scott and Alex who are pretty much the people who if anyone's gonna beat me at this game It's one of them.
Scott: I wondered see I think The only reason I lost is because you jumped into my farm at the last second when I had no time to possibly defend it Further.
Rym: that was my plan.
Rym: I know I realized that later you put that big farmer in and I thought wow That's the only farm in the game.
Rym: That's worth a goddamn.
Rym: I'll just jump in at the end in time.
Rym: See actually that's what I did to the whole game.
Rym: I also tied Scott on a big city and I tied Alex on a big city and I just king made back and forth back And forth taking points for me points for them one for you one for me And then in the end I'd done that more times than anyone else.
Scott: Yeah, I had thought about putting another farmer in that farm for a while.
Scott: I should have done it.
Scott: if I had I probably would have won.
Scott: but oh well Carcassonne crazy try.
Scott: if you want to see the biggest set of tiles you ever seen good guy out It's pretty crazy.
Rym: But I know you've all been waiting for us to talk about not a board game but a video game because we know that Wario where smooth moves is out and everyone has had a chance to play it at least everyone cool and In a word underwhelmed.
Scott: Well, I think it's uh, it's definitely better than Most of the other Wario games.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think On a raw scale the game cube Wario where is the best Wario where ever made?
Scott: Well the thing you got to understand right this what this for Wario games that Wario where game Wario where touched Twisted the Wii one right there the game cube Wario.
Scott: Where is sort of this odd game?
Scott: and that it's the same exact game as the original Wario?
Scott: where for the Gameboy Advance?
Scott: It's the exact same game.
Scott: Only they added a little bit of multiplayer a little bit.
Rym: They actually added quite a bit of multiplayer.
Scott: They added let's see what there's like nine ten little multiplayer games on there something like that.
Scott: Yeah, all right, and they added a bunch of little multiplayer games and they ported it over to the game cube instead of the Gameboy Advance.
Rym: Yes Thus transforming Wario where from in my opinion a worthless game into one of the greatest party?
Rym: multiplayer games ever made.
Scott: Well, you know the thing about the original Wario.
Scott: where is it's meant to be sort of like a crack you can play.
Scott: No, it's not crap.
Rym: I'm gonna come out and say it that game is worthless.
Scott: I think it's only worthless to you because the situation in which that game is played does not exist for you.
Rym: Oh, you mean you have time to kill and you're bored.
Rym: So you just want to play a mindless nothing game.
Scott: It's like hey, I got five minutes to do nothing.
Scott: I'll play a little bit of Wario where it's quick.
Scott: It's fun You know, it's not too hard.
Scott: You can turn it on turn it off without caring.
Scott: There's.
Scott: no you know It's not a game You got to play for a long time or think a lot about you.
Scott: just you know.
Scott: Move your hands around and think a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, but even if that is I mean people are free to like that sort of thing.
Rym: But that doesn't really.
Rym: it doesn't make it a good game overall It just makes it a game that fills a very specific niche.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it is fun You know to especially if when there's ever there's new games in it.
Scott: That's what makes it fun.
Scott: It's like, you know, if it's a new Wario where it's fun If it's the same old games mini games or micro games that everyone to call them.
Scott: if you've played the micro games before Like okay, I've threaded the needle ten times in my life.
Scott: It's not fun to thread the needle anymore, you know.
Scott: So Wario where games tend to get played out very quickly.
Rym: see but that's the beauty of the GameCube one.
Rym: It never got played out because no matter what if you sit down Adding multiplayer to something so simple and adding it as elegantly as they did makes it just basically an infinitely replayable party game.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I mean the intensity of our Wario.
Rym: our matches rivals even our Mario parties.
Scott: I must agree Yeah, I'm not arguing against you on this that you know, of course Wario where multiplayer is the shit-off.
Scott: And you know, all I want is what.
Scott: there's tons and tons of Wario where multiplayer for the ultimate hotness But there is merit to the single-player Wario where even if it has no place in the life of Rym.
Rym: Yeah I guess my problem is that The GameCube Wario where was an amazing game and in a way in many ways it changed the way we play games as a group.
Rym: Are the front row crew Wario where it became this party game that just got whipped out constantly.
Scott: Yeah, I think the real advantage it has over something like Mario Party.
Scott: right Mario Party was a great party game except All you really wanted to do was play minigames with people, you know you wanted to play your dungeon duos and your dominations and your Can cans and everything but there was such this long Periods of not doing anything and watching animations between those minigames that it's sort and it took an hour.
Scott: It's like oh god Wario where you've got the same multiplayer minigame action But it takes like five minutes and it's really fast paced and you play a lot of minigames and you get all the fun Of a whole Mario Party and that takes an hour squished into like five minutes.
Scott: and that's either.
Scott: the multiplayer is freaking awesome Yep.
Rym: Well, there's different philosophies.
Rym: I mean what Mario Party is definitely a. we're gonna sit down Socialize yell have fun and interact for an hour around Mario Party.
Rym: Wario.
Rym: We're playing WarioWare with each other.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: That's for sure.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah WarioWare smooth moves is the latest installment, you know, we had.
Scott: we already talked about what the other Wario was.
Rym: Yeah, now basically if you played WarioWare touch for the DS, this is the exact same game Only it uses the wiimote instead of using the stylus.
Rym: I mean the minigames are different obviously But in terms of the way you unlock things the kinds of things you can unlock the kinds of modes you can play in The games are 90% identical.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: It has, you know a different set of games, but that's about it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the characters are mostly the same.
Rym: They added a couple characters.
Rym: They took some characters from touch that weren't in the other Wario's.
Scott: Yep, some characters that you've seen before aren't around anymore.
Rym: But it's basically the game of play a small subset of these micro games.
Rym: if you beat enough of them it unlocks Another subset of the micro games and eventually you'll unlock all of them along with a bunch of chinchy chinchy Extras that really don't take you anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like, you know, the single-player would be a lot cooler if there was.
Scott: you could beat it in.
Scott: you know If it took more than a day to beat it I mean I literally sat down started playing and the only reason I didn't beat it in one day is because I just didn't want to.
Scott: It would have taken me literally like I played it for the first day and I just beat it beat it beat it beat it Beat it beat it beat it.
Rym: Hell we got the game.
Rym: We put it in.
Rym: I end up playing a little bit.
Rym: I beat half the game in like 20 minutes.
Scott: Yeah, now there are you know Even if you beat the game in quotes and unlock everything in the whole single-player mode and then unlock everything in the multiplayer mode There is still some micro games that you are still not available and you have to play the single-player, you know It's the correct modes on the single-player enough to get those mini micro games to appear so that kind of Makes you play the single-player enough so you can get all the games to show up now.
Rym: Well, I'll put aside the multiplayer for a bit and look at just the actual gameplay because there are two really important things about Wario.
Rym: Where one is that, you know You can play it with the Wiimote and this is really the first game to show off in full glory how the Wiimote works because Wario where smooth moves is Excellent from a gameplay perspective.
Scott: Yeah I mean if you think about the way monkey ball minigames use the Wiimote, which is based which is not at all 180 degrees The Wiimote actually works in Wario where Wario where is as good as monkey ball is bad.
Scott: Yeah, I mean what basically what happens is the game teaches you these stances, right?
Scott: And the first one is the remote control and the guy, you know It's pretty cool.
Scott: when they introduce a new stance.
Rym: a guy always comes out and says something like like a cool breeze on a summer's Night, so too will you understand the blah blah blah.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yep, and he teaches you a new stance.
Scott: So the remote control stance.
Scott: you hold the Wiimote like a remote control.
Scott: and If when is it?
Scott: when you're about to play a micro game any micro game?
Scott: The game tells you which stance you should be in.
Scott: so it might say okay for this game Get ready hold it like a remote control and you hold it like a remote control and then the game starts.
Scott: now Just cuz you're holding it like a remote control doesn't mean you're gonna be moving it the same way.
Scott: some remote control games require pointing Some require moving it left and right up and down pushing a button not pushing the button, you know.
Scott: So it could often be deceiving.
Scott: You know, you're holding it like a remote control you expect to move it in a certain way and then nope You actually had to move it in a different way.
Rym: Yeah that tripped me up on a couple of minigames.
Scott: yeah, there was the what the flip one where it gives you like a Pancake on a spatula and I keep trying to flip it up in the air.
Scott: But no you're supposed to rotate and just flip it down onto the pan and I go.
Scott: I messed it up so many times.
Scott: I just flipped the pancake onto the wall now.
Rym: There are a lot of forms.
Rym: I can't tell you how many there were offhand, but I mean there's the mohawk.
Rym: you hold it over your head My favorites pie the big cheese where you hold it at your hip and you stand there laughing like a CEO I don't know.
Scott: I really kind of like the the sketch artist one and the thumb wrestler one.
Rym: Ah the thumb wrestler not used very often but used to great effect.
Scott: Yeah the oh, I also like the the driving one the courier.
Rym: Yeah, actually there's one of the boss stages.
Rym: cuz you know all these warrior war games They have boss stages, which are if the games are micro games.
Rym: The boss stages are essentially minigames.
Scott: Yep, and well, they're really just micro games that last more than five seconds.
Scott: They last maybe 30 seconds.
Rym: But there's one where you just drive a car through the woods and the way you control the car Gave me such a hard-on for a Wii racing game other than excite truck like a straight-up.
Scott: Actually that boss stage controls the driving better than excite truck does.
Scott: it's pretty crazy.
Scott: It's really great like you're just driving casually through the woods on a normal road in a normal car and The Wiimote makes an amazing steering wheel that's like perfect in every way.
Scott: and this little Wario boss game Oh, the other great boss stage is the Star Fox one.
Rym: Yeah Oh, I want a Star Fox game and not some sort of weird adventure around and collect the doodads star.
Scott: Well, there was a GameCube one and a DS one whatever.
Rym: Those are all using a Wiimote to control.
Rym: any sort of free space shooter is going to usher in a new era.
Rym: I look forward.
Rym: My speculation here is that you know, they're talking about a Star Wars game lightsaber control.
Scott: Well, there's gonna be rogue squadron ring.
Scott: No doubt.
Rym: Yeah any kind of free pay free space shooter?
Scott: Oh Rogue squadron isn't really a free space.
Rym: That's why I said specifically free space shooter and I just kind of ignored my.
Scott: I might get rogue squadron.
Rym: Anyway, who knows Scott Johnson will get it.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: We'll just have to wait until it's 20 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: That's about worth 20 bucks.
Scott: It's not definitely not worth 50 unless there's a super a supreme drought of games.
Rym: Anyway, but they the L I mean when they first announced WarioWare for the Wii which we knew was gonna come and you couldn't not Make a war.
Rym: I knew we were gonna buy it But I wondered how are they gonna handle the Wiimote?
Rym: because you could deal with in any sort of way and I think this form Idea and also the way they prevent presented.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Imagine if the mini gate the micro games are just like, okay Thread the needle.
Scott: Well, what do you do?
Scott: Do I told the wiimote like this and move it to the left?
Scott: Do I you know hold the wiimote like this and move it that way?
Scott: it would be impossible.
Rym: But also they iconify all of them into very easy to reference very quick pictures that not only are a picture of you Holding it correctly, but the name will remind you anyway.
Rym: So they kind of flash it like do the mohawk and then the minigame starts and the timing is just Absolutely.
Rym: Perfect.
Rym: You have exactly enough time to put the wiimote in whatever configuration and go unless you're playing.
Scott: What's the mode?
Scott: the thrilling mode where it doesn't tell you the stance and you have to figure out you to remember the stance?
Scott: Because you already did the game before.
Rym: yeah Now I'll actually note that after having played most of the game.
Rym: That mode is no different than any other mode.
Scott: Yeah If you've played enough of the WarioWare, you know Stances for most of the games.
Scott: the only time it'll trick you is if it's a game you haven't played before and I don't think that mode gives you games you haven't played before.
Rym: well It does me because you unlocked some games that I hadn't seen while I wasn't home.
Rym: Oh I went to play it and this guy appears on a pole rope and I don't know what's going on.
Scott: And yeah, that's a good one.
Rym: Yeah, it is a good one.
Rym: Anyway Well, yeah, the control is absolutely superb.
Rym: The minigames aren't actually as crazy as the games from WarioWare and the GameCube.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: Is that the in the other WarioWare games maybe not so much touched but the twisted and the original WarioWare?
Scott: The themes of the micro games are sort of way out there and wacky certainly in a chromatic kind of way.
Rym: I mean, there's the anime girl with a Booger coming out of her nose that comes down and snatches your little dude off the ground.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, yeah that one Wow, or probably the most or there was like, you know, the human looking Koopa and Mario that fight, you know It all sort of had this kind of air of you know kind of weird Japanese Grungy styling.
Rym: Yeah, also perhaps the most disturbing game which I would basically call it the rape metaphor.
Scott: Which game was that?
Rym: where it shows a nose in the middle of the screen and there's four players with fingers pointed at it And then text appears and the text is a single word that says Inserts.
Rym: Oh, yeah that one and then it spins around while you try to shove your finger into the nose before someone else.
Scott: Yeah, or the capitalism game?
Rym: Capitalism must crush capital.
Scott: Yeah, the games in this WarioWare tend to have a lot more broad appeal in their theme.
Rym: However, it's like everyone can kind of relate to the games and the style the visual style of the games more easily Because this was a WarioWare that was made for the Wii as opposed to taking Gameboy games and putting them in a container on a GameCube.
Rym: The games are extremely beautiful or extremely ugly on purpose, but the animations and everything in the game is absolutely phenomenal.
Scott: Yeah, everything actually looks really shite, you know bright shiny not so nice colors You know, it's as quality is like a cartoon you would watch on TV.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The music's really good.
Scott: Oh, the music is so awesome.
Scott: Like when I'm standing there in between minigames, I cannot help but dance.
Scott: It is actually impossible to not dance no matter what level you're doing.
Scott: There's always you know, the little music between the minigames and you just dance.
Rym: Oh hell the opening song after it's a Wii Oh Wario is just fantastic.
Rym: I could disco dance to that all night long You know and I'm playing the disco stage with Jimmy T or Jimmy P. Yeah, I just danced the whole time I can't stop and actually When Jimmy has his cats and they do the thriller dance with him.
Scott: I know it's not the thriller dance But well, it's a dance.
Rym: It alludes to the thriller dance.
Rym: It does.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it's more like funky cat.
Rym: Maybe
Scott: all of the you know Cuz whenever you're about to play a new stage in the single-player There's the pre stage video in a little FMV that tells the plot And in quotes and then there's a little video after you beat the stage that shows you the resolution of that plot.
Scott: Yeah, they're all really good.
Scott: Usually they're kind of a or they don't?
Scott: you know, I think of the original warrior where they didn't even really exist.
Scott: But now they're all there and they're all kind of awesome.
Scott: You know, you want to see what happens?
Rym: My favorite one is still Ashley.
Scott: Yeah, I think Jimmy P is always gonna be the best seconded by Mo.
Rym: No, Ashley is great.
Rym: Just I mean, it's a run-of-the-mill whatever.
Rym: But at the very end when she succeeds and doing the thing and then it cuts to her face And then she does that tiny little smirk.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that was great.
Scott: It's good.
Rym: It's good, even though they didn't have her funny song from the DS game.
Scott: No, the DS game actually has a funny song and in the Wii game She doesn't.
Rym: but yeah If we're talking about the single-player just why are you aware as a single-player game or even as a single-player?
Rym: Pass the controller around.
Rym: who can get the high score?
Rym: who can unlock things?
Rym: game a plus.
Rym: Yes, wonderfully executed.
Rym: There is not a single minigame micro game.
Rym: That doesn't work.
Rym: They all function.
Scott: Well, one of them I thought didn't work, but if you ever think it doesn't work It's actually because you don't know how to hell to do it.
Rym: Yeah Luckily they have the temple of form where you can go in and play any one minigame on all three.
Scott: Yeah So like if you're playing and a new minigame comes up a micro game and you can't beat it You just go.
Scott: what the hell am I supposed to do?
Scott: You can go to the temple of form Select it and just keep playing it over and over again until you figure out how it works playing and that's pretty cool.
Scott: It's also pretty cool because if there's a game that you like and it only showed up once and it never gets to show Up, you can go and play it on purpose.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I can also see how many games you have yet to unlock.
Rym: Sadly, we don't have so many more.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, they're.
Scott: they're like three or four per stage.
Scott: We don't have so far now.
Rym: if they had had even half the multiplayer experience that the game key warrior were head I would have rated this game the best multiplayer game Currently available for the Wii possibly going to be one of the greatest of all time for the Wii.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it has.
Scott: the multiplayer is Average.
Rym: Oh, it's kind of and it's so underwhelming don't?
Rym: we can't.
Rym: even I can't mitigate this with well But it's I mean at least I.
Scott: the only thing I can say about the multiplayer is it's there it works.
Scott: See
Rym: it seems and Scott mentioned this when we were playing the game that we expected the GameCube game which was great and I have a feeling and well Scott brought this up first that the Nintendo and the people who designed WarioWare didn't realize that the multiplayer Aspects of the GameCube one is what made it so amazing for so many people.
Scott: Yeah I just think you know.
Scott: think about all the WarioWare games.
Scott: They've come out with the original Game Boy one completely a single-player experience Twisted single-player experience touched a single-player experience entirely, right?
Scott: The GameCube one was just an odd game out that they just poured it to the GameCube for the sake of it.
Scott: I don't even know why they did that.
Scott: me You know, it was a Game Boy game.
Scott: But I guess they just needed a WarioWare game on the GameCube so that they could cover all the systems.
Scott: Yeah, they just ported the original one.
Scott: I guess it also, you know, you could use the Game Boy to play it with the link cable.
Rym: I should look at the credits and see who's lacking or who's different between all these games.
Scott: So when they came out the Wii one what you know, of course there had to be multiplayer.
Scott: They would have been completely stupid Just not have any.
Scott: but you know to put the most effort into that what was primarily a series of single-player Games, I guess they just didn't realize that.
Scott: you know, the multiplayer is what everyone really wanted.
Rym: So the multiplayer has a number of.
Scott: the thing is though is like when you watch the ads for WarioWare.
Scott: They always show like a whole bunch of people enjoying it together.
Rym: It seems like well if you really look it looks like the way this game is designed because when you're playing even the single-player Between sets of like 20 it'll tell you it'll give you a pose and there's a lot of poses in the game.
Rym: It'll be like pose like this and it doesn't score.
Rym: you doesn't know if you do it or not.
Rym: it seems like the game is designed with Japanese sensibilities for one person's just playing and Everyone else is being entertained by watching them play.
Scott: Yeah I mean if you're a normal non geeky people and you actually do with this game tells like if you get normal people to play This and normal people to sit around it'll probably entertain the hell out of them because they're like, oh my god Someone's doing something silly lol, but for geeks it's like no we all need to play this at the same time.
Scott: We take it completely seriously And we're gonna see who's the best at it.
Rym: god damn know even if it only had round robin Which it does.
Rym: cuz if you look at the GameCube one, a lot of people were saying Oh, it doesn't have simultaneous multiplayer.
Rym: That's shite.
Rym: But if you look at the GameCube one, there was almost no Multiplayer simultaneous action.
Scott: I mean, yeah, I mean it the even in the disco game, right?
Scott: Which is the most simultaneous game for the multiplayer for a multiplayer option?
Scott: on the GameCube WarioWare?
Rym: No It wasn't the most multiplayer one was the turtles because it had the four player game between every set.
Scott: I guess I guess.
Scott: but even So most of the time, you know It was one person play a game.
Scott: if they win they get ahead if they lose they fall behind.
Scott: and then you know There would be some interlude that involved four people.
Scott: the disco game was usually you play a game now You play a game.
Scott: now you play a game.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Now everyone play a game.
Scott: now just you play a game, you know there wasn't a whole lot of everyone playing at the same time, but The the way they did that where at least one everyone has their own controller.
Rym: You're sitting there with your controller and While they weren't a huge part of it Like they were interspersed within other games the four player games that they had in the GameCube one were for the most part Fantastic or at least silly enough to still be fantastic yeah, and the fact that there was periodic multiplayer and It weren't round robin passing it around and everything mesh so well made it great.
Rym: Not only is there no simultaneous multiplayer at all Zero in WarioWare smooth moves, but you can't even use more than one.
Rym: we mode ever.
Scott: Yep, if you're playing, you know Let's say the angel game which is just round robin.
Scott: everyone plays a game one at a time.
Scott: if you lose you're out.
Scott: if you win you stay in.
Scott: you have to pass the wiimote to Whoever's turn it is and they only get it.
Scott: not only that but they only give you so much time to do it.
Scott: No, if you're actually playing with 12, I'd like to actually try to play this to 12 people in one room.
Scott: Oh, how would you pass the wiimote to the right person every time?
Scott: I mean and what if I'm trying to beat save Rym?
Scott: if I if I just played a game and now it's rims turn I'll just hold on to the wiimote and hand it off to him late and he'll die.
Rym: See again Japanese sensibilities that this game does not have asshole safeguards in it.
Scott: Nope It's it's not.
Scott: you know The multiplayer is not constructed to be an actual competition of who knows these micro games and who can do well at them.
Scott: It's constructed to just be let's all look silly playing micro games and it's not really a game now.
Scott: granted Let's the weed tells people to do silly things and everyone laughs.
Rym: granted You don't need the asshole protection if you actually have friends who aren't just horrible people.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I might do that once but I'm not gonna do that most of the time.
Rym: Yeah, or not?
Rym: if we're having a semi serious game?
Rym: Yeah, but the fact that you have to pass the wiimote now, this would be fine.
Rym: Normally.
Rym: All right I just passed the wiimote.
Rym: Not only does the aim tell you to use the strap.
Scott: Yeah, it's so contradictory.
Scott: use the wrist strap But you didn't give me enough time to take the wrist strap off.
Scott: pass it and have someone else put the wrist strap on Before the game starts, that'd be okay.
Rym: That's just you know Nintendo covering their butt.
Rym: There is one micro game One where you have to just let go of the wiimote and let it fall on the wrist strap.
Rym: You can't win it if you don't have the wrist strap on but you can't play multiplayer with the wrist strap.
Rym: And yes, that game is in the multiplayer.
Rym: Yes
Scott: I've managed to cheat that game a couple times by when not wearing the wrist strap by just Dropping the wiimote and then catching it like a foot lower Yeah, or by I would play I would have a wiimote with the wrist strap on it But I wouldn't be wearing the wrist strap.
Scott: I would drop the wiimote I'd let go and then I grabbed the wrist strap with my fist and then it would yank on the wiimote and I'd win that Game, but it's totally hit or miss.
Scott: It is totally hit or miss.
Scott: There's no way I can guarantee to win that game.
Scott: how can they reasonably expect you to pass a wiimote and Apply the wrist strap properly.
Scott: It's just insane.
Rym: They missed out on so many opportunities.
Rym: They have this telephone game where the phone rings and you pick it up and it says something in your ear.
Rym: they could have made games where four wiimotes and four people hear four different things or You know say there's like ten different colors or who can pick up the phone the fastest.
Rym: Yeah There was so much potential that they missed out on now.
Rym: that alone would not have failed the multiplayer because the passing around works.
Rym: Okay, and playing the bomb game or the angel game It's not that big a deal to pass the wiimote around other than losing the fun psychological factor and losing the simultaneous multiplayer.
Scott: on top of all that Aside from the fact that most of the multiplayer modes are utter shite Yeah, I mean the only two multiplayer modes that are worth playing more than a couple times are the angel mode Which is just round-robin survival and the bomb mode Which is.
Scott: you get to choose which form the next person is going to have to do.
Scott: so I can say aha Rym Let's see you do a mortar and pestle game and then Rym goes.
Scott: I did it.
Scott: Let's see you do A remote control game etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: And when someone loses, they're out.
Rym: Yeah, every multiplayer mode is Single elimination.
Rym: Yep, which really ruins a lot of the fun I mean the disco mode.
Scott: in the original the GameCube one was three times losing.
Scott: so that if you play multiplayer It's like you play you play you play someone loses.
Scott: It's over.
Scott: Well, the running one is not single elimination, but that one's crap.
Rym: Anyway, yeah The running one was really cool up until you end it and then it goes to the like the second half of the running game Which is 100% random mitigated slightly by your score from the previous one.
Rym: It's just nothing.
Scott: Yep, but it's pretty bad.
Rym: So the only two games were the crowd for the angel game in the bomb game.
Scott: The darts are pretty bad.
Scott: you play them once you figure it out.
Rym: I this is sad.
Rym: while monkey ball for the Wii is one of the worst games I've ever paid money for Mm-hmm, and while I'd throw it away if it weren't for the fact that I want to get some of my money back Yeah, the darts the one thing that monkey ball did.
Rym: Okay are better than the darts in Wario.
Scott: Yeah, the darts in Wario where it seems to be like you just aim it and then you shake the reed You just snap the remote, you know quickly and shortly and then the dart will go right where you aimed.
Scott: and that's it.
Rym: I'm gonna be slightly lower than where you aimed but to bring the expectations and my satisfaction level even lower Let's look at the two micro god multiplayer games that work.
Rym: the bomb game cool idea.
Rym: if you Pat you pick, you know It tells you who's up next and you pick what form you want them to have to use.
Rym: I already said this and buy up and every time a form is used it gets harder.
Rym: All right That's a really cool mechanic.
Scott: the game constantly gets faster.
Rym: No matter what you can only use that mechanic in the bomb game.
Rym: there's no option to use it in any other style of multiplayer.
Rym: and The only thing the bomb game does is whoever messes up a minigame they lose.
Rym: everyone else wins games over.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like let's say there's five people playing the bomb game one person loses.
Scott: Everyone else wins.
Scott: Shouldn't it be?
Scott: keep going until everyone blows up except one guy.
Rym: now They do that in the angel game.
Rym: The angel game is last man standing wins.
Rym: great But you can't do the cool.
Rym: pick the form thing from the bomb game.
Rym: It's just single elimination with no options.
Scott: Yep, it gets faster and faster every round, but you can't choose forms or it's just it randomly selects a game that you've played before.
Rym: Yeah So while the bomb game would be better You can never play it with someone who isn't as good as you or else it just ends right away and it's not fun.
Scott: And what's the other?
Scott: what's the fourth one the one on the right?
Scott: Well, there's the pump-it-up game that oh, yeah That one doesn't really make sense.
Scott: I mean in the original in the old Wario where there was a game where you would inflate a balloon and whoever was playing a micro game when the balloon exploded would lose.
Rym: and that's still the truth in this game and it was Simultaneous all the other three people could pump up the balloon while they were playing.
Scott: Yep So I'd be playing micro games while other three people are pushing a as fast as they can to pump up a balloon.
Scott: Now it's like you pump it up and then I start playing because you hand the wiimote to me.
Scott: It's like it doesn't?
Scott: it doesn't?
Scott: it doesn't work out because you can't really tell like, okay I just pumped it a whole bunch.
Scott: When does that count?
Scott: you have to calculate like when the pumping you want it to explode, you know You might pump it up a whole bunch and then when you get the wiimote It'll explode and it kind of sucks.
Scott: The other way where it's simultaneous, you know when you want to pump it whenever you can.
Scott: end of story.
Rym: It makes it's a lot more fun yeah, and basically it just comes down to.
Rym: I mean I would give Wario Ware touch for the DS a C+ just because it's a good game very well executed But the lack of multiplayer basically renders it almost worthless and it has almost no replay value once you've played it through.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's basically, you know, a lot of the things with the Wii.
Scott: It's like everything for the Wii is great.
Scott: everything that they have made is great But it's still Disappointing all the things they have not made.
Scott: the Wii is supposed to be a huge party system compared to the 360 and the PS.
Rym: Yeah, and yet there's no good party game.
Scott: Oh, there isn't a party game out and they're probably you know That raven grab as I've heard but whatever.
Rym: Well, I'll try just get that cuz I'm hurting here.
Scott: Yeah, and There's no party games and let's see What else.
Scott: the virtual console could be 10,000 times more awesome than it is But it isn't.
Scott: there could be a million awesome Wii channels, but there aren't.
Scott: it's like why are they going so slow?
Scott: they just open up the can and let people make you know, all sorts of crazy shit for the Wii and Everyone would be happy holding back and not You know taking advantage of the full potential of this amazing system.
Rym: I can tell you why it's going so slow one They're selling wheeze faster than they can make them anyway, and they're selling games in crazy quantities.
Rym: The Wii is making money hand over fist.
Scott: It's like they're not interested in doing better than they have to in order to sell stuff.
Rym: so I imagine the moment we sales start slackening or the moment the Release cycle of games start slowing down.
Rym: They'll start bit by bit incrementing the level of quality to keep people like us interested.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We'll see what they do.
Rym: I mean the DS is just now really starting to hit its stride.
Rym: when it first came out It was the same deal.
Rym: the DS had so much potential.
Scott: We're about to enter another DS.
Scott: Glut actually Yeah, but I think it's like the end of the world.
Rym: until the Pokemon games come out the first year the DS There was.
Rym: I mean it was a good system But there was so much it could have been doing that it just wasn't.
Scott: there's still a whole bunch of the DS could be doing That.
Rym: it isn't yeah, but bit by bit It's starting to figure itself out and I think the DS is gonna have a really really long life cycle.
Scott: Yeah, I definitely get a DS is gonna hang around for a while But you know it's like when we first got the DS.
Scott: We were seeing games like.
Scott: you know What's it called the Kirby's?
Scott: Canvas curse right you know.
Scott: and now the stylus is mostly being used for games like Phoenix Wright and Hotel dusk which is fine.
Rym: Those are the kind of games.
Scott: I want I like those games, but it's you know It's like all the you know potential of the DS.
Scott: It's Wi-Fi and it's stylus and all that stuff.
Scott: You know hotel dust could have been just doesn't even need the stylus.
Scott: You know it's like come on people They're very.
Scott: they're not taking.
Scott: the microphone on the DS doesn't get used for shit.
Scott: The what else?
Scott: on the DS the Wi-Fi is barely used.
Scott: I mean Tetris is the last game to make use of the Wi-Fi in any reasonable good way.
Scott: You know I don't know.
Scott: It's just sad that these things could be awesome.
Scott: They have been used in awesome ways But it doesn't really stick because no one keeps hammering it with the full potential.
Rym: I think the other problem is that a lot of the people in Nintendo They make a game and it sells really well.
Rym: I don't think they realize that if they'd made the game a little bit better.
Rym: It would sell so much more.
Scott: Also, or the people you know the other thing is that they made a game a little bit better.
Scott: It would not only sell so much more But the price would stay up for longer on the shelf because people would just keep playing the game.
Scott: for you know I mean WarioWare.
Scott: I don't see us playing this game of you know.
Scott: six to twelve months from now It's probably just gonna sit there not being played.
Rym: however what I do see us doing is playing WarioWare for the Gamecube forever.
Scott: Yep, exactly, and you know that's gonna sell You know copies of WarioWare for the Gamecube down the road, so I guess come on Nintendo.
Rym: Give us a dev kit.
Scott: Goddamn, yeah, I think that's the real problem.
Scott: that this shit goes down is because Nintendo is just so.
Scott: you know they promised hey We're gonna make it cheaper to make Wii games.
Scott: And it's true.
Scott: if you want to develop games of the Wii you don't need as much money as you would need To develop 360 games or ps3 games because the dev kit is cheap.
Scott: The thing is they don't give the dev kit to just anyone with enough money.
Scott: They check you out And they very restrictive and who they give it to and who they don't give it to for you know corporate secret Intellectual property reasons.
Scott: they don't want you telling.
Scott: well I think it's also the secret of the Wii dev kit.
Rym: Nintendo is very much.
Rym: I mean even way back back when they used to be sued for antitrust stuff all the time They were very much.
Rym: They wanted to make sure that the games that came out on their systems met their standards of quality.
Rym: And they were and I can understand that well.
Rym: They were so afraid of any non gamer Seeing a bad game and thinking poorly of their console as a result.
Scott: well it was mostly people like coming out with Tengen games and stuff because when you if you want to make a Gamecube game or a DS game or a Xbox game you have to pay Microsoft or Nintendo or Sony a license for you know your game.
Scott: That's why that Nintendo seal of quality is there.
Scott: That's why you know if you're 360 game if you want there you to have a game Published for the 360 in those little 360 DVD cases that works you have to pay Microsoft money.
Scott: And that's how they make most of their money.
Scott: when you sell a video game console You know you don't.
Scott: it's Microsoft doesn't make enough first-party games.
Scott: You know they what they make.
Scott: halo.
Scott: That's about it.
Scott: You know all these third parties pay Microsoft money.
Scott: So if you have people like Tengen just making games for the NES without paying fees to Nintendo.
Scott: That means that now Nintendo can't make money.
Rym: So except at least Nintendo also makes a huge profit on the Wii itself and on all the accessories.
Rym: Yeah, see Nintendo.
Rym: We said this last week to Nintendo.
Rym: they make a lot of great things and Despite the fact that we just spent a while bashing Nintendo They're far and away doing better than Sony and Microsoft in my book in terms of quality games and potential and yeah Everything.
Rym: but primarily they want your money, and they'll do anything to get it.
Scott: and currently They don't have to do all these things that we complain about.
Scott: they don't have to meet their full potential in order to get your Money, I mean, so why should they?
Scott: it's like a communist.
Scott: I don't have to work on the farm.
Scott: I get paid anyway.
Rym: Here's what I would have done if I was Nintendo.
Rym: I would release the current WarioWare as is because look we bought it.
Rym: every gamer bought it.
Rym: They made had money over it hand over fist.
Rym: all the people who don't want to buy Wario Where they're buying wheeze just to play Wii Sports.
Rym: They're making money off of them.
Rym: They'll release another Wario game Years from now.
Rym: yeah, and it'll have what we want because now we've been burned we won't buy another Wario.
Scott: That's a very optimistic outlook.
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: I don't know if I'm so optimistic.
Rym: It's such a cynical optimistic outlook though It's like Nintendo conspired to force me to buy a crap war.
Scott: yeah But I'm talking about the fact that you believe that they're eventually going to meet the full potential.
Scott: I'm 50/50.
Rym: I think the full potential.
Rym: I think they're gonna release a WarioWare in a year or two that will have Enough more multiplayer to trick us into giving another Wario game a chance.
Scott: Yeah, my I'm 50/50.
Scott: I think that they're probably just.
Scott: they're not gonna do any more than they have to to keep selling stuff.
Scott: You know all that.
Scott: They're not gonna.
Scott: You know if people keep buying virtual console games.
Scott: They're not gonna lower the price.
Scott: if They don't need to put out you know free demos of virtual console games to trick you into buying them Right out then they're not going to.
Scott: you know if they're not gonna put out original content on the virtual console.
Scott: if they don't have To they're not gonna put out more channels.
Scott: if they don't have to they're gonna do only what they have to Just to get money, and they're not gonna do anything.
Scott: There's a chance of not being profitable.
Scott: You know if they spend a bajillion dollars making a new we channel and only Thousand people get it there.
Scott: They're not gonna take a risk on that.
Scott: I think that's how it's gonna go.
Rym: Oh, well, yeah, I think we've ran it enough.
Scott: yes So Wario aware if you feel like micro games a lot if you like you know Warioware touched and Warioware Twisted and all that.
Scott: you'll like this Warioware.
Scott: You might like it more.
Rym: if you like the GameCube Warioware stay the hell away from.
Scott: yeah If you're looking for mostly multiplayer, and you don't really give a crap about single-player This is not worth the $50 that they're charging for.
Rym: it's worth Maybe 10 bucks.
Scott: yeah wait a long time for it to be used and get it for 10 bucks.
Rym: Oh, and as a quick little aside here you might remember that I gave kind of a preview about Castlevania portrait of ruin mm-hmm And I was.
Rym: I mean it wasn't the greatest game, but I definitely said it was worth getting.
Rym: yep I retract that this game could die in a goddamn fire.
Rym: whoa Good happen there.
Rym: I almost Upon reaching a certain point in the game discovering what I had to do in order to be allowed To play the rest of the game.
Rym: it was horseshit.
Rym: I almost just took the game out and said screw it not worth it not gonna play the rest.
Rym: Wow the only game I've done that for ever other than what I almost did with portrait of ruin was Princess Peach.
Rym: Nah, when yeah, you know go you didn't get all the toads better go back And I just took the game out and that was the end.
Scott: Yeah, I don't I never really do that with games.
Scott: I mean you just kind of yeah give up.
Rym: you have got to cast a spell that you can find in a secret area Of the game on a specific boss But the boss has to be in range and your partner has to cast it.
Rym: You can't control your partner while you're casting it and the spell takes like a minute to cast and if anything touches her Or she goes too far away from you or off the screen or you die.
Rym: It doesn't work.
Rym: Wow Scott Scott was actually in the room while I was trying to beat it and the conversation was basically me going fuck Fuck and I turned the DS off.
Scott: I'd reset it fuck reset fuck reset god damn it reset reset For like a half hour and of course, there's no way to know that you have to do this without looking at a fact online.
Rym: Yeah, well granted if you find the secret spell it's pretty obvious what to do.
Rym: Oh, okay, cuz the spell cures vampirism and then you fight a vampire.
Scott: So but is finding the secret spell arbitrary or is there like hints that say hey the secret spell over there?
Rym: No, there's no hint that there's a secret spell.
Rym: really there's an all the way hint where another guy contracts vampirism And she's like there's probably a spell that could undo this but no hint as to where it would be hidden.
Rym: Okay, and you have to turn into a frog and run into this little corridor and run oh and you'll find it like hidden in The corner, you know, I'm not gonna start another rant now, but arbitrary stuff in games pisses me.
Rym: It wasn't as arbitrary as the side quests in Crystal Chronicles, which we're just so not worth.
Scott: No, that was the most arbitrary thing ever.
Scott: Oh, no, the most arbitrary thing ever would be the stuff in ogre battle 64.
Scott: You never played that but I know anyway, no, that's why people learn something from the Zelda games.
Scott: in the Zelda games Nothing is arbitrary.
Scott: It's all right in your face.
Rym: Yeah, if you can't figure out a puzzle.
Rym: the answer is to step back and look cuz you're just not miss.
Rym: you're missing something.
Scott: Yep in in other games.
Scott: It's like yeah that perfectly normal looking wall.
Scott: There's no way you could have known but if you hit it with this item that you only have one of in the entire game It'll crumble and behind it There's another item that you can use somewhere else to get another secret which leads you to the secret ending.
Scott: It's like You didn't give me a hint.
Scott: You didn't put a crack in the wall.
Scott: You didn't have a character say, huh?
Scott: There's something funny about that wall.
Scott: If only I had an X to use on the wall.
Rym: at least at least if you get past that bullshit in Portrait of ruin it looks like the rest of the game is a really good game.
Rym: Uh-huh, okay So it's worth it.
Scott: Just is it worth the full price right now of what 30 35 dollars?
Rym: It could be it's it's not.
Scott: if you really like Castlevania.
Scott: You should definitely go.
Rym: Yeah, if you played Castlevania DS and you're just itching for more gotten by it There's no reason not to yeah, but if you didn't if you haven't played Castlevania DS yet, don't even look at this game.
Scott: Okay, are we done?
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: Okay This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.