Rym: It's Thursday January 4th.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We tell a geek fable of New Year's parties past and present.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So today I encountered what might be called an awkward social situation and being tired from the whole week as I am Instead of dealing with it pithily I dealt with it in a rather lame manner.
Rym: How awkward could it be when you're just walking around the city?
Rym: no no no no there was some trickery involved and In addition to that I mean doing this show.
Rym: and just from the stuff We did at RIT a lot of people tend to know us who.
Rym: we don't know them.
Rym: So we'll be out somewhere like at a con.
Rym: so we'll come up and say hey Rym and Scott Whoa it's great to see you or something like that and we'll be like look at each other with the who.
Rym: the hell is this?
Rym: RIT?
Rym: does he listen to the show?
Rym: did we meet him at a con?
Rym: did we?
Rym: did we play board games with them?
Rym: Who is this person?
Rym: Oh god?
Rym: Yeah, is it my brother's?
Rym: Is it a friend of a friend?
Rym: yep, is it just some stranger trying to con us?
Rym: We don't know and there's no way for us to know at this point We know there are too many people seek us out.
Rym: so as a result And especially enough.
Rym: I'm wide awake.
Rym: I tend to deal with it better and usually I just kind of manage, but if I'm tired Kind of secondary to the whole conversation I tend to go on autopilot in Social situations that I'm not particularly caring about or enamored with.
Rym: it really just be like hey Not saying who you are or anything.
Rym: well you heard yesterday when we were tired And I kept going things of the day, and I'm all loud and boisterous even though I'm just in tired to Scott I can go on autopilot socially for a long time before I finally pass out.
Rym: So I'm over lunch at work going to the supermarket to pick up some lip balm because my lips are a little bit chapped Bomb bomb bomb and I buy something on my way out.
Rym: this girl this somewhat attractive girl who?
Rym: Kinda in retrospect looks like a few people.
Rym: I've knew like back in high school Says like hey hey, and I'm about to walk out and just hey again.
Rym: So I turn around and those girls looking right at me, and she's like she says something like hey.
Rym: How are you doing?
Rym: And it's definitely the hey how you doing of?
Rym: I know you.
Rym: so I stand there.
Rym: for maybe she just thought you were someone else.
Rym: No, no, no, that's where it gets interesting, so I stand there, and I go oh hey, and she says what brings you here?
Rym: I'm holding my little chapstick my little mango butter organic chapstick not for any organic reasons but just cuz I like the taste of it and I'm like at this point my brain is going.
Rym: I know this person obviously or they know me must react in socially responsible Manner alpha B.
Rym: I just came to buy a chapstick.
Rym: So I say hey fancy seeing you here of course which I say a lot.
Rym: What if it was someone that actually just thought you were someone else?
Rym: and you said that?
Rym: well the thing is I had turned around I was close enough to where.
Rym: there is no way this person could have mistaken me for someone else.
Rym: now after I say this She stands there Unmoving looking at me with and her eyes changed.
Rym: They give me the look of oh shit I don't know how to deal with this situation.
Rym: This is not the social interaction.
Rym: I expected.
Rym: so now I'm standing there going Damn it now.
Scott: What and we're both standing there.
Rym: So who are you know before I can react remember?
Rym: I'm tired.
Rym: you know when I'm tired And I really don't expect like I'm in a place where I don't expect to run into anyone like I'm at a diner alone Somewhere in the Bronx the odds of me running into someone.
Rym: I know there are practically zero And especially the way she engaged me with this.
Rym: hey, how you doing was it?
Rym: Threw me off.
Rym: so then she snaps out of it, and she says well come on over.
Rym: So I'm like ah and I walk over there.
Rym: my mind's going all right all right serial killer.
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: stalker?
Rym: Maybe she's with someone that you know.
Rym: then you'll be like.
Rym: yeah, I'm totally.
Rym: I have no idea What's going on?
Rym: And I'm not awake enough to come up with some funny way to get out of this.
Rym: and then she raised me over to a Table and on this table is a bunch of charity bullshit.
Rym: And she starts trying to give me the rigmarole of buy this t-shirt to save homeless kids.
Rym: And then I realized that she was using the overly friendly demeanor to trick people into walking over in order to get them to Our guilt them into buying this charity.
Rym: BS.
Rym: Oh and the fact that I reacted in a normal social manner and The fact that I reacted in a way she didn't expect totally threw her off.
Rym: so then after she goes into her standard sales pitch I At this point don't care anymore, and I'm tired.
Rym: so instead of making up something funny.
Rym: You're being like sorry I gotta go kill a cat or something stupid.
Rym: I just kind of go.
Rym: Sorry I don't have any cash, which is the total cop-out answer, and she says don't worry about that.
Rym: We take Visa and MasterCard.
Rym: Yeah, and I just look at her for a second.
Rym: I shrug, and I just walk away.
Rym: Yeah, and I look back.
Rym: you didn't give her the finger.
Rym: I just walked away.
Rym: I gave.
Rym: I gave her the without saying.
Rym: so much.
Rym: I basically gave her the Gesture.
Rym: that means I know you caught me in my lie.
Rym: You caught me in my bluff.
Rym: I'm well aware of that, and I don't care because I'm not going to interact with you anyway.
Rym: So I walk out and as I look into the window kind of as I'm walking out She's still looking at me with his look at what the fuck was up with that guy And I just went back to my car and drove back to my office drank a couple of Red Bulls and went on with my day
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and now I spent five minutes and some 30 seconds telling everyone in the world about this.
Rym: So what do we got in the news Robin?
Rym: I'm Chewing some bubblegum actually a blow pop and it's all crunchy, so I'm holding the microphone away from my face.
Rym: You don't hear this now?
Rym: see I wasn't looking at Scott.
Rym: I was talking so I kept pausing waiting for Scott to come in and then finally I turn and look at him like you're gonna say something and he just gives me The look of I'm chewing on something and we sat here for several seconds in silence.
Rym: That's how these things go.
Rym: yeah, I'm gonna cut all that silence out, but suffice to say it was there.
Rym: So anyway in the news being Thursday I can talk about whatever I want and it seems like Brazil the country Brazil is trying to Put forth a lot more clout and influence over the internet than it has any warrant to do so to do.
Rym: See a while ago there was some sort of illegal pornography issue on or cut which is the Popular in Brazil social networking software that was nominally put out by Google.
Rym: There are also drug dealers.
Rym: using or cut.
Rym: or cut is basically a thing kind of like my not really myspace But
Rym: like a friendster
Rym: Friendster Facebook that Google that a guy at Google made and there was a hubbub about it, and then it died Except in Brazil where it was adapted heavily yeah
Rym: well in fact It's more that it was kind of.
Rym: it was half endorsed by Google And it was really kind of cool.
Rym: And then someone invited someone from the nation of Brazil and within a week Gorka was done.
Rym: It was just over.
Rym: there were more Brazilian people speaking other languages than they were.
Rym: I was almost I almost said Brazilian.
Rym: Then there were you know anyone else or any other nationality or any other language?
Rym: so uh now it's just a den of child pornography and drug dealers and just general mayhem.
Rym: and And Brazil said hey Google shut this shit down and give us the names of the people posting.
Rym: and Google said yeah, Brazil Sue us or cuts had problems lately.
Rym: I think I heard it was down for a while and it came back.
Rym: it had problems when it was new.
Rym: it never really worked.
Rym: I know it's having big problems lately.
Rym: I think it might be finally dead dead instead of just dead.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: So it is.
Rym: that would be a good thing if it died.
Rym: died so more recently the ex-wife of Ronaldo who is very famous in the game of football or for you Americans soccer.
Rym: There was a video of his ex-wife having sex.
Rym: This video was posted on YouTube.
Scott: doesn't YouTube not allow sexy videos?
Rym: YouTube the thing is even if it gets taken down I mean anytime a video is popular for every one that gets taken down like 10 more get posted.
Rym: and honestly, I think that part of YouTube strategy is that they purposefully allow such things to happen so that they can say that they Put forth the good-faith effort of removing the offending copyright, whatever.
Rym: yet at the same time They know that the users are gonna keep posting them sometimes.
Rym: They'll change the spelling.
Rym: Sometimes they'll post it in like 10 parts So it's not easy to find and they'll just keep posting it and the stuff is always there and nothing.
Rym: YouTube does keep the stuff From being there.
Scott: Well, the reason people post it in 10 parts is because YouTube only allows like 10 minutes of video every in one shot.
Scott: So you have to break up your TV shows in the two or three parts.
Rym: No, but I've seen things broken up into more parts than that.
Rym: I have yeah, yeah, especially things that are very likely to be taken down Mmm, but things that are long.
Rym: I definitely think there is some implicit cooperation between Google or God between YouTube and all these people posting illegal stuff.
Scott: Well, Google does own YouTube now.
Rym: Yeah, so that's why I got confused.
Rym: But this is specifically YouTube.
Rym: Google's not mentioned anywhere in here until at the end of our or cut.
Rym: Funny how it's always Google who gets involved in this stuff with Brazil.
Rym: But anyway Brazil and Ronaldo and his ex-wife have sued and ordered whatever and it came down to Brazil ordering YouTube to shut down Until they resolved the issue.
Scott: Ah Now YouTube in Brazil physically.
Scott: no then tough shit Google slash.
Rym: YouTube's response was basically a giant middle finger.
Rym: That's what I would expect and I don't know where Brazil gets off.
Rym: I mean If we tried to shut down some Brazilian website You can bet that the Brazilians would be pissed at us and the government would make a sting about how.
Rym: yeah We're defying those evil Americans trying to mess with our internet and yet they're trying to get us to Right.
Rym: Imagine if the Ford Motor Company right did something to upset the country of Paraguay.
Scott: Paraguay, right?
Rym: Well Paraguay might be upset and Paraguay can say we are no longer Allowing the import of Ford Motor vehicles into our country until you do X Y & Z and that's perfectly fine.
Rym: They can do that and No one would have a problem with that except the people in Paraguay who wanted Ford's.
Rym: They couldn't tell Ford Motor Company.
Rym: You have to shut down Like laughs.
Rym: they very much can and Ford would say we'll get right on that.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: So why is it?
Rym: because when we're doing Internet's Like, you know countries all of a sudden think they can do this sort of silliness.
Rym: What do they not understand?
Rym: Well, the funniness here is that one quote from this article.
Rym: the court honored the request on Wednesday But the Brazilian court.
Rym: but legal experts say the ruling by the Brazilian court Could be difficult to enforce in the United States where YouTube is based.
Rym: if Brazil wants to keep YouTube out of Brazil They can tell all the you can make all the ISPs in Brazil block it.
Rym: now even worse the people involved here are suing YouTube for $116,000 per day and damages for each day that the video remains up.
Rym: and the video has been up for a while and I don't think anything will come of that.
Rym: but one what damages?
Rym: you can't prove damages in a US court for having a video like That on YouTube.
Rym: I mean I guess you could if you were a professional porn star and now your Your marketability has been degraded from having it given away for free or something.
Rym: But especially in this case where neither of these people are terrible celebrities.
Rym: I mean, it's not her having sex with Ronaldo it's someone else.
Rym: I mean that he is famous in other parts of the world.
Rym: Just not here.
Rym: here You know what?
Rym: She's not $16,000 famous no let alone per day not even close.
Rym: It's not here.
Rym: See the thing is she's hot.
Rym: I guess I.
Rym: Part of the reason I generally don't like the idea of a world government Is that I don't want to lose the ability that we have now to do things that should not be illegal in a country But are in countries where they're not illegal.
Rym: a lot of the good things on the internet Only exist because they exist in countries that don't have the shit laws that exist in some other places in the world.
Rym: Yeah, that is one problem with the world government.
Rym: is you know So one part of the world to be pissed off about something?
Rym: and now you can either.
Rym: You know, it'd be difficult to outlaw something in one part of the world, but not the other part of the world.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the way and you'll have one guy who's pissed off and like, you know the middle of nowhere in Mongolia making a law that affects everyone else in the world just because one guy's pissed.
Rym: and don't think this is just like a one-way Street with the US.
Rym: there is stuff that has to be hosted outside the US and there is stuff that has to be hosted in The US.
Rym: that is right.
Rym: It goes both ways.
Rym: So as long as different parts of the world people like different things and people will be able to get whatever they want.
Rym: if We make everything homogeneous then there'll be this set of stuff.
Rym: You can get the set of stuff you can't and that'll be the end of it, right?
Rym: So anyway, you got some news for me.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you know the Creative Commons.
Rym: Creative Commons is it?
Rym: You know, it might seem like all they do is give out Creative Commons licenses.
Rym: Well, they do more than that.
Rym: they're actually, you know, the Creative Commons Foundation or whatever they call themselves.
Rym: and Well, they've just released a new tool the termination of transfer beta tool its beta.
Rym: basically, there is a copyright law that says if you sign away your copyright to someone else that It is possible after a certain amount of time for you to terminate the transfer and take your rights back.
Rym: For example, they give some hypothetical examples.
Rym: I'll just read one of them.
Rym: You're an author who wrote a book in 65.
Rym: You wrote it on your own time and dime not as a part of your employment or at anyone else's suggestion Commissioning or order.
Rym: in 1980 you got a publication deal.
Rym: So you signed exclusive publishing agreement with big book corporation Which gave them the right to publish and distribute your book for the term of copyright, which is your life plus 70 years.
Rym: They published it in the same year in 1980 and now it's the year 2007. the book sold well But your royalty check is pretty small.
Rym: You want a better deal and want to see if you might be able to terminate the publishing deal?
Rym: Well, there is a law that just allows you to do that.
Rym: You can just terminate and get your rights back.
Rym: let's say you were a musician and you signed away your music to a record company and Then that was a long time ago and like the 50s and 60s and now you want your music back.
Rym: You can get it back now.
Rym: Obviously, it's not trivial or terribly easy because there are a lot of people who aren't able to get their music back.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: apparently according to the Creative Commons This law exists and you can just get your music back or get your rights back after a certain amount of time and under certain conditions.
Rym: however, the bureaucracy and stuff necessary to actually do it is Incredibly expensive and time-consuming and difficult and you need lawyers and money.
Rym: So while the law is basically clear that you can just get it back The actual process of doing it is next to impossible.
Rym: hence this new tool which allows you to just get your shit back if you're allowed to have your shit back according to the law and It's currently a beta tool and it's not a hundred percent yet But as soon as it's done You'll be able to get your rights back if you are legally allowed to do so.
Rym: This is going to be the awesome I am all about this.
Rym: I mean think about how many people artists out there You know made awesome stuff while they were working for some company.
Rym: or you know, think about how many I don't know like musicians Signed their music away.
Rym: It is like record companies a bajillion years ago.
Rym: Now imagine if they can take it back and you know.
Rym: Give the finger to these giant companies that just hold the rights to a million things You'll have like these big TV stations forced to go into their vaults and grab old videos and films out of there.
Rym: You'll have like.
Rym: it'll be crazy.
Rym: There's definitely.
Rym: This will definitely help because despite the fact that copyright lasts so long There'll be a lot of people who are just get their stuff and dish it out.
Rym: You know because it isn't being held by some greedy ass who's gonna hide it away forever.
Rym: So if you have any copyrights that you know, you've made some artwork like 35 40 years ago and You don't own it.
Rym: How many of our listeners are over the age of 35 or 40 and how many of the people who are over the age of 35?
Rym: Made something when they were two years old.
Rym: That's how that they signed away to someone else.
Rym: Ah Yeah, the only thing I've signed away is stuff I've done for jobs.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, they got a few hypothetical situations.
Rym: I'm not sure exactly what the law is about what you can get back and what you can't under what conditions but You can definitely get stuff back after a long enough period of time.
Rym: You know even if your contract specified a long without knowing those conditions, which I imagine our owner is I don't know how big a deal this will actually be.
Rym: Well, I think that's what the tool is for.
Rym: with a tool you enter in like You know what you did and then they'll tell you if and when you can get it back and how and they'll do it.
Rym: Why don't we make some stuff up and use the tool and see what we can come up with?
Rym: Because we'd have to also prove that we were the people who you know signed away the rights.
Rym: No, we just use the tool and try and then they'll say hey I'm pretty sure.
Rym: if we just if I read more of the words on this page It would just say what the provisions are.
Rym: Why don't you get on there?
Rym: We'll wait.
Scott: cuz I'm lazy.
Rym: things of the day.
Rym: So tonight my thing of the day.
Rym: actually Scott found this just before the New Year's party and we all know I found it like a week or two ago.
Scott: I just didn't actually show it to anybody.
Rym: great Well, eventually he showed it to a bunch of people at the New Year's party and I finally just watched it And I got to say this is pretty hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, it's been a while since I've discovered a new stand-up comic who was funny.
Rym: Yeah I listen to pretty much the same stand-up comics.
Rym: I listened to five years ago.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty sad.
Scott: I mean, there's definitely new people out there in the stand-up comedy realm and it is a entertainment medium.
Scott: I enjoy greatly.
Rym: Well, we have now discovered Russell Peters who very much does the.
Rym: you know.
Rym: what man do this black man?
Rym: do that comedy except He's Indian and his twist is white boy.
Rym: Do this black boy?
Rym: do this Indian boy.
Rym: do this.
Rym: He also does.
Rym: a lot
Scott: of Chinese
Rym: people do this,
Scott: but
Rym: it's that style of humor.
Rym: But give him a chance.
Rym: It's pretty funny.
Rym: And if nothing else I suggest you watch the final bit We've linked to here part five.
Scott: Yeah, part five is definitely the funniest part.
Rym: That's his grand finale joke, if you will Yeah, suffice to say it involves probably our new catchphrase Somebody's gonna get hurt real bad somebody.
Scott: Think you might know him.
Rym: You might know him very well.
Rym: Yeah, I don't want to ruin it.
Rym: And I'll say now that knowing the punchline to the joke does not ruin the joke at all.
Rym: In fact, if anything it heightens the joke because he starts telling the joke and if you know the punchline You know exactly where he's going with it and you'll be laughing all the same.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: Definitely good stuff.
Rym: And it's definitely you know that.
Rym: oh, it's so true Back in high school.
Rym: I had several Indian friends because there's a lot of Indian people where my high school was and Suffice to say their parents were all very much like the head.
Rym: I definitely also have to say this guy the what you can tell.
Rym: he's a talented comedian because like, you know his He doesn't just sit there and tell the jokes He like his facial expressions and his like body language is definitely like dead on.
Rym: like like Eddie Izzard and this guy.
Rym: It's kind of a. hearing them is funny, but seeing them is twice as funny.
Rym: Yeah, cuz like like it does.
Rym: like he does like a smile a frown, you know, he just hits it dead on.
Rym: It's all good.
Rym: He does the face of an angry Indian dad.
Rym: It's that's exactly what Donald's dad looked like.
Rym: every time It's the raised.
Rym: just the way they stand there and they back up a bit like they're rearing back and they're just waiting and they're Gonna say something and then they're gonna hit you somebody gonna get alright.
Rym: So it's been a while since I had Legos for my thing of the day.
Rym: it has And so I found this is perhaps one of the greatest Lego things I've ever seen, you know Lego this Everyone knows that Lego is but Lego mind store.
Rym: Well, you mean Lego bricks.
Rym: Yeah, you can't call them Legos, right?
Rym: yeah, Lego mind storms is a set of Legos that involves programmable motors and You know, it's sort of a branch off of like the technic Legos which are like the mechanical gears and such You know.
Rym: and it adds in electrical power and computer programming and a bunch of sensors like, you know Infrared sensors to those gears, you know, like Legos with yeah, you know robots in him.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, you can make Lego robots.
Rym: They they used to.
Rym: I started off with this great r2d2 set that you know make an r2d2.
Rym: it was cool stuff.
Rym: So some guy took this and he said, huh?
Rym: Let's see what I can make.
Rym: and people have made a lot of interesting things Lego mind storms over the years and many different Languages and all sorts of goodies.
Rym: this guy made Get this ready.
Rym: Get ready.
Rym: Ready?
Rym: I'm ready.
Rym: He made a Lego factory.
Rym: Now out of Legos.
Rym: when Scott says Lego factory, I don't think you quite understand the scale of what this man is created.
Rym: basically, he loads up one end of the thing with Legos and these trays and these robots made of Lego.
Rym: grab these Legos and move them around and Eventually put them together to create a Lego car.
Rym: now He even gets to pick the front end back end different colors.
Rym: Yeah, the way the machine works is there's a bunch of levers and each lever is for a different color.
Rym: So the first button you push is the front bit of the car and the second button you push is the second piece of the Car.
Rym: there's four bits of the car that you can change which color you want and all the different color pieces are loaded into The machine.
Rym: so you push color one you wait for it to the light to turn on.
Rym: you push color to color three color four And then it puts together the car that you ordered.
Rym: It is quite sweet.
Rym: It takes a while to watch the video like a good six minutes.
Rym: It's not the most efficient machine and it can only make one car at a time.
Rym: But hot damn this thing can make a Lego car.
Rym: It's made of Legos.
Rym: It's like a robots making robots, you know when robots make robots That's generally not going to end.
Rym: Well if they know what they're doing.
Rym: Yeah, the same, you know, well know what happened when people made people.
Rym: it wasn't good.
Rym: So anyway, we decided in spirit of the new year We're not gonna do what every other goddamn podcast did and do some sort of retrospective about 2006.
Scott: Yeah, we're not gonna tell you the best of or the worst of or whatever.
Rym: Well, it's real easy.
Rym: best podcast GeekNights.
Rym: best people front row crew.
Rym: Best operating system Linux awesome, that's it.
Rym: Best.
Rym: best person.
Rym: I don't know Richard Dawkins.
Scott: best video games Nintendo.
Rym: Yeah best video game There's like eight of them.
Scott: best manga still.
Rym: Osamu Tezuka by far Ka.
Scott: worst comics Marvel and DC still okay.
Rym: and a certain webcomics that we could call out for hilarity.
Scott: No, how.
Scott: best webcomics still.
Scott: penny arcade?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I don't know the order of the stick and bow is this are right there They are.
Scott: don't forget freakin.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: McNinja and Wondermark and Parryvival Fellowship.
Rym: and yeah, you know every webcomic we read.
Rym: best webcomics the ones we read for the most part.
Rym: There are some I read that are not that good.
Scott: I read it.
Scott: I read like two crappy ones.
Rym: Yeah, but everyone has their secret secret secret dark.
Scott: That's a new word.
Scott: I think what is secret mean?
Rym: Decret means a secret that you're ashamed of.
Rym: Ooh, I like that a lot.
Rym: dark secret combined into Decret That's that's very Japanese.
Scott: it is the way they say like lolicon instead of you know What pedophilia?
Scott: well, we know lolicon is Rym's Decret.
Rym: Okay, well we've all we've got our katsu.
Rym: It's not a Decret.
Rym: It's not even a secret.
Scott: with best place to buy computers.
Scott: still new egg Yeah, all right.
Rym: back in the day used to be what TC computers.
Scott: No, it doesn't even count.
Rym: or egghead calm.
Rym: Yeah, all right anyway, so we decided instead we would tell a geek fable something we haven't done in a while.
Rym: Oh gasps, you see this.
Scott: Oh that sucks for all you people looking for zombies.
Scott: part two, you know better luck next time.
Rym: I was all set to do zombies.
Rym: I can do zombies any day any time, but Scott Scott really doesn't want it.
Rym: He's really keeping us back here.
Scott: No, I just want to keep all the zombie people in suspense.
Rym: You know, it's not hard to keep zombie people in suspense.
Scott: That's the point.
Scott: It doesn't take much effort and it's fun.
Rym: cuz I mean it is not if you run around the corner away from zombies and the Zombies are coming.
Rym: You've got like five minutes before they get around that corner.
Scott: And those are a suspenseful fucking five minutes All right.
Rym: So what we I mean this year?
Rym: you might have noticed that we took a bunch of days off for the show Because we threw as we have for the last two years now a crazy party in our house.
Scott: I think we threw one three years ago, but it wasn't in this house.
Rym: Yeah, and before that I really remember I was thinking I wasn't drunk either.
Rym: well I was going because I've never been drunk at work.
Rym: today all the New Year's is we've had and I've got pretty much the Chronology of all of them.
Rym: that matter you see our first New Year's gatherings.
Rym: We're not the most well thought-out or awesome things.
Rym: In fact many of them sucked balls Quite and over the years we learned what was wrong with our gatherings and we refined them.
Rym: We refined them and finally now that we live here in the giant geek house We were able to have perhaps the penultimate awesome party because the ultimate party would require us renting out an anime convention over New Year's.
Scott: Mmm, that'd be good stuff.
Rym: Yeah, you know, there isn't a New Year's anime con is there?
Scott: I don't think people would go.
Rym: I have this feeling, you know I think that could be a small to lower mid-level con if marketed properly.
Rym: Maybe you'd have to market it to the same kind of people who go to katsu-kan like the slightly older.
Rym: I think you just have to you would.
Scott: you couldn't call it a con.
Scott: you have to be like we're gonna have the ultimate geek New Year's party.
Scott: come to the geek New Year, huh?
Rym: That bears further consideration.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: So we thought we just kind of go through the various New Year's is we've had and the pros and cons of all of them Because many of them ended in hilarity.
Scott: Well in the early college days.
Scott: I spent New Year's going home, you know.
Rym: Yeah our freshman year We all went home partly because we lived in the dorms and RIT does this wonderful thing where they close the dorms and turn Off the heat.
Rym: great.
Rym: So if you try to stick around campus over over the holiday, you know Christmas Kwanzaa New Year's break You'll just freeze to death if you don't get locked out.
Scott: They change the locks and everything You might get locked in which is even worse.
Rym: It wouldn't be so bad.
Rym: But like here's Greenwood.
Rym: I'll tell you froze to death.
Scott: Yeah, not not so good.
Scott: If you watch that part of here is Greenwood.
Rym: Yeah, so we uh well, I know I went back home to Michigan and had a Somewhat lame New Year's party with a bunch of people.
Scott: I knew in high school I had an average New Year's that year mostly like the New Year's kick came before.
Rym: so the next year we decided You know We'd made some friends and we had some friends that we really respected and they said that they were gonna have some sort of New Year's party.
Scott: was that the next year?
Scott: I think that was two years later.
Rym: I think that was the next.
Scott: I don't really remember All right.
Rym: Well the nice relevant party.
Rym: Yes, and this is the one we'll start talking about some of our friends said yeah We'll have a New Year's party at our apartment because we have the best apartment for that.
Rym: and we all said, you know What cool will show up?
Rym: So, you know, we don't even really think about it.
Rym: we assume they're throwing a party.
Rym: we'll just show up at it.
Rym: It'll be great.
Rym: These people are really cool.
Rym: There's no way they could throw a lame party.
Rym: So we get there, you know that day and no one's there Oh turns out they're out of town.
Rym: They're gonna be back that evening the evening of New Year's Eve.
Rym: So we wait and there's like one person.
Rym: the apartment was kind of sitting around.
Rym: We brought some food some snacks and some champagne which I'll say now didn't get opened at all.
Rym: Nope, nothing.
Rym: So we're waiting.
Rym: we're waiting and a couple more people show up But the people hosting the party have not showed up yet and there's not too many people there.
Scott: I mean people are showing up but there's basically an equal number of people who live there and An equal number of people who are there for a party.
Scott: There were like eight people not even less than that.
Scott: Well by the end there were eight people and we were sitting around like watching TV or something else lame.
Rym: Yeah, we started playing a couple of GameCube games.
Scott: Yeah, it was pretty ass.
Rym: So eventually at like 1150 they come in the door Mmm, and we're all sitting there and we're looking at him and they don't even be like, hey, sorry, we're late.
Rym: Hey happy new year.
Rym: They're like, oh Hey, and we sit there and we're like Hey.
Rym: And then the blue man group comes on the TV to do a little performance and we all stood around silently watching the blue man group count down the new year and Then we stood around for another 10 minutes.
Rym: We went home We went to bed and that was that.
Rym: that was perhaps the lamest Evening of my entire life.
Scott: That wasn't the lamest.
Scott: I mean my lamest was like eating Chinese food alone on Christmas in Rochester.
Scott: I Was lame.
Rym: I feel bad now.
Scott: Okay, so anyway What's the moral of this new year?
Scott: seeing as this is a geek fable?
Rym: Well Part of the moral I think would be if someone else is throwing an event and you have no control over it Do an accurate assessment of their ability to project awesome and plan accordingly.
Scott: Yeah, ask them like, you know, what's gonna be going down?
Rym: Well, I guess it depends on how much you trust them.
Rym: I mean if you just trust someone you just show up at their house.
Rym: Do you know something's gonna happen?
Rym: But if you don't trust him ask or more importantly don't go to parties that give all the signs of not being awesome Mmm, because the odds are they won't be like if you're expecting a party and you show up at the house And you don't see partying.
Scott: Like don't stick around.
Rym: Yes See this was before the Otakon and all that where we realized that if people suck you have to drop them like Bags of dirt.
Scott: That's I don't know but like a hot potato.
Rym: Hot potatoes are great.
Rym: You don't drop that you eat that shit.
Scott: You don't hold on to it though You got to put it on a plate and wait.
Rym: No you toss it from hand to hand periodically taking a bite.
Rym: You know, you do you drop.
Rym: burn your mouth that way.
Rym: you drop it like dog poop that somehow ended up in your hands.
Rym: Okay, you drop wipe and run.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, so we the what we should have done.
Rym: Here's how this party would have done.
Scott: poop on your hands is actually better than on your shoe or your clothes because you can get It off pretty easily.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I have to agree because I've spent many a day picking dog poop out of the bottom of my shoe with a stick.
Scott: I've also spent many a day doing the same.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: There's always still something.
Scott: there's always still something there.
Scott: You got to use a hose and a better steak.
Rym: All right, okay.
Rym: So here's how this would have gone down.
Rym: now being older and wiser one We probably wouldn't have even gone.
Rym: we would have thrown a competing party, but say we were lame.
Rym: Whatever we ended up going we show up and there's no one there.
Rym: We'd probably wait an hour.
Rym: No power maybe because we show up early in the day.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: No one shows up in an hour.
Rym: We try to get a hold of the people throw in the party If the answer they give is not awesome enough or if we don't get a hold of them We gather everyone who's at the party we say screw this We're going to blah and having our own party.
Rym: who's with?
Scott: or we go to find another party.
Scott: I mean if you're at a college or something, it's not hard to find a party.
Scott: No, not you find someone, you know.
Scott: Maybe you can find someone that you.
Scott: maybe they're not your friend like directly But they're a friend of a friend or you know them from a class.
Scott: You worked on a project with them or just and they were cool
Rym: nothing else wander around campus
Scott: Yep, you'll find some people holding red cups going
Rym: woo Yeah, and I mean if nothing nothing else just go home with all the people who were also Burned by this crap party and have a party.
Rym: Yep Alright, so after that moment the next day We're those of us who went to this and got burned by it or sitting around and they had kind of a like mini After-party the next day, but it was over.
Rym: they had already failed in terms of New Year's.
Rym: Yep So we decided alright that will never happen again next year.
Scott: Let's freakin do something.
Rym: So we planned and by we planned and planned we decided eventually that what we were gonna do is we were gonna get everyone who?
Rym: Wanted to be cool together.
Rym: We were gonna carpool to Niagara Falls because Niagara Falls is a rockin town and there's no way we wouldn't have a good time in Niagara Falls Mm-hmm.
Rym: So we gathered up a good number of people.
Rym: actually we went in a bunch of two cars Two cars that were crammed stock full of people.
Rym: Yep, and we went up to Niagara Falls.
Rym: We parked at the casino and we wander off into the street looking for a place to get Canadian dollars.
Scott: Now if only we were 21 that casino would have been good stuff Scott.
Rym: We could have gambled.
Rym: It's Canada.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: Yeah, why didn't we?
Rym: because no we'll get to that.
Scott: Okay The same reason we didn't seem to remembering like we couldn't get or didn't gamble for some reason and I like that would have been Okay, if we did no, no, in fact some of all I remember.
Scott: why.
Scott: okay keep going I'll say it when it comes.
Rym: All right All right, so we don't go to the casino cuz I've been to the casino before.
Rym: it is not my favorite casino by any stretch.
Rym: It's not a great casino and it's full of smoke.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So we got into the street.
Rym: We wander around a while.
Rym: eventually We go to get Canadian money and I get like a hundred bucks worth of Canadian dollars because I figured that'll do me and I Can use my credit card for anything else like drinks at a bar.
Scott: I also got a fistful of Canadian dollars now up.
Rym: a couple of our friends didn't even bother Getting Canadian money or if they did got it in very small quantities They must.
Scott: they were either poor college students or cheap.
Scott: I think both.
Rym: we didn't even think about this at the time.
Rym: Remember I was poor but I had at least some money at this time.
Rym: Yep So we're going around and then we decide alright, let's go get some dinner.
Rym: We go to a really awesome restaurant.
Scott: It was all fancy.
Scott: It wasn't crowded, but the food was awesome.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The dessert was awesomer.
Rym: In fact, that was the first time any of us had encountered a chimney, which is the awesome Which is basically everything in the world on top of a banana.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's a fried cheesecake banana ice cream Syrup caramel.
Rym: Oh my with the cherry.
Scott: It's hot and cold and Cheese cake.
Rym: it was in fact I remember when we were there and there's a lot of us sitting around this table and the waitress is like you want any dessert We're all like no, we're good.
Rym: And she says have you ever had a chimney?
Rym: we're like what.
Rym: and she explains what a chimney is and By the end of her feel every single person at the table wanted one.
Rym: Yep, which was a mistake.
Rym: We probably got in half as many.
Rym: those things were gigantic.
Scott: They're awesome.
Rym: So the bill turned out to be like over 200 bucks Canadian soaking like five bucks back then.
Rym: But it was a decent amount of money and Scott and I didn't think much of it.
Rym: I mean, we weren't rich we weren't terribly poor, but we weren't that.
Rym: well, I mean it was enough.
Rym: Yeah, we had enough money to have more fun.
Scott: I expected to pay that much.
Rym: So it turned out that many of the other people with us spent their last couple of dollars on this meal.
Rym: But we'll get to why that fucked us.
Rym: So then we wander on Niagara Falls, you know, we look at the frozen Falls and all the lights.
Rym: There's this nice Christmas thing and we're wandering around just having a good time in the street talking to people looking at things Going to cheesy cheesy tourist stuff that's free and looking at it and poking it and walking around.
Rym: We still got plenty of time before the new year.
Rym: It's not even dark out yet and Then it starts to get dark and a few of the people start complaining that it's cold.
Scott: It was kind of cold.
Scott: However, I Inside action, it's mostly walk around the street.
Scott: outside action.
Scott: Yeah, so plus there's a lot of running water there on there.
Scott: Yes, and it makes it a little colder.
Rym: plus this wind started picking up.
Rym: Yeah, so a few people in the group are complaining that it's cold.
Rym: Why aren't we inside somewhere?
Rym: Why are we outside?
Rym: and our response was we came to Niagara Falls?
Rym: Probably if nothing else to look at Niagara Falls, which is outside.
Rym: Got a plan accordingly.
Scott: Yeah, why aren't you wearing warmer clothing?
Rym: So whatever we're hanging out and eventually half the party decides You know what?
Rym: Fuck this and they abandon us Crammed more people into the second car than could possibly have fit comfortably and drove home.
Scott: Well, that was good for us because we drove home is gonna be nice and cozy.
Rym: So the few of us who remained decided All right Now that now that the poor people are gone and now that the complaining people are gone We're gonna have an awesome time.
Rym: now at this point I'll note that we weren't them.
Rym: We weren't that wise yet to the ways of the world.
Rym: and we're walking around and we see a balcony and there are rather Attractive women hanging out with rather attractive men up on this balcony holding drinks and wearing party hats And they look down to us and they wave and they're like, hey, come
Scott: on up Whoa,
Rym: and they look like they're having a great time and they're all rather attractive.
Scott: And I wasn't just getting.
Scott: you know There are a lot of places around where there were just people Drinking and screaming and I wasn't really into the drinking and screaming but it looked like this place had a dance party and I was Like
Rym: oh, yeah, so I mean we heard good techno coming out of there
Scott: and everything.
Rym: Yep So we go in we figure out, you know, this back alley we figure out the way to get into this place.
Rym: There's a bouncer standing there a little line.
Scott: I think it was actually a hard rock cafe.
Rym: No, it was next to the hard rock cafe.
Scott: Okay, the hard rock cafe.
Rym: We walked by and they wanted like 30 bucks to get in.
Rym: so we gave him the finger.
Rym: Okay, so we get to this place and the bouncer is there.
Rym: so we all get in line and halfway through the line Some of the people in the party say something to the effect of is there a cover the drift pay to get it here?
Rym: And we're like probably and it comes down to wait a minute.
Rym: We don't have any money.
Rym: We can't go in.
Scott: Yeah, me and River standing there with money like wanting to pay to go in like we're going in.
Scott: People with us are like we can't pay.
Scott: to go in if you go in would be stuck out here.
Rym: Now it's pretty much like two people who couldn't go in.
Rym: so it's not like.
Rym: it was just us who had money Yeah, but we couldn't abandon the people who didn't have money.
Rym: I mean that would have been assholish.
Scott: It would have been as I see.
Scott: but the thing is back in those days We had not let your yet learn the plan of you know, drop people off by the side.
Rym: Well also because it was our planned event.
Rym: We had no right to leave people behind.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I mean if we say we're going to show people a good time and We fail to take into account every factor.
Rym: We'll deal with that.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, which might?
Scott: it's only because we said things already.
Scott: Yeah, if we hadn't said things if it was just we're going to Niagara Falls who wants to come?
Scott: then we could have totally dropped Him.
Rym: yeah, but we definitely convinced a lot of people to come.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So what we ended up doing after you know wandering around the sides for a while is Go into this outdoor bar with no cover and had these big heat lamps and we stood around him Having a couple of beers or a couple of non-alcoholic beverages talking and it was generally a good time.
Rym: And then we all stood up yelled Happy New Year stood around for another 10 minutes and went home.
Rym: Of course the on the way home we had some trouble.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you see there's no moral here.
Rym: Scott was driving and the rest of us were intoxicated.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We pull up to the border and Scott I'll be the border guard and you beat you.
Scott: All right.
Rym: so, uh, when did you get into Canada?
Rym: earlier today and How long were you there?
Scott: until just now?
Rym: and the guy stands there for a second and he gives us this look of Somebody's gonna get hurt.
Scott: But I answered those questions.
Scott: Like I thought those are perfectly valid answers.
Scott: I wasn't trying to be wise or anything.
Scott: It wasn't until like a minute after saying what I said that I realized uh, did that sound like kind of like snarky?
Scott: Cuz I just died.
Scott: Those are my honest answers.
Scott: I was like I got here earlier today.
Scott: I'm leaving now.
Scott: Hey That's what what he want to know.
Scott: How many hours?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: six eight.
Rym: So we grilled us for a while.
Rym: Why are we there?
Rym: and you know, we gave normal answers.
Scott: But you know everyone in the car puts their IDs up and then you get them all back and you go home.
Scott: You go home.
Rym: Yeah Now also before that the one good like really good thing that happened was and I can't believe we didn't mention this but before everyone Gave up on it.
Rym: We went into this bar slash arcade where there was a DDR machine.
Rym: Oh, he played some drunken DDA played a bunch of drunken DDR.
Rym: It was great fun.
Scott: I wasn't drunken so I displayed regular DDR.
Rym: Yeah, I played drunken DDR and I did.
Scott: I mean I think it was a fifth mix machine.
Rym: It was and this was before we were that like we weren't super super good at D.
Scott: Yeah, this is a fifth mixes news.
Scott: It was hot and I was playing like basic.
Rym: Yeah, I played like one or two trick songs.
Rym: I was happy with myself.
Rym: Yep, so the more.
Rym: now there's two morals here.
Rym: The first moral is if you're gonna do something like that You got a plan ahead and you've got a plan ahead for all the people coming with you because Anyone on a trip who fucks up you can't just leave them behind in Canada.
Rym: Nope So you've got to deal with them.
Rym: you make sure that everyone with you on a trip where any one person can screw you is ready to deal with the consequences of being screwed or Is not going to screw you.
Scott: it's like this if you go to amusement park And you bring three people in your car and not everyone can afford to get into the amusement park you have a problem.
Rym: Yes Now if one of those people say said they had enough money and it turned out they didn't and then they decided they didn't want To go into the amusement park.
Rym: Anyway, knowing full well that you would leave them behind Well, you leave them in the parking lot all day to die in the heat.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm just saying you know, if if you say hey, let's all go here and it's not you know In advance like, you know big monies and you're not willing to pay for people and there's hidden expect Oh semi hidden expenses, then that's a problem.
Rym: moral number two, and we didn't realize this until later.
Scott: Oh, like I guess it also counts like if you go somewhere and then like Anyone over a certain only people like six feet tall and taller allowed in and you bring some five feet people with you And you didn't know that rule existed.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: it would be kind of bad to go inside.
Rym: Yeah So the moral number two and we figured that we didn't really worry about it we didn't think about it We didn't get into that party.
Rym: But in retrospect being older and wiser we realized that that party was most likely hiring those people to stand at the balcony and trick people into paying the covering going in.
Rym: and There's a good chance.
Rym: There was a totally lame party.
Rym: That's a very very common tactic Especially in places along the Canadian border where Americans who aren't old enough to drink in America But are old enough to drink in Canada frequent.
Scott: Well any place where there's college students hanging out for a party does that kind of thing?
Rym: So if you see people who are very attractive hanging out in an obvious You know hip awesome way in a balcony.
Scott: that's visible because I mean you don't get to go on balconies and hang out.
Scott: I mean, what have you ever gone to?
Scott: a party where there was like a balcony and you could totally go be awesome on it?
Scott: And you know and when were you out there?
Scott: like inviting people from the street to come up who were just schmucks.
Scott: never I don't think anyone.
Rym: so while we fail to get into that place We can't blame the people who caused us to fail because they actually saved us 15 Canadian dollars.
Rym: Yep So then we had a couple other random New Year's parties.
Rym: We tried to just have one in our colony apartment which went okay.
Rym: their apartment was too small to do much.
Scott: So I guess the other moral is if you're a geek looking for geek action And you go somewhere where all there is is drinking and going whoo It's not gonna be too much awesome there for you not at all.
Scott: I mean the DDR was the awesomest part.
Scott: we should have just stayed and played DDR the whole time we did for a while though.
Scott: Yep, we should have spent the whole time playing DDR.
Scott: Yeah, right out of money.
Rym: It was like two Canadian bucks a game though.
Rym: Yeah, it was too much anyway Alright, so then you know we don't really tell the story of our geek house parties other than that.
Rym: once we had a house That was big enough.
Rym: Immediately that New Year's house isn't big enough.
Rym: Well.
Rym: It was big enough.
Rym: now
Scott: Barely
Rym: considering that much of the front row our house was filled beyond capacity this past weekend We could not have comfortably dealt with any more people and in fact We could not have comfortably dealt with the people we had mm-hmm the our house was an unmitigated Disaster and we're just now finishing cleaning it up.
Scott: not even we're halfway done cleaning it up.
Rym: I think yeah, I still got a mop a couple times.
Rym: then we got a steam clean the apartment.
Scott: I got to clean them bathrooms.
Scott: I purposefully didn't clean them before people came because I knew they were gonna mess them all up.
Scott: Yeah, and they did.
Rym: now We're not gonna talk about how we ran an awesome party because that would be a whole different episode on how to run a party.
Scott: Just let it be said that if you want an awesome party to happen There's that rule that always applies if you want something done right do it yourself.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at Frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: Somebody's gonna have some things of the day real soon.
Scott: That's not funny.
Rym: I thought that was kind of funny.
Scott: No, that's a good fine.
Rym: I'll do it again.
Rym: No Things of the day she That was lame.
Rym: Oh, she.