Scott: It's Thursday August 30th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: how to not suck at making youtubes?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm taking tomorrow off at work.
Scott: Yeah, my co-workers taken tomorrow and Tuesday off I think I'm going to be going to work and not doing so much there because we sort of Cleared up all the work to be done.
Scott: You know for the bait for the Three-day weekend, and we didn't make any new work to do.
Scott: well up.
Rym: Why not just not go in?
Scott: because I need those days for other times.
Rym: But we could be playing natural selection all day.
Scott: tomorrow We'll be playing natural selection a whole lot on Sunday and Monday.
Scott: Do not fear.
Rym: Yeah, it's probably good because if you were here We'd just be playing but I'm at least gonna spend some time Installing that Nick that'll actually work in Linux and then fixing my computer so I can easily boot into Windows.
Scott: Yeah, sounds like a good idea because right now Sort of not so good over in your department, but it's really great in my department.
Rym: well the issue I've got let's see you don't have to boot into Linux anymore.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I do quite often.
Scott: That's where all my music and my movies and stuff are.
Scott: oh yeah, and my all my files.
Scott: Oh well Yeah, it's just kind of hot and I'm kind of tired.
Rym: and what do you have to be tired about I?
Scott: Don't know just am.
Scott: maybe it's that article I read that was like hey Don't use technology before you go to bed so much, or you'll be all tired.
Rym: Actually, I read an article like that.
Rym: I think three or four years ago when I've been trying to do that.
Scott: since then yeah I've been trying to read before I go to sleep instead of technology and emailing.
Scott: But the problem is I've done it all this week.
Scott: actually the problem is I end up reading for way long And you do that thing where you just keep reading and reading and then eventually I keep reading Hold my eyes open anymore.
Rym: you ever get that point where you think back And you realize that you didn't actually read like the last ten pages.
Rym: you've just been fun.
Rym: I hate that so much, and then you're trying to flip back like man.
Rym: How far did I go?
Scott: what I have been doing though is I've been reading.
Scott: I'll talk.
Scott: I'll just get right into it.
Scott: I'm gonna do.
Scott: I got no news.
Scott: I'm gonna do a geek back.
Rym: You mean a geek bite?
Rym: all right geek bite Way to fuck up the new thing.
Scott: yeah doing a geek bite on these books I'm reading.
Scott: so I'm actually been doing a thing with these books where I haven't been using a bookmark or anything.
Scott: So whenever I have to stop and start reading again I end up like skimming through like the most recent chapters until I find the spot where I left off.
Rym: You know I've always done that and I really think it's the best way to read books.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's actually a really great way because then if I just start where the bookmark is I might forget something important And I've remembered a lot of things because of this and it doesn't really take me that long To get back into the book after I've you know stop reading and pick it up again.
Scott: And also I mean I've read almost two of these books within like five days.
Scott: Let me talk about the book.
Scott: so Rym knows and some of my friends know I am NOT a fan of novels that have you know labels on them professing that they are part of some Licensed property.
Rym: so none of those forgotten realm.
Rym: yeah mech warrior Star Trek Star Trek Battletech.
Scott: none of these none of these books Really interest me because I say wow that person couldn't come up with an original story.
Scott: They just Took this world and put another story in it so they could milk off the people who were.
Scott: you know like Star Trek fans Will buy the book no matter what even if the book sucks.
Scott: There's no reason to read these.
Scott: and one licensed property that has novels is of course Star Wars which I am more a fan of than any of the other licensed properties which Have novels in the sci-fi section.
Scott: and while obviously I think many Star Wars novels are fan fiction basically and many people agree Everyone has always professed that the Timothy's on yes on Like Admiral Thrawn series of books is not bad and in fact the best.
Scott: now I said well if I read the best I'll know that all the other ones are worse than that and I'll be able to judge from there.
Rym: now what I can say because A lot of you might not know about Admiral Thrawn.
Rym: I didn't know about him until one of the best games ever made came out a game called tie fighter Such a simple name and in Thai remember, that's a game that got a 97 in PC gamers definitely one of the top 10 games ever.
Rym: the only game to beat it in Any reasonable span of time.
Scott: was the PC CD-ROM release of tie fighter?
Rym: Yes, which got a 98 because it was slightly better.
Rym: Yep, but in that game there was.
Rym: you saw in the opening movie Which the movie is kind of lame by today's standards, but back then in that era of computing that opening movie was fucking amazing.
Scott: It was pretty good and it talked it talk.
Scott: Maybe you could watch it on YouTube.
Scott: We should try to find a link.
Rym: Yeah, I'll try to find one.
Rym: But anyway, you get to see a big scary-looking blue guy and his is Admiral Thrawn and you don't know much about it.
Scott: And Admiral throw.
Rym: other than that you get the impression that he kicks.
Rym: and actually back then.
Rym: No, he was only vice Admiral Thrawn.
Rym: Oh, I believe Darth Vader says signal vice Admiral Thrawn to have our our Thai squadrons launch immediately Uh-huh or something to that effect.
Scott: Yeah anyway From reading these books I can tell that the the Star Wars outside of the six official movies.
Scott: Continuity is totally crazy and all over the place and not so contiguous between video games and books and things.
Scott: But it's self consistent within.
Scott: I guess if you just like read watch the six movies and then read these three books It's pretty contiguous.
Scott: I mean the first three movies like episodes 1 2 3 not Perfectly contiguous, but it's pretty close.
Scott: You can you can bend the rules and get away with it.
Rym: It's one of those.
Rym: don't worry about it.
Rym: Just go with it.
Rym: kind of things.
Scott: Yeah, I mean these are written I guess in the early 90s.
Scott: So after Return of the Jedi and before the crap fest phantom, whatever.
Scott: so anyway, I'm reading them and Everyone says they're the best Star Wars books.
Scott: and well I could say they're better than fanfiction.
Scott: So knowing that the rest are fanfiction that I guess everyone agrees that these are the best because they are now.
Scott: they're not like Literary masterpieces of all time or anything.
Scott: Don't go don't go fooling yourself about that.
Scott: but if you like Star Wars Star Wars universe and you like Horatio Hornblower books or the lensman books or you know a novel with not so much deep meaning or symbolism but you know a story of People are all badasses Trying to beat each other out with lots of twists and turns and details and tricks and things like that.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's worth your time to read it because like I said, I've read One and three quarters of these three books in like a week.
Scott: So it doesn't take very long It's it's a quick read and I'll probably go buy the third one because I got to finish the second one.
Scott: real soon I'll go buy the third one.
Scott: It's like the Barnes & Noble tomorrow or something.
Scott: And then I'll probably be done with Star Wars books forever and that'll be the end probably done with Star Wars forever.
Rym: Oh, yeah, pretty much except I could watch those original three movies over and over, you know I kind of want to watch return of the Jedi right now.
Scott: I kind of want to watch return of the Jedi right now also.
Rym: Yeah, maybe this weekend not tonight.
Scott: We got to get some DVDs or something.
Rym: So speaking of Star Wars This one's kind of complicated.
Rym: I got a news here and you're gonna have to bear with me.
Scott: Actually Star Wars related.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: You just watched it Right.
Rym: So I'm gonna explain this because it's you got to just bear with me and at the end you'll see where I'm going with This.
Rym: so a guy ran for school board in some town.
Scott: Awesome school board is awesome to run for and he made a little commercial.
Rym: That was basically he is a Jedi and he's going to with his lightsaber Save the day in the school and it was a you know Cheesy but yet
Scott: that definitely get all the nerds at the school to vote for him all the 18 year old nerds Anyway,
Rym: plus what little we learned about
Scott: him all the nerdy parents
Rym: his stances on various educational issues.
Rym: I would have voted for him.
Scott: Yeah, he said.
Scott: he said that he is displeased with the leave.
Scott: no child behind act.
Rym: it displeases him.
Rym: I see.
Scott: I see he will open up some sort of Jedi Academy to train the students with the force.
Rym: I figured he just choked death.
Rym: anyone who opposed him.
Scott: Haha.
Scott: I don't know what color was his lightsaber.
Scott: Did he shoot me lightning from his fingers or not?
Rym: It was kind of white.
Rym: Oh, well, but anyway, so he made this video and then he put the video up on the youtubes.
Scott: He's an awesome person.
Scott: anyone who's awesome enough to run for school board with a Star Wars commercial also Guaranteed to be awesome enough to put that video on YouTube.
Rym: So then not too long ago Someone took this commercial and aired it on TV with some humorous commentary of their own.
Scott: This someone was vh1, you know, I've noticed there's a lot of you know, professional and I don't know how to say professional but like mainstream big like big-time media that's scooping up a lot of our you know, homegrown content and using it for their own purposes.
Scott: and Sometimes that's okay.
Scott: And sometimes it's not.
Rym: well Usually it's not because a lot of times these companies don't actually understand or agree to the Creative Commons license.
Scott: Well, I don't know did the guy put it up under Creative Commons license?
Rym: He might have just put it up in general Yeah, but in this specific one regardless you could say pretty clearly that it was fair use.
Rym: But yet maybe not because on one hand they broke it down and while they aired the whole thing It was pretty short and they kind of humorously like how did I how did I how did I on their show about that?
Scott: Is a vague thing.
Scott: I didn't think it could be fair use.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Well, the argument is it is fair use for everything except the fact that vh1 and this whole thing is purely Commercial and was purely making money and it.
Rym: the argument could go either way.
Scott: So I'm not gonna need a judge to decide that sort of thing.
Rym: Yep So the guy says wow vh1 made some commentary on my thing.
Rym: So he takes the vh1 video with the commentary of his Star Wars video and puts it on YouTube.
Rym: vh1 then Sends a takedown notice to YouTube saying that he is violating via comments vh1, don't they?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes The biggest YouTube opponents that he is violating his own copyright and therefore the video must be taken down.
Scott: That's a vague thing there.
Scott: I mean if someone take we a GeekNights We have a share alike license Which means that if you were to remix GeekNights that then you would have to put it under a license Which is you know pretty close to the license we you give you.
Scott: so there's no way that you could remix GeekNights And then we couldn't legally take that remix and use it ourselves for our own purposes.
Rym: Yes a lot of people.
Rym: This is a kind of viral clause in the license we use and there are other open source licenses that are viral in there.
Scott: That's the reason we chose to put the share alike there because while it sort of restricts us in that You know some people who would have otherwise, well, no, it doesn't restrict us at all.
Rym: No, if anyone wants to use it for something else, all they have to do is ask us.
Scott: But the thing is it does hold people back who don't want to ask from using our stuff.
Rym: who good if someone won't put Forth that tiny bit of initiative.
Scott: I don't care about them I know but it does decrease the exposure theoretically, I guess or the potential exposure anyway.
Scott: But if anyone ever does anything with our stuff, we can always go and use it our own way.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically the.
Rym: if you fuck up we get whatever you use GeekNights in.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So this guy I don't know what license he used but let's assume he just did nothing.
Scott: So we have this vague.
Scott: They might have infringed on his copyright to create something new and then he definitely Infringed on their copyright by taking that something new back now And it's it's pretty sketchy going on.
Rym: the rabbit hole goes a little bit deeper.
Rym: Oh, man, and this is the part that I just found out.
Rym: so he posted that back on YouTube, right?
Rym: But he only posted it on YouTube because he uses that as a video host.
Rym: He can't put videos on his blog.
Rym: his blog won't stand up to that.
Rym: in his blog.
Rym: He embedded it and then he had commentary on the vh1 commentary.
Rym: So that would be fair use.
Rym: However, it's the whole work which puts it into a slightly gray area.
Rym: But to know why did he modify the actual work?
Scott: or was the commentary next to the work in the blog?
Rym: That doesn't matter.
Scott: Oh, it doesn't know.
Scott: I figured it would.
Rym: no You can take a picture like a fair use picture and put it in an article talking about the picture.
Rym: So and there's argument of it.
Rym: well, he took the whole work.
Rym: so yeah, but and the weird part is alright.
Rym: now We have this technological problem where he used a host in order to put it somewhere else.
Rym: So alright say I have the commentary to something I'm fair-using on my blog and I just put it on my web hosting not even YouTube.
Rym: What if someone else just links to the bare file that I'm embedding in my thing?
Rym: Are they now?
Rym: Violating?
Rym: what's the violation?
Rym: at what point does it not become fair use?
Rym: and the problem with our?
Rym: Copyright system is that unless you have a lawyer and a judge to tell you there's no way to know and in the end Whoever has a lawyer and money just wins because I can't fight against those people.
Rym: Well, I guess I can because we have a lawyer here.
Rym: But yeah, most other people can't.
Scott: it's just more examples of how broken The copyright system is and you know things are gonna happen every day Just like this that further expose all the faults in the system and I'm just waiting for it to finally fall apart completely.
Scott: I don't know how long it's gonna take but I've been waiting at least.
Scott: oh, it's five six years.
Rym: It just bothers me because if you look at it from a purely Years, I have.
Rym: I think that the way this would have should be legally.
Rym: I don't care how it's written But the end result should be that vh1 could use it because he posted it freely But then he can use the one because they took it from him in the first place.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I would say.
Scott: We should be okay because I'm all for the you know, more information spreading action It's.
Scott: it's all cool by me.
Scott: The problem I'm seeing though that that's that's more important here is Originally in the Napster days right before people like us were creating content.
Scott: It was just us Infringing on the copyrights of the big companies who created stuff to get stuff, right?
Rym: Yep, and they would just sue or send down take-down notices just all the way because they were always right.
Rym: It was always the Britney Spears song.
Rym: It was never like I made something else.
Scott: But now that people are making stuff we've got the big companies that we were stealing from before stealing back from us and The law while on paper.
Scott: we're in the right and they're stealing from us the same way that you know They say is wrong.
Scott: It's sort of like one of those.
Scott: Yeah We the law only is for the big people to protect against the little people not the other way around.
Scott: sort of like how Free trade means that the importer exporters don't have to pay tariffs.
Scott: But I still can't get a DVD from Japan at a reasonable price.
Rym: I hear he's an importer exporter.
Rym: What's the import chips?
Rym: What's the export diapers?
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I'm just getting tired of all this bullshit.
Scott: and We have the Creative Commons thing and I have decided to Basically strictly adhere to it in all cases unless I give specific permission.
Rym: Otherwise, yes And very few people have actually been given permission.
Scott: So I have.
Scott: so if anyone tries to violate our Creative Commons license I am gonna come after you just because I have nothing better to do.
Scott: Yeah, all I may not have mad moneys for a lawyer.
Scott: I have a little bit of moneys for a lawyer.
Rym: Well, also we have a lawyer.
Scott: Yeah And I got nothing better to do and I really want to come after you so that my show will become popular and I'll get All-over slash dot and dig.
Scott: Yeah, so bring it on.
Rym: so I don't have permission to bring it on.
Scott: I welcome you to violate my Creative Commons license.
Scott: Actually, I don't.
Scott: I don't want to say that because that means that you know I'm allowing you to.
Scott: I'm not allowing you to violate it.
Scott: I'm daring you to violate it.
Scott: up.
Scott: to be more precise I dare you things of the day.
Rym: So a while ago.
Rym: I did a thing of the day about Rowan Atkinson.
Rym: I think it was a fatal beating or something.
Scott: A lot of people say I look like him.
Rym: you kind of do Yeah, but uh way back I kept saying oh But there's this other thing.
Rym: Rowan Atkinson live like all the different bits in it and the best bit Was the one.
Rym: well other than the surreptitious wink was the one at the end.
Scott: I Tell you you did a pretty good surreptitious wink.
Rym: I must say But the bit at the end kind of the climax of his live show was the invisible drum kit.
Rym: and back when I wanted to Talk about it on this show.
Rym: I couldn't find a link to it anywhere.
Rym: I couldn't find a video that was hosted of it.
Rym: I found it.
Rym: Here it is.
Scott: It's on dig videos today.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So enjoy.
Rym: This is quite amazing.
Scott: It's a pretty good bit.
Scott: I wonder how he does it.
Scott: does he do it with like practicing a routine that is time to record it audio or is there?
Scott: Someone backstage making the audio live, you know in sync it.
Scott: he could have done it a number of ways and Depending on which way he did it It's the skill and practice required maybe more or less impressive and I'd like to know I
Rym: Get the same enjoyment out of this that I do out of watching like a pen and teller act.
Rym: Yeah, definitely cuz it's not the oh my god.
Rym: He did a magic trick.
Rym: It's how the fuck did he do that?
Scott: Well, it's it's yeah, I don't know what you want.
Scott: all right, my thing of the day is a bunch of pictures from Cuba a place that is hard to see if you don't live there because Crappy old grumpy old people in the US government don't want to just forget about this bullshit from like 50 years ago.
Rym: The fact that Cuba is still Embargoed by the United States is just ludicrous.
Scott: What say the?
Scott: what's supposed to be the point of still having it embargoed?
Scott: I mean, I understand Embargoing it back then I might have done the same thing I mean, but eventually you're just like why are we still doing this back then?
Rym: There was a Soviet Union.
Rym: There was a fear of communist dominoes and all that nuclear missiles Yep.
Rym: Yeah, but there's no longer any fear of the Soviets coming over into Cuba.
Scott: Yeah, not so much.
Rym: So granted there is the kind of pink revolution going on in South America right now that Cuba may or may Not become a part of.
Rym: but that's beside the progress.
Scott: I learned a few things from looking at these pictures and from the captions on them.
Scott: First of all, I learned that some parts of Cuba.
Scott: There's a lot of really nice stuff, which I knew.
Scott: Some parts.
Scott: there's some not so nice stuff.
Scott: I also knew that I learned that people in Cuba's They can't get parts for their cars because embargo.
Scott: So they're the best mechanics in the world and they all fix their cars without replacement parts.
Scott: and there's all sorts of pictures of people with really old cars like able to keep them running without any replacement parts whatsoever like they make their own parts and supposedly the best mechanics in the world.
Scott: and I sort of want to Undo the embargo just so I can get new mechanics over here.
Rym: Yeah, that's where we need them the power of necessity like way back when we did that Gallery of interesting tools that prisoners.
Rym: Yes Yep If you got if you got no tools and no stuff and you need something and all you've got is time You're gonna come up with a pretty clever way to get that thing done eventually.
Scott: Yeah, especially if you're stuck on the road needed to move.
Scott: There's some pretty funny anti-bush propaganda that I can sort of read.
Scott: There's a lot of abandoned like big fancy buildings that never weren't completed or abandoned or fixed You know with cinder blocks in the windows.
Rym: There's a lot of that in Russia.
Scott: I've come to find that I you know, I've read about North Korea and Russia and China and it seems like in all the actually communist countries there seems to be this common trend of start an ambitious construction project that seems to be going well and then Scheduling delays or just complete failure to finish the thing all together like that giant hotel in North Korea that's never finished and they stopped working on it.
Scott: and Russia there's all sorts of stuff like that and it's like what.
Scott: why does this happen?
Scott: I mean I could think of a whole bunch of reasons why in a communist nation this thing would happen.
Rym: the reason Communist nations have that problem is the same reason token ring is not used today.
Rym: Oh Real simply token ring and Ethernet were kind of competing with each other to be the way that people would do networking with computers.
Rym: Communism and capitalism were the two economy ideas that were competing with each other.
Rym: What are we gonna use capitalism or communism now token ring?
Rym: Essentially the way it worked is that everything was deterministic and controlled.
Rym: There was no randomness.
Rym: There was no chance for error.
Rym: It was the token goes around.
Rym: every computer has to be smart.
Rym: every piece of networking equipment has to be smart.
Rym: every piece of the way everything has to be controlled.
Rym: a hundred percent and as a 16-megabits per second you got no matter what the full 4 or 16 megabits per second Because you knew exactly what was happening on the network at all times.
Rym: It was all controlled In Ethernet.
Rym: you pretty much threw packets out there and you let the network just deal with it.
Rym: And as a result while Ethernet was 10 megabits per second You would often only get four or five at best.
Rym: just because you're not controlling it You kind of let it work itself out on its own.
Rym: But as the scale of networks increased you couldn't make token ring go much faster than 16 megabits per second because you had to control it at every step of the way and The token ring bureaucracy got too big.
Scott: But with but with Ethernet, I know I understand that it's you know The comp the the complications of the bureaucracy and stuff that bog it down.
Scott: But I'm wondering specifically like is it that they build a building and then they mess up and they can't finish it because of engineering?
Scott: Is it because the workers don't want to work anymore?
Scott: is that they can't afford to work on it anymore?
Scott: Is it you know what?
Rym: I think it's mostly just the poor allocation of resources.
Rym: I mean not to say that capitalism is perfect if they run out of materials But in capitalism at least the system tends to correct gross deficiencies or gross problems.
Rym: Like if there's a super discrepancy between the demand for steel and the production of steel a bunch of people are gonna start making Steel on their own because they can make some money and then the market kind of corrects itself.
Rym: And again, it's not perfect.
Rym: But at least it kind of works itself out.
Scott: Yeah well the only other picture I want to draw your attention to is this one of a pretty cute girl working at an ice cream stand and Apparently ice cream is two and a half Cuban cents if you're a Cuban or a dollar if you're from anywhere else.
Rym: You know, I'm fine with that.
Scott: Yeah, but it's a lot of stuff.
Scott: It's one of those places where they have really nice things and some not so nice things and apparently tourists I guess not tourists but anyone from elsewhere in the world who's not Cuban gets all sorts of nice things and Cubans don't get those nice things.
Scott: This acts like museums here that Cubans can't even go to and stuff.
Rym: Well, the one thing is I communism on a very small scale seems like it can work and Cuba was very small and generally prosperous.
Rym: and it does kind of bother me that I do believe that if we had After the Cold War it ended.
Rym: if we just embargoed Cuba and not just kind of completely dick them at every possible opportunity I don't think it would have been the greatest place in the world But I think it would be doing a lot better than it is now.
Scott: I think you would be a happy place to go on vacation is what I think.
Rym: I just think America even to this day is kind of afraid of a communist country being prosperous.
Scott: I think this is a bunch of old people still in charge of the government.
Rym: I mean, we can't pretend that China is communist, but that that's Cuba is mostly actually communist from what I'm led to believe.
Scott: Yep It's so communist that the people don't care about repairing their houses because the houses belong to the state not to them.
Scott: What do they care?
Rym: Right.
Rym: So, uh, we're kind of tired and it's hot out.
Rym: So we're gonna do a how to not suck which I haven't done in a while and we're gonna have to break it Internally into two bits because there are two very different sets of rules depending on what you're doing.
Rym: But tonight it is very simply and very briefly and very succinctly how to not suck at Making a YouTube video.
Scott: now I could sum this whole thing up in like two sentences and we can go to bed But I want to break it up now.
Scott: I do want to break it up.
Scott: But let me just say the two sentences.
Scott: people have short attention spans and They want instant gratification now.
Scott: Keep it in mind before we continue.
Rym: Word.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: we're not gonna talk about an art film or a short film or anything like that those things those works of art.
Rym: you do whatever you want because YouTube is just the medium and you don't really you shouldn't let the medium to Dictate what your content is going to be.
Rym: if you're gonna make a short film just make it however you want.
Rym: We're talking about the YouTube videos, which is the majority of them that consist of oh my god.
Rym: Here's a video of something that just happened in the street.
Rym: or oh my god Here's a video of the prank me and my friends pulled out.
Rym: or check it out.
Rym: Here's the video of me blowing up my high school.
Scott: Oh Like check it out.
Scott: I made this, you know cool thing out of Legos.
Scott: or you know, check it out.
Scott: Here's some crazy thing that I saw in the news or you know, something like that.
Rym: so I think the biggest mistake that people make when they're making a standard YouTube video is That they like to have a lot of exposition.
Scott: Basically when you make it, let's say let's use an example video you ready?
Scott: Oh my god, there's a crab person in my backyard.
Scott: Alright, well don't sit there for like a minute telling me Alright, so I went to the store and when I came home I looked out the back window and I saw this crab person.
Scott: No your video.
Scott: as soon as I click play I want to see your camera pointing out the back window and I want to see a crab person.
Scott: That's what I want to see.
Scott: I'm not I don't have time.
Scott: I have a short attention span remember and I want instant gratification.
Scott: crab person and only the crab person.
Scott: shut your trap now.
Rym: I'm okay with a short introduction Especially if it's going to be a strange thing or a scene that you're really gonna need some prior knowledge to parse.
Rym: Yeah, sometimes exposition is needed like in a how-to video or even in that I'd be okay.
Rym: Here's a good and bad.
Rym: good There's a crab person outside.
Rym: cut crab person bad.
Rym: so I came home from work on Friday.
Rym: music starts playing as in in the video.
Rym: music starts playing and I saw something crazy.
Scott: And then and and and and and and and and and sorry I couldn't help myself.
Rym: All right number two Unless you have a good reason to and you're sure that is going to work.
Rym: Well, don't put music in your video.
Scott: Yes, for example, I have a video of Rym setting himself on fire.
Scott: Should I set it to music?
Scott: No You know why?
Rym: because the people watching something like that are sick bastards and they want to hear Rym scream or in the very least They want to hear me go, all right, I'm totally going to set myself on fire.
Scott: Oh, oh, oh, and they want to hear the fire like, you know, crackling as it burns his pants.
Rym: And maybe they want to hear Scout with the camera going dumbass.
Rym: Yeah, but they what they don't want to hear is that's exactly right.
Scott: A good time to put music to something is when perhaps the audio of the video itself is, you know, not going to bring any entertainment value whatsoever.
Scott: Or like, for example, I don't know, you're flying in an airplane and you see something funny outside the window or something like that, like you see lying in an airplane.
Scott: The only noise you're going to hear is jet engine, jet engine, jet engine.
Scott: No one wants to listen to.
Rym: So if you're in an airplane and someone like tries to eat a hundred eggs, just film that as it goes.
Rym: But if you're flying in an airplane and you see outside the window, a biplane covered in clowns, just that is perfectly appropriate to that.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Now, number three, if you're going to make music in your thing at all, one, make it appropriate to make it not stupid.
Rym: I know that's the same as one.
Rym: Three, don't use poison or or winger.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Another thing you want to do in YouTube videos is if you're going to have audio.
Scott: that's not music, you want to make sure people can fucking hear it.
Scott: because, I mean, how many times you put a YouTube video on it, someone saying something you can't hear what the fuck they're saying.
Scott: It's like a podcast.
Scott: It's even more important.
Scott: But in a YouTube video, if what?
Scott: if someone's saying something and part of the importance and the entertainment value of the video is what are they saying?
Scott: I should be able to hear it if I can't hear it.
Scott: What's the point?
Scott: The video is ruined now if it's inconsequential.
Rym: It's just kind of side banter or whatever, and it's unintelligible, replace it with music or something seriously or just make it silent.
Rym: It's OK to have a silent YouTube video.
Scott: Yeah, no reason that there has to be noise.
Scott: I mean, how many times do you watch a funny guy robs a convenience store video?
Scott: There's no audio on those things because they have the cheapest, shittiest security camera they can possibly get.
Scott: And, you know, it's just as good as the ones where the video and the audio are full on.
Rym: Now, if your your event, not the exposition, but the thing you're filming itself is a very long build up to a climax.
Rym: You don't really want to have the entire build up and then the climax.
Scott: You must learn to make the montage.
Rym: Now, this is the one case where you probably should have music because otherwise it might sound really disjointed.
Rym: But say you've got a video of I don't know, I got.
Scott: I got an example.
Scott: Let's say you got a video of a prank that involves one hundred people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there's a lot of.
Scott: it takes you time to collect the hundred people.
Scott: Well, instead of showing like a 10 minutes of footage as all these hundred people start to gather around and someone explains to everyone exactly what's going to happen in like five seconds of video, you can show like a stop motion of like 10 photographs of, you know, the group is five people, 10 people, 50 people, 100 people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And just go like did it did it did it did it.
Scott: And we'll see the group go from small to big and the matter of like five to 10 seconds.
Scott: And that's all I need to see.
Scott: OK, a group formed that you got the information across.
Scott: You basically want to get all.
Scott: you don't want to cut any information or entertainment out of your video.
Scott: You just want to cut time out of the video because, like I said, short attention span is the gratification.
Scott: You want to get all the content of your video, everything that people want to see in it into as small a time as possible without removing any of the good stuff you want to eat minus Jeff.
Rym: If you want a good example of this, check out watch a show like Mythbusters.
Rym: Notice how they kind of fast forward through and show just quick clips while they like.
Rym: they show a bunch of clips of all the setup for a thing.
Rym: And while they're showing that, they do the exposition at the same time with an audio over.
Scott: That way you get the exposition and you don't have to sit there for like an hour while they're building things in the shop.
Rym: But that way also you get the exposition and at the same time you're getting all the setup video.
Rym: You're killing two birds with one stone.
Scott: Another thing, how many people?
Scott: when they're making videos of stuff, especially, you know, sort of really amateur videos, you have this incredibly shaky camera that is always pointing in the wrong place.
Rym: The shaky cam is bad.
Rym: If you can't keep your hand still, don't put it on YouTube or at least get a steady cam thing or a tripod or something along those same lines.
Rym: If you don't know how to use a camera, don't film stuff and put it on YouTube, because a lot of people like they just keep zooming in and out or they keep like moving the camera around.
Rym: like, look at this, look at this, look at this, look at this.
Scott: I don't know how many times I've watched YouTube where there was something interesting happening that I wanted to see, but the camera didn't capture it because the person using the camera sucked balls.
Scott: And thus I knew an awesome thing happened off camera or perhaps I could see it, but not very well because the camera was shaking all over the place and I just didn't get the enjoyment that I would have gotten if the camera was used properly.
Rym: Now, if due to the limitations of the size of a file you can put on YouTube, you have to choose between extra exposition or extra setup or showing me the denouement, the payoff, the end result, the aftermath, we'd rather see the aftermath.
Rym: If you pull an awesome prank and I don't get to see the video of you telling the guy it was a prank, that's a definite minus.
Scott: Yes, it's basically we only want if you look at the title of your video, right?
Scott: When you when you put a video on YouTube, think about what the title of the video is going to be.
Rym: If the title is Guy Gets Hidden Balls, LOL.
Scott: As soon as I push play, I should be seeing something already headed for his balls.
Rym: Or in the very least, I see like a shot from far away of a guy walking and at the same time a voice saying he's about to get hit in the balls and then immediately a ball hit.
Scott: Yeah, I don't want to see like some guy playing soccer for like 10 minutes and then a guy kicks him in the balls.
Scott: That's I don't have time for that.
Scott: I don't want to skip through YouTube video to find the exact point where the ball hitting takes place.
Scott: There's obviously one part of the video I want to see.
Scott: So that should be the only part you put on YouTube.
Rym: Now, right along with that, don't upload a video of someone getting hit in the balls.
Rym: It's already been done.
Rym: It's on the Internet.
Rym: Everyone has seen someone get hit in the balls.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We need something.
Rym: YouTube doesn't need to be nothing but like horrible accidents and snuff films and people getting hit in the balls.
Rym: Cute puppies are OK.
Scott: Well, there are also a zillion cute puppies out there.
Scott: We need if you're putting something on YouTube and you actually expect, you know, you want a lot of people to look at it, make it something we haven't seen before.
Scott: Remember, most of the people looking at your video are people who go to YouTube a lot.
Scott: They or they go to dig videos.
Scott: They've seen it.
Scott: They've seen it all.
Scott: They've seen the craziest batshit you can imagine.
Scott: They've seen Goatsy.
Scott: They've seen that Darth Vader in the supermarket guy.
Scott: They've seen Ask a Ninja.
Rym: So if you're you've got something, you think, hey, I want to put it up on YouTube and I want it to be like a big YouTube video.
Rym: I mean, of course, all these rules don't apply if you're just uploading it to send it to your mom or whatever.
Scott: Or again, if it's a short film, I'm talking about you expect me to look at it.
Scott: You expect it to be thing of the day material.
Rym: Now, in that case, search and see if anyone else has put up something similar and then think to yourself, one, is what I'm doing the same thing essentially as that?
Rym: If so, don't do it.
Scott: Are they?
Scott: am I doing it better than the second question?
Rym: is my thing better than that?
Rym: Because if someone has a cute video, for example, a cat parachuting off of a building and you make a video of that's a thousand times better of like a cat parachuting off of a building onto a dog, because that's better.
Scott: That is better.
Scott: Or perhaps, you know, one guy has a video of.
Scott: I don't know, I can't think of a good example.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Scott, fail and lose.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Cat per 10 cats parachuting off of a building.
Scott: You can't parachute 10 cats.
Rym: I can't parachuting off.
Rym: And then when the other cat's parachute fails, he jumps down, saves the cat and then lands on all four legs because he's a cat.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I kind of want to do a crapo episode.
Rym: I think I'm going to go to bed.
Scott: I think we should go to bed.
Scott: But I just want people when they make YouTube videos to actually think about what they're doing, put a little bit of effort into it.
Scott: I mean, if you're only going to put two minutes of video on the Internet, you should make those a pretty good two minutes.
Scott: You know, and you could, you know, even if your videos are not the greatest videos, if you actually put a little bit of effort into them, they'll get a lot more attention than they probably deserve.
Rym: And one last thing, we don't need any more videos of, oh, my God, some stater kids were kicked out of a place.
Rym: They were skating illegally by a security guard.
Rym: But look, the skater kids gave the security guard some guff.
Rym: There's been a lot of those lately.
Rym: I'm really sick of them.
Scott: There have been a lot of those.
Scott: And so it's it's tough.
Scott: It's it's annoying.
Scott: Don't make anything that, you know, some people are going to go, yeah, get grumpy about.
Rym: You want to make people getting people get grumpy about things all the time.
Scott: I know.
Scott: But you want to make a bit.
Scott: generally the best YouTube videos are the ones that just anyone can enjoy and not sort of the things that make people upset.
Rym: Scott, I would submit that the most popular videos on YouTube are people.
Rym: Well, maybe not the specific thing of people getting hit in the balls, but it is the spiritual equivalent of people getting hit in the balls.
Scott: That is the majority.
Scott: I'm getting kind of tired of those, actually.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just saying you don't have to make it something everyone can enjoy.
Rym: Just make it not be crappy.
Rym: That's the only thing I care about.
Scott: There's one last thing to take into consideration, right?
Scott: If you're putting up a video of, say, you know, mice going through a maze, you have to understand that someday someone's going to make a compilation of all the mice going through a maze videos on YouTube.
Scott: So design your video in such a way that when it is added to that compilation of a hundred other mice going through a maze videos, the year stands out.
Rym: Also, if you're going to make a compilation video, see what other compilation videos have already been made, because they're like a billion owned compilations.
Rym: And I think they all include the same clips just in different orders with different shitty music.
Scott: Yes, if you compile, do not compile what other people have already compiled.
Rym: or like the same thing with cute puppies.
Rym: There's one cute puppy compilation that's like the best cute puppy one ever.
Rym: Everyone else, don't bother.
Rym: It's already been done.
Rym: It's perfect.
Rym: You're not going to make it better.
Scott: Yes, but there is a. there's supply and demand here.
Scott: And the supply of cute puppy videos is well above the demand, even though that's an incredible demand.
Scott: The supply is that much more incredible thing.
Rym: There's a lot of cute puppies and a lot of cameras and YouTube.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, well, do we got anything else to say?
Rym: I'm going to either play some natural selection or go to bed.
Scott: I'm going to go somewhere where they can eat some food.
Rym: I don't have to go to work tomorrow.
Scott: They get some air conditioning.
Rym: Amen.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknight@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution, non-commercial, share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.