Scott: It's Wednesday April 11th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we review the OAV Dominion tank police.
Scott: Let's do this Man.
Rym: it's always like this ordeal whenever we want to get groceries.
Scott: Yeah, we're too used to that Wegmans action and now we got to do with the shitty-ass shop.
Scott: right everything sucks.
Rym: Yeah, it seems like the stars and the planets aligned today at the specific time But I was trying to check out with my tiny basket with a few tiny things that I wanted to take home and eat because I was rather hungry.
Scott: Yeah, I got to the checkout line.
Rym: We're about to leave and everything's fine And just as we're walking toward the checkout like a thousand people just kind of all shuffle up.
Rym: Well, that wasn't the problem.
Scott: The problem was there only two lanes open - they're like 25 lanes in this grocery store And I've never seen more than five open at this time.
Scott: There were two open.
Rym: Well, you know what one?
Rym: for some reason It seems like a lot of people suddenly converged on the exit.
Rym: That's sure but I'll - there's no reason for them to keep those open because they know that everyone there is a captive audience.
Rym: They're gonna go to that same shop, right?
Scott: I know I was a kid though The grocery store would have a shit ton of aisles and they would all be open.
Scott: and now you go to stores these days like you can go to like stores that were built in the 90s and they have a million checkout aisles and only a few of Them are being used.
Rym: You know what old man?
Rym: There's no profit in there.
Rym: There's no reason to have all those aisles open.
Rym: that the stores today make a lot more money.
Scott: I know it's like you go to a modern store though, and every aisle is open.
Scott: They just have a lot less of them.
Scott: Like look at a Best Buy for example Not so many aisles has only like maybe five or six.
Rym: The worst is Home Depot.
Rym: There's usually just one that's open.
Scott: Well Home Depot has the self-checkout which kind of works.
Rym: No, it doesn't kind of does failed like 80% of the time.
Rym: I've tried to use it.
Rym: The problem is you can't use those things with a non-standard item and pretty much everything Store of non-standard items.
Scott: It would work in almost any other store like a bookstore.
Scott: You can just pile the books on there would work great.
Scott: But a Home Depot, it's.
Scott: it's not happening.
Rym: Yeah, I wouldn't work at a bookstore because people just steal the books.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: you know how many people I see just trying to steal stuff when I go to the Grocery store near my work.
Rym: Yeah Wow Granted it's a scummy grocery store in Yonkers.
Rym: So what do you want?
Scott: So anyway, we finally check the hell out and we're all grumpy because you know They didn't have the right tomato sauce, which I told Rym.
Scott: They didn't and I was right.
Rym: Yeah, he was right.
Scott: I and We had waited.
Scott: we spent more time and waiting in line to check out that we did getting all our groceries.
Rym: I think the worst thing was that not one but two separate customers in front of us in line Decided to pay with cash and furthermore they counted out exact change.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is the guy in front of me like it seemed like his dad was with him.
Scott: He was immediate middle-aged guy and his dad was an old Senile old man and he kept yelling at his dad because his dad kept bringing back the wrong cat food.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think he was definitely being unfair to the old man.
Rym: I also but then again the old man might had problems, but you don't.
Rym: if the old man has problems You don't yell at him.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it was one of those situations You know where probably someone has to take care of their parent and the parents not a hundred percent anymore.
Rym: He's probably getting a little bit resentful all that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah in front of me, so yeah, so we went from one Situation that's kind of awkward to another much more awkward situation.
Scott: so we go out to the parking lot with the groceries and we start putting them in the hatch and We see some people.
Scott: one of them, you know, there are these people at the grocery store who push the carts around.
Rym: Yeah, there's two of them with their little orange vests on.
Scott: Yeah They go and they get the carts and they bring them back to the grocery store from the parking lot.
Rym: Yeah, one guy and one girl and then there's this guy who isn't wearing one of the vests and the three of them are kind Of standing in a little triangle of people.
Scott: Yeah, and it seems like the guy who isn't wearing a vest and obviously is not a store employee is Doing something with the girl who is a store employee like she's yelling like get away from me or something.
Scott: And then they're hugging and then she's screaming and walking away and it was kind of weird what was going on?
Rym: We're like 40 feet away with our groceries at the car.
Rym: So we're standing there watching and we're talking to each other like so we need to call the police.
Rym: Let's keep an eye on this and see what happens.
Rym: Yeah, we're like I'd have to intervene here.
Scott: Yeah, we're like, hey What's going on?
Scott: Are we gonna have to go beat up that guy?
Scott: No, the guy guy who's the guy?
Scott: the other guy in the vest who's standing there not saying anything?
Scott: What's he doing?
Rym: the guy who seemed to be the focus of the this issue with the girl looks at us Notices that we're watching and says you guys should mind your own business.
Scott: I think he actually told the guy who the guy with the vest who is standing there Tell those guys to mind their own business.
Rym: Yeah, he said that and then he turned and said to us - yes I was like.
Scott: Obviously, there's something he doesn't want us to pay attention to over there.
Rym: Yeah, so they keep going on for a while and the girl tries to get away and the guy grabs her.
Rym: and finally we're like All right.
Rym: I didn't have my cell phone.
Rym: So Scott called the police.
Scott: I just call the police, you know that they say if you see something say something.
Scott: Hey guy, if the guy really is, you know, there's no really bad stuff going on.
Scott: What's gonna happen?
Scott: the police will show up and they'll say we were called we showed up and there's nothing illegal happening here.
Rym: So Scott just calls the police and he says exactly what's going on.
Scott: The 911 guy was smart and cool.
Scott: He was easy to talk to go 911 guy.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So we were debating, you know, hey Let's stick around and watch because we're pretty much the catalyst here.
Scott: Well, I asked the 911 guy if I should stay or if I should go home and he's like well Do you want to give a statement to the police?
Scott: and I'm like, I'll leave him.
Rym: Yeah, the situation is pretty self-evident.
Rym: I don't want to be involved.
Scott: I called the police can sort it out.
Scott: There's a scene in the parking lot, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, so as we start to leave because we have the show to do and all that other business and we're talking to each other Well, I wonder how long it'll take the police to get.
Scott: and then sure enough the police were there before we got out of the Parking lot.
Rym: In fact the second the third police car See, here's.
Rym: here's what makes this interesting because as we're driving out first Scott has to go off this road and we see a cop car go by like right away.
Rym: We're like, alright, it's handled.
Scott: and then another cop car goes right away and we're like, okay There's two cops which is which makes sense for a situation that might have be violent.
Rym: Yeah, I mean a lot of places.
Rym: if there's domestic violence or anything like that They always send to patrol cars if they can yeah.
Scott: Plus if there's a fight if there's any sort of fight at all is always two people's.
Scott: you need two cops one to stop Each person.
Rym: so then Scott's about to leave the parking lot and then he has the green light But he has to stop because the state trooper flies by and by calling the police we'd effectively delayed ourselves another.
Scott: I know.
Scott: why did a state trooper come to what is a local thing?
Scott: It's kind of weird.
Rym: Oh, probably because called 911 as opposed to the local police.
Rym: Yeah Which that's starting to be a problem in the u.s.
Rym: Where I often run into situations where I might need to call the local police, but it's not an emergency.
Rym: I don't need to call 9-1-1 some areas.
Scott: They have the special number.
Rym: Well in some areas they say call 9-1-1 for everything.
Scott: Uh-huh fact in a lot of areas Where I live but like in New Jersey like where my grandma lives they added another number.
Scott: It's like 311 or something like that.
Scott: I don't remember, but if it's not an emergency like someone's dying someone's murdered This is a robbery and going on as a violence going on right now.
Scott: You call that number and a police just shows up at your door like hey, how's it going?
Rym: Yep, or I remember when we were leaving for somewhere and we saw this shady looking contractor guy Basically shoving the clippings.
Rym: He had cut off of trees down the sewer.
Rym: So I called the local beacon police reported his license plate number.
Rym: I don't know what ever happened with that.
Rym: Yeah, but so I finally we get back on the road and we're driving home and we start debating Well, I wonder what's gonna happen and we figure no matter what everything's gonna be okay because the police are right there.
Rym: So even if the worst-case scenario this guy goes nuts and like does something horrible the police are right there.
Rym: It's gonna get resolved.
Rym: Yep, but then we start wondering You know that guy seemed a little bit Unstable one of those the kind of person who would be involved in a domestic dispute where the police were called.
Scott: Anyway, yep And my bet is that if if we had left and just not called the police There was a 50% chance He would do something later didn't look like anything illegal or bad was gonna happen right then but later something probably would have happened.
Scott: But by calling the police I think the police might have their presence might have caused that crazy guy to do something.
Rym: because the guy It's just like those guys if you watch any of those old Fox shows about people interacting with police when they're on the wrong side of the law.
Rym: and The guy definitely was one of those people who if the police show up, he'd probably fly off the handle.
Rym: So we're debating.
Rym: I wonder if we basically set this guy up to get beat down by the police.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like entrapment in a way Like if the police didn't show up he would have just done his normal thing.
Scott: But now there's a policeman staying there.
Scott: He goes crazy and because the police are there He does something stupid.
Rym: So we decide that even if that happens that's a good thing because that means he was gonna blow up sometime.
Rym: Anyway, now the police are gonna take care of it before he does something bad.
Scott: Yeah, we don't know what happened though Cuz.
Rym: however right after we're having this debate Another state trooper goes by like a few minutes later toward the scene.
Rym: So I think he could.
Scott: he could have been going somewhere else, but I doubt it.
Rym: I would my guess.
Rym: my bet is that the state trooper went because it was a 9-1-1 call.
Rym: the two fish kill police went because Fishkill has more police than it does people And two obviously a dangerous situation.
Rym: but the second Significantly later state trooper leads me to believe that the situation escalated and I can't wait to read the local paper.
Scott: Yeah, because by the time we saw that final state trooper We had been on the road for a couple minutes and after a couple minutes those cops should have figured out if it was The situation that where they could just say all right everyone don't bother coming here.
Scott: Yeah, it's all right.
Rym: We also observed that in the last year or two The two of us specifically me have called the police more times than we have in the rest of our lives combined.
Scott: Well, I think I figured out.
Scott: the answer to that is because for most of our lives who were in school And when you sit in school all day, you tend not to see a lot of things that require police calling, you know I mean at RIT most things you just call campus safety or whatever.
Scott: and in high school if there was any police calling the school Did it.
Scott: you didn't really need to call police while you're in school and not too many illegal things happened in our suburban schools.
Scott: Anyway, you know our white bread fools.
Rym: So anyway after 10 minutes of that it is anime manga comics day.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I'll be quick on this because I kind of want to spend Talk about this.
Rym: Well, we've already talked about this issue that Bandai visual is releasing well co-releasing DVDs in both America and the US and charging Absolutely crazy stupid amounts of money for these DVDs.
Rym: Yep I mean, they're basically charging Americans what they charge the Japanese which I guess kind of works in Japan But that doesn't fly in America.
Rym: No one's gonna spend 40 or 50 dollars on a DVD that has one or two episodes of content and no dub.
Scott: Well at Sakura Con the anime convention in Seattle a fan of well I guess an anime fan.
Rym: They there was a Bandai visual panel and the CEO of Bandai visual Tatsu nori kono was there and he did his little presentation and then he was about to end that and show a bunch of trailers for upcoming shows and some fan kind of politely interrupted him and basically asked him what the hell they're thinking but in a very polite manner and He seemed kind of taken aback by this and he gave this the most stupid lame Corporate.
Scott: Well, what could he possibly say?
Scott: All right, so you're you're the Bandai visual CEO and I say why the fuck is freedom?
Scott: 40 goddamn dollars.
Scott: No one's gonna buy it.
Scott: What are you thinking?
Scott: And what do you say?
Rym: Well, what he actually said was something along the lines of anime is becoming more expensive to produce That's true and we're releasing it in two places at once.
Scott: They are releasing it here at the same time as they're really seeing it in Japan, which is something no one else is doing.
Rym: Simultaneous release everybody and he didn't really say much more substantial than that.
Rym: so a bunch of other fans started agreeing with the person who had brought this up and They never really got an answer out of the guy other than the corporate cheese.
Scott: At least now we know that these guys aren't totally oblivious.
Scott: They know that there are people in America who say nobody pays that much for a DVD in America.
Scott: The thing is I get the feeling from reading this article.
Scott: I mean I wasn't there.
Scott: So what do I know?
Rym: There's a recording but it was god-awful and I just couldn't listen.
Scott: I couldn't listen to that recording but I get the feeling that it was lost in translation Like they didn't drive the point home like no really, dude You don't understand.
Scott: people in America are used to paying $20 for like a whole season of a TV.
Rym: It looks like some nobody's gonna buy this.
Rym: It looks like someone's did say pretty much straight up to him that DVDs in America are a lot cheaper than that.
Rym: People aren't going to buy them.
Rym: But he just kept saying the same lame answer over and over again as far as I don't think he really like.
Scott: Got a grasp of it sort of like.
Scott: well, here's.
Rym: here's a quote.
Rym: This is paraphrased in the anime news network article from the audio from him.
Rym: So we are thinking that you guys should get the same products as Japan at the same time.
Rym: So the price will be the same.
Scott: Yeah Good luck with that.
Scott: Yeah, anyway yeah, someone should also tell him that he's ripping off the Japanese people and that you're lucky that Japanese people are.
Scott: so I Don't know that there are so many Japanese people willing to pay that much money cuz they're crazy I don't know.
Rym: Well considering that there has apparently been an ever-increasing problem of re-importation Yeah, I wonder why huh?
Scott: Maybe because it's 40 bucks an episode.
Rym: or you can look on the internet and not only get all your fan subs for free If you're that kind of person even in Japan.
Rym: hell if you're in Japan just watch the Ross But buy the American DVD.
Rym: it's in Japanese.
Scott: Why buy the jet?
Scott: the worst part?
Scott: Is that these DVDs that they're selling at the simultaneous release that are overpriced don't have dubs Which I really don't mind personally, but shouldn't that mean it's cheaper because you didn't have to dub it?
Scott: Hello, it makes no sense.
Scott: I Really wish I spoke Japanese and was there and I could maybe all right anyone who goes to an anime convention this year If there's a bandai visual panel go and confront them.
Scott: go and do it.
Scott: And if we keep doing it at every single bandai panel at every single con We can really.
Scott: maybe we can make a move on this.
Scott: Maybe they'll realize that we want the Simultaneous release subtitles only at the right price.
Rym: Well, it looks like some reporter for anime news network who was there said quote no one was ever rude to Kono-san.
Rym: However, it was clear from Kono-san's expression and gestures that he was quite surprised by the intensity of feelings toward bandai visuals marketing decisions, huh.
Rym: So I get the impression that he might not have really gathered exactly what the beef was or why people were so angry But he obviously realized that for some reason these Americans are really worked up about something.
Scott: All right You know what that guy is at the top of the list for people to get like a private Interview with at some con if he's ever there.
Scott: like if we can sit down with him in a translator I think we can get him to realize like oh Take him to the dealer's room.
Scott: be like you see that.
Scott: Yeah You're not gonna sell against that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: It doesn't matter how good your show is Even though I'd like it more than every other show here.
Scott: It's not that much money All right, so, you know studio four degrees C.
Rym: They might do.
Scott: indeed They making all the awesome cool a nimes for us to enjoy a nimes.
Scott: Yep, a nimes.
Scott: They're coming out with something new called genius party.
Scott: now Genius party is a very apt name for what they're coming out with.
Rym: they're getting awesome directors to make awesome shorts.
Scott: basically, they're gonna make another movie that just like the one they made before.
Scott: that I forget the name of that is a combination of short movies and The thing is it's a genius party.
Scott: everyone who's making these short movies aren't you know, just people who work for studio four degrees C. They are getting the best animators in Japan to make Shorts and then they're gonna combine them all.
Scott: this might be better than memories.
Scott: I think I don't know.
Rym: I really like 1.5 of the memories babe.
Scott: I know that's why it's gonna be better than that credit.
Rym: I think I disagree with Dave and Joel a little bit cuz.
Rym: I actually really like the last one.
Scott: I like all of them at least a little.
Scott: I don't hate any of them.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: the magnetic rose is a thousand times better than the other ones.
Scott: Well, of course who did it?
Scott: who was responsible for magnetic rose?
Rym: What was his name?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: probably my favorite man in the world other than possibly King Leonidas.
Scott: Okay, so Yes.
Scott: So here's some of the geniuses they have working on this genius party writing The.
Scott: I'm just gonna say what they do instead of saying their Japanese names whatever.
Scott: the animator for Akira The eska flow named Matt cross guy the steam boy tech on King Creek guy the author of the Don Giovanni manga Which I really want to read.
Scott: I also want to read that Jojo's Bizarre Adventure and a matrix guy Jojo's the mind game person and the samurai Champloo cowboy bebop guy.
Scott: and Of course the samurai champloo cowboy bebop guy whose name is Shinichiro Watanabe.
Scott: for anyone who didn't know that He's going to get all his musical friends including a whole bunch of awesome people in yokokana Yes, pretty much.
Rym: Scott says, you know He's getting they're getting to do the music and I said yokokano and he sets their name in all the people who aren't yokokano.
Rym: And then he says and yokokano.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So this is gonna come out in Japanese theaters Soonish I guess in the summer maybe and I Imagine it'll be in America.
Scott: Oh never.
Scott: and then there's gonna be a second one possibly in early 2008.
Scott: So look forward to this in the torrents because you're not gonna get a DVD not even at $40.
Rym: Now one more a little bit before we move on to the things of the day.
Rym: But ConnectiCon which is a generally fun anime web comics gaming convention in Hartford, Connecticut.
Scott: We did an episode on it last year when we went for just Saturday.
Rym: Yep, but ConnectiCon has one leg up.
Rym: I mean it was a good con.
Rym: We had a good time.
Rym: We covered it a while ago if you want to hear about that.
Rym: But in terms of dealing with cons and talking to cons and doing stuff at cons ConnectiCon has gotten back with me and worked with me more quickly more readily and more Coherently and confidently than just about any convention I've ever dealt with.
Rym: good These people are on top of their game this year.
Scott: Yeah I mean other conventions.
Scott: you go to them.
Scott: we went to ConnectiCon in our episode with didn't speak of it in the most glowing Terms.
Rym: it wasn't the best convention ever but it was by no means a bad convention.
Scott: No, no, no Great German board game and that's for sure.
Scott: But you know, we go to lots of conventions and some conventions are awesome and some are not so awesome.
Scott: But it seems like even the most awesome cons like Otakon.
Scott: if you email Otakon or a staff member at Otakon that you need To know something from or you want to ask them a question or tell them something.
Scott: They just don't email you back.
Rym: Yeah, it's not just Otakon.
Rym: I can say this about just about every con I've ever contacted for anything even when I before GeekNights.
Scott: other stuff Yeah But this is a note to anyone who ever runs a convention or anything.
Scott: check the goddamn email and reply Everything.
Scott: if you're not you're doing it wrong.
Rym: Yep, so I'm still hashing out the details with the people at ConnectiCon but it looks like Rym and Scott of GeekNights.
Rym: You know the two of us plus probably a few other expert panelists and hopefully a bunch of guests from the con.
Rym: We'll be doing a whole holy ton of programming this year.
Rym: So if you want to see us live come to ConnectiCon July 13 through 15 2007 at the Connecticut Convention Center in Hartford, Connecticut Connecticut Connecticut Hartford, yes, the only con that actually emails you back regardless of how awesome their convention is.
Rym: I mean, we're gonna be running the stuff.
Scott: We always run Is even if this convention falls apart Which I don't know as long as they still have that Convention Center rented on those days We'll still show up and do all the awesome stuff.
Rym: if there's the apocalypse of the world We'll be in the crater that remains of the parking lot running challenger on fire.
Scott: No, he won't.
Scott: We're gonna be doing the things that we need to do.
Scott: when there's an apocalypse of the world.
Rym: It'll be a much more literal challenger on fire in that case.
Rym: But yeah in addition to the stuff we normally do with cons They're letting us most likely try out a couple of new things that we put together But we haven't actually run at a con or an event ever.
Scott: Yes, so to experience the Experimental convention panel event games you should come.
Scott: Yes the first still be the first time ever.
Scott: So when we're running this thing like pros at like Otakon 2020, you can say I was there ConnectiCon 2007 when they first ran this thing.
Scott: Oh, it was better.
Rym: in old days I had an onion on my belt, which was the style of the time understand things of the day.
Rym: So I have a slight fascination with hearing foreign people Doing that mocking English accent or that mocking American accent much in the vein of when we do a mocking any other accent.
Rym: Oh, I'm speaking to frown.
Scott: Oh Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I know what it sounds like when an English person tries to make noises in another language like it's sort of weird, but languages have sounds to them like French sounds like these home, but the Italians At least as far as Kramer is concerned.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like it's not.
Scott: it's not a stereotype or a racism or anything like that.
Scott: It's like that's really usually but that's really what it sounds like when I hear those kind of people talking.
Rym: Well more it's just.
Rym: I love hearing other people making fun of an American accent.
Rym: this started with movies.
Rym: you should see when one of them was making fun of one of the other ones for saying I think Z instead of Z. and This whole thing is like so what now?
Rym: you're gonna have your Z's and then you're gonna drive your car To the store and buy pants and then go on a vacation.
Rym: Yeah to the hospital.
Scott: It's like it was to hear British people We usually speak British English saying English American English.
Scott: it was like, whoa, that's hilarious.
Scott: So I really just want to hear lots of people who from all around the world Pretending to speak English.
Rym: So luckily.
Rym: I'm not the only person to have this idea and this is kind of a new thing.
Rym: We'll see if there's more responses to it.
Rym: But someone posted on YouTube a video where he does a whole bunch of the fake Sounding French and the fake Spanish and the fake Russian and some are pretty good.
Scott: Pretty good job with that fake Russian.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well you say a lot of yet Nesvits dasvid on yachts ski.
Rym: Yeah and He's basically calling out the world and saying hey I want you guys to record either yourselves or other people Faking English the way I faked all these languages because I like that sort of thing and he's gotten some responses.
Rym: I'm waiting for some more.
Rym: but just follow the whole cluster of YouTube videos here and is generally interesting.
Rym: Also if anyone sends me quality audio of any foreigner as in not a United States native Making fun of United States accents.
Rym: I'll send you a prize.
Scott: What prize II innocent?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'll send him something anyway.
Scott: So remember I said we were gonna learn the Hari dance because we have to learn all the anime dances.
Rym: Well, we got until Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, how much have you learned of it so far?
Rym: Uh, I Know parts of dances that may or may not have originated in Japan.
Scott: We haven't started Jack or shit.
Scott: We don't know even the first step.
Rym: So I have the mirrored video to watch.
Rym: I just haven't watched it Lately, yeah at all more than once.
Rym: Okay to make sure it was actually married.
Rym: Yeah I can't deal with that non mirrored crap.
Rym: We played para para.
Scott: If you need to learn a dance, you need a mirrored video or else it is going to just wreck your brain.
Rym: Yeah, granted if you learn how to deal with non mirrored video you're probably better off because that's a valuable skill.
Rym: but Modern technology you can just flip the video.
Scott: Yes, so Yeah, we haven't learned that yet, but I'm beginning to give up because we have been bested.
Scott: We have been bested a thousand times by of course the nation of Japan.
Scott: Yes Here is a video for you to watch of a flash mob a bunch of Japanese otaku.
Scott: These people are definitely otaku in the Japanese sense of the word converging on a street suddenly and then doing the Haruhi dance in More unison than you will ever see anywhere else.
Scott: There's a lot of these people.
Scott: This is at least a hundred people there.
Rym: This flash mob was better produced than probably the best of the best of the best cosplay skit I've ever seen at an American anime con.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: and Then something funny happens.
Scott: So watch to the end.
Scott: Of course if you read the words on the web page I'm linking you to it's gonna be given away But it's pretty funny to actually see it happen.
Scott: I don't want to ruin what happens at the end But I left.
Rym: so the show we were about to talk about tonight is One that is very near and dear to the hearts of everyone who is cool in the world.
Scott: Well, anyone who watched anime on the sci-fi channel in the late 90s is all about this show.
Scott: Yes, everyone else probably doesn't know about this show at all.
Rym: Yes now apparently also Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentleman reviewed this Before us partly because due to the fact that I hadn't bothered to show Scott the second half of it Back when we planned on doing it.
Rym: We pushed it off for like a month.
Scott: I didn't have.
Scott: the DVD was scratched and we watched goes in the shell instead.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah speaking of ghost in the shell Dominion tank police is based on a manga called Dominion by Masamune Shiro, who is the guy who made ghost in the shell.
Rym: however, I'm not gonna talk about that tonight mostly because the manga is Effectively completely different from the OA.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I've ordered the manga.
Scott: I've never read it.
Scott: I've ever.
Scott: I do want to point out one thing The manga is originally just called Dominion and in Japan the show was just called Dominion.
Scott: Of course in America We call it Dominion tank police because well, that's that's what it is, but I realized something very recently It's Dominion tank police by Masamune.
Scott: Shiro ghost in the shell is really also tank police.
Rym: Think about what kinds of things Shiro writes.
Scott: He likes tanks and he likes police.
Scott: Yeah apple seed in a way is also tank or mech police at least.
Rym: No, see, here's the difference between the manga and the anime and then we'll leave it at that.
Rym: Dominion tank police the OAV is.
Rym: You can be described in two words collateral damage Or all possibly dancing cat girls Cat girl damage.
Rym: Yeah Meanwhile dancing collateral perspective The tanks in Dominion tank police.
Scott: I just I just can't get the picture out of my head of a guy like signing over his car is collateral and he's dancing dancing car anyway.
Rym: Okay The manga is in a way more coherent serious together and plot II than the anime.
Rym: to put it Lightly, I would almost go so far as to say that the two are almost completely unrelated except in name.
Scott: It's one of those things where sort of like the Akira manga goes into incredible detail.
Scott: There's a billion characters and there's a whole world and a whole big story and the Akira movie is just part of it.
Rym: Well, I think what the one big thing is that in the manga the tank police and what they do and the tanks they use Make sense, they would probably at least nominally Actually function in the way there to intended the tanks in the OAV Dominion tank police.
Rym: Well, I'm just gonna play something.
Rym: that is basically a conversation between the chief of the tank police and the mayor of Newport City Where tank police takes place.
Rym: and if you don't have an idea of what this show is about after this then There's no hope.
Rym: Why in hell does our police department have to carry enough firepower to wipe out the city's population five times over?
Rym: The police are here to protect the people's rights and property not to threaten them.
Rym: When innocent lives are sacrificed in the name of crime prevention the police are no better than the hoodlums They're fighting against.
Rym: madam mayor.
Rym: You should have said that to the council years ago when they set up the tank police.
Rym: It's worth remembering that the percentage of civilians killed or injured and tank related incidents is a mere 5% of incidents related to traffic Accidents or bacterial poisoning.
Rym: what's more the crime rate is dropped 20% since we started using tanks.
Rym: I think the police should be commended 5% and you're proud of that.
Rym: that kind of attitude could cost us our jobs.
Rym: I don't think you've had any idea how easily the voters could kick us right out of office.
Rym: I know that the voters are happy to see muggers and rapists get their asses shut off.
Rym: make up your mind.
Rym: Do you want to give in to a few fairy pinkos or keep little old ladies safe on the streets?
Rym: You have a duty to everyone and that includes rapists murderers and fairy pinkos.
Rym: Don't give me the same crap you feed the press.
Rym: the thing you really care about is getting reelected.
Rym: You can't cut out cancer without spilling a little blood.
Rym: Would you tell a surgeon to go ahead and operate and then order him to stop while the patient or in our case the city?
Rym: die slowly and painfully of the tumor taking over its guts?
Rym: I Am not ordering the surgery to stop.
Rym: sure you are you can't take the heat in the kitchen.
Rym: I'm simply ordering you to stop doing the operation with a black chainsaw chainsaw.
Rym: a Surgeon operates with a scalper which he takes good care to sterilize to prevent unnecessary infection.
Rym: if he uses a tank the patient tends to die.
Rym: I Resent that.
Rym: it was you politicians who gave us surgeons those tanks in the first place.
Rym: besides these days tanks are about as effective as toothpicks.
Rym: Thanks Well, if tanks are no better than toothpicks, what would you consider is appropriate equipment for the police to use in prevention car?
Rym: I'm glad you asked me that I wouldn't mind replacing our guns with tactical nuclear weapons.
Rym: Nuclear weapons.
Rym: Nuclear weapons can stop war.
Rym: if they have done they should be able to stop criminals though.
Rym: I'm a pessimist.
Rym: I don't think we'll ever get rid of crime completely.
Rym: See you cannot be serious deadly serious.
Rym: There was people like you who gave us the tanks and told us to fight the bad guys.
Rym: I can argue about whether the law that set us up was a good one or not But the law is the law and now we're here.
Rym: We're right at the sharp end of the fight against crime And if you want law and order I've only got one thing to say if you want us to sap them give us more tanks.
Rym: Don't you understand?
Rym: This is war and my tank police are at the front line.
Rym: For you see the only way to stop crime or at least to prevent crime from getting worse is to have tanks bigger than Buildings destroying the city every time anything happened.
Scott: Oh, then why do we call the regular police just now?
Scott: That was pretty dumb.
Scott: We should have been calling the tanks.
Rym: See I get the impression that no one actually wants to call the tank police.
Scott: Well judging by the fact that what there's a crime and a super emergency in the city every 36 seconds or whatever and The tank police spend most of the day sitting around and when they actually roll out It's this huge event that basically just guaranteed to destroy a building
Rym: Well, the idea they actually talk about in the show is that the tank police don't exist to actually do anything.
Rym: They exist solely as a deterrent to hope that crime doesn't go to one every 35 seconds.
Rym: In fact, they say that pretty much straight up.
Scott: No, they do.
Scott: they say exactly that in the show.
Rym: Yes but before we continued tank police is actually directed by two people.
Rym: because you see first there were the OAVs which Theoretically, there are four different episodes but each set of two episodes is basically just a movie and all of them together come on one DVD and Most people when they say tank police they mean these two things or these four episodes all mashed together.
Rym: But the first half was directed by my man one of my favorite directors Koichi Mashimo.
Rym: Mashimo Mashimo Who you might remember from such classic says well, maybe I shouldn't say classics because noir and doc head dot hack We're not good, but he also did dirty pair project Eden and one of my favorite shows ever irresponsible captain Tyler.
Rym: Yeah, it's Rym show right there and I gotta say I do like the first half of Dominion tank police a lot more.
Rym: It's much more Silly humor tanks blowing stuff up and a lot of little subtle jokes in the background and all that sort of fun stuff.
Scott: Yeah, the first half definitely is better I think mostly because it concentrates more on the tank police than the second half.
Scott: does I mean you watch the first half of the second half and The tank police are barely in it and when they are in it some of its reused footage from the first movie?
Scott: Well first two episodes of the OAV.
Scott: So yeah.
Scott: Anyway, the second half was directed by another guy Takaki Ishiyama who is basically looking at his resume and I'm gonna go down the list cuz that's just why waste your time.
Scott: He's basically the storyboard master.
Scott: He did storyboards on a lot of things.
Scott: You've heard of pretty much all sorts of awesome shit.
Scott: But he directed one very important thing that some other people don't like.
Scott: that I do like and that thing is kitchen core.
Rym: to this day.
Rym: I still haven't actually watched kitchen core.
Scott: really Kitchen core is a short OAV.
Scott: It's a few episodes of steampunk Nazi alien robot action and I Quite enjoy it.
Scott: It's not the best thing ever, but it's pretty awesome and it's worth your time, especially since it's so goddamn cheap.
Rym: It's called Geo armor that in the America But it's kitchen core now despite the fact that Dominion tank police was made in the late 80s.
Scott: Wow, that's old.
Scott: Yeah, it looks really good than ten years old when they made this.
Rym: It looks really good comparatively as I mean even compared to modern stuff.
Rym: I think it holds its own.
Rym: It definitely has an older style in some ways But it doesn't show its age as much as a lot of other shows that came out in the late 80s.
Scott: Oh, no, it has the sort of like faded coloring of old animation technology.
Scott: But it has the decent enough, you know, the good drawings everything smooth.
Scott: There's not a lot of like glitches in the animation or any and no one is drawn stupidly or anything.
Scott: The character designs are pretty nice You know, it really it won't strike you.
Scott: you'll see it and you'll say wow, that's old but you won't.
Scott: it doesn't.
Scott: It doesn't have an older style has the modern anime style that is not irritating.
Rym: Well, actually I really really like the character designs I think that each character is distinct in a good old-school kind of way and while Pretty much every character in the show is in some way or another a straight-up Stereotype or pretty much all of them.
Rym: This guy is the angry chief.
Rym: This guy is the chaplain who likes hand grenades.
Scott: This guy is the badass commander.
Scott: This guy is the the dopey comic bad guy, but not really the bad guy.
Scott: This guy is the evil bad guy with no motive.
Scott: He's just evil.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: but the plot of Dominion Tank Police is actually fairly simple because while there is this kind of overarching plot over the four episodes and They always keep hinting at the setting and the background and sinister things to come and all this business While that's addressed in the manga in the show It's basically just background especially for the first two episodes Which are pretty much just the story of this gang of criminals is up to criminal mischief Stealing urine from a hospital.
Rym: Yeah, and the tank police are called in.
Rym: actually There's a great scene Where they bust in and the normal police show up and the normal police just marching with guns like that.
Rym: We're gonna stop them and the cat girl takes one look at him fires off a couple of rounds and the police Immediately run away and then the tank police.
Scott: Wow Maybe they wouldn't need tank police if the regular police didn't suck and weren't complete wusses.
Rym: See, I have a feeling that the regular police are just fine as long as it's not cat girls wielding machine guns.
Scott: Hey, you know we had.
Scott: we don't have tank police in the modern world today.
Scott: And if there's you know badasses with machine guns, they call the SWAT team.
Scott: They don't call the tank police.
Scott: You'll never see tanks go in to stop a bank robbery.
Rym: Well, I think part of that is that this is a comedy and it's not supposed to be serious at all.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: the second half gets way Serious, and if you are just looking for humor the second half is worth watching.
Rym: But it's very much different from the first half in that it kind of ties together a lot of these background Plot elements that were brought in in the first half but not really actually explained.
Rym: they like they keep touching on this whole idea about a bacterial cloud and people who are perfectly healthy and this project designed to study human souls or to create a being that could somehow get rid of the bacterial cloud or live within the Bacterial cloud.
Rym: and there's this whole deep setting the kind of setting that Shiro just seems to love.
Rym: But it's really all just background because the actual story here Is that the Dominion tank police are a group of ruffians and thugs who are barely better than the criminals.
Rym: They're fighting That in one scene in the second half.
Rym: there there's an emergency call at Sotheby's Which is full of billions and billions of dollars of priceless art artifacts and heirlooms.
Rym: The only way he can really convince the tank police to go respond because they don't even want to respond.
Rym: They want to just sit around and continue interrogating suspects.
Rym: Interrogation by the way generally involves hanging upside down with a grenade in their mouths and Throwing knives at them until they confess to whatever crimes they're looking to get confessions for that day.
Scott: The interrogation parts is like this sort of this ongoing joke if you can consider it something in an OAV Ongoing and that it happens two times.
Rym: Yes It's hilarious the first time and it's even more hilarious the second time.
Scott: Yes If they had kept going with this I would have been very interested to see how they would take the interrogation scenes a step up Because I don't really think it could go anywhere else.
Rym: Yeah I mean even in the first one.
Rym: they get a little elaborate with these grenades.
Rym: Speaking scientifically the bucket falls over when it's hit by a ball The string is pulled tight pulling the pin out of the grenade stuffed in the suspects mouth, which leads to certain results.
Rym: But the only way he could they convinced the tank police to actually respond to a call for help is to point out that the place they're going to help is full of Priceless artifacts
Scott: and the tank police seem to get off on the idea that they're going to destroy all these priceless.
Rym: Not only that but half of them seemed more interested in looting the museum than actually fighting any crime.
Rym: The best part is they show up and there's some sort of firefight going on inside and instead of responding They just have a ring of tanks around the museum and they're cheering and yelling and eating rice and ramen and having a party.
Scott: Yeah, the tank police is sort of like these group of guys who are just really awesome and they have this great camaraderie.
Scott: There's not a lot of infighting except with the chief.
Scott: In fact,
Rym: I would go so far as to say that the way they all are together is kind of like here is Greenwood in that It's this adversarial but at the same time Almost Spartan Brotherhood of friends, you know like the group of gay the gang of kids who gets into mischief together.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they're all like.
Scott: yeah, let's all go screw shit up.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: yeah,
Rym: I love when they actually get a call because they all the tanks have those dit-dit-dit-dit-dah kind of horns, huh, and Basically, the whole crew comes down and yeah, let's go And the tanks tear out into the street
Scott: also tear the street tearing up the street apart into bits.
Rym: They pretty much destroy the city if they're ever actually deployed for anything.
Scott: I think that's sort of the point.
Rym: Yes, the thing is there's been a lot of shows in the past that try to pull this.
Rym: oh no collateral damage over the top.
Rym: Oh, look, they blew up the building and now the Chiefs yelling at him.
Rym: But I think there's this level of campiness and this kind of tongue-in-cheek Way of going about that that makes tank police a lot more charming and in the end actually funny as opposed to a lot of shows like that that just come off stupid and A lot of the humor are Little things people say are little background thing.
Rym: Like there's one scene where one of the main characters who happens to be a Goyle.
Scott: So what can the tank police do for you?
Rym: Sir officer Leonio Zaki transferred to the tank police from the city motorcycle headquarters unit Who has been transferred to the tank police.
Rym: she ends up getting Really Really attached to her tank.
Scott: you see yeah you watch a lot of shows these days and like Pat LeBour has the girl who really likes a robot and You'll all you'll see like these girl characters who are really attached to something like a pet or something And this one was the first one that I ever saw that had that.
Scott: so anytime a show came Afterwards at least in terms of the order in which I saw them where there was a main girl character who's really attached to something I was like, oh they're copying tank police.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Plus.
Rym: I mean all the people.
Rym: all the tank police are like that.
Rym: I mean the one captain Britain who all I'll really say that he's exactly Exactly.
Rym: He looks like him.
Rym: He sounds like him.
Rym: He acts like him.
Rym: He's just like my high school band teacher.
Scott: Well, go kick is people listening?
Rym: know your high school, but I'm just saying my high school band teacher was exactly like this guy The kind of guy who sits there reading a magazine obviously a periodical.
Scott: That's the kind of funny joke you see in tank police is there'll be a guy sitting there reading a magazine.
Rym: The magazine is titled how to kill and he is reading it very seriously and obviously is taking pointers from it.
Rym: He threatens to shoot people's asses off a lot at least in the dumb.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's just the way it's translated.
Scott: I don't know what he's actually saying.
Rym: Well, we'll talk about the dub and the sub and all that in a bit because there were actually a lot of changes.
Rym: But the girl gets really attached to her tank
Scott: and there's
Rym: one little scene where Somehow a grenade goes off in the hangar where all the tanks are somehow
Scott: somehow gee I never thought that would happen where there's you know A hangar full of tanks and troublemakers and all sorts of grenades
Rym: and then one of them goes off and it scratches her tank.
Rym: So she's runs over and she's freaking out about it and she steps on some guy who was knocked out by the blast.
Rym: So there's this whole scene where she's yelling about the tank and all this stuff's going on.
Rym: But in the background the guy she stepped on like gets up and he's like, ah And then she spins around and hits him again by accident and he falls down.
Rym: It's like ah.
Rym: and then she kicks him and then he gets up.
Rym: He's like, yeah, and he goes to like punch her or something and she accidentally knocks him out again and eventually he's just standing there behind her with a gun and he's about to kill her.
Rym: and There's a lot a little background humor like that in this whole show.
Scott: Well, I think around that time There's a funny joke where she's about to shoot someone and kill them for real and the Jesus II guy comes up and he's like Wait a second.
Scott: What's more valuable a tank or a human life?
Scott: And she's like a tank and it's the Jesus guys you expect him to be like, huh freak out, but he says oh Thank you.
Scott: She's finally become a true member of the tank police.
Scott: The Jesus guy is so great because usually a Jesus character is annoying because they're all preaching their Jesus.
Scott: He crap all over everybody, but this guy He preaches the Jesus II stuff, but he's really just like all the other tank police.
Rym: I believe a relevant quote is in order.
Rym: pay heed to the words of my brother for it is better to name thy Accomplices and have them with thee in prison than to die by grenade now in the manga as far as I remember There's a lot more because there's also a sciency guy on the tank police and he's the one who basically explains to all the idiots What's going on?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: He's a stereotypical nerd character.
Rym: Yeah, kind of like Egon from the real Ghostbusters or Professor Frank.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah pretty much and He's an atheist and pretty much.
Rym: him and the chaplain are obviously friends But they they like to dig at each other just a little bit.
Rym: I don't think that really comes out in the show But you can see how there would be a lot of humor potential there.
Rym: now You might notice we've been fairly vague as to what actually happens in tank police other than a few choice bitch.
Scott: Oh, you don't want to spoil it.
Scott: We want people to watch it.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is it's not like a TV show.
Rym: It's a four episode OAV.
Scott: Those are kind of long though.
Rym: Yeah, they are but if we talked about what happens any more than what we've already done.
Rym: We'd ruin a lot.
Rym: there's there's a moment late at late in the first half where an obstacle is placed before the tank police and is perhaps the Greatest obstacle ever presented to anyone in the history of anime.
Scott: Well, here's the thing is I own I didn't realize that obstacle was in the show when I saw it on the sci-fi channel Because it was cut out.
Scott: a lot of the show was cut out for America.
Scott: In fact the American dub version of this show Especially the one that was shown on sci-fi channel is so different from the original yet somehow it didn't actually ruin it.
Scott: It's sort of weird.
Scott: Usually when someone edits a show for release in America and cuts out a lot of things or dubs it poorly or Changes music or anything like that Inevitably makes the show worse.
Scott: example initial D. Ah Yes This seems to be what a weird case where they must have been trying really hard because the American release of tank police changed a lot Of stuff yet.
Scott: It was different but still good.
Rym: There are basically three cuts of this out there.
Rym: first There's the Japanese version which is uncut Japanese whatever.
Rym: it's exactly what they made.
Rym: then there's the American dub Which I stand by as being really really good and really really funny.
Scott: I think I'm not saying it's a bad dub It's a good dub.
Scott: It is also humorous.
Scott: However, I think rims opinion of it is boosted by nostalgia.
Rym: See, I doubt that highly because I saw tank police right around when I saw a whole bunch of other anime And I saw the dubs of all those two and all those dubs are piss-poor, but did you like those shows?
Scott: Yes I love them.
Rym: vampire hunter D is awesome to me and I really love that movie.
Rym: However, the dub was pretty piss-poor.
Scott: Well, the dub of tank police is good, but I'm not saying it's as great as as you seem to think it is.
Rym: I think it's really good.
Rym: I'd say it's in the top 10% of dubs ever made Name.
Rym: good dubs other than cowboy bebop and hell sing.
Rym: I Got to think of any tank police is really well done.
Rym: the voice they picked spot-on voice actors for all the characters.
Rym: I mean I think Lisa Ortez who did Lena inverse plays Leona the girl and the tank police and She pretty much pulls it off exactly like the Japanese voice actors does.
Rym: the guy playing Captain Britain is hilarious.
Rym: The two cat girls are done really really well in my opinion.
Scott: Yeah, they're okay.
Scott: I mean, it's obvious definitely a good dub.
Scott: if you like to watch dubs You will not be disappointed by this dub.
Scott: It is incredibly tolerable and very entertaining and not much is lost in the dubbing.
Rym: See, I don't know why you're so down on this stuff.
Rym: I mean the comedic timing is good.
Scott: I'm not down on it I'm just not a hunt.
Scott: It's like you're saying this dub is excellent.
Scott: and I'm saying the dub is like a good dub.
Scott: Well, and now you're saying why are you down on it?
Rym: Well, you know what it is.
Scott: you give it a plus and I give it an a-minus.
Scott: I'm not down on it.
Rym: if you rate it.
Rym: It's excellent because most anime dubs especially nowadays are piss-poor.
Rym: I would say that this dub is better than almost every dub that's been made in the last several years.
Scott: any dub That is tolerable is better than any dub that's made in the past several years.
Scott: So yes, that is true.
Rym: This is well above tolerable and I actually prefer watching it in English and I have seen it both in English and Japanese numerous times.
Scott: Yeah, I could go either way.
Scott: It doesn't really matter to me.
Rym: But aside from the dub being pretty good.
Rym: There's there's the sci-fi TV dub cut which is the same voice actors and mostly the same.
Rym: but aside from having cut out I think like some 15 or 20 minutes worth of footage and Cutting out one of the funnier moments in the show because they just couldn't show that on the sci-fi channel.
Scott: There's no way they could have shown that.
Rym: they also Removed all the explanation of what the plot was in the second half and it was when I was a kid.
Rym: I saw tank police and I thought it was hilarious, but I had no freaking idea What was going on at the end because they cut so much out.
Rym: It just didn't make any sense at all.
Scott: Yeah, there's basically a scene in which they explain in plain English or plain Japanese Exactly what the hell's going on because they don't have a whole manga where they can, you know, reveal it to you slowly and correctly.
Scott: So they just explain everything to you and then show you the end in a way so that you know what the hell's going on at the end at least as far as you were expected to know how it's going on.
Rym: and Luckily the the real dub on the DVDs also includes all that.
Rym: The only bad cut is the one they actually aired on the sci-fi channel.
Scott: Yes, you don't want to see the one that was on the sci-fi.
Rym: I have a tape of it somewhere.
Scott: Yes, I mean it might be entertaining to watch it and see what they cut out But it's it's.
Scott: you're not gonna get the effect of the show.
Scott: You'll just get you'll understand why we liked it from watching it on the sci-fi channel.
Rym: Yes, because one thing the sci-fi channel cut does have going for it Is that it's a much tighter edit because they did cut out a lot of long panning environmental ambiance scenes.
Rym: that if you take those out the show is much cleaner and there's better Transitions between all the humor and it feels like a tighter show.
Scott: The thing is I really like all the sorts of long panning environmental things.
Scott: That's why I like.
Scott: it's one of the reasons.
Scott: I like to anime in the first place.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: except in this show It's kind of half-and-half because on one hand it's a goofy comedy and yet on the other hand There's this serious dead serious backdrop for the comedy and there's also and I find this really interesting They changed a lot of the music in the dub pretty
Scott: almost all of it.
Rym: The thing is they didn't change all of it and it's hard to figure out.
Rym: I didn't actually do any research to figure out why or what rationale they might have had.
Rym: I don't know if there were licensing issues or if maybe they decided some songs would play better.
Scott: Maybe they had like the tracks for some of the songs, but not some of the other ones.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't do any research.
Rym: We're not anime world order here and I don't really care why but the fact remains that they changed a good bit of the music and I'm of the opinion that now not all of the changes are good.
Rym: no, no, but a few of the songs that they put in the English dub I say are better and fit the mood of the Show and fit the humor and fit the scenes a lot better than what was originally in the Japanese.
Scott: Yeah, unlike the aforementioned Initial D dub where all the music was changed to crap instead of eurobeat awesome.
Scott: Some of the music that they put in to the dub to replace the Japanese music was better Or than the Japanese music or at least I like it better.
Rym: whether it's like there's an opening scene I don't have a clip for this one where they're panning over the city and you're kind of getting the atmosphere of Alright, this is kind of a dystopian future.
Rym: The world's not so hot.
Rym: and on the English dub the music is this really kind of slow ominous grooving thing and it's definitely Early 90s synthesizer, but it's pretty well done and it really seems to fit the animation on the screen in Japanese it's a little more light-hearted and it really doesn't feel like it fits.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I kind of like both sense.
Scott: That's one of the changes where I think it's equal both ways.
Scott: Yeah, the American one isn't isn't bad and the Japanese one isn't bad.
Rym: I just think they both set very different moods for the show and I think both work.
Rym: I kind of prefer the dub one a little bit more, but I guess I like it a little bit darker Which is surprising considering that again, it's a comedy.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really prefer either one, but it's kind of surprising.
Scott: It's like hey, they replaced the music and they replaced it with different music.
Scott: That's just as good.
Scott: So who cares?
Rym: Yep No sometimes it seems obvious that they took out some music that might have sounded weird to an American who wasn't familiar with Japanese music or Anything and replaced it with I guess more Western sounding or easier to accept and understand or wouldn't stand out music
Scott: like 80s music.
Rym: but yet at the same time they left in a lot of very distinctly silly Japanese II songs that Work really well in the Japanese and they didn't get rid of him in the English.
Scott: I really wish I knew how they decided what to change and what not to and who they got to make this music and why And when.
Scott: and I would just be really interesting.
Rym: I'd really like to ask anime world order.
Rym: I'm sure they would know but I'm kind of afraid to send them another email.
Rym: Yeah, they might say You guys are your anti-tank guy anti-tank guy, but I think the most striking change in the music.
Rym: I'm just gonna have to play the two here and you can judge for yourself.
Rym: But here is the opening theme from the English dub.
Rym: We'll give it up.
Rym: Now.
Rym: not only is this awesome and I love this song this song is on my iPod right now.
Rym: I don't get to it on the way to work.
Rym: Oh, yeah Yeah, cuz I have an old.
Rym: don't ask why I got taped these a long time ago.
Rym: I eventually made him into mp3s when I got the front offer Kodak way back in the day.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway They made it specifically for the animated opener to tank police and it fits what's going on on the screen Exactly, and I think it's really good and I really like it.
Rym: and it sets the kind of over-the-top.
Rym: Yeah, it's about tank police.
Scott: Yeah, the English opening song with you know, take police.
Scott: It's pretty good I like it.
Scott: It's fun.
Scott: It's memorable.
Scott: Some of the lyrics are kind of a but whatever what lyrics it's tank police.
Rym: Feel the power that we've got.
Scott: feel the power that we've got is kind of corny.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: It's not that corny in music.
Rym: It's only corny if you say it without the music.
Scott: Yeah, it's still corny.
Scott: when you think anyway, you stop to think it's corny.
Rym: Here's the Japanese opener.
Scott: I Think to do with tank police.
Scott: it a lot of anime back then seemed to have these doo-doo random Mediocre j-pop openers.
Rym: that I don't know.
Rym: Maybe they just licensed the song because it was popular.
Scott: Well, I agree that hot dance and cherry moon has absolutely nothing to do with tank police.
Scott: So he's nothing that I know.
Scott: I kind of like that song.
Scott: It's a good song.
Rym: I know you like music like that.
Rym: I. I like music like that less than you, but I still like it.
Rym: But it really doesn't set the right mood for tank police and it doesn't match the opener at all.
Scott: I don't think it.
Scott: I don't think it does match the mood of the show.
Scott: That is correct, but I don't mind that.
Scott: I mean you could play either opener for me and I don't care.
Rym: there's also another music change.
Rym: that kind of stood out to me partly because I remember the song very well and I think part of that is because When I first saw tank police I was young and I was full of hormones and this Dave and Joel I Imagine would have talked about this.
Rym: I actually avoided listening to their show on tank police until I'm gonna listen to it tomorrow on the way to work.
Scott: They stole our idea and did a tank police show before us, but that we're not gonna let that get us down.
Scott: Yeah, if anything this will double emphasize to people that they should watch this show.
Rym: But there is a scene that I think is memorable because despite What the scene is actually about I think it was very well done and very comedic the cat girls.
Rym: You see there are cat girls in this show.
Scott: There are two girls Anna Puma and Una Puma and they're members of block whose criminal if anyone challenges you to name some Actual cat girls and you don't name these two you suck.
Scott: Yeah lose God.
Rym: Well, remember we ran the cut the anime match game at Katsucon and no one could name cat girls from anime at all.
Scott: Yeah, cuz yeah, they suck yet.
Rym: There's this stereotype.
Rym: Oh, yeah cat girls in anime, but no one can name any cat girls.
Scott: Well, here's some actual cat girls.
Rym: people don't miss out not gonna get into why they're cat girls.
Rym: It has to do with cyborgs and all that business, but suffice to say there are two semi gratuitous cat girls.
Rym: However, they are awesome characters and when cornered by the ten by not the tank police.
Rym: But that to quote Captain Britain the piss ant SWAT team They really have a bad opinion of the SWAT team is being.
Scott: Well, I would I would have a bad opinion of a SWAT team that ran away at any sign of dangers.
Rym: Well, I think the people who ran away were the normal police and then this was the SWAT team.
Rym: Uh-huh But the cat girls are cornered and what do they do?
Rym: Well, obviously music starts playing and they begin a fairly well done tasteful striptease Which ends in hilarity.
Rym: now the songs in the English and the Japanese are a little different.
Rym: I like them both equally.
Rym: I think I have a little bit of preference for the English one probably just because I saw that one first But they're both good songs.
Rym: I'm not gonna bother playing them both, but I didn't bring this machine gun to surrender.
Rym: Hey, don't you just love being in the spotlight?
Rym: I don't remember having such a big audience in a long time to you.
Rym: You haven't forgotten the routine.
Rym: you bet I haven't.
Scott: Yeah, I kind of forget which one is which.
Scott: that's how they're like sort of in my mind.
Rym: if you show me that scene with Either song I really couldn't tell you I do think again, however that the English song was better matched to the animation.
Rym: It seems like a running problem where the music in tank Please didn't always perfectly match up with what was going on the screen and the beats and the transitions didn't match up with the scene Changes.
Scott: I think it's probably because they just didn't try to have things match up in those days Like, you know nowadays you make a people make these anime music videos with their crappy windows computers And they all about matching up the beats of the music to the animation itself and back then I don't think people cared so much.
Scott: Yeah, so when they brought it over to America They were I guess they tried to do that sort of like how that Jap German Sailor Moon opener the music matches the animation.
Scott: It's the same animation that.
Rym: yep Of course It also gives you a much different mood and idea as to what Sailor Moon is about a better one, of course Yes, of course.
Rym: But for any of you who haven't seen tank police I will just note that this scene the striptease I'm not gonna ruin.
Scott: what a famous anime scene.
Rym: Yes I would say that among at least our generation mine and Scott's of anime fans We all grew up having seen that scene and I'll even admit it's pretty hot.
Rym: It's kind of hot You're not gonna.
Scott: usually it doesn't go.
Scott: I don't go for the animated cat girls.
Rym: You're not gonna find me very often admitting to being titillated by some cat girls doing a striptease in Front of a SWAT team in an anime.
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: I'm not gonna say I'm not that titillated, but I'm titillated greater than zero.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's a well done scene and the what happens during the scene is well worth it.
Rym: I Think my favorite part is when the one SWAT team sniper guy uses his scope not to get a bead on the girls But to zoom in.
Rym: hey, and thus Dominion tank police.
Rym: now, don't be confused I gotta end on this at least because there is the manga.
Rym: is the OAVs?
Rym: the OAVs are what you want to see.
Rym: There is something called new Dominion tank police, which I haven't actually seen.
Rym: people have said it's okay But it's really not the original.
Rym: It's something new.
Rym: It's something different a separate DVD and there's also this funny cel shaded 3d animation tank police.
Rym: I forget what it was called.
Scott: I also forget what it's called But I haven't.
Scott: we watched it and it was basically just a story in the tank police universe of the tank police Characters that didn't have anything to do with anything and it's kind of funny.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of funny It's.
Rym: I think it was pretty cool and it was short enough to where it would have gotten really lame if it drug on at All but it ended exactly what I wanted it to end and it was actually a lot more serious than almost all of tank police.
Scott: Yeah, the animation though was a little initial D kind of crummy But that was okay because I think that might actually been the encoding and not the original production, but it's hard to tell.
Rym: Yeah, but in some Dominion tank police and again it might be hard to get this impression since we couldn't talk much about it is Not one of my favorite anime of all time But it is definitely on my list of anime that I really really love and I I can watch it anytime.
Rym: I've seen tank police like seven or eight times and I crack up and laugh out loud Every time I watch it.
Scott: I Don't think it's one of my favorite shows is definitely a good show and it's definitely regardless of how good it is.
Scott: It's a show that every anime fan, especially an anime fan in America should see at some point.
Rym: well The thing is there are certain scenes that really crack me up and really all I should do is make rims tank police fix and all I have to do is take all the tank police pull out this like 45 maybe 40 minutes worth of the stuff that makes me laugh out loud Put it on a DVD and pop it in whenever I feel the urge.
Scott: I think what they really just need to do is make like 30 scenes of them interrogating people.
Scott: Oh I just make like, you know famous tank police interrogations.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I think like the top 10 tank police interrogations.
Rym: It's an understated moment, but I think my favorite scene and all of tank police hands down Not the striptease But they're talking about these this weird hospital that only treats healthy people and the captain is like, oh, yeah if hospitals only treat healthy people then the police should go rob banks.
Rym: and then he pauses and says I Want to rob a bank?
Rym: I've always wanted to but I've been keeping myself here, but no today's the day I'm gonna go rob a bank and the other cop who's with him is like up.
Rym: What wait No, don't ah.
Rym: and just that scene cracks me up even thinking about it.
Rym: I'm laughing now a little bit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I also want to rob a bank so I can sympathize with that guy.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.