Scott: It's Thursday February 22nd.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight an episode full of geek back.
Scott: Let's do this Tomorrow.
Scott: Friday February 23rd is the first day of the second New York comic convention Outstanding.
Rym: I'm so excited.
Rym: I'm so glad that I spent $30 to spend a few hours there.
Scott: Yeah, the convention is only open tomorrow For normal people from 4 p.m.. To 9 p.m..
Rym: And it still cost 30 bucks to get in.
Rym: and it still cost 30 bucks.
Scott: and Yeah, well we'll be reporting on it next week, but if you want to see us there.
Scott: We'll be there tomorrow only.
Scott: We won't go on Saturday or Sunday because we're busy, and I'm never gonna go to a comic-con for more than one day.
Rym: I don't know after.
Rym: I'm mostly going so I can say I mean unless this con is awesome I don't think I'm ever gonna go back to a comic-con.
Scott: I'm going mostly to see certain people to enhance my pirate sketchbook and To gather information about this convention, so I can report on it.
Rym: if I hadn't already bought my ticket I totally would have copped out and not gone.
Scott: Yeah, oh well.
Scott: I will see you know.
Scott: I think I might actually Depending on what goes on there.
Scott: I don't know if I'll ever go to it again.
Scott: That's basically what it is.
Scott: It's like a litmus test.
Rym: well considering the track record.
Rym: I mean they're batting.
Scott: Oh right now Yeah, well they only took one swing and it.
Scott: I don't know if it's three strikes.
Scott: You're out on the convention circuit like it isn't baseball, but I got to give everyone at least two strikes.
Rym: I don't know the way it happened.
Rym: It wasn't like they just struck.
Rym: it was like They.
Rym: someone threw the ball instead of swinging at it.
Rym: They stood there went by then they beat the catcher to death went after the pitcher Caused a riot and burned down the stadium.
Scott: yeah Well this convention does have a slight advantage in that it is so big and high-profile That not as high-profile San Diego But a high-profile enough that there will be a significant anime and gaming presence that I can retreat to if the comic ness Overwhelms me.
Rym: yeah, we'll see how well I mean I can't imagine the video game room will be big enough to deal with a number Of people who will be wandering around looking for something to do.
Scott: well the video game room was actually the one part of the con I got to see last year, and it was.
Scott: It wasn't like an awesome game katsu But he was pretty big and spacious and had games to play and game companies were there.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway welcome to all of our new listeners.
Rym: We see you've all been joining the forums.
Rym: I would mostly like to say to anyone who has joined the forums and not gotten an approval email You actually did and your hotmail spam filter blocked it.
Rym: we have yet to not approve a single one of you.
Scott: Yes, many people have applied and all have been given the thumbs up.
Scott: if you use hotmail You just won't find out that you've got the thumbs up because your email is crappy.
Scott: get gmail.
Rym: Yeah, totally, but anyway in the news here because I'm gonna get right along.
Rym: We did a long show last night, and we've been generally going along for a while now.
Rym: I don't want to run out the biggest libsyn.
Scott: Yeah, we run out of libsyn.
Scott: We're gonna have.
Scott: our four nights a week is gonna turn into three real quick.
Rym: actually I already talked to him and we could very easily pay to get better libsyn service beyond what is offered on the website.
Rym: Well if we ever get near the quota That's I think what we're gonna do, but anyway in it We got a little bit of local color here cuz I just find this hilarious.
Rym: now There are two malls up in the in Dutchess County.
Rym: You know the mid Hudson Valley one of which is Old and decrepit and is eventually going to be torn down, but it's awesome.
Rym: Oh, it's totally awesome.
Rym: It has an anime store in it not, but while it's awesome Notwithstanding it is decrepit and falling apart and almost no one goes there and a lot of the stores are empty And you could totally rent one for cheap for cheap.
Rym: You could probably rent one for free just to keep the place from looking like it's empty.
Scott: we should.
Rym: But there's also a mall directly next to it.
Rym: That is not new and fancy, but it's pretty much the newest mall around here, and it's a standard normal mall.
Rym: It's no better than the one in Rochester.
Scott: It's your standard two-story American mall.
Scott: It's got a target.
Scott: It's got a Best Buy.
Scott: It's got a bunch of department stores.
Scott: It's got an EB.
Scott: It's got a food court.
Rym: now The weird thing about this mall is a normal mall as a giant parking lot, but for some godforsaken reason I still to this day can't fathom why they would do this.
Rym: they have a big enough parking lot already.
Rym: It's plenty big.
Rym: it goes around the whole thing.
Rym: There's plenty of land around it.
Rym: They built on one side of it this one extra story parking garage That was so shoddily put together and put up against the mall and had like these horrible support beams Everywhere under it was just useless hard to get into hard to get out of and eyesore.
Scott: What were they thinking?
Rym: well technology back then existed to make a better parking garage, and they had enough parking.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: It's not really a parking garage, it's more like a deck.
Scott: It's like there's a parking there's a parking lot and then raised above it on Stilts and I beams is another parking lot.
Scott: that way if you park up there You can just walk right into the Best Buy on the second floor.
Scott: You know cuz the only other way to park and walk into the second floor of the mall is at the target You know and the Best Buy is isn't the targets on the bottom floor?
Scott: I don't even realize.
Scott: I can't even remember how this mall is laid out.
Rym: regardless They had this this terrible just poorly thought-out parking garage.
Scott: I think a long time ago They must have built that thing and paid nothing for it, and it's a piece of shit.
Rym: wasn't the malls not that old?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: man.
Scott: a parking thing looked pretty old.
Rym: No.
Rym: It's not old.
Rym: They just didn't want to pay money.
Rym: the thing is built like in that shoddy way.
Scott: Yeah I mean the mall next to my house as like two different parking decks and that are the same kind of thing on opposite ends Of the mall, but they're sturdy as all hell.
Scott: They're not going anywhere.
Rym: so the interesting story here is that apparently during the snowstorm that had happened right before Katsucon last week There was a lot of snow and the people who are in charge of the mall decided to have all of the snow from around The top of it plowed into one area of it and it proceeded to collapse.
Scott: Well, it was funny.
Scott: Is that the thing was already sort of collapsing?
Scott: I mean there was an area of the parking deck that you weren't allowed to park in.
Scott: that was roped off.
Rym: We weren't allowed to park under it either, and it was ever-growing.
Scott: Yeah And it was.
Scott: you could actually stand there and in the safe part of the safe part of the deck and look at the collapsing Part and go wow that's totally collapsing.
Scott: and if I had any forethought at all I would have realized hey You know when it snows that's gonna put a lot of weight on that area And it's gonna cave in.
Rym: someone see it wouldn't have it.
Rym: It was fine.
Rym: the thing is they when they were plowing the top of it They use big big bulldozers instead of normal little snow plows, and they pushed all the snow into that area Because that way it would be out of the way of the cars cuz no one could park there anyway.
Scott: What were they thinking?
Rym: I think they were thinking I don't know.
Scott: Well the evil parking lot of doom finally collapsed.
Scott: will they build a new one question mark?
Rym: now the funny thing is the the local Municipal government has well has the power to.
Rym: they haven't said if they're going to do it.
Rym: yet find them up to a $1,000.
Scott: I thought they did.
Scott: they gave him a ticket for a thousand dollars.
Rym: They said they were going to.
Rym: I knew I never saw anything that they actually did and they have the option of Assigning some trivial amount of jail time, but they said they're not going to pursue it.
Rym: Man when the it's the same ticket that they'd give some guy if the deck in front of his house collapsed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if someone had like a shoddy deck Basically the the you're breaking code you should be forced to fix it.
Scott: Wait a minute wait a minute.
Rym: You're the one who not too long ago tried to argue with me that we shouldn't have any sort of building code whatsoever.
Scott: The difference here is that you've got a mall that people are going to.
Rym: oh So suddenly there is a rationale for having building codes if it's a publicly traveled place.
Scott: Oh, that's it Not if it's a private house where you're not inviting anyone over.
Rym: That's a bit of a reversal from your previous position.
Rym: but anyway I just thought this was funny because it the fact that this thing collapsed due to human stupidity and the fact that it's been There for so long and I just plus more importantly I couldn't find anything else.
Rym: I wanted to talk about.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about Britney Spears or Anna Nicole.
Rym: What's-her-name?
Rym: I'm still not entirely clear on who that is.
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: I'm only partially sure of who that is and I know her Britney Spears is but I don't know About anything she's done since I was in high school.
Rym: There's some guy named kay fed.
Rym: I think he's a rapper something who knew her.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: There's all that news and then there's all that political news that if you want political news just go to our forums.
Scott: Yeah, someone else is talking about it.
Scott: Not me.
Scott: I don't care.
Rym: So that's all I got.
Rym: What do you want?
Scott: Alright, so I don't know if you've noticed but there was a crazy kid.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I forget.
Scott: where was it, Georgia?
Scott: I wasn't paying attention to where it was and He was bad and he killed the homeless guy.
Rym: Wait, so he was bad and independent of that he killed a whole.
Scott: no not independent of that.
Scott: He was bad and he killed it.
Scott: He was a bad kid who killed a homeless guy.
Scott: Yeah, apparently for fun Yeah, and he was like, yeah, I did it.
Scott: What of it?
Rym: and I do what I want.
Rym: I do what I want.
Scott: He was a bad dude and he blamed it on video games or of course even if he didn't the media totally tried to pin it on the video games as usual and penny arcade had the usual comment.
Scott: like here we go again and I can't be sure if it's true or not, you know, cuz I'm always skeptical.
Scott: but supposedly the stepmother of this bad kid is a penny arcade reader who sent a big letter to Gabe and Gabe put the letter on The penny arcade website.
Scott: now if it's actually from the stepmom who knows I'm 75% sure It's real and 25% sure It's not regardless.
Rym: I suggest you read it because I have met people who have been in similar situations to what this woman is describing.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Now I read the letter like two times and I read it and I said, huh?
Scott: You're right There is nothing you could have done, you know, you had this horrible kid, you know You tried real hard as parents.
Scott: you you did everything you possibly could.
Scott: you punished him?
Scott: You tried positive enforcement negative reinforcement counseling talking to people.
Scott: You did pretty much everything in your power to do and the kid remained bad.
Scott: Meanwhile, his brother was good.
Scott: So you're obviously doing some sort of parenting, right?
Scott: What is the deal?
Rym: so Scott comes home and I hadn't read this.
Rym: so he's showing it to me on the Mac downstairs was sitting on the couch and He's like, yeah, I agree with there's nothing you could have done.
Rym: and then and I say what about military school?
Scott: Well, yeah, I sweet sorta came up with it like hey there is something you could have done.
Scott: Yeah, could have sent the kid to military school and the internet seems to be agreeing with us.
Rym: Yes, however, then we looked it up and military school is not as prevalent as it used to be.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like the same issue with nut houses.
Scott: like back in the day We had nut houses But they were terrible places and you would never want to send anyone to one of those nut houses no matter how nutty they were.
Scott: So they got rid of the nut houses and now we have nuts roaming the streets.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, you know as bad we talk a lot.
Rym: Well, we don't but we as a nation talk a lot about the homeless problem in major cities But all the statistics so show that the majority of those people who aren't in shelters and getting help are also insane.
Scott: Yeah, who knows that they went insane because of homelessness?
Scott: or if they are homeless because of insanity It's probably a mixture of both who knows?
Scott: but the fact is they're insane now and they're homeless now and they need help and we need A good nut house to take care of these people, but we have to pay for it with some taxes.
Scott: Yeah Now the thing is the same thing with bad kids.
Scott: you have bad kids and we got nothing to do with them and no Parent can control them.
Scott: We need some sort of military Academy boarding school to send these kids to because the only other option seems to be that they're gonna kill a homeless guy and go To jail granted.
Rym: I still think that in most cases a kid while the parent might not have intentionally done anything Or might not have even been a particularly bad parent There were just some set of factors in the way they raised the kid possibly due to not Punishing them enough when they were young.
Rym: if they did bad things or not not teaching them proper respect or just not I don't know.
Rym: There's a lot of things.
Scott: there are a lot of things.
Scott: I mean there was some guy who pointed out like he looked into the ages of the people involved.
Scott: He's like hey you had these kids when you're way young.
Scott: He's like you're 29 and the kids 14. wonder You got a problem taking care of them something something and I was like, maybe I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I mean my brother and I turned out just fine.
Rym: Yeah, despite the fact that as kids we actually had almost no.
Rym: in fact in high school I always was amazed because I didn't have any curfews or anything and I had a credit card to pay for gas for my car.
Rym: That was all I was supposed to use it for and pretty much I could do whatever I wanted whenever I wanted to.
Rym: my parents Trusted me and I never knocked over a bank or killed a homeless guy.
Scott: Yeah The thing is no one is quite really sure what the factors are that make people turn out the way they are.
Scott: It's sort of like random baking you put a bun in the oven and you never know what comes out.
Scott: Well, if you're a good maker you do yeah, but you just kind of have to.
Scott: it's like mystery baking not actual baking You know, but when a bad kid comes out and we're in nut comes out you gotta have something to do with them.
Scott: and therefore we say that there should be good nice nut houses and Practical military and boarding academies of some sort.
Rym: now you might be thinking wait a minute Rym and scot.
Rym: But you always say you're libertarians.
Rym: How come you're for, you know spending tax dollars on something and one libertarian with a lower case L and Two common good.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, would you rather have nuts walking around the street?
Scott: It's what I mean.
Scott: sure you're free to walk around the street But if you're a nut or if you're a bad person who's gonna you know, kill people then you're a danger to others.
Scott: Which is you've gone beyond your freedom and we need to take you out somehow.
Scott: and if we're gonna do that then we need somewhere to put you and that's what that's all that is.
Rym: now Scott doesn't drink alcohol at all and I drink it in moderation.
Rym: I like wine with dinner and I like an occasional southern comfort at a convention.
Scott: I like me some grape juice and some grape juice.
Rym: Yeah, you like grape juice before it's turned into wine.
Rym: You like that wuss juice.
Scott: It's so great It like.
Scott: it totally cleans out everything.
Rym: I will actually say I don't particularly enjoy grape juice.
Rym: You suck at all you suck, but I really like wine and I really like other juices and nectars.
Scott: Oh good for you.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: but anyway one thing.
Rym: I read about this a long time ago in a guide on how to drink.
Rym: like a Russian and Apparently in Russia, there is a huge huge social stigma to drinking alone.
Rym: That is the sign of a sad individual.
Rym: Well, I tend to agree.
Scott: Well that agree.
Scott: That's true everywhere.
Rym: Yeah, well, I agree with it.
Scott: It's very much like it's especially stigmatized in Russia for various reasons Because Russia has a huge alcoholism problem and they try to thwart it.
Rym: with social stigma I mean apparently what alcoholics will do in Russia.
Rym: I read this however in dig is That they'll stand outside a bar and wait for other Alcoholics to gather and then they'll pretend to be friends and go in so they can all drink and not look like losers.
Rym: So some enterprising young person has decided to create a product to mitigate this very very important problem of.
Rym: I Am alone and I want to drink.
Rym: So now we have the USB shot glass.
Scott: Hey, so you go to liquor store.
Scott: you buy some Vodak.
Scott: Yes, you bring it home.
Rym: Yep, you pour it into your USB shot glass Which is plugged into your computer and you're plugged into a chat room with some sort of Vodak meter Software and a bunch of other lonely alcoholics.
Rym: you then proceed to drink with these people Via this online mechanism pouring your own Vodak.
Scott: So what is the USB do?
Scott: does it cool the Vodak?
Rym: No, no, no, all it does is Show how much Vodak is in your Vodak glass to everyone else.
Scott: Yeah, does it count how many Vodaks you've drunken?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I just assume the software could do.
Scott: how does it know?
Scott: I'm not just pouring the Vodak out back into the bottle.
Rym: if you want to sit there sober hanging out with a bunch of drunk People on the internet, that's your prerogative, but I can get them to think that I've drinking like 80 Vodaks.
Rym: I Imagine they'll know in one way or another.
Scott: I don't know why they even need to do this.
Scott: You could just use a webcam and then people can see you drink a lot easier than a USB shot glass.
Rym: Mostly this is just kind of a silly gadget.
Rym: But two it is a little more practical than a webcam.
Rym: I mean what if you want to be naked while you're drinking?
Rym: now, you don't have to worry about that.
Scott: What if you're gonna be naked while you're drinking?
Scott: That's more reason to have a webcam not less.
Rym: What if you're ugly?
Scott: Dan you deserve to be drinking alone and no one wants to see you or talk to you or drink with you.
Scott: No, it's kind of it's.
Rym: while this actual implementation is kind of silly the idea of it's kind of neat They take because when you're drinking with friends one important aspect of it is always no you can see what is in everyone else's glass And you kind of you can gauge the progress you can gauge how much everyone's drinking You know what context and all that and you lose that drinking on the internet.
Rym: Of course why you'd want to be drinking on the internet is beyond me.
Scott: I guess I didn't realize that sort of thing was paid attention to because I don't drink.
Rym: well Yeah, it is but in Russia because drinking I guess is a much bigger deal.
Rym: There is now this silly device.
Rym: I don't know how seriously people are actually going to take it over there.
Rym: I find it hilarious If nothing else it
Scott: is definitely pretty hilarious that eventually there'll be USB everything and then USB will be obsolete and we'll have wireless USB or something else and it'd be crazy All right, so I Often use stories on this podcast about f1 racing which is a sport that I am quite fond of that other people May have varying levels of caring about it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm probably the next biggest fan of f1 in the front row crew and I have no desire to watch it at all.
Scott: Yeah, so this guy he's some sort of auto Reviewing for magazine journalist guy and he got a chance to ride in an f1 car.
Scott: now Not just any f1 car a four-year-old f1 car.
Scott: So what this is?
Scott: car is old and slow.
Scott: Not only is it old and slow It was also one of the slowest and shittiest cars that year.
Scott: like it came in last all the time it's a slow and shitty f1 car and he drove it and it was the craziness.
Scott: and Even if you don't like f1 or care about racing I think that you should read this little three-page article because it just it'll.
Scott: it's the best way to get an idea of exactly why and how f1 is Crazier than every other possible type of racing on the earth.
Rym: Yeah I mean I don't enjoy watching it other than maybe the first two laps and the last two laps or the lap or whoever passes whoever.
Rym: And other than I don't care.
Rym: but the technology behind f1 is actually a big deal and it's really neat science.
Scott: yeah, and this guy like He's driving this car like 170 miles an hour and he approaches this turn and he's fearing for his life because he's going so Incredibly fast, you know, like basically everything's a blur.
Scott: You can't even see what's going on.
Scott: So he steps on the brakes and The brakes are so incredibly powerful that he actually broke too soon.
Scott: and then you realize what you compare his speed.
Scott: it's like the speed of Michael Schumacher the greatest driver and The the guy who drove this car in races who was the shittiest f1 driver.
Scott: and you go wow I'm totally not laughing at that shitty f1 driver anymore because that guy went into this crazy turn at ludicrous speed and broke Later, yeah, I mean the worst driver at f1 is still one of the best drivers in the world.
Scott: Yeah, it's actually pretty big news.
Scott: I don't know if you've been paying attention but in shitty NASCAR a Former f1 driver and possibly soon two former f1 drivers will be are racing in NASCAR.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah JPM is Juan Pablo Montoya.
Scott: He's driving in NASCAR.
Scott: He was in the Daytona 500, but then I think he got crashed in the final lap or something Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah, it was kind of a crazy race actually the Daytona 500, but whatever.
Scott: It's not as good as the f1s, right?
Rym: So tonight kind of a short episode because again, we're tired from Katsucon and we went long last night, obviously Yep, I had a bunch of interviews from last night that instead of putting him in the show because we went long I'll use him for a special someday.
Rym: You'll hear and we recorded a bunch of stuff at Katsucon, which was fun Yep, but we've always gone 50/50 on what we're about to do since on one hand people Well half of our listeners really like geek backs.
Rym: You know where we read email or stuff from the forums or things people send us and they won't tell us to have more.
Rym: They send us email in hopes of being on the show.
Rym: And on the other hand the other half of our listeners hate it and don't want to hear from other people.
Rym: They want to hear from us.
Scott: Yeah, I'm actually kind of torn on this myself and it seems like it's some podcasts I listen to.
Scott: all I want to hear is the hosts talking and I don't want to hear their stupid listeners.
Scott: But other podcasts I listen to like dragons landing like dragons landing.
Scott: I only want to hear them respond to listener emails and voicemails and I don't give a shit about what they have to say.
Scott: Well, not as much of a shit about what they have to say.
Rym: So you don't give a shit.
Rym: Why even listening?
Scott: I listen to the feedback episodes only.
Scott: but yeah, it's kind of a toss-up, you know.
Scott: So I figure we'll do it one more time.
Scott: See what the hell happens.
Rym: Yep So we'll do tonight partly because it's also a great cop-out episode.
Rym: It requires almost no effort other than looking at all the emails we've gotten.
Scott: It's also a lot of fun and it makes listeners excited.
Scott: So why not?
Rym: and also right now?
Rym: I'll tell you all out there that even it and we respond to a lot of the email we get.
Rym: but if we don't respond To you, don't worry.
Rym: We read your email.
Rym: We read every email we get.
Rym: that isn't spam.
Scott: Yeah, just some emails I got nothing to say to.
Scott: Mostly if you just send me a link, I got nothing to say to you.
Rym: Yeah, or if someone just says hey I love the show.
Rym: I'm not gonna bother saying.
Rym: Thanks.
Rym: I you thank me enough by listening and I whatever.
Rym: I don't worry about it.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes I do mean to reply and then I just the email.
Scott: I don't reply immediately.
Scott: So the email sits there but it's marked as red so I don't look at again and then you fall down the queue.
Rym: Yep, yep.
Rym: Yep There's also the fact that sometimes an email we don't really have anything to respond to it or maybe it asks a question that requires A complex answer.
Rym: usually we ruminate on that and eventually do a show on it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, well, I'll start off here with the first email.
Rym: I wouldn't read that whole thing.
Scott: It's long I'm not but basically there's a guy named Mike O'Neill and he has a company called mr Smith which he is the owner and designer and this company sells the Jimmy.
Rym: now You may I am I that we a while ago bought these wallets part on the show where it's talked about it.
Rym: So we could try them out because they were kind of weird.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: The Jimmy is a strange non-standard wallet.
Scott: It's basically a small plastic thing that holds credit cards and cash and your ID and all this stuff and it's pretty cool.
Scott: And we both use them for wallets.
Rym: and yeah I really like the one.
Rym: actually whenever I pull my wallet out at least half the time Whoever I'm paying money to says something like wow, what kind of wallet is that?
Rym: Where can I get one?
Scott: Yeah, people always, you know comment like whoa, what kind?
Scott: what's up with that wallet?
Scott: Why is it all weird?
Rym: And and the company that does you know the Jimmy company?
Rym: They're really socially responsible and recycled goods and money to the environment and all that business.
Scott: Yeah, it was like 1% of revenue goes the environment whatever.
Rym: that's cool.
Scott: It's alright.
Scott: I don't really care either way.
Rym: But anyway, well, that's cuz you're a godless heathen.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So they also sell some other cool stuff like they have some new like SD card clips.
Scott: It's like if you have a lot of SD cards for your digital camera, they have stuff that holds them.
Rym: I was actually thinking again that iPod nano case because my my cover.
Rym: it's great for carrying it around.
Rym: It's not so great for listening to stuff while I'm that's right.
Scott: They do.
Scott: they sell an iPod nano case.
Scott: I forgot about that.
Scott: Maybe I'll get one too anyway.
Scott: Yeah, so Apparently we've told a lot of people about this wallet all the time because people comment on it and someone we told about it Went to the website bought the Jimmy wallet and said they heard about it from GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, the guy who runs the company emailed us and he was like, hey someone bought my wallet and they heard about it from you.
Scott: Do you want some stuff?
Rym: Well, mostly he just wanted to say thanks.
Rym: And yeah, I think that's cool.
Rym: I mean we weren't trying to promote the product.
Rym: We just actually like the product.
Scott: yeah, I mean I bought it sort of randomly like my last wallet died and I said you know what there has to be something better out there than a wallet.
Scott: and I actually found a whole bunch of stuff but most of it was expensive or hard to get.
Scott: the Jimmy was easy to get.
Scott: I Bought it from a website and it was cheap and I figured if this thing doesn't work out for me I'll just put it away and get something else and it's worked out.
Scott: It's pretty cool Yeah, so this is not a paid for.
Rym: and yeah, don't think that we're advertising.
Rym: I think to all of our new listeners we dislike advertising more than just about anything in the world.
Scott: Yeah, we're not gonna take sponsors or sell ads or anything.
Scott: We are legitimately happy with this product and we bought.
Rym: we bought it with no persuasion whatsoever In fact, I bought it mostly so I could hate on it and make fun of it And the fact that I liked it was kind of yeah.
Scott: And then we used it and we still use it and now the guy who makes it knows about us and he's cool All right, so now here's a fun one.
Rym: Hey guys I've recently started an anime club at my school and I'm having trouble picking a good funny animated screen.
Rym: I choose Death Note I choose you Pikachu But most people have already seen much of the show and I was wondering if you guys Spelled with a lowercase.
Rym: you can tell me a good shounen style anime that most people have not seen yet.
Scott: That's a run-on sentence right there from Abdul in Sydney.
Scott: Sydney, Australia.
Scott: Oh PS.
Scott: Sorry for such a noob question.
Rym: Well, uh, I can think of thousands.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I replied to the email and I was like, huh a funny shounen.
Scott: well Cromartie Excel saga maybe go kudos slayers.
Rym: You pretty much named all the stuff.
Scott: I would have named Naruto one piece Whatever, you know, I named a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Oh Dominion tank police.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah, and the guy replied with thanks a lot.
Scott: I started watching slayers and im really enjoying it.
Rym: No period yeah fair warning when we get email.
Rym: if we're gonna make fun of pretty much any mistake you make don't take it Personally, yes, we will make fun of your punctuation and spelling.
Rym: Oh, I see a pretty good typo in the next one on this list.
Scott: All right, so yeah if you're looking for more anime it's not really hard to find them.
Scott: if Actually if you're someone who you know, you know You want to watch anime, but there's so much anime out there and you've only recently gotten into the hobby or the you know Whatever it is the culture and you're not really, you know, there's thousands of anime.
Scott: Which ones do you watch next?
Scott: a good idea actually is to go to like the anime news network Encyclopedia and you can sort of browse anime by genre and you can like find an anime you like and click on the director and see what else they directed and It's a pretty good way to find shows.
Scott: You might be interested.
Rym: Yeah, of course You can always just ask us because we'll usually answer and without a beat I could always say watch cowboy bebop butana eska flown a Evangelion try gun Lane.
Scott: Yep, something like that.
Scott: All right What's the next one saying?
Rym: Oh, we could do this other one with the typo.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah do the one with the typo All right.
Rym: I like this one.
Rym: Would you guys happen to know of any cons going on in the Boston area?
Scott: Thanks, Steve Well, the subject of the email is computer cons.
Rym: See now that throws me for a loop because I know about anime Boston, but I don't really go to computer cons.
Scott: Yeah, if you're looking for an anime convention near you there is a website called anime - cons.
Scott: calm and they have every anime convention.
Scott: So don't ask us about where.
Scott: if there's an anime convention near you There's a website that lists all of them that you can go to.
Scott: as for a computer con.
Scott: That's more difficult I mean, do they really have computer kind?
Rym: Well, there was penguin con.
Scott: Yeah, penguin con was a Linux convention in Michigan, Michigan There's Def Con and things like that which like the hacker cons, I think there's one in Vegas and one in New York I'm not sure.
Scott: but yeah, what are the kind of computer cons are there?
Scott: I don't really know.
Rym: I don't know what I do to computer con.
Rym: I mean, honestly, I there's not much I'm gonna learn from a computer con that I can't just learn from a book or the internet.
Rym: And I already went to college.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's computer conferences where you can go listen to people give speeches like O'Reilly something something But those cost a lot of money and there's not really.
Scott: it's not the same as an anime convention.
Scott: It's not a social fun thing.
Rym: It's just a Well penguin con was a social fun thing.
Scott: Yeah, thank God didn't have so much, you know, it was most more sci-fi Gaming going on there.
Rym: Oh the panels were almost all computer stuff.
Scott: panels were a computer.
Scott: That is correct, huh?
Scott: Yeah, thank.
Scott: what cons sort of unique in that way.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: No computer cons.
Scott: All right, let's pick another email here.
Scott: There you go, let's see.
Scott: Hey Rym and Scott longtime listener first time mailer love the show and I don't know how you can put the level of content at the quality You do each night.
Scott: It's magic.
Scott: Oh, all these are exclamation points.
Scott: I don't know if I'm the first person listening to UK but you are international.
Rym: We have a lot of listeners in Australia and the United Kingdom Albion.
Scott: Yes We have a lot of listeners throughout the English-speaking world and outside of the English-speaking world.
Rym: You know where we don't have any listeners is France, oh really as far as I can tell.
Rym: so we got any French listeners.
Rym: Give us a shout out.
Scott: Yeah, let's see.
Scott: The networking show is really good.
Scott: I did some networking a while ago So it was a good refresher and has got me thinking I need to get up to speed with it all again.
Scott: Exclamation point.
Scott: please feel free to do another show on this as it was really interesting.
Scott: Am I right in thinking that there are certain IP ranges or numbers that cannot be used together?
Scott: as I said, I'm rusty man Cheers Rob.
Rym: IP ranges or numbers that cannot be used together Really just comes down if you have two separate networks that use the same like if I've got my network that says 10-dot Whatever and someone else has their network.
Rym: That is also internally 10-dot whatever.
Rym: you can't just stick the two together.
Rym: You got to change one of the sides or in some way reconcile.
Scott: Yeah, two computers on the same network can't have the same exact IP address.
Rym: That's all it comes down Barring fun things like multicast, but we're not.
Rym: Multicast is well beyond the layman's networking thing.
Rym: We're gonna have to do a special show on that and I don't think anyone would want to hear it.
Scott: No, that would be a very boring even though I think multicast is really cool.
Scott: Yeah, but who uses it?
Rym: a lot of people actually really?
Rym: Yeah, we use it IBM for images.
Rym: Oh sending, you know reef like sending an image a hard drive image to a hundred machines.
Rym: We could multicast it to all those machines at once instead of sending a hundred packets to each machine over and over.
Scott: Doesn't ipv6 have stuff to do with that?
Rym: ipv6 has some awesome stuff like that.
Rym: All right I should do a show on ipv6 Maybe about what it is.
Scott: a lot of people don't understand that at all Mostly because well we could do it after we do a show on net.
Rym: Ah Yeah, I like this one is nice and short.
Rym: just found your podcast.
Rym: I have to tell you that your podcast about IP addressing was awesome.
Rym: Would love to show about creating a home network wireless versus wired etc.
Rym: Can't wait to hear your other podcast.
Rym: Cheers al from Rhode Island.
Rym: Wow, Rhode Island.
Scott: Yeah that stayed so small.
Scott: I didn't think that like there would be anyone in it who listen to podcast.
Rym: Yeah, what I can say is very briefly since that networking and layman's terms run over so well We are going to probably do every aspect of networking with the same level of technical talking in the same level of metaphor.
Rym: So expect a bunch more of those to come as soon as we get around to it.
Scott: Ah Let's see.
Scott: Oh, here's another one about the IP episode as well.
Scott: I don't think I'm gonna read this whole thing But I'll skip to the part.
Scott: We actually asked some questions.
Scott: I have an idea for a while now and wanted to run it by someone who's interested in your opinion.
Scott: Okay, most of the viruses spam malware on the internet is propagated by armies of botnets.
Scott: ie infected pcs.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Most of the viruses are written to send spam and apart from taking a percentage of the resources of machine They don't do anything seriously malicious and consequently most people are unaware that they have them.
Scott: that is sort of true.
Scott: But a lot of those spywares and things actually will steal your paypals or your eBay's Yes, or all kinds of evil stuff like that.
Rym: You may not have met any of them but rest assured it happens.
Scott: It happens a lot.
Scott: Sure, there are really bad viruses that collect your credit card details, etc.
Scott: But I personally don't know anyone who's had their identity hacked or been the subject of fraud.
Scott: Anyways, what I think we need is a white hat.
Scott: I know I don't.
Scott: I've actually heard of a lot of people who have been the subject of fraud But I really I got to say right now.
Scott: I don't like this term identity theft.
Scott: Identity theft is if I go around the street with rims ID in a Rym disguise pretending to be Rym.
Scott: that is identity theft.
Scott: I mean sure technically if I take rims credit card and buy something with it You could say I'm pretending to be.
Rym: well They usually refer to.
Rym: when you do identity theft is when you gather enough information about a person who poses them in order to Get lines of credit.
Scott: Yes, but you're not actually, you know, your crime is is credit fraud?
Scott: That's the crime, you know, sure you're posing as them because you're using their information instead of your information.
Scott: Yes Yeah, but your crime is credit fraud.
Scott: identity theft is.
Scott: it would be a crime where I pretend to be someone else.
Rym: You are pretending to be someone else only technically and not so I disagree with you a hundred percent.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't like the way they call it identity theft.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: I'm just.
Scott: it's an it's a disagreement about a label.
Rym: So I know I'm just saying that I disagree with your assessment.
Scott: All right, I obviously.
Scott: yes you are Using someone else's identity to achieve a crime of credit fraud, but I don't like calling it identity theft.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: You're just weird.
Scott: You're just weird.
Scott: A hacker who basically writes a virus that simply trashes any machine it infects thus schooling the user on the virtues of running a decent OS or at least patching slash protecting it.
Scott: Alright virus writers would never write this.
Rym: I can answer that real quickly.
Rym: That used to happen a lot more often than it does now, but it wasn't white hats.
Rym: I can tell you that No It wasn't.
Rym: basically all that did was cause the FBI and various Organizations to hunt down the people who made the viruses and piss a lot of people off.
Rym: But the people who were angry didn't even try to secure themselves.
Rym: They just did damage control and went right along doing what they were doing before.
Scott: Yeah, there are banks that get hacked all the time But the banks will never say they were hacked nor who and we have no idea of knowing how much effort they put into actually Securing their fences because they would lose more money if people found out that they were insecure.
Scott: Then they lose by people hacking into them.
Scott: So your crazy idea of going around and Erasing everyone's hard drives with an actually evil virus is a crazy Very immature and childish idea granted.
Rym: I had the same idea when I was 14.
Scott: I also had the same idea when I was 14 and now that I'm 24 I no longer have this.
Rym: I think part of the reason we don't have the idea anymore is that now we're business Professionals in our industry and we have to deal with that shit.
Scott: Even if I didn't have to deal with it, I would strongly advise against anyone actually making a horribly evil virus Although I am often puzzled as to why no one's done it.
Scott: You'd think that with all these bad guys on the internet and with such Insecure systems everywhere with all these windows because the people who write the viruses aren't motivated by being hackers They're motivated by being paid by spammers.
Scott: Yep, the people who are motivated by being hackers.
Scott: nowadays They're not hacking.
Scott: other people are causing harm to others.
Scott: They're trying to increase benefits for themselves like getting rid of DRM and stuff like course.
Rym: What if we took this idea, but instead of making it do something malicious, we made it pop up a window saying your computer is insecure.
Scott: Because here's how to think because we're trying to teach people not to click on those sorts of things.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This is the last one you should click on.
Scott: Yep thoughts.
Scott: We gave you the thoughts.
Scott: regards Christian All right.
Rym: Oh, here's a cool one.
Rym: Remember when I had jury duty.
Rym: Yeah, I just listened to the podcast on jury duty.
Rym: I'll try to read this quickly.
Rym: It's kind of long.
Scott: Yeah funny thing happened to me.
Rym: I was supposed to call an 800 number.
Rym: go back in December to see if I will be selected for jury duty.
Rym: I forgot and then I remember the following Monday I kind of it's kind of freaked out.
Rym: My wife sent me a text message freaking out like something bad happened.
Rym: realized what I did.
Rym: So I called the courthouse and told him I forgot.
Rym: there was no big deal.
Rym: They figured I'd forgotten.
Rym: They'd already rescheduled it in March and if he gets elected to go, he'll report his experience to us.
Scott: I'd like to hear that experience.
Rym: a great show.
Scott: if you forget again, I would like to hear that as well.
Rym: Yeah, this is Steve from.
Rym: he doesn't say where he's from.
Rym: Not that it matters since this is the internet.
Rym: We're all sovereign members of this nation.
Rym: Yeah of the internet.
Scott: Yeah, everyone still send in jury duty stories if you have them because jury duty is cool.
Rym: Yeah, but I gotta say it seems like I mean this guy had the same experience.
Rym: The courts are doing their best to make jury duty.
Rym: Okay for people I mean they could have you know, totally screwed you if you didn't show up But instead they did the right thing.
Rym: just obviously he forgot.
Rym: Let's just reschedule him.
Scott: Yeah, I mean no one would act, you know Anyone who's trying to get out of jury duty always tries to get out of it straight away, you know They'll say they'll call up and make an excuse or they'll show up and try to give a story.
Scott: Someone who just doesn't show up most of the time like 90% of the time either something happened to them or they forgot and I think The court realizes that.
Scott: All right.
Scott: We got to pick another email here.
Rym: I see a really long one.
Scott: I see a short one.
Scott: That's better.
Scott: Did you guys hear the pen show about the moon landing?
Scott: Here is a show.
Scott: talk about the moon landing and why it is true.
Scott: Thanks for professionalism Brian Ps.
Scott: after hearing the professionalism show I want to party with you guys.
Rym: Well, you should have come to Katsucon.
Scott: Yes, you should have come to Katsucon.
Scott: If you want to party with us You must come to a convention that we are at.
Rym: as for the moon landing I gotta say this one of my favorite moments in the history of the world is when some nut job Was bothering Buzz Aldrin about how he didn't really go to the moon.
Rym: and it's all a conspiracy.
Rym: and Buzz Aldrin Just punched the dude in the face.
Scott: That was an awesome time.
Rym: That was the proper response to that kind of thing.
Scott: to anyone out there.
Scott: who's a crazy conspiracy nut?
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: They landed on the moon.
Rym: Yeah, and those markers on the backs of road signs don't direct the UN troops to the secret concentration camps.
Scott: Yeah, if you take a powerful enough telescope, you can see shit on the moon.
Scott: It we went there.
Scott: Yeah, that's dust that we brought back from the moon.
Scott: It's moon dust You.
Scott: you won't find anything like it on earth except the stuff that we brought back from the moon.
Rym: Oh, here's a fun one.
Rym: Are you guys going to follow the match game 7x format six stars two contestants?
Rym: I hope you have some good questions lined up for the show.
Rym: I suggested you online polls for the audience.
Rym: match blah blah blah blah.
Rym: See you at.
Rym: Katsucon, Jeremiah.
Rym: Alright, I'm so happy that there are people out there who actually remember the match game and know anything about it.
Scott: But there's actually a whole big segment of game show geeks out there Like you.
Scott: don't know about them because they're kind of small and they're not really connected with each other.
Scott: Yeah, they have a whole TV channel.
Rym: They do all seem to agree the people out there that the match game in the 70s was one of the best game shows ever.
Rym: Well, it's not so much in terms of fun and humor and watching it and being entertained.
Scott: Well, I think that's really the trick with game shows as opposed to just games.
Scott: Is that what makes a great game show?
Scott: is that it is entertaining to watch it Even if you're not playing it, you know, I mean that's what sports are.
Scott: game shows are sort of like Spectator games that aren't athletic in nature, you know.
Scott: And what makes a good one is when it's entertaining and the match game seems to excel at entertaining the crowd Even if the actual game itself is just kind of random.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Oh Here's one.
Rym: Here's one.
Rym: I can keep reading them.
Scott: You got him.
Rym: All right, I got one.
Rym: I like this.
Rym: when you guys were discussing anime openers and closers You mentioned the Auriga themes from both Ghost in the Shell stand-alone complex seasons.
Rym: Maybe you were speaking of anime in general But you talked about not understanding Japanese in an anime and enjoying a theme even though you don't understand the language.
Rym: Just to clear up the Ghost in the Shell themes are in Russian.
Rym: I believe I love them so much that I hunted down the lyrics.
Rym: I've included.
Rym: I've included them here But we've all got work to do.
Rym: He talks a bit more.
Rym: why Vegeta?
Rym: obviously not his real name unless his parents are totally awesome.
Rym: Again, we are well aware that the music in the Ghost in the Shell things was Russian.
Rym: We were just talking in general about the allure of hearing music in a language.
Rym: You don't understand.
Scott: Yes People often send us emails to tell us things like we didn't know or we got something wrong and most of the time they tell Us something we knew already.
Scott: It's like people also send us links to things I get.
Scott: how many emails are we not reading because they're just links to things.
Scott: It's like if you're sending me a link, there's a 99% chance.
Scott: I have seen that link.
Rym: Well, are you the king of the internet?
Scott: Well, you know, I read dig I read slash dot I have a lot of RSS feeds to gaming and gadget and nerd blogs and boing boing and all sorts of stuff.
Scott: if Something happens on the internet and there's something interesting to see the odds are that within 24 hours I will see it unless I am on vacation and not using a computer.
Scott: So Send us a link if it's something really cool But before you send it to us check to make sure if it's already popular on dig or slash.
Scott: Not even that.
Rym: just look at our dig histories.
Rym: or even better if you send us a link just send it to us in delicious.
Scott: Yes, if you're not using de l that I see I owe us.
Scott: you're not using the Internet's.
Rym: granted I'm not as frumpy about this as Scott and I think it's cool when you guys send us links because it means that you're well.
Rym: Yeah, I had to contribute to the show.
Rym: I know I like not a captain grumpy pants here.
Scott: Well, I do like getting any email whatsoever Even if it's just a link, but I am always sort of disappointed when I like ooh an email from a listener.
Scott: Ooh, they sent a link and then I click on it and it's something I saw to a week ago.
Scott: and then my oohs go Plus.
Rym: in this case I can see why they thought Why people might have that because the way we phrase we kind of jumped from talking.
Scott: I think we do make that mistake.
Scott: a lot is well, we'll phrase up We won't be so perfectly explicit and people will get the wrong idea about something We said and then hit us on it.
Rym: or there's people like my co Scott here who when I said the guy who writes Dragon Ball But I didn't say his name Scott immediately assumes that I don't actually know the guy's name.
Scott: Well, because I thought you didn't know the guy's name.
Scott: cuz you.
Scott: sometimes you'll pull that trick.
Rym: When have I pulled that trick?
Scott: often when just cuz I can't remember a specific instance doesn't know.
Rym: So you're gonna read an email.
Rym: cuz.
Rym: I got another one here.
Scott: I got one.
Scott: All right.
Scott: All right I just listened to the podcast from eight three.
Scott: Oh six dot dot dot dot.
Rym: Which one was that?
Scott: I'll tell you in a second.
Scott: I want you to know that I just almost peed my pants laughing when the show came on.
Scott: I thought hmm, maybe they will do it.
Scott: then I thought dot dot dot.
Scott: nah They will have someone in place of them.
Scott: You didn't?
Scott: it was awesome.
Scott: If I had your address, I would mail you a box of kudos Steve.
Scott: I think this Steve guy is going through the archives listening to stuff but a lot.
Rym: actually it seems really interesting to me that Most of our new listeners are going through the archives.
Rym: our old episodes are getting hammered.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like you know, normally I would expect a graph of like episode downloads.
Scott: I would expect the oldest episodes to be low on the graph and the newer episodes to be high on the graph like a big Diagonal line, but actually it's sort of like this horizontal line and the whole thing goes up sort of equally as people go through The archives.
Scott: now for me some podcasts I go through the archives like 12 Byzantine emperors got to go through the archives.
Rym: Yeah, well, I guess for me, it really depends on how much time I have how good the podcast is.
Rym: I mean if a podcast is great.
Rym: I love it.
Rym: I'll go through the archives and like movies.
Rym: you should see.
Rym: I've listened to almost every show they've done at this point.
Scott: Yeah, but other podcasts like Penn radio, you don't go through the archives, you know You pick out.
Scott: obviously you do go through and pick out the choice Episodes from the archives, you know because there are some oldies but goodies, but you don't listen to everything.
Scott: I mean what the hell.
Scott: but yeah, if you want to listen to all our archives more power to you I don't recommend it.
Scott: But if that's what you want to do, you're crazy.
Scott: Awesome All right, let's see, yeah, so that episode 8306 that was the last one we did before Otakon.
Scott: that was special number.
Rym: Oh, oh, oh special number six or seven.
Scott: I think it was number four I don't remember.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: but yeah, basically when we went to Otakon We said that we were trying to get other people to do the episodes for us and we did.
Rym: but yeah It was actually two of the movies.
Rym: You should see people.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: They did it on the Monday, but The day before we on the Thursday when we left for Otakon We put up a short episode and if you want you can go into our archives.
Scott: This will teach you how to go into our archives and listen to the 8306 episode and you'll see it's.
Scott: it's pretty funny.
Scott: I think at least one guy left.
Rym: All right, we should probably end this since it's Thursday and I'm tired and we got to go to a con tomorrow.
Scott: Do you want to do one more?
Scott: and that's it?
Rym: Yeah, let's do one more.
Rym: I won't read this whole thing.
Rym: It's really long.
Rym: But thanks to Frankie G for the email.
Rym: I know you've heard it a thousand times now, but thanks for putting on a fun show.
Rym: I wanted to thank you guys for turning me on to Carcassonne.
Scott: Oh Carcassonne is a good board.
Rym: got to play it for the first time last night.
Rym: We all had a good time.
Rym: I won the first game and they did a little king making to keep me from winning the second game.
Rym: the bastards You have a good set of friends if they're smart enough to do that.
Rym: So which expansions are worth getting?
Rym: and you guys like playing with or without the river?
Scott: Okay, we talked about this and split that up into two.
Rym: yeah the river in my opinion is a bit shit.
Scott: Yeah, I also I'm not a fan of the river.
Rym: I mean, I guess it could be good to teach people how to play but it really just kind of ruins the game Especially if you play against me.
Rym: captain farm.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really see a point in the river.
Scott: all it seems to do is force people to put down some farmers early and Then go on with the game as usual just starting the game out normally without the river.
Scott: It seems to be just fine and concentrates a lot more on the core mechanic without throwing this kind of wacky river in the middle Of things.
Rym: wacky wavy inflatable arm-flailing river man.
Scott: as for what?
Scott: Expansions?
Scott: it kind of depends what you want.
Rym: They're mostly crap.
Scott: Yeah, most of the expansions are gimmicky and Just kind of cute like the princess and the dragon.
Scott: if you want a wooden dragon go get it.
Rym: Well, I mean all we really play with now are the one that adds the inns and the cathedrals.
Scott: It's called ins and cathedrals.
Rym: Haha And we bought the tower.
Rym: we don't play with the tower We just I just bought it so I'd have the tower to put all the tiles in while we play.
Scott: Yeah, actually my number one recommendation to you if you want to play Carcassonne with expansions is The game is pretty cheap.
Scott: the ins and cathedrals are pretty good and you probably want that set because it gets a lot of tiles that the normal set doesn't Have.
Scott: that makes the game a little better.
Scott: But and also the greatest expansion to Carcassonne is another set of Carcassonne.
Rym: However, be wary if you add another set to Carcassonne.
Rym: the more sets you add the more important farming becomes and the more powerful Certain moves become and the game becomes unbalanced very quickly.
Scott: Yes the game will also take a lot longer and you need to figure out how many meeples you're gonna give to people because when the Game is longer and there are more tiles You need more meeples or maybe you just have to manage the meeples you have more carefully.
Scott: But I think it definitely makes it a more exciting game for experienced players.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now, uh, he has another whole half.
Rym: It's not gonna read the whole thing.
Rym: I'm gonna paraphrase here, but out of the Trigon podcast.
Rym: just for the record I do like and I've owned the series on DVD many Trevor on the Sun blah blah.
Rym: I hope you received some feedback.
Rym: damn you guys really downplayed Nishimura Satoshi.
Rym: Well, he hasn't done all that much.
Rym: he did go on to direct Hajime.
Rym: no motherfucking epo Aka fighting.
Rym: motherfucking spirit a show I find superior and probably every way to try gun.
Rym: now I haven't actually seen this show yet.
Rym: Daryl Surratt and anime world order and you have talked it up to and Dave and Joel and Dave and Joel and we got a Couple other emails about it.
Rym: I haven't seen it.
Rym: All I have to say is that if you're saying this is better than try gun and all of try gun That's a really heady claim.
Scott: That's that's pretty heavy right?
Scott: We're gonna watch Hajime.
Rym: no motherfucking epo.
Scott: Yeah, isn't it a sports anime about boxing something like that?
Rym: Yeah, so I like boxing.
Rym: but I mean, uh What was that movie?
Rym: We watch the one with Clint Eastwood in it.
Rym: I don't remember whatever the bud million-dollar, baby Yep, a rocky or anything like that.
Rym: I like boxing.
Scott: You never saw the first rocky movie.
Rym: you said no I never saw any of the rest of the rocky movies and I never saw the first rocky movie in one go.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Anyway, I Think try gun might be better, but I haven't seen this show.
Rym: So I can't really say but if this show is better than try gun, it's gonna be in my top five.
Scott: Yeah, so that you're you're.
Scott: you got a big heavy claim here.
Scott: We'll see if you can live up to better than try.
Rym: gun puts it right up there with cowboy bebop eska flown And I know Dave and Joel will hate me.
Rym: but Evangelion Yeah, which as much as I agree with you on every one of your points, you can't deny that Ava was a well-done show.
Scott: Actually, I think I want to do one more email and that's it.
Scott: I was actually from some people I want to.
Scott: I want to Mention.
Scott: so you remember we did that interview with Luke crane and such.
Rym: Ah, that was awesome.
Scott: Yeah Well, he mentioned some people in the podcast in in that interview and then those people finally found out about it and contacted us.
Rym: Well, I'll talk about a roundabout.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: so he says gentlemen I'm writing.
Scott: I am the writing half of the team that produces the dire destiny webcomic.
Scott: I recently happened upon your podcast interview with Luke crane from October son.
Scott: Oh six Thereabouts a burning wheel and ubercon 8. it was well worth least it listening to as I got to hear either Luke or Tor Describe dire destiny as really freaking awesome.
Scott: I'm always looking to promote the site even though we're in a bit of a lull right now and on top of that We're releasing a D&D three and a half Adventure sometime in the next couple of months.
Scott: Oh, I don't know if either of you have seen dire destiny But if you have and if you need grist for your show, I'd be happy to make myself available for an interview.
Scott: I'm in Virginia and the artist mikkelage is in Poland, but maybe we can work something up over the net with Skype or something.
Scott: Thanks for your time Robert.
Scott: Ah A webcomic that I am NOT reading yet.
Scott: The person is a fan of our show.
Scott: perhaps we should read their webcomic.
Rym: Yeah, we also got to start reading Apple Geeks.
Scott: I don't know if I'm gonna read Apple Geeks.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: I'll probably like every time someone tells me to read a webcomic and I actually do I end up liking it.
Scott: Yeah, oh, so I guess anyone out there looking for a new webcomic.
Scott: Dire destiny seems to have cool people who know how to spell and punctuate.
Scott: Yeah, that was a well-formed email Even though he didn't capitalize Skype.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Oh, that's okay.
Scott: Cuz Skype is becoming a generalized term It's true, but his email was better written than pretty much every other email I have here and His webcomic may or may not be cool.
Scott: And since the guy likes D&D and burning wheel.
Scott: He's probably a cool guy and thus it is likely that his webcomic is cool.
Rym: So anyway, we mostly did this episode to prove to you all that yes We read the email we get.
Rym: you can keep sending it to us But we're not gonna read it in every episode because that doesn't seem to be what you guys want.
Rym: Of course if that's changed let us know.
Scott: Yes, you also this episode because we are lazy and we do not want to come up with some other idea of something to talk About.
Rym: yes, I'm ready to play Phoenix Wright until I fall asleep.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't realize the hardest part about GeekNights is coming up with what to talking.
Scott: talk about not actually doing the talking.
Rym: Yeah, we do more pre-production than post-production these days.
Scott: Oh, well, the show is easy and now it's over.
Rym: Yeah We'll see you Monday when we're probably gonna talk about how net works since a lot of people have a lot of trouble with it.
Scott: A lot of people don't even understand what the hell net is.
Rym: if you're a new listener and you're not so up on tech I'd recommend you check out our recent Monday episode on networking for layman's Yep, and then you will be much better prepared to understand the next show on net?
Rym: Yes, but it will definitely be at that same level of technical whatnot.
Rym: So it's not gonna be some sort of doctoral thesis here.
Scott: We should make it a doctoral thesis then say we're doing it at layman's level and see what people say.
Rym: God start talking about algorithms for assigning IP addresses based on.
Rym: Okay, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.