Rym: It's Wednesday May 2nd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we preview darker than black Romeo and Juliet rocket girls and perhaps one of my favorite shows ever sighs and Jotaro.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, I found a blackberry.
Scott: You found a blackberry.
Rym: well pretty much whenever I drive home instead of taking the train I always drive past breakneck Ridge, so Invariably I climb it real quick and then climb back down and get on my way and go home.
Rym: and while I was climbing I saw what looked like a little DS case or something.
Rym: so huh, and I look over there and sure enough There's a blackberry.
Scott: well usually when you turn a blackberry on it'll say this blackberry belongs to so-and-so.
Scott: we live at so-and-so.
Scott: Does it say that?
Rym: I haven't looked at it at all other than that I saw it has a bunch of really lame messages in it.
Scott: What variety of blackberry is it?
Scott: what color is it black?
Scott: okay, so it's the.
Rym: it's that guy I don't know or care.
Scott: It's green color or black and white color?
Rym: all right doesn't matter.
Rym: It does.
Scott: it doesn't matter at all.
Rym: It has no bearing on the story.
Rym: the point is I found some dumbass his cell phone who lost it on the mountain Very low on the mountain.
Rym: I might add like sitting openly in the middle of the trail.
Rym: I don't know how you could drop something that big and heavy and not notice.
Rym: Yeah, uh, but I guess I'll have to contact him somehow and give it back to him.
Rym: Maybe I'll get some sort of reward like I gave that kid who found my cell phone way back in the city.
Scott: Well, what about your cell phone?
Rym: Oh you mean my smashed cell phone?
Rym: Yeah that one I smashed it.
Rym: good job.
Rym: You realize that cell phone has been smashed crushed dropped or immersed in water like 20 times in recent memory alone.
Scott: Yeah Well you got to stop doing that.
Rym: if I go climbing or biking or running I bring a cell phone.
Rym: that way if I hurt Myself I can call the police or the ambulance or whoever to come get me.
Scott: You can still like strap it to yourself in such a way that it does not get smashed.
Rym: Where am I gonna stress say I'm climbing where am I gonna put it?
Scott: well like for the iPod?
Scott: They have like those little wrist armband things.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna put a cell phone there plus it would get smashed.
Rym: You can't climb.
Rym: I bang my arms into rocks all the time Alrighty yeah Plus.
Rym: the cell phone is over three years old beating the hell out of anyway.
Scott: So and my cell phone that was three years old is still working.
Scott: I just stopped using it cuz it was old.
Rym: Yeah, I still have my original cell phone.
Rym: It still works.
Rym: fine I just oh it does it.
Scott: Yeah, it does.
Rym: yeah It's right over there.
Rym: You can charge it up and still use it to call the police or something if you want.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think you can make regular calls.
Scott: and isn't the screen broken and only the outside screen?
Rym: everything else is fine.
Scott: The outside screen is the most important part.
Scott: I use my cell phone more as a clock that has a phone.
Rym: Anyway alright alright, so what do you have in the news gun?
Scott: well if you weren't paying attention to the Internet's there was the gigantic news and it was so gigantic.
Scott: you basically conquered dig like a Goliath or a Cyclops or something probably Cyclops.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: basically There's a key an encryption key that can decrypt HD DVD movies.
Scott: so if you had this key and you wrote a piece of software using this key You could take an HD DVD movie and do anything you wanted with it.
Scott: You can make copies you could put it on the bit Torrance whatever.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: so of course this key is Technically DMCA not okay, and the people who you know are in charge of maintaining this key the AACS Went around and they found people posting this key on the internet, and they said hey don't post that key.
Rym: Well the problem is the key is actually a very short is Relatively easy to remember number.
Rym: It is just a number and that's it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's just a number.
Rym: It's trivial to just type it anywhere.
Scott: yep, so what happened is early in the day yesterday people You know on dig would just post the number in a comment on a story that had nothing to do with it And the people would bump the number up.
Scott: and then some people would submit stories to dig And they would say they would put the number as the subject and the content and they would link to a page that had the Number and so on and so forth.
Scott: and dig started out by saying all right listen We can't do anything illegal if you want us to still exist.
Scott: We're a very small company.
Scott: They're a very big company.
Scott: We're gonna get in trouble, so we're gonna have to get rid of these stories.
Scott: That was a bad move by dig because as anyone could notice within a few hours Every story on dig was the number.
Scott: the entire front page was covered with the number and nothing else.
Scott: Whether dig was gonna get destroyed by being sued by Under the DMCA for allowing this number to be posted on their site Was not an issue because dig was now useless because there was no news on the front page.
Scott: There was just this number.
Rym: well unless you went to any other category where then this number wasn't there and dig was normal?
Scott: Yep, but you know no one goes to the I do.
Rym: I don't go to the front page.
Scott: Oh really I go only to the front page But I have it sorted.
Scott: so like only some categories appear on the front page and some don't I filter out the categories I don't like.
Rym: no I just if I want to know news about a given category I go to it.
Rym: I didn't even notice the stupid front page key business whatever.
Scott: Anyway, even if you didn't notice it on the front page on the right side of dig where it says top 10 in all topics It was covering that entire thing was all stories about this key.
Rym: I don't know on one head.
Rym: I don't think this is really unexpected or particularly important or interesting.
Rym: it's just that's what nerds and geeks do.
Rym: if they feel threatened and The way to fight back is something that you can do easily online They'll do it.
Rym: so if you have a den of geekery or nerdery like dig Where most people know what this key is and know exactly what's going on?
Rym: They're definitely gonna just post as much as they can and cause as much trouble for everyone who's trying to hide it as possible.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not saying that it was unexpected But I think it shows that.
Scott: now look here is a real example Where people's on the internet with the civil disobedience coming on strong and actually getting something done?
Scott: And now all the regular news media and everyone is taking notice like oh shits look at those people are doing.
Rym: I think the relevant quote someone pointed this out on dig in fact and it was from an old show I used to like called news radio and the quote is basically Trying to take something off the internet is like trying to take pee out of the swimming pool.
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: I mean there's really no way to keep this key.
Rym: people already registered domain names that have the key And the key can be incorporated into an ipv6 address straight up.
Rym: yeah Yeah, so there's already stickers and t-shirts.
Scott: so what dig eventually did?
Scott: is they said all right apparently?
Scott: One of the stories involving this key was the most dug up story ever.
Scott: I got like.
Scott: I dug it even.
Scott: it was like 20,000. it was a ridiculous number of do.
Rym: I actually went in and dug every single story that had the key once I figured out What was going on?
Scott: I only dug a few of the biggest ones just because I didn't want to.
Scott: some of the lower ones are crappy or linked to Bad stuff, so I didn't want to pump them up, but Eventually dig said all right.
Scott: we can't we don't have the manpower to go around deleting all these stories with the key and Apparently use guys.
Scott: you users of dig have decided that you would rather see dig fight and die Then censor all these stories, so we're gonna keep them up, and that is what they did.
Rym: I don't think it's gonna matter because Regardless of what happens it's there's no way they can see and D And then follow through everyone who's posting this key.
Rym: it would cost more.
Rym: It would basically cost an infinite amount of money because this key has appeared Everywhere on the internet.
Scott: yep, and the question is what they even sue dig at all will even try.
Rym: well They even think about it.
Rym: They have many bigger fish to fry right now.
Scott: Well the only.
Scott: I think actually there is a possibility that this outright You know the the outrage of the users on dig and the fact that the regular news media took notice of it might attract Attention to dig as one of the sites that disobeyed the C&D whereas other sites disobeying it might not get in trouble.
Rym: Well, it wasn't just dig because slashdot had a much more.
Rym: I mean slashdot is generally.
Rym: I don't want to say people on slashdot are smarter or more erudite or anything like that But it is definitely a different kind of site.
Scott: I think just what it is is that the only people who are still on slashdot right all the dumb people have left Slashdot.
Scott: so now it's only Some smart people.
Rym: actually the other day because I haven't posted in a while But I used to have this game that I played for the longest time and the game was literally how many?
Rym: Plus fives?
Rym: can you get in a row without anything less than that in between?
Rym: yeah?
Rym: I once filled my entire slashdot history with plus five.
Rym: He's not lying.
Rym: I saw it, and I started up again.
Rym: I haven't posted on slashdot in like a year.
Rym: So I post.
Scott: I've been actually slash dotting a little bit more recently lately.
Rym: well I saw a thing about AMD.
Rym: someone was like is Apple gonna buy AMD?
Rym: and I was like no that's crazy and stupid.
Rym: the fuck's wrong with you.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I saw that headline as well.
Rym: Yeah I got my plus five and then I remembered that when GeekNights first started a Decent number of you came from slashdot post because my signaling to us.
Rym: So I think I'm gonna start posting my plus fives again.
Scott: actually It's like I've always been subscribed to the slashdot RSS feed for as long as it's existed.
Scott: You know and that's how I read it ever since RSS existed and was useful.
Scott: You know I just look at the headlines and slash dot and if there was an interesting story I'd click on it, and I noticed that in the past few weeks I've been ending up on slashdot more often than I have in weeks prior.
Scott: I think the editors at slashdot have gotten smarter And they've realized the kinds of stories that you know people want to read nowadays.
Scott: They're not the kind of stories that they would have read in say 2002.
Rym: at least the formula for making a plus five comment has not changed a Science to get plus five comments the same formula on dig even to get a bunch of thumbs up.
Rym: So it's a different.
Rym: like it's a different formula the post that would get you the ups on Slashdot will not get you the ups on dig and vice versa.
Scott: I think it will it just it depends a dig has a lot more.
Scott: It depends a lot more on the timing of your post and the the noticableness of it based on its formatting and such like that.
Rym: Anyway, not to get on a long rant about slashdot dig and all that but the article on slashdot talking about this issue Had no you know it wasn't in the title.
Rym: people weren't really posting all over the comments so much.
Rym: But there's a tagging data.
Rym: You can tag stories and immediately the story was tagged with none other than the key.
Scott: I have a feeling this key is gonna become a category on some blogs out there.
Rym: Well I noticed someone may or may not have posted it in our forums.
Scott: You all know it is our policy to never delete a post ever Yep, and I don't think we're gonna get to cease and desist and if we do that'll be awesome.
Scott: if we do I'm gonna do a Cory doctor.
Scott: Oh, did you know he did?
Rym: did you just post the cease and desist that has the number in it?
Scott: That's exactly what he did.
Scott: he took the number off and he put up the cease and desist PDF that had the number in it.
Rym: I just we can't get into it cuz it's not that kind of day.
Rym: It's Wednesday.
Scott: Yep Well, I only said this on Wednesday cuz it had to do with HD DVD.
Scott: So a reminder again anyone who thinks about watching anime or anything on DVD because you really need all those HD's to make your animes look better.
Scott: I know right, but anyone's thinking about it now You can decrypt that shit and make copies and watch it on whatever doesn't matter anymore.
Rym: So many of you may or may not be fans of the right honorable Lord going a guy Going a guy going a guy famous for being the king of various things Cutie honey devil man Messenger a getter Robo.
Rym: well at the Napoli comic-con in 2007.
Rym: We have Napoli isn't Italy?
Rym: Yeah, Wow, you know, wait, wait Naples or I don't know.
Rym: I don't know anything about Italy.
Rym: I know about old Italy.
Rym: I don't know about modern Italy.
Rym: There are however anime cons in countries other than the United States and Japan Unbelievable.
Rym: so at this con he had got a very interesting cool interview and Someone has decided to translate it transcribe it and put it on the internet.
Rym: It is highly worth a read.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of funny cuz it's like what the interview was conducted in Italian.
Scott: So you got the questions translated from Italian and then the answer is translated from the translator Translating from Japanese to Italian.
Rym: Well, I think one of my favorite answers He gave is that when they asked what he's working on now?
Rym: He said he's working on four kinds of stories two of which are manga about samurai set in medieval, Japan.
Rym: Two of them.
Scott: Wow, I guess the other two must be violent sexy robots, right?
Rym: I'm not even gonna comment on what kinds of things going guy might actually be putting into his manga.
Rym: It's a pretty cool interview.
Rym: I'm not gonna go through it much but check it out.
Scott: And apparently anime news network says Napoli comic-con, but the actual interview says Naples comic-con.
Rym: so last night I was complaining when I do my things the day about how everything worth seeing on the internet is on dig and I generally anything I pick whether it's on dig or not will be on dig by the time we do the show about it.
Scott: well I think that was not true last night because dig was just a sea of numbers and nothing interesting.
Rym: But I mean in general Most of what is important on the internet to people like us is on dig slash dot FARC and gadget.
Rym: There's a list of websites and between them they cover talking 99% of everything we care about.
Rym: that is correct But every now and then a little gem slips through the cracks.
Rym: who for whatever reason go to places other than we go on the internet?
Scott: Ah, so they're very strange people.
Scott: they go to strange places places that we would not even dare to go even if we knew they existed such as 4chan or Deviantart.
Scott: well Deviantart's not so bad, but I don't go there live journal myspace etcetera.
Rym: So I could describe my thing of the day which last night our friend I do Message me and demanded that it be a thing of the day and was shocked at the fact that I didn't know about it.
Rym: Uh-huh, and I found further investigation.
Rym: It was in fact submitted to dig almost a year ago.
Rym: Oh But it never got dug up so I never would have seen it.
Scott: That's very strange because this is the kind of thing that would be dug up if people noticed it.
Rym: Yeah, and I saw a lot of knockoffs that are actually pretty bad by different people.
Rym: But this is the original all I can really say about it.
Rym: He's coming.
Scott: He's coming.
Rym: He's coming coming Ways, uh, I'm not even gonna try to quote it.
Rym: suffice to say it is a Rappish kind of video about George Washington that is entirely historically accurate 30 dicks It's.
Rym: it's pretty much a straight-up history of George, Washington.
Scott: Yes, all you people from other countries can learn about the father of the United States.
Rym: I mean we used to debate about oh could anyone beat Chuck Norris.
Rym: I think we found the answer George Washington first.
Rym: Chuck Norris in George Washington wins, maybe maybe I'm not gonna do it justice if I try to make jokes from it or quote it.
Rym: All I can say is one the song is going to be stuck into your head.
Rym: You won't think it will.
Rym: you'll listen and think yeah, that was funny.
Rym: And then the next day you'll be humming it.
Scott: watch it two times.
Scott: Then it'll be really be stuck.
Rym: It's just it's in my head right now.
Scott: It's in my Washington, Washington.
Rym: All right All right, he's coming.
Rym: he's coming.
Rym: so I Got something that I saved the children, but not the British children.
Scott: so Man, we're gonna be quoting that for a bunch of episodes to come.
Scott: So anyway, I found something that's pretty cool.
Scott: You know how people always find like knockoff toys and they're hilarious cuz like lol.
Scott: Look at that.
Scott: It's a dragon ball toy, but the colors are wrong and it says dragoon ball.
Scott: Or you'll see like I don't know A ninja turtle and it's like a frog.
Rym: well Emily and I were in Manhattan way back in Chinatown and she found these wooden slipper clog things That had Naruto characters very poorly painted on them in entirely the wrong colors.
Scott: Understand how these people get the colors wrong.
Scott: I mean I could get it if you got the shade wrong like oh I use the wrong shade of blue or the wrong shade Of orange.
Scott: Yeah, but Yeah, what the fuck is up with?
Scott: like the green pikachu's it's like or maybe just not have yellow paint.
Rym: Maybe they do that and then they say no, it's the original character.
Rym: See yeah, it's not the same.
Rym: It's not the same.
Scott: so this is a knockoff that I found today.
Scott: I don't think it's on dig but it is on some gaming blog.
Scott: I think that I found it on.
Scott: and what this is apparently in Korea China.
Scott: I'm not quite sure.
Scott: It's difficult to say.
Scott: there is a game a PC game called power Mon plus and it is pretty much a direct Pokemon ripoff.
Scott: like directly.
Scott: it's the same font for the logo.
Scott: Pikachu is there It's just Pikachu.
Scott: the jigglypuff is there.
Scott: I see Eevee I see meows I see Oddish.
Scott: It's a direct ripoff.
Scott: However, the important thing to note about power Mon is that there are multiple power Mon games.
Rym: Wow, it must have made some money.
Scott: It's a knockoff franchise that seems to be continuing and able to put out more than one product.
Rym: See while I have somewhat complicated views on some piracy and that sort of thing There's a big difference between copying someone's DVD ones or blatantly outright ripping off an extremely popular and nationally renowned property.
Scott: Yeah, I also say that this is not cool, but it is cool to look at the screenshots in this game because they're hilarious.
Scott: Oh my god, you got this Pikachu that's like totally demented and has a neck.
Scott: Pikachu doesn't have a neck people Alright and he's throwing baseballs and ice cubes and bubbles and his frogs and it's like some side scroll and shit.
Scott: And there's a Pikachu with wings flying around like an angel Pikachu.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: You you don't know shit about Pokemon.
Scott: You know shit about Pokemon.
Scott: Oh, yeah, apparently this PC game power Mon plus plus Requires weight plus plus?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's it's the word plus followed by the plus symbol requires windows.
Rym: That's incorrect That's just yeah, that's not you don't do that?
Scott: Yeah Apparently requires a hundred and thirty three megahertz processor 32 megs of RAM Windows XP and it came out in 2001 from ID soft.
Scott: Not only not only did they rip off the gate the license for the property of their game that they made But the name of the company is a ripoff of a company in the US that makes games.
Rym: Wow They still make games.
Scott: I don't ID that like in the US.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, they make cell phone games and things.
Scott: I think they they.
Scott: they got someone else to make quake for yeah I just realized they may.
Scott: I think most recently they made the doom cell phone RPG.
Rym: I was just thinking about it.
Rym: I realized that they pretty much fell off my radar a long time.
Scott: Well, it's mostly cuz they didn't do anything for a long time and then doom 3 was not so hot.
Rym: Nah, hell actually I didn't even think quake 3 was so hot.
Scott: No me either.
Scott: but Carmack is.
Scott: he's got good ideas and how to make a lot of money and he's making moves.
Scott: So watch it watch out.
Scott: He's gonna cut pull something out of the Hat any year now.
Rym: So now that Washington's out of the way, yeah Washington all right.
Scott: last week we talked to you about four new anime from the new anime season.
Scott: in this week We have four more new anime from the new anime season.
Scott: actually one of them I think is from last year something again.
Scott: It doesn't matter when they're from there for very recent anime that you probably have not seen or heard of.
Scott: And we are going to tell you based on one episode of watching what we think some of them might be.
Rym: okay I'm actually considering watching more of at least one of these shows.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: See if you can guess which one I'll give you a hint.
Rym: It's not the last one.
Rym: We're gonna.
Scott: yeah, we'll do that one last.
Rym: actually I kind of have an idea to watch.
Scott: all of that if there's ever says there's 11 episodes It's all you okay, so the first show we will talk about is Romeo X Juliet.
Scott: It is a TV show based on yes, Romeo and Juliet.
Scott: Well, well, yeah, and it is a gonzo show.
Rym: All right Well you say based on and as far as I can see The level of based on this is that the main characters names are Romeo and Juliet and there is a character named Benvolio and there are Capulets and Montagues.
Scott: and There's a guy.
Scott: there's a character William Shakespeare in the story, but they call him wheelie.
Scott: Yeah wheelie and that's about it.
Scott: Everything else is just Fantasy.
Scott: now this flying horses and shit.
Scott: It's out of control.
Rym: It's actually really well animated and pretty cool from the way it began.
Rym: So the opening song it borders on the cheesy just a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, I think it is cheesy.
Rym: The show is very much symphonic rock music playing at all times very whimsical very Oh, it's a light-hearted fantasy.
Rym: Look people draw swords But no one's dying except when there's major plot things going on and a whole bunch of people are dying.
Rym: But you can tell when those things are gonna happen or not?
Scott: Yeah, and we haven't even seen any of those things happen because you only watched one episode now.
Rym: It begins with the Capulet family in their floating castle.
Scott: in the sky being it seems like there's a whole town like a whole city or the whole world is on a floating rock and there's big And there's nothing else.
Rym: so the patriarch of the family is being murdered by the Montagues or systematically killing Everyone in the castle in order to ensure that the bloodline is destroyed.
Scott: yeah, basically the Montagues are genociding the Capulets and then you know even after and that's in the past and even when they're Done with that in the present time of the show They're still running around looking for Capulets to genocide.
Rym: because you see it turns out that someone awesome saves a young girl named Juliet Ah, really and some other girl and then they grow up a little bit, but she has to hide her identity.
Rym: They have to hide the fact that she's a Capulet because there's a death warrant out on anyone with Capulet blood.
Rym: In fact, they execute people who they suspect of having Capulet.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like a witch hunt for Capulets.
Scott: of course in the real Romeo and Juliet, it was sort of a Hatfield and McCoy kind of deal and not so much a Jew and Nazi kind of deal.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Now the thing is if it weren't Nominally based on Romeo and Juliet if it were just a show that had some other theme it'd be okay.
Rym: It's a pretty good show so far.
Rym: It's not a great show.
Scott: It's it's definitely an average show.
Rym: I mean little above average.
Scott: I think it's got some fun fantasy.
Scott: It's got some good animation.
Scott: Some of the character designs are cool.
Scott: Some of the character designs are not cool.
Scott: voice acting is pretty average, but I think I'd like.
Rym: I Think the story it's there is pretty interesting.
Rym: I like the setting.
Rym: I like all that.
Rym: What I don't like is that one they pull some kind of your tennis shenanigans where the main character s you know Juliet Dresses up as a boy and Furthermore dresses up as the red whirlwind who's basically the Scarlet Pimper now going around saving people and all this time She has short hair and looks like a boy, but whenever she puts down a dress out of nowhere these long flowing locks appear.
Scott: Yeah, I could understand if she was hiding the hair like in down the back of her shirt or something like that But you can clearly see she's not hiding the hair.
Scott: She's got hair that is cut short And then it magically elongates.
Scott: and now I can buy the flying horses.
Scott: right just because.
Scott: well There are some biological flying horses.
Rym: I kind of like them just because they're different from what you would expect.
Scott: They're really shaggy and lanky yeah But there isn't any magic in the show as far as I've seen.
Rym: so you can't in the floating castle.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but I mean if you're gonna pull this hair appearing out of nowhere.
Scott: You better show me some other magic somewhere else, or I'm not gonna buy it.
Rym: I think it's pretty safe to say that there's more magic in this show.
Scott: yeah But it's like all right.
Scott: so far the only magic is hair out of nowhere uh-huh.
Rym: So I guess the end result here is that the show is called Romeo and Juliet as far as I can tell For no reason other than to call it Romeo and Juliet, and it's so loosely based on it that it's almost laughable.
Rym: Yeah, however.
Rym: I see a potential for a pretty good show because Spoilers for Romeo and Juliet they both die.
Scott: yeah, if they end this and they don't die That's kind of silly.
Scott: But but if they do and the show is set up as it is if it keeps going in its current direction And that current direction somehow ends with them both dying That's pretty crazy because that means that the in-between has to exist which is a place where a good show lives.
Rym: Yes, just if they have the guts to end this as a tragedy the way it should be Then this show is probably gonna be worth watching.
Rym: However, if it does not end that way the show is probably not worth watching.
Scott: well It's gonzo, so you never know what they could do.
Rym: Damn you gonzo.
Scott: Damn you all right.
Scott: the next show I want to talk about is sort of this Happy silly show that we watched called rocket girls.
Scott: Basically the premise of this show is you have a space program a Japanese space program that's on some island out in the middle of nowhere and They're trying to send rockets into space But they suck like they had a rocket that could go pretty high and it worked But it wasn't powerful enough to really get into space.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: No.
Rym: It's a silly group of scientists.
Rym: It's not Generally very.
Scott: it's one of those sort of character groups where you know sort of like the tank police.
Scott: So there's one of everybody or pat labore where there's one of.
Scott: you know, this is the.
Scott: this is this character in this character In this character, it's one of those goofy camaraderie shows.
Scott: Yep, which we really like usually I do usually like those and You know now they're trying to develop a more powerful rocket that can actually get to space but it's hella unreliable and it explodes and it sucks and It's.
Scott: it's pretty funny watching them like bet on whether the Rockets gonna make it and watching the island the native islanders like going Hooray a fireworks show.
Scott: Hooray.
Scott: I don't.
Rym: I think the best part about the show is there's all these interactions between the scientists people I mean, there's the main character girl, but whatever about her Yeah I'll talk about her in a second and The one scientist girl who runs the whole like science program thing.
Rym: there is always testing and doing experiments on the astronaut.
Rym: Yeah, there's one astronaut and the astronauts this really cool guy and she basically tortures him constantly.
Scott: Yeah, he was in like, you know the Centrifuge the centrifuge simulator thing.
Scott: He was in the centrifuge and she turned it up too high and he's like.
Rym: I saw you You know like with your gleeful smile and she's like damn.
Rym: I should have expected a fighter jet pilot to pick that out.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, and there's a lot of fun animosity there, but then they start to realize that alright We got to use the smaller rocket, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, they had to use the smaller rocket because the big rocket is unreliable And if they don't get into space by the end of the year they lose their funding.
Rym: So the best part of the whole first episode happens when they decide this.
Scott: Yeah, so the the guy who's in charge decides All right If we're we're gonna do this.
Scott: The only hope is to use the old rocket that we know works But isn't strong enough and somehow reduce the amount of weight we put into space so that we can still make it.
Rym: So he turns to the scientist woman and says so how much weight do you think our astronaut can lose?
Rym: and she has their evil grin and looks at him and The best part of the episode she pretty much backs up like oh no Oh no, and he runs out of the room.
Rym: anything.
Rym: All right, and this evolves into a rather Extended scene that involves him not just running away, but stealing an armored car Crashing through the gates and trying to get off the island.
Scott: Okay Now he's driving this very armored Humvee very quickly away from the space base, right?
Scott: They chase him with a helicopter and they shoot missiles at him like a fully armed Anti-tank helicopter comes after him and is shooting him with rockets and missiles.
Rym: And the thing is he'd rather die than stop that car.
Rym: So he keeps going.
Scott: He just keeps going.
Scott: It's pretty hilarious now But the show is actually about that's sort of.
Scott: the main deal is that this is girl and she's a girl who lost her father.
Scott: I think her father must have been a space research.
Rym: Oh, it doesn't matter It's the flimsiest excuse for a plot ever.
Rym: They wanted to make a show about little girls who are also astronauts.
Scott: Yep So the girl ends up on the island and while that guy that the astronaut is running away this girl ends up Getting into his armored car and in the end they say they they catch the you know Astronaut guy and the girl is with him and the head of the space program goes, huh?
Scott: How much do you think that little girl weighs?
Scott: dumb dumb dumb.
Rym: It's such a flimsy premise.
Scott: It's so flimsy.
Rym: and the best part is there's two other girls that you can obviously Tell just from the way they're animated and the fact that the camera focuses on them that they are going to be the other two Rocket girls.
Rym: There's the native girl who's cute.
Rym: And then there's the Chinese restaurant girl who's obviously cute.
Scott: Yep, three cute girls going into space.
Scott: funny space program camaraderie Comedy whatever.
Scott: it's a light-hearted Silly not very deep show with some comedy and probably some cute girl fanservice.
Scott: That's pretty much all there is to it.
Scott: It's just one of those.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: I don't regret that I watched the first episode.
Rym: I could see myself watching the rest of it someday when I've gone through all of my cue But I really have no interest in watching.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if I really need a cheap, you know Sort of like some giggles I would watch this show.
Scott: I would actually recommend this show highly to say an anime club because if you watch it at an anime club It would pretty much make everyone go.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: This is definitely one of those benefits from a crowd shows.
Scott: It's not something you would actually watch seriously But if you have a giant auditorium full of anime fans turn this on and everyone will laugh their heads off.
Rym: So moving on cuz.
Rym: I want to get to this show.
Rym: This is probably actually the best show in the lot.
Rym: Well best in terms of goodness not best in terms of most memorable.
Scott: Yes, now the show is darker than black and it's sort of a supernatural fight not so much fighting but action show.
Scott: and The first thing I want to tell you about in this show is the opening song because I learned something from this opening song.
Rym: What did you learn?
Scott: Well, first of all, let's talk about the music in general before we talk about anything else.
Scott: The music is by yoko kana Of course.
Scott: Whoo-hoo.
Scott: That's awesome because yoko kana rules, right?
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: I just realized that despite having done GeekNights for however many 300 something episodes I don't think any of our listeners know about yoko kana in a box.
Scott: No, probably not.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, the music is by yoko kana.
Scott: The opening song is by a band called Abingdon boys school a bi?
Scott: ng don.
Rym: now I'll say that I really like the opening song.
Scott: It's a really good opening song, but it sounded so familiar and I was like Sounds like either TMR or lark on CL, but I can't tell it was.
Scott: you know I can hear a j-rock and a lot of j-rock sounds similar, but this is a really familiar j-rock.
Scott: Well lo and behold The front man for this band Abingdon boys school is Takanori Nishikawa.
Scott: Who's the TMR guy?
Scott: Apparently he's not doing the TMR anymore.
Scott: now he's doing this.
Scott: I also found out that the band is named after Of course the Abingdon school.
Scott: the Abingdon school is the all-male school where the British rock band radio head was established.
Scott: So that's kind of weird.
Scott: That's like if I named my band like strawberry fields.
Rym: It's not a bad name for a band actually.
Scott: Yeah, but you're totally like if you're.
Rym: if you're a Beatles cover band, that's okay But otherwise no no, in fact, I think if you're a Beatles cover band you have less of a right to do that.
Rym: You gotta be like some weird off-center punk noise band have a name like that.
Scott: That's no good.
Scott: Anyway, yeah so you got a show already without knowing anything else about the show.
Rym: that is yoko kano music and also has Awesome j-rock opener and the show definitely has high production values really well animated.
Rym: the character designs are pretty solid.
Rym: Actually like all the characters we've seen so far they remind me quite a bit of the characters from licensed by royal one guy.
Scott: does the other people sort of remind me of?
Rym: What do they remind you of?
Scott: I don't know sort of like something in between.
Rym: There's a little bit of read or die there - yes a little bit of read or die.
Scott: One character looks like Roy Mustang with a mask.
Rym: I like that mask.
Rym: It's like that Sailor Moon mask.
Scott: It is a cool mask and I don't know it's sort of it's.
Scott: it's cool.
Rym: either way I can't.
Rym: we're not gonna talk about the plot of the show because part of the problem is that this show does a very good thing in one way and that it has a very interesting setting and they explain a lot of the setting to you pretty much right away because there's a lot to get out of the Way and they seem to really want to get to the meat of the show very quickly.
Rym: Yeah, unlike a lot of crap anime.
Rym: They don't do it in the slipshod way.
Rym: You might expect.
Scott: Yeah Basically, some of it is stereotypical Like there was an incident in the past.
Scott: that's mysterious and you don't learn about it Even though everyone else knows about.
Rym: yes And now the city is surrounded by this wall and the sky is fake and there's the truth is on the other side of the wall But no one can get out.
Scott: No one knows it's out there.
Scott: There's something out there.
Rym: I like how they show that though how you look at the sky and then you realize that half of it looks like it's painted The wrong color.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yep, and they make some you know metaphors and they're trying to be meaningful because there's one character who looks through Telescope and they're like, hey all the stars are fake.
Scott: Why are you looking at that telescope?
Scott: And it's like He's looking at a telescope with the fake sky.
Rym: The coolest thing about this show so far is that there are these two groups of people who seem to have powers Contractors.
Rym: there are a lot of jokes not getting into that and dolls.
Rym: Yep Now there's all typical anime kind of names like.
Rym: we're gonna call them things like this But it actually means something.
Scott: the contractors are really cool.
Scott: Yeah, they're people who have powers and do jobs and fulfill contracts.
Scott: But whenever they fulfill a contract like they don't say this outright, but you just see it with a show They have to do something.
Rym: I think it's more that they make a deal in order to get a power and in return for getting the power They have to pay a price after the fact.
Rym: It's not that they're on contract to do something really it's that they paid the price of having this contract.
Rym: It's like selling your soul to the devil and then the devil gives it back to you after you I don't know break your ring finger or stack a bunch of pebbles in a specific intricate pattern on a table.
Scott: yeah, and Then you have these other people with powers who are dolls.
Scott: which are?
Scott: they describe them as mediums You know like psychic mediums like the girl in Phoenix Wright or whatever, you know They channel powers from somewhere else or something.
Scott: It's they don't really explain it very well but they they're dolls and they're mediums and they're the other group of people with powers and of course there are people with no powers and They're sort of tied up fighting over.
Scott: You don't know what.
Rym: The show at least for the first episode has some pretty good action scenes and it starts pretty much right off with all the business.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they just get right to it.
Scott: There's like a new guy comes to town and right away He's involved in some craziness.
Scott: Like you see this guy come to town and he has sort of like this Crazy old landlord lady who's a.
Rym: oh, yeah, the main character is actually just some like high school punk kid.
Scott: Yeah, he's some high school punk kid.
Scott: He comes in from another.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: That's kind of weird.
Scott: Like they were like, huh?
Scott: I just realized something.
Scott: the guy's kind of foreign, right?
Scott: Maybe he's he's mr.
Scott: Lee and he's something right?
Scott: He's foreign, but he came to a city with a wall around it.
Scott: Huh?
Scott: That's interesting.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: is the whole is there like other?
Scott: how big is this wall?
Scott: How big an area does it surround?
Rym: Well, the first episode doesn't reveal much of that.
Rym: It just kind of reveals the basic setup Yeah, but it's also Starts out with two totally different threads that come together by the end of the first episode and that's the direction The show is obviously going to go in from that forward.
Scott: I liked how when he first showed up at his apartment, you know, they introduced the funny landlord lady.
Scott: But then they're like, oh he has the mysterious female neighbor, right?
Scott: Then they immediately show you why the female neighbor is mysterious and they immediately bump into each other instead of holding that off.
Scott: So, you know like huh?
Scott: I wonder about her and then you should bring her back.
Scott: in the third episode You forget who she was.
Scott: This is mysterious female neighbor.
Scott: There she is.
Scott: This is why she was mysterious.
Scott: the end, you know.
Scott: And that way you didn't forget about her when they finally brought her into the plot.
Rym: like happens quite often in many shows the show Starts out dark gets light-hearted for a little bit and then gets dark again and then gets really dark.
Scott: Yeah, the characters I like best in the show are actually the police.
Scott: I guess they're the police or the FBI or equivalent.
Rym: It doesn't really matter.
Scott: It doesn't really matter the law enforcement Agency and you know some of the characters in this law enforcement agency are stereotypical But they're pretty funny and some of them are really cool and the one girl who seems to be smart and the police is pretty Cool, and she's always like right up in the business and on top of everything which is not so typical.
Scott: Usually police are bumbling or falling way behind or something like or have tanks or have tanks.
Rym: Yes I think this show is worth watching.
Rym: I'm definitely gonna check out at least a few more episodes Episodes.
Scott: you just got to watch him.
Rym: So I'm feeling it.
Rym: I'm feeling it more with this than I have with just about any other show that's come out recently.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely has the potential to be quite awesome and to have some cool Action, and maybe if the plot goes in interesting places If actually I'd say it's the second most the show that I like the most because that bokurano with the with the robot I'm really liking that.
Rym: I really like bokurano - and I've only seen one episode.
Rym: Yep Emily's seen more and all she has said is that it's very sad Very sad.
Scott: Oh, maybe this will be my cool action show and that'll be my said.
Rym: Balance out, but if you want a cool action show probably the best action show to come out in a long time Is this last one?
Rym: government crime Investigation agent Zai Zen Joe Taro.
Scott: Oh god.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: You want to say in Japanese?
Scott: I'm gonna try.
Rym: I kaku kenryoku hansa kyosei tori shimari kansai Zen Joe Taro.
Rym: Yeah, it's just the sea kanji.
Scott: It's it's the show with the long name.
Scott: now This show.
Scott: you probably haven't heard of it because the name is long and no one can even tell you the show exists because the name Is so long.
Rym: Well, we were going to tell you about this show But I think I'm gonna have to take a quote from upside.
Rym: I used to link to a lot and I just kind of forgot about so recently but bossy gossy bakahatsu anime blog.
Rym: They tend to review anime pretty well.
Scott: Yeah there it's a really good anime review site and they get.
Scott: they always get lots of screenshots from the anime they review and sometimes videos and It's actually I'd say it might be the best anime reviews on the net.
Rym: I only stopped linking to him because their server was slow as shit, but they seem to have fixed that.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: And of course their tagline is because sometimes buses explode.
Rym: Yeah, so what they had to say about this anime is the following not gonna say the name again.
Rym: Zazen Jotaro's claim to fame is that it's quote that one anime with a freaking long name.
Rym: I haven't seen anyone write about this anime and I wondered why it Became pretty apparent after watching about one minute of the anime.
Scott: all right now Zazen Jotaro if you are someone out there who is entertained by Go Go 13 Then you will be entertained by at least one episode of Zazen Jotaro.
Scott: now Zazen Jotaro, he's no Duke Toga.
Scott: No, but he's just about as close as you can get.
Scott: he's pretty much If you'd replace the fucking and the killing of Duke Togo with saying da bomb with saying da bomb Da bomb and spending money.
Scott: You've got size and shorter.
Rym: all right Zazen Jotaro is probably the manliest man in all of anime and I say this because This is a man who when he has to steer his car, I'd Scott say you're a normal person you want to steer your car.
Scott: What do you do?
Scott: I turn the wheel.
Rym: Well, uh, that's not good enough for Zazen Jotaro.
Rym: You see when a badass a manly badass wants to steer his car He shoots the goddamn steering wheel and does that work.
Rym: that works perfectly?
Rym: That's what this show is.
Rym: The thing is I don't think it's a parody.
Rym: I don't think they're making fun of anything.
Rym: I think it's actually straight up.
Scott: I think it is straight up which is kind of weird.
Rym: So it starts with a fighter jet and a bunch of people in a control tower at an airport.
Rym: Yeah And they're like who could that be?
Rym: because this fighter jets coming and then Zazen who is flying this fighter jet has hacked the radar Screen terminal in the control tower to say hey It's me.
Rym: and then post a stupid picture of himself Stabbing his fingers and being all awesome.
Rym: He then ejects from the plane and parachutes to the airport.
Scott: Basically, there's a guy named Zazen Jotaro.
Scott: He's supposedly been dead for a few years But really he is awesome and alive and his current occupation is like government crime Investigation agent.
Rym: it's hard to say what his job is.
Scott: It's a government crime investigation agent, but you see he has his credit card designers gold card And he has basically infinite money.
Scott: That's his superpower is infinite money.
Rym: Yeah, Batman has biological webs.
Scott: Superman Batman has biological webs.
Rym: No, not that man.
Rym: I guess I meant spider-man.
Scott: spider-man's webs aren't biological.
Rym: Yes They are.
Scott: he invented them.
Rym: No, that's BS.
Rym: I like the ones from the movie.
Scott: You're stupid.
Scott: anyway Zazen Jotaro has infinite money.
Scott: He also has the power of the Zayner's Club credit card.
Scott: He also has the other superpower of make the Navy SEALs appear whenever he wants.
Rym: Oh my god, that's probably the point at which you realize just exactly what this show.
Scott: No I realized exactly what the show is about 30 seconds in.
Scott: well soon as he jumps out of the plane and says Dabam there's the scene when he gets attacked by those three Friars.
Scott: that's just random and stupid.
Rym: that scene or perhaps the Stupidest method of trying to assassinate someone ever where they have the four trucks box him in.
Scott: Yeah, he's driving down the highway in his awesome sports car.
Scott: four tractor trailers box him in He takes his gun and he shoots at the four corners of the roof of his sports car without looking without looking.
Scott: He just kind of you know reaches behind himself while always looking forward at the road and driving.
Scott: then he ducks his head down low.
Scott: So he's looking at the girl, you know, his head is below the you know The door of the car and he drives right under one of the trucks and the roof of the car gets ripped off.
Scott: Meanwhile, the trucks go off a cliff and he stops on the edge of the road and he's like, oh, yeah.
Rym: So in the last bit now keep in mind that there's absolutely no story.
Rym: No, no, no It is literally just seen seen seen seen.
Scott: It's basically watch Zazen Jotaro be a badass.
Scott: watch Zazen Jotaro be an even crazier.
Scott: badass watch him be an even crazier.
Rym: So eventually this Japanese government, whatever Yakuza really you don't know what he is He's.
Scott: he calls himself an elite of Japan.
Rym: So he corners eyes and he's got a bunch of guys with guns and he's like, ah You'll be abandoned.
Rym: the Japanese government would never abandon me because I'm a member of the elite.
Rym: They won't abandon me like.
Rym: they abandoned people like you you commoner.
Rym: and then just then One of the guys cronies gets a phone call and then the guys like we're not protecting you anymore.
Rym: The Japanese government called you're no longer a member of the elite.
Rym: They've abandoned you and Zazen's like see what I mean.
Rym: Haha, I'm Zazen Jotaro.
Rym: So the guy goes nuts and pulls a gun.
Rym: It's like oh well I'm gonna shoot size that.
Rym: and then in what is perhaps the second worst moment in the history of animation The Navy SEALs as far as I can tell all of them Swing around the top of the roof of this building.
Scott: Well, if they appear the same way bad guys appear in Hogan's Alley like whoop and then from behind the Navy SEALs appear the most poorly drawn Helicopters I have ever seen.
Scott: I could draw a better helicopter.
Scott: the helicopter and chop lifter for the Atari 2600 looks better than that helicopter.
Rym: I think you mean for the 7800.
Scott: It doesn't matter the 2600 helicopter looks better.
Rym: bossy gossy bakahatsu has a Really good screenshot of just how bad these helicopters.
Scott: Oh, do they really?
Rym: Yes Man they're so poorly done Like they would be okay in a show like Lupin.
Rym: Yeah, I guess they're okay here too because this is perhaps one of the worst things I've ever watched.
Scott: There's the helicopters.
Scott: Oh my god, they're so poorly drawn.
Scott: But yeah thing with this show is that everything is poorly drawn.
Rym: Everything is poorly animated character designs are inconsistent The animation is shoddy inconsistent poor bad shitty.
Scott: There's no music to be heard.
Rym: that the voice acting is da bomb Blah blah blah zai ten so Jotaro.
Rym: Oh blah blah blah zai zai and whatever credit card.
Rym: Zayna's Club.
Scott: Blah-blah-blah gun blah blah blah elite blah blah blah.
Rym: the camera angles don't make sense.
Rym: The proportions are off.
Rym: they use overlays constantly and stupidly.
Scott: Pretty much everything in the show.
Scott: Yeah, there was the part where like all the guns appear from like all sides of the screen except the top part of the screen And then they waggle and then they wiggle her out.
Scott: There's like two or three scenes that are like that.
Scott: Now I thought the animation was bad, you know And I realized the encoding of the show that we watched was a bad encoding.
Scott: So and the screenshots of the show on Basu Basu got to like whatever are much better.
Scott: Let's say it Basu Basu Baku Hatsu Yes, are much better than looking than the video that we watch.
Rym: Well, I think part of the regardless They're still terrible.
Rym: You see you look at these screenshots and you think all right.
Rym: The show looks actually pretty well drawn compared to a lot of anime.
Rym: The thing is all those screenshots don't really actually move.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's another part of it.
Scott: Is that the animation is really terrible?
Scott: So even though an individual frame might look okay I mean none of them look great, but they'll look okay.
Scott: any two frames in sequence will be all terrible and it's just God It's.
Scott: it's worse than like some college student animation projects I've seen now.
Rym: if I ran an anime club still I would probably show this on April Fool's Day.
Scott: Probably This is a show that no one's heard of and it's definitely falls into the category of so bad.
Scott: It's good However, however be warned.
Scott: This is basically the limit of so bad.
Scott: It's good it if it gets any more bad.
Scott: It's not good anymore.
Scott: It's just bad.
Scott: In fact, it's so bad that it's only good once.
Scott: if you watch it twice It'll just be so bad the second time around because it skips through.
Rym: I mean, it's well beyond the just kind of mediocre and it is outright bad.
Rym: Yeah, but when he says to bomb It's just so says the bomb.
Scott: You gotta play him saying to bomb in the show.
Rym: now I'll just let them watch this video.
Rym: cuz without the video you don't get the full effect.
Rym: cuz literally it zooms in on him and he looks at the camera and he says Duh bomb and then snaps his fingers and points him as you're like, hey, I'm so cool.
Rym: You're not so cool I'm Zazan Jotaro.
Rym: You can die in a fire.
Rym: Look at me in my credit card and my fancy sports car that I shoots shoots more than once.
Scott: Yeah, it's so weird because you know some of the best shows and manga out there are basically stories of incredible Manly badasses that do all sorts of badass things.
Scott: However, there's a point at which you become so badass That you just become comedic.
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: there's really no difference between this and say gogo 13 or crying Freeman or sanctuary Except that this takes the badassness to a much higher level.
Scott: they purposefully make scenes Where Zazan Jotaro can do things that are more badass than any?
Scott: Anime or manga character has ever been before and that makes it silly when really it's the same exact thing.
Scott: It's just more badass and therefore humorous.
Rym: See the thing is though.
Rym: It's so poorly animated I really can't.
Scott: it is bad in every way.
Rym: I still would rather watch Hokuto no Ken than this.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: I would much rather watch Hokuto no Ken than this.
Scott: I mean, it's so good.
Scott: No, no Ken is Is entertaining and ironic fashion.
Scott: This is entertaining just because you look at how bad it is and you go.
Scott: I can't believe someone made a show this bad.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I really feel bad for whoever did this show.
Rym: This is this is I said it's based on a manga.
Scott: I'm kind of curious to see what the VON manga looks like.
Rym: see there's a chance that the manga is okay And this is just an adaptation, but I can't see that hat.
Scott: I'm pretty sure this is a direct adaptation for the manga.
Rym: This does have a lot of the tropes of those geeky guy kind of manga.
Rym: We like it's not a geeky guy No, it's you know, but it has a lot of the things in it that you would expect to see in a sanctuary.
Rym: Yep Yep, but they're just so dumb and poorly executed.
Scott: Because basically what it does is it gets rid of all those Political talking scenes and those you know, why is someone doing this scene?
Scott: and it gets rid of the plot surrounding the action and it just has Incredibly badass action scene incredibly badass action scene one after the other.
Scott: yeah on stop I mean nothing in between.
Rym: look sanctuary has some awesome action scenes and this is a manga I'm talking about.
Rym: But the most in the most climactic moments and the most tense moments in that entire manga Were when someone just said something.
Scott: Yeah, and then everyone said You could watch this show with no sound and would be the same.
Rym: They're pretty much just saying his name over and over again.
Scott: You only have to listen to the parts where he says duh, but you can watch that on the link So it doesn't even matter.
Scott: Yeah, so I don't recommend you actually watch this show.
Scott: if you do I recommend you watch only one episode.
Rym: for the sake of humor I recommend that everyone watch this first episode because this will inoculate you to all sorts of bad anime out there.
Rym: Perhaps
Scott: and I do recommend everyone whether you like anime or not Go to the link for that We are putting up on the site at front recruit calm and in the middle of that page of vasugasu bakuhatsu calm You will find a video of him saying to bomb and you should watch that.
Scott: It's like 30 seconds of your life and it's worth it because that tells you everything you need to know about the show.
Rym: See while he's such a badass in the context of the show I don't think you could take out either Chuck Norris or George Washington.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Rym: Okay, Scott's watching him say to bomb again.
Rym: So I think we're done.
Scott: I think we are done and good God.
Scott: So it was a terrible show.
Scott: Ah, good.
Rym: Yeah, I really would like to hear Dave and Joel's thoughts on this show.
Scott: Yes Oh I'm pretty sure that like this is right up the alley of Dave and Joel and Daryl and maybe Gerald and all those people like.
Scott: They'll recognize that this show is terrible, but they will also be incredibly entertained by it possibly aroused possibly aroused And thus I want them to watch it.
Scott: I want to see if they know about it and Yeah, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at Frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: Devilman Messenger a getter Robo.
Scott: Is he the getter robo?
Rym: I guess whatever You see the getter robo.