Scott: It's Wednesday, November 28th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight Full metal Alchemist, which I hope you didn't do a show on before.
Rym: Let's do this You know for as much as I like anime.
Rym: It's kind of sad that I really haven't had the time to watch any in like the last two weeks.
Scott: Well, look at me I got four Unbeaten Wii games sitting on the Wii I got just I just got a DS game.
Rym: I stopped playing worms just long enough to do the show.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: the the pile of comics that I got early in the month has I mean, I've been eating away at it But it's actually grown some because I traded comics with some people like I've rid of stuff that I'm never gonna read again And they sent me stuff that was actually really good.
Scott: So and
Rym: I thought I was done I thought I was gonna start catching up and then a friend of mine lent me some Chiyo Saito manga that I'll talk about once I read the rest of it, which is gonna take a while
Scott: Yeah, but it's like I got these anime I want to watch.
Scott: I've downloaded the fan subs or I'm waiting for them on Netflix or who knows and It's just not gonna add next year.
Scott: I think when the new year rolls around there will be a resurgence of anime watching.
Rym: Yeah, I mean weren't we watching Gundam double-o and baka?
Scott: No Yep, all those things by the time we get around to watching they'll be on Netflix.
Scott: that will delete all the fans.
Rym: All right, we never even finished Nana.
Rym: We got right up to her.
Scott: Oh, man Is that gonna be on DVD or what I assume?
Scott: so it must be right.
Rym: I haven't been paying attention to be honest me either right.
Rym: So, uh, what do you got for me?
Scott: All right There's no anime news and I'm also.
Scott: I'm no anime news.
Rym: What about odex?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: I'm tired of just doing news from anime news network.
Scott: So, oh great.
Rym: So you're never gonna talk about anime news again Pretty much.
Scott: Um, so I'm gonna do a geek bite.
Scott: a geek bite on this manga that I read in that giant pile of comics I was talking about now.
Scott: This manga is called once upon a glash ma GL a SH Ma and if you read in the back of the book where sort of like, you know The funny extra section is they sort of talk about where the title came from and it's like one of the editors.
Scott: I think it says here Glass shoes and magic is is glass ma.
Scott: Yeah Once upon a glass from us, so it's sort of like this fairy tale title once upon a magic glass, right?
Scott: So I bought this manga.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: it's a one volume manga from a TV manga.
Scott: It's the whole thing as far as I can tell.
Scott: it's not volume one.
Scott: It's the whole thing For two reasons.
Scott: number one It was originally published in newtype and then I think also a newtype USA.
Scott: and you know those manga that are published in new Newtype are usually you know, not bad.
Scott: and the person who did the manga is Kumiko sue kane Which is the person who did the Phoenix Wright character designs if I am correct.
Scott: So I said well, I like them Phoenix Wright character designs.
Scott: I'll buy it.
Scott: It's only one volume now and it was good enough to be a new type.
Rym: That is a dangerous preposition because we all know that Liking character designs does not follow for liking a show in many cases.
Scott: But you know, I mean this thing the cover price is 1095.
Scott: I paid like seven or eight, you know, not a bad deal.
Scott: Oh, no so this manga Not good It's just.
Scott: it's not bad.
Scott: It's not like oh, this is painful.
Scott: Oh, this is terrible.
Scott: I don't want to read this.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm gonna talk about now.
Scott: Basically what this is about is there's a world and For some reason is no more women in the world.
Scott: There's only guys, right and Because for some reason no one knows guys are just getting magic powers sort of randomly.
Rym: But how do they know that girls aren't also getting magic?
Rym: There are no girls aren't any girls left?
Rym: You can't say that.
Rym: Well guys only are getting magic.
Scott: the magic power the the increase of the number of with male wizards started.
Scott: it coincided with the Complete disappearance of all females, uh-huh right, so you have these characters who work for sort of like the Government bureaucratic agency that sort of you know keeps track of.
Scott: you know Who has magic powers and what magic powers they have and how dangerous they are Uh-huh, and of course they end up having to deal with like people turning into dragons or you know people turning other people into women.
Rym: But I thought there were no women.
Rym: so what if I turn someone else into a woman do they immediately become a man?
Rym: what?
Scott: No, yeah, the the it's not like there's some magic force keeping women away.
Rym: It's just all the women disappeared Suddenly, so just make a bunch more women.
Rym: We're good to go.
Scott: You know, they got to make women without women not easy.
Rym: Ah Okay, we have at least one friend in our lives who got a sex change.
Rym: Imagine there are enough people in this world, but yeah But I want to become women that the magic will allow it to happen.
Scott: a sex change doesn't make you reproductive, but it's magic.
Scott: The magic in this book there isn't a whole lot of controllable magic like there's actually one really cool character Who's like he's a big tough, dude But he's afraid of his boss who isn't big who his boss is not big and scary But like his power is turning invisible, but he can't.
Scott: he doesn't like control.
Scott: it like does sometimes But not really.
Scott: mostly he turns invisible when he's afraid like sort of uncontrollably.
Scott: It's magic sort of like that.
Scott: Not not like we're all Merlin the Great here you know, it's like.
Scott: everyone has specific power and some people don't have a power like the main character right and It.
Scott: there's a few chapters and then in the course of this entire one volume You know, they reveal all sorts of stuff and then they solve the problem of where all the women went.
Scott: Oh spoiler, whatever and It's just sort of shallow and silly and it's got a lot of parts that are Fan service II and painful and anime cliche of every kind you can imagine.
Rym: and all right Scott Yeah in the spirit of what zero punctuation did today who would like this?
Rym: Who would this be recommended to to?
Rym: Improperly form a sentence as who would like this.
Scott: I think it definitely would.
Rym: are you gonna take the roundabout way of Defining an audience such that you have both insulted the audience and the work simultaneously.
Scott: I don't know because I actually think that you know the the cliche Stereotypical American fangirl would like this and they would think it was kind of cool.
Scott: It wouldn't be like their favorite thing ever.
Scott: I mean, it's someone's favorite thing ever, but I think the typical Stereotypical fangirl and the u.s.
Scott: Would enjoy this.
Rym: so it's not cute funny Stereotypical shallow like say dragon half which is one of my favorite shows Dragon half.
Scott: it is enjoyed by the typical fan boy.
Rym: I Just remember being so embarrassed when I had to convince my mom to go to the store and buy dragon half for me Because it said you've got to be 17 to watch this and I wasn't really sure why.
Rym: then I found out why.
Scott: Yeah, someone who like enjoys, you know, like the cliches of anime, you know.
Scott: Like if you like a love Hina, even though this is not a harem thing in any way But it you know has a lot of those same stereotypes that all those sort of you know anime have.
Rym: oh my god He looked at me punch in the face nosebleed sweat drop.
Scott: Like if you like the Auron this probably.
Scott: hey Auron's awesome.
Scott: Yeah, this isn't as good as the Auron but you know, it's the same.
Scott: if you like it You'll probably like this for similar reasons.
Rym: I guess How much of Auron have you seen?
Scott: Yeah a few up two episodes.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's the only thing I know that feels similar to this at all.
Scott: If anyone wants my coffee I'll be glad to trade you or sell it to you or something cuz I don't need it anymore.
Scott: It's in my get rid of file.
Scott: So yeah, right.
Rym: so I What's the name of it again?
Rym: Since someone pointed out that whenever we go by we should probably upon a glass muzz.
Scott: GLA sh ma by kumiko sue kane from a TV manga and I think if you get new type USA It was him.
Scott: You must have read it already, right?
Scott: If you if you're I don't know, right?
Rym: So I'm going to tell you a tale of whoa.
Rym: You see back when Scott and myself and the rest of the front row crew were still in college living at RIT in the middle of the wilderness surrounded by snow and ice Locked into our little set of buildings connected by tunnels trying desperately to avoid ever having to go to class or go outside.
Rym: We would often sit around the computer looking for cool things and one day we found this teaser Wasn't even a trailer.
Rym: It was a teaser for some Japanese movie and we were into the Foreign movies we've been going to.
Rym: the video barn which had the video bar is probably the best video rental place Ever at least in Rochester, you know, you can go there like you'd see a title and you pull it out And it just says on the front some name in Japanese But then in marker under that the owner has written very good sword fighting.
Scott: Alright this place still rents VHS's and they've got like every movie ever period and like literally.
Scott: this is how you know The video barn is the best video rental place.
Scott: I walk in and I say, you know, we my friend friend Scott Johnson had seen On the internet, you know, some randomly some movie called attack the gas station, right?
Scott: which we've talked about before on the show and on movies you should see.
Scott: and So we go to the video barn and we're like, do you have attack the gas station?
Scott: The guy just reaches behind him and puts the DVD on the counter and then he says you're really gonna like this.
Scott: Yeah, the video barn blockbuster, you know can suck video barns dick.
Rym: I mean the fact that I could walk in there and be like and the guy knew us.
Rym: cuz we came like every week and I'd be like, I don't know what I should watch.
Rym: and he'd say you want funny or violent.
Rym: I'd say a Violent.
Rym: he'd say watch this.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, those were good days Good days.
Rym: our Problem wasn't getting access to these movies because we could see pretty much any weird movie We wanted.
Rym: the problem was knowing which ones to get because even if we got recommendations He'd recommend pretty much everything in the store, which was usually accurate.
Rym: So we saw this teaser and it appeared from what we had seen to be the greatest movie ever made It qualifying that by saying if you were us in college
Scott: Yeah, if you're us in college and you look at this trailer for this movie Immediately all I could think was wow, that's gonna be the best movie ever.
Rym: It was the the music and what was going on in this teaser not trailer because I'll talk about that later.
Rym: But this teaser which I can't find anymore It had airships and technology and robots and it and it looked really serious explosions and awesomeness and a lot of scenes of like politicians yelling at each other.
Rym: and it was.
Rym: I Was so there and we looked forward to this movie look forward to this movie and we just kept watching the internet waiting for this movie to come out and we all kept watching the trailer and over and over again like check this out this is gonna be the best thing ever.
Rym: and Then at some point cash earn came out.
Rym: we saw it Not enough now independent of the fact that it was that it was hyped up to us mostly by us Say I'd seen it in a vacuum.
Rym: It was perhaps The worst movie I've ever seen Definitely one of the worst movies of our team.
Scott: and I would say even if it's not the absolute worst movie I've ever seen it is the most time.
Scott: I've wasted watching a movie.
Scott: It was the most pain I felt while watching the movie.
Rym: It was almost as bad as Clifford with Martin short.
Rym: It was awful.
Rym: Now.
Scott: It's terrible very bad very very bad.
Rym: But worse than that was that say my expectation was zero and that movie was you know negative 100 out of it.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: and the thing about it is it's not bad like a Fist of the North Star where you can laugh at it.
Scott: It's it's just bad.
Rym: It's bad like For all the explosions I saw in that trailer.
Scott: where the fuck were they in that movie?
Scott: all at the end, but all What.
Rym: why didn't the trailer show me the stupid costumes everyone was wearing?
Rym: Why didn't the trailer show me that no one see?
Rym: the trailer wasn't even in English.
Rym: We didn't have subtitles.
Rym: So we just said oh, man Seeing if the trailer had shown me in any way what those people were actually saying.
Rym: I probably would have known better.
Scott: It definitely would have known better.
Rym: But the worst thing is my expectation wasn't zero and I got negative 100. my expectation was 90.
Rym: So I had I had an expectation deficit of a hundred and ninety on this movie.
Rym: Fuck this movie.
Scott: I think the other problem with the movie is that they called it cuss Hearn, right?
Scott: Which is ca SS H e RN if we were more intelligent as we are now Right and more and less and more aware of things.
Scott: We would have realized at the time which we did not that it was related to kassan The the robot hunter which I've also seen written kass Hearn.
Rym: But I didn't know that because I'd seen.
Scott: I didn't think I didn't make the connection between Cassern and kassan until after seeing the terrible movie.
Rym: I made the connection when I saw that stupid helmet.
Rym: I was like, oh Oh This.
Rym: oh, it's that because I saw kassan robot hunter on the sci-fi channel a long time ago And I liked it because I was in fourth grade.
Rym: I Don't like it anymore.
Scott: Actually, well, no, you know what's on robot hunter the anime I can like in an ironic way.
Rym: Well, I think that there's also like the TV show but let me put it this way the the anime and the TV show.
Rym: I liked it when I was in fourth grade.
Rym: I didn't like it when I was in high school and learn better.
Rym: I like it again But only because of respect for old-school kind of style and aesthetic and as a result my thing of the day Which I'll get to.
Rym: but yeah, so The I would rather watch kassan robot hunter in English a thousand times then even watch the trailer to this Goddamn movie again.
Scott: Yeah, we tried to find the.
Scott: the teaser that you know made us think the movie was awesome So that you could see.
Scott: you know why we thought the movie was awesome, even though it sucks.
Scott: But all we could find was the trailer which reveals the movie to be the second that it is.
Rym: I don't think it reveals it fully.
Rym: you couldn't grok the fullness of how bad this movie is from seeing the mirror trailer But if you find the teaser, it was like 30 seconds long.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: I found freaking anime music video if you can call it that mashups between this and Skycaptain and like Gears of War machinima, oh god, but That's not my news and my news is not just this PSA that don't watch this movie.
Rym: so We're guests at the New York Anime Festival.
Rym: We're doing a whole bunch of events.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about it a lot because we're probably gonna do a whole show on it next week But suffice to say December 7th 8th 9th Javits Center, New York City.
Rym: It's gonna be you know, big anime con and It turns out that they're having the American theatrical premiere of cash earn at The New York Anime Festival.
Rym: now, you know, not only that but it's gonna be unedited Which means that if you are stupid enough to sit down and watch this you're gonna be stuck in that room in an extra 20 Minutes and I doubt highly that those 20 minutes are one uninterrupted explode.
Scott: I watched this thing on a fireside Friday when everyone else watched an anime club and It was so long I did was just.
Scott: I wanted it to be over so many times So making it even longer.
Rym: if that that unedited one might be the worst movie there is now Like I said, the 20 minutes might be one uninterrupted explosion, which would be kind of cool.
Rym: But I'll bet it's a lot more just insipid uninspired dialogue while people just talk about nothing and then fight with each other stupidly.
Rym: But yeah go to the New York Anime Festival.
Rym: do not for the love of God see this movie do not.
Scott: I want that premiere to be empty because People, you know to show the people who are bringing that movie to this country that it's a bad idea that we know it sucks.
Scott: You're not fooling anybody.
Rym: So right along two things of the day.
Rym: my things of the day are in fact two things.
Rym: They are the opener and closer to the 1973 cash earn anime And all I want to say is that I don't know why.
Rym: maybe it's nostalgia maybe just cuz I don't hear this sort of thing as much as I'd like to.
Rym: but This kind of music and this kind of styling even if I don't like the shows I just really dig these kinds of openers that I love.
Scott: I totally love all those old like robot anime type show like theme songs with like the like the oh Japanese guys singing Over like the you know, the this really really retro music.
Scott: I love that.
Scott: I love those songs.
Scott: I could have my iPod just full of that sort of music like the messenger song.
Rym: Don't forget go go go.
Scott: That's not the same kind of song I think like a man cross.
Rym: Oh, I think that the go go go song is in the same spectrum, but it's not the far end of it.
Rym: No, I don't think it's at the border between that and something else kinda.
Scott: But yeah, I like I would really like those kind of songs and this has them so awesome.
Rym: Yeah, and I'd recommend that you watch these and the anime and the animated movie before you watch.
Rym: Well, you know not before.
Rym: don't ever watch the movie we talked about.
Scott: No, do not watch the new light the relatively new live-action concern.
Scott: It is bad super bad All right in a bad way.
Scott: Yeah, my thing that is kind of lame.
Scott: So, you know, they make Hello Kitty everything.
Rym: Are you talking about the Hello Kitty treads on the bike?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, that's lame.
Scott: It's pretty lame.
Rym: Yeah, I know it's a bike tire and the treads are in the shape of Hello Kitty, which is that can't be the best shape.
Scott: No, that's not good for the traction.
Rym: I imagine I guess it could be okay.
Rym: If you're not I mean cuz you know They use basically non treaded kind of like racing slicks in certain kinds of street racing.
Scott: But yeah, I guess if you're just riding your bike around the street slowly and casually this won't be too bad.
Scott: But if you're riding serious, you know any speed this is not gonna be good.
Scott: You'll be slipping and sliding and in badness.
Rym: So what are we talking about tonight?
Scott: Let's talk about one of the biggest anime in recent years that we realized we never talked about And is also very easy to kill a show talking about ha funny you put it in those terms The the full metal alchemists full metal Alchemist.
Rym: now, it's rated on the anime news network encyclopedia.
Rym: This is F nav it open as Effectively the greatest fucking show to ever have been made.
Scott: according to everyone It's an okay show.
Rym: Well, here's the thing I'll set the stage full.
Rym: metal alchemists came out in an era which wasn't that long ago Where maybe it wasn't.
Rym: the error is just more that it was the big show of its time.
Scott: Well, we're basically what was going on right is that?
Scott: you know, we were in like with a third or fourth year college Something like that, right?
Scott: Yeah, and You know, we were super anime fans and we had you know We had been watching bit like tons and tons of anime starting freshman year.
Rym: We were like super anime watching right and mostly we were watching old stuff.
Rym: We'd never seen and kind of getting caught up in the anime We're
Scott: watching like the best shows ever and we were watching You know new best shows and it that the well was sort of drying up, you know I mean
Rym: it got to the point where I considered watching beyond the first season of fushigi Yugi.
Rym: That's how much anime I was watching.
Rym: I was running out.
Scott: Yeah, you know and we were watching all kinds of shows around then and you know It was a new anime season and everyone was grabbing mad fan subs with our mad bandwidths, right and You know, there are a lot of shows that came out that season.
Scott: We were trying different ones out and you know, some of them were good and some of them were okay.
Scott: but it was sort of like the first season where people were going through the fan subs looking for the new hot show and It's sort of everyone by what everyone was going to the same site download the same fan subs and sort of.
Scott: this Consensus came out that full metal alchemist was the hot show and like.
Scott: I had known it about it and I downloaded an episode but I hadn't watched it and then people started talking about it, so I watched it and Everyone was sort of like oh, yeah This shows the business
Rym: now as time went on and then when it got released, you know legitimately in the u.s.
Rym: And it became the super big show most and it seems like this happens Every like.
Rym: there's a cycle of years whereby the show will come out.
Rym: that does this to anime fandom where?
Rym: Everyone who's new ish to anime.
Rym: I'm not saying that older fans didn't like it too, but for people who are kind of just getting into it There's like a certain kind of person who was primed for this.
Rym: they'll see full metal alchemist or back when it was on for Shige Yugi did this.
Rym: a lot of shows have done this over the years and They would just kind of decide collectively that it's the best show ever.
Rym: that this show is so amazing and so beyond anything they've ever seen and ever will see and This is going to go down in history is one of the best anime ever and I guess you could call it full medical full medical full metal alchemist.
Rym: frenzy People were just Every con at a billion FMA cosplayers and they still do.
Scott: yeah I mean basically.
Scott: But we when I when we were at the point where we had only seen like four or five episodes of this show It was like, you know, wow.
Scott: Look here is you know, like a show that's giving us.
Scott: You know the kind of plots we get in our Final Fantasy type games, you know That's sort of plot which you know, everyone who's like anime fans.
Scott: That's their favorite kind of plot I know.
Scott: so everyone was digging that and it had a lot of awesome characters and people were digging that.
Scott: It was coming out right now.
Scott: So every time a new episode came out like everyone would get together and watch it like all man's a new episode.
Scott: Oh man's a new episode and the show was doing things that you know.
Scott: We're I guess okay ish and people and you had really good opening and closing music all the time.
Rym: Yep I mean, I think the thing is it seems like this show was almost Engineered to be that big show.
Scott: definitely was it had something to appeal to?
Rym: Everyone Everyone who was a fan of anime with rare exception there was something they would like enough to watch this entire show.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you like some fighting action, there's some fighting action.
Scott: if you like some, you know Character dramas this character drop you like this stupid bald man.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, you like wacky comedies.
Scott: They got wacky comedies pervertedness.
Scott: They got some girls in there the show girls.
Rym: We got girls.
Scott: The show is a little bit of everything Awesome j-rock j-pop opening and closing music The music actually that the show music is actually really good Even today, you know I looking back on it.
Rym: Yeah, it was kind of modal and there were a lot of like little almost light motifs and we'll talk about that later.
Scott: But and the show is coming out now.
Scott: Well, not now But then it was now so and everyone is all over it and there wasn't much competition from the other shows at the time.
Rym: What was even out at the same time?
Scott: I Don't really remember because FMA sort of overshadowed all of them.
Rym: Yeah but The show in addition to all that it had kind of the plot or the hook or what was going on was Kind of different and kind of interesting and I think if nothing else that is what drew a lot of people to it.
Rym: the story effectively is that there are two brothers the Elric brothers Ed and Al Elric and one thing led to another and Their mom is dead and they know alchemy and the principles of alchemy are kind of like the driving force of this universe and they kind of drill it into you constantly that Nothing can be created without destroying something equal, you know equivalent exchange to Oka Oka
Scott: Yep,
Rym: and I don't really how much should we spoil?
Rym: I mean, I feel like most people have seen this show.
Rym: I feel like this is more commentary than telling people to watch it.
Scott: Ah I don't know.
Scott: You probably don't want to give away too much action.
Rym: Well, let me put it this way the show the first two episodes Set up the whole scene for you without any doubt.
Rym: the first episode
Scott: the first two episodes are actually sort of like this contained like story on its own like just within the world of the characters that really introduces to you the core characters and Then sort of shows you the way the world works and then closes up that tiny story and then the characters move on To another place where the actual plot is happening, you know.
Scott: So it's sort of like they tell you sort of like this mini story with the characters sort of like in Trigun like the first like, you know, four or five episodes.
Scott: actually a lot of the episodes dragon are just like many stories that are sort of self-contained involving the characters to set everything up and Then they move on to where the big plot is elsewhere.
Rym: now What help is that?
Rym: all the things that introduced in this little two episode mini story?
Rym: Were great and also because they didn't really have to Flesh a lot out and in terms of you know beyond what what we see at face value And because they didn't bother with backstory yet.
Rym: They pretty much threw you in media res.
Rym: I used a fancy word It.
Rym: it just hit the ground running and you were pretty much captivated right away.
Rym: if you if you were gonna like the show at all, you liked it in the first five minutes of the first episode and Definitely by the end of the first episode.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And also they were able to make things appear extremely symbolic and there was a lot of like.
Rym: I guess the theme or the moral or kind of what was going on in that first two episode thing.
Rym: I Don't want to say it was deeper than the actual show because I don't think it was.
Rym: I think it's more that It set the show up to be very heavy.
Scott: It did the show definitely, you know appeared even though I think it was.
Scott: the show in reality is a lot shallower than it appears.
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: it's sort of.
Scott: I think Gerald was complaining that like the the director has actually a trend In all the the things they direct of making things Appear to be a lot deeper than they actually are, you know, it's sort of like, you know They go around saying toga coca like there's some this big deep hidden message of you know Symbolism and well
Rym: at the same time.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil but I do point out what happens with all that.
Scott: But while there is a metaphor some message it's not a super deep message, it's just.
Rym: I'll put it straight up in the first two episodes one of the One or two of the themes that come up and they hit you pretty strong with this are a lot of kind of controversial and possibly uncomfortable ideas about the nature of religion and belief and fanaticism.
Scott: and Yeah, but it's not like it's.
Rym: some Was not really about that But the first two episodes in a vacuum very much made it appear that the show was about that.
Scott: Oh, that is true.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: There was very much this science versus religion.
Rym: What is belief?
Rym: What are we?
Rym: What are we made of?
Rym: and the show didn't really keep running with those ideas as much as it probably could have.
Scott: Yeah after after that stuff the show basically the format of the show is Everyone.
Scott: they set up or they bring in a bunch of characters that everyone loves and then they just sort of play up the characters in.
Scott: You know ways that make you continue to love them because there's a character for everyone no matter what you like and they just keep
Rym: playing
Scott: up all the characters and you know to make them be at their best all the time and They just keep moving forward with the plot at a steady pace to keep you going.
Scott: and it worked.
Scott: Everyone was watching it every week and continued to look forward to watching every week until it ended.
Rym: So I thought what they did that was actually was I I think it worked really well was since they started kind of in the middle of the story and then they flash back.
Rym: so you're introduced to a Boy, who's kind of yelling but yet he's powerful for some reason and all these other minor characters and a giant empty suit of armor Huh?
Rym: And you then it seems like almost superficially.
Rym: All right, this is gonna be one of those kind of Nonsensical silly shows despite all the themes and morals and things that we've been kind of peppered with right away.
Rym: and Then you so you're kind of set up to you know Where the show is going to get to and then it backs up and you see how they got to where they are.
Rym: Yeah, and then it dawns on you that because it when it backs up It's just two young brothers two little boys with a sick mother and a missing dad.
Scott: Yeah It's the typical, you know slowly reveal the past instead of like Trigun revealed the past all at once.
Scott: But this is the typical.
Scott: many shows do this where you slowly reveal more and more about the hidden past Until the whole past is finally revealed and they did it, you know About it.
Scott: They didn't do it amazingly.
Scott: They did it, you know as well as could be expect.
Scott: Well, I think what is a formula and they executed it, you know as it should be.
Rym: but enough about.
Rym: I mean just to.
Rym: I don't Really go into like.
Rym: I don't want to discuss the show as though we're trying to sell it to people who haven't seen it and I don't want to I don't know review it fully because that would require, you know spoilers and final thoughts.
Rym: But I think what really drew me into the show the point at which I decided that this show is going to be great.
Rym: I'm gonna like it was after the first two episodes and they go through the backstory And I'll spoil in case you haven't heard.
Rym: but the deal with their mother.
Rym: because essentially what happens is their mother dies.
Rym: I don't think that's that much of a spoiler, but she dies.
Rym: She had cancer or something.
Rym: she'd been sick for a long time and These boys know alchemy because their father was an alchemist who went off to war or something.
Rym: They're not too clear about that.
Scott: They don't really say he's like.
Scott: they show you the family photo and the dad is like blurred out.
Rym: You can't see his face but The and this is actually and I know this is the moment because our friend Luke had avoided this show on fansub.
Scott: Well, because what he had the opinion that it's popular it can't possibly be good.
Rym: Emily avoided it for similar reasons and a lot of people did because The hysteria around this show by a lot of fans really turned off a lot of I don't want to say more discerning people But maybe it's it seemed
Scott: really
Rym: Possible that the show was one of those crap shows that people suddenly get really really into for no good reason.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I can't I can't blame the people who felt that way because like I felt the same way initially about Naruto I sort of didn't go and see Naruto on purpose And then I saw the first four episodes like at anime club, you know, I didn't go out of my way to see them I just happened to see.
Rym: I think there's a difference between if I see a show just in a vacuum or if I'm at a Con and like eight kids wearing identical poorly made costumes run past me yelling the characters names from a new show.
Rym: Yeah, I just I probably irrationally feel like maybe I should avoid that show.
Rym: Yeah, I can't blame anyone.
Rym: No, our friend Luke is a huge anime fan had avoided it and avoided it and avoided it.
Rym: So finally, we're at Otakon.
Rym: We're seeing Laruku live in that awesome concert.
Scott: Yep, and then the band that did this, you know the second opener for the show The Fullmetal Alchemist.
Rym: Yeah, that was also like I think possibly one of the best Otakons just for that concert.
Scott: So at this concert before the concert started while you were sitting there waiting for them to come on Right on the giant video screens.
Scott: They show the first episode of Fullmetal Alchemist.
Scott: and You know This is the first time Luke had ever seen the show that he was avoiding.
Rym: and I believe they also showed a trailer Like for the show.
Rym: it was like they were shown the first episode and the short little trailer kind of thing like this is what this show is about and I remember they revealed to some degree the fact that the boys tried to bring their mother back to life with alchemy.
Rym: But what do you trade it?
Rym: You know Toka Koka equivalent exchange?
Rym: Well, we've got all the components of a human body.
Rym: we've got the sulfur and we've got the whatnot.
Rym: What do you trade for a human soul?
Scott: Dan Dan Dan I think that is one thing that definitely attracted a lot of people to the show is that you know Part of the.
Scott: I think one of the main reasons that a lot of American people in the u.s You know became such fans of anime in the first place way back was because you know, they like Animation and cartoons because that's you know, what they grew up on and They were looking for.
Scott: animation and cartoons that had more serious stuff going on in them instead of you know Looney Tunes drop an anvil on this our serious fan and this our serious business.
Rym: So
Scott: when you have a show that's you know dealing with issues like, you know Bringing your mother back from the dead and then having to sacrifice your soul and getting horrible punishment for that and stuff like that That's sort of the kind of thing that really attracted people anime in the first place And thus if you have a show like that will attract more people
Rym: and also helped at the show.
Rym: I mean that was a very dark element and I remember seeing that like when the whole thing with their mother was revealed Initially, that was a chilling Scary dark disturbing and sad scene in an otherwise serious but kind of upbeat and silly anime and it seems like shows that have Elements of humor and elements of seriousness like that as long as they don't go overboard like Gravitation which was like super happy super sad super happy super sad.
Rym: It seems to work really well, especially in terms of getting people to watch the show.
Scott: Well, what you do is you get it happens I think more in Fullmetal Alchemist than any other show I've seen is sort of those, you know The.
Scott: those times when you know They they all they stay bring the stark Contrast right up in your face.
Scott: like you see these characters laughing and making stupid jokes about being short that aren't funny and They're like and then they remind you like there's actually horrible.
Rym: and you see the characters going like And then it cuts back to them being happy and you just can't help but think.
Rym: but they went through all of that.
Scott: It's like the put they'll have kill you.
Scott: they'll show you characters laughing the voice actors will be laughing kinda and then they're playing like the dark theme music and Like half the screen is the character laughing.
Scott: the other half of the screen is like some Visual symbol that reminds you of a horribleness that is awaiting.
Rym: the music did that really well in this show.
Rym: the soundtrack we mentioned before the the musical motifs like.
Rym: there were certain themes and phrases of music that were Kind of synonymous with certain characters or certain events or certain memories in the show and you'd start to associate these with certain kinds of happenings.
Rym: So a lot of scenes that would otherwise be just a normal scene or just seen in the anime.
Rym: They play music that didn't fit and you think back to other scenes for that music played.
Rym: and I think that was one of the Show's strongest points is its use of music to create a mood.
Scott: Yeah, the music Remember later in the show.
Rym: There's that scratchy song playing on the record that Yeah Yep, and that was one creepy scene I gotta say in the music in the show.
Scott: It's not the best music ever for an anime But it's definitely among the best music's for animes mean 15.
Rym: it's one of them and they use.
Scott: the music is as bad as well as it can be used.
Rym: It's not the best music like ever but it's one of the best uses of music in anime.
Scott: I've seen in a long time Yeah, the other anime is you know, a lot of animes.
Scott: now They're not using music, you know, because the use of music in anime in general is one of the things that really sets anime apart.
Scott: You know, you have these original Composed orchestral score just for the show.
Rym: Look at eska flown a. how many just basically symphonies were written just to be background music in that show.
Scott: Yeah, and you know they they have a different you know song for every possible theme and mood in the show and for every character and for every type of Thing that goes on.
Scott: and they they reuse them or they reuse them by changing them slightly to sort of you know really set the mood and the tone and whatever is going on and Full metal alchemist does that as well as that anime can.
Rym: basically the show really seemed to kind of change gears in Pretty much every possible sense at the perfect intervals to keep anyone interested like no matter What kind of scene was going on sad happy fighting whatever.
Rym: they'd always kind of switch it up or cut away or flash to something different.
Rym: it's like they were juggling all the different kinds of anime fans and making sure that every kind of fan had their five minutes in Every episode.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So do you think if someone hasn't seen full metal alchemist?
Scott: Do you think it's worth it to like buy all the DVDs and watch it?
Rym: I think it's worth it to watch the DVDs on Netflix, perhaps maybe it's you.
Rym: This is what I find interesting because I this happens to people a lot, especially.
Rym: well maybe not especially but just because I see it more here because I pay attention more.
Rym: but it happens to anime fans where When a show is good and you're watching it as it comes out It seems like it's just this amazing show.
Rym: Yeah, but then when you're done with it and you you're so satisfied it was so great and then years later you think back and You feel like you could never watch the show again, or you wouldn't enjoy it Or maybe it wasn't as good as you thought it was even though you remember enjoying it.
Scott: I definitely have.
Scott: I definitely have that feeling where.
Scott: well I think part of it is.
Scott: I didn't enjoy the ending as much as some other people did.
Scott: I mean it was okay, but it wasn't like oh my god an awesome ending.
Rym: well the end made me cry that doesn't?
Rym: that doesn't necessarily mean it's a great ending because I've Cried at the end of I think a good third of all the anime I've ever seen.
Scott: it didn't make me cry I was just like.
Scott: it wasn't like I was Expecting or an anticipating an ending that would like blow me over and it was just kind of an ending like ah an ending.
Rym: Yeah, see the thing is regardless of the physical, you know what happened at the end of the show because that I think could have been had a lot better and It pretty much The I. well this is my main beef with the show and I'll do a quick aside about this because it relates to the movie the show ends on.
Rym: They tried to have their cake and eat it too, but the cake was a lie There is.
Rym: they tried to milk every possible way.
Rym: the show could have ended by kind of doing all of them like ah and you get this kind of ending but then up and you also get this kind of ending and They instead of wrapping up all the loose strings they kind of unfrayed the end of the rope and made a million more strings and then ended on a Super cliffhanger.
Scott: Yeah, I definitely like.
Scott: during the course of the show There were like certain characters and certain plot lines that were ended Climactically like, you know about two-thirds of the way through the show like there was a holiday So they had to miss an episode because there was a soccer game or something like that.
Scott: So the next week there was a double episode and with that double episode Which is basically two episodes that I think aired together they like ended a part of the plot line and remitted made a big reveal and a climax and That was like super awesome at least at the time and I felt like the show the end of the whole show should have ended.
Scott: You know been as awesome as that.
Scott: well The thing is it wasn't.
Rym: it could have been because the end of the show basically set up The best fucking movie ever much like cashier and set us up for the best fucking movie ever.
Scott: It was like, all right still haven't seen the Full Metal Alchemist movie cuz I know better.
Rym: Yeah, but if the movie had been what it should have been then Then the end of Full Metal Alchemist would have been great because it set up a great movie.
Rym: but from what I have heard from everyone I trust the Full Metal Alchemist movie is Barely, if at all worth watching.
Rym: I'll probably watch it someday Yeah, but it's I don't want to spoil at all what it's about because that that actually ruins the kind of big reveal in the show.
Scott: I think generally my feelings on Full Metal Alchemist is that when I was watching it when it was new it felt pretty awesome.
Scott: I mean, it didn't feel as awesome as like, you know the best shows ever But it was like one step under the best shows ever.
Rym: It was no Cowboy Bebop Escaflowne, Evangelion, Trigon.
Scott: No, it was like right under all those shows which was you know better than any anime I had seen in a long time.
Scott: And now looking back it feels like it's two steps behind those shows, you know.
Scott: And like at the time it felt better than it does.
Scott: looking back on you know what.
Rym: I'll sum it up The show was a great show to watch but it's not a show to rewatch and it wasn't a show that had staying power.
Rym: It's like Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: I could finish it.
Scott: I could watch any episode at any time any number of times for the rest of my life.
Scott: It's probably the only show that can do that.
Rym: Well, let's see.
Rym: What is there that's like that for us?
Rym: There's the first three Star Wars movies as in the fourth fifth and sixth Star Wars movie.
Rym: Yep, and like Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: I think Escaflowne for me.
Rym: I just that show was so great I've only seen it once.
Rym: I've seen it three times all the way through and every time I love it.
Scott: So there are lots of leiji Matsumoto things that I can watch but it's like I have always.
Scott: It's not like I can watch them over and over again.
Scott: It's that when I get in the mood to watch one I can watch one and I'm in the mood to watch them Relatively often.
Rym: Yeah, it's just the show Wasn't good enough to watch again like.
Rym: I think most of what drew people forward and most of what kept me going was that I Wanted to know the mysteries of this world.
Rym: I wanted to know what was behind that gate and why the things happen the way they did and what does all the stuff where their dad went who he was and all those mysteries.
Rym: and It's kind of like as the mysteries got revealed.
Rym: I cared less about the show and unlike say an Escaflowne which is just so well executed that I could watch it again or unlike say a Nutenna where I can watch it again and get more of it because now I'm like getting Understanding from learning the reason behind a mystery or something that happened later in the show Could kind of illuminate things that happened earlier.
Rym: I feel like that's not true in Fullmetal Alchemist.
Scott: Fullmetal Alchemist after one viewing everything is illuminated There's no more to to illuminate.
Rym: everything is illuminated by the way is a fantastic movie, right?
Scott: It is Yeah, also I'm buying the Fullmetal Alchemist manga like I have every volume of it.
Scott: It's in English so far.
Scott: Yeah, we should probably mention this Yeah, and I'm not stopping buying it.
Scott: But first of all, it is by no means some amazing manga of all time.
Scott: It's no Akira, Tezuka, whatever.
Scott: It's a slightly above average manga.
Scott: That is funny and entertaining and for me at least it's worth buying at a discount price, which is what I pay.
Scott: I wouldn't buy it if it was full price.
Scott: and For the first part of the manga, it's a lot like the show.
Scott: I mean the first volume is basically a lot like the first few episodes, you know, and whatever.
Scott: But then a few volumes in I think like six to ten.
Scott: I don't remember exactly where.
Scott: Basically, the manga becomes completely different from the show like super different.
Scott: There are just Blatant differences like wow, that is not like it at all.
Scott: And there's.
Scott: there's characters in the manga that never appear in the show.
Scott: There's things that like things are.
Scott: there's just basic facts Like who people are is different in like.
Scott: there's characters that are in both but it'll be the same like character design and the character of a different name in one in the other or a different role in One in the other or act a different way in one in the other.
Scott: and so the anime and the manga are not equal Which is in a way it's actually okay because if you've seen the show already It's not like Death Note where if you've seen the movie the anime There's no reason to buy the manga and vice versa because they're exactly the same.
Scott: You can read the full melagamous manga having read the having watched the anime and you'll get something different out of it.
Scott: It's a different thing and it's pretty.
Scott: it's a lot longer and it goes more but it's most.
Scott: it's more typical anime plotty stuff and less of the the deep kind of stuff though or at least the Pretending to be deep stuff.
Rym: I mean, I guess in the end FMA was kind of just a blockbuster anime much like a blockbuster movie.
Rym: It's great to watch you'll enjoy the ride.
Rym: You'll probably not bother watching it again.
Scott: Yeah, it's just like one of those like summer fun fests you go to the movie theater You spend some money you sit down you go woo his explosions whatever and you know, it's pretty awesome.
Scott: while you're in there You know, it's rocking your socks off and then you know a year later if someone mentions the movie like yeah I saw that in the theater.
Scott: Yeah, there's no really reason to ever see that again It's it's not worth.
Rym: my thing is I just don't think the show will have the staying power.
Rym: Even you know in the years to come that you know cowboy bebop Italia had.
Rym: I think that it's kind of gonna go the way for Shiggy Yugi.
Rym: I just use that because it's the perfect example of a similar Show in terms of how the fans reacted to it.
Rym: And I think it'll always be known.
Rym: like a lot of people just know for Shiggy you even if they haven't seen it and you Always see at least one It's for Shiggy.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: No, alright, Scott Johnson always said But you always see a Miyake or two.
Rym: it pretty much every anime con.
Rym: you're probably always gonna see an Edward Elric or maybe I'll lost at every anime con for the next decade or so.
Rym: But the show is not gonna be remembered as this great work ten years from now.
Rym: Well, I think ten years from now cowboy bebop will still be considered one of the greatest works of anime probably.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.