Scott: It's Thursday January 11th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight geek Thunderdome.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So a little while ago and what is a semi-rare occurrence in the geek house meaning This is the first time it's happened in a long time We had some non geeks in the house while we were here and there's not much you can do with non geeks.
Rym: I mean, they're cool people.
Rym: I know from IBM and I had a lot of fun with the people at IBM.
Rym: I mean, I was probably all things considered one of my favorite jobs ever other than obviously when I worked for the government which was super awesome because you didn't have to do any work and they paid you a lot of money.
Rym: and If no one cared about the well, it was great.
Rym: just hanging out, but you know, I had fun there.
Rym: But hanging out with non geeks.
Rym: I mean, it's not like the bad people.
Rym: What do you?
Rym: what can I say to him?
Rym: What joke can I make?
Rym: it's always not awkward, but there's always this kind of disconnect.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, huh?
Scott: What can I say?
Scott: Well, I can't say you can't hold ten Pokemon Yeah, or we were watching.
Rym: we showed him some cowboy bebop, which they kind of liked.
Rym: I mean everyone.
Rym: I've never met someone who I've shown cowboy bebop to who didn't like it and they They would just wouldn't be humans if they didn't like it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but
Rym: like There's a joke about big O and I you know I make the joke about big O and because
Scott: it is a scene in episode 3 where Faye looks at her Well, not her watch but this bracelet and she pushes a button on it and then she says show time We're like big O. and they totally were like why?
Rym: Though to their credit there was.
Rym: they were reminded of Star Wars and they made a fairly pertinent Star Wars joke They did to which I made an equally pertinent Star Wars joke and they laughed at it, which was good.
Scott: Yep, who knows if they actually realized it was a Star Wars.
Rym: No, they did.
Rym: There's no way they didn't.
Rym: unless it was I can't imagine what else that could have been from.
Scott: Just let you just laugh.
Scott: when someone says something cuz you know, you're supposed to you know happens.
Scott: You do that a lot.
Rym: Well, I What are you doing?
Rym: a social situation where you're hanging out with someone.
Rym: you have nothing against them.
Rym: They're a cool person, but you just have almost nothing in common with him like anything.
Scott: That was.
Scott: the other thing is that we're like, alright, we're eating dinner where you got Chinese food in the living room.
Scott: What do we watch?
Scott: we got to watch something?
Scott: Well, we don't have television.
Scott: We don't have a movie is too long because we got to get these people out of our house pretty soon So we can do the show so we don't want to borrow him.
Rym: I mean nothing's worse than going to someone's house and they try to show you something.
Rym: That's two hours long that they like that.
Rym: You really don't care about.
Scott: Yeah, so we're like, huh?
Scott: What do we got?
Rym: cowboy bebop was the only thing we had that was the closest thing to something a normal person might enjoy That is even anywhere near our house.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like we hang out with all these geeks and people all the time and you know Everything seems kind of on the level and as soon as someone who's even slightly normal comes into the fold It's like whoa, it's like what do you say?
Scott: It's like the same way they must feel if we go to their house and they're like, whoa.
Scott: Yeah, it's mad.
Rym: like any time we started talking about a geeky thing They just kind of get quiet and anytime they were started talking about.
Rym: I don't know something real in the world.
Rym: We were just like, uh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, how about that weather?
Rym: Talked about the weather like four times.
Scott: All right, so it's Thursday.
Rym: It is Thursday We'll get to the show in a bit, but we don't really care about the news.
Rym: So he just kind of picked some random stuff out there on the internet.
Scott: Yeah, I picked your standard Fark style injustice story and I picked it.
Rym: Well, there was another one that I almost talked about but I decided that too much injustice zombies something Mmm, yeah swallow joke.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So instead I just wanted to talk about Cedar Point and coincidentally they've re-begun construction.
Rym: Yes, re-begun on Cedar Point's new roller coaster the maverick Uh-huh.
Rym: Now I didn't care at first.
Scott: When's the last time we rode a roller coaster?
Scott: Wildwood?
Rym: God at Wildwood We paid like eight bucks each to ride this chintzy little wooden roller coaster.
Scott: It was pretty good though.
Scott: Well, here's the thing.
Scott: Mostly because I hadn't had a roller coaster in a while.
Scott: Yeah It's like having chocolate after not having chocolate for a month.
Rym: I'll say this it was a piss-poor roller coaster And as far as even as far as wooden coasters go it was pretty low on the scale.
Rym: It was probably the worst wooden coaster I've ever been on But I hadn't been on a roller coaster since the last time I went to Cedar Point Which was when I was in high school.
Rym: No, no, no, it was after my freshman year of college.
Rym: I went one more time.
Rym: So that was a pretty fantastic roller coaster all things considered.
Scott: Yeah, the last roller coaster I went on before that one.
Scott: Yeah, the last time I went on a roller coaster before what the great white in Wildwood Oh God was.
Scott: I went on the Superman at Six Flags New England in the summer of 2001.
Rym: While I'm generally down on a lot of non-seater point places the Superman gets respect.
Scott: It was pretty good.
Scott: It's actually that is also like the biggest and baddest roller coaster I've been on mostly because I don't go in upside downy ones was yeah Why what?
Rym: upside downy roller coasters are the second best kinds of roller coasters now?
Scott: I prefer it.
Rym: it goes in this order.
Rym: the standard three Hill is the best roller coaster as far as I'm concerned Followed right away by upside downy followed by wooden followed by well from there.
Rym: We have to argue semantics.
Scott: I'm a big fan of Wooden roller coasters But as long as they're like newer wooden ones like the ones that go digga digga digga And they're all shaky not so good.
Scott: But there's some like the Cyclone or the Gwazi that are the high quality stuff And it's a nice smooth ride and real fast and real fun.
Scott: I'm also a fan of you know stuff like the Superman which is badass.
Rym: see now Here's the semantics.
Scott: there's a lot of action.
Scott: You know I don't like to have it like a long stretch.
Scott: It's got to be left right up down.
Rym: See hands down.
Rym: the best roller coaster.
Rym: I've ever been on is still the Millennium Force at Cedar Point.
Rym: That's a pretty damn fantastic roller coaster.
Scott: It might be it's my style too.
Scott: It goes.
Scott: It's not upside down upside down It's real fast.
Rym: It's super fast.
Rym: There's a lot of up and down a lot of left and right some tunnels a gigantic Hill.
Scott: that's just oh god.
Rym: You can see Canada from that hill.
Scott: yeah, well.
Scott: It's pretty close to Canada.
Rym: No, it's not like.
Scott: I don't know it would.
Scott: one thing if the roller coaster was in Louisiana and you could see Canada.
Rym: no it's in northern, Ohio, but you can see Canada due to a technicality because there's this island.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but dude I built this roller coaster in The you know Baja, California, and you could totally see Maine from there at the top Right.
Rym: so fun fact for the day.
Rym: well one this roller coaster.
Rym: to get back on topic I was really unimpressed with it.
Rym: I thought why is Cedar Point building?
Rym: this would intimate.
Rym: even make a roller coaster this tiny because it's like a hundred feet tall.
Rym: Then I looked at it.
Rym: I finally saw a picture of it and Basically they took the second good part of the Millennium Force Which is going real fast close to the ground left and right twisty.
Rym: And they made a whole roller coaster like that with some magnetic launches in the middle not just in the beginning.
Scott: It's one of those.
Scott: you know you're going you're going surprised you're going faster You're going real fast real close to the ground.
Scott: on this one I kind of wish someone make a roller coaster where the whole thing was constantly Accelerating.
Scott: you who with magnetic force until the end.
Rym: that'd be pretty cool.
Scott: Actually, you just constantly going faster even going uphill like you go down a hill then you start going up But you're going faster than you were going down And then when you get to the top of that hill and go down you're going even faster.
Scott: It just gives like a hundred miles an hour you go.
Rym: Oh, God some face flies off someday.
Rym: We got to make a trip to Cedar Point one final time.
Scott: We should you know we should do.
Scott: we should make a roller coaster that doesn't go up and down.
Scott: It's just a big ring just a horizontal ring not a vertical one and you go around in a circle But you go around in a circle at like 300 miles an hour.
Scott: I got ridiculous.
Rym: I did that at space camp.
Rym: It's not fun.
Scott: That's gotta be fun.
Rym: No.
Rym: It's not fun It hurts.
Rym: you feel like you're gonna vomit But you can't.
Rym: it feels like someone has their fist in yours.
Scott: well You know how they made like they used to have the upside down ones that were a perfect circle And then they made the ones that were sort of like.
Scott: you know the little loop.
Scott: Yeah, and the loop doesn't make you bargo, but the circle does.
Scott: oh, yeah Maybe there's a way you could do that on the ground.
Rym: no the issue was the g-forces.
Rym: They spin you around and you can't.
Rym: you'd barely breathe And it just sucks and you get off and everyone else is like isn't it awesome.
Rym: I can't wait for my turn and you just say Good luck with that.
Scott: That's all you but didn't you see the video?
Scott: I am interested in that Japanese coaster though.
Rym: Oh, yeah We'll save that for a thing of the day.
Rym: or maybe when we talk about roller coasters didn't we already?
Rym: yeah I don't know.
Scott: I'll tell you wait until we actually go to an amusement park which we plan to do for years and still haven't done.
Rym: yeah someday We're gonna go to a real roller coaster park like either a really good Six Flags or cedar point.
Scott: They pretty much Six Flags, New England because that's the best place within reach or cedar point because that's the best place slightly out of reach.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if we go to a water park.
Scott: We'll either go to Six Flags, New England because it's within reach.
Scott: see this.
Scott: I love litter bond, which is out of reach.
Rym: I love roller coasters, but I don't love them enough to put significant effort into getting to them anymore.
Rym: Yeah, cedar point is worth the 60 bucks to get into me.
Rym: It is not worth going to Ohio from here.
Scott: You know what they should really do is like instead of having amusement parks You know, I mean like come here and there are a bunch of rides.
Scott: Why can't there just be like I go down the street I see a supermarket.
Scott: I see a blockbuster I see a roller coaster And then if I want to ride the roller coaster, I walk up and I pay five bucks and I ride.
Rym: well where I grew up in Michigan, there was lakeside mall.
Rym: and inside of lakeside mall in the middle of this two-story mall one section was blocked off all like the whole two stories vertically and where the store would be there was big glass window going all the way up and down and Inside of there was a small water park with a. The slides went like around the malls that had Ferris wheels.
Scott: real fancy Ferris wheels?
Scott: No No I've been to malls with carousels.
Rym: real fancy care thing had a water park with water slides where the tubes Were like kind of it like they ended here in this big pool.
Rym: You can see people like come in and there's like a translucent one that went across the top and they went around other parts of The mall I guess in the back substructure or whatever.
Scott: dude if I'm ever see.
Scott: that's one thing.
Scott: They're building like bigger and bigger malls trying to compete with the Mall of America Like they're doing something in Syracuse or the giant mall.
Scott: and what a lot of places are trying to build giant malls.
Scott: Right, none of these giant malls have a monorail Monorail monorail.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Alright, so so I got their standard story of modern injustice.
Rym: ah Injustice, I know thee well.
Scott: There is a substitute schoolteacher in Connecticut Probably near Eastern Connecticut in near Norwich because the Norwich newspaper is reporting on it Right now.
Scott: this teacher has been found guilty of exposing children to porn.
Scott: They are going to be sentenced.
Scott: The maximum sentence is 40 years in prison, but they probably won't get the maximum sentence.
Scott: Anyway, the defense says it was a case of spyware on the school machine that the teacher didn't like.
Scott: You know open some porn and show it to kids like hey kids check this out That she was just using a computer and there's a bunch of pop-ups that happen to have porn and kids saw it.
Scott: The school did not have did have.
Scott: they did.
Scott: they had content filtering software, you know to filter out porn But the license was expired, huh?
Scott: according to another article Computer expert Herbert Horner who I trust who performed a forensic Examination of the computer for the defense.
Rym: All right, he had a class on that.
Scott: cops who took it said Amero might have.
Scott: Amero is the guilty person may have been redirected to the sexually oriented sites through a Hairstyling site accessed from the computer.
Scott: He said the site allowed spyware to be downloaded onto the computer which allowed the pop-ups.
Scott: According to one source only one source So who knows the trial judge?
Scott: Was seen falling asleep during proceedings and made comments to the jury that she wanted the case over by the end of the week.
Rym: now I would hope I wish that I didn't believe that outright but I've been to some trials where the judge obviously didn't give a shit.
Scott: It was also reported that the judge attempted to pressure the defense into an unwanted plea deal in place of a trial.
Scott: the defense attorney Moved for a mistrial shortly before closing arguments Friday based on reports that jurors had discussed the case at a local restaurant.
Scott: The detective in the investigation admitted there was no search made for adware which can generate pop-up ads.
Scott: Was justice done here?
Scott: a bad spot just that you can read the article that there's only like one sentence left.
Scott: All right, while oh and then the local newspaper is like Yeah, the local newspaper is kind of against this defendant.
Scott: They're like, this is bad.
Scott: You shouldn't be showing porn to kids.
Scott: We need to you know, all right.
Rym: So we're not arguing that showing porn to little kids is a good thing, especially in school.
Scott: Well, I mean I Personally do not have a problem with little kids seeing naked people or naked people doing it.
Scott: You know if I had kids and they saw porn I'd be like man that I would be like.
Rym: that is porn.
Scott: Oh, but but at the same time it's a public school in a public school.
Scott: You cannot show kids prawn.
Scott: That's not cool.
Scott: It's obvious why it's not cool.
Rym: No It seems like this whole issue comes down to the fact that not a single person involved From the defendant to the school to the judge to the jury to the prosecutor to anyone Knows a single good goddamn thing about technology.
Scott: the only person who seems to understand about technology is this computer expert Herbert Horner who performed a friend's examination for the defense.
Scott: and Why that you know.
Scott: that didn't help convince the jury.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: see this is part of the reason why more and more I want to go into law school since I already have a degree in IT.
Rym: I'd be that lawyer who knows about tech and could explain it to people in ways.
Rym: They could understand.
Scott: Yeah, see now here.
Scott: I think the problem when you know when I look at this big picture here is First of all the judge.
Scott: I don't know if I should trust that one source with the reporting on the judge.
Rym: there's a story about a judge falling asleep in trial or Like saying something like let's just fry this guy and go home like every week.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm willing to believe it but I can't just believe it right out without without some more evidence.
Scott: However, I'm pretty sure that the problem here was the jury just not understanding because the jury says well This person had porn on the screen.
Scott: Kids saw it the person was using the computer.
Scott: Yeah, that they don't understand anything more than that.
Rym: Yeah, I mean seriously what if the same situation happened?
Rym: But it was some kid in the local high school who hacked in and used some sort of screen control thing and popped up a boob.
Rym: Now what it was on the screen.
Rym: send him to jail mark him as a sex offender then cut off his ball.
Scott: All right high school kids This is what you got to do.
Scott: if you got a teacher you don't like Right go and like.
Scott: use their computer and install VNC server on it.
Rym: Oh Scott Do you know how many times in my high school someone would make pornography suddenly appear at a whole bunch of pieces?
Scott: then Go and connect to that computer and how many of those times I was involved.
Scott: open up the most porn you can possibly find like make a website that opens up like automatically with pop-ups a bunch of other porn sites and Then make your teachers go to it while you're looking alright while someone else is looking like you gotta have a tag team where your friend is sitting with the teacher and you Connect to the computer.
Scott: make the porn open up and then the kids gotta be like, huh?
Scott: Why are you looking at porn?
Scott: OMG and then have that kid report the teacher and you can get rid of the teacher?
Rym: Yeah, I'm really glad that our legal system allows this to happen.
Rym: Yeah, I'm real glad that this is an option to me.
Scott: another thing.
Scott: I just want to point out really quickly This is yet another reason on the heaping pile that No public education system should be permitted to use non free open source software, etc.
Rym: Yeah, this couldn't happen in Linux.
Scott: if it was a Linux machine, which would have saved the school system a lot of money.
Scott: Then kids wouldn't be able to look at porn.
Scott: teachers wouldn't be able to look at porn.
Scott: There'd be no proprietary software.
Scott: So the content filtering license could not have expired.
Scott: There would be no spyware.
Scott: No one could have even done this by accident.
Scott: it there would be no question.
Rym: yeah, it'd be obvious that the teacher had to have done it on purpose at that point or someone had hacked in and Extraordinarily set them up.
Scott: Yep, if I ever have kids and send them to school, you know how I could tell the good schools They'll be running the edge.
Scott: Ubuntu.
Scott: I don't think Ubuntu Ubuntu.
Scott: How do you say edu boondoo edu boondoo edu boondoo?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I kind of like edu boondoo Yeah, but it's education.
Scott: So it should be edu boondoo.
Rym: It could be yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I like saying boondoo anything before.
Rym: that is fine.
Rym: Ah zoo boondoo Things of the day.
Rym: So we've linked to various owned videos over the year and change Can ever get it.
Rym: didn't we blink to the owned compilation at one point that we did and that was every decent owned video We've ever seen like we decided at that point that we never needed to link to one again.
Rym: That was it.
Rym: That was the most owned you could ever see without I don't know crying or killing yourself.
Scott: I'm surprised I'm still here.
Rym: So then we were joking about because we saw this video a while ago of a guy.
Rym: It looked like an owned video like this guy was gonna get creamed by a car and there's some crazy miracle Totally survives with out of scratch like he's just fine.
Rym: and Then you know one time we saw this video of this kid on a skateboard and he's he's about to get hit by a bus And he totally pulls it off and doesn't die and he's just fine and he has his look on his face of oh shit.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: So we joked about hey wouldn't it be great if someone made an anti owned video of a bunch of people who almost get owned but totally get away with It and everything's just happy and awesome.
Rym: Someone made that.
Scott: They did and I like how.
Scott: I've seen some of these videos before but not all of them But I'd like to point out that half of them involve world rally cars.
Rym: Yeah, a little note if you're ever at a world rally I know it's cool to stand in the corner right in front of where the cars come right where the cars will crash.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's not really if you're at a rally race.
Scott: I mean these cars are driving down a hill usually and it's all windy roads.
Scott: So it's not like a racetrack.
Scott: There's a circle where you can sit and the cars keep coming by.
Rym: It's like initial D. You got to stand at the corner like the critical corner and you look down the hill as the cars come right at you.
Scott: Then you get out of the way and the cars you watch the car go around the corner and then you chase the car down The other side as it goes away.
Rym: There's no safety.
Rym: like some people are smart and they stay back a bit but a lot of people just stand like right there.
Scott: a lot of you will run out into the road that they get out of Maximum time watching the car.
Rym: These people are colloquially referred to as idiots.
Scott: They are indeed see an initial D. There's much better to watch the rally on television.
Rym: Yeah, or just watch initial D.
Scott: No, just watch initial D. I mean, there's play initial D.
Rym: There's no the initial D arc or to drive in the rally.
Scott: That's really the best way.
Rym: We got to talk about the initial D arcade game someday.
Rym: Okay, cuz that was okay.
Rym: Anyway, so all these people totally don't get owned and it's really amazing cuz every time you think wow That guy's about to die and then something crazy happens and he's totally okay.
Scott: It's a anti snuff videos the noss noss funds.
Rym: Well, they call it luck people.
Scott: Yeah Look like look like look like owned.
Rym: talk like not owned.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So I'm pretty sure most people who would listen to GeekNights are aware of the concept of hot linking.
Scott: But because I'm not a hundred percent sure that everyone is aware.
Scott: I'm going to explain it to you very quickly.
Scott: Let's do Dave and Joel style.
Rym: Do a little roleplay.
Rym: I'll be the webmaster and you be the punk kid.
Scott: Well, no, no.
Scott: Okay, so what?
Scott: I'm just gonna explain it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You got a web page.
Scott: Don't want to larp it And you end.
Scott: when you go to a web page It sends you some HTMLs and in those HTMLs are some lines that say hey go get this picture Get this gift from that website and get this JPEG from that website and then it will get those JPEG.
Scott: your web browser will see That.
Scott: get the JPEGs and the gifts and maybe the ping pictures grab them from those other websites and then load them on the page.
Scott: Now usually what you do is you put your HTMLs on your web server and you put your pictures on your web server.
Scott: Then you know everything that when someone visits your website Everything they need to see comes from your web server with the bandwidth that you are paying for.
Rym: Now some people do things like you'll have a website and say you have really really high content like crazy images.
Rym: Maybe you'll have all the images hosted on another server you own somewhere.
Rym: Mm-hmm stuff like that.
Rym: Yeah, they can point anywhere.
Scott: Yep, so what happens is let's say I've got a website and on the website.
Scott: I've got a picture of Cute kitten.
Scott: a cute kitten.
Scott: someone else makes a website, you know They make.
Scott: they just want to make a website and they decide that they want a picture of a cute kitten on their website.
Scott: Now what they should do is they should go to my website Get the picture of the cute kitten put it on their web server and then make a web page.
Scott: that way They could.
Scott: there's no technological thing stopping them from just having the picture from my website load on their web page.
Scott: So whenever anyone visits their web page on their web server That person ends up downloading a picture from my website using my bandwidth and that's generally not cool.
Scott: Now there are a lot of stories on the web this week about people who would do the thing that most people do and that's if someone tries to Hotlink an image from your web server Which they shouldn't do.
Scott: you replace it with goatse or porn or something that says pun diamond thief bla bla bla bla bla Etc.
Scott: to make those people look bad because you know.
Scott: So let's say someone links to your picture of a cute kitten on their website.
Scott: Then they go and look at their website and all of a sudden.
Scott: Oh, it's goatse awesome.
Scott: Now my thing of the day is a screenshot of a gmail of A guy and let me read just a little bit of this Hello, I must say I'm quite upset.
Scott: Oh, by the way, the punctuation and spelling and grammar is horrendous.
Scott: I have been using images from your website on my website for a long time now and suddenly they are gone and I am concerned.
Scott: I am using my website to build up my business Which is not easy and you change the location or deleted them or something.
Scott: My concern is that if you do not upload the images again I might have to contact my lawyer as I am using these images for the purposes of advertising And this sudden change without warning means I have to find where you have moved them to and get them working again.
Scott: Would you do such a thing?
Scott: I am an honest businessman and small business like mine never get respect.
Scott: I hope you realize it took me a long time to find images.
Scott: I liked now.
Scott: I have to find your images again.
Scott: Please put them back right away.
Scott: I don't think you want me to call my lawyer about this.
Scott: Please contact.
Scott: I just read the whole email.
Rym: Oh, well, all right I think it's safe to assume and correct me if I'm wrong.
Rym: I don't know if this is an ordinary claim or an extraordinary claim But I don't think that kid has ever even seen a lawyer.
Rym: No, no, let alone has a phone number.
Scott: I don't think it's a kid.
Scott: I think this is actually.
Scott: if this email is real Oh, no it's probably like some 40 year old guy with it's probably like some small business owner who doesn't know shit about technology.
Scott: and You know, I mean if people in this world are illiterate like they can't read or bright.
Scott: We don't give them jobs They don't run businesses.
Scott: They're basically like second-class citizens, but they did it to themselves.
Scott: So it's fair.
Scott: I mean, you can't do much if you can't read or write.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I'm gonna hire someone.
Rym: I don't care how cool they are.
Rym: if they can't read There's no job.
Rym: I could have them do other than possibly cleaning the bathroom, right?
Scott: So it's come to know couldn't read the cleaner instructions.
Scott: It's come to the point where technological literacy is just as important as plain old Reading and writing literacy.
Scott: if you don't know how to use computers If you don't if you're so stupid that you would write this email You are no better than someone who cannot read or write.
Scott: as far as I am concerned in this modern society.
Rym: now It's not quite at that point yet I don't get
Scott: in there give
Rym: I mean in ten years someone who can't use a computer or doesn't understand at least the bare bare basics of basic basic basic basic simple internet concepts and computer concepts is Not gonna get very far in anything.
Rym: no and the problem is well, I mean even now I couldn't imagine I wouldn't hire someone for anything.
Rym: I did.
Rym: who couldn't use a computer.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Not at all Because I also wouldn't hire anyone who couldn't type properly.
Scott: That's also true.
Scott: Yeah, if someone sent me something with this grammar and spelling There's no way they'd be hired ever even for like the lowliest job like crap secretary No way.
Rym: Well, especially secretary since their primary job is to write things for you.
Scott: I know I know.
Scott: Anyway, this is just hilarious.
Rym: That's what if their job was to make typos?
Rym: What if you were hiring them to write poorly and you needed that poor writing output as fast as possible?
Scott: Then I would know to go and hire this guy.
Scott: He looks like he could use a job because there's no way his small business is doing very well.
Rym: So I'm kind of excited about what we're gonna do in a moment on the show Really, and I believe I'll let Scott Introduce it because he's the one who gay came up with the thing.
Rym: What were your how the way we are going to handle this?
Scott: Alright well We were gonna do first, you know, we were thinking everyone wants the zombie episode.
Scott: But no, we're not gonna do the zombie episode.
Rym: You'll get the kids on the episode when you least expect it.
Scott: Yes, someone else made a suggestion that we should do like what if we had a time machine?
Rym: Well, that's the crab people idea.
Scott: Yeah, that's the crab people idea.
Scott: I was like, huh?
Scott: I don't know if we want to talk about what if we had a time machine, but what if?
Scott: Yeah, but what if that's?
Scott: that's pretty popular.
Scott: Nothing gets geekier than going what if I mean remember all those x-men.
Rym: what if comics like?
Rym: what if the x-men were all vampires?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Well, it was Marvel.
Scott: What if actually whatever like?
Scott: what if spider-man was gay?
Scott: No, no, he just makes you gay with his dance.
Rym: Yeah, he's not gay.
Rym: He just dances in a gay gay way.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So, you know, I was thinking about that for a while.
Scott: I was like, huh?
Scott: What if?
Scott: what?
Scott: What if we had a million dollars?
Scott: No, it's not such a good episode.
Rym: What if there was a draft and then no one wants to hear our plans to go to Canada?
Scott: I thought of the geekiest nerdiest thing ever.
Scott: What do all geeks and nerds always discuss?
Rym: Goku could totally beat up the Hulk.
Scott: Yeah, what if so-and-so fought so-and-so?
Scott: and then I remembered something else.
Scott: in some forums I frequent they have Thunderdome where what they do is they pick someone and then they say, all right, we're gonna have.
Scott: you know I don't know the Hulk fight Optimus Prime Optimus Prime's good.
Scott: Yeah, totally wins But yeah, and then they go, okay and everyone votes and whoever wins stays in and the other person is out.
Scott: it's Thunderdome.
Scott: one man enters one man leaves.
Scott: so as Thursday is random geek talk.
Scott: There's nothing geekier than Doing Thunderdome and I think it's gonna entertain you.
Scott: it's gonna be a lot of fan service.
Rym: So I drew the short straw meaning I get to pick.
Scott: the first person said you wanted to go first.
Scott: You didn't draw a short straw in my head.
Rym: I drew the short straw.
Rym: There was only one straw and it was already in my hand.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So Rym is gonna pick someone and then I'm going to pick an opponent and we will then discuss and agree Eventually agree upon who would win in a fight with no weapons in a Coliseum that they cannot leave and also no hazards or traps and Yeah or items.
Rym: In fact, we'll assume that it occurs in effectively like a football stadium.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's a football stadium.
Scott: There's grass and dirt.
Rym: There's a force field so you can't leave it But it scales to be as big as whoever needs to be there.
Scott: There are no items or weapons and There's sunlight because I know that affects some people.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's earth.
Rym: It's not a yellow Sun.
Scott: What else what else could possibly affect the deal?
Rym: Ah Gravity's normal airs normal standard earth.
Scott: You can't run out of air.
Scott: You Don't get any tools unless they're like part of you.
Scott: so for example Lion-o would have the sword of thunder and panthro would have his nunchucks and optimus prime would have a laser gun But spike spiegel wouldn't just have a gun.
Scott: No.
Scott: No, he wouldn't because that's not part of spike spiegel, but Lupin would have a gun.
Scott: Yes, and so would James Bond would have a Walter PPK or even G.
Rym: again Who would have possibly the same gun?
Scott: Yes, and you know go among would have his sword, but you couldn't be like.
Scott: Oh, well going on could go get an anti-tank rifle.
Scott: No, he couldn't he only has that sword.
Rym: No, the only other thing we have to bring up is that sometimes people playing this game suck at it.
Rym: You see I'm going first so I can't be like the Hulk Juggernaut God Galactus yet.
Scott: See the thing is if we just tried to win that's no fun because I just be like, oh, I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, it's a lot more like hunkbag.
Rym: You're trying to make it last as long as possible, right?
Scott: So to make this more entertaining we got to start small.
Scott: So I decide I've been keeping a secret what he's gonna start with but he thinks it's a really great idea.
Rym: I think it's a great place to start.
Rym: It's a good starting point cuz it's someone that I could beat up.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right, so glass Joe From Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Scott: You're gonna pick glass Joe.
Rym: I'm going to glass Joe.
Rym: He's my man.
Scott: You're going with glass Joe You know what?
Scott: I could say little Mac because that would just be I win.
Rym: Yeah, you could also say the Kaiser and you would just win.
Scott: but I'm gonna pick something funnier.
Scott: Oh Gabby Jay Gabby Jay.
Scott: Gabby Jay beat glass Joe in one fight one time.
Scott: Therefore Gabby Jay is the winner.
Rym: the fight already happened.
Scott: Plus Gabby Jay is like a few years younger than glass Joe.
Scott: I think all right.
Scott: Mm-hmm That ends that one.
Scott: All right, he's gonna fight Gabby Jay.
Rym: see now I'm on this trend.
Rym: now I keep going with boxers or something, but no I got to do something different from that.
Rym: I'm gonna have to go with Mario.
Scott: Mario Mario vs.
Scott: Gabby Jay.
Scott: That's tough.
Scott: Yeah, cuz because I was pretty tired, you know Mario can't get any items.
Scott: So if you just said Mario didn't say Super Mario Oh shit.
Rym: No, therefore.
Scott: It must be the Mario from the original Mario Brothers and not Super Mario Brothers.
Scott: All he can do he can't.
Scott: there's no items.
Scott: He can't hit the POW.
Scott: All he can do is jump.
Scott: He can hit Gabby Jay from under maybe but how's he gonna get under the boxing ring and hit him from under.
Rym: see here's What he might be able to do.
Rym: he runs up to him.
Rym: Gabby Jay has trouble punching him because he's so freakin tiny It's true.
Scott: It's pretty inaccurate with his punches.
Scott: And then he John the only one worse than him is glass Joe.
Rym: and then he jumps Straight up and hits him in the chin with that brick breaking head of his.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is that'll kill you in the original Mario Brothers if you touch the other opponent with your head.
Scott: Yeah, they hit him from under.
Rym: it might be a double suicide.
Scott: I think I don't know.
Scott: It's this tough call.
Scott: here I'm leaning a little bit towards Gabby Jay.
Rym: Yeah, I think Mario is gonna die.
Scott: So you're gonna have to come back with Super Mario.
Rym: I'm gonna let him die and come back with Super Mario from Super Mario Brothers one with a fire flower power.
Rym: Well, so he just stands at the other fireballs at Gabby Jane.
Scott: He has no chance.
Rym: Gabby Jay turns into.
Rym: I don't know Goomba.
Rym: Alright, I can white.
Scott: so Gabby Jay is down because he got hit with the fireballs and I caught Rym on a technicality.
Scott: one point Yeah one point for Scotty Scott.
Scott: so I could pick someone else in the Mario universe like Koopa.
Scott: But no one could beat Mario with firepower because firepower beats everything.
Rym: Well, except the hammer suit, huh?
Scott: So, let's see.
Scott: Let's say we're gonna stick with the video game.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I can jump.
Rym: I can break bricks with my head.
Rym: My head's real strong.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta pick something harder than bricks.
Rym: Nothing's harder than bricks.
Scott: Who can withstand fire?
Scott: Aha I will pick fireman from Megaman one.
Scott: it's a tough call because Freaking Mario gets punned by fire and fireman is pretty much immune to fire.
Scott: You just got fire coming out of his head.
Scott: Mario tries to jump on fireman.
Scott: He'll burn his feet.
Scott: You can't beat fireman.
Scott: He's a robot Alright, what is he gonna do?
Scott: shoot fireballs at him jump on him?
Scott: There's no bricks.
Scott: What can Mario do against fireman from Megaman one?
Rym: Well, he keeps shooting fireballs at him.
Scott: Hopefully he'll eventually get too hot and I know it does so little damage and you need to hit fireman so many times like 50 Times.
Scott: fireman would only need to hit Mario two times.
Scott: fireman shoots a lot of fire But fireman is not that mobile.
Rym: He's used to working in a really jumps all around.
Rym: Yeah, he's used to working in a really small room with a bunch of walls right there.
Rym: What's he gonna do in an open field?
Scott: What's Mario gonna do an open field when there's fire being shot all over the place?
Scott: He can't dodge.
Scott: He can't jump very high.
Rym: He can jump.
Scott: is that the mobility of Megaman?
Rym: He can just more mobility than Megaman.
Rym: Mario can jump higher faster further with greater effects.
Scott: But the thing is even Megaman fighting against fireman.
Scott: First of all, he's Megaman has better weaponry.
Scott: He's got like bubble shots and whatever water guns he needs.
Scott: I see he's got Iceman's weapon in Megaman one right to help him beat fireman not true?
Scott: and Megaman also can take a lot more than two hits.
Scott: and you will take two hits fighting fireman And it only takes two hits to take Mario out.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I think Mario would lose that fight.
Scott: I think he would.
Scott: he would need a star then he could win.
Rym: All right Oh, well in that case since I'm looking at it right here.
Rym: I'm gonna jump a bit.
Rym: I have to jump a bit to make this awesome.
Rym: Edward Alaric from Fullmetal Alchemist would totally kick fireman's ass into the ground without a second thought.
Scott: Somehow I think that's true because he would just Trent Trent.
Scott: I mean fireman's not a human He's a robot.
Scott: so you could totally just use the alchemy on fireman and just discombobulate him and it's over.
Rym: or you could just surround Him in an ice cube.
Scott: he could drop a rock on him surround transmute some water into ice.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I would do know.
Rym: here's what he's gonna do.
Rym: He's gonna stand at the far end of the football field transmuting dirt into Megaman pellets and throwing them.
Scott: But Megaman pellets are made of energy not dirt.
Scott: It's tough.
Rym: Um, he turns Plasma with his alchemy and people from World War one, I guess.
Scott: okay.
Scott: So who can beat Edward?
Scott: Eric I might have to try a few that can't beat him cuz he's pretty powerful and I don't just want to jump way up To someone I know can beat him guaranteed.
Rym: Plus I got a fetish sitting right here.
Rym: I got a little Edward Alaric Holding him.
Rym: He's got his little knife thing.
Rym: Let and his hair is kind of discolored to turn green.
Scott: I don't know why do I want I could go back to video games But I think I'm gonna try something else.
Rym: We got to hurry this up.
Scott: We do have to hurry this up.
Scott: All right M bison.
Rym: Oh Now this one will take some debate.
Scott: This one will take some debate.
Rym: on one hand We have M bison a train fighter with the cheapest freaking move in any fighting game ever.
Scott: Yeah, I mean even if Elric can do some transmuting right and he can do it pretty fast So that I'm having to draw symbols and whatever M-bison can just get like Psychokinetic energy out of nowhere all the time and fly back and forth real fast before Ed has even a chance to do anything.
Rym: No, I mean watch the anime.
Rym: Ed can totally just transmute things like that without a second thought doesn't need circles or anything.
Scott: Yeah, but think about this.
Scott: remember in Street Fighter 2 the bonus stage.
Scott: if it's even if it's a big metal car M Bison can punch the car into smithereens.
Scott: What's he gonna do?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Ed could also punch the car into smithereens with a giant rock fist.
Scott: It's a tough call.
Scott: and also you've got two equal fighters roughly I said one of them with alchemy powers and one with psychokinetic powers.
Rym: I submit to you that M bison is no more tough than King Bradley.
Rym: In fact, I think they fight in a very similar fashion.
Scott: I do think they do as well because they're very similar as swords which are which give.
Scott: actually King Bradley would have an advantage over M bison with his swords.
Rym: Yeah, but then again M bison has his cheap cheap cheap moves.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: Let's look at it this way right?
Scott: can Ed beat Al?
Scott: we got to use a third Like, you know, you got to make a triangle when you have a trot problem like.
Rym: I don't think Ed now can beat each other.
Rym: I think they fight to a dead standstill when they actually fight.
Scott: Well could M bison beat out.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: see, he might be.
Scott: I don't think he could because M bison can only like really hurt you if you're a squishy human.
Scott: if you Tried to just you know, I mean he could punch a car to smithereens.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: I was armor breaks all the time.
Rym: Yeah, maybe right through it.
Scott: So maybe M bison could beat out pretty easily.
Rym: But I think that's only because Al is kind of weak against straight-up physical attacks of that nature.
Rym: Meanwhile Ed is just super badass.
Rym: I mean look at how many people's asses he kicks throughout that show not even counting the movie.
Rym: Yeah How many amuncula does he fight?
Rym: I don't think M bison can beat him.
Scott: plus when you're actually, you know I think I'm gonna have to concede that M bison would lose because if you look at some other guys in the street fighter people That would definitely lose to Ed like I don't know Chun Li God or Dal seen Honda.
Scott: those people can beat M bison if They're up to par because you could beat M bison in Street Fighter 2 with any of the characters if you're good enough.
Scott: and So yeah.
Scott: All right, so L would be.
Scott: I mean Ed would beat M bison.
Rym: Yes, he would.
Rym: Oh hands down All right.
Scott: Let's go back go back a bit.
Rym: Okay, I think Edward Elric is a consummate badass and unless you move into giant robot territory I think you're gonna have some trouble here.
Scott: All right, I'm gonna try one more outside of giant robot territory.
Scott: All right, and it go for light with his death note.
Scott: He'll just write down Ed's name the end Whoo, but do they know who they're fighting?
Rym: Does he know his name?
Scott: He's the famous full metal alchemist Edward Elric.
Scott: Everyone knows who he is.
Rym: We didn't set the parameters.
Scott: I mean, he doesn't know what he looked like.
Scott: But as soon as he sees him when they're in an arena, remember he would just see him right there.
Scott: He knows it.
Scott: He looks like he knows who it is writes him down a little book game over.
Rym: Yeah Here's the problem though We didn't set.
Rym: I mean What if these people are just transported suddenly into the arena to fight and they don't know who they're gonna fight.
Rym: So it comes down to if he knows his name or not.
Rym: if light knows his name It's over because Ed can't react fast enough.
Rym: But if he doesn't know his name, he dicked.
Scott: unless he trades the eyes with ryuk Okay, so he's not gonna trade the eyes.
Scott: We know that.
Scott: Yeah, so the only question here right is is light smart enough to trick Ed into telling him his name?
Scott: and Ed Ed is even cautious about that.
Scott: He doesn't know death notes or anything, right?
Rym: Alright, I have to concede now because here's exactly what would happen light to be standing there Ed to be standing there.
Rym: It doesn't just attack people with a sucker punch and they always talk in the anime like well blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: And light, you know that motherfucker likes to talk and tell everyone to keep a plan before he enacts it.
Rym: So they'll be standing there and light will be smart.
Rym: He'll realize doesn't know this guy's name But while they're having their banter, he'll probably notice that this guy's short.
Rym: He'll probably determine that a lot of his attitude comes from the fact that he's short and he's mad about it.
Rym: Mmm, that is a sore point for him.
Rym: so he'll say something dismissive like who's this pint-sized piece of shit?
Rym: and then Ed Will in classic fashion say who are you calling a bitch size bean blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: I'm Edward.
Rym: I work the full-metal alchemist.
Rym: I'm gonna beat your ass into the ground and while he's going on his tirade He'll just write his name down.
Scott: Yeah game over All right.
Scott: So now I'm gonna give you a hint on how to beat light.
Scott: you need someone either Who is concealed such as being in a giant robot or something like that or someone with a secret identity?
Scott: Or else you're gonna have no chance.
Rym: Well, see I got two candidates here and one of them is clever and one of them is Cool.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'm not gonna use either one yet.
Rym: I'm just gonna say that Roshach from the Watchmen.
Scott: Ooh, that is an excellent choice.
Rym: Rajag would just walk over and snap at a light's neck without even thinking that is true and Light wouldn't know who he was.
Scott: Roshank wouldn't Roshank?
Scott: whatever Roshak He wouldn't be able to do.
Scott: you know, you just beat him up.
Scott: light can't hold himself in a fight.
Rym: very well that's all about the thinking and Look at the things that Roshak does in that comic Roshak could probably take like 40 bullets and be just fine.
Rym: Now my funny answer is Ryuk I'm not gonna talk about Elle cuz.
Rym: we read the manga.
Rym: we know exactly who would win that fight.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, you know what?
Rym: I'm gonna go with Roshak cuz.
Rym: Roshak just walks over snaps his puny neck.
Rym: That's the end of that.
Rym: and now Roshak's got a fucking death note.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, no, it doesn't count.
Scott: I don't think he gets to keep it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't work.
Scott: bodies disappear.
Scott: It's like do yeah He only gets the stuff that he comes with.
Rym: Well, no, I'm doing.
Rym: bodies didn't disappear.
Rym: It's like early counter-strike.
Scott: No, the body the corpses are there, but all the items go away, you know, because no one has the.
Scott: you know They don't have inventories.
Rym: We don't want to leave the corpses there because that won't end.
Scott: Well, not true true.
Scott: Some people like are made of metal and that wouldn't work.
Rym: Well, yeah, or some people are swarms of things or some people are made out of poison.
Scott: alright, well Roshak's not gonna be too easy to get rid of because he's just a Man, and I just need someone stronger than he is.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's a pretty strong man, though.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the only person who really could fight him well on an even footing was I don't know Dr.
Rym: Manhattan.
Scott: Yeah squishy.
Scott: We're not gonna go that big yet.
Scott: Yeah I'm not gonna go that big yet.
Rym: or actually Ozzie Mandy is held off held him off in a fight.
Rym: memory tries to stab him With that fork and Ozzie man.
Rym: He's just like punks him.
Scott: Yeah All right, let's see who am I gonna pick?
Rym: Roshak's real strong.
Rym: remember when he killed that guy in the prison.
Rym: He's locked in the room.
Rym: The guy's coming to kill him.
Rym: He's just sitting there like you're gonna die.
Rym: I'm gonna walk over there and kill you and the guy's like you're not gonna do that.
Rym: and then he does it just like Dr.
Rym: McNinja's dead.
Scott: Yeah, oh shit.
Rym: Yeah, what if it was dr.
Rym: McNinja's dad versus Russia?
Scott: Maybe that's.
Scott: I'll bring dr Minijan later, but right now I'm gonna bring in pan throw from the Thundercats.
Scott: So I mentioned before who's.
Scott: oh He's real strong and he's got nunchucks and he could just beat the shit out of Roshank in a straight fight.
Scott: Roshak in a straight fight and not a goddamn thing you could do about it, huh?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think it's still.
Rym: I think in the end Roshak would lose because he is just a human and His pan throw is a real fast.
Scott: He's a he's a cat person.
Scott: He's a furry He's he's.
Scott: I mean pan throw.
Scott: I was thinking about using Mike Tyson, but I didn't want to go back to boxing.
Scott: But pan throw could probably beat Mike Tyson when you really think about it.
Scott: Yeah, and he's got nunchucks with cat claws on him.
Rym: However, someone very similar to pan throw is jet from cowboy bebop.
Rym: Ooh, they are similar and I think jet and pan throw Would be a knockdown.
Rym: drag him out fight the likes of which we've only seen and they live.
Scott: That'd be a tough call.
Scott: cuz nunchucks versus metal arm Mmm.
Rym: Yeah jet is real freakin strong.
Scott: He is but I I think pan throw might still win that one.
Rym: I think path road win in the end, but he'd be bloody and And it'd be like the final like.
Rym: and then he's standing there barely alive Mm-hmm.
Rym: So path row is still standing.
Rym: Yep now lion.
Rym: I'll could just kill panther anytime he wanted.
Rym: So I'm not even gonna think about that.
Rym: chitar would just seduce him and break his neck bond style.
Rym: Mm-hmm James Bond would probably stand at a distance and shoot him a bunch of times.
Scott: Oh, you're gonna do that, but wood bullets work is pants.
Scott: I mean James Bond throws not immune to bullets.
Rym: No, but James Bond uses that tiny ass little pistol.
Rym: Those bullets probably wouldn't take Panther.
Scott: Oh, that is right.
Scott: I have seen pan throw block Projectiles by swinging his nunchucks very quickly in a Michelangelo fashion.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's unless I use one of the James Bonds that has a rocket launcher.
Rym: He pretty much just has that little pistol.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Panther was tough to beat.
Scott: He is tough to beat.
Scott: You're gonna have to start getting more superhuman here.
Rym: Yeah, you know who could be pantro real easily though.
Rym: Oh There's a lot of options here.
Rym: I think von fon L even without his guy my laugh.
Scott: Oh, I don't know who that is from eska flown a.
Rym: You know the secondary main character.
Rym: Yeah von.
Scott: All right Fon L confused me von fon L. Yeah, the main guy with the red shirt in the yeah How could you?
Scott: eska flown is like one of the best and I remember that the last name threw me off.
Scott: You just said von.
Scott: I'd be like, oh von from eska phony, right?
Scott: Fon L. You said fon L. I was like von fon L. You know, I was like I was thinking of his one word.
Scott: like von fon L I was like what the fuck see.
Rym: I learned from initial D that if you say someone's whole name Mmm, see von.
Scott: I love to bring initial D into this but We already determined that M bison can punch cars to smithereens and he was way back.
Rym: So yeah, talk to me would just come with his car, but it wouldn't matter.
Scott: It wouldn't matter.
Rym: So yeah, von fon L can pretty much kick anyone's ass with the sword He does.
Scott: he has a sword and pan throws got nunchucks.
Rym: It would be tough, but On kills dragons without a guy.
Scott: my left That is right.
Scott: and the best pan throw can't even beat up mummies in the first episode.
Rym: He was trained by barges.
Rym: Yep, what was that guy's name?
Rym: Boggess?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't remember the guy's name.
Rym: Anyway, he was trained by a consummate.
Rym: badass Kills a dragon in the first episode.
Rym: Panther has got no chance against that shit.
Rym: Panther is not a dragon Alright, I was just a cat boy with an awesome voice.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Who can beat the sword of Von L. That is a very quality sword.
Scott: We're gonna have to probably pick the greatest swordsman ever The greatest swordsman ever.
Rym: yes, I can think of like five.
Scott: there is only one greatest swordsman ever.
Rym: You're stalling for time.
Rym: Nope, I've already thought of it.
Scott: Okay, who the dread pirate to Roberts?
Rym: Von might win just for the fact that he usually cuts through people's swords and then through the people.
Scott: that is true.
Rym: Von is just crazy fast and powerful and while the dread pirate is what probably the best swordsman ever He is human in the normal sense of the word, but he is so cunning and God, yeah, Von's not very smart.
Scott: No, he's not.
Scott: he could totally fool him, but he's some cool trick about poison in a cup.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: Even if Von couldn't beat him Alan Shazar from the same anime would just kill him with the sword like that.
Scott: Oh, yeah, Alan is almost as sword skilled.
Rym: Alan is smart against everything in the world except women.
Rym: Whereby he acts like a jackass.
Scott: Hmm, so I'm gonna take it up a notch.
Scott: You're ready.
Scott: You're ready Alan Shazar right week against women.
Scott: Yeah, we're going up.
Scott: We're gonna have to start using people with more powers.
Scott: Now you can use priss.
Scott: No We're gonna use Makoto Kusanagi up.
Rym: She wins she wins She's invisible.
Scott: She's got guns.
Scott: She's Cyborg she's.
Scott: you're done.
Rym: Not only you're gonna need to take it way up, but after you killed it She'd be like, why doesn't he have a cyber brain?
Rym: What's up with that?
Scott: Yeah So you're gonna need to be like.
Scott: we're already way above spider-man levels here.
Rym: We need to like, you know I mean the major can kill pretty much anyone in the ghost in the shell series.
Scott: Yeah anyway, I mean I mean anyway, like she can only get really be stopped by tanks and People with like serious even people with serious battle armor can't beat her.
Rym: now Bear in mind Scott said tanks plural because we know very well that one tank is no match for her.
Scott: Yeah, that's the end of the first movie.
Scott: Yeah, like the one big tank doesn't win.
Rym: Not at all.
Scott: So Yeah.
Scott: All right, you're gonna have to bring out something big now.
Rym: fucking damn the major.
Rym: I mean, I thought Oh Ellen Shazar in Scheherazade.
Rym: But no the major would just like punch through the front and rip his face off.
Scott: Yep she wouldn't even think he tried to stand how even like An eight an Ava I was about to say Ava is a tough fight against the major.
Rym: I don't know how you beat me to it.
Rym: I was gonna say an Ava I was gonna go there You're gonna go there cuz I first I was gonna go with a gassaraki.
Rym: But well who see the regular robots in gassaraki from the early part of the show the major which is destroyed.
Rym: Yeah, I mean regular commandos can take those things out.
Scott: Mm-hmm But a whole fleet of them, but I don't think we're gonna allow teams.
Scott: No team.
Rym: What about the the other?
Rym: Gassaraki from later in the show that the actual one Mmm, cuz that thing's organic and shit.
Scott: It is organic and shit and while she'd probably tear it up It might get her.
Rym: but here's the thing.
Rym: even if she beat it It would be that situation where she beats it.
Rym: But all this left to her is like a torso and an arm and part of her head.
Scott: Yeah, does that who we gonna count as the winner in that case though?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: so I'm gonna go with the Ava because it's a more interesting argument.
Rym: I also don't want to accidentally ruin gassaraki.
Scott: Yes Well, here's the thing with the Ava.
Scott: right.
Scott: if the Ava is up and about right?
Scott: She could probably hide from it being invisible until it runs on.
Scott: Ava can totally find it.
Scott: It's got scanning and shit and they've got crazy technology in nerve.
Scott: They know where it is.
Scott: They know when angels are coming from far away.
Scott: They can find one invisible cyborg.
Rym: Yeah, and Ava the Ava definitely comes with nerve though nerve can't isn't in the battle Nerve is in a separate screen talking to the pilot.
Rym: I think it comes down to who the pilot is.
Scott: No, no It doesn't has nothing to do with it So powerful with his giant guns that if it shot her and hit it would just win.
Scott: however Ava's only last for a few minutes.
Scott: could she avoid it until the power ran out?
Rym: or if the power were plugged in which could be feasible because the powers everywhere.
Scott: in Tokyo three, but we're not in Tokyo D. We're in a sealed Forcefield.
Rym: the powers him even if the power were there.
Rym: Here's my worry.
Rym: while they're fighting She would like jump onto its leg and somehow get up there and mess up that power cable.
Scott: She would get inside of it and shit ripping stuff apart.
Rym: See though I don't know if she could cuz it's basically God kind of.
Rym: yeah, it's it's part of God.
Rym: It's a piece of God.
Rym: It's also Shinji's mom.
Rym: See here's the thing.
Rym: if it's Shinji the Ava loses cuz she'll flash a boob.
Rym: Shinji will freak out the Ava will just sit there and then she wins.
Scott: All right, so pick which Ava it's gonna be.
Rym: All right, it's Asuka in the movie where she's all pissed off.
Rym: All right, but All right, so way or you know what you want to go all the way.
Rym: It'll be one of those white things from the end.
Rym: All right, one of those white It'll be Ava series with its giant giant sword.
Rym: That's also the sphere of longanews.
Scott: Those don't run out of power.
Rym: She's fighting against what is effectively a tiny deity.
Scott: Well seeing as those don't run out of electricity She's got no chance.
Scott: Yeah, she could avoid it for a while.
Scott: Maybe do some damage to it But eventually is just gonna just give her credit.
Scott: It's gonna squish her under its boot.
Rym: She would hold out for a while.
Rym: I mean, I've seen her fight some pretty dangerous things but these those Ava series from the end not I mean aside from being tiny deities.
Rym: if you Put one through a meat grinder.
Rym: It comes back in like 20 minutes.
Scott: Hmm So I know I think we're scaling up a bit too fast because well, we're running out of time.
Scott: So I'm running out of time.
Rym: We've been talking about this for almost a half hour.
Scott: All right, let's see.
Scott: Then I got to go way big.
Scott: you ready?
Rym: All right, I'm gonna go For I mean, I got Ava series here.
Scott: I'm gonna go for oh What's that anime with the that was made by this.
Scott: the slayers guys in space lost universe?
Rym: I never actually saw.
Scott: lost me there, but they had a ship with the Jew gun.
Rym: Nothing's gonna beat an Ava but that Jew gun See while the Jew gun would probably take out your ordinary run-of-the-mill Ava.
Rym: This is Ava series.
Scott: I think that you gun would still win.
Scott: I mean it's in space.
Scott: The thing can't get up.
Scott: Yes, it can.
Rym: Ava series has the spear of longanews.
Rym: They all do remember the episode where they throw the spear of longanews into space and take out that angel.
Rym: That's actually a space station.
Rym: They just do that to that spaceship and that's the end I don't know.
Scott: but the space station gets shot off in the Coliseum.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: We're not in space.
Scott: We're in a Coliseum.
Scott: No, no fine.
Rym: The spaces could be in space or real bombardment.
Rym: It doesn't matter cuz just it'll stand there.
Rym: It'll throw the spear that turns into the spear longanews.
Rym: that thing can go into orbit from earth as we saw Go right through the space station turn everyone into goop.
Scott: All right Well, there's no way that that could be the most powerful thing There is.
Scott: there's got to be something better than that.
Rym: I can think of one thing more powerful than that.
Scott: I got something.
Scott: you're ready.
Scott: Who's the name?
Scott: Who's that wizard from the forgotten realm?
Rym: Oh shit What's his name?
Scott: Elminster Elminster?
Scott: We'll go with him.
Rym: He'll just cast hold monster Hold monster wouldn't work cuz you know that the Ava has one fuck of a saving throw.
Scott: It does not matter.
Scott: He's about like level 20 bajillions.
Rym: I forget the cannon level because it used to be.
Rym: he was just effectively a tiny god.
Rym: But with the advent of third ed they gave him epic levels and they defined all that stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I mean he could just cast freaking disjunction on the lands of longanews or whatever.
Rym: All right Yeah, you would cast that but the explosion might kill him.
Scott: No, cuz he would just teleport away somewhere.
Rym: no I think while he is super powerful and While he has the essence of the goddess mistra in him and he's the chosen mister and all that business He's also really really old.
Rym: He's a frail old man.
Rym: He is held together by magic and bits But he's got feats like quicken spell.
Scott: the Ava couldn't even act before he dismantled it with magic.
Rym: Yeah, but think about how little damage those spells do.
Rym: a 20th art a 20d6 fireball.
Scott: He could just cast wish.
Rym: You know wish isn't really that powerful.
Scott: it's powerful enough to get rid of any what bad one bad guy.
Rym: No, cuz a wish alone does not destroy the tarrasque.
Scott: This is okay.
Scott: the tarrasque All right.
Scott: You know what that?
Rym: the reason I brought up the tarrasque is because the Ava series Could beat the tarrasque without even trying.
Scott: why not not even a chance.
Scott: Are you kidding?
Rym: The Ava series is so powerful once again tiny God, you know The only way to destroy and as far as we know, there's no way to destroy it.
Rym: You have to do something special.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Scott: They like half of them got their heads smashed in by the other Ava.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what.
Rym: they all came back.
Rym: I just ruined part of the movie, but it doesn't matter cuz that movie sucks All right, they come right back.
Rym: You got to kill them with something special like the end of the world or some crazy thing the tarrasque.
Rym: All they would do again is beat the hell out of it and then stick it with the spirit long enough Okay.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: I was gonna go with the obvious, you know ace in the hole Which is always Galactus cuz he just eats the whole world and everything on it.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm not gonna do that.
Scott: I got a better right.
Rym: Where are you going?
Scott: I'm going to get my buddy from the bottom of the ocean the great Cthulhu.
Scott: Fuck you I thought you could do Cthulhu six times.
Scott: You don't mean shit.
Scott: He come back.
Scott: He might be dreaming for a while.
Scott: The battle might last a while while the Ava's wait for Cthulhu to come back.
Scott: But when he does one tentacle and you're done, it's all over.
Rym: See now if there's a human piloting this then it'd be over immediately.
Rym: Just go insane and die.
Rym: They'd see it and be like.
Scott: Isn't the the Ava biological in some way it is wouldn't it go insane and die?
Rym: No Because the Ava series remember is not it's got a dummy plug in it.
Scott: the dummy plug would go insane and die.
Rym: See, here's the thing.
Rym: Remember it's not a human biological.
Rym: It's a it's deific.
Rym: So while it is definitely not as it might be marginally as powerful as Cthulhu might be close because Cthulhu is not Really a god, he's just a priest of a god.
Rym: who is that's.
Scott: If Cthulhu goes down, you know where I'm going next, right?
Rym: I know you're going next but here's the thing a fight between Cthulhu and an Ava series.
Rym: I think they're on close to equal footing and as long as the person inside of Ava series or the dummy plug can resist Going insane and dying.
Rym: I think cuz remember nukes can't take out Ava's nukes can't take out angels.
Rym: This thing is an Ava angel.
Scott: Yeah, well is the thing you?
Scott: Cthulhu can't really be destroyed.
Scott: he'll keep coming back and every time he comes back He'll do a little more damage to that Ava.
Scott: but I think even if the Ava takes out Cthulhu eventually it'll run down.
Rym: but I think this thing will keep coming back to because The thing is.
Rym: the only reason Cthulhu keeps coming back is because nothing conceived by man can destroy Cthulhu.
Rym: We can't fathom what would destroy Cthulhu.
Rym: It's like an ant and it bites me on the toe and I go stupid and I'll be back and I step on the air.
Scott: I can't accept that Cthulhu would lose to your Ava series.
Scott: There's no way.
Rym: I don't know if it would lose.
Rym: I think it would be like two minor gods fighting and while the Ava series might lose eventually I think it would lose in the end Which is what matters.
Rym: but once again the spear of longinus the fact that this thing is part deity and Cthulhu It's got that spear.
Scott: that could be tough for Cthulhu.
Rym: See that's the thing the Ava series.
Scott: but good Right, but is it good at handling the spear?
Scott: Cthulhu could block it with his tentacle.
Rym: I don't know if anything can block the spear.
Scott: He's got a tentacle.
Scott: He could totally grab it.
Rym: I mean, it's basically a piece of a deity Wielding the only thing that has ever killed a deity and it's fighting a priest of a deity.
Rym: So I think you're gonna have to go to your Trump, which I have nothing to say against.
Scott: Oh, well, my Trump isn't gonna be what you think.
Scott: You thought I was gonna say something like Azathoth or Nyarlathotep.
Rym: I expected Nyarlathotep.
Rym: I really expected Nyarlathotep But I'm not cuz he would just blink and the Ava series is gone.
Scott: That is not where I'm going.
Scott: I'm going to the Flying Spaghetti Monster with his noodly appendage Actual deity.
Scott: all he would do was reach down with his noodly appendage touch it and it's gone.
Rym: No, it wouldn't be gone.
Rym: It would convert.
Rym: it would join him.
Rym: It would join him which the only being that is immune to being converted is a priest or a nun According to that Flying Spaghetti Monster game.
Rym: Yes, so it would turn into a pirate a tiny pirate That is right.
Scott: So cuz what in all the universe can beat the Flying Spaghetti Monster?
Rym: All right.
Rym: So now we're asking what can beat a god in a in a world.
Scott: Oh, he's not easy Flying Spaghetti Monster But newly appendages.
Scott: I have a funny answer to what can beat him, but I want to see if you can.
Rym: well That would be an Italian chef.
Rym: or yes All right, what is it Mario?
Rym: because they like it there spaghetti.
Scott: that is right.
Scott: so which one of those are you gonna go with?
Rym: See, I'm gonna go with the more fun round where the only reason it beats Ava series.
Rym: cuz.
Rym: Ava series is a piece of a God.
Rym: Cthulhu is a priest.
Rym: Ava series is a mod like an angel.
Rym: It's a minor deific.
Rym: being FSM is effectively a god.
Rym: so the only thing that could beat the FSM is a more powerful God and Yahweh for all is whatever.
Rym: isn't actually that great.
Rym: He was just some mom.
Scott: We've been talking about creatures of fantasy the whole time.
Rym: So yeah But he's this minor Judaic God among all these other gods that the Jews worship and He just kind of had an arrogance complex and wanted to be the only one worshiped in whatever.
Rym: so he's not that great.
Rym: He just won by trickery and bullshit.
Rym: Who could beat the FSM?
Rym: I know Thor has a mighty appetite and Thor is a major deity.
Rym: who's got that hammer?
Rym: now?
Rym: I'm not talking about Marvel.
Rym: whatever thought I'm talking about Thor but God it's the same Thor.
Scott: actually The Marvel Thor is Thor.
Rym: all right if the Marvel Thor is Thor then how come there is ever a question?
Rym: how come there's ever an issue where Thor Disagrees with anyone and they are not turned into goo by his hammer?
Scott: Because the problem is the way they do?
Scott: Thor is like Thor is doesn't have his own body.
Scott: He always possesses whoever picks up the hammer.
Rym: I'm not talking about Thor's avatar.
Scott: It's not Thor's avatar It's if you pick up the hammer the Thor possesses your body.
Rym: That's what an avatar is.
Scott: That's when a god possesses a physical body in order to but then your body is like transformed into Thor's body Which is the equivalent of as if Thor had his own.
Rym: but it's not as powerful as the raw Essence that is Thor.
Rym: that it is.
Scott: no But only difference is that in the back of Thor's mind is that original person thinking on their own outside of Thor?
Scott: It is Thor basically through and through.
Scott: no, but it doesn't really matter.
Scott: It doesn't matter because we're talking about Thor in general.
Rym: Yeah, you know what fuck Thor.
Rym: We're going right to the top with Odin.
Scott: Odin versus the Flying Spaghetti monster would just destroy him.
Rym: He would ride sleep near into battle and fucking cream him.
Rym: There's no question that Odin would win that battle.
Rym: Odin is mighty badass.
Scott: Odin is a mighty badass course.
Rym: the problem is if you know anything about Norse mythology You know exactly what can kill Odin, but I don't want to go that obvious route.
Rym: Do you even know who kills Odin in Ragnarok?
Rym: Loki guessing Alright, so who do you think in every who you gonna have?
Rym: beat Odin, huh?
Scott: Well Odin was in charge of an entire pantheon of gods Yeah, one of the best pantheons.
Scott: and he had a raven and he was missing an eyeball.
Rym: Well, he had two Ravens.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you get immune and thought in memory.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And the Ravens are there.
Rym: Yeah, and you know, I mean he's Odin He's probably got like a thousand axes on him.
Rym: Well, he's riding a horse with a bunch of.
Scott: I think I'm gonna try a horizontal a horizontal move.
Scott: I'm not gonna try to go up or down.
Rym: You're gonna say Poseidon.
Scott: No I'm gonna say Zeus Because Zeus is about equal in the power levels in charge of a pantheon, but he doesn't swing axes.
Scott: He throws lightning bolts.
Scott: So what you gonna do?
Scott: I think I really just safe in his cloud up in the sky throw in his lightning bolts and Odin be like fuck Fuck fuck.
Rym: see here's the thing.
Rym: the gods are spawned by the beliefs of their believers.
Rym: So they and since we're talking about the leaders of the pantheon which are effectively equal what this comes down to is which?
Rym: Civilization and culture is more purely badass the Greeks or the Norse?
Rym: That is what this has come down to and I submit the Norse As much as I love the Greeks.
Rym: the Greeks got their asses kicked by the Romans.
Rym: They got their asses kicked by everyone.
Rym: they kicked each other's asses.
Rym: Granted the Norse were just consummate badasses.
Scott: They were badasses, but they also got put in by the wussy English.
Scott: Yeah, yeah while the Greeks, you know while they were maybe punned by the Romans They were still around and Byzantine was mostly Greek as you know, mr.
Scott: Byzantine Emperor.
Rym: Yeah, but it wasn't Greek like that Great.
Rym: there's a lot of different kinds of Greeks and by then it was Greek Christian, which is a totally different breed of Greek We're talking about like pre-hellenistic Greeks Mmm, very tough Dorian's and shit Illyrian and all that.
Scott: Yeah, so Greeks or Vikings?
Scott: Great, like I like Vikings.
Rym: Well, I don't want to say just Viking.
Rym: I'm gonna go with Norseman in general because they weren't all Vikings.
Scott: So it's Hagar the horrible.
Rym: Remember.
Rym: the Norseman as people know them came way later than the Greeks So they had the advantage of better equipment in some cases But they were also more barbaric.
Rym: true true.
Scott: I don't know might flip a coin.
Rym: See the problem is I'm arguing mostly from the fact that I really like the Norse and I think they're cool.
Rym: Yeah, and you're arguing the fact that Zeus is awesome.
Scott: This is awesome.
Scott: Definitely more awesome than Odin.
Rym: Yeah, I'm surprised you didn't say Poseidon.
Rym: You seem to always like Poseidon.
Scott: I do but I just don't think a guy with water is gonna beat a guy, you know He's also horses and like war all this other stuff Poseidon is really powerful.
Scott: Yes He's also an ass jackass.
Scott: That's why I like him so much, but I don't think he's gonna beat Odin.
Scott: I think it's gonna take Zeus.
Rym: See, I don't think the Greek pantheon could win because if it's between the leaders if we bring in the whole pantheon I mean look at this Ragnarok.
Rym: The only thing that can beat the Norse pantheon is the Norse pantheon.
Rym: So if they if an outsider comes and see the Greeks would fight with each other constantly.
Rym: Athens and Sparta fought each other Pretty much to destroy all of Greece.
Rym: and just bullshit and bullshit.
Rym: and in fighting and whatever.
Rym: and when enemies came from the outside They'd squabble.
Scott: when enemies come from the outside Enemies don't come from the outside.
Scott: the Vikings take it outside on their own.
Rym: But if the Norse are about to have their Ragnarok and then Zeus and his Pissant army of Greek gods comes like we're gonna start shitting your little pantheon I think that the Giants and the AC and all of them the van They're just gonna come together.
Rym: None of that Ragnarok stuff.
Rym: They're gonna kick the Greek pantheon's ass.
Scott: See.
Scott: the only thing I can say is that you know while Vikings were better than actual Romans in the real world Right when you look at the mythology the Greeks are much better at delegating powers to those below them.
Scott: They had Hercules they had in Herakles.
Scott: Yeah, they had Achilles.
Scott: They had all sorts of bad guys to like Medusa's and they had all kinds of clash of the titans shit going down.
Scott: Right the Viking gods they kept it all to themselves.
Scott: They didn't get the Vikings shit.
Scott: They didn't give them anything.
Scott: They were just like yeah, we're all powerful and you're Vikings.
Rym: Yeah, but here's the thing every Norseman who died in battle was waiting in Valhalla.
Rym: So when the Greeks come how many Vikings do you think are standing there ready to fight along with the gods?
Scott: yeah, and all those Vikings in Valhalla are still sitting around bored waiting and the Greeks are going.
Rym: ah No, the Greeks are going.
Rym: Oh shit the Romans.
Rym: Oh shit the Roman.
Scott: Well who did better in the Olympics?
Scott: Greece or Norway?
Rym: I Don't know Depends on when I mean in the old Olympics.
Rym: Well, I don't think the people from Norway were competing.
Scott: Oh, I wonder why that is.
Scott: Maybe they couldn't stand up.
Scott: Why did this turn into Greek verse Norway?
Rym: Oh, you know we have concluded Regardless of who would win the Greek pantheon or the Norse pantheon.
Rym: We know this.
Rym: Odin and Zeus could beat class Joe.
Scott: They sure can.
Rym: This Has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.