Rym: It's Monday December 17th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Technology in education and why it's not going so well.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Well for perhaps the first time ever the visigoths came over and they uh didn't visit got the house so much.
Scott: Yeah, that was pretty good times.
Scott: actually you know on one hand there were fewer visigoths But on the other hand the visigoths that were missing were not the worst of the visigoths.
Scott: So it's it's hard to tell.
Scott: is it is it a matter of who comes that is the worst the cause of the problem?
Scott: Or is it a matter of how many come?
Scott: and I'm?
Scott: or maybe to lean towards is just how many come and not who?
Rym: Maybe it was just the fact that there was a blizzard and a bunch of them were stuck here So they had to clean the house up before they left or they would have looked extra visigoths.
Scott: Yeah, we could have easily told who it was because you know some people stay here longer.
Scott: You know then that we know which problem which which messes are made by who.
Rym: also possibly and I realize this now My character in our game almost died, and now he's kind of an invalid right now.
Scott: Maybe they felt awesome.
Scott: isn't burning wheel?
Scott: great that shit never would have happened in D&D.
Rym: well think about that encounter in D&D.
Rym: Alright burning wheel.
Rym: someone shot guys with an arrow.
Rym: now He's on the ground bleeding to death and permanently crippled because it went through his lung.
Rym: D&D I take 1d6 damage and keep going.
Scott: yep Burning wheel.
Rym: so awesome, but yeah the one best thing beyond all that the visigoths less be left behind one vanilla cream soda with cane sugar in it.
Rym: Drinking it right now.
Scott: Okay, I don't really care.
Rym: All right, so you don't like the good things in life.
Scott: Do you mean the poison?
Scott: all right.
Rym: so a delicious creamy soda made with the finest?
Rym: Madagascan Bourbon vanilla beans?
Scott: Yeah I'm sure business.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's not it's it's mostly marketing.
Rym: I'm sorry that you cannot enjoy the wonders of sparkling water cane sugar juice and vanilla.
Rym: yeah I'm sorry.
Scott: I can only enjoy things that are real.
Scott: and you know the label on something doesn't suddenly make me think it's so great.
Rym: It's not so much the label.
Rym: It's the fact that it's sugar water with vanilla extract in it.
Scott: Yeah, you could just take sugar water, but then I'll extract.
Scott: you don't need to get fancy sparkling water.
Scott: That's all bullshit.
Scott: Just made up.
Rym: um Scott sparkling water doesn't mean anything other than being carbonated.
Rym: I can't easily carbonate.
Scott: carbonating immediately makes things worse.
Rym: I'm sorry that your mouth for whatever reason can't handle the carbonation not even that carbon dioxide Poison.
Scott: not good for you.
Scott: your body gets rid of it.
Scott: Why would you put it in?
Scott: you get all that goes out.
Rym: if it goes in the stomach doesn't hurt you still not good Why not?
Scott: Why wait what what's good about it?
Rym: What it tastes really good?
Scott: Carbon dioxide is days like anything.
Rym: it had the sparkling.
Rym: this of it in a drink does?
Scott: no it doesn't.
Rym: uh I Submit that it was the flavor of it.
Rym: then Scott I submit that in a double-blind test people could taste the difference between carbonated and non carbonated anything.
Scott: Yeah, cuz they would feel it.
Scott: It wasn't it?
Scott: not a taste?
Scott: you if you had no taste buds you can see guys the difference.
Rym: You know smell is a large component If not the primary component of taste.
Scott: so I would argue that a carbon dioxide doesn't smell like anything.
Scott: So I would argue that a person with no olfactory nerves and no tongue could tell the difference.
Scott: I would argue it is a matter of feel.
Rym: I would argue that why limit the idea of taste to just one or two senses?
Rym: because because then Like something or don't like something because the texture the texture is just feeling.
Scott: yeah, you know I've never really understood those texture.
Scott: people I mean oh I guess the only thing where I don't like it because of the texture is like tentacles or something other than that.
Scott: Textures of foods.
Scott: really don't bother or not bother me you do understand it because you just said you understand it only that only the tentacles.
Rym: Cuz they're too chewy so someone else might have that feeling about something else.
Scott: Yeah, they stupid.
Rym: Okay, so captain tech news.
Rym: What do you have in the tech news?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: we haven't talked about tech yet.
Rym: Shall I go first.
Scott: let's try to talk about tech for the rest of the show all right.
Scott: I got it going.
Scott: I'll go first.
Rym: all right cuz I got this here.
Rym: I just read this article, but it's the funniest thing.
Rym: you know I got this new job a while ago and I Actually do work at this job like for real and as a result I don't just sit there surfing the internet for you know one day out of the week.
Rym: So I actually don't get to read the news until I get home.
Scott: usually no man.
Rym: So uh I get home, and I see an article student given detention for using Firefox totally believable and I click on this.
Rym: and it is in fact a Piece of paper that has been scanned into the internet for us all to peruse.
Rym: and the I think the important part is Incident description today in class a big black bar.
Rym: That's kind of a weird name, but Had a program launched called Firefox or Fox fire dot execute.
Rym: I had told big black box to close the program and to resume work But he told me that it was just a different browser, and that he was doing his work.
Rym: I had given him two warnings, but he insisted that he was it was just a better Browser and that he wasn't doing anything wrong.
Rym: I then issued him detention.
Rym: mm-hmm Yeah, big black box should have been using that Fox fire program.
Scott: No not at all.
Scott: well I can say about this is first of all you want to tell the rest of the story or alright.
Rym: So the rest of the story here cuz alright.
Rym: That's a slash dot article, but you know how slash dot is.
Rym: It's not quite to the dig level of you know every single headline being complete and utter bullshit.
Rym: but at the same time Slash dot has been known to Redact or perhaps update a story a couple hours after it comes up.
Scott: I'm sure not something which dig is incapable of doing sure enough there.
Rym: Well.
Rym: Why would they bother fixing the Ron Paul article?
Rym: That's obviously incorrect when they can just have another Ron Paul article.
Scott: No good call.
Rym: So uh it's updated here And one of these cool officials was nice enough to contact us us being slash dot and let us know that this is a hoax.
Rym: If you were planning on calling the school, please refrain from doing so now.
Rym: This is where it gets interesting.
Rym: They know it's a hoax because the school said show said so and I'm not gonna read these schools claim that it's a hoax but Looking at it basically their claim is Doesn't really contradict.
Rym: What was in this detention letter.
Rym: They say it was modified, but I Kind of believe that this student was given a detention for something very similar to what was described in this letter.
Scott: well for me You know basically the the fact that the school said this and it is something the school definitely said because it's on the school's website Right.
Scott: so it is an actual.
Scott: You know notice from the school and basically this Specific incident of the you know detention for Firefox.
Scott: I have no clue whether it's true or not or how much of it's true.
Scott: It's completely uncertain.
Scott: That's that doesn't matter.
Scott: What does matter is that this sort of thing does happen because it was happening how.
Rym: I was in high school I got we got to be careful here because that is a dangerous slippery slope.
Rym: That's an argument that can get you in a lot of trouble.
Rym: I mean remember a while ago when there was a noose hung outside of a firehouse somewhere and someone was there's a big racism thing and Then it turned out later that that was a hoax that it was completely made up and that the person who was complaining had actually Put the noose there himself
Scott: uh-huh,
Rym: and The people who had been so vocal about it including this person basically said yeah, well that one was a hoax,
Scott: but
Rym: And then they just continued with their argument as though nothing had happened
Scott: Uh-huh,
Rym: so yeah, you got to be careful there right, but
Scott: I don't need to be careful because when I was in high school I got I got my circum anecdotal evidence here when I was in high school.
Scott: the school basically had a system where if you Like added any application to the system any of the desktop computers in the school or ran any Exe's that like weren't on this list.
Scott: like someone who did something at the school will I get an email about it, right?
Scott: So like this school probably has one of these stupid systems where someone runs an exe.
Scott: Right that is because how else would the teacher know Firefox study exceed Fox fire dot exe exactly?
Rym: how do we know?
Rym: is Firefox?
Scott: I know right it could have been Fox fire some other program, but anyway You know.
Scott: this kid probably you know downloaded Firefox ran You know the exe and the teacher you know probably got a little notice on their computer.
Scott: That was like someone is running an exe that isn't one of the ones on their computer.
Scott: go punish them You know.
Scott: so the teacher went over and of course the teacher is incompetent and knows nothing about computers Just doing what the computer tells them to and this student is being all not doing what the teacher says they must be bad.
Rym: Well, I I would go one step further And I think that it's a fairly more specific situation because if you read what the school said their statement about how The reports blogs and other sources on the internet indicating that big string student was assigned detention for using Firefox Instead of Internet Explorer are untrue and based on the fake letter Detention is assigned in our schools after appropriate warnings are given.
Rym: if students continue to engage in Non-academic activities or fail to follow a teacher's directive during class time Discipline can and will be assigned.
Rym: now I don't think we need another discipline.
Rym: reading, but I Think what happened the real story my guess here total guess.
Rym: you can't.
Rym: uh libel me because I'm guessing I don't know if this is true.
Rym: Well slander because it's not written down yet.
Scott: It's educated guess though.
Rym: Yes, it is an educated guess in my not so professional, but completely opinion istic opinion But based on what real life experience, but yet an opinion nonetheless.
Rym: yep this kid whoever he is you know big black box Was on the computer and he know he knows how to use a computer.
Rym: He's probably in a computer class or doing work in a class that involves computers.
Rym: But like pretty much any kid in middle school or high school Who is ever in a class with a computer teacher in a middle school or high school?
Rym: The assignment was probably something completely stupid, and he was bored.
Rym: So he just went to myspace or something and he happened to be using Firefox.
Rym: So a teacher comes over and says you're not doing your work.
Rym: kid gives her guff She gives him detention and to make it all formal.
Rym: You know he was running Firefox an unauthorized application, and that's just the.
Rym: the Specific legal is rule that he broke, but really he was just mouthing off and not doing his work.
Scott: Yeah, I get the feeling it's more like one of these systems that tells the teachers when they're running something.
Rym: I'm almost certain that I am because how well.
Scott: so this incompetent teacher know about Firefox?
Rym: seriously She probably got the someone else in the school to write it up Or maybe the letter was altered a bit And he was just trying to capitalize on the fact that it's Firefox because he knows that these slash-shot people freak out about it.
Rym: No, maybe look at they make very clear that he was given this detention for not following the teachers rules.
Scott: right now Here's the thing.
Scott: here's the thing right.
Scott: if You're not following a teacher's instructions, but you're right, and you oh You're up, then you should be rewarded in the teacher should be punished in fact fired.
Rym: the difference Here is that it depends on what I mean.
Rym: if he's supposed to do an assignment He's not doing it.
Scott: I guess the teacher you have evidence that he did it.
Scott: innocence.
Scott: I'll proven guilty.
Rym: uh well one That's not true in school, but beside me beside Otherwise.
Scott: the school's unjust if it teaches all.
Rym: the teacher wouldn't be doing anything wrong if the teacher assigned work And the kid just refused to do it.
Rym: because they can grade him accordingly punish him accordingly.
Rym: It's all in the rules.
Rym: That's all cool.
Rym: Yeah, so uh so much for your argument You can't put.
Scott: well the only way you can punish a kid for not doing work is give him a bad grade.
Rym: Uh no who says that you can punish?
Rym: you can have rules for you could say anyone doesn't do their homework gets detention.
Rym: That's bullshit, but a lot of schools.
Rym: Do that.
Rym: Well.
Scott: It's bullshit.
Scott: those schools are shitty, okay?
Rym: I think the the greater issue here since Scott seems to want to talk more about the the instance of dealing with Having teachers who are incompetent using computers.
Rym: If a teacher.
Rym: I'm of the opinion that if a teacher in you know a public school in the u.s.
Rym: is going to use a computer at all in their lectures in their stuff if they're gonna let students use computers in the classroom if They're not at least as competent as the students at computers.
Rym: They should not be allowed to use computers in the classroom.
Scott: Yeah That's what I'm.
Rym: they're only going to lose the respect of the students and not be able to effectively teach Pretty much immediately and going to just completely discredit themselves as teachers.
Scott: as far as those kids are concerned Yeah, I mean it would be the imagine if like some like eight-year-old kid had to teach calculus to calculus professors.
Scott: That's what it's like.
Scott: you know the The calculus professor is gonna goof off and do calculus together while the eight-year-old kid is like.
Rym: I was in middle school, and we had a computer lab and I. it was mandatory.
Rym: you had to take computer class Every year in middle school.
Rym: There's computer class one two and three.
Scott: yep that's what we had.
Rym: also, and I remember sitting down a computer class and Computer class basically involved the teacher Giving you a printed out word document or works document or possibly and a spreadsheet yep.
Rym: And by the end of the class period you had to duplicate that on the computer, and then email it to him.
Rym: yep And being smart one I could do it in like five minutes.
Scott: I did like 30 seconds.
Scott: usually they were really long and I had to type a bunch of ours weren't so long But what they would do is they make you do all sorts of different stuff like.
Scott: it would be pretty short But you had to bold this part and italics that part.
Rym: From what I hear from kids this sort of methodology and teaching about computers is still pretty much the predominant way of teaching computers in School.
Rym: it is I think that it is 100% ineffective and will do nothing but harm kids in the future.
Rym: I think it's just an awful way to teach and anyone who does that is not qualified to teach kids at all.
Scott: nope
Rym: but Beside all that being even smarter than just you know doing it quickly I Noticed that I could log into the computer locally instead of having to go through the you know net system yep, and If I got in locally I could do some shenanigans and mount network drives.
Rym: and that on those network drives were in fact the completed Assignments and the assignments that he had made and printed and then saved in his own personal directory.
Rym: that was not in any way protected Yeah, and basically every day.
Rym: I would just go to his directory get the file and then send it back to him.
Rym: Yeah, I did this for three years awesome, and he'd always come over and say like he Knew I was cheating.
Rym: he was so sure that I was cheating cuz no one can type that fast.
Rym: he didn't see me typing that much, but He could never figure it out And if he found me probably expelled me or something because the rules for messing with the computers were crazy.
Scott: The rules at the school right at my high school for like messing with the computers are crazy.
Scott: It's like if you're messing with the computers bleh bleh bleh hacking.
Rym: I was caught yeah hacking one tagging.
Scott: basically They had a desk the.
Scott: basically their Security was.
Scott: they had some sort of novell system on top of Windows where if you logged in as a student account There were no icons that you couldn't open the start menu, and you couldn't go to start run.
Scott: But if you pushed like f3 the find file dialog would show up.
Scott: So you would search for like star dot star right you'd right-click on a folder and say explore Explorer would show up and you could explore every single directory and run any executable you could find and do anything you wanted.
Rym: I went one step beyond that.
Rym: I just brought boot disks to school.
Scott: I could even run the novell like you know the novell Administration program and I could administer the school's network as a student account.
Scott: all the only security was that there was you know No icon for it on the desktop or in the start I think the best thing was.
Rym: in one day I showed my English teacher how I could just look at all the grades any time and change him if I wanted.
Rym: there's no way She could know yeah, and she was like you're lucky.
Rym: I'm not Incredibly stupid or I probably would have expelled you and called the police And then she told me to never show any other teacher that again and pretend we never had that conversation.
Scott: see that's the thing Is it?
Scott: it's just so.
Scott: uh we'll talk about it more later.
Rym: Yeah, well I'll state my controversial thing because I'd love to have anyone argue this against me.
Rym: all right I'm of the opinion.
Rym: now There is one allowance And I think the allowance is purely for people who are already teaching as in you know people who are older who?
Rym: Started teaching before the modern era and when I say the modern era at this point I mean like the last two years because the world in terms of technology and the internet has changed a lot in the last two Years.
Rym: yep, I'm of the mind that going forward Anyone who is teaching children at all and anyone who's a teacher in a school for primary education secondary education What have you?
Rym: Who is not computer proficient as in?
Rym: Basically computer proficient able to do the things that people should be able to do on a computer.
Rym: computer literate Should not be allowed to be a teacher because computer literacy is literacy.
Scott: I think I'm gonna take it a step further.
Scott: you ready There's some of this sort of like this dogma Especially in Western schools.
Scott: right that it's sort of like.
Scott: you don't even question it because it's so basic that the subjects are English math Science and you know social studies reading writing arithmetic exactly and no one even dodgeball nobody even thinks about changing that right It's not even it's like.
Scott: it's like a structure.
Scott: That's just accepted.
Rym: people do all the time.
Rym: It depends on what kind of school you go to.
Scott: yeah, I know.
Scott: but well I guess there are some crazy schools You know that are pretty cool that do stuff that I mean.
Rym: I think that the general idea of teaching now and a lot of high schools and middle schools You know there's English and my school was lucky.
Rym: We broke it.
Rym: We broke up language and literature separately and most people have to take a foreign language.
Rym: Then you have the sciences and they pretty much break that up into physics biology.
Scott: Not until high school did they break them up.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but even then like there's still science And then there's social studies, and then later you get you know history and they specialize and all that yep And I think they do an okay job of that because we had computers.
Rym: the only problem with having the technology was that one.
Rym: They were trying to teach computer literacy and technology Separately.
Rym: when really I feel like every single subject in a school Requires computer literacy means you're in English.
Rym: I think I'd be typing everything on a computer.
Rym: Yeah, if you're writing things out by hand that something's wrong.
Scott: pretty much.
Scott: computer should be part of every class.
Scott: But there should also be computer class where you learn how a Computer works and you know bits and bytes and how to write Basic and all that stuff and they should actually teach you that it should be.
Scott: they should have as much time in that class as You do in English class.
Scott: it should be a full subject along with all the others.
Scott: the fifth So I wouldn't even say just computers.
Rym: I would call it like technology.
Scott: Oh, yes everything You should learn how to like.
Scott: you know solder circuit boards of course You know what.
Rym: I'm also of the mind that kids in middle school in high school should take classes on How banking works how loans work how credit cards and the economy work?
Scott: Yeah, they definitely need because in high school They told that there was an egg one economics class, and it did not teach you that stuff.
Rym: The only reason I knew about credit cards cuz my parents got me one when I was 16, and they said how it worked.
Scott: Yeah, there really needs to see that stuff should be part of home economics, but there oh,
Rym: you know what home economics for me was sitting in a room full of Barely sentient fellow classmates one of whom stuck needles in the teachers food one day And yet was not expelled because they decided that he was special And it wasn't like a special ed class.
Rym: this was just normal.
Rym: it required home economics for everyone And there were fights in the class all the time.
Rym: I was kicked out of the class eventually because I was trying to get kicked out because I was kind of afraid of those kids On a visceral.
Rym: wow they're trying to poison the teacher.
Rym: I don't know what they're gonna do to me.
Rym: Yeah, but we learned how to cook sausage And I sewed together a cube and that was the extent of it.
Scott: I in my home economics class the only ones they ever took.
Scott: Were in middle school, and I cooked Apple strawberry pie with some kids and Then I sewed some boxers, and then I sewed an alligator Jimmy Dean sausage the same sausage I had cooked at home the day before.
Rym: I cut it into slices.
Rym: I put it on a frying pan, and then I sewed a cube and stuffed it with stuff.
Scott: Yep, I made an alligator so much cooler all right anyway.
Scott: I let's move on to different news here.
Scott: all right.
Scott: Okay, the story here is did the NSA put a secret backdoor in the new encryption standard?
Rym: well I didn't read this article.
Rym: so about.
Rym: is the answer yes.
Scott: Well, maybe most likely possibly that there's actually significant evidence, right?
Scott: Basically, here's how it goes down.
Scott: right the NSA puts out a document You know some crazy government thing that says these are gonna be the encryption standards, right?
Scott: You know we're gonna use this one in this one in this one in this one, and there's a you know different.
Scott: There's different ways.
Scott: It's mostly random number.
Scott: generation is what we're talking about here, and there's many different ways of Generating random numbers right.
Scott: so there's like you can do it with.
Scott: You know you could do one with hash functions to generate random numbers.
Scott: You can do one with ciphers right, but and there's one that uses elliptic curves, right?
Scott: And the one that does elliptic curves the one that the NSA says to use is dual Underscore EC underscore DRBG.
Scott: all right now.
Scott: The other ones are fine.
Scott: You know they know all about the other random jump number generating things They know how they work, and they're cool, but this dual ER DRBG.
Scott: Whatever it is.
Scott: I'll just call it the dual EC.
Scott: from now on right it.
Scott: It's an elliptic curve random number generator a well-understood Technology here and some guys studied it and first of all it's slower and shittier than other elliptic curve random number J. Awesome Okay, second of all they've noticed a slight bias right now.
Scott: the slight bias doesn't in itself doesn't really prove anything.
Rym: Well, yeah, because random number generation to make truly random numbers is Effectively almost impossible right.
Scott: and this this small bias isn't a big enough bias to make the algorithms You know pointless is just a slight bias, and there's actually a workaround in the standard and how to avoid the issue.
Scott: But it is a slight cause for a concern, right?
Scott: Anyway the fact that there was a slight bias You know makes the crazy encryption guys the cryptographers be like whoa.
Scott: we're staying clear away from that when we got this other one That doesn't have a slight bias right.
Scott: there's a whiff of a problem.
Scott: We're gonna stay clear right now.
Scott: Here's the worst one in the.
Scott: in the document that describes the standard early on there's some constants that you have to use.
Scott: It's like here's the.
Scott: is this constant in this other constant?
Scott: right, but it doesn't tell you where these constants come from at all.
Scott: It just these are the constants.
Scott: use them.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: We use those constants, right?
Scott: some guy proved mathematically that There are some set of secret numbers.
Scott: all right and If someone had these because the you know because of these constants, right?
Scott: He was able to prove mathematically if there's a set of secret numbers, and if you had the secret numbers What you could do is you could collect 32 bytes of output
Rym: from
Scott: the random number generator Combine it with the secret numbers and then you would be if you would know everything that the random number generator was gonna do from There on out all right, so if you have the secret numbers it this particular random number generating algorithm You know What it's gonna do and you it's totally broken and not secure in any way.
Scott: the question is the the only.
Scott: So there is a back door into this random number generator.
Scott: The question is does the NSA have those numbers?
Scott: did anyone bother to figure out the numbers?
Scott: because it's it's ludicrously impossible To just figure them out, but whoever made the constants?
Scott: You know the constants that are in the paper that are unexplained where those constants came from.
Scott: if whoever made those Constants when they were doing the math to come up with those could have easily also gotten the secret numbers.
Rym: now Basically, I'm always of the mind that if ever I find out that Encryption or anything that I use is compromised.
Rym: I abandon it immediately unless there's no alternative.
Scott: Yep Now here's the thing is that Just now recently Microsoft Vista Windows Vista has added this algorithm as an option.
Scott: I know they say it's not on by default, but you can turn it on if you want and I don't know there must be how to use online like how to turn it on or how to turn it off or whatever.
Scott: but Yeah, basically you do not want to be using this random number generator.
Scott: No Your keys or anything your SSLs or anything.
Scott: you basically don't want to use this random number generator at all for anything Even if it's not a matter of security.
Rym: Well, I have to read more before I form my because you know, I have opinions on things But whenever you know my I guess professional opinion like as an IT professional What is my opinion on this?
Rym: but my hunch opinion is that this is in fact intentional just because the odds of something like this Being so perfectly there.
Rym: Yeah, that's that's kind of out there.
Scott: Yeah, basically if you're smart don't use this random number generator at all.
Scott: Just completely ignore it.
Scott: The problem is this is like the government standard.
Scott: that's in you know, the National Institute of Standards and T Whatever.
Scott: What's it?
Rym: Yeah nice time time, right?
Rym: I use them a lot.
Scott: Yeah, right this is their thing.
Scott: like these are the standard random number trainers use these and What the the elliptic hurt.
Scott: they the other ones they've you know suggested are okay, but the elliptic curve one they suggest is shit It's slow.
Scott: It's insecure.
Scott: It has a back door.
Scott: Even if the NSA doesn't have the keys to the back door There is a back door in it and someone has a small bias.
Scott: Eventually, I guess someone could figure it out.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: But yeah Well, I mean, you know process is getting better and you can always throw the quantum computing will fuck everybody.
Scott: Yeah Regardless don't use this don't enable it and make sure that You're steering.
Scott: steer clear of the dual EC DRBG random number generator things of the day.
Rym: So you realize that in Sweden they used to drive on the left-hand side of the road.
Scott: I didn't know I was never actually aware of which side of the road Sweden drove on.
Rym: Well from what I can read it seems like the majority of people in the world drive on the right side of the road.
Rym: Yep, that's that's pretty great and that very few places bother with this crazy driving on the left-hand side of the road business.
Rym: Well, Japan drives in the left right and Britain and Britain, but there's a lot of people There's always that.
Scott: from what I hear a lot of people are always advocating just switching Yeah, and that way that karma it's easier on the car manufacturers only to make cars with the wheel on one side.
Rym: But I was thinking about that and then I you know, I suddenly realized wait a minute How the hell would you go about that?
Scott: I mean if I had to suddenly drive on the left, that'd be pretty rough one.
Rym: I would probably crash into something because I mean especially for someone like me where I drive plus I wouldn't go buy a switched car right away.
Scott: So I'd be driving the left side of the road in my left-hand wheel car.
Rym: Well, I'm just thinking more along the lines of all my driving instincts.
Rym: cuz think I drive so much.
Rym: The driving is like this this subconscious thing.
Rym: My brain would just go into the wrong lane and kill someone.
Scott: probably I'd have to be thinking like turn plus highway on ramps totally broken suddenly.
Rym: Oh, yeah Especially in the US.
Scott: even if like everyone went home in their driveways and then everyone went back on the road driving on the left The highways wouldn't work.
Scott: You couldn't get on and off.
Scott: It'd be back.
Rym: Yeah, that's one thing.
Rym: Well, I know we have a lot of non-us listeners and I know there are freeways in the rest of the world But I don't think you quite understand the extent to which our freeways are freeways here.
Rym: Yeah now I'm not saying that's necessarily a good thing.
Rym: But yeah but anyway, and then I really started thinking about this and then I started looking online to see if it's ever happened before and sure enough Dagen H Aka the H day not D day.
Rym: We had D day and I guess F day and G day but then H day really.
Scott: so they act someplace.
Rym: actually The H stands for Holger traffic, which is the Swedish word for right-hand traffic.
Rym: So this day was on September 3rd.
Rym: That was a long time ago and basically from what I can gather Sweden drove on the left which was dumb because every one of their neighbors drove on the right.
Scott: And so what did you do at the border before Dagen H?
Rym: at the border users you swapped?
Rym: Oh, that sucks.
Rym: And also most people in Sweden had cars with the wheel on the left side because Right side right hand wheel cars are not that common, huh?
Rym: So it was pretty much just stupid that Sweden was driving on the left and Sweden realized that and for a long time there.
Scott: It must have caused a lot of trouble to not just with Swedish people going to other countries and having to switch at the border But people from but like, you know, Norway come into Sweden crash because they had to switch on the wrong side of the road.
Scott: They're not used to it.
Rym: So this is the story and it's on Wikipedia.
Rym: You can read it of Exactly how they pulled this business off and basically everyone go home then everyone can drive again.
Rym: They've been thinking about it for 40 years 40 years.
Rym: for 40 years this idea had been voted down and people kept voting to keep driving nonetheless.
Rym: and then in 1963 four years before they did it.
Rym: They said alright, we're gonna do it and they established the Stottins Hoeger traffic commission Mm-hmm, which was if you remember Hoeger traffic, it was the Hoeger traffic commission Uh-huh, and it was the state was basically the government entity that was going to oversee the change.
Scott: You pretty much need to make a whole new government entity to do something like that.
Scott: Now as long as you remember which the u.s.
Scott: Never remembers to do to remove the government entity when it's done Now it was.
Rym: it was a four-year effort not so much in terms of fixing the infrastructure but four years of doing psychology and Advertising to remind people that this was gonna happen Mmm, and then we should do some of that for our you know, turning off the broadcast TV.
Rym: So as the day neared apparently Every single intersection in Sweden was given an extra set of poles with an extra set of traffic signals wrapped in plastic Uh-huh.
Rym: So they basically built an entire parallel network of traffic signals Everywhere and they put a parallel set of lines were painted on to every single road with white paint and then covered with black Tape, uh-huh because previously they use these yellow lines.
Rym: So they're switching to white lines, too.
Rym: So basically they built an entire parallel infrastructure and then on Sunday December 3rd They took all the tape off and took all the plastic.
Rym: All non-essential traffic was banned from the roads for five hours from 1 a.m.
Rym: To 6 a.m.
Scott: It's a.
Rym: so only ambulances and fire engines and whatnot Yep, and any vehicle on the roads had to follow special rules.
Scott: and then at 4 45 a.m So most people stayed home because they were worried about dying every.
Rym: well who's gonna be on the road that early?
Rym: anyway?
Scott: I know right.
Rym: so at 4 45 every single vehicle on the road had to come to a complete stop And wait five minutes.
Rym: then carefully and slowly Everyone switch sides and then at five o'clock traffic is allowed to proceed.
Scott: So wait, so when did like people all around the country run around tearing tape and plastic office?
Scott: Yes, like whose job was that?
Scott: Did they have the government?
Scott: They had government people ever there?
Scott: also probably the best thing How did they have so many government people everywhere?
Rym: because Sweden is smart about that sort of thing.
Rym: one socialism alright - It's something that why can't they the u.s.
Rym: Do it.
Scott: We have so much money so much power We don't know to the left side of the road.
Rym: How come How come when the u.s.
Rym: Wants to do something we don't just do what Sweden did which is Get a bunch of smart people pay what it costs to do it right and do it because they're stupid yes, and people don't like change and It just read the rest of the story.
Rym: It's kind of crazy.
Rym: But my favorite thing in this Wikipedia article There's a picture of Stockholm shortly before traffic resumed and it's utter chaos.
Rym: It's just cars just kind of pointed.
Scott: Now, right.
Scott: So how long did it take before it was all good?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: cuz I mean.
Scott: now they're driving on the right and everything's cool, right?
Rym: Actually, there were fewer traffic accidents then that day than any other day.
Rym: Well, because everyone's going all carefully there weren't accidents But people were probably all like well or the speed limit for like months after it just until people got used to it.
Rym: I would probably obey a lower speed limit if something like that reason Oh, you know slow I'd be driving for like a year after something like that happened.
Scott: Yeah, probably But I'd be like every intersection.
Scott: I'd be thinking real hard like, okay No Right turn on red left turn on red and stop wait for the right turn signal.
Rym: there I do have to point out that in a nation like the United States.
Rym: I Believe that doing something like this today would be effectively impossible.
Scott: Yeah, this is too big.
Rym: It's not just that it's too big It's that our infrastructure is for cars is so advanced and so specialized.
Rym: now advanced is relative because it's invented someplace.
Rym: It's advanced.
Scott: It's it's special.
Scott: Well It's special.
Rym: our freeway network a modern freeways in the u.s Like the ones that are in Texas or even like in the Midwest most of the Midwest and even the major ones in You know New York area that don't go through New York City.
Rym: Our marvels of engineering and even the ones that are in like are totally screwed up like i-95 near New York City or I 287 near New York City Yeah, or any of those Despite I mean that's just a matter of there's too many people on the road.
Rym: The fact remains that there's still marvels of engineering and the fact that they work at all is kind of crazy.
Rym: But they're so specialized for the way traffic goes that you'd basically have to rebuild every freaking goddamn Onramp in this country over the course of 20 or 30 years.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So yeah, okay.
Rym: This is pretty cool.
Scott: All right, you like Star Wars toys room.
Rym: You know when I was a kid and I like Star Wars But there weren't Star Wars toys except for the old ones that were valuable.
Rym: I wanted nothing more than Star Wars toys.
Scott: Yeah I see when I was a kid like I kind of knew what Star Wars was but I didn't really get into it like I Got into a little bit later than everyone else.
Scott: Like all the other kids were like kindergarten first grade.
Scott: They were Star Warsing it up.
Scott: I wasn't Star Warsing it till like a few years after that I don't know when it was.
Rym: but one day my dad sat me down and showed me Star Wars and I was in awe.
Scott: So like my friends had Star Wars toys, you know.
Scott: But I didn't and I didn't really care because I didn't really understand like I could recognize C-3PO But I didn't know what his name was.
Scott: I just knew that was the gold Star Wars robot and stuff like that.
Scott: You know, I knew that there were lightsabers and Darth Vader, but that was it.
Scott: I guess I knew.
Scott: I knew what I knew from Muppet Babies, right?
Scott: So Star Wars toys, I didn't have so many.
Scott: and you know if you go to buy a Star Wars toy now They make a Star Wars toy out of everything.
Scott: I mean even if they're not making it right now it fucking exists.
Scott: They got like, you know any pose any character even the most minor character.
Scott: There's a Star Wars toy for it.
Scott: You know every single dude like background guy number five.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: He's got a figure you know, so There are though a few things that they have not made Star Wars toys out of and this website has pictures of them.
Scott: Let me let me tell you a few of them ready.
Scott: First of all, there is no Star Wars toy for the planet Alderaan But here's a picture of one.
Scott: It's just a bunch of rocks in a box.
Rym: Oh I don't know that that one's good.
Rym: But I think the Uncle Owen action figures probably the best.
Scott: Well, it's not just the uncle Owen action figure because I'm sure one of those does exist.
Scott: It's smoldering uncle Owen corpse and smoldering on Peru corpse action figures.
Scott: They are not included in the smoldering moisture farm playset.
Scott: They are sold separately.
Scott: Yeah, there's also the the dead ewok toy and the force.
Scott: actually that's all of them.
Scott: that's on this website.
Scott: The force is just an empty box.
Rym: The only problem with this thing of the day is that there aren't enough.
Scott: Yeah, they need this.
Scott: They should have made us something awful.
Scott: or perhaps You know some sort of Photoshop Friday worth 1000 like Star Wars toys that don't exist.
Rym: Maybe someone should do that Maybe.
Scott: so I want to see here people come to our forum and show us the Star Wars toys that do not exist.
Rym: Yeah, let's see what your Photoshop skills are.
Scott: Let's see if we can think of one right now.
Rym: So much for that.
Scott: Oh, I know Just a toy.
Scott: That's just the hole on the Death Star.
Scott: They have to shoot into just the hole.
Rym: I think you're forgetting Something very important the Sarlacc.
Scott: I think there might be a Sarlacc toy.
Scott: Let me go now.
Rym: I don't know if there is a Sarlacc toy.
Scott: I'm looking it up, right?
Rym: There should be but hold on.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Okay, there is a Boba Fett unleashed toy that has the tentacles of the Sarlacc grabbing Boba Fett by the leg.
Rym: But it isn't a Sarlacc with a digestive pit.
Scott: It's a part of a Sarlacc that is and Boba Fett statue on top, huh?
Scott: Yeah, so it's close.
Scott: It's it's quite a bit of Sarlacc there, but that's all.
Rym: so yeah, this is Star Wars toy of everything Right, so I guess we can just pick right off where we left off in from my news earlier in the show.
Scott: Yeah, basically, let's start off with it with a more general view here zoom out of it, right?
Rym: So you have a planet?
Scott: Yeah, we know we have this country or at least this, you know many countries in the world I assume are having a similar problem.
Rym: Wait, are we doing the global statement that we're gonna narrow our focus and then have a thesis statement?
Rym: Maybe I'm proud.
Scott: Okay where knowledge about Technology and computers and electronics, you know is becoming more and more essential?
Scott: We've said it before on the show that we how many times have I said the exact words?
Rym: computer literacy is literacy.
Scott: Yes, you know it right if you are alive today and you are not literate in the language of your nation or you know The the language most used near you if you cannot read and write your life is severely limited and you you cannot progress in society and many options are unavailable to you unless you become literate.
Scott: and In today's world if you are not technology literate It is going to hurt you almost as bad as if you are not literate in language and your you knows and I mean time Goes on that problem will only get worse.
Rym: I mean you might say well, it isn't right this second, but it's getting there.
Rym: I mean think about how much the how important computers and the internet got in the last five years the last ten years the last 20 years.
Rym: They're gonna change more in the next two years than they did in the last ten.
Scott: I mean right now if you can't read and write or do simple math, you can barely even get a job at McDonald's.
Rym: You're basically relegated to hard manual labor.
Rym: You could be a janitor maybe no because janitors have to be able to at least read the cleaning stuff.
Rym: They gotta know how to That's true.
Scott: I mean Yeah, so I mean, yeah think about that right the janitor if you can't read He might put out these slippery floor sign when it's the door closed sign or something.
Rym: I think the the multiple languages plus the nice picture of a guy being killed.
Scott: I know that does help it does help but I'm more worried about that.
Rym: You know mixing let's say one kind of cleaner and another kind of cleaner, right?
Scott: So as time goes on I say in the next decade or two It's gonna get to the point where if you are not computer literate You can't even work at McDonald's because everything will be computerized at McDonald's, you know We're.
Scott: you know If everything eventually is gonna be computer controlled every job is just gonna be Controlling the computer.
Scott: is it telling the computers what to do or not?
Rym: Even that.
Rym: but it's getting to the point even now where all basic jobs I mean your job is X like say my job is PR, right?
Rym: Well, I have to use a computer to email on my contacts because the business world runs on email now not on much else Mm-hmm.
Rym: And I have to be able to use a computer to design my PR press releases.
Rym: And then I gotta have to use a computer to go on the internet know where to send these press releases to check the internet buzz.
Rym: You can't be a PR person and not know about the internet and not be able to use computers effectively.
Scott: I think about a business.
Scott: a long time ago Let's say you know and nowadays businesses sort of have two parts They have if they're if they're a manufacturing business where they make stuff, right?
Scott: they have a building where they make stuff and they have a building where they do business.
Scott: and the buildings where they do business are just desks with computers on them and that's it.
Scott: and Back in the day if you went to a place of business You might see like the accountants have one kind of desk with you know Sort of you know adding machines and slide rules or whatever abacus is and the the other the other couple Yeah, the other people have desks where they have lots of files and folders and everyone sort of has you know Their desk is different.
Scott: They everyone has to learn to use different tools for their specific job and learn different things.
Scott: Nowadays, it's everyone is a desk of the computer.
Scott: You can't really do much if you don't know how to use the computer.
Scott: even in the factory.
Scott: you go into the factory.
Scott: There's a big machine that makes things with a computer next to it that controls the machine.
Rym: Yep I mean even when I was worked at IBM the even though the low is like the menial Jobs in the factory like the ones were.
Rym: basically you would go to a machine and pick up a whole bunch of things And carry into another machine.
Rym: put him back in.
Rym: then you had to sit at a computer and do a whole bunch of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, and if you couldn't do that stuff, you didn't end up working there that long and that wasn't the most glamorous job.
Rym: It was pretty much the lowest man on the totem pole.
Rym: You were paid less than the janitor.
Scott: Yeah, you're the guy who puts things in the machine.
Rym: That's that's a Things in the dumb machine because there were smarter machines where you had to know how to put stuff in it.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean that's basically the most unskilled You know least knowledge required job you can get in the United States is put things in the dumb machine all right, and you still need to have computer literacy for that even now to some level.
Scott: and The thing is is most people in this country, especially people who are older than us, right?
Scott: It's pretty much like we're pretty close to the line.
Scott: It's like people more than say 10 years older than us there are.
Scott: you know, that's sort of where the line is.
Scott: There are many older people have learned.
Rym: I think I can put this pretty succinctly because I'm not we're not talking about like right this.
Rym: second in terms of it's not like if you're 40 and you're working in the industry and you're not super computer proficient that You're done and you're screwed.
Rym: You're probably gonna make it till retirement.
Rym: just fine.
Rym: The problem is that people and it's not just older people a lot of people in this country And I think a lot of the problem also has to do with how these things are taught.
Rym: But we'll get to that because I think we mentioned earlier in the show It's that they separate using technology from Doing other jobs like they'll.
Rym: they'll teach the X skill X and then independent of that They teach skill computer when really skill computer is a part of skill X. like they try to remove the computer From the English or they try to remove the computer from the math remove the computer.
Scott: Some schools try to do that thing where everyone gets a laptop and they try to use technology in everything.
Rym: It's that's a great idea.
Rym: Let's not talk about the failings of why that doesn't work, but But in principle it should be that way.
Rym: computers should be used in pretty much every aspect of education.
Rym: Mm-hmm I mean I could see like if you're gonna have a tell like a an impromptu test I could see You know writing things by hand and this we're not saying you must type everything you must use the computer blah.
Rym: What we're saying is Computers are not a separate skill anymore.
Rym: The separate skill of computer is IT and CS and coding and when the computer itself is your job.
Rym: But a lot of people seem to think that if the computer itself is not your job Then you don't need to know about the computer and that's completely false.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like a car where you don't have to know how in the mechanism of internal combustion But you can still drive.
Rym: it might someday get to that point with AI and such but not in the next couple generations.
Scott: Nope, I at least were well beyond the point of DOS where you had to you know, use a command line.
Scott: now It's.
Scott: it's a lot easier now, you're better off, but you still have to learn a lot to be able to use a computer.
Rym: Yep, so you don't have to be like us.
Rym: You don't have to be a computer professional unless your job is to be a computer profession Which it might well be but you have to be able to use a computer.
Scott: Do you have to be able to use a computer without having to have like the system in yell at you?
Rym: so How come now may I don't?
Rym: I mean there's might be a lot of reasons for it.
Rym: How come?
Rym: at least in my experience I have never met a middle school or high school Computer teacher who knew one good goddamn about computers.
Scott: Well, here's part of the in my high school online.
Scott: Well in my high school in my schools, they didn't actually have computer teachers, right?
Scott: It was that, you know, some teachers knew more about computers and others, you know And some of them were actually good at using them, you know, but for example in my high school There were a bunch of computer classes you could take But pretty much all of them were like in the business school like how to use and they were all how to use word how To use.
Scott: you know Excel how to use whatever taught by business teachers and they would mostly teach business.
Scott: or you know Like when I took a how to type it was mostly like how to format a letter and how to type on these old.
Scott: I you know They that was the one class that used incredibly old computers as the how to type class because they had the old clackety XT Keyboards.
Scott: it was good stuff.
Scott: But the only other computer class was A Computer science classes visual basic taught by a math teacher who got read a book on visual basic The math teacher not a computer teacher.
Scott: and the reason is first of all, you know schools, you know People talk about schools not having enough money.
Scott: I'm not gonna talk about that now But I think you know, I'll just say that I think schools have plenty of money.
Scott: They just spend it stupidly.
Rym: Well, I think it's much more complex than that because there are schools that have plenty of money and spend it stupidly.
Rym: There are schools that spend their money smartly.
Rym: They just don't have enough money.
Rym: Yeah, it's all kinds To defray and just dilute all the flames.
Rym: We might get you can't apply a Blanket solution to the school funding problem in the United States because every school every state every town is completely different.
Scott: But I just want to say that there's a lot of people who are like money is the solution to all school problems.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: It's not school.
Rym: There are a lot of people who say money is the problem too are the solution to all Problems.
Rym: Yes, a lot of government agencies in the US like to just throw money at a problem And usually that just makes the problem bigger.
Rym: and now I have less money Yep.
Scott: But anyway, they the thing is is that anyone in order to actually have a good computer education You're gonna need someone at the school at least one person who actually knows about freaking computers like actually knows like as Much as we do or almost as much as we do someone knowledgeable who really knows like how a CPU works at least basically You know and these kinds of things.
Scott: how else can they teach them if they don't know?
Scott: right?
Scott: you your teacher?
Scott: Must know more than the student or else it doesn't work, right?
Scott: So the problem is is anyone who actually knows That amount of stuff can go and get a job and make a zillion dollars because there aren't enough of those people?
Rym: I mean, I'll be honest I really want to be.
Rym: my dream job for a long time was to just be a high school Computer.
Scott: that was also my dream job.
Scott: Summers summers off, you know don't have to work the whole day work in the town in which you live very short commute Really good benefits.
Scott: you get to work with cool kids and tea.
Scott: I like teaching kids and telling them what's up.
Scott: I mean, you know, I like I do a podcast or I tell people how computers work.
Scott: How awesome would it be if I sat there for you know, seven hours a day or I guess not seven hours But many hours a day telling high school kids how to do a computer.
Scott: So,
Rym: you know I applied to a bunch of teaching jobs and you know I was willing to get my masters and be a teacher as long as I could teach computer classes and I was even willing to stay after school and run computer clubs and anything computer they wanted and Be the head IT guy for their school if they wanted because I can do that.
Rym: Yep, but Pretty much every non teaching job.
Rym: I looked into paid Two to four times more than the best paying teaching job.
Scott: Yeah, even if I was like head computer guy for a school district it paid a pittance a Pitons compared to what I make at my sort of average coding job.
Rym: the other problem is it seems like it's pretty much impossible for someone who knows about computers and is you know a computer professional to Just become a computer teacher.
Rym: because schools don't want a computer teacher.
Rym: They want a teacher and they want them to teach a bunch of things especially in like American public high schools.
Rym: So they don't like.
Rym: they couldn't just get someone like me to teach a computer class.
Rym: They'd have to get me to get my masters.
Rym: They probably make me teach a math class or something stupid - they make you teach like physics And then you teach like one computer class a day And also I think the more even a bigger problem than that schools pretty much with rare exceptions I mean.
Rym: actually my old high school offers a lot of really good computer classes.
Rym: But that's because they're shall we say a wash in the money that comes from being one of the wealthiest suburbs in the country Even in places of washing money.
Scott: They do a lot of.
Scott: they try to run good computer class and they fail.
Rym: So that's what does they teach the kids see really well and a lot of teaching it though It's a special case.
Rym: there aren't many schools like that.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Rym: I could do a whole show on my high school.
Rym: Yeah, what I think it was a pretty good high school.
Rym: I think they did things right.
Scott: my high school is okay.
Scott: Yeah, wasn't the best wasn't the worst just kind of good good.
Rym: But it seems like a lot of schools aren't willing to put computer literacy as high up.
Rym: I mean they say like oh well you know math is important and science is important and all those things are important and they are.
Rym: but basic computer literacy is just as important if not more so because no matter it doesn't matter if you're good at math and good at Science and good at all these other things in the next decade or two if you're not also competent at computers.
Rym: You're worthless.
Scott: Yeah, also, you know, maybe I just thought of this just now Maybe some of it has to do with the the no standardized.
Scott: You know the standardized testing because it's like all these schools seem to care about.
Scott: is you know Their test scores and blabbity blabbity?
Rym: well part of that also has to do with the fact that You know the big problem again of how to distribute money to schools and every now and then people get the misguided idea that Why don't we reward schools who have better students by giving them more money?
Rym: or why don't we reward schools that?
Rym: Get more kids to pass and then schools either lower their standards So more kids pass or teach to whatever test they're using to determine how good the school district is or in a lot of cases Cheat outright.
Scott: Yeah teachers just say, huh?
Scott: We'll get more money if the kids do better.
Scott: Well, let's make all their grades go up.
Scott: We'll do get more money if the kids do worse.
Scott: We'll make all their grades go down.
Rym: It's like yeah, but let's not get off on the tangents of schools because I want to get specifically on technology.
Rym: Yeah, let's suffice to say boil it down.
Rym: core issue
Scott: Core issue is that schools don't know how to teach technology They don't have an incentive to teach technology and as a result, we're gonna I think the u.s Especially at least I don't know how it's going in other countries I think we're gonna fall behind the rest of the world because we're gonna have a generation of people who don't know enough about Technology who won't be able to do anything unless they know about technology.
Scott: and I there are some other places in the world maybe like South Korea and such.
Scott: We're gonna pull ahead of us and make a bunch of awesome things.
Scott: and we're not gonna make awesome things because their people their labor Force knows how to use computers and ours doesn't.
Rym: so specifically why I mean I think they're on one hand one really important issue here is that like I said before, you know They always separate the technology from the rest of the classes.
Rym: so there's the computer class and then there's the English class and they don't use computers in the English class, but Beyond that they a lot of schools try to integrate like they say Oh, we're gonna integrate computers everywhere as it should be, you know computers are going to be you're gonna
Scott: use technology in all the classrooms Everything's gonna be all teched up and I all sorts of things and they put technology in every classroom of some sort.
Rym: now Even if the school has the the rare competent computer teacher or the good computer teaching department in the high school That's great.
Rym: So the computer classes are good.
Rym: but now kids are in an English class and That English teacher doesn't know jack all about computers and they use the technology Inefficiently and incorrectly and it go.
Rym: it's worse than just you know using it inefficiently.
Rym: but like I said earlier in the news part when a kid is in school and A teacher is trying to teach them something and the kid actually does know more than the teacher The kids not gonna listen that teacher ever again.
Rym: They've lost all respect for that person.
Scott: as an educator I can't tell you how many times especially in high school, but also middle school, right?
Scott: Some teacher would have some sort of technology in the classroom that they were supposed to use to teach us with right or like a graphing Calculator or some sort of.
Rym: you know overhead graphing graphing calculators were the worst.
Rym: They didn't know how those work
Scott: or or some sort of you know computer display or some sort of magical chalkboard Right, and it's like the teachers would just have sort of like this instruction like this sort of like manual Like here is how to use this technology to teach the students right and they would just do what the manual said.
Scott: and if it even worked at all and I'd be sitting there and I'd be like I know how this shit works and you're doing this in a stupid way and You're don't actually understand how this technology works and you don't.
Scott: the teacher needs to have an Understanding of how the technology works not just following directions But actually needs to know how it works now.
Scott: It's not to be able to use it as an effective teaching tool Even if they really know how to teach really well.
Scott: They if they have a tool that that has the potential to help teach and they don't know how to use the tool That don't know any point in using it.
Rym: now.
Rym: remember they don't have to be a computer scientist They don't have to be able to write the program They don't have to be able to set up the network.
Rym: They just have to be able to use the tool.
Rym: and the fact that I think the majority of educators in the United States Cannot even use the tool is the biggest problem in education today Discounting money problems in poor districts.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, some teacher might have say You know like a magical, you know chalkboard.
Scott: that's all digital, right?
Scott: And there could be a lot of.
Scott: there's a lot of cool things you could do with the digital chalkboard to to teach better.
Scott: Right many things.
Scott: you could get some videos up on there and pictures move them around.
Scott: I could think of a million things right now a way in which a digital chalkboard That's just like a giant LCD screen or something would improve educate could be used even by like a math teacher To make it, you know to teach the students better and have them understand math better.
Scott: and this is they do with a regular.
Rym: This is why money often doesn't solve the problem because look poor school can't afford even textbooks.
Rym: So they're screwed.
Rym: already Rich school can afford everything they want.
Rym: So they spend the money on you know, the big technology.
Rym: We're gonna get the smart classrooms and then none of the teachers know how to use it.
Scott: And when the school comes to get inspected they go look we have all this cool technology.
Scott: Look how cool we are.
Scott: We're the best school.
Scott: We have technology and the teachers are using it to teach students.
Rym: I mean while I you know as a kid.
Rym: I sit there at the computer and I've already broken out and I'm on the internet or Chatting on prodigy or something and playing some games.
Rym: I installed while the teacher is Laboriously trying to explain how to make something bold in Microsoft Word.
Scott: Yep I mean you think about it.
Scott: you give the teacher the digital chalkboard, right?
Scott: There's a potential there to to really have an amazing teaching experience better than with the regular chalkboard.
Scott: But what's really gonna happen?
Scott: that teacher who doesn't know how to use it doesn't know how to use the tool properly is actually gonna do a worse job of teaching than if they had the plain old chalkboard.
Scott: because they're only gonna be able to Do things with that because they only know to do things with it that they would do with the normal chalkboard.
Scott: So they're not actually creating a better teaching experience.
Scott: They're just using the technology because that's what you're supposed to do.
Scott: You're supposed to use technology in the classroom.
Scott: So that's why they're gonna do it worse because they don't know how to use the technology.
Rym: sadly It's not just technology because I can think of a lot of instances when I was in middle school Especially where it wasn't just I'd be in a class and the teacher would be wrong
Scott: Outright
Rym: Obviously wrong and yet to point that out was often cause for disciplinary action.
Rym: Yep I mean I think the my fate one of my favorite moments ever in middle school is this teacher was teaching us how to like plot.
Rym: It was a social studies teacher nonetheless, but she's teaching us how to like plot data and analyze like a graph.
Scott: I should be math teacher.
Rym: Yeah, but she's doing it.
Rym: You know and I can see the point cuz I'm really a big advocate of cross curriculum.
Rym: Definitely because I that's you can't I?
Rym: you know, we said, you know if you split the technology from the other things then it's kind of like how a lot of people especially older people have trouble with computers because even though they could solve the problem on their own if they apply just their rational intelligence Which they have to the problem people Compartmentalize things and they don't realize that they can use their life skills in areas.
Rym: They might not have expected They can fork it in, you know a field of related knowledge.
Rym: Yep I mean you might be 70 and you know jack all about computers.
Rym: But if you use the computer and it breaks and you read what's on the screen and you're smart You can figure out how to make it go, but a lot of people run into a computer problem and they say oh It's a computer.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It's in the computer don't even read what it says on the screen.
Scott: That's why you say what was the error message?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Just with technology people Compartmentalize partly I think because the way education is in the US and as a result They don't have this ability to fuse knowledge together.
Rym: and you know, the whole is greater than the sum of the parts.
Rym: kind of deal yep, but This teacher is teaching this wrong like outright wrong.
Rym: It is just pathetically incorrect what she has said and I raised my hand to basically say, um, you're doing it wrong that's not how you do it.
Rym: and She says no, I'm doing it right.
Rym: What do you know?
Rym: Yeah, I'm the teacher and I said you're doing it wrong.
Rym: Do you want me to go get the math teacher and prove it?
Rym: and then she freaked out?
Rym: And the freaking out culminated in where if you're so smart Why don't you teach the class?
Rym: and she like stood up there and she's like she folded her arms And she gives me this look of how do you like it now?
Rym: now that spotlights on you and I get up I walk to the front of the room and I take the chalk and I take the thing and I taught the class Yep, and then I was recommended for detention.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: See I read a story online.
Scott: Don't know how true it is because the story online.
Scott: but the story was that there was some some high school class.
Scott: I think it was a science class and On the first day of this class the kids went in and the teacher taught him all about this animal.
Scott: I forget the name of the animal, but the teacher of Jabberwocky Maybe not the Jabberwocky But some other animal right.
Scott: and the teacher taught everyone about this animal and told them there's gonna be a quiz the next day All right.
Scott: So the kids are all taking notes about this animal that teachers teaching them about and you know in the next day they come in And they get a quiz Right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I think he gave him the quiz at the end of the class or something I don't remember regardless.
Scott: He taught him about an animal.
Scott: He gave him a quiz on the animals.
Scott: It's the first thing they do in this guy's class, right?
Scott: he gives him back the quiz and everyone got all F's right and those F's fucking counted and Basically everything the teacher told him was a lie on purpose told him about a fake animal made up a bunch of bullshit.
Scott: That was totally believable and he said it was all wrong.
Scott: I totally lied to you.
Scott: so you got all the questions wrong because you answered what I told you and Those students went on first of all.
Scott: They loved that class and that teacher was awesome and every teacher needs to be like that and any teacher less than that shouldn't Be a teacher.
Scott: but the problem is there aren't enough people like that because they weren't.
Scott: there's not enough people taught.
Rym: There aren't even enough people who know how to make a US business have that guy teach the entire country with over the internet.
Scott: That's what they should do.
Rym: I've had a couple teachers like that.
Rym: So yeah, definitely.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, there were a few.
Scott: they're always a few in every school, but there's never enough.
Scott: and The the students those students would go into the other classes and always be questioning the teachers Just like he taught them to and they'd often be getting that telling other teachers They were wrong and the other teachers didn't like that guy so much.
Scott: But that's he was a good teacher and the rest of them were shitty teachers and the kids that were in his class turned out Awesome.
Rym: Well, I remember the one time my little brother was.
Scott: it was a true story because it was a story.
Rym: This is a true story.
Rym: I think I told on the show before but it bears repeating.
Rym: I'll be brief.
Rym: my little brothers in like elementary school and The textbook has a typo.
Rym: it switched am and p.m When talking about time like noon and midnight, so it was wrong.
Rym: in the textbook The teacher teaches this my brother little brother raises hand little elementary schools kid and says oh you're wrong, you know 12 p.m.
Rym: 12 a.m.
Rym: Is like this and The teacher basically says you don't know anything.
Rym: You're just some kid.
Rym: I'm the teacher I'm right and then proceeds to teach but the textbook said which was wrong.
Rym: now This isn't like some esoteric thing 12 a.m.
Rym: 12 p.m.
Rym: Noon midnight.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: So she then, you know, my brother says well you're wrong and he won't let it drop.
Rym: So she basically ridicules him in front of the class like 10 minutes about how how dare he?
Rym: you know, look at him.
Rym: He's dumb.
Rym: He doesn't know anything and yet he's trying to you know, show me up.
Rym: He's trying to ruin your education and get in the way of you all being taught because he thinks he knows better than me the teacher.
Rym: So he comes home in tears, you know little kid obviously and tells my mom No, no, so that's it you could.
Scott: you can tell if you have a good mom cuz a Bad mom goes and shut up and a good mom goes and smacks teachers around.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: it's like in Donnie Darko when his parents get called into the school and they you know that that counselor is telling his parents what he Did and instead of being angry they're just laughing like That's so great.
Rym: Yeah I can't believe he did that.
Rym: He's That's how it should but the righteous fury.
Rym: now it gets better.
Rym: My mom goes into the school All right, and you know, she goes to talk to this teacher and she tries to explain and the teacher basically says yeah Well, your kid was wrong.
Rym: So I corrected him and he made a fit.
Rym: So my mom says, you know that 12 p.m.
Rym: Is noon and 12 a.m.
Rym: Is midnight, right?
Rym: So she pulls out the textbook and shows to my mom says see Mm-hmm.
Scott: So obviously this teacher was taught by someone that the teacher in the textbook is always right.
Scott: Well, she had ten and not to question authority.
Scott: Yeah ten your problem.
Rym: Yeah, she had tenure.
Scott: I don't think that tenure should exist.
Scott: I think teacher to be fired immediately.
Rym: So, um, my mom goes and just walks out finds another teacher and the teachers like well, oh, it's that teacher.
Rym: Oh, I'm coming for this.
Scott: Oh And give me must've hated this teacher.
Rym: the teachers like see she And the guy looks at the book and says well yeah, there's a typo in the book and then he walks out of the room and Yeah, that was the school district we eventually sued.
Scott: so yeah, but I'm you know threatened to sue.
Scott: There's just a general problem of how can we I think the fundamental problem here, you know Cuz we talked about the technology aspect I guess as much as we could but the fundamental problem seems to be how can people educate our children when they themselves?
Scott: Or at least not all of them, but enough of them are not educated enough themselves Like they don't even know everything that they're teaching?
Scott: How what do we do about that?
Scott: and more specifically and you can't just rely on?
Scott: Textbooks and things like that because obviously they're not always right.
Rym: Plus, I mean just to get back to the technology thing to just I am of the feeling Seriously that within 10 15 20 years at most you are not qualified to teach at all.
Rym: If you are not basically proficient in computer, you're not qualified to work at McDonald's.
Rym: All right, I'm hungry.
Rym: I think that's the end of that.
Rym: yeah stay tuned tomorrow.
Rym: I'm not sure what we'll talk about yet.
Scott: I have no game day.
Scott: No clue at all.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.