Rym: It's Monday October 8th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm sick, and this is GeekNights tonight since Scott is indeed sick.
Rym: We talked about something a little boring printers.
Scott: Let's do this so I'm not Above the weather.
Rym: Oh, what was that?
Rym: What's going on Scott?
Scott: Um This show's not gonna be easy to do.
Scott: I don't think Now.
Rym: now why is that?
Rym: I mean to some.
Rym: someone like you who you know very very loudly proclaims They never get sick, and he never.
Scott: They never.
Scott: but you know sometimes less often than other people like or Scott didn't go to work today, and he's feeling really sick uh-huh.
Scott: and Yeah Maybe I should just say less.
Scott: so the show doesn't waste a lot of time.
Rym: And but I suggested we just skip a show, but you wanted to do this.
Scott: I gotta prove that I'm better than all those other Podcasters who who just skip shows at the drop of the Hat they come out with like one show a month.
Rym: One show a month if we're lucky yeah, so like we're better than all you.
Scott: we're doing shows and we're sick.
Scott: We don't let shit get in our way.
Scott: We're better than you.
Scott: you suck.
Scott: If you ever try to say that you're better than us in any way I'll say I did a show when I'm sick, and if you?
Rym: well I think you would have said you did a show when you were sick or I say not.
Scott: So you gotta do.
Scott: you got to do a show and I've got.
Scott: I don't know what I've got But there's not.
Rym: I know what Scott's got.
Scott: he has a cold But when there's you got to be in worse condition than me and do a show before you can say anything about me.
Rym: Well anything about you.
Rym: in regards to podcasting Also, it's not like this gets you a free pass out of anything also in completely unrelated news.
Scott: We used to do these like Harris polls, and it's basically you sign up, and they send you links in the email.
Rym: Yeah You know the only reason I stopped doing that Was because I got a bunch of Harris points, and I asked for a knife set And it was like a $80 knife set and it never came.
Scott: See you I see I did it and I asked for a simpson season 1 on DVD.
Scott: After I got enough points for doing enough surveys And they gave me simpson season 1 on DVD, and I still have it.
Scott: so I kept doing it and then I decided today They've been emailed.
Scott: they email me like about once a week You know and I decided I didn't want to do these polls anymore.
Scott: I got tired of them I didn't care anymore.
Rym: the reason I always did him not so of one because I always wanted to win that 10 grand.
Scott: Yeah, every time you do a survey.
Rym: There's a chance to win $10,000, but more importantly I did them just because I I Noticed and Scott.
Rym: I think would agree that I was often the outlier
Scott: Because
Rym: I always showed you some of the like pending results as you were going and you could always see like wow That's that little lump that lump is me But it's really the results
Scott: of the end because they don't want to influence your choices
Rym: Yeah, but you can always see like huh like most people watch you know 20 hours of TV a week There's Rym the only person who said zero
Scott: yep, but you know I also Partially did them because I felt like I was having a say because someone you know no one.
Scott: They don't make a poll unless some company is doing market research You know.
Scott: so if I'm answering some come that is gonna factor into the the numbers that some company is paying for and they're gonna Change their decisions slightly based on what I have as a result to try to I guess throw my way What little weight I had around more.
Rym: I always gave very extreme answers.
Rym: I don't like voting but in companies It's like if I didn't like something a little I'd give it a zero and if I liked it at all I give it a 10.
Scott: Yep, so I used to do these things for a long time And you know I only ever the only you get even every time you do when you get points And you also get the chance to win $10,000.
Scott: I never won because if I did I'd pay off my car loan, but You know I got these points and at first I spent the points on the Simpsons season 1 DVD But then I never spent the points again.
Scott: so today I go and I have enough points to buy the biggest prizes they offer right.
Scott: so I'm looking through and I'm like what the hell Should I get with these stupid points, and it's like a fancy watch.
Rym: Luggage Electric grill luggage is kind of expensive.
Rym: I should have gotten that.
Scott: I don't need luggage though And it takes up space which I also don't have.
Scott: get rid of your own luggage But I have perfect luggage.
Scott: it takes up a lot less space because it's a duffel bag.
Rym: I'll let on eBay, and that's all my duffel bag sell the old the new luggage on eBay, but hey no Why not get some cash instead of whatever you're gonna get?
Scott: no so so to my amazement There was also like some iPod dock boom boxes things which I thought about getting.
Scott: there was a 2.1 stereo system I thought about getting because that's what I've been kind of looking for.
Scott: you should have gotten that but it was actually a DVD player That came with 2.1.
Scott: Speakers, so I'm not sure how it hooked up, so it might have been useless, but regardless I ended up getting something.
Scott: I need a lot which is the Sennheiser Wireless RF headphones, so we'll wait to see if they show up.
Rym: You realize the problem with the headphones is not the wire here But it's the splitter and the fact that we're using one headphone hole for two people.
Scott: I know, but I still think it'll be vastly superior to my current situation.
Scott: And how does it plug in with a either the big or the small headphone hole?
Rym: it has both.
Scott: Yeah It said it actually said to my amazement the little information they provided me about this product was that it had it 1/8 inch stereo mini jack with a quarter inch converter And I'm like huh look at that, so I clicked get because that was the best thing I could have gotten for all that time I spent
Rym: Right.
Rym: so in the news I got to talk about this because it's you know it's the news and everyone's buzzing about it And it's all the big deal, and I have a few things to say.
Rym: and that's it.
Rym: The RIAA won its first jury trial.
Rym: Oh no Now that would have been you know bad news like what everyone always said.
Rym: if there was a jury trial They'd lose because everyone hates the RIAA.
Rym: and while that's true the the facts of this case make it a little bit interesting for one.
Rym: From what I can read Almost everyone on the jury didn't even own a computer.
Rym: Yeah, like they didn't know anything about technology at all They.
Scott: it's the same problem with judges don't know juries don't know.
Scott: this is why we need a situation in which There are expert witnesses intelligent judges and juries that either know about computers or no juries.
Rym: instead They had expert witnesses who just said whatever they wanted him to say And - I gotta be the expert witness me call me the lawyers call me.
Rym: the instructions the judge gave to the jury very much Interpreted the law in a very specific way that may or may not be the end interpretation of this law.
Scott: Yeah, I hear they're appealing which is I guess of course.
Rym: They're gonna appeal.
Scott: You kind of have to these days You know.
Rym: but also there's a bunch of little things that can be learned for all of you budding pirates out there.
Rym: One the only reason this lawsuit actually worked was because this person Had a name online a handle if you were like many people do and this person was well associated with that handle and this person pirated the music of their choice from Kazaa with the same username.
Rym: Real smart good game.
Rym: rule number one if you're gonna pirate something use bit torrent and Don't have a username on some stupid cuz I kind of site because those sites are all worthless.
Scott: Yeah, and also it was sort of obvious that this person actually was pirating lots of music Intentionally and knowingly and all that like the the facts of the case.
Scott: It's like wow the person totally did it.
Rym: Even worse it looks like one of the defenses was that oh well I had a computer party and anyone could have downloaded those songs And the guy's a week as defense.
Rym: well That's not that bad of a defense.
Rym: the problem is they showed records that the same device had been connected continuously to as far as the cable company could see for all that time and That device was not a router.
Rym: No And there was all this actual evidence that she really didn't have any defense there.
Rym: He or whoever was.
Rym: I don't even know who were the trial was for I?
Rym: Mean all I have to say is that if anything like that happened to us we have an insecure wireless access point.
Scott: Well, it's not as it's not so insecure, but it's using WEP.
Rym: It's a hundred percent insecure.
Scott: Yeah, yeah to anyone intelligent, but normal people.
Scott: It's completely locked out.
Scott: They don't know what they'll do.
Rym: Yeah, but the problem is I almost worry that even if I didn't do something but if someone just used our access point and did something shady online if The jury is gonna be a bunch of people who don't even own computers, and I don't even understand what the internet is I?
Rym: Don't really have much confidence in me being found innocent of something I'm actually innocent of let alone getting off of something.
Scott: I might have done yep, so it really just kind of sucks.
Scott: I mean Basically it imagine if we had to go and sit on a jury in the year 3,000 and it was a case of like you know the the some guy made He made some mischief with his teleporter, so like we don't even know how teleporters work.
Scott: So the facts of the case are completely lost on us.
Scott: We don't understand.
Scott: Are you really peers at that point?
Scott: you know does it?
Scott: is it really?
Scott: I mean we always.
Scott: it's sort of vague and and Subjective what jury of your peers really means and people always argue about it.
Scott: but I think clearly that when you are dealing with subject matter that you the person who is the defendant or perhaps the the plaintiff clearly understand that if the jury also does not understand it and if a Expert witness testimony is not enough to make them understand it Then they are clearly not your peers.
Scott: and that is.
Scott: that is one case where I'll say they're not your peers And you need to get a different.
Rym: well the best part is it looks like the RIAA even in all the you know cases They made against this person.
Rym: one of them was that she is not some illiterate dumb computer user But actually was very tech savvy, and then she knew full well that she was doing or ha ha ha.
Scott: no Well, I guess on a scale maybe more tech savvy than the jury, but not as Evidence was.
Rym: this person had a Bachelor of Science in an unrelated field and because this person had graduated from college Obviously they are tech savvy and also.
Rym: I think this person had known to play online games once or twice in the past.
Scott: Wow, yeah, if that makes you tech savvy then Fucking Maven's here, I'm fucking like a genius if that for if that person savvy I don't know a word used for me triple plus savvy Maybe sal V Sal V like.
Scott: you know salve like.
Scott: you put salve on your instead of cream Scott.
Rym: you haven't even had any Sudafed lately, so I Don't think you know what you know.
Rym: salve savvy Whatever Scott.
Rym: What do you got in the news?
Scott: Okay, so you know the the Linux BIOS.
Scott: everyone talks about cuz right now your computer.
Rym: Not many people talk about that.
Rym: not many people know what that is okay, so your computer has this BIOS right the by.
Rym: It's probably Phoenix BIOS.
Scott: It's some sort of you know IBM PC BIOS.
Scott: if it's a PC Max the new max have like this open a firmware thing is completely different.
Scott: The most PC is pretty much every piece you're gonna buy us is BIOS, and we're not gonna talk about the BIOS.
Rym: It's a whole episode talking about by should do a show on that because it's kind of interesting and I think very briefly think It is.
Rym: your computer has changed a lot in.
Rym: you know the last.
Rym: I don't know 10 minutes, but especially the last decade The BIOS of computers has not changed very much.
Scott: Yes, the purpose of the BIOS back in the day was you turn basic input output system Not built-in operating system.
Scott: So it's basically your computer turns on and the first thing it does is it goes to the BIOS and says hey BIOS I got to start doing something here.
Scott: You know or else.
Scott: What's it gonna?
Scott: Do it's gonna do something first?
Rym: your computer has to know what I mean.
Rym: you think oh my computer just boots.
Rym: How does it know how to boot?
Rym: How does it know to start booting?
Rym: What does it do first when you put electricity into it?
Rym: How does electricity turn into a booting?
Rym: and yes, so I was does all that?
Scott: the BIOS helps with a lot of that.
Scott: But back in the DOS days right DOS didn't know dick DOS is dumb as shit.
Scott: That's why when you install the game in DOS and need to tell every single game that you had a Sound Blaster 16 And what IRQ it was?
Scott: Yeah, so the BIOS is sort of was the helper in those days.
Scott: That's why you didn't need to like tell DOS your video card drivers because the BIOS would help you out, right?
Scott: Nowadays, we don't need the BIOS to figure out that shit because Linux and Windows and Mac all these you know modern operating systems We don't need to tell them what where our sound card is.
Scott: they're very intelligent And like.
Scott: right now if you boot, let's say you have a computer with Windows or Linux on it, right and a BIOS.
Scott: Basically, you turn a computer on the BIOS counts your RAM and it checks what kind of CPU you have and it does all this Shit, and then your operating system starts to boot as soon as the BIOS is done and then your operating system Ignores everything the BIOS just did and does it all on its own a thousand times better than the BIOS did.
Scott: The only reason you need the BIOS is if you want to use a shitty operating system like DOS from the olden days Which I guess if you it's kind of good that it's there if you want to play old DOS games and install DOS that You would have this
Rym: DOS box
Scott: I know right but also free DOS which you would still need the BIOS free
Rym: DOS EMU.
Scott: Okay, okay But you know what?
Scott: I'm saying You want to get.
Scott: you say if you want to get the real experience over the real experience?
Rym: You mean the horrible experience?
Scott: Yes, that's what I'm saying.
Scott: But it's the true experience.
Rym: games like Suddenly crashing into a sea of ASCII and then a DOS prompt and boot disks.
Scott: Don't forget boot disks.
Rym: So boot disk because I didn't have enough random exact I bet right.
Scott: so hitting f5 manually loading mouse drivers because we don't use DOS anymore We really don't need the BIOS anymore We don't need to have.
Scott: the computer doesn't have to do that much when it turns on.
Scott: all it has to do is like get like say hey see that kernel over there low to go and The operating system takes care of the rest.
Scott: and if you got rid of the BIOS People have gotten rid of the BIOS.
Scott: They have these machines running Linux BIOS, which basically turns the computer on those Linux.
Scott: They can boot the machine from like nothing to ready to go in like three seconds.
Scott: It's ludicrous, right?
Scott: So Take that a step further.
Scott: I didn't even think of.
Scott: this is genius.
Scott: There's a thing that someone's coming out with called splash top And what they did is even better than getting rid of the BIOS to put a Linux BIOS, right?
Scott: Basically this motherboard with no hard drive at whatsoever.
Scott: No hard drive No disk drives.
Scott: just the motherboard with a CPU and some RAM and a monitor plugged in right?
Scott: You turn this thing on.
Scott: they got flash on the draw on the motherboard boots fucking.
Scott: they got Linux.
Scott: in that flash It turns on.
Scott: you got Firefox.
Scott: You got Skype.
Scott: You got Linux.
Scott: your mouse works it right in the BIOS.
Rym: You know, I've seen things like that before.
Rym: there was a. there was talk a long time ago But I don't know how far like this wasn't anything practical where people made a BIOS where you could check your email, right?
Scott: But that's not news.
Scott: That's not news because I am Scott and you know that if I see something like this I'm like that's bullshit.
Scott: You're never gonna see that.
Scott: in the end a product.
Scott: you could buy a new egg.
Rym: So do we see this as a product we can buy a new way?
Scott: if you want you can go and buy the aces p5 E3 deluxe and it's got this shit and I am so getting that.
Rym: Oh my god See this is the problem.
Rym: So getting that don't bother waiting for the next good thing to come out and buy your computer cuz you know what?
Rym: The next good thing is gonna come out every three months.
Scott: anyone who's thinking about buying a PC Aces p5 e3 deluxe motherboard.
Scott: There is no other.
Rym: if that is is the one I might have broken my Unbroken streak of only ever buying a bit mother below the streak.
Scott: It's so broken.
Scott: This is the motherboard.
Scott: people.
Rym: Hopefully Scott won't break any other streaks tonight.
Scott: aces p5 e3 deluxe.
Scott: buy this motherboard.
Scott: It is the shit you can.
Scott: you know that.
Scott: plus, you know That Linux is gonna work with all the stuff on the motherboard because Linux is on the motherboard.
Scott: You can't go wrong.
Scott: It's gonna work.
Scott: It comes with Firefox and Skype, right?
Scott: So like we always have computer problem, you know what if I think about that if you know We always have you know, if we didn't have two computers or more than one computer You have a computer problem.
Scott: computer doesn't work.
Scott: you go.
Scott: Ah shit.
Scott: What do I do?
Scott: I can't even look up the answer to my problem this computer if everything fails as long as your CPU and your RAM are still Good.
Scott: Boom you turn this on your network interface and your network interface and your network connection Right as long as the motherboard itself isn't broken.
Scott: You can turn this baby on get your Firefox and your Skype get some help and fix the thing without having to have two computers To play the slight devil's advocate.
Rym: I can do that now with a live CD because the odds of enough being broken to where a live CD won't work.
Rym: But yet the motherboard is fine.
Rym: That's not that great.
Scott: But what if your computer basically had a live CD built in?
Rym: that's nice.
Rym: That's update that Firefox in there.
Scott: It's quite hot.
Scott: The only - I can see to this is that the motherboard is kind of expensive, but it's so worth how expensive I think like $350.
Rym: Hey, I Paid a hundred bucks for my motherboard.
Scott: I know so my mother board has ten serial ATAs.
Scott: It is an expensive motherboard.
Rym: So if you if you're the penny pincher, I gotta say it's not worth it yet $300 I think about it.
Rym: This is just her mother board.
Scott: This is just the first motherboard.
Scott: Oh, yes, but it has it.
Scott: It's real.
Rym: So I'm excited, but I'm not willing to pay 300.
Scott: The other thing is, you know I'm probably if I didn't just upgrade my video card and my RAM I probably would have gone out and bought this despite the price because I'm crazy like that.
Scott: but if Since I'm gonna be waiting anyway until you know I guess my computer is completely old and busted in like two or three more years, but I'm two or three more years I'm getting a motherboard.
Scott: that's got this shit.
Scott: No doubt and it's pretty cool and anyone with you know, the money This is where it's at Things of the day.
Rym: So I don't think I've used this before.
Rym: Well, I've.
Rym: we might have seen something similar to it and I know a lot of people have made jokes like this before but this Is probably the best done version of this.
Scott: I think I've seen something like this But same people doing something slightly different.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: I think it's just part of this trend that college humor is more and more becoming the center of all funny videos on the Internet.
Rym: That aren't just a baby ripping paper and falling over trying to drink from a hose.
Scott: It's sort of like the slash dot.
Scott: It's like if like dig in YouTube and then the other end you have slashed on college humor, you know It's sort of like college humor only picks the really good ones or they make them, you know, and it's always Everything they have there is.
Scott: it is either quality or at least you can see it be quality to someone whereas unlike dig videos It's like some stuff gets dug up and you're like what the fuck is this shit like that YouTube poop thing?
Rym: Yeah, anyway, this is just one of those.
Rym: what if people talked in the real world the way they talk on to Internet and It's a pretty accurate representation of the average kind of conversation that takes place Representation of the stereotypical internet conversation, you know what?
Rym: go to FARC.
Rym: that's pretty much what's going on.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, go like something awful for him plenty arcade for I don't know.
Rym: I think the highlights are when the captchas come into play.
Rym: Yeah, just when he's like read this and the guys like Yeah, that was good stuff the the cap check and just the one guy who's like that's gay Gay.
Rym: Yeah, people actually type that.
Rym: you'll see people type that whole thing.
Rym: I just said out they sure do and I like it was okay.
Rym: I didn't really laugh out loud, but I found it funny.
Rym: I laughed out loud at the end.
Scott: It's sort of like it's one of those things where it's not actually funny, but it's sort of it's like, you know It's like you just smile and nod and you know, and you know, this thing has to exist.
Rym: It's like yep At the end when the guys are like first thing they're guys like ah fuck I just I cracked up I couldn't stop.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good one.
Scott: All right, so, you know them model rockets.
Scott: you like model rockets.
Rym: Um, we haven't done a show on model rockets have we?
Scott: I've only made like five.
Rym: I was heavily into model rocketry as a child and also the laws in Michigan were much laxer than they were in, Connecticut Or New York.
Rym: I made some.
Scott: I made most of mine in Pennsylvania where the laws are much laxer.
Scott: So Um, yeah model rockets are cool, you know, it's even cooler.
Scott: model rockets that look like stuff like.
Rym: I had a model rocket That looked like an x-wing but it was little and I broke it.
Scott: Yeah Well, this guy made one that is an x-wing big like real big like I guess as big as a real x-wing.
Scott: It's real big It's it's it's really big.
Rym: It's not as big as a real x-wing.
Scott: No, but it You mean you mean I guess Wow This thing is a real x-wing.
Scott: but so how big?
Scott: There's no such thing as a real x-wing.
Scott: then how big is one?
Rym: You know how big one is long ago and far away.
Scott: No, but think about this.
Scott: right Star Wars universe.
Scott: Everything is a long time ago in a galaxy far far away, right for all we know.
Rym: They're all midgets.
Scott: for all we know everything.
Scott: there is half size of what it is here or twice size.
Scott: They're all Giants.
Rym: You know why?
Rym: we know that's not true.
Rym: the same reason why Gulliver's giant couldn't be the surface area thing.
Rym: There are inherent qualities to size and very large things act differently from very small things.
Rym: Yeah, that's why ants can lift a hundred times their weight.
Rym: But if an ant was the size of a human not only could it not lift as a hundred times its weight But it would be crushed by its own body in gravity Gravity the great Gravity because you pull based on not.
Rym: you pull based on mass, but you don't pull more if something's heavier.
Scott: Yes, okay you pull he pulls.
Rym: he's about that.
Rym: I shouldn't say that because heaviness has nothing to do.
Rym: yeah, you know what Great equalizer.
Scott: It doesn't discriminate.
Scott: Okay Right regardless.
Scott: some dude made a model rocket of an x-wing and well What do you think would happen if someone actually tried to launch that?
Rym: it would explode.
Scott: well here you go.
Scott: video For your eyes free viewing on internet all over the internet the guy who did the y-wing.
Scott: I think he did that in the past because you don't get to see there might be a video elsewhere on the internet of the Y-wing.
Rym: he's not gonna fly.
Scott: I think the y-wing is more successful actually.
Rym: well He probably just put two really big rockets in it.
Scott: I think that's what he did.
Scott: I'm not sure, but but yeah, so check this out.
Scott: if you like Star Wars or rockets or explosions right or fire.
Rym: But Scott's kind of sick as you we might have noted.
Rym: so we didn't want to do one of our like a shows.
Rym: We didn't want to talk about something that requires research or anything where we have a lot of loud and violent opinions like biases.
Rym: We could have gone on a while But instead we're gonna do a real briefly because there's not a lot interesting to say about this topic and Scott was really excited about It.
Scott: so I think it's one of those things where it's a really boring topic at least to most people.
Scott: But I kind of know enough about it, and I think it's kind of interesting.
Rym: well It's also funny.
Rym: How quickly timing.
Rym: I remember when I was in high school.
Rym: if you bought a computer you bought a printer and Every computer had a printer attached to it like every single computer.
Scott: or yeah, or if you're at school There's a computer lab with a printer.
Rym: Yeah, but like the printer was seen as this Absolutely essential thing and everyone just always had.
Scott: well because back then before Internets was widespread the primary use of a computer besides playing games writing papers right typing something Oh and looking at the online encyclopedia and watching that same.
Scott: I'm talking about before those days You know I mean like you had a something with like a 486.
Scott: What could it do?
Scott: you could it was basically an infinitely better typewriter?
Scott: But the it was still a type.
Scott: You know you're still using it for the goal of getting your thing printed on paper or mostly handed into the teacher.
Rym: Honestly my primary goal using a computer back Then was to play scorched earth and stuff.
Scott: that was also my goal.
Rym: cracked by kill fit.
Scott: But printing was also necessary in fact essential.
Scott: Meanwhile nowadays not so much printing going on I mean a lot of work.
Rym: But that's just because paperless office is one of the biggest lies of this decade.
Scott: I don't know I barely print.
Scott: it work.
Scott: There's a lot of PDF mailing going on.
Rym: you work for a much cooler company.
Scott: I have to print sometimes But it's usually what I want to have like I print out the seating chart of the office and like pin it up on my Desk wall thingy you know, but they mail it to me as a PDF.
Scott: They don't.
Rym: well my company never saw fit to give me a laptop or a PDA or anything even though that sort of thing would Probably save them hundreds of thousands of dollars in wasted time.
Scott: awesome.
Rym: So I have to print out like work orders and crap to carry around with you.
Scott: Cuz you're shown to people.
Scott: yeah, I don't move around.
Scott: I sit at one desk.
Rym: Yeah, I move around which is good because when I'm bored.
Rym: I could just get the hell out of my office.
Rym: Yeah, and I just make up excuse like yeah, I'm going to.
Scott: well I don't even need an excuse.
Scott: if I want to leave the office and say I'm going to Best Buy.
Scott: I'm going to Staples I'm going to.
Scott: you know I'm in the city at some time.
Scott: people need to go places.
Scott: I'm going to get a haircut.
Scott: I'm going to whatever.
Rym: I think the turning point for me was RIT because I went to RIT and I brought a printer.
Scott: I also brought a printer an HP deskjet 820 CSE.
Scott: I brought my 810 C.
Rym: Yeah, and we both had a printer.
Rym: each one of us had a printer.
Scott: I bought that printer for 150 dollars when I was like 18 in high school and Didn't use our printers so much.
Rym: I printed out a color goat C and taped it to Scott's orange juice because he'd Never seen it before and he'd avoided it all that time.
Rym: I figured that was the only way to get him was to pull the the one-two punch And I kept.
Scott: I just reminded me that my orange juice is they still don't make.
Rym: oh That's a story.
Scott: I think I said been said on the podcast.
Rym: Yeah, but other than that I never.
Rym: Wow goat C was one of the things I printed.
Scott: That's why I'm getting all sick.
Scott: It's because it's been enough time I don't have that orange juice that would cure all my disease news.
Rym: But the thing I didn't use the printer anymore because all my professors wanted things turned in electronically except my one really dumb liberal arts.
Scott: Well, my computer teachers want to turn electronically.
Scott: some liberal arts teachers wanted stuff printed out But I didn't have to do that.
Scott: many papers, you know that the dreaded mythical like super long paper I never had to do that ever the longest paper I ever had to write in my entire life was like 12 pages long.
Scott: I think the longest one I had to write was like 10 pages.
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Rym: granted I'd use APA.
Scott: It's really easy and I double spaced come on.
Rym: But yeah, even if I needed to print it was a college campus I always went to the computer lab and printed it over there.
Rym: Then I went over to the surly lab assistant It was always surly and said could I have my print out and he'd go And get up and give it to me.
Scott: and then yeah, but yeah I occasionally printed from my desk yet, but it would seem to be most of the time It just sat there printed from it sort of in bursts.
Scott: Yeah I didn't.
Scott: I could have lived without it.
Rym: desk jets if you don't because they were designed for an era Especially because we had two old desk jets where they were used a lot.
Rym: if you don't use a desk yet It stops working pretty quickly.
Scott: Well, let's let's talk about different kinds of printers right originally?
Scott: Well, I guess originally there were all kinds of different kinds, you know There's kinds that like use the for plotting.
Scott: they like grab pens with robotic arms and drag them around the paper.
Scott: Those do exist.
Scott: They're good for like AutoCAD stuff.
Rym: We had a couple at RIT for the IT stuff that we use.
Rym: they were really awesome.
Scott: They just call them plotters.
Scott: I think yes.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, there's.
Scott: there's all kinds but the main kinds.
Scott: originally there was the dot matrix printer Which was you know people out there the ones that go The ones with the paper that has the holes in the side and then you tear the holes off and you play with the hole.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of times the paper was like alternating green and white or green and yellow.
Scott: Paper would stick together sometimes and cause a big jam and the paper came in one continuous sheet.
Scott: yeah, it'd just be one big sheet of paper either by special paper to go in the printer so that the roller could roll the paper out.
Rym: and Basically, they were called dot matrix because they were just a matrix of dots.
Scott: Yep there was a there's a little ribbon of ink and there was a matrix of dots and it would move the ribbon of ink back and Forth and the dots would either hit or not hit and anything you print it out would basically either be it's like pixel or no.
Scott: That's why you know you've seen all those printouts like they used to have that banner printing program for the Apple.
Scott: to that every school would use too much and You would make every kind of banner the school needed.
Scott: they'd print out this big long banner from the Apple - and some people had the color dot matrix Apple - printer which the ribbon had like You know four different colors of ink on there and it would go through like four times.
Scott: and whoo It was all fancy.
Rym: those printers are shitty and people say oh they still have their uses They don't have any use anymore forget it They all the uses they have exists solely because a lot of companies do things in really archaic ways.
Rym: But I digress.
Scott: yeah, there's like a lot of people have a very old point of sale system or something that only works with incredibly old equipment.
Rym: they always claim but what if I need to fill out an Existing form with carbon paper on it to which I say you shouldn't be using carbon paper.
Scott: Yes, that is correct Okay, so the next kind of printer that anyone cared about was the desk jet bubble jet Whatever and this is probably what you're used to.
Scott: it's got a cartridge and it moves back and forth.
Rym: It just sprays ink on a piece of paper.
Scott: That's all it does.
Scott: It just goes.
Scott: It just sprays ink on the paper.
Scott: It's really not interesting.
Scott: It's got.
Scott: maybe you've got one with that's got color.
Scott: So it has cyan yellow magenta and black ink.
Scott: so we can make any color at once by spraying little dots You know.
Scott: and it mixes different dots together to make different colors.
Scott: You know, you get some cyan and some yellow together and make some I guess green bluish whatever, you know I don't know the colors on what do I know?
Rym: Yeah, they weren't the best printers.
Rym: now the cartridges were expensive.
Scott: people still use them because I guess they're.
Scott: they're good.
Scott: I guess for home.
Rym: use easy Nowadays because we don't print enough.
Rym: I guess there's there's no good solution for printing in the home.
Rym: Every solution sucks.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean the desk jet is a good technology for printing in the home.
Scott: The problem is if you don't print off and the cartridge can dry up and the cartridges are overpriced because they have a racket going On but the printers themselves.
Scott: the technology is incredibly cheap.
Scott: It's incredibly reliable.
Scott: You know, it's very.
Scott: it doesn't print very quickly But that doesn't matter because you know, you're printing not so often.
Scott: where you're printing like a birthday card or your photos You know, you don't really need like honestly The only thing I print at home anymore and it's always the same things as us hotel reservations Confirmations map quests convention reservation confirmation.
Scott: Yeah, and that's receipts the things I buy online and Playing games.
Scott: Yeah Sometimes I actually print out rules to games like, you know board games like liars die.
Scott: I print out the an entire game.
Scott: liars die.
Scott: They're like games you can print.
Scott: also Paper crafts print out paper.
Rym: when was the last time you did a paper craft?
Scott: when I was at that job?
Scott: I quit.
Scott: I made that dragon where you turn it.
Rym: I also made that but I printed it out in color on a wax printer.
Scott: I did I printed out in a laser color printer at work and I stuck it in my office.
Rym: and Every day people walk by and then they just go like woo And then I took it home because I got sick of that.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, but yeah, so this is a laser printer and Lasers.
Scott: and see the thing about the laser printer is a laser printer is actually kind of expensive.
Scott: I mean, it's like what few thousand dollars for a color laser printer.
Scott: That's like high quality.
Scott: I guess there's some.
Rym: they're cheaper now see black and white laser printers are dirt cheap.
Scott: Yeah, you can get one for like a hundred bucks and I recommend that but we'll get to it.
Scott: Yep, but you know the the way a laser printer works.
Scott: I'm actually pretty proud that I know this and I think it's really cool.
Scott: I'm not gonna go into stupid detail because someone who knows better than me and more details is gonna rat me out.
Scott: But the basic fundamental way a laser printer works is this you have this plastic area, right?
Rym: And there's a guy standing there.
Rym: he says I'm charging my laser.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: He says I'm a charge in my laser and you shoot this laser.
Scott: It's actual.
Scott: there's a reason they call laser printer.
Scott: This laser shoots this piece of plastic and wherever it's a special plastic and a special laser and wherever the laser shoots the plastic the plastic gets Charged.
Scott: and then there's the toner opens up and the toner gets stuck to the plastic Wherever the plastic got shot with the laser.
Scott: So you shoot the plastic with the laser.
Scott: the toner touches the plastic where it got shot But it doesn't touch the plastic where it didn't get shot.
Scott: And the result is what you want to print is now in toner on the plastic.
Scott: Then it heats up and it touches the paper to the plastic or rolls the paper across the plastic.
Scott: Usually it's a roll and it does it, you know one not, you know one part at a time.
Scott: It doesn't do the whole sheet at once and it rolls the paper across the plastic while it's hot and the toner melts and sticks to the paper instead of the plastic.
Scott: and you got your print.
Rym: now two interesting things.
Rym: one the toner is.
Rym: It actually looks and acts like liquid but it's actually a very very very fine solid.
Scott: It's pretty scary.
Scott: If anyone ever if you ever find like a big big like color laser printer like a big copier fax scanner at an office They'll have separate toners cartridges for each individual you know for black, cyan, magenta, yellow and They're usually clear and you could take them out and you move them back and forth and it looks like yellow Liquid or inker is inside of it.
Scott: when you look closer It's just a million really really really tiny balls So tiny that it looks like liquid if you don't get your eye really close to it too.
Rym: If you ever spill toners somewhere somehow which it happens every now and then you should avoid it.
Rym: It's not like it'll kill you but it is kind of toxic.
Scott: it does it sucks.
Scott: Basically, it's not like mercury or But it is sucks.
Rym: It's actually easy to clean up.
Rym: But here's a little hint for all of you out there Don't get it hot.
Rym: Yeah, if you ever have to wash toner off set the washing machine on cold.
Rym: Otherwise, you're going to tone everything black.
Scott: Yep okay, so That's how laser printer works.
Scott: and if it's a color laser printer it just does the same thing with all the other colors instead of just black.
Scott: and Laser printer, you know, it's sort of this weird thing.
Scott: where for a home user for a business Obviously because for in terms of no amount of money per page you print a laser printer is unbeatable.
Scott: It's absolutely unbeatable.
Scott: It costs you like a few cents to print out one page a laser printer, but for a home user it's sort of rough because the And a cost of the printer plus the cost of a single toner cartridge is pretty high Compared to say a desk jet which you can buy a desk jet for like 20 bucks and a cartridge for like 30 bucks.
Scott: So buy another desk jet right but the laser printer over time Will save you money compared to the desk jet.
Rym: now a lot of people say but I want to prints in my color.
Rym: And the answer is think about what you print and how often you really print.
Rym: The truth is most of the printing that the average person will do is gonna be in black and white with obvious exceptions for you Know artists or people with home Businesses who need to print in kind of
Scott: thing is there are a lot of people who do like like to print their photos in The digital can now.
Rym: in that case your best bet is to have a photo printer.
Scott: That's what I was just gonna say.
Scott: They make photo printers that print out photos on photo paper.
Scott: You can get one.
Scott: They're very cheap.
Rym: They're really nice really cheap.
Rym: They'll do well, they're not super cheap But they'll do what you want if you're not better than any other.
Rym: you are doing that a lot.
Scott: if you find yourself printing photos from your digital camera a lot and you want quality get a photo printer or Just do that thing.
Scott: where you go and there's like those Kodak kiosks and you put your memory card in them and they print photos Out do that thing because that thing's not so bad and they're everywhere.
Scott: They're in grocery stores and targets and CVS.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: I'll be honest There's.
Rym: I feel like there's almost no use for the average person to have a desk jet anymore And I feel like it's mostly because the cartridges are ripoff.
Scott: now some people they say, ah, but I refill the cartridge I do this I do that.
Scott: Well, here's the thing free filling a cartridge.
Scott: I guess there are you know for the most part it works.
Scott: There are places you can go to have them do it for you to avoid the trouble, you know and such.
Scott: but They try to screw you.
Scott: they have like DRM and stuff.
Scott: It's sort of like those coffee pods where you can't make your own, you know And it's basically sure you can save a lot of money if you do that if you go through the hassle But it's not worth it and it just sucks.
Rym: Well, I think it's more that laser printers are generally just better in every way and it's kind of the high initial investment long-term returns as opposed to short and it's small initial investment Continual investment.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: It's.
Scott: the only other thing you got to think about with your printer is how it connects to your computer.
Rym: The answer nowadays is just USB.
Scott: I know back in the day.
Scott: You said those big parallel cables.
Scott: now It's USB, but some people they like to share the printer.
Scott: You know, they want.
Scott: they want the every, you know, if you got a lot of computers in your house Why should you buy a printer for each computer?
Scott: You can buy one printer for the whole house.
Rym: now obviously honestly for most people They use Windows.
Rym: It's super easy.
Rym: You just click on the right click on the printer and say share and then everyone else can print To it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: There's two ways to do it.
Scott: One way is what Rym just said.
Scott: you plug the printer into just one computer and that computer.
Scott: you tell that computer to share the And every other computer.
Scott: you say find the printer that's shared and use it and it works.
Scott: It's pretty simple.
Rym: now another thing you can do and this is actually a good idea Especially for a family or if you don't want to bother you can buy a little box with a USB hole.
Rym: Oh You plug the printer into that and some of these boxes are wireless Like you just plug them into power then and that's it.
Rym: and some of them.
Rym: You'd like to have an Ethernet hole, but they basically serve your printer out as though it were a network printer.
Rym: Yep, so you just print to it.
Scott: it's basically a little tiny print server in a little tiny box and it's pretty cheap.
Scott: and you connect your printer to it and now your printer is shared and Tada, you don't have to plug your printer into a computer to have it shared amongst all the computers in the network.
Scott: The third thing you can do is get a printer that actually has a network card in it.
Rym: Those tend to be expensive.
Scott: Yeah, they actually.
Scott: they make printers now that have Wi-Fi in them.
Rym: now that I think is a good idea.
Scott: It is it's still kind of expensive compared to any other sort of printer But it could be really useful for you.
Scott: I mean you're gonna spend the money on the print server.
Scott: or if you're gonna spend the money and having a printer with a print Server in it.
Scott: Why not get the printer obviously server in it?
Rym: If you have money to burn get the print server.
Rym: But if you just need a printer and you need other people to print to it, just use the windows sharing.
Rym: it works Fine.
Rym: don't even bother with security.
Scott: It really comes down to how much you're willing to spend how much how smart you are and how good you are at setting this Sort of thing up.
Scott: what kind of network you have going on and the physical surroundings, you know Where are you going to put the printer?
Scott: You know what's near that?
Scott: is it close enough to a network connection or is it?
Scott: is it within Wi-Fi range is it?
Scott: Don't put your printer on Carpet like.
Rym: don't do like we do.
Rym: don't put it on the floor like we do if you smoke.
Rym: don't keep it anywhere near Where you smoke?
Rym: Yeah, don't put your computers anywhere near where you smoke either.
Scott: No your computers and your printer will fill it with dust and it kind of ruins it over time No matter what kind of printer it is.
Scott: It doesn't matter You don't want to put your printer anywhere near any sort of dusty crap.
Scott: You want to keep it clean.
Scott: you also printers use a lot of power.
Rym: I mean in my thinking of that no normal printers don't late like desk jets don't.
Scott: no not so much for these laser Printers.
Rym: do not let them share circuits with any delicate electronics And I'll give you our house if I start printing the printers downstairs.
Rym: if I print to that printer The lights in my room dim a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, I used to have in my room.
Scott: I think there's like two or three circuits in my room, right?
Scott: I would have had it arranged in a certain way where the printer was on the same thing as like the air conditioner and some Lamps and when I would print like it would the UPS is like Watch out.
Scott: He's printing.
Scott: Oh, no, but now I rearranged the room and I moved the printer downstairs.
Scott: That doesn't happen.
Rym: I had to convince some people at my company once because they these people wanted like three gigantic laser printers.
Scott: Oh, they are separate circuits.
Rym: These things are like as big as like in like freezers three separate circuits and They want to put them in this room.
Rym: and I'm like, well, there's no network drops.
Rym: And then I look and I see one outlet in the room.
Rym: Yeah, I look at that outlet.
Rym: So I find the schematics and that outlet is shared with several other outlets in other rooms And I win.
Rym: they were like, so what are we good to go?
Rym: and I was like hell's no You can't plug even one of these in a car electrician.
Rym: They're like why I was like.
Scott: You should say get it go get a power strip for five bucks from staples and try it.
Rym: I didn't want him to burn the building down.
Scott: I wouldn't have burned the building down It would just flick the circuit breaker.
Rym: most thing is I read the book that came with these printers X I actually read it apparently no one else.
Rym: What did it say?
Scott: dedicated lines said?
Rym: Dedicated 20 amp circuit per.
Scott: ah, that's nice.
Scott: You know what though?
Scott: That's pretty good printer.
Rym: You know what it's fucking awesome for.
Rym: Oh, they also wanted to put all these printers in an unventilated room Which is bad for a lot of reason.
Scott: remember what I said about needing to heat up the toner.
Rym: Yeah, not a printer.
Scott: Not only is a printer basically a computer that's doing all.
Scott: you know modern ones Anyway, they're computing all the time and doing stuff.
Scott: They're also have motors in them and not only do they have motors But they also are purposefully making heat in order to melt toner.
Scott: So as a lot of heat coming out of that It's not enough to hurt.
Rym: like a printer gives off a small amount of toxic gas when your laser printer when you print.
Rym: That's just how it works, but it's not gonna hurt you.
Rym: It's a really small amount.
Rym: it dissipates in the air.
Scott: It smells good.
Rym: like computers give off toxic gas technically they make ozone a lot of the time just in really small quantities.
Rym: It's not gonna hurt you.
Scott: not like those ionic breeze Airfares that will hurt you because they make too much ozone.
Rym: well the old ones.
Scott: apparently they fix that well They still they were hurting old people and they still things suck.
Scott: You're better.
Scott: I'm just getting a fan.
Scott: Yeah, or uh what the other kind of air filter the hepa hepa whatever.
Scott: I had one of those kind.
Scott: It's actually a filter and not some ionic shit.
Rym: Yeah, but They well if you want to put a bunch of printers in a airtight room with no ventilation Not good that room with hot toxic gas in a hurry.
Rym: It sure will all right.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: We said we wanted to go short.
Rym: We didn't so much, but that's fine.
Rym: I'm kind of This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.