Scott: It's Tuesday January 16th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we tell you all about blockus.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Some people around the world live in a place where video games are easy to come by.
Scott: you know There's like an ebay right next door to their house.
Scott: Or there are five different stores selling video games within spitting distance.
Scott: some people live in parts of the country Where you're lucky if you can find a video game store at all.
Scott: I mean, I remember then here in Wildwood at the time that Advance Wars DS came out God, we had to drive how far to go to the only EB within range.
Rym: Yep I remember we then bought pretty much every copy of the game that guy had.
Scott: Yeah I mean, it wasn't only the only EB within range.
Scott: It was the only video game selling store.
Scott: It's kind of crazy.
Rym: Well, there was that target or whatever.
Rym: Kmart Yeah, whatever it was, but they don't really have launch games on launch day.
Scott: No, they don't.
Scott: so, you know when I this week there are two very important video games coming out.
Scott: There is Wario where we is coming out in the well in the u.s.
Scott: Some of these games are already out elsewhere Bastards Wario where we is coming out this week.
Scott: You can consider that Rym's most anticipated game of 2007 and Scott's most anticipated game of 2007 Phoenix Wright to justice for all is coming out.
Rym: It's a good time to be alive and it's a good time to have a we in a DS Yep, so, you know, it takes us how long to go down to the GameStop.
Scott: I mean, there's a bunch of video game stores here, but they're not right next to our house.
Scott: You have to drive at least 10 15 minutes to get to one.
Rym: Whoa, Lord at 10 minutes Whatever will I do?
Scott: you know it.
Scott: the other thing is you're not only just to drive 10 15 minutes to get to one but it's sort of a Pain in the ass.
Scott: and you know doing the show and doing stuff on the weekends I'd have a lot of time to go down there just to do buy a video game.
Rym: It's not just that.
Rym: in general I more and more really dislike going to Normal stores to buy normal things.
Rym: If only there are a way I could without leaving the comfort of my desk ask other people to get these things for me exchange For money and deliver them to my door.
Scott: Oh Well, you know I used to when I worked in the city go to the GameStop.
Scott: that was right near the office as one Would.
Scott: yes, but now I kind of gave up on that.
Scott: for the first time ever I bought some video games on Amazon.
Rym: See this all started this whole saga of us not needing to go to game stores anymore Way back when I was buying stuff on Amazon and I thought well, I'm buying stuff.
Rym: Anyway, I might as well buy as much stuff as I can to get the free shipping whatever.
Rym: and I don't lark.
Rym: I decided to type in the name of some DS games and They were selling them pretty cheap in many cases far less than I would have paid for him in a game store Especially games that weren't the newest games anymore.
Rym: and even the newest games are usually like five bucks off.
Scott: No, the newest games are you know, at least Wario and Phoenix Wright were like a few cents off.
Rym: Yeah, but portrait of ruin was six bucks off.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah depends on the game.
Scott: It's kind of random Yeah.
Scott: But the best thing is if you pre-order and the price goes down between the time of your pre-order and the time they ship it To you then you get the lower price.
Rym: But the thing is the price is never more than you would pay in a GameStop or an EB.
Rym: Nope, so in this day and age I think we've come to the conclusion that at least for new games as opposed to used games There is no reason to get games from anywhere other than Amazon.
Scott: Yeah, I mean as long as you get the free shipping and as long as you don't have a desperate need to have the game Right now, I mean, I'm not gonna get these games.
Scott: these games come out tomorrow.
Scott: in the next day I'm not gonna get them, you know, I'll be lucky if I get them on Friday, you know I'll probably expect to get them on Monday Maybe even later than that.
Scott: I think the expected delivery date that it says on Amazon is Wednesday.
Scott: So, you know the next Wednesday not not two days from now or I guess tomorrow or whenever you're listening They're not gonna be here real soon.
Scott: No, they're not.
Scott: so, you know, I'm willing to suffer that because right now I've got more entertainment than I have time to consume.
Scott: so getting a video game like Wario or Phoenix, right?
Scott: Which doesn't sort of have a time need on it a week later.
Scott: Not a big deal.
Scott: I'm willing to suffer in order to not have to leave my house and waste my time.
Scott: So we'll see how this works.
Scott: and Yeah, it could be cool.
Scott: It could suck.
Scott: We'll let you know.
Rym: So in actual gaming news This game is kind of a blind side to me for a number of reasons because you see every year for the last many years I've attended ubercon Last year, I decided to bring other people along with me and every year It seems like more and more people come because ubercon is probably one of the best gaming conventions anywhere near us.
Rym: Well, the thing about ubercon is that they always had two a year.
Rym: There was one in the fall just before winter and run in the spring just after winter.
Rym: So you kind of begin the gaming season the gaming season being the time you can't go outside.
Rym: Yeah with the gaming con and then at the end of gaming season You have one final fling before you go back out into that horrible dread Sun.
Scott: I think it's also kind of necessary for gaming cons because when you're at a gaming con I'm like other cons.
Scott: the activities the individual activities at gaming cons tend to take many many hours.
Rym: Yes So
Scott: at one individual gaming con Even though there are the same number of hours in say ubercon as there are in Otakon You don't get as you don't feel like you did as much because you only played in like one RPG and you played ten board games and that was it
Rym: Yep,
Scott: and you feel kind of like eh and you paid a lot of money for it.
Scott: So having two gaming cons, you know is kind of a bonus.
Rym: Yeah, you get to spend twice as much money.
Rym: Yeah But I mean really all of you out there who go to gaming cons.
Rym: You know gaming cons are very different from anime cons.
Rym: I like both equally.
Scott: Mm-hmm Just we should go.
Scott: we should pick a new gaming gun.
Rym: I think we should.
Rym: well we're gonna have to because you see ubercon for various reasons has been forced to Cancel this year's spring ubercon due to I think scheduling concerns.
Rym: It hasn't been made a hundred percent clear as to exactly why but I imagine they couldn't get the dates.
Scott: Yeah, well those guys were never the most super organized con.
Rym: see that is the one thing about gaming cons as opposed to anime cons.
Rym: If an anime con isn't run Absolutely wonderfully by the staff.
Rym: It will fall apart in about seven minutes.
Rym: Yep gamers While they I'm not gonna say gamers are better than anime fans or vice-versa But gamers tend to really want to play their games and gamers tend to self-organize.
Scott: If you just have a gaming con and all you do is get a bunch of gamers in a big room with enough tables They'll play games on their own and you don't have to do so much.
Rym: Yeah, in fact RIT was a good example of that.
Rym: there was the anime club which had a large board of very dedicated directors who did Constant effort to make the club better and get people to come and make it an awesome time.
Rym: and any time they made a mistake Club didn't work out at all.
Rym: People just like what's going on and leave.
Rym: the gaming club was run by a bunch of incompetence.
Rym: to put it lightly there were times when I was never really sure if it was actually a club anymore, but it didn't matter because they provided a room and 100 to 200 people would show up every Tuesday and play games all night.
Scott: Yeah, I think it really has to do with the nature of the individual hobbies.
Scott: I mean anime is so passive compared to gaming.
Scott: people just sit there.
Scott: So if they are coming to some sort of club Someone has to do something because if not everyone else will just sit there waiting for something to happen.
Scott: Yep Or as with gaming people are coming to something to do something and they're in.
Scott: they got it on their mind.
Scott: I'm gonna play this game and whether anything happens or not if there are other human beings they're willing to join in they will.
Scott: you know if uber con canceled and Ten guys still showed up anyway They would get rooms in the hotel and play board games on those tables in the hotel rooms or set up a little campaign And play the whole weekend.
Rym: Well because of this uber con looks like they're going to expand because ever con as far as I can tell has been very successful.
Rym: Yeah, they definitely need a little bigger main room and well They're not expanding in New Jersey You see since they can't have their normal spring uber con this year.
Rym: Instead they have announced uber con Great Lakes one, which is going to be held in Livonia, Michigan March 30th through April 1st 2007.
Scott: I'm guessing that's just more convenient for some of the people running uber con who probably aren't living out there.
Rym: Well, I think this is going to be very interesting.
Rym: I mean one.
Rym: the first convention I ever went to period gaming con whatever was a gaming con called Michigan in Detroit.
Rym: It was somewhere.
Rym: I don't actually remember where it was.
Rym: I was too young to even know where my dad drove me other than it was about 45 minutes away.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: but I can tell you that in Michigan and in the Midwest in general there is a lot of gaming and there are a lot of little gaming cons and I think that an Organized this is like the Roman army marching into Gaul and setting up a little encampment.
Rym: I think uber con Great Lakes is gonna do really well.
Rym: Livonia is easy to get to thank.
Scott: penguin con is out there.
Rym: Yeah in Novi yep, but Livonia is easy to get to from pretty much anywhere in the Midwest.
Rym: In fact, if we lived in Rochester, I would very much be inclined to go to this uber con.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I think it's just too far away for us.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not driving nine hours.
Scott: There's enough gaming cons around here that I think we can replace spring uber con with a different gaming con.
Scott: Maybe pick up two gaming cons.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, of course, they're still in the planning stages.
Rym: They're looking for guests They're looking for all sorts of stuff.
Rym: So to all our listeners in the Midwest go to the uber con website uber con calm and check this out.
Rym: Uber con is a great con and I almost guarantee you won't be disappointed if you like gaming.
Scott: if you don't like gaming Don't go don't like gaming.
Rym: Why are you listening to Tuesday GeekNights?
Scott: It could be just video game fans.
Scott: uber con is very light on the video games.
Scott: They got them but not much.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: They always have the guitar heroes in the DDR.
Scott: Yep, and they have a little and party.
Scott: Yeah all right, I don't have a gaming news because I already talked about how I'm buying Wario and Phoenix, right I'm gonna talk about a news that I should have talked about yesterday, but I didn't know it until today.
Scott: So tough shit.
Scott: One of the best books ever is diamond age by Neal Stephenson.
Scott: It's a really good book.
Scott: It's real good.
Scott: You should read it.
Scott: If you haven't read it go read it.
Rym: the gods conspired to force Scott to read it.
Scott: Yeah, it was real good too.
Rym: And finally he basically told all those.
Rym: All right, you jackasses I'm finally gonna read this book so you'll shut up.
Rym: and then he said oh, that was a good book.
Scott: Yeah Well, I've always thought that it should be made into like a really good movie or like a 26-episode show or something like that because it could be pulled off really well if done right the sci-fi channel is gonna try
Rym: If you'd said anyone else
Scott: They're gonna try to make a diamond age mini series with executive producers George Clooney Darren star and mark Burnett, whatever whatever.
Scott: All right, we'll see Sci-fi channel is really six hour mini series.
Scott: if I'll get it pretty much I think my plan on this is I'll get like the first episode on bit Torrance or something And if it's good, I'll buy like the DVD set or Netflix it or something like that.
Scott: Cuz they always make DVD sets of these things.
Scott: Yeah, you know you don't have to watch this shit on TV.
Rym: I mean nowadays shows like this practically especially if it's six hours.
Scott: I mean if it's a six hour mini series Why would I watch it on?
Scott: TV with all those commercials making it take eight hours of my time See nine hours of my 50/50 on it.
Rym: because on one hand it seems like there's some talent involved And I think the people who run the sci-fi channel know that if they screw this up, they'll generally be hated forever.
Rym: But at the same time the side I turned up Earthsea and they they're not.
Rym: Well, the sci-fi channel is not known for its high quality original content.
Rym: No, not really other than Stargate SG-1, which I think is awesome.
Rym: However, I want to clarify that by saying that it is not good.
Rym: It is just awesome.
Scott: I'm just generally not a fan of most Sci-fi television.
Rym: Yeah says the man who doesn't like Firefly or Battlestar Galactica.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All right So we'll see if this is any good.
Scott: cuz I really like diamond age.
Scott: So I want to lie or I?
Scott: well it's not so much that I want to like it's I want there to be a video of diamond age that I like and We'll see if this is it or not.
Scott: I give it a 60% chance of not being painful to watch Things of the day.
Rym: now, I know yesterday last night.
Rym: I said that I had two awesome Japanese video things of the day.
Rym: well I'm afraid I'm gonna have to postpone the Super double Trump awesome one till tomorrow since I think tomorrow's demographic would enjoy it more so than tonight's demographic.
Scott: Oh, so what are you gonna give us?
Rym: Well instead I'm gonna give us something that will give you something since we've both seen it That while it was an awesome thing of the day, it kind of slipped through the cracks for various reasons.
Rym: there's this video that some hick somewhere filmed of this snake hanging out and the snake obviously was up to no good because there's this little rabbit and The little rabbit is none too happy with this snake.
Scott: Well, if I was a rabbit I would be happy with the snake either because the snake could probably you know Bite me and all sorts other nastiness.
Rym: so the rabbit runs up in front of the snake and the snake goes to bite it and the Blings itself in a backflip through the air away from the snake and then charges it.
Scott: That's pretty fast to move to avoid a snake bite, you know snakes are like This video got to be.
Scott: you got to be quick to avoid that shit.
Rym: This is pretty impressive.
Rym: and this goes on for a while and the snake can't get a hold of this rabbit.
Rym: The rabbit just bounding around and charging.
Rym: finally the rabbit starts biting the snake and attacking the snake.
Scott: Yeah, he goes around to the end of the snake that doesn't have the biting poison on it and he starts Attacking the back of the snake.
Rym: now at this point the snake says fuck this and starts trying to get away.
Rym: But the rabbits not done.
Rym: The rabbit chases the steak.
Rym: just watch the video and see what happens.
Rym: This is great.
Scott: The best part of this video is the hick is, you know, okay They're not the smartest people but you could tell this hick is a fun guy.
Rym: Yeah, I would hang out with this guy.
Scott: Yeah, it'd be fun.
Scott: Just hang around it for a little while.
Rym: He's reacting to this in pretty much the same way.
Rym: weird react to it just in a different accent.
Scott: Yeah Cool guy.
Scott: All right my thing today.
Scott: Well You may or may not know about sodium now.
Scott: a lot of times people say sodium.
Scott: They mean salt.
Rym: No, we don't mean that we don't mean that.
Scott: so we mean sodium.
Scott: the element sodium is a metal You can get.
Scott: it is just sodium na on the periodic table.
Scott: Now the thing about sodium is that due to its chemical properties it?
Scott: Explodes.
Scott: pretty much everything on the left-hand column of the periodic table of elements Explodes.
Scott: the reason for that and I'm not going to go into all the details of the chemistry Is that the outermost ring of electrons and all of those elements in their default states has one electron?
Scott: Therefore that one electron all in its own in the outermost ring is real easy to take away.
Scott: In fact, it wants to get away.
Scott: So if you put anything near some sodium or some cesium or whatever else mean it friends him.
Scott: Yeah, that can take an electron such as water.
Scott: There are lots of chemicals that can take an electron real easily.
Rym: Yeah water, however, really really likes to take electron.
Scott: Yeah water works.
Scott: Some things work better some things work worse But water likes to take an electron.
Scott: so you put some water near some sodium.
Scott: The electron flies off the sodium into the water.
Scott: in that process energy is released in great quantity with great rapidness and that makes Explosions.
Scott: now we've seen a lot of videos of various experiments of this kind taking Yeah, we saw those guys the British guys on that show with the bathtub and they put cesium in the bathtub and ran away.
Rym: Yeah, we've had at least one or more things of the day involving this exact item.
Scott: Yep Well, this one is incredibly interesting.
Scott: basically in 1947 after the war They had a bunch of sodium left over and they couldn't get anyone to take it because no one would ship it because it would explode.
Scott: So they had big barrels full of sodium.
Scott: They know what to do it and there was some water.
Scott: It was an alkaline lake.
Scott: So Basically on the eastern side of Washington State closer to Montana and such or I guess Idaho is in the way, right?
Scott: It must be I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, it's Idaho and then month.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, it's a Washington, Idaho, Monta.
Scott: Anyway way out in eastern Washington State, you know, which is on the west side of the country There was a lake that was alkaline.
Scott: There were no fish in the lake.
Scott: The lake didn't have anything living in it It was just bad water.
Scott: so they dropped the sodium into it a barrel at a time and it exploded and someone decided to take a video of it with a 1947 film camera.
Rym: basically, he was a primitive youtuber.
Scott: Yep, and Now his video is on Google video instead of YouTube.
Scott: it's fairly impressive.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I've seen sodium explode.
Scott: I mean at summer camp, you know, we threw a chunk of it into the lake, you know We would do all kinds of stuff with it.
Scott: This is the biggest sodium explosion ever seen.
Rym: So we'd said last week that we were going to review battle lore But I think we're going to wait another week just so I can play the game a few more times before I decide I really Don't like the game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, there are a lot of features of the game We haven't played with.
Scott: we didn't play with the goblins or the dwarves or the monsters or the war council?
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: I have a pretty good idea of what kinds of effects those will have on the game.
Scott: Yeah, I have a pretty good idea as well.
Scott: I already played with the goblins actually by Rym didn't.
Rym: so yeah Yeah, so we'll wait on that and we decided instead we'd do a nice little quick game.
Rym: You see over our New Year's party our good friends James and Lisa came up from Texas to spend time with us and with him James brought a blockus.
Rym: the two-player variant of blockus is travel blockus.
Rym: Effectively the two-player variant because you player normal blockus is terrible.
Rym: Basically, you can buy the four player and the two player.
Scott: Yeah The default version of blockus is a four player game and you could play with two players Which is kind of sucky or you could play with three players, which is really sucky and unplayable.
Scott: I don't even know why.
Scott: they offer it as an option and Travel blockus Actually offers a really good two-player experience.
Scott: So yeah, it's pretty cool.
Rym: So blockus, it is a game put out by a strata gems brain building games And they're really touting it as an award-winning educational awesome game.
Rym: I mean wasn't it up for a spiel this yar?
Scott: Yeah, it was a spiel.
Scott: discern nominee.
Scott: It's some year.
Rym: It won the doctor toy 100 best children's product of 2003.
Scott: You can never easy tell once you see this game why it wouldn't so many awards because it has such a broad appeal.
Rym: It won the Oppenheim toy portfolio best toy award.
Scott: Yeah, you know it really kind of fits both into that.
Scott: Toys R Us, you know market.
Rym: but Mensa decided to endorse it - I don't like Mensa so much either.
Scott: But also it fits into the.
Scott: you know, German board gamers are also like playing this thing.
Rym: Well, the thing is it's really hard to find a two-player game.
Rym: That's good and block is at least.
Rym: the two-player variant definitely fills the role.
Rym: now blockus is a very very Simple to play game, but that does not mean that it is a strategically or tactically simple game.
Scott: Nope, not at all.
Rym: Basically, you will have.
Rym: well, we'll talk about the two-player one because they're always effectively the same.
Rym: Yes, Scott and I there's a little bore with a bunch of squares on it.
Rym: in addition, you're given each player a whole bunch of Tetris like pieces.
Rym: they're called pentominoes Comprised of various squares and various numbers of squares.
Rym: you get a whole bunch of them and you both get the same kinds.
Scott: Yeah, so you've got you know The standard the t-shaped piece the plus piece the square piece the long L the short L the really short L. Yeah, you've got a whole bunch of pieces that are five squares large.
Scott: You've got a few pieces that are four squares large.
Scott: You got like a couple that are three squares like a one that's two and one that's one.
Rym: Yeah, you have only one one piece which actually comes into play rather significantly.
Rym: Yep Now the way the game goes is you take turns starting from your designated starting position Placing these in a way that they fit on the board.
Rym: and the rules of placement are very simple.
Rym: You cannot place a piece so that it goes over another piece.
Scott: Obviously it has to fit on the board in empty squares - outside of your first piece.
Rym: any additional pieces you play throughout the rest of the game must be Diagonally adjacent so the corners must touch.
Scott: Yeah, so if I put down the T I Guess I can't.
Scott: the corner of the piece that I put down has to touch a corner of the next piece.
Scott: I put yes diagonally speaking.
Rym: now the third most important rule and this is where the game is interesting Is that no piece of the same color may be orthogonally adjacent?
Scott: Yeah, so you can't have any of your pieces actually touching any of your other pieces So they'll all be all these diagonal holes all over the place.
Rym: Yeah So say you've got two one pieces and you want to somehow even though you can't have those you want to connect them to each other and you've got a nine grid of nine squares and the first piece is in the middle.
Rym: the second piece can only Go in the top right top left bottom right or bottom left.
Rym: Those are the only possible legal placements Yep.
Rym: And the object of the game is to get as many of your pieces on the board as you can Before you run out of legal moves.
Rym: your opponent is trying to do the same.
Rym: Scoring is very very simple.
Rym: you get negative one point You start at zero.
Rym: you get negative one point for every block.
Rym: that comprises every piece that you still have Unplaced at the end of the game.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So if I have a square piece and a Tetris T piece left, then I have a score of negative eight.
Rym: Yep, additionally, you can get a five point bonus If the last piece you play is your smallest one piece.
Scott: Now the reason they have that rule is because the one piece is very useful because it is only one square large It's pretty easy to play it at any point in the game.
Scott: However, there are many situations where you will be able to play the one piece in order to sort of break out.
Scott: and do You know add more pieces to the board.
Scott: So if you keep playing in a fashion in which you never need the one piece to break out Which means it's more difficult for you and that you can just save that Powerful one piece and not actually use it to break out but just put it at the end Then you get five points for doing that
Rym: but at the same time there might be an incentive to use the one piece early because There is also a 15 point bonus if you somehow place all of your pieces on the board.
Rym: Whoa?
Rym: So the maximum possible score is 20 and that is if you place all your pieces on the board and you place the one piece last.
Scott: Yeah, when you can't put any more pieces on the board possibly by any amount of rules That's the game.
Scott: just you're just done until and then other people keep putting pieces until no one can put any more pieces Legally and then games over now.
Rym: That's really it.
Rym: That's the entire game and you to go back and forth until you both can't place pieces anymore.
Rym: The three player game in the or the four player game are pretty much the same.
Rym: They just have rules to deal with that.
Rym: I mean the travel version of the game.
Rym: You just play two players straight up.
Rym: in the full version.
Rym: to play two players Each of you has to use two colors.
Rym: So you have two of every piece.
Rym: just so the board.
Scott: I just realized something.
Scott: There's no reason why we couldn't just cut out a section of the big board in the four player version Put those dots on it and then play it just like the travel.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: Yeah, not at all You know what?
Rym: All we should do is take a marker and mark what the small board would be.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah something like that All right, great.
Scott: Yeah, we don't even have to mark up the whole thing.
Scott: Just the corners.
Rym: Oh, yeah We'll just put little dots like a little go board or something.
Scott: Yeah, so but yeah, it's fun block.
Rym: This is incredibly fun unless you try to play it three player and then it's just annoying.
Scott: Yeah, three player because then you actually have to play the fourth player.
Scott: Just everyone takes turns being the fourth player and the fourth player doesn't count.
Scott: So it really kind of sucks.
Rym: Now, I guess we'll talk about the two-player game because it's a lot like all those games You'd play as a kid like pick up the sticks on a piece of paper or any of those two-player game.
Scott: I think it's a lot.
Scott: It's a lot more like Tron and Tetris kind of combined.
Rym: No, but see the way I look at it as the pick up sticks game is that the pick up sticks game is a game of stable and unstable states and Any time you move you can put the game into a stable or an unstable state.
Rym: and in a game You generally want to put it in a state that prevents the other player from putting it into a state that is desirable to them.
Rym: and in this game Like say I'm building toward the center of the board and Scott is building toward the center of the board.
Rym: now I have a choice to jump in aggressively or hold back a little bit.
Rym: now I might jump in aggressively and take control that part of the board or I might jump in aggressively but haphazardly and then Scott will be able to counter-attack and Place a piece that blocks all four corners or all three corners or whatever of the piece I place
Scott: like there's a u-shaped piece, right?
Scott: So let's say Rym puts down his his stick piece.
Scott: It's five just five squares right in a row.
Scott: if I put that you piece So that his stick piece goes right into the middle of my you piece like a cup like a stick going into a cup.
Scott: that kind of screws him because now I just cut off the corners of that stick piece and I've Basically prevented him from making any more moves in that direction at all.
Scott: It's that's why I feel it's kind of like Tron because you're sort of drawing this line around your territory But the line isn't really solid.
Scott: you've kind of got a you know.
Scott: Lock the territory in you know, and then you can use up your part of the board filling it in, you know.
Scott: And whoever has the biggest area can beat the other guy.
Rym: Yep There is definitely a general strategy of try to wall off an area for yourself And then at the same time try to get inside the other person's area to mess up their strategy.
Scott: yeah, what often happens is you'll wall off an area, but not completely but enough and You'll then what you'll have that area semi walled off You'll try to break into someone else's area and you might succeed.
Scott: but every time you're playing one piece of turn Everyone is playing one piece of turn.
Scott: so you often have to decide all right, I can put a piece here and move in on Rym's area or Alex sitting next to me, you know, he's gonna put a piece in my area.
Scott: So I can either block him and be defensive or go on the offense against Rym.
Scott: but I have to figure out which one of those two moves is Gonna end up with me having the most pieces on the board at the end.
Rym: This is definitely one of those minute to learn lifetime to master games.
Rym: I mean anyone will learn how to play this game in about two minutes.
Scott: little kids are playing this game.
Rym: Yeah, you could.
Rym: I could probably teach a monkey to at least play the game without breaking the rules.
Scott: It had to be one of the smarter monkeys like attempt, but you could yeah do easily The.
Rym: despite that the game does not bog down or become a foregone conclusion at all At least in all the experience.
Rym: we or many of the other people playing this game of head.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you won't stop in the middle of the game and be like, oh Rym one.
Scott: Oh, it's got one.
Scott: Yeah, you play to the end and then you go.
Rym: One of the more recent four-player games we played.
Rym: I was winning.
Rym: Everyone on the board except Alex said wow Rym's gonna win no matter what he's put almost all his pieces out.
Rym: He's got this big walled off area and Alex is just being real quiet.
Rym: and then Alex proceeds to place Practically all of his pieces.
Rym: like I didn't think he did place all of his pieces kick our asses into the ground and none of Us saw it coming.
Scott: Yeah, I think that was the first time we played with someone who put all the pieces down.
Scott: It was kind of crazy.
Scott: We're like, ah shit.
Scott: Fuck.
Rym: Yeah, the game is definitely not easy to be very good at and The only way to get good at it seems to be is just to play it.
Rym: enough to start recognizing patterns Like.
Rym: there are certain configurations that make it very easy for a person to break through.
Rym: In fact, if you look at a picture of the board It's pretty obvious that due to the way pieces are allowed to be laid It is very easy to break into places and very hard to prevent people from doing so.
Scott: Yep It's it's.
Scott: the thing I like about it is that it feels like it's the same sort of game as go.
Scott: Well, you know with the everyone has the same rate of tile of placement of pieces.
Scott: You can put them not anywhere liking go but you know you put them on this board That's a grid and you're trying to acquire territory and wall the other guy off and such.
Scott: But you don't have the same sort of suffering you have with go.
Scott: You know, it's like even if you're sucking you're still getting somewhere you're still feeling good about it.
Scott: You know, you're having fun.
Scott: just you know Not even trying to beat the other people but just looking for places to put pieces is fun on its own.
Rym: This game also has the great benefit that is incredibly quick to play quick to set up quick to tear down.
Rym: You can just sit down and knock off ten rounds of this with me.
Scott: the official playing time is 20 minutes And I think that's laughable.
Scott: They mean the playing time is five minutes.
Rym: Yeah, especially two players who know how to play the game.
Scott: It's just better than it and the game's over and then and even then if the game's over you feel like playing it again.
Scott: I mean we played that two-player version.
Rym: how many times God over the New Year's party.
Rym: the game saw pretty much constant play.
Scott: Yeah, just people kept playing.
Scott: it kept playing.
Scott: it kept playing it.
Scott: You know, it's like you're playing.
Scott: keep playing.
Scott: It's like you play the game.
Scott: you fill up the board You dump all the pieces off and you do it again and it's just as fun as the last time perhaps more fun now.
Rym: the production values of the game are also Incredibly high.
Rym: quality the piece.
Scott: I don't know about that compared to how much it costs and I was simple The game the price is right for what you get.
Scott: I mean the game is officially $20.
Scott: we paid 10.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, but got it grid.
Rym: I mean, it's a cheap plastic grid, but it has ridges and the pieces have indentations in them.
Rym: So the pieces just lock in.
Scott: yep, perfectly.
Scott: They just fit and they're nice plastic translucent pieces.
Scott: You can tell the colors apart real easily.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Everything's very uniform.
Scott: They feel really nice.
Scott: The thing is for an abstract game.
Scott: usually a lot of people like the super gamers They like to have you know, like the fancy wooden piece and stuff.
Scott: That's why you'll see a lot of these abstract games that know an abstract game is a game That doesn't have a theme like ticket to ride has a theme.
Scott: It's trains.
Scott: Puerto Rico has a theme.
Scott: It's people trading goods in Puerto Rico.
Scott: blockus doesn't have a theme.
Scott: It's squares.
Scott: See, I don't know liars.
Scott: dice doesn't have a theme It's just dice.
Rym: when a game gets abstract enough I actually enjoy it more if it doesn't have a theme because then I don't mean I don't feel Bound by but that's the definition of an abstract game.
Scott: It's just games without a theme.
Scott: if you took Puerto Rico and you just changed it to be, you know Brown discs and you know yellow Wooden bits that would be considered an abstract game.
Rym: Yeah, except the thing it will.
Rym: yeah the game play itself like this.
Rym: game Doesn't have a real world analog.
Rym: Well, Puerto Rico very easily has a real world analog.
Rym: Yep, Puerto Rico It's obvious build buildings.
Scott: It makes sense Mechanically, yep, I mean like chess is considered to be an abstract game Even though there is a theme of knights and kings and things, you know, because the what the gameplay style is abstract Yes, but chess is less abstract feeling than blockus.
Scott: It is However, most like I was saying gamers that the super gamers they tend to like the abstract games to have higher Production values than the themed games, you know, it's because the game is abstract.
Scott: They feel sometimes that you know.
Scott: since it's just simple pieces Why not make them real fancy?
Scott: because you know, then they put them out as like display.
Rym: See, I'm hit or miss on that.
Rym: I mean if I were hosting a symposium, I suppose I would like a really fancy thing.
Rym: But the cheap looking nature of the game a coupled with the fact that while it may look cheap.
Rym: It's functionally perfect Really is conducive to just knocking the game out playing it.
Rym: Whatever.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The thing is a lot of people.
Scott: I know some people they buy abstract games because they look pretty and they'll just leave them out on a table.
Scott: It's sort of like a decoration like some people leave a chess set just lying.
Scott: Yeah, you know, this is not a game you can do that with.
Scott: this is a game that for playing No, they might one day make a version of blockus.
Scott: That is like fancy wooden blockus.
Rym: We should get a chess set or something and leave it out and have an ongoing game But I don't like chess.
Rym: Well, I don't like just that much either, but I enjoy playing it.
Scott: I don't really enjoy playing it that much.
Rym: No, I mean, it's alright, but maybe we could do that with some other game.
Rym: Anyway, I digress.
Rym: The.
Rym: the other nice thing about this game is that because it's so simply done the pieces are super bright super Contrasting.
Rym: so if you're sitting there playing you can very very readily Just glance at the board and all of your abstract thinking comes together real quick.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I spend a lot more time thinking in this game than other people.
Rym: That's just god damn It's god spends too much.
Scott: I think the thing is in this game You could take your turn in like less than 30 seconds easily and I actually sometimes spend your turn shouldn't take more than 10 seconds In this game.
Scott: Yeah, actually sometimes spend maybe a minute thinking about what I'm gonna do on my turn.
Scott: just cuz I'm trying real hard That's but I'm still not winning so much.
Rym: See this game is definitely.
Rym: the main skills you need are the ability to Put forth abstract predictions in an unpredictable board based on mathematical probabilities.
Rym: You definitely need to have a good sense of spatial relationships Mm-hmm.
Scott: I think that's the number one thing you need.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think it's a mix of the two because even if you have a good sense of the spatial relationships if you can't predict where Other people are going to want to go.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't say it's the only thing is it's the number one thing.
Rym: Yeah But the thing the problem here is that people like Scott can sit there forever Holding pieces over the board and rotating morale.
Scott: Yeah, well see even that even if you let me spend time doing that It's not gonna help that much because you still need to look turns and turns in advance Which I don't do at all.
Rym: See I do that very much.
Scott: See I just look at the current turn because I can't be bothered.
Rym: but therein lies the one problem with this game.
Rym: If you are not of the bevagon school of gaming and you let people take as long as they want on your turn You will run into people with this game who will sit there and brute-force the best possible moves.
Scott: Yeah, they'll look at every single piece they have and they'll figure out every possible place They can put those pieces and it'll figure out what everyone else is gonna do on their turn if they do each and every move And then they'll make the best move.
Scott: you if people are taking more like if people are taking more than a minute on their turn You really just say alright take your turn It's times up or else this game becomes unfun as people sit around going in.
Rym: Yep, plus you'll text your brain a lot more if you force yourself to think quickly.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that's true for any game of perfect information and you know, that's what you got to do.
Rym: Yeah, well, I'm very much of the mind that when games are perfect information You generally should force people to take their turn more quickly and also force yourself to take your turn more quickly.
Rym: You'll get smarter quicker.
Scott: Yeah, just go if you don't feel bad.
Scott: if you just made a move and you're not sure if that's the best move just go with your instinct and then Over time just keep playing it and your instinct will change to do something smarter next time.
Rym: Yeah I mean Scott and I and a lot of our friends.
Rym: just because we played so many of these board games it gets to The point with a lot of these games or even with games that are similar to games We've played where I'll make a move without a lot of thought and I'll feel like it was a really good move But I won't immediately be able to say why and then five minutes later well after my turn I'll realize that it was a good move
Scott: and then you'll come back and say oh, you see that move I made five turns ago.
Scott: I made that one because blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: Look how smart I was.
Scott: I thought of why it was smart afterwards, but I'm gonna pretend like I knew why it was smart before I did it.
Rym: Well with most games I mean with most games you do plan ahead like that.
Rym: just you do it quickly.
Rym: But you can get an instinct where there will be certain situations where you'll see a pattern arising.
Scott: But I'm making it funny.
Scott: You're not supposed to like just start talking about something else.
Scott: It's so fair.
Scott: You can't do that because I'm like a duck.
Scott: what Whatever?
Scott: yeah, okay.
Rym: But anyway, like once you figure our game out like that doesn't have to be in Tigers new phrase anymore.
Rym: I just I know what I'm doing straight up because we played the game so much
Scott: Yep,
Rym: but when he first started playing Tigers new phrase because we played so many abstract games I'd see patterns that seem like they were good patterns but I wasn't sure why like certain checkerboard configurations of red and black seemed really really powerful and they worked really really well or certain placements always seem to win the game and certain uses of disasters always seem to be much better than other ones.
Rym: and Then as we played the game more I figured out why those patterns worked and then I was able to use them even more effectively.
Rym: But by forcing yourself to take your turn more quickly You'll start to get the sense of these patterns more readily in other games you play.
Scott: Yep I think the biggest thing in block is that I've still like got to try to get down is Early on in the game when you can make just about any move you want.
Scott: Those are some of the most important moves in the game.
Scott: But you also have the least information with which to make those moves.
Scott: because especially, you know, if you're going first It's like what piece you put down first as the game progresses from most freedom least information to most information least freedom.
Scott: Yep, the other thing is that's a common game.
Scott: I think going first has the tiniest advantage.
Rym: I think it does especially in the four-player game.
Rym: going going early has a slight advantage.
Scott: in the two-player game going first doesn't buy It that much.
Rym: in fact, it might be possible that going first is not actually an advantage in two-player against a skilled player.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not sure yet.
Rym: I got to play the game more.
Scott: Yeah, it could be like Othello where it doesn't matter if you go first or second.
Rym: now having played the game enough and Especially having done well in the last few games.
Rym: I think I figured out a basic and somewhat counterintuitive strategy.
Scott: All right, let's let's hear your fancy strategy.
Rym: All right now I've cemented this strategy a little bit.
Rym: having now actually looked at the instruction book and actually looked at the back of the board and I noticed that all the examples do this - it seems like everyone's initial idea especially in the four-player game is to try to Like wall off an area that they that they generally have them a decent amount of control over and then try to build inside that area later After they've built.
Scott: to the extent of that's what I've done and I'm beginning to think it's it's a better idea to walk to now Build in that area a little bit earlier.
Rym: Here's why in my opinion that idea fails.
Rym: one You've walled off an area, but you won't be able to fully deny all other players access to that area.
Rym: Mm-hmm - you'll have wasted some of your useful pieces walling that area off.
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: three And this is the part that I took me a while to realize if you've walled off an area You won't be able to make very efficient use of it because it is very difficult to place any Significant number of your pieces anywhere near each other due to the orthogonal rules.
Rym: Yep So no matter how big of an area you wall off You're gonna waste most of that space.
Rym: then people are gonna run in.
Rym: Hmm a much better strategy is to spider off with long thin chains in every possible direction you can.
Rym: That way you always have a front of expansion and it's very easy to expand inside of other players domains.
Scott: In fact, the thing is if everyone does that right?
Scott: I mean that strategy kind of works because other people are walling off these areas and you can just reach for the other players Areas and try to infiltrate them.
Scott: What if everyone's trying to reach and everyone else's hair?
Scott: Then you just sort of get it these crazy things going everywhere and it's just gonna become this piece is all over the place.
Scott: Where am I gonna fit another one?
Rym: Yes, and you know what?
Rym: I think that among for advanced players Almost every game will look like that.
Rym: I don't think the walled garden strategy works at all.
Scott: Yeah I have.
Scott: no.
Scott: I do agree that when you do manage to wall off a garden and begin filling it with pieces.
Scott: It is very difficult to efficiently fill it with as many of your pieces as possible also because number one Controlling the shape of the garden is rather difficult because that is just a circumstance of the way in which you walled it off.
Scott: and two because you don't have a lot of time to pick up all your pieces and figure out the most efficient way to lay all of them out within the area.
Scott: and Three because you can only put one in your area at a time and by the time you're you know done filling up the area Someone might have put something in there.
Rym: and now there's more than that.
Rym: I don't think it's just that someone might fill in the air A foregone conclusion that someone else is gonna get into your area and use it more efficiently than you will yep.
Rym: more importantly Be you feel like your walled garden is safe.
Rym: You can wait and fill it in later It's.
Rym: yet if you go into someone else's area It's even safer counterintuitively because They are not free to place their pieces within their own area because they're constrained by the orthogonal placement rules Mm-hmm.
Rym: So you can build into someone's area and then ignore that because they cannot place a piece that will block you and then you fill That in at the end and then you work on infiltrating someone else's area and the moment you get you're in you don't bother building There anymore because there's nothing they can do to stop you.
Rym: And you go in every direction you can where someone can't stop you and you only fill in the places where someone can stop You when you don't have any other places to expand.
Scott: Yep, like definitely is the sound strategy.
Rym: Yeah, and just looking at all the examples I've seen of perfectly filled boards and victory conditions and people who have placed all their pieces I have not seen a Substantial victory or a a victory that looked like it was against other people who are equally intelligent That involved a any sort of walled garden.
Scott: Yep I'm looking at this completely filled board and it seems like everyone.
Scott: It's sort of like if you cut the board in half Diagonally, right then like blue will take up.
Scott: you know all their pieces are in like the bottom right half and Red is in the top right half and yellow is in the bottom left and green is in the top left You know and they sort of you sort of need half the board Diagonally speaking to fit all your pieces.
Scott: So and usually someone from another area of the board is gonna come in to you know One of the areas and then you're gonna go into someone else's.
Scott: and that's how it's gonna be.
Scott: But you can still fit your pieces because the way the rules are for placing them as long as you place them in ways In which they're very close, you know, it's like you got to be real snug.
Scott: if you want to fit as many as possible.
Rym: Yeah, the four players filling the board thing.
Rym: I don't think can happen among four players.
Rym: I think that can only happen with one player playing the brainteaser variant.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I think that's also unless four players are trying.
Rym: Yeah, but even that's just not gonna happen.
Scott: No, but income.
Scott: I think the idea though is if you want to fit more pieces in you want to be real snug right up against people plus that if you're right up against other people's pieces That usually hurts them a lot because it makes them much more difficult for them to play.
Rym: anything doesn't always hurt as much as you Think.
Rym: not always.
Rym: right up next to them are the places where they couldn't place anyway.
Rym: Yes, but if you're right up next to them on the edges see I think in general It looks like most of the people we've played with.
Rym: whenever they see an opportunity to screw another player they'll always take it assuming that will benefit them.
Rym: and I think because there are often times where you don't even want to worry about what the other play is doing because you're gonna get much more benefit from just building your own empire and letting them jump through because The pieces you're gonna have to spend to block them are only going to delay them and you're gonna waste useful pieces.
Scott: Yeah, it's always a question when attacking is okay.
Scott: if I tack I'm gonna use this piece to attack them.
Scott: Maybe while that piece is the best for attacking Maybe that piece is not the best for efficient placement of all my tiles.
Scott: So maybe I should play something else instead of attacking or do a lighter attack with a more efficient piece or something like that.
Rym: So I suppose considering that we've spent quite a while talking about the strategy of block is one of the sim proudly the simplest game We own Perhaps at least in terms of play.
Scott: Yeah, we don't have candy land.
Scott: No, we should get it though I think I own Yahtzee technically.
Rym: Oh However Yahtzee you have to.
Rym: you have to know a little bit about statistics a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, I like Yahtzee though But despite how simple this game is we've spent quite a while talking about the deep strategic and tactical elements of it Even though it's just putting Tetris pieces on a board.
Rym: So I think I can say with certainty that the vast majority of gamers will like this game.
Scott: There's no reason the vast majority of non gamers will like this game.
Rym: Yeah, this is a great gift for kids.
Rym: It's a great gift for anyone.
Scott: Yeah, give it to your mom your dad your brother your sister.
Scott: You know just if you go buy a copy of block is and the next time you visit your family bring it along and they'll Totally play it with you because even if they totally hate it you only took up ten minutes of their time.
Scott: It's a lot easier to get someone to play block is for ten minutes than it is to get them to play something else.
Scott: You know, I mean even tickets a ride which goes over real well with families and such.
Scott: It takes a while to set it up and it takes a while to teach.
Scott: block is takes no time.
Scott: It's like BAM.
Scott: Let's go rock and roll Block and roll.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.