Scott: It's Tuesday January 23rd.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discussed the new game battle lore.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, I certainly came home to a pleasant surprise today.
Scott: Yeah Well, I said last week that I would try something new and I bought video games on Amazon.
Scott: I ordered both Wario where we and Phoenix Wright Injustice for all the new Phoenix Wright game.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Now I had previously done this with Castlevania portrait of ruin And well the game showed up today Monday, which is about a week after they came out.
Scott: So if you're thinking about pre-ordering games on Amazon, I can tell you a few things.
Scott: number one The price is right.
Scott: You'll pay the same price or less than you'll pay at EB or GameStop.
Scott: You know, maybe Best Buy will get you a lower price.
Scott: Sometimes maybe they like to have sales there But you know, probably not.
Scott: Also, you'll get the games about a week after they come out.
Scott: if you're pre-order and choose the free United States Postal Service shipping.
Rym: I mean you could pick overnight shipping if you're a nut.
Scott: Yeah, so if you really kind of need games the day they come out and for some games you do need that You know Especially online type games Like if I was a World of Warcraft player and I didn't think it was a complete waste of time the stupidest thing ever.
Scott: Then yes, you would need the Burning Crusade the day it came out.
Scott: but WarioWare, you know, it's not like I was having a party this week.
Scott: So I don't really need it any sooner.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: We may possibly have a party next weekend.
Scott: No, I can't.
Rym: We have to know.
Scott: Anyway, we might not even have the Wario unlocked by then we better.
Scott: all I can say is that Wario and Phoenix right?
Rym: Whoo WarioWare smooth moves is exactly what I could hope it would be and All I have to say is that monkey ball can die in a fire.
Rym: Monkey ball for the Wii is perhaps the worst launch title.
Scott: Yeah It's dumb I know because there are those other launch tiles the kinds you don't even mention like what the kinds based on crap Tea kids cartoons.
Rym: those might be better.
Rym: No Monkey ball is pretty bad.
Scott: monkey ball is bad, but it's not that bad I think it is.
Scott: I mean no because there are games out there like yours The Barney game for the Sega Genesis, you know what I'll bet that those games for the Wii work.
Rym: Monkey ball doesn't even work if those minigames are non-functional.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Scott: It's bad.
Scott: Maybe we'll do a show on how bad the monkey ball is.
Scott: You might have to eventually but that's not for today.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So anyway in the news it appears that some people over at the score hero forums have figured out how to put your own songs into guitar heroes - oh Well, that's something that's very necessary.
Rym: The bad news is it takes eight separate programs 12 complicated steps a modded ps2.
Scott: How what the hell are they doing?
Scott: It's like wow, how could it take eight separate?
Rym: I didn't read it.
Rym: But from what I gather what you essentially do is rip the game Futs with it burn it to a new disc with your modified version and then play it like a mod game in your modded ps2.
Scott: Yeah, they should have really just combined all those things into.
Scott: you know, you don't go out and say no I think here's a way to hack guitar here.
Scott: You say here we wrote a program that does it in one step.
Rym: I can guarantee that within a few months.
Rym: Someone's going to do just that.
Scott: Yeah, that's sort of a necessity.
Rym: This was definitely not the hey, this is now common.
Rym: This was the hey, there's a way to do it.
Rym: post.
Rym: This is the very beginning.
Scott: plus this thing kind of wouldn't really be necessary if there was a step mania equivalent for guitar hero.
Rym: But there is.
Scott: oh there is really.
Rym: it's called frets on fire and we talked about it.
Scott: It's kind of a lame name.
Scott: They should have called it just guitar mania or something to get a step mania or like Oh String mania or even fret mania.
Scott: if you want to keep the fret fret mania school They might have been worried about being sued or something like that.
Rym: Yeah, you never know.
Rym: Anyway, but the issue here is that from the screenshots I've seen and from what I've looked at Compared to guitar heroes 2 frets on fire looks pretty goddamn lame.
Rym: Yeah I mean at least step mania does everything possible to perfectly emulate a DDR machines.
Scott: That mania is in many ways better than a DDR machine.
Scott: I mean other than a supernova machine step mania.
Scott: the current version and that's I'm not even counting the beta version just the current stable version is About as good as a DDR 8th mix or a in the groove 2 machine.
Scott: I mean as long as you have a powerful enough computer and your song files aren't screwed up and your music is in sync And you have a pad that's good and you have a good dance pad.
Rym: Yes, but yeah I mean it emulates right down to.
Rym: you could set it up like an arcade machine.
Rym: You could hook up a coin slot and it would deal with it.
Rym: It has an interface ready for a coin slot.
Rym: Yep, it's just straight up.
Rym: frets on fire.
Rym: Just kind of looks like lame 3d cubes coming down strings.
Scott: yeah, I have a feeling the people who made frets on fire are not the Not of these step mania developer caliber.
Rym: Well, their website is slow and at a weird domain.
Scott: That's always a tip-off that someone is not too bright.
Rym: Well, I have a feeling that the people I mean I might be totally wrong and if you if I'm wrong about this people who make frets on fire feel free to correct me.
Rym: But I get the impression that frets on fire was made and rushed out the door.
Rym: So they could be the first ones to make that hoping that the community would grow around them like it did in step mania.
Scott: Hmm and I'm realizing that the community grows around quality not the first to the gate as evidenced by the we.
Rym: Fret sound fire does have one new cool feature.
Rym: Apparently you can take a guitar heroes or guitar heroes to put it in your computer Rip it and then play all those songs straight up in frets on fire.
Scott: Oh now if only see that's not in step mania needs.
Scott: Yes, why doesn't step mania see?
Scott: yeah, yeah, they got what.
Scott: so basically step mania has everything that DDR needs except one feature frets on fire has Basically the barest bones of what guitar hero needs plus one feature.
Scott: the step mania doesn't have.
Rym: yeah because for step I mean we already actually have third mix fourth mix fifth mix Extra mix all those we have the discs.
Rym: Yeah Somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, if we didn't have we couldn't find about.
Scott: just buy them.
Rym: Yeah, they're not that hard to get.
Scott: the thing is It sucks because you know Those are all like ps1 games and the other DDRs of ps2 games and new DDRs or Xbox and ps3 games.
Scott: It's like without a ps3 and a 360 and a ps2 you can't play every DDR mix.
Scott: There is so step.
Scott: if there was a way to load those things off the disc into step mania Then with one computer you could dance every DDR dance that ever dance though Honestly, I think the long-term answer is just to buy a DDR machine.
Scott: It is and put a step mania computer inside of it After ripping the songs off of the discs inside of it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, though.
Rym: Here's the problem.
Scott: You can buy DDR machines on Amazon.
Scott: Also crisis machines and air hockey tables.
Scott: They're not that expensive Just as expensive as a car.
Scott: That's all you know are.
Scott: or DDR?
Rym: They're not as expensive as they used to be.
Scott: no they used to be more because you had to import them.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway that the problem with this feature is that apparently on a computer faster than any computer We own it takes more than eight hours.
Scott: No.
Scott: Well, that's bound to happen.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, so I will watch and wait and I guess in the meantime We'll probably just buy a ps2 and guitar heroes and Okami.
Scott: Yeah, the only thing is I'm worried that if we you know We'll buy a ps2 which will be free technically and then we tar heroes will come out Yeah, and then we won't.
Scott: then the next guitar hero games will come out for the 360 Which you won't have.
Scott: so we'll have guitar hero 1 & 2 but not we won't be able to get any of the future ones.
Rym: But then if they don't release guitar heroes 1 & 2 on the 360 Then we have to get a ps2 anyway because guitar heroes 2 has some great song.
Scott: It does.
Scott: it really just kind of sucks that you know.
Scott: this whole Stop doing.
Scott: I can't talk.
Rym: talking.
Scott: Really sucks to have a series that spans multiple consoles because then if you don't follow those consoles Then you can't get the whole series like Final Fantasy.
Rym: Yeah, like Soul Calibur was like 1 2 3 is just on the ps2 It's not gonna be on anything else though I think it's telling that at least as far as I've seen among the general gamer community Soul Calibur 2 is still more popular than Soul.
Scott: Calibur.
Scott: 3 wasn't so good.
Scott: The only thing it added was you can make your own guy, which is pretty cool pretty cool But not worth paying for a game just to make your own guy.
Rym: Also, the GameCube is more powerful and yeah, it would have looked better on a GameCube.
Scott: I don't care what it looks like they care how it fights.
Scott: But anyway, I got some other news is going on besides whatever you're talking about.
Rym: Well shoot up.
Scott: All right, so Everyone knows that this summer PC gaming is gonna get some sort of well this year PC game is gonna get a revival.
Scott: Supposedly spore will come out.
Scott: supposedly supreme commander will come out.
Scott: Supposedly a new command and conquer game will come out which I don't care too much about but I'm kind of interested.
Rym: I haven't played a little bit in a long time.
Scott: If I'm buying a new computer I might go for it, especially once it gets to that $20 discount rack.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: However, the biggest release this year is going to be Half-Life 2 Episode 2.
Scott: Half-Life 2 Episode 2, Portal and Team Fortress 2 are all gonna be one big release by Valve on Steam And it's gonna be huge.
Scott: I mean those are three games.
Scott: I want to play all of them.
Scott: You know I've already got Half-Life 2 and Half-Life 2 Episode 1 got to get Episode 2 because the other one was so awesome.
Scott: Gonna play Portal cuz.
Scott: that's a first-person shooter puzzler that looks just out of this world.
Scott: and Team Fortress 2 Be the revival of Team FPS action.
Rym: Oh, yeah Team Fortress 2 has the possibility of being the game that will bring that genre of gaming back to the masses.
Rym: Yes That's a whole genre a whole segment an important segment a huge segment Once the only segment of online gaming that was of any value or note and it's dead.
Rym: now It's gone.
Rym: There are kids today who have never played a game like that.
Rym: Yep, and also I think the people making it know exactly what they're doing.
Scott: for the videos.
Scott: I can only agree with you.
Rym: if that is what my the evidence I will judge by I'll give it a 90% chance that this game is going to be probably The destruction of our lives and it you know If no one.
Scott: possibly the end of the night even though at the worst possible chance, right?
Scott: No one plays this game, but us Still awesome.
Scott: Yes, so Here's the news for people like me.
Scott: you already have Half-Life 2 and Half-Life 1 and all the mods and everything and Half-Life 2 Episode 1 and Just about every Half-Life thing there is.
Scott: we only want to buy episode 2 portal and Team Fortress 2.
Scott: We don't want to buy anything else because we got it all well.
Scott: valve is going to sell that to me in the black box Which will be PS.
Scott: Well, not PSP.
Scott: It was not gonna be on the PSP.
Scott: Sorry kids It's gonna be PC only and it's gonna be $40.
Scott: That's a good deal 40 bucks for three games.
Scott: Hell I paid like 15 to 20 bucks for just Half-Life 2 Episode 1.
Scott: I paid $65 for Zelda - yeah, I paid 40 bucks for Half-Life 2.
Scott: So now I'm paying 40 bucks for a whole episode of Half-Life 2 and portal and Team Fortress 2.
Scott: This is like a steal is the bigger news.
Scott: There's also gonna be the orange box.
Scott: I get the black box because I'm cool and I've already played Half-Life.
Scott: but for those of you out there Who are not into the Half-Life already?
Scott: You don't have Half-Life 2.
Scott: Maybe you're like Rym where you would have played Half-Life 2, but you didn't upgrade your computer.
Scott: So now it's finally time to play Half-Life 2.
Scott: They're gonna sell you the orange box.
Scott: The orange box will come with Half-Life 2 Half-Life 2 Episode 1 Half-Life 2 Episode 2 Portal and Team Fortress 2 and it will be a mere $60 once again less than Mario 3 cost me when it came out for the price of a single Xbox 360 game.
Scott: That's brand new for the price of a single ps3 game for only $20 more than I paid for Half-Life 2 Alone, you will get Half-Life 2 Half-Life 2 Episode 1 and 2 portal and Team Fortress.
Scott: Not only that but this orange box will be available for the PC the ps3 and the 360.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: Now is there a possibility therefore that I'll be playing online with my computer against in say Team Fortress 2 Against some people using game pads on a 360?
Scott: There might be a possibility of that.
Scott: I don't know because no one said anything.
Rym: because if that's true There have been a lot of people lately who don't remember the glory days of FPS and on the computer and they would contend that The non mouse and keyboard controls of an FPS that consoles have is perfectly adequate for a game of that difficulty in caliber and complexity.
Rym: and I have never in my life anticipated proving people so wrong so powerfully and so easily.
Scott: Well, I think you can technically do it in Halo 1 if I'm not mistaken.
Scott: The problem is Halo is designed for the gamepad play and thus the keyboard and mouse doesn't give you a huge advantage.
Rym: Yeah, I'd love to see someone try to play.
Rym: I don't know mega TF.
Scott: It's not enough buttons, but if you're playing weapons factory, you just don't have enough buttons.
Scott: god There's no way you'd have to open up menus in order to do anything.
Rym: action quake.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But even if that's not a possibility, this is still the awesome especially for people, you know Because all of these games except for Team Fortress are single-player games.
Scott: So even if there isn't gonna be that kind of action if you're a 360 owner or a ps3 owner and You don't want to buy a souped-up computer to play all these games Which are some of the best FPS is ever way better than any of those shit console FPS is.
Scott: you're playing like your halos and whatnot.
Rym: Yeah, I mean not to make.
Rym: I mean, I'm not disparaging Halo because they're pretty good games.
Rym: But halo 2 for as good as it is is really got nothing on FPS.
Rym: is that came out in the mid 90s?
Scott: Yeah So well, maybe the late 90s, okay Yeah, so now all of you will have complete access to the real deal for only 60 bucks.
Scott: You're gonna get freaking one, two, three, four five games.
Scott: Holy shit This is like the greatest thing ever.
Rym: and never feel bad about playing a game late.
Scott: I mean while I never feel bad about playing a single-player game late.
Scott: Yeah multiplayer team fortress - not team fortress late, but playing tribes too late big mistake.
Rym: Yeah picking up mega TF now There's one other guy to play with.
Scott: yeah multiplayer games You sort of have to get in when the boat, you know is about to sail.
Scott: if it leaves without you You might as well not get on but single-player games.
Scott: There's nothing wrong, you know.
Scott: I mean if a kid was born today He would have no shame playing Zelda 1 eight years from now because eight years old and he wasn't alive when Zelda 1 was new.
Rym: I mean I was playing counter-strike for as long as I was in college and you know All these mods for half-life.
Rym: despite that I had never actually played half-life 1.
Rym: I owned it, but I only owned it for mods.
Rym: It wasn't until like three years ago when I finally while I was living on co-op and didn't have internet access and lived in the mountains Where even my cell phone didn't work.
Rym: I sat down and I played half-life 1.
Scott: it's good, isn't it?
Rym: It's pretty damn good game.
Rym: I must say.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: All right, that's enough of my news.
Scott: I can.
Scott: yeah, sixty bucks five games.
Scott: sixty bucks five games.
Rym: So contrary to what you might have learned in I don't know middle school or high school Especially if you're in our generation, which we were actually alive when the Cold War was still going on Which is weird to say because that wasn't that long ago.
Scott: No, it feels like it was a long time ago.
Rym: But no, no, I mean parastroic I mean 1989.
Rym: I knew exactly what was going on.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I was a little kid.
Scott: I didn't know what the hell's going on Now.
Rym: I was politically motivated in fifth grade.
Rym: I was all about Bill Clinton.
Rym: I Was and Ross Perot.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't care.
Scott: I didn't know or care.
Rym: I didn't even know right from left until well anyway when I was one in in in Soviet Russia Someone made this little nice.
Rym: You might want to call it a propaganda film except I don't know what I'd call it.
Rym: Just a fun little stop-motion animation with all these little matches and it is decidedly Anti-war.
Rym: it is definitely peace propaganda.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And also well, it's kind of well done.
Rym: It's kind of funny It's kind of poignant and all I really have to say if you watch it is that peace aside Those blue guys really kind of brought it on themselves and deserved everything they got.
Scott: that's what I was gonna say.
Scott: I mean if we learn anything from this.
Scott: this video is a green is awesome and blue is assholes.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the green guy was you know, the the border moved a little bit.
Rym: the green guy very diligently Just put it right back and everything was okay.
Scott: Yeah, the green guy didn't try to push it into the blue area or anything.
Scott: He was a nice guy.
Scott: He said oh the border is messed up.
Scott: It's not supposed to be like that.
Scott: I'll move it back.
Scott: So we're even again.
Scott: then the blue guy was like no fuck you We're gonna take some of your dirt.
Rym: and the green guy says hey, you can't do that.
Rym: Then the blue guy kills him Yep, and then war escalates.
Rym: But yeah, this is a nice little I'll bet a lot of people Maybe people who are older than us Might not have really realized that Despite the fact that the u.s.
Rym: Really painted the Soviet Union to be this evil horrible menace of doom and gloom to all the world.
Scott: It was kind of bad.
Scott: Yeah, it was but it's not.
Rym: it wasn't Consummate evil it just had problems.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it wasn't like everyone in the whole Soviet Union was a horrible evil KGB nutcase.
Rym: Yeah, I mean in general While the Soviet Union was very often misguided in many of its policies It's not like they were thinking how can we screw the peasants today?
Rym: I dare Trotsky.
Rym: I Mean a few people might have been thinking that but most people were At least trying to do some good for their people.
Scott: Yeah, and there are people there in the early 80s making videos like this and it was awesome.
Rym: Yeah, this is a good video Yep, and I can't really say anymore, but I'm not gonna ruin what happens, but they're matches Matches.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty obvious.
Rym: Figure out what's gonna happen.
Rym: It took us by surprise and we knew it was coming.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it was done So well, it was all right.
Scott: My thing is pretty simple.
Scott: It's well, let's see How many times have I talked about Second Life even though I've never played it at all.
Scott: in my god.
Rym: So you talk about Second Life and World of Warcraft like there's no tomorrow yet.
Scott: I've never played either of them at all.
Scott: Anyway, here's a funny website called get a first life.com.
Scott: It's it's got the same design as I think the Second Life website and at the top of it It says your world.
Scott: Sorry about that.
Scott: And then they're funny.
Scott: It says funny things on the website.
Scott: Like it says go outside membership is free.
Scott: First life is a 3d analog world where a server lag does not exist.
Scott: Find out where you actually live fornicate using your actual genitals.
Scott: Access your closet to build your first life.
Scott: Look Man under 18 get a teen first life.
Rym: I just remember back when I still played MMOs and in the realm at my house and I was obsessed with getting stuff to put in my house and it was a big deal when I got a hold of some fancy chrysanthemums and some diamonds and things to put on my floor and on my little trophy case and in my little chest and I was really happy about you know, building up my little house.
Rym: now I got a real house and that house there was actually just some bits on a server somewhere not so exciting.
Scott: No, it's funny bit.
Scott: we got first life questions, we've got answers.
Scott: our five cents is enough.
Scott: What's this body thing?
Scott: And what do I do with the dangly bits?
Scott: Why can't I build a dirigible?
Scott: with my mind Penguins spoons and you?
Scott: what's life like among the flightless?
Scott: You know, I think I've just read the entire website because you can't really click on anything on this website.
Scott: None of it will take you anywhere.
Rym: Oh, so it's one of those joke websites.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can click.
Scott: dig this you can click the credits to see the guys who made it.
Rym: You know what in general there's.
Rym: I've seen jokes like that before.
Rym: It's a good way to go because a joke like that if taken to more depth becomes increasingly less funny.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if this actually that you know at the top there's a menu that's like what.
Scott: what is life?
Scott: showcase business partners developers?
Scott: If those actually went to different sites if you could actually log into this and do stuff.
Scott: It would just become a.
Rym: there's only one site that's ever gotten away with that?
Rym: maybe two but high space yeah high space.
Rym: Anyway, you get a which I wonder if that's updated.
Rym: I haven't been there.
Scott: like there is one link actually besides dig this and the credits that actually works.
Scott: It's the webs.
Scott: It's the link to cafe press where you can buy first life merchandise.
Scott: Really yes, really Well, you know what it's right under the fornicate using your actual genitals link Which doesn't go anywhere.
Rym: good job because that's the one people are gonna try to click on.
Rym: while they're clicking furiously They'll probably accidentally hit that store link.
Rym: Yeah, and then they'll get excited.
Scott: It's pretty big.
Scott: It's got some pictures of t-shirts on it.
Scott: Yeah, whatever the funniest thing is you should go to the website Just look at it for a second to see all the kids that they have on the front page.
Rym: So in the board gaming war gaming world if you don't exist in this world or have a presence there You probably don't even know what we're gonna talk about, but that's good because you're gonna learn something.
Rym: So we're going to talk about Battle lore which has been all the rage in the board gaming war gaming community.
Scott: Yeah, this game went from a game that wasn't out yet.
Scott: Let's see where this game is on the top board game geek games.
Scott: Oh, let's see.
Scott: This game that wasn't even out months ago is now number five on board game.
Scott: geek.
Scott: That's pretty damn good, you know going from nothing to five immediately.
Rym: now this game has brought.
Rym: It's a war game, but it's not like a lot of other war games.
Rym: It's very much in the same vein as battle cry or memoir 44.
Scott: Well, it's.
Scott: it uses the come.
Scott: Richard Borg is the guy who designed it.
Scott: oh, oh, he's the guy who designed the command and colors system, which is also used in memoir 44 and Commanding colors ancients and another game that I forget battle cry.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: These games are basically the basic mechanic.
Rym: I mean war games in general tend to be along the lines of you have units You move them around by a set of rules Command them by a set of rules and fight with them by a set of rules.
Rym: the fighting could range from looking up things and tables to rolling dice to Drawing abstract lines on a piece of paper and seeing which ones get crossed off.
Rym: all sorts of different ways.
Rym: these things work, but the purpose is to simulate tactical strategic or Tactical strategic war play yet.
Scott: You want to simulate military tactics?
Scott: so the people playing the game feel like military commanders on some level be it a squad or giant armies across the entire world.
Scott: and you know simulate having guys fight and die and kill other guys and you know It's my guys versus your guys.
Rym: now a lot of war games are broken down into grid hex games where you have units on hexes that move around or The more popular in some circles, but also more hated in the same in some circles the kind of freeform games.
Rym: We have miniatures and you put the miniatures in terrain.
Scott: Yeah, you got stuff, you know, the war games also include stuff like risk and dice wars even.
Rym: Yeah advanced wars Warhammer 40k Battle system battle tech all that.
Rym: but this game is definitely designed to be simple.
Rym: This is a war game that anyone could pick up and learn in about five minutes.
Rym: This is not a complex difficult to learn onerous war game.
Rym: You're not going to be sitting there with a tape measure Trying to figure out if your skirmishers can make it the four inches through the woods to attack the wolf riders.
Scott: Yeah, it's also a very short war game.
Scott: Whereas if you play something like Shogun or Warhammer.
Scott: you could be sitting there for a very long time.
Scott: battle tech takes hours and hours to play.
Rym: You know, you could be sitting there for some war games take days to play that battle system a Large battle in battle system could easily take four hours and that's if everyone knows what you're doing and you're using the simple rules.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: battle lore even a simple game Even the very complex game of battle lore will take an hour a little over an hour depending on you know if anyone if Everyone tries to hold back and to let because it's you play until you kill a certain number of guys.
Scott: So if everyone plays very defensively, it'll take longer.
Scott: Yeah, but it's sort of impossible to not fight.
Scott: So the game doesn't take very long at all.
Rym: but this basic mechanic that runs through all these games that we're talking about right now and battle lore is the newest iteration of This is very simple.
Rym: you will have by some means a number of cards and these cards allow you you like you'll have a hand of cards and Each card whichever one you play allows you to give orders to a certain number or type of your units.
Rym: So say you'll have a card that says order two units on the right side of the board or Order all your units in the center or order all your green units and you take turns.
Rym: So I play a card order all my green units Scott plays a card order all my cavalry and we go back and forth.
Rym: So instead of moving all your units every round you move a subset that you have to choose Tactically from a hand that you've drawn
Scott: and this is why this is a big reason why the game doesn't take very long because you Don't have people, you know, usually in a war game.
Scott: It's like, alright It's my turn now and now I spend 15 minutes to a half hour moving all my stuff.
Scott: Like if you play advance or is on a big map Someone's turn usually takes like five minutes because they're going all around this map looking for every single unit They haven't used and where to move it.
Scott: and you know thinking all this stuff out in this game on your turn At most you're not gonna move so many units.
Scott: You're never gonna move all of them.
Scott: most turns most of your units just sit there doing nothing because you can't order them.
Scott: So you just you know You pick which guys you're gonna move and you move them and those are the only guys you have to worry about.
Scott: so your turn Is very quick So no one is sitting around waiting for a long time.
Scott: and also because your turns are so quick The game doesn't take very long because you can take a lot of turns very quickly And it only takes so many turns for the games to be over.
Rym: Now if battle or is basically the same as all these other games only with a different theme Why is this game the hotness?
Rym: Why is this game being lauded while the other games in the system while popular were never near this level of popularity?
Scott: Well, I can figure out two reasons But I think the biggest reason is the theme.
Scott: the theme of battle lore is heavy Thick rich and awesome.
Rym: It is basically the hundred years war.
Rym: Only it is the hundred years war in a world where there is some degree of magic.
Scott: Yes now their first two or so adventures adventures in the book That come the book of adventures that comes with the game are medieval adventures.
Scott: they're Agincourt and first chef O'Shea, whatever you call it and There's no magic.
Scott: There's no goblins or dwarves or giant spiders.
Scott: It's just military guys fighting and those are meant as the introductory Battles for new players because if you don't know the command and color system already That's a great way to learn without having to worry about the complicated rules of Goblins and dwarves and giant spiders and magic spells.
Rym: So yeah The theme is definitely drawing people because the hundred years war has been at least for war gamers an object of fascination Much like the Napoleonic Wars and the Gallic Wars.
Scott: Another thing that I think people are drawing to this game is that the production value of the game is very high.
Scott: now There's a problem with the first print.
Rym: run in the dice, but now you can get better dice for free Yeah, and if you get ahold of the old one, they'll send you better dice.
Scott: They'll help you out Yep, and also this game sort of has like aspects of Collectible card games and aspects of miniatures games without actually being collect.
Scott: It's not a game of who spends the most money wins, you know or you need to spend a certain amount of money to get the stuff you want because there isn't sort of a Construct your army mechanic where you know, you pick the best bits to make your army like there would be in Warhammer or something.
Rym: Yeah, it's more.
Rym: it's more that this game is very Expandable and you can get or make or whatever expansions that modify the rules or add units or add difficulty or add players or change units or do something to Make the game different.
Rym: So anytime you get tired of the game, it would be trivial to go pick up one of these Many myriad expansions that are likely going to be coming out.
Scott: Yeah, I mean when I bought the game they gave me a hill giant with the game.
Scott: So in the box is the giant spider that was the only monster.
Scott: then they gave me the hill giant and then when I bought The dice on I didn't buy them for I got the dice online.
Scott: They gave me the earth elemental, you know.
Scott: And they keep adding creatures.
Scott: I'm sure they'll add more units.
Scott: They'll add more maps.
Scott: They're gonna add all kinds of stuff to this game.
Rym: now more importantly.
Rym: I said it was expandable.
Rym: It's not just that there are expansions like this.
Rym: It's more that the way the game is written and the way the rules work is very conducive to easily adding Expansions.
Rym: it's kind of like a program that has hooks for other programs.
Rym: It has hooks built into the rules to make it trivial to add rules without breaking anything.
Scott: Yeah For example a lot of the specific rules of the game are on these cards and the cut the root It's all everywhere in the instruction manual.
Scott: It says if a rule is on a card that overrides a rule in the book.
Scott: now How can I explain this?
Scott: in the array in the game that comes in the box of battle or without any expansions?
Scott: There are a total of four different weapons the units might have you know as normal units might have.
Scott: there's the short sword the long Sword the bow and some dwarves had the crossbow.
Rym: Yeah, and there's just a card for each one of these items.
Rym: So whichever what you want a unit has the rules for that item are just on this card in front of you, right?
Scott: So it would be very easy to say make a bunch of miniatures that had Spears and then in that box of miniatures with Spears you put a card that says Longspear and it has the rules for the long spear on it.
Scott: And now Congratulations, you've expanded the game So kind of.
Rym: what you do when you play a game of this is you take all the relevant rules cards for whatever you're doing which there's a standard set that comes with the game and you lay them out alongside the board and it's kind of like.
Rym: you have Constructed the full rule book for this individual battle that you're having right now.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you're playing a game and on the map for this particular adventure, it's a mountainous map.
Scott: So you take the elevated terrain rules card and you put it down in case you remember the rules for elevated terrain.
Scott: But there's no forest in this hill.
Scott: It's it's a snowy hill.
Scott: so you take the Forest card that has the rules for forest tiles and you put it in the box because you don't need to look at it.
Rym: Yep so basically you have instead of a reference book you have a Play every time you play Which is kind of neat.
Rym: I like this mechanic.
Scott: Yeah, another thing about this game is it sort of bridges.
Scott: the miniatures gap is all the miniatures are plain gray plastic so it's sort of ink.
Scott: it's sort of like this bridge between like a war board game like Shogun or something and Like a war hammer, you know, it's like.
Scott: ah, here's the miniatures.
Scott: you could paint them if you want.
Scott: You can buy more if you want.
Rym: I would recommend against painting them.
Rym: while they're fairly high quality They are not the type of miniature that would be easy or fun to paint.
Scott: Well, I don't know I'm not big on miniatures painting mostly because I don't have the skill or the time to do.
Rym: I painted a few in my day.
Rym: that turned out.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I have some friends who were absolutely amazing at it.
Scott: Yeah, but I look at some of these pictures of people who did paint them on board game geek and they're fairly impressive.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I guess if you have the skills and you're already a miniatures painting type of person Battle or is not so bad mostly because you got a whole lot of miniatures for relatively little money.
Scott: I mean this game is 70 something bucks.
Scott: You could probably get it for like high 60s.
Rym: I've seen it a lot of people about it for 50 online.
Scott: No, maybe on eBay or something.
Rym: No on straight-up websites I forget the exact name of them, but all the board game geek people were like, yeah Why would anyone pay more than 50 bucks for this?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: Anyway, plus $10 shipping.
Scott: Oh, well, there you go.
Scott: But yeah, no, but if your main interest is miniatures painting you probably don't want to buy this just for miniatures painting.
Scott: But if you might want to think about miniatures painting and you also want to play battle or not a bad idea Well, you know what?
Rym: It'd be a good thing to learn a little bit on just because you wouldn't worry about messing these pieces Up, they're not the highest of quality.
Scott: Yeah, and there's so many of them.
Scott: It's like, you know You go buy Warhammer you buy a pack with like maybe five little dudes or one big dude.
Scott: here You get a box with like a hundred dudes in it.
Rym: Well, there's also the issue that in this game the miniatures themselves don't mean anything.
Rym: All that matters is the number of them on a hex.
Rym: Yeah And the type of unit has nothing to do with the miniature like it would in a normal war game.
Rym: It only has to do with the banner that's on the set of units.
Scott: Yeah The miniatures and the actual look at the miniatures in this game is all flavor and this game is heavy with the flavor.
Scott: You got the flavor text the flavor miniatures the flavor tiles.
Rym: I'll admit that I've been mostly ignoring the flavor and just playing the straight-up tactical game.
Rym: Yeah, I've been paying.
Rym: I don't even segregate the proper kinds of miniatures.
Rym: I just throw down a little gray guys and put banners on them and go.
Scott: I haven't been paying to the As much attention to the flavor as the book would have you but I have been paying attention to it because it is it's kind Of fun.
Scott: It's like oh, I'm moving a little spider.
Rym: Now more importantly we don't need to get into many of the details of the game.
Rym: You can read all that online.
Rym: You can watch.
Rym: if you really want to see how this game works check out board games with Scott.
Scott: Yeah, if you go to boardgameswithscott.com there's a video this guy shows you the basics of how this game works.
Scott: He doesn't go into the advanced rules, but he goes into enough rules that you understand what's going on.
Rym: Yeah, because there is one other thing we didn't talk about.
Rym: what we'll get to that?
Rym: But the game itself.
Rym: if you've ever played there's this old game I think was called battle system.
Rym: that came with a big vinyl mat and had all these hexes on it and It plays almost the same as this game.
Scott: Yeah, I never played the game.
Scott: So, I don't know.
Rym: it plays almost exactly the same with minor differences and Therein lies the point of contention between myself and other pretty much everyone else.
Rym: We know and Scott who stands alone in that Battle-lore is fun and battle-lore is well done and I think battle-lore has a lot of potential especially with the fact that you can expand The game but I do believe that the current game as it is now is Has enough randomness in it to the point that any individual victory or loss means very little.
Scott: Well, yeah, I will.
Scott: I'm not going to dispute the fact that battle-lore it is not a German game.
Scott: It is not a heavy game.
Scott: It is not a deep game.
Rym: It is a game for like 12 and up.
Scott: Well, it says on the box like 10 and up, right?
Scott: I guess 12 and up would be good, too.
Scott: But yeah, this is not a game.
Scott: That is a heavy hitter.
Scott: It is very light, which is why it only takes an hour and the rules are simple.
Scott: I mean the book of the rules is big and impressive, but really it's not all that complex.
Scott: Especially if you played a command-and-colors game before It's not exactly the hardest game.
Rym: Yeah, in fact if you played one of these games before this adds just one thing really Yeah, any middle school kid can play this game with ease without messing it up ever.
Scott: So if you are the kind of person like Rym who can only seem to have fun in a game That is very very deep and difficult No, it's not even that.
Rym: it's not that the game has to be very deep.
Rym: It's that it has to be deep enough for me to get my foot wet.
Rym: God damn, I think this game is so close to being everything I've wanted in a war game ever.
Rym: It's so close and I really wanted to like it and a lot of people could tweak this game But I think they go after the wrong things like for example the card drafting thing.
Rym: you'll have four or five cards in your hand and That really limits what you can do on the board.
Rym: and while that can be annoying and while there is in Individual hands the individual games a lot of randomness there It's mitigated at least partly by the fact that you're an intelligent human being who can make decisions.
Rym: And also it is a fairly elegant way to kind of abstract fog of war and difficulty of giving orders and delays of Communication and all those things that happen in a battle without having to have individual mechanics for all of them.
Rym: The card drafting thing on its own does not hurt this game very much And in fact, I'd say that that's one of the best strengths of this game is how the card drafting works.
Rym: but in addition to that combat is all resolved with dice and Just for the scale of the number of dice used versus the number of hits it takes to kill a unit.
Rym: Luck can factor extremely heavily into sudden victories and defeats and I have won in lost battles very obviously Simply from one roll of the dice.
Scott: Yeah I mean there are ways that you can play to get you know Plus one dice here minus one dice for the other guy there die.
Scott: Yeah die for the other guy there, but When it seems whenever anyone rolls the dice most of the time It's just you miss because to hit is so incredibly difficult unless you're in such an advantageous position on the board.
Rym: Yeah, I mean on a normal unit against a normal unit you pretty much have to roll one Space of a six-sided die to do any damage.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you have a dice die and only one side will hit.
Scott: So it's basically roll a d6 on a one you hit on anything else You don't hit but four hits kills a unit.
Rym: and say you have a unit who rolls four dice.
Rym: There have been times where a powerful unit was suddenly wiped out by a random lucky roll.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, let's say you've got I don't know a mounted unit a red mounted unit Which is very powerful and it can pursue.
Scott: so let's say it comes in on someone and you give it a plus one.
Scott: You use a card to give it plus one.
Scott: So it rolls five dice.
Scott: Let's say gets two hits and a flag.
Scott: that unit gets loses half of itself and is forced to retreat Now that he can pursue and attack again, it's just like up you're dead when normally it's so difficult to hit.
Scott: So it really gets frustrating when when a unit battles either nothing happens or it just dies.
Scott: There doesn't seem to be a whole lot of in-between.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: couple this with the fact that this is a full strength till the end game.
Rym: This is a game where no matter how damaged a unit is it fights at 100% full power until it is destroyed.
Scott: All right, so if I have that number I was just talking about a red mounted longsword unit.
Scott: it's very powerful unit.
Scott: Let's say it's been damaged by some archers pretty heavily.
Scott: It can attack just as ferociously as it could at the beginning of the game.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: It's full offensive strength until it's dead.
Scott: when at which point it has no offensive strength.
Rym: Now even that would be okay with me.
Rym: See my problem is that the game is so close to being good.
Rym: But the card thing is okay on its own.
Rym: and even the card thing plus the dice thing are okay on their own because While they're both kind of random in the end, they do kind of even out.
Scott: Yeah And you know when you really look at those the card thing and the dice thing What they really.
Scott: if you start looking at the numbers they just abstract, you know, like look at risk, right?
Scott: Risk is not a game of you know, you're either dead or you didn't get hurt at all.
Scott: It's a. it's a game of slowly get hurt slowly get hurt slowly get hurt.
Scott: But it's also based on dice and while the odds of those dice might be a little different You know and drawn out over time and it makes the game feel different.
Scott: It really is just you roll the dice and someone wins and someone dies.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: this game is so Abstracted to make it so much more simple that it just does everything.
Scott: risk does in 20 minutes in one second.
Rym: but that also gives you the problem of you.
Rym: strategically you don't have many options because if there's one Unlucky roll suddenly your whole strategy is boned.
Rym: But because of the way the game is you have no you understand it's boned.
Rym: you have no way out You have no way to remaneuver.
Rym: You have no way to reconfigure.
Rym: It's just suddenly everything's done.
Rym: Yeah and it happened so quickly that every time I win I feel like any other intelligent person playing my side would have made the exact same decisions I made or Very close and the outcome would have been the same.
Rym: and every time I lost I felt like I was playing as best as I Could and anyone else sitting here would have played almost the exact same moves I played.
Rym: as long as they were reasonably intelligent.
Rym: and I think our friend Pete said it very well.
Rym: It was either Peter wide who said that this game is like playing Warhammer on a 12 by 12 grade In that you have units and you feel like oh I'd like to send my cavalry around those woods to hide and wait and then ambush while my archers come up from this side Or have some sort of even short-term minor strategy.
Rym: But because the hexes are so big and there are so few of them and because the rules of movement make it very difficult to move very far and Just in general you have very little actual maneuverability and in most cases any tactical movement you make is obvious.
Rym: There is obviously a place you want to be.
Rym: put that blue infantry on that hill put those archers in that wood Put those archers behind those two dwarves to make them double bold circle around back.
Rym: Like I never have to make any significant decisions.
Rym: It's just obvious what the best thing to do is on the back of the board.
Scott: if you flip it over there is another half of a map with small with slightly smaller hexes on it and They have been.
Scott: they're obviously going to make an expansion for like epic play that may or may not include options for more than two players playing at once and It you know will obviously be where you combine two boards together to make one bigger board with you know More hexes and more of that action.
Scott: But yet the compared to other games like what else?
Scott: what the games can I think of?
Scott: I mean just battle tech where there's a whole lot of hexes and you can move around a whole lot and there's all sorts of action Battle lore for as short as the game plays you don't really move very far in that short time.
Scott: yet You fight a lot.
Scott: It's a lot less moving and a lot more fighting and the fighting is dice rolling
Rym: Yeah, and those three things together the lack of actual tactical maneuverability the fact that the dice are very random and the fact that the cards Are also random leaves me feeling very unsatisfied when I play.
Rym: I mean, I I would much rather spend the extra time to play Shogun than to play a game like this because Shogun is while there is still randomness of the dice because other aspects of the game are more deterministic and because you have more maneuverability and Options but not so many options to be paralyzed the game feels so much more solid to me.
Scott: Yeah I think the reason that I still like this game even though I agree with pretty much everything that Rym said is Because when I play a war game, I'm not looking for like like.
Scott: I don't find war games fun for you know Military tactics and strategy because I don't know much about military tactics and strategy and I don't care I don't think about oh, I'll flank those guys or I'll go hook around those guys from behind.
Scott: I think ooh, I'm moving guys around and they're gonna fight You know, so when I play advance oars, you know, I just move my guys around.
Rym: that's why you always lose it.
Scott: advance wars Yeah, I mean if I'm if I want a game of.
Scott: you know strategies and and you know big thinking.
Scott: I go to my German games because those are the kind of games that have things that I enjoy thinking about and that I can Grasp and then I like that.
Scott: but when I'm playing a war game It's because I like to move guys around and I like to fight.
Rym: so I'm actually curious What other war games have you played?
Rym: axis and allies risk battle tag All right, so you played mostly bad war games.
Rym: shogun is okay, but shogun is more is not.
Rym: shogun is a special case.
Rym: It's a very interesting game.
Scott: Vance or is a couple of PC games.
Rym: advance wars is Pretty much the minimum level of tactical thought I can deal with.
Scott: Problem see the thing is it's like every time I think about battle or you know, it's like, uh, yeah They made these dice random, you know, and but you look at advance wars and say alright advance wars the gate the combat is deterministic There's.
Scott: no there's barely any randomness in the combat and you say wasn't wasn't wasn't wasn't wasn't Randomness in the combat of battle lore then that would mean that everyone would spend a lot more time thinking to a. you know Before you actually fight figure out you know What the best combat was.
Scott: see.
Rym: now to me the easy way to solve that is the same way you solve it in German games.
Rym: You just play a game where you've got to make a decision and if you can't think quickly enough and Reasonable, I give someone a minute, but you just don't let people sit there and I know I know that I know.
Scott: that's that I would agree.
Scott: However war games tend to be anti bevaca.
Scott: I mean you watch guys playing miniatures games and war games and places and For them it seems to be all about taking as much time on your turn as possible and thinking about all this stuff.
Rym: Whenever I played war games, I always forced myself to think quickly because in the real world I wouldn't have had the luxury to sit there for an hour Measuring the distances between all my troops to figure out if they're actually cohesive or if they're gonna be routed when those riders
Scott: come.
Scott: Yeah, that seems to be what war gamers are all about though And we're not.
Scott: that's the problem is that we're not war gamers, but sometimes we like to play a war game or two.
Scott: So it's very difficult because the war games that war gamers like with their crayons and you know They're little painted tanks and stuff like that We really can't get into very much.
Scott: or the games that are like, you know Really thick with historical accuracy while we might like the historical ness are very difficult for us to play.
Rym: See, I like them a lot more.
Rym: I mean I guess battle lore is just a little bit below my line.
Rym: if the hexes were have if there were twice as many hexes on the board and if the game had one more tactical element just one more like Troop formations like say my infantry could switch between a line a column and a square Anything like that?
Rym: I think that would be enough to make this game bearable to me.
Scott: Yeah, it does.
Scott: I do a good.
Scott: they just aren't enough decisions to make and often like, you know When you have a decision that you can make like oh, should I do this or do that?
Scott: It's usually not one or the other.
Scott: it's usually either yes or no and the answer is almost always yes Because you should do whatever you can to get ahead because the game is gonna be over soon.
Rym: do something Yeah, but also one time I played and there was nothing I could do about it.
Rym: I just got dicked by the cards and While I think the cards are a cool mechanic and I'm not saying we should change that.
Rym: It was just the fact that I drew pretty much no useful cards And in fact, I drew cards that I couldn't use effectively at all for the first like seven turns of one battle.
Scott: Yeah, I do like the cards a lot But I do feel like they could have made this card deck like bigger more varied and more kind of balanced.
Scott: You know, it's like alright, I can understand.
Scott: you have this card.
Scott: This is Scout, you know move one unit on the left All right But you also Get to draw two and keep one instead of just drawing one at the end of your turn.
Scott: that that seems pretty.
Scott: that's a nice Balance.
Scott: you move less units which kind of sucks But you get an advantage and now you're gonna have a better chance of getting the cards you want next time.
Rym: now Consider that can just imagine this because this is similar to a variant I came up with as a kid for a battle system Which was you battle system.
Scott: I just looked up.
Scott: is that is the D&D thing?
Scott: It's not what you're thinking of.
Scott: You're thinking I think battle masters battle masters.
Rym: I confused the two because I played battle system with pieces of cardboard.
Scott: I'm gonna look up battle masters right now and battle masters.
Rym: I just played all the time somewhat incorrectly because we just mess all the units up and have a big brawl.
Rym: But the variant I came up with was the difference between that game and this game was that instead of Each person having a hand of five cards you shuffle this deck that has movement cards for both sides And then you draw them one by one so you don't even know what order your units are gonna come up in.
Rym: What if you had a drafting mechanism where you have a hand of cards and you are allowed to put X of them into the?
Rym: Communal deck?
Rym: the other person is allowed to put X of them into the communal deck.
Rym: you shuffle them and then bring them up One-by-one.
Rym: so now you have a race condition.
Rym: Now you have a situation where you're choosing What situation you want to put yourself into or what options you want to give yourself?
Rym: But due to the fog of war you can't determine the order in which they will take place.
Scott: Yeah, they're like the other.
Scott: like I was gonna say you have the scout card, okay on its own It seems balanced, but then you compare it to some of the other cards in the deck such as move to in each sector.
Scott: Okay, so that's not really even if you know you draw one card and it allows you to move one unit And another card may be like there'll be a card in there that says move to on the left.
Scott: There's also a card in there.
Scott: This is move to on the left to in the middle and two on the right.
Scott: So it's like how is that if someone draws the cards that let them move a lot of units and the other guy gets a car Get all the cards that let him move very few.
Rym: last game We play.
Scott: it'll be very easy for the person who can move a lot of units to keep their units in tight formation and Because the only units that you can order can attack I mean, let's say I get all threes and Rym gets all twos I can attack him three times a turn and he can attack me two times a turn.
Rym: Well in the last game we played my starting hand of five and I had a bunch of cavalry and a bunch of good archers.
Rym: I had two dark in the skies two mounted charges and a center command.
Rym: That was like like I had every good card in my hand right then and there and I just trounced all over Scott And there was nothing he could do.
Rym: there was no amount of skill on my part.
Rym: It was just the fact that I not only did I start with that hand But I drew nothing but amazing cards for the whole game.
Rym: I couldn't have cheated to do that.
Scott: Well, yeah it's like I like the mechanic of not having to deal with every unit every turn and having some sort of deck of cards that You know you play a card and that's what you do this turn.
Scott: You know the card dictates what you're allowed to do with your units.
Scott: That's cool.
Scott: But if you're gonna do that Then you can't make it to where there are so few cards that you can be stiffed and you know that the odds of being Stiffed are pretty good.
Scott: It has to be such that No matter which cards you get by playing the correct ones and using them to their fullest ability You can win and that under almost, you know, almost not a hundred percent because that's not possible.
Scott: But almost under no condition will the best player in the world lose to a ten-year-old kid because he drew crap cards.
Rym: Still I think in the end the best way to mitigate the problems I see with this game which are numerous would simply be to add one more tactical element.
Rym: and Granted we haven't talked about lore.
Rym: Lore is basically the super co powers from advanced wars and it's in this game.
Scott: that's really what the difference is in this game.
Scott: because Well as you described the game so far That's the same.
Scott: it's basically the same as memoir 44 and all the other command and colors games.
Scott: What battle lore adds is the goblins and the giant spiders and the lore which is the magic action And it does as Rym said work just like the co powers from advanced wars.
Rym: but even that added in does not add any tactical thought of any depth because again, it's obvious what spell to cast and The scenarios at least for now give you your war council.
Rym: So there isn't even the drafting of deciding your war council.
Scott: Well, you do in the later adventures in the adventure book.
Scott: You do decide your war council.
Scott: They'll give you like X levels and you can Allocate them to your lore council, however you want.
Rym: Yeah, that's the only thing we haven't played with yet.
Rym: However, I don't think that that level of drafting is going to have any substantial effect.
Scott: Yeah, it does seem like the level of your people in your war council doesn't really matter that much.
Scott: It's like, you know for some of them it matters a little bit like the cleric I've heard and for the command it matters a lot.
Scott: but it seems like you're pretty much choosing like.
Scott: well, I have a wizard and thus my Any wizard.
Scott: spells be better?
Rym: Go get a rogue and thus any road as the added element of the way they Determine how many of each card are in the deck to be drawn is based on the level.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: so if you know the deck of magic spells then you gay.
Scott: Okay, I really want to have the rogue spells in this game.
Scott: So I'm gonna put levels into rogues.
Scott: So there's more rogue cards in the deck, you know, and I guess that's just a matter of knowing the deck.
Scott: But I don't think it really would have a big effect on the game.
Scott: It's just choices of your CEO power.
Rym: as the game stands I feel like between two reasonably intelligent people.
Rym: the deciding factor and who wins will more often than not be luck because unless one person makes a mistake or isn't smart enough or just doesn't understand how the game works on a fundamental level or just isn't paying attention to which cards have already been played or Which side an opponent's been favoring or you know all those little things that you just got to pay attention to in a game like this.
Rym: There's not so much to the game.
Rym: And I think if they added just one more tactical element and I'm gonna think long and hard and see if I can just write That expansion to make the game the end of game.
Rym: I want the problem is I need a a more dense hex grid.
Scott: Yeah I mean there is the back of the board and they are going to release Another board to go with it and to make a double board.
Scott: and who knows what will come of that in the end.
Scott: But it'll definitely come out sometime and if battle lore is still interesting to us May or may not get it depending on the price.
Rym: if you're expecting a hardcore war game give this a pass at least for now.
Scott: Yes, if you like only games where you have to you know Where there's some strategic thinking the smartest guy wins and any other kind of game pisses you off.
Scott: Don't buy this game.
Rym: if you've got 10 to 15 year old kids or nephews and they're at all interested in board gaming They'll probably eat this right up.
Scott: Yeah, get this instead of heroscape which is cost a lot more money and is not as good.
Rym: not as good or as fun.
Scott: Yeah, but if you just like moving guys around and fighting and you know You're the kind of person who likes to play risk But it takes so long and after the first hour You're no longer having fun and you just want to give up.
Scott: but and you like fantasy settings battle lore might be what you want because you get the same fun you get in the first hour of risk with the about the same level of thinking and After the first hour you're done it the game's over so you don't have to cry about the other three hours of playing risk.
Scott: That aren't fun.
Rym: Yep However, the front row crew we were talking about it and most of us agree that we would rather have played Shogun Despite the fact that it takes three hours.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is like the in Shogun for me like I like it a lot But it's only fun for me in the first hour and then it's really painful.
Rym: That's like is by the.
Scott: It's like a bigger graph.
Scott: It's like the beginning hour of Shogun is way fun and then it goes way down to be incredibly painful.
Rym: I think part of that is because by the second and a half hour You've got one army holed up in your fortress on Kyushu hiding from about the massive Ronin armies of me and Pete.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: I mean, I've done okay at Shogun in the past.
Rym: You have we all have Shogun's.
Rym: a great game Yeah, but it's still.
Scott: it's like battle or is just isn't?
Scott: you know, it's fun for an hour.
Scott: if you like that sort of thing, you may or may not and Then it's over.
Rym: Yeah, I'll say that I haven't enjoyed it really at all yet but I keep playing it because I want to make sure I'm not missing something and I want to figure the game out enough to know exactly What point it is?
Rym: Where I go from having fun to not having fun and make an expansion that fixes it.
Scott: because I'm not gonna shit talk because at The very least if you buy battle or this game comes with a lot of stuff There's a lot of stuff in there and it's really easy to change.
Scott: I mean they give you access to this adventure editor online and they pick like people's adventures to be like super like Official adventures and stuff.
Scott: So if you're really like customizing games, but you don't want to collect games.
Scott: There's also that aspect to it.
Scott: That's pretty fun.
Scott: All right, so that's battle or yep.
Rym: So I guess.
Rym: last and certainly not least just because we haven't mentioned it any day other than Wednesday I think but since we're doing the video game room, it's probably relevant.
Scott: Ah,
Rym: if any of you are headed to Katsucon next month
Scott: If you live anywhere near Washington DC or you can get to Washington DC with you know effort
Rym: Yes, well Katsucon is a great anime convention But in addition to that we are going to be hanging out in the video game room MCing running tournaments doing game shows and generally having an awesome party time for the entire weekend at the con.
Scott: Yes, so if you want to come see us and perhaps get some stuff.
Scott: I can't promise that though.
Rym: Yeah, we may have the first tiny bit of swag or swag depending on whether generous We're feeling ready by Katsucon and if nothing else we'll be running some tournaments that may or may not have some prizes.
Scott: Yep, so come to Katsucon see us in the video game room Participate in our awesome.
Rym: Yeah, we might even bring you on the show.
Rym: We'll have all our equipment there.
Rym: We'll basically be doing what those wacky radio guys do live outside of bars.
Rym: No only without the wacky radio guys or the bars.
Rym: It'll just be live.
Rym: and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333.
Scott: 1 5 3 7.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.