Scott: It's Tuesday November 20th.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm exhausted and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We make fun of the game of life.
Scott: No the other game of life.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: You know one of the worst things in the world is when you're going on like this someone for CD poop and torches you do Or something horrible like that.
Rym: go no It's very much when you're gonna go on vacation and everyone else in your house is going on vacation in a few days.
Rym: So you're running low on food in the house But you don't want to go grocery shopping because you're either gonna have to go again as soon as you get back.
Rym: Are you gonna buy stuff that's gonna go bad as a result?
Rym: There's not much food left.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Scott: I mean I go down there and there's some food, but it's like I could defrost something.
Scott: But it takes a while to defrost and by the time it defrost will all be gone, and then it'll go bad.
Rym: So I think the real problem is that there's plenty of food just got.
Rym: won't eat any of it.
Rym: He doesn't like ham He doesn't like sausage doesn't like crab.
Scott: There's plenty of food like.
Scott: what the thing is you seem to like?
Scott: Just have these black all you the only food You see is like the food that I don't eat because all the food you'll eat is frozen and won't thought before I go to The grocery store will come home, and you'll be like.
Scott: I'll be like alright.
Scott: You know the next day I'll be like what are we?
Scott: you'll be like oh, there's only stuff You don't like and you act like I don't eat any food.
Rym: well No, cuz after we get back from the grocery store We usually eat you know things you'll eat like chicken and beef But then we eat all the chicken and beef and the rest of its frozen.
Scott: So you know that there's that game that Psychonauts game that people.
Scott: it's one of those games where everyone's like oh It's the best game ever but apparently nobody bought it.
Rym: well Like five people say it's the best game ever because no one else has ever heard of it.
Scott: No, lots of people say it's the best.
Rym: I wouldn't say that many people compared to how many people play games.
Scott: Very well talking about like.
Scott: you know the games.
Scott: You know journalism.
Scott: if you go to any like you know blog of video games or any magazine of video games You know.
Rym: as for an opinion of Psychonauts There's probably more blogs about World of Warcraft than there are about people than there are people who know about Psychonauts.
Scott: Probably what I'm talking about is you know in terms of the it's a critically acclaimed game That did not sell well and is not popular and despite critics Continuing to bring it up and continuing to clamor for you know respect for this game that no one played and very few people bought.
Scott: You know it it's yeah anyway, so the game now you can get it for free.
Rym: Will it just work on my computer?
Scott: it works on I guess Windows PCs.
Scott: It's.
Scott: you know it's those game tap people.
Scott: they let you like pay a monthly fee to like get all these games on their service.
Scott: It's from them, but you can get it for free without paying for the monthly service supposedly, so That's all I know about it, but I assume it's the whole game for free.
Scott: I played the demo of this game and It's sort of a rough-around-the-edges platform 3d platform game.
Scott: But the thing it that makes the game special is like all the plot and the character designs and the levels.
Rym: wait wait wait.
Scott: So it's not a great game, but I never said I thought it was a great game.
Scott: Aha, I said it was critically acclaimed.
Scott: many people keep talking about how.
Scott: it's some great game, and they you know They want it real bad.
Scott: It's sort of like how they really want.
Scott: and you know earth bounds in the u.s.. And they won't bring it.
Scott: It's sort of like hey, you'll release this game in the u.s.. And no one bought it.
Scott: fix it.
Rym: and you know It's one of those situations People yell about how a game is so great that no one bought except I don't know I mean even the zero punctuation guy basically said yeah this game was great But it's not actually that great to play.
Rym: It's not actually that good of a game.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what I figure the demo was fun enough for however many minutes.
Scott: I played it maybe 15 minutes.
Rym: I've never played a single second of that game.
Scott: Yeah, but if you need a video game to play and either you're poor Or maybe you already beat all the video games that have come out or are coming out and you sit in there you say man I want to play a video game, and I don't have a video game to play.
Rym: That should never happen to you.
Rym: There are already How many games you have to play to run out of games to play now.
Scott: well imagine if you're like a college student and?
Scott: You had a lot of money, but you didn't have anything to do.
Rym: I didn't care.
Rym: I played tribes or counter-strike.
Rym: Those games alone were enough to amuse me in my idle single hours pretty much continuously.
Rym: I know time I was ever bored was when other people were around and I didn't feel like playing a one-guy game.
Rym: And I consider counter-strike to be a single-player game because there aren't actually humans playing with you.
Scott: Yeah, the point is is that is what a good free game.
Rym: Yeah, well I thought we just agreed that it wasn't good.
Rym: It was only critically acclaimed.
Rym: Well.
Scott: It's good It's just not.
Scott: it's not super amazing.
Rym: How good is it better than I don't know.
Rym: Mario 2?
Rym: Yeah, is it better than Mario 64.
Scott: Yeah, maybe not.
Rym: is it better than doom - he depends I could just go play doom - right now you already played doom - though.
Rym: Yeah, but you know what really good for something new.
Rym: I've never gotten sick of doom - well.
Rym: That's you doom I got a little sick of.
Rym: but doom - I played slightly less even though it was better.
Rym: So I feel like I could play through it a few more times.
Scott: All right you got a news over there.
Rym: Well, I tried to go buy a second DS light today, and I failed at this before.
Scott: I want to buy a DS light, but you know what all the colors suck, but wait There's one good color gold that's coming out.
Scott: Oh, but it comes with phantom hourglass, which I already own.
Rym: so what the fuck I point out that I care more about.
Rym: I don't know the system And how good it is and useful and practical is.
Rym: then what color the plastic on the outside is?
Scott: I'm not getting the Like the pink one all right.
Scott: It's not gonna happen.
Scott: Well.
Rym: There's a black one.
Rym: It's perfectly fine.
Scott: No, I need.
Scott: I need the silver one or the green one or something.
Rym: so you're saying that Aesthetics matter that the look of your DS Was gonna force you to wait and then pay the same amount later that you would have paid now for a clearly superior product.
Scott: Well, you know if I already have a DS fat that works right I?
Scott: Probably shouldn't buy a DS light in the first place.
Scott: well So if I'm gonna buy one to replace if I'm gonna buy a thing to replace a working thing I Might as well wait for one.
Scott: That's perfect.
Scott: It's not unless like the green one costs more or the silver one costs more.
Rym: apparently the gold one does cost more.
Scott: Hey, it does it you notice.
Scott: I'm not buying it I'm just.
Rym: I find it funny that you of all people now.
Rym: Oh, I gotta wait for the special colored DS.
Rym: I can't just use the normal DS.
Scott: No, you know given a choice where it's equal cost for the same thing gonna choose what it's not a color.
Scott: You're forgetting the the cost of an action the fact that every day is no cost of an action because I have a DS fat That works.
Rym: if you ever use a DS light You'll realize that the cost of an action is the fact that the DS fat looks like crap compared to the DS light.
Scott: I'm using DS light.
Scott: It's better, but it's not so much better that it's hurting me.
Rym: I'm so much better than it is hurt.
Rym: I can't play on a DS fat anymore.
Scott: The Phoenix right through the DS fat.
Rym: it was Wasted that game on a fat with an old screen.
Scott: Whatever you crazy piece like.
Rym: the worst thing you could do No, it's not.
Scott: the worst thing I could do would be to not play Phoenix, right?
Scott: Which is what you did.
Rym: Well, I'll be honest.
Rym: I liked Phoenix right.
Rym: one Phoenix right - was more of the same but the puzzles weren't as fun and I cared less about the story.
Rym: Thanks, right three is better than - it better be because I'm not that excited about it.
Scott: I'll be honest I think you just got to get past where you are in two to get to the good part.
Rym: Well part of it too is I started noticing I think it was more so in the second one than the first one that They I mean they did localize the living hell out of that game understandably But I really think that they didn't change.
Rym: they just changed the words.
Rym: and they didn't change the facial expressions because People's facial expressions often do not match what they're saying at all.
Scott: and three they match up I think a little better better than two.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see Plus and two.
Scott: I didn't really notice them not matching up.
Rym: So but yeah, I take the six train down and I go to the game stop at 34th Street and I think alright I'm gonna go grab two copies of worms and I'm gonna grab a new DS light.
Scott: Did you order the worms in Amazon yesterday?
Scott: Not yet?
Rym: Oh, it doesn't matter when it comes if it doesn't come before I go on a trip.
Scott: Okay, that's true I'll try.
Scott: maybe I'll try to get at the no way.
Scott: I'm not going any malls.
Scott: forget that.
Scott: I was thinking I go to the mall next.
Scott: my parents Like wait a minute now.
Rym: my news story ostensibly Is that the Wii is selling like crazy fuck and Nintendo can't keep up and there's shortages worldwide like always.
Rym: and the reason for that Is pretty simply.
Scott: they're making 1.8 million and the demand is higher than that.
Scott: Well, it's all there is to it.
Rym: I think the reason the demand is so high is that the Wii was kind of this new thing last season.
Rym: now It's established.
Rym: it's known.
Rym: people out there even you know, normal muggles don't play video games so much.
Rym: They know what the Wii is.
Rym: It's that Nintendo thing that everybody likes and everybody wanted.
Rym: there's a big rush for it last year.
Rym: Oh Shit, it's Christmas.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: I don't have a gift for little Billy.
Rym: I should get him that we thing.
Rym: and every parent who doesn't already own a Wii is buying a Wii for Billy and There's a lot more than 1.8 million of them per month.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I mean think about it.
Scott: They're gonna sell.
Scott: what two points.
Scott: There's two months left.
Scott: two point six million wheeze.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: How many people are in this country?
Rym: How many of them want wheeze and don't already have them more than two point six million?
Rym: But I didn't really think about that as news.
Rym: I mean, oh Nintendo's kicking everyone's ass again.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Well money wise maybe not online content wise but I digress.
Rym: So I go to this GameStop and now I expected a line.
Rym: There's always a line not just that a lot GameStop has.
Scott: the biggest lines of any GameStop thing is every GameStop.
Rym: I've realized now that of the last like six times.
Rym: I've gone into any GameStop anywhere in this country.
Rym: I have walked out having put down the thing I was going to purchase and left in disgust because the line just didn't move well except for the one in Baltimore.
Scott: Did I buy something there?
Scott: I don't remember if you bought anything there, but it was a pleasant experience.
Rym: It was.
Rym: but I wanted to buy something and I think I remember failing.
Scott: what did you want to buy?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: every time I go to a GameStop.
Rym: There's some old used game I want to buy but I always go walk up to the counter and there's always two people two employees.
Rym: One of them is dealing with the kid who's selling like every video game He's owning and the other one should stand there not doing anything and I usually go god Damn it after ten minutes put my thing down and walk away.
Scott: Yeah, that happened one time pretty badly.
Rym: Well that happened to me when I went to the GameStop in Times Square not too long ago.
Rym: Well, not not Rockefeller But it close enough.
Rym: and it happened to me again when I went to 34th Street Because there was one dude man in the line that went out the door.
Rym: even though worms was cheaper It was like 28 bucks for some reason.
Rym: I Wasn't gonna stand in line for an hour and change.
Scott: This is why I've been buying all my video games on Amazon.
Scott: The only problem with buying video games on Amazon is that they might come like a few days after the game comes out.
Scott: So you're not gonna get the game on the release date, but you just go online.
Scott: You click your mouse and then the game shows up at your door with no trouble.
Scott: You know what doesn't get better than that.
Rym: release date only mattered when I thought that I would care about the online offerings and Now that Nintendo Wi-Fi is pretty much useless Doesn't matter if I own the game the day it comes out or not.
Scott: the only game that I care about getting it on the release date is of course the Smash Brothers which I Ordered from EB world calm or which is you know, guess is the same as GameStop calm.
Scott: so we'll see if they can actually deliver the game like the day after the release date.
Scott: or if Yeah, we'll see what happens with that.
Rym: I think I'll live if I don't get that game right away.
Scott: Yeah, I just figured you know cuz Amazon was back in before the game got delayed.
Scott: Amazon's estimated ship date for the game was like a month after it was supposed to come out So I ordered it from the other site instead.
Rym: But the all this comes together in that I have a tradition not really tradition more of a One of those things that allows you to live your life in a way that is better.
Rym: It's kind of like you have a rule and you might forget why you had the rule.
Rym: But anytime you break that rule you suddenly remember why that rules.
Rym: they're like.
Rym: don't pet the weird animals at the zoo Don't go poke a hippo, especially if it's angry, especially if it's a hippo hungry hungry.
Rym: but When I went to that GameStop, I realized that I had vowed long ago that from the end of September until the middle of January I will go nowhere near a retail establishment unless I am forced to because except the grocery store.
Rym: Yeah, I consider that necessary food and not so much retail.
Scott: Yeah, it counts as retail.
Scott: I guess not wholesale.
Rym: I don't think many people count that as retail anyway, and yeah, I made that mistake.
Rym: I went to that goddamn GameStop, you know how long it took me to fight my way into the door let alone to fight my way back out let
Scott: alone even get in
Rym: near the place because all the people who were shopping for Christmas and Once Thanksgiving comes wealth God, I'm just not even to get in my car.
Scott: Yeah I just don't go to stores in the winter until you know the worst January around here.
Rym: you pretty much can't drive north because once Thanksgiving goes by The road that goes by the mall is pretty much a sea of people trying and failing to get into the mall until January.
Scott: Yep, so, you know I went and I it since I am a dad.
Rym: What was that?
Scott: Yeah near my work.
Scott: There's some stores I can go to.
Scott: so like I needed a winter hat So I just walked to the EMS near my work at like 10 and I bought a winter hat, you know.
Scott: So I have a way to get things if I need them, but you could have bought it online.
Scott: A winter head.
Scott: Yeah where?
Scott: and the shipping?
Rym: Amazon?
Rym: the shipping's practically nothing.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'd rather like try the head on.
Scott: it was $15.
Rym: winter heads all fit the same.
Scott: No, they don't.
Scott: Yeah different sizes.
Rym: There's three sizes little kid normal and big head.
Scott: No, there's different side.
Scott: No, there aren't.
Rym: they're all the same.
Rym: Wint knit like winter hats are all identical except that mine had a Zelda on it.
Scott: Well, the ones on the internet here more expensive.
Scott: So yeah military Gore-tex cap black 20 bucks.
Rym: get the one like George stands ahead.
Scott: What kind of do you have?
Rym: Yeah that big Russian thing.
Scott: No, you know how much those cost?
Scott: Yes, like a zillion dollars There's a real full wall a real fur on the side of those things.
Rym: That's not wool fur.
Scott: It's for animals.
Rym: Anyway things of the day.
Rym: Surprisingly I had not actually seen this before.
Rym: It's a bunch of deleted scenes from the life of Brian.
Scott: Oh you took my future thing today.
Scott: It's gonna use that.
Rym: I said I was using it.
Rym: No, yes But yeah, the one thing I can say is that whenever there are deleted scenes especially from Monty Python stuff They're usually not that funny whenever this deleted scenes from anything.
Scott: There's usually a reason that they were deleted.
Rym: They're two times either it was deleted because it wasn't that good or it was deleted because of censoring.
Rym: Yeah in the case of the latter.
Rym: It's usually hilarious.
Scott: Usually sometimes it's deleted for other reasons though.
Scott: Like just they ran out of time in the episodes.
Scott: They took out the least funny joke, but least funny joke is still pretty funny.
Scott: that could happen.
Rym: Yeah more and more.
Rym: I feel like a lot of movies purposefully have deleted scenes just so they can put them in the extras.
Scott: Yeah, I think they're purposefully like, you know, they people just come up with scenes and they film them all and then in editing You know some of them they just don't put in.
Scott: or you know They know they're filming more scenes and then they then they're gonna put in the movie in the first place.
Rym: yeah, but these scenes are all about.
Rym: it looks like semi-nazi but ottoman style German suicide soldier extravaganza.
Rym: It's just a bunch more with those guys.
Scott: Yeah, it's those guys.
Rym: It's pretty funny like the part at the end there It's funnier than the deleted scene from Bonnie Python and the Holy Grail Which no it was never actually filmed or at least if it was.
Rym: we don't have any footage of it.
Rym: I've seen an animated version of it where people did the voices and I have the script for it, but it's not that funny.
Scott: No, it's really not.
Rym: I think the only good joke in that at all was there's a bunch of archers that only have one leg and where they're marching They go left left Left.
Scott: I wonder how they were gonna film that.
Scott: That's probably why I didn't make it into the movie.
Scott: Yeah They gotta have all those one-legged guys hopping.
Rym: actually what's really weird.
Rym: if you ever read the original screenplay like the early treatment of Monty Python and the Holy Grail It's a totally different movie.
Scott: Well, you know if you if you have a plan to make a movie and you go to make that it ends with God not Knowing how to drive an automatic.
Scott: Yeah But I mean if you make if you make a plan to make a movie and you go to make that movie you'll end Up with something pretty close to the plan.
Scott: if you got a plan to make a movie and you get drunk and then try To make that movie.
Scott: It's gonna be nothing like the plan and you know what they did.
Scott: the latter.
Rym: Ah Graham Chapman We hardly knew ye.
Scott: All right So I can do my thing of the day.
Rym: I guess.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, we were talking about Phoenix Wright before right?
Scott: We were yep You like you like Phoenix, right?
Rym: I think I made my statement earlier about that.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: Well, it's pretty funny I like those Phoenix wrongs until they got stupid.
Scott: Yeah, well imagine if you took the lolcats Which are pretty amusing and the Phoenix right and you combine them and you had a great quantity and varying quality.
Rym: I See what you did there.
Scott: Here's a gallery of Phoenix Wright lolcats.
Scott: and Well, some of them are lol and some of them are epic lol.
Scott: and some of them are Oh.
Rym: and I should point out because Scott didn't tell me until I saw one spoilers for the love of fucking God spoilers.
Scott: Yeah, some of these are pretty spoiler epic Like someone will say I'm in your blank blank in your blank and that's like the what happens at the end of one of the mystery Cases or whatever.
Rym: now granted one of those spoilers that I actually knew what happened in was uh, hilarious.
Scott: Shall we say yeah, some of them aren't spoilers to you know, some of them are miss spoilers But if you look at all these and you haven't played all the Phoenix rights, you're good.
Scott: Well, there's no spoilers I guess for Phoenix.
Scott: right for but the spoilers for one two and three, but that's it.
Scott: So yeah Phoenix Wright fan, you owe it to yourself to look at these here and get some lol's.
Rym: So back at Connecticut last year, which is an awesome con you can pretty much guarantee.
Rym: We'll be guests again this year, but we did a panel on German board gaming and board games in general and we got a guy in the audience who Really?
Scott: Hayes a hassler.
Rym: No, I was gonna.
Rym: he really wanted us to talk about American board games and we shouldn't you know slight the American efforts in the field of board gaming because American efforts are just as valid and important to the the medium of board gaming as the German and French efforts.
Rym: So I thought it was about time for us to talk about an American board game.
Scott: Well, actually we were gonna talk about an extremely German game But since we only ever played it once or twice I decided to not do that and do something else.
Rym: Oh you decided That's right.
Scott: I decided it was my idea.
Rym: I actually know.
Rym: I think the reason I decided not to do that was that I want to have Alex on board for that show.
Rym: since He has as much experience as me which is twice as much as you and I figure between the three of us We I think we should just play more before we do that show.
Rym: yeah, the real issue there is just that we actually came to an epiphany and realized that we had beaten and become dissatisfied with almost every board game we had ever owned and We realized there's only two directions to go that game which is pretty much the last bastion of fiddling with abstract cubes and Then the other direction which is all the way abstract and just playing.
Rym: go Maybe but anyway, well my go boards in the mail.
Scott: So yeah, so we're gonna.
Scott: today We're gonna talk about an American board game that when I was a kid I liked it a lot and now I hate it to death.
Rym: I can say this when I was a little kid I liked it in terms of playing it with the family.
Rym: But at the same time I often angered my family because I would pretty much constantly throughout the game Whenever anyone and in any way insinuated that them doing better or worse than anyone else had anything to do with skill I would begin the argument that I always began which was we'd might as well just flip a coin.
Rym: This game has about as much skill as flipping a coin.
Rym: In fact, I could probably affect the outcome of a coin flip more so than I can.
Rym: the outcome of this game and My family would always say I was just a curmudgeon who couldn't just lighten up and enjoy a fun board game with the family.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We're talking about probably one of the more Derided yet well-known games in America and that is the game of life.
Scott: and we're not talking about you know, the the mathematical Game of life, you know that computer science students will study.
Rym: that game is awesome.
Scott: That is an awesome game.
Scott: That's not really a game.
Scott: You can play so much, but you can.
Scott: yeah, you can.
Rym: There is a game that is based in that game.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: It's kind of like that 7-up spot game.
Scott: Yeah, but you know if you want to learn about that game of life I suggest you go ask Google about it or wait for us to do a show about it or something.
Rym: No We're talking about a game that is designed to teach children a few important things about life.
Rym: Like for example, if you don't go to college You're gonna lose - the more kids you have the more money you'll have.
Rym: Not true In the game, it's true.
Rym: It's patently true.
Rym: three life insurance will always pay out for car insurance.
Rym: We'll never pay out normal fire insurance.
Rym: I don't even know why that was in the game.
Scott: and right before you're ready to retire You've got one shot to make it big like super big and if you fail, you'll be super poor.
Rym: There's pretty much two options in life Millionaire tycoon or Philosopher.
Rym: I like how philosophers?
Scott: Well, no, this millionaire is the default millionaire.
Scott: tycoon is the super lucky and philosopher is the not as the sucky I love.
Rym: I love a game that teaches you that philosopher means you lost.
Rym: Yeah, of course I guess if money is the game that's probably true.
Scott: All right, so the game of life.
Scott: Here's how this game works.
Rym: Everyone has a car and in that car you put yourself now it has to be there's a little pink Phallus for a man and a little above well for a woman, I guess Blue phallus for a man, I guess the pink phallus is to represent Rym.
Rym: They're these little Peggy things and they stick in the car.
Scott: But and so you drive your car and the fur and basically the way the game works is you spin this spinner Which is numbers one to ten and then you move that many spaces.
Scott: and if there's a fork in the road you can choose which way to go.
Scott: and every time you pass a payday spot you get your salary.
Scott: and If you land on a payday spot, I think you get your salary and a card.
Scott: whatever this is cards You can ignore.
Scott: and if there's a fork in the road, you can choose which way to go.
Scott: The game is Candyland plus money pretty much and I guess why I liked it when I was a kid.
Scott: Let's start with that.
Scott: when I was a kid I liked it because you actually got to choose which way you were gonna go.
Scott: So it felt like you were making some decisions.
Scott: see now.
Rym: Here's the real issue.
Rym: my family Decided when I was a kid that it was cheating to count ahead at a fork to figure out where you'd land.
Scott: I was bullshit.
Rym: She was the best.
Scott: everyone.
Scott: everyone can count whatever they way they want.
Rym: So they made a rule you can't count and I just counted.
Rym: and as a result, I don't think any of them did.
Rym: I don't think anyone else cheated but me.
Rym: So as a result, I tend I wasn't cheating.
Scott: you're allowed to count.
Scott: Yeah, sort of the pull.
Rym: the other thing was I could spin the spinner to whatever number I wanted But that was so.
Scott: that's because the spinner suck.
Scott: They should use a d10.
Scott: Anyway there yeah, and then see you move the number of space on the spinner.
Scott: you land on a space and you do what the space says and Eventually you get to the end of the game.
Scott: So why else did I like it when I was a kid?
Scott: the other reason I liked it was because in monopoly what the biggest dollar bill was like 500 right in The game of life.
Scott: The smallest bill is a thousand and you can get the biggest one was a hundred thousand.
Scott: They were whites.
Scott: Yeah, it was like you had mad monies playing this game and it felt really good.
Scott: We're a little kid.
Scott: Just have like a zillion dollars.
Scott: You're like, oh man, look how much money I got.
Rym: You can also get promissory notes and go into debt.
Scott: Yeah if you end a debt they gave you these $20,000 promissory notes and it was like you had to pay them back.
Scott: and it was.
Scott: it really sucked if you got him.
Scott: But I always sort of wanted him because they sat there unused because no one was ever bad enough to actually get them bad enough.
Rym: That that is that you can't be bad at that game there.
Rym: You cannot make poor decisions.
Rym: The only decision you can make that's bad is skipping college.
Scott: Yep, right at the beginning of the game Oh and buying fire insurance?
Scott: Yeah, right at the beginning of the game you can.
Scott: you know There's a little this.
Scott: you make a few spaces But then you can choose to go right or left.
Scott: if you go, right?
Scott: You have to go through a lot of spaces and it's gonna take you a lot longer.
Scott: if you go left You can run through really quickly to sort of you know Get ahead of everyone and sort of beat the game faster, which has advantages.
Scott: But you'll only get like a high school diploma if you go that way and your salary will be shit if you go the long Way, you have a chance of landing on.
Scott: you know Different degrees in from college and you could land on like doctor and your payday will be like 40,000.
Scott: And I think if you go to high school your payday is like 16,000.
Scott: So you're gonna end the game with almost no money if you do the high school thing.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, there was also.
Rym: I mean going ahead had the one advantage in that there was the bridge and the first dude to cross The bridge.
Rym: that was always a big deal when you're playing it as a kid.
Rym: Oh shit the bridge.
Rym: Everyone across after had to pay a toll to whoever crossed at first.
Scott: Yeah, the bridge is pretty close to the end of the game.
Rym: Though yeah, it just meant you got a bunch of money from everyone.
Scott: Yep The other.
Scott: the other thing in the game that you can do is some spaces you land on.
Scott: well some spaces you pass Allow you to buy insurance and it's pretty much you can choose yes or no for auto Yes and no for life yes and no for fire and all they do is During the game you might land on a space that says hey if you've got insurance do this if you don't have insurance do this and it's usually good if you have insurance and bad if you don't and So it costs money to buy the insurance.
Scott: you have to decide, you know What are the odds that I'm gonna need this insurance?
Scott: Is it gonna make a profit for me in the long run and at the end of the game?
Scott: if you still have?
Scott: because sometimes?
Scott: You might lose your insurance if you still have insurance at the end of the game some of them you can turn into money Like you can turn your life insurance into money at the end of the game.
Scott: What else that?
Scott: the only other thing in the game?
Scott: Is that some spaces you land on give you children and wives and kids and all that stuff and you fill up your car with?
Scott: People besides yourself and the more people you have the more money you get.
Scott: so you want to get lots of people And that's the whole game.
Rym: For some reason this game has kind of legendary iconic status in the United States.
Rym: Everyone's played it a lot of people like it a lot even people who are not six years old which kind of surprises.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: it's like one of those big games in this country You know, it's very historic like Monopoly Scrabble the game of life Like these are like big, you know, very big parts of like Americana in a way these games.
Rym: but the game now I mean not only was it not a game I mean it was about the same level as candy land, but it went once every land with one step further.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: But the step further it went was that every choice you made there was the Obviously clearly superior choice and the stupid choice the.
Rym: I want to lose this game choice.
Rym: There was no middle ground.
Rym: There was no debate.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't like.
Scott: huh, man You know if I go around the board this way I might become a doctor and at least I'm gonna be like, you know a teacher make some money.
Scott: if I go this way Broke-ass poor and even though I might have a chance of getting to the game for end faster That's not gonna make up for the money.
Scott: I'm gonna lose.
Scott: there is no reason to ever skip college ever.
Scott: That's the dumb it.
Scott: You just lose if you do that unless everyone does that or so Why would you do that?
Rym: life insurance cost pretty much nothing at the end of the game?
Rym: I believe it's worth a hundred thousand.
Scott: It's worth a lot of money at the end of the game.
Scott: There's no reason not to buy life insurance.
Scott: I mean Even if it never pays off on any spot Even if you land on every spot on the board.
Scott: that says haha life insurance you lose.
Scott: If you still hold on to at the end of the game, you're okay.
Scott: The only way it can fuck you is if you buy it and you happen to land on like the one space.
Scott: that says lose Your life insurance.
Rym: now, not only was the game completely random But they added this extra fuck you at the end where you see, you know, we talked earlier.
Rym: You can win or you can double win.
Rym: tycoon win.
Rym: Mm-hmm anyone at the end of the game Can choose.
Scott: well, I think what it is is as you approach the end of the game right on the board You're getting to the final space on the board.
Scott: The final space on the board is millionaire.
Scott: retire in style right a few spaces before that like five spaces before.
Scott: that is the day of Reckoning space and when you get to the day of reckoning space no matter what you spun you have to stop there And there's a whole big set of stuff you have to do on the day of reckoning.
Scott: and then you decide are you gonna?
Scott: Bet it all I'm becoming the millionaire tycoon and the instant winner or Are you going to just end the game normally and hope you have more money than everyone else that you can win?
Rym: Which money is not secret so you can pretty much just calculate that.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like huh you look at how much money you have and you figure out how much money you're gonna have after you Land on the millionaire.
Rym: I always hid my money.
Scott: Yeah, you look at how much money everyone else has and you say well if I end the game normally do I have a chance Of winning?
Scott: if yes Then just end the game and you just go to the end now.
Scott: if no you might as well gamble on the one in ten Chance of automatically winning.
Rym: now the rules were very clear.
Rym: There's this little rainbow board.
Rym: It's like a strip has one to ten on it.
Rym: You take all your money and your car and everything you've got in front of you.
Rym: your insurance is your cards And you put them on one of those numbers.
Rym: then you spin And if you make that number game ends immediately.
Rym: you double win.
Rym: everyone else It's over.
Scott: you win one in ten chance of just winning.
Scott: so no matter what you did the whole game No matter what even if you became the shitty teacher even if you you know just spent all your money even if you're holding a Fistful of promissory notes at the end of the game you have a one intense ten chance of just automatically winning no matter what?
Scott: Has has that for a good game it?
Rym: I mean on one hand I would say oh well maybe the game is good for kids because it's simple like Candyland and all that.
Rym: but What really bothered me was that the game of life kind of got re-released a bunch of times and From what I've read of the re-releases they dumbed it down.
Rym: that game wasn't dumb enough for kids today.
Scott: Well, I know that the version I had was slightly different from the version like my parents had.
Rym: well I had the like 1960s version.
Scott: I had I think the 1990 early 90s version.
Scott: so but yeah like The game also had these cards that you could get at certain times, and they let you do stuff.
Scott: But we mostly ignored those cards.
Rym: I don't remember that.
Scott: yeah, they were sort of like community chess cards But not really sure those that weren't just in your newfangled version.
Scott: They might have been but that made the game more complex.
Scott: so as opposed to the more simple It's like consider that a good thing.
Scott: I think you got one if you landed on a payday instead of going past one.
Scott: I don't remember exactly.
Rym: I just I really I can't understand why this game is popular among people or why it is retained its status as like the game Americans play.
Rym: they play Monopoly they play this.
Scott: there are a lot of American games that boil down to roll the dice or spin the spinner and move forward that many spaces and see what the board says.
Scott: I mean Monopoly careers Candyland, Uncle Wiggly The game of life.
Scott: there's a whole bunch of them, and they're all the same exact game pretty much shoots and ladders.
Scott: Oh, it's just ladders.
Scott: actually good Trouble.
Rym: sorry right there was one good game.
Rym: It was called payday, and I remember pretty much It was.
Rym: you have to make it through the week and pay all your bills With your paycheck, and it was kind of learn about managing money.
Scott: learn not to waste money on Educational game even if it wasn't a strategy game.
Rym: It was also a little bit strategic But yeah.
Scott: so the thing that all these games have different is the theme and I guess it was the theme of the game of life that Really carried it along as opposed to you know the game itself.
Rym: the theme was just kind of very like 1950s idyllic.
Rym: you Marry a nice young person, then you have a million kids, and then you retire after working your whole life.
Scott: It's pretty much the American dream guaranteed.
Rym: Well, no because if you failed you could millionaire tycoon.
Rym: you became a philosopher, and it showed this sad little goat Sad little farm right next to the mansion where everyone else was living.
Scott: I always kind of wanted to be the philosopher because it was like that space on the board didn't really get used.
Rym: Ah that was the other thing I did.
Rym: I always run for millionaire tycoon No matter what really because.
Scott: and then why even bother doing anything the rest of the game?
Scott: because it's just.
Scott: you might as well Just spin the spinner.
Scott: right.
Rym: at the beginning rationale was that all right mom and dad and brother I would rather be a philosopher, so if I have the chance of being super wealthy But also a philosopher why am I not gonna take that chance?
Scott: yeah, it's like The only thing about the.
Scott: I say I win.
Scott: the only thing about becoming the philosopher.
Scott: the only reason you don't do it at The beginning of the game is because whoever gets there first has the first dibs at it.
Scott: So it's sort of like if you do that right away.
Scott: That's not quite right.
Scott: you had to like roll a d6 to see who gets there to.
Scott: you know It's is Rick because it's whoever gets there first is completely random.
Rym: Well that you could do is just Flip a coin or roll the dice to figure out who wins and then roll a d10 for everyone in Order of the number they got on the first die to see if no they win.
Scott: And I don't know because then the person who goes last sorta has an advantage because if no one else wins Then they automatically win.
Scott: They don't have to roll the d10 well.
Rym: No they just have a 10% chance.
Scott: Well, I guess it's temporary.
Rym: whatever it works believe me it works.
Scott: Anyway the game of life is a pretty sad game.
Scott: I don't recommend playing it.
Rym: see it's not even.
Rym: I mean, I guess it was nominally fun when I was a kid, but that was mostly because I played it with my family.
Scott: Yeah, it was cuz.
Scott: I played it with my family my relatives, and you know we were kids We didn't really understand.
Scott: We like to play with.
Scott: we'd like to put the people in the cars and drop the cars around and play with huge amounts of Money, but as a kid once I played monopoly.
Rym: while it wasn't a great game Skill mattered a lot more there than it did in life.
Scott: Oh, I sure did.
Rym: I pretty much hated the game of life from the day.
Rym: I knew the game monopoly onward.
Scott: Yeah, it's something like that.
Rym: I just feel like if you're a parent and you got a kid give him Carcassonne or at least give him Monopoly.
Scott: But the game of life they have kids of Catan that you can get and get.
Scott: have your three-year-old playing the settlers.
Rym: I'll say that I think the game of life has absolutely no redeeming qualities Other than to make fun of.
Scott: retroactively I I think I'm gonna show you the first redeeming quality of the game of life.
Scott: Oh, everyone's gonna tell their stories of the game of life in the forum for fun times ah But even then it's pretty much retroactive.
Rym: making fun of.
Rym: yeah pretty much I guess one use it could have is that if you force a kid to play the game of life Then he's gonna appreciate settlers a lot more.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.