Rym: It's Thursday, May 3rd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: we respond to your requests and do a show that was suggested to us via email.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I Was doing something today that I don't do so often anymore that is put gas in my car.
Scott: You know now that I don't drive to the middle of nowhere every day.
Scott: I just drive to a train station.
Scott: That's five minutes from my house.
Scott: I get gas Rarely, so I'm at the gas station pumping the gas and this guy There's two guys in their car on the other at the other pump and the guys like hey How fast that go.
Scott: and I'm thinking he's talking about the gas pump.
Scott: cuz you know some gas stations They fiddle with the pump to scam you out of some money And then they don't give you know.
Scott: They make the pump like that the counter goes a little slower and the gas comes out or something like that.
Rym: See while I know they check gas stations very rigorously.
Rym: I remember a case in Michigan back when I was a kid where they caught a gas station where they had a lamp and If you turned the knob on the lamp it didn't turn on the light in the lamp It switched all the gas pumps to rip people off and they knew they knew what the inspectors looked like.
Rym: So whenever and they watch and whenever those people were there or whenever they knew they were coming They'd make him legit, and then they put him back.
Rym: otherwise Wow wow so the fact that they got caught gives me a little bit of hope that people look into those sorts of things.
Scott: Yeah, plus there was some lady yelling about the gas being 320 And I thought that maybe they were you know wondering if my gas pump was like scamming or something.
Scott: But then they're like no man your car.
Scott: I like my car like it's.
Scott: it's kind of fast.
Rym: Yeah, Scott drives a normal Mazda 3.
Scott: It's nothing special 2006 Mazda 3 hatchback, and I'm like it's got like 150 horsepower whatever.
Scott: these guys are driving like a late 90s Lumina and You know they were like oh something something.
Scott: I'm like all right.
Scott: They're like how much that cost you.
Scott: I'm like 19 something.
Scott: they're like that's not bad.
Scott: I'm like that's all right.
Scott: It's a good car.
Scott: They're like hey those taillights So those a custom job like no it came like that.
Scott: I didn't change anything on this car.
Scott: the guys like whoa You must race that thing huh?
Scott: I'm like Not really.
Scott: I drive to the train station.
Rym: has this guy never driven on a freeway?
Rym: There's like millions of Mazda 3s everywhere.
Rym: There's like 12 in the parking lot of my work.
Scott: Man.
Scott: if there were wannabe racers or whatever I have no idea, but they were okay guys.
Scott: But I just thought it was kind of weird that I'm just sitting there with my car Filling it with gas a perfectly normal car in every way and some guys think it's like an awesome rice rocket Somewhat ill-informed I guess about the world.
Scott: uh at least about cars.
Scott: speaking
Rym: about cars I'm running into this issue more and more, but a lot of times because I work in Yonkers usually I drive down to a bunch of places to eat or sometimes I walk, but one of the places I go to is next to a grocery store and a bank and Because it's during the day the only people who are ever at that grocery store or bank are old retired people.
Rym: And I have never ever driven to this parking lot Without running afoul of old people who can't drive causing all sorts of havoc.
Rym: And today was perhaps the most egregious of them all I'm pulling in and I'm in.
Rym: there Was this woman who looks like she's about a hundred thousand years old in this gigantic white SUV, and I'm
Scott: wow So
Rym: I'm waiting and she's like pulling up slowly And it looks like she's gonna pull into the bank,
Scott: and then
Rym: she just stops in the middle of the road Parks her car gets out and goes into the bank door.
Rym: open car Just sitting in the middle of the road blocking it not even just like in her lane But in the middle of the road.
Scott: I just stole in the car.
Scott: I would have gotten into it.
Rym: She took the keys with her.
Rym: She let the door open not all the way open But the door just kind of hanging open and the cars just stopped there.
Rym: And she goes into the bank.
Scott: I would have held the horn down and not let go of it or I would have called the police and said tow this car.
Rym: See I cared so little I just parked and got my feet.
Scott: so you were able to park.
Rym: well I just went around her.
Rym: I'm not I can maneuver my car.
Scott: Oh, you know the streets over there usually narrow.
Scott: So I was thinking maybe you wouldn't be able to get around.
Scott: no No, I could definitely get a white SUV in the middle of the road.
Rym: No if I couldn't have gotten around.
Rym: I would have been on the phone with the police before you could blink.
Scott: okay, okay?
Scott: I just had the picture of the couldn't get around in my mind.
Rym: now Not that I mean I don't know what to do about this issue because people just because someone's old they still have a right to get around But at the same time they shouldn't be piloting large dangerous vehicles if they don't have the mental capacity well to properly.
Scott: I think that no one should be piloting large vehicles in less.
Scott: they can prove they have a need for them.
Scott: You know it's like.
Scott: you know sure any vehicle.
Scott: you have a right to buy a vehicle But you shouldn't be allowed to drive it in New York City unless you're filling it with people and stuff.
Scott: You know it's like.
Rym: what about freedom.
Scott: Yeah, there is a freedom, but you're hurting others, and that's your man.
Rym: What if you drive it very well?
Scott: You make it difficult for others to drive because they can't fucking see around your vehicle.
Rym: But then all delivery trucks and everything are just as bad in fact worse.
Scott: Yeah, maybe they should deliver something besides.
Rym: honestly people who complain about not being able to see around or past SUVs is kind of lame and really I often have that problem.
Scott: I'll be like at a stoplight and like I'll have those SUVs in front of me I basically just can't see anything enough to trust.
Scott: you know wait for the SUV to get out of the way And then I can resume driving.
Rym: Uh-huh, I've never had that problem.
Scott: I've had that problem quite often all right all right or like I'll be trying to turn right and an SUV will be in the left next to me trying to turn left.
Scott: So I got a look to the left to see if there's a car coming before.
Scott: I could turn right But I can't see because the SUVs in the way.
Rym: But the SUV doesn't really block your vision much more than a minivan or a jeep or even a lot of sedans.
Scott: I don't know it.
Scott: just every time it happens where I can't see it happens to be an SUV I don't know.
Scott: I'm telling you a Corvette couldn't possibly block my vision anyway.
Rym: I'm just more of the mind that people who can't pilot vehicles properly shouldn't be able to pilot them.
Rym: That's also true because also at my work very recently it was yesterday, but I didn't talk about it yesterday There was a gigantic accident like gigantic And they're like four fire trucks and all these ambulances and it totally blocked the road near the sawmill.
Rym: And it's at this big intersection, but if you look at the intersection There is absolutely no way you could hit anyone there unless you were a complete and total jackass.
Scott: Well you ran the red light or something.
Rym: now you running the red light cuz people run the red light anyway You'd have had to come up to the pre-existing red light Somehow without anyone being in front of you or been sitting at the red light and then suddenly decided to just gun it.
Rym: That's the only way there could have been an accident.
Rym: There's no way to hit anything there all right, and the thing is there's accidents there about every couple weeks.
Scott: Yeah, this is why I don't drive in the city And it's also why I don't drive in Florida because Florida is pretty much the worst place to drive in the world.
Scott: the roads in Florida are actually nice.
Scott: they're really long they have a whole shit ton of lanes and The blocks are.
Scott: they're big and wide and it's all a grid.
Scott: But there's so many old people on the roads that it's just the most dangerous roads in the universe Despite the fact that if there were only people who could drive on those roads They'd be the safest roads in the universe.
Scott: They're the best roads and the best cars and the worst drivers And it's more dangerous than New York City, which is perhaps the most dangerous roads.
Rym: I mean the thing is the only roads that are really dangerous in New York City are the commuter roads.
Rym: during the commuter times Every other time it's just slow or there's traffic or whatever, but it's not like people are dying.
Scott: no No, but I'm saying like the roads in the city like are far narrower And there's a lot more traffic going on a lot more opportunities for like you know all sorts of fender-bendering And all that kind of.
Rym: yeah, but at the same time.
Rym: It's just generally a very Unique experience driving in the city often because you pretty much have to do What's right as opposed to what the law says yeah?
Rym: And there's a lot of times where not only should you run the red light not only are you expected to run the red light?
Rym: But the cop who's behind you will force you to run the red light just because you're in his way.
Rym: Yeah, I have that happened to be once.
Scott: yep But yeah If we took the Florida drivers and put them on the city and we took the city drivers and put them in, Florida.
Scott: There wouldn't be any accidents in Florida and all the old people would die.
Rym: Florida roads aren't really so great.
Scott: They're really awesome.
Scott: They're big straight wide roads with a million lanes, and there's nothing wrong with them.
Rym: Yeah, big creative awesome roads with a million lanes are actually generally pretty bad and inefficient.
Rym: I read a cool article about it hub.
Rym: once you get beyond a two or three lane road Those extra lanes cause a lot more problems than they solve and the the extra lanes would be much better served instead of having those By just having other roads elsewhere or more efficient roads.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing for doesn't have too many roads.
Scott: totals generally like these.
Scott: be it's like a grid but the grid is like these giant blocks and the giant blocks are just filled with a zillion condos and then like you turn off The giant road into the condo place, and then it's just.
Rym: everyone I know in Florida says it's actually generally hard to get anywhere And it's kind of a pain in the ass even without the traffic just the roads.
Scott: I think it's mostly the old people that make driving in Florida.
Rym: besides We can't complain about anywhere because we have driven to New Jersey perhaps the worst place in the world to drive other than I don't Know India.
Scott: yeah, we saw that there are more old people in a jersey that already are.
Rym: They wouldn't be able to find their way to the Garden State, so it wouldn't matter.
Rym: I guess all right, so what do you got?
Scott: All right in the news now.
Scott: We've been talking about this Obama guy.
Scott: You probably heard of him.
Scott: if even if you're not from the u.s.. He's running for president Or he's gonna try to run for president.
Scott: He's seeking the Democratic nomination and such when's the election next year?
Scott: I think right yeah, and you know I was kind of lukewarm on all the candidates.
Scott: I was a little up on Obama over other people because he seemed cool.
Scott: He had a podcast.
Scott: he You know he's very anti-corruption, which I agree with.
Scott: I didn't agree with everything.
Scott: He's got, but I don't agree with anything.
Rym: Oh, what do you disagree with?
Rym: I don't know oh?
Scott: Huh, but I'm pretty sure I don't agree with them 100%.
Scott: Uh-huh, I don't think with anyone on your percent.
Rym: all right.
Scott: There's no way because I'm sure he doesn't say Obama.
Rym: stand on gun control Scott I Don't know.
Rym: how does he stand on technology issues like net neutrality?
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: uh-huh Where does he stand on freedom of speech issues?
Scott: I'm pretty sure he likes the freedom of speech.
Scott: uh-huh It doesn't really matter.
Scott: point is I was kind of lukewarm mostly cuz you know Rym just pointed out I don't really pay that much attention, so I'm lukewarm and anything see.
Rym: I unlike Scott I actually pay a lot of attention to politics and now that I listen to it's all politics from NPR News.
Rym: They talk a good game.
Rym: They talk about politics the way football.
Rym: people talk about football.
Scott: Yeah, I just don't care, but now Obama has done something.
Scott: he has done something that Basically negates anything else he has ever done.
Rym: He is proven.
Rym: It doesn't matter what his stance is it doesn't matter.
Scott: Obama could turn could say tomorrow that he thinks that we should kill all the Jews Go start war with the rest of the entire world nuke everybody.
Scott: He could say all those things and I would still vote for him because of what he has just done.
Scott: He has said that he thinks that The presidential debates should be licensed with the Creative Commons license.
Scott: now Not only is that an obvious thing that should be.
Scott: I mean obviously you know they don't.
Scott: Of course the kind of thing should be done with the Creative Commons license.
Scott: It's obvious, but the point is he is proven.
Scott: He knows what a Creative Commons license is.
Rym: see even if he had said nothing should be out on the Creative Commons He said those two words.
Rym: those two words probably mean Nothing to anyone else in the United States government at all.
Scott: you say those words, and they say what yeah And if you've read sanctuary, you'll know the problem is old Circle old people who don't understand What's going on in the world.
Scott: and Obama regardless of his stance if he knows the Creative Commons is he Understands what's going on in the world?
Scott: He's.
Scott: he knows he's not one of these clueless old people who thinks is a series of tubes.
Scott: He knows the Creative Commons and therefore even if he thinks we should Do crazy stuff and that the death penalty if you robbed the convenience store I'll still vote for him because he knows.
Rym: See the thing is there is the chance that he does this.
Rym: pipe fries an aide who was like you should do a podcast.
Rym: Maybe he didn't know what one was and they convinced him to do it.
Rym: and now they're like hey Say the words Creative Commons the next time you talk and you get all the nerds to vote for you.
Scott: I'm gonna read exactly what he said.
Scott: sure all right.
Scott: I am a strong believer in the importance of copyright especially in a digital age But there is no reason this particular class of content needs the protection.
Scott: We have incentive enough to debate.
Scott: the networks have incentive enough to broadcast these debates.
Scott: Rather than restricting the product of those debates We should instead make sure that our democracy and citizens have the chance to benefit from them all in way Benefit from them in all the ways that technology makes possible your presidential campaign.
Scott: use the internet to break new ground and citizen Political participation.
Scott: I would urge you to take the lead again by continuing to support this important medium.
Scott: blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: Well, I think it's safe to say because even if this is just all his aides and advisors telling him this stuff Doesn't matter because they're the ones influencing him.
Scott: Yeah, it's a letter that he sent to the DNC asking them to license the debates under Creative Commons attribution license.
Rym: Yeah, it's still too far out for us to do anything But we definitely here at GeekNights take the stand that the media I mean back in the day newspapers and news stations Whatever would always endorse candidates, and they'd be straight-up partisan.
Rym: We the people of this chronicled of Gotham say that Joey Jojo Shabbat ooh should be the president.
Scott: It's a waste name.
Rym: I have a high Joey Jojo and We're pretty much real close to just saying we're gonna endorse Barack.
Scott: Hey, I mean yeah, okay, I endorse spitzer for less we did and he's anti-video game.
Rym: Yeah, that didn't come out as much until after we endorsed him.
Rym: in fact we considered revoking our endorsement.
Rym: not that it matters That matters.
Scott: he won 70% of the votes.
Scott: Yeah, that's course.
Rym: now because of him our friends who work for the government can't surf the web at work anymore.
Scott: Well, you know what while our friends it sucks for them I support not having government workers waste time browsing the web.
Rym: that shouldn't be so that's good Alright, so in semi related news, and I bring this up only because I didn't see anything else worth talking about and the two other Stories I'm thinking about talking about I have to verify because they seem a little dubious.
Scott: Yeah There were some news.
Scott: is that we can't 100% verify?
Scott: like if these are real news is wouldn't they be in real?
Scott: Newspapers like from the town or state that these events happened in and we looked at the newspapers from those towns and states and did Not find these news's therefore.
Scott: We're pretty sure it's just a bunch of hokey.
Scott: and yet again the Unscrupulous video game media has fallen for some bullshit rumors.
Scott: ah video game media Yeah, why don't you try verifying that shit next time?
Rym: just related to all this Barack?
Rym: Additionally it's always Barack is Currently according to the news being placed under protective Secret Service.
Rym: Well, I guess protection.
Scott: so he's got the the men in black following him around.
Scott: make sure he doesn't get killed.
Rym: Yeah, now apparently as his campaign has gone on he's been receiving Ever-increasing amounts of hate mail death threats all sorts of things like that I expected.
Rym: the government must just feel that he is a serious candidate who has a very good chance of Winning because they're putting him under Secret Service protection at this early stage Which isn't that uncommon.
Rym: the Secret Service will often start protecting potential candidates for the presidency long before the election.
Scott: Yep, also think about this right.
Scott: imagine if Barack was assassinated today.
Scott: Just imagine if it happened.
Scott: right just you know.
Rym: pretend I'd lose all faith in American government.
Scott: well No, no.
Scott: But but think about what kind of craziness would happen because of that.
Scott: like.
Scott: how crazy would there be a whole mess of people?
Scott: Who would just go nuts like there might even be like riots in many places?
Scott: Therefore regardless of whether he is going to they think he's likely to win the presidency.
Scott: They protect him for the security of the country because he is someone who if killed would There would be riots.
Scott: so they're gonna make sure he doesn't die.
Rym: most definitely I find it funny that at the end of the article I looked at it just notes that Hillary Clinton because she's the former first lady already has Secret Service protection.
Rym: Huh, it's like they're trying to.
Rym: you know there.
Rym: Obama was in the news.
Rym: We got to make sure Hiller is in the news a little bit, too.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if I was like a senator Which they both are and I wouldn't have the Secret Service protection all the time And I probably wouldn't be a super important senator, so they probably wouldn't force it on me.
Scott: But I might from time to time say hey Can you send me some guys to make sure I don't get you know beat up over here alright?
Rym: things of the day
Scott: Alright, so well you probably don't know this because you're probably some sort of geek who doesn't pay attention to what's going on in The world, but there is a huge fight You know like the fight of the year, and it's this Saturday May 5th probably on pay-per-view.
Scott: But I don't recommend paying for pay-per-view.
Scott: go to like some sports bar if you really want to see it.
Scott: But it's Oscar De La Hoya verse some pretty guy Floyd Mayweather who doesn't look like he's ever had a fight in his life Which means he must be pretty good, so he's like Vega.
Scott: He sort of looks like like a Vega.
Scott: I guess yeah, but anyway and in the forum people have been discussing you know the MMA.
Scott: You know which is the mixed martial arts sort of fighting like.
Scott: you know the pride In the k1 and all that sort of crazy stuff.
Scott: You know and it.
Scott: you know it came down to the old.
Scott: well is the problem with you know?
Scott: martial arts for entertainment value.
Scott: The most entertaining martial arts are the kind with lots of punches and kicks and jump kicks and maneuvers and possibly weapons and all That sort of stuff, but when it comes to actual hand-to-hand fighting with no weapons and no magical powers of Hadouken's or anything like that The guy who's gonna win most of the time is a guy like Zangief.
Scott: It just grabs you and doesn't let you move.
Scott: That's why if you watch like a street fight 90% of the time it ends up on the ground because the more realistic a fight is the more boring it is.
Scott: and that reminded me that my favorite form of fighting for entertainment other than the barge is Plain old boxing.
Scott: because whether you've actually ever watched plain old boxing You know or you just don't seem to care about it because it's not that popular.
Scott: unless there's like a giant fight going on It's actually pretty good.
Scott: And there's a reason that guys like Muhammad Ali are so famous, and you're probably geeks.
Scott: You might not even ever even seen Muhammad Ali fight in your life.
Scott: You might know the name Muhammad Ali and that he's some great boxer of all time Float like a butterfly sting like a bee.
Scott: yeah, you might know all the stuff.
Scott: You might have heard of Rocky also, but Rocky was a fictional character, but you might never ever watched Muhammad Ali actually fight someone.
Scott: well.
Scott: Here's a video of Muhammad Ali versus Brian London in 1966. now you know the video starts with the Hamel Ali dancing around the guy.
Scott: You know punch here punch there, and then you know as he gets the guy into the corner.
Scott: Just watch what he does.
Scott: It's it's absolutely amazing.
Scott: It's like holy shit.
Scott: look how many punches.
Scott: He throws.
Scott: It's like fucking Kenshiro.
Scott: It's like It's almost inhuman like the the level the quickness and the number and the force of the punches that this guy throws.
Scott: and Whether you care about boxing or even if you detest all violence think boxing is a barbaric thing that should never be watched.
Scott: Look at this and maybe you'll have some respect for amazing people with amazing talents.
Rym: Well right along those lines since Scott was doing a boxing thing and I didn't say anything particularly interesting on the internet I remembered that when I was a kid I would go to see hockey games in Detroit, and there was this statue Near the Joe Louis arena, which was basically a gigantic fist Hanging from some kind of triangle structure.
Rym: It was in fact titled the fist.
Rym: the fist is no other than the fist of Joe Louis.
Scott: It actually take his fist and model it.
Rym: you know I don't actually know any of the history of it other than that it is supposed to be Joe Louis's fist.
Scott: I'm gonna look this up right now.
Rym: Yeah, it's called the fist, so I'm sure you can find it anyway Joe Louis is also one of those famous boxing names you probably hear.
Rym: oh, yeah, Joe Louis.
Rym: He beat that Nazi whatever and Here's a video of him beating that Nazi.
Rym: the guy wasn't actually a Nazi the guy he fought Max Schmeling.
Rym: he was just a German.
Rym: who was he had to fight him to prove that yeah the master race is superior and Kind of got shown up didn't look too good.
Scott: All right, so you might remember last week We said hey listeners give us some ideas for Thursday shows cuz we don't have so many now.
Scott: I'm gonna be perfectly honest with you.
Scott: We asked for show ideas for shows quite a bit and we receive not a whole lot But plenty of show ideas.
Scott: the thing is we just veto the vast majority of those ideas.
Rym: well It's usually a pocket veto.
Rym: We just ignore them, and then they disappear.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much what it is.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's not because we think the ideas are bad even though some of them are bad.
Scott: It's usually because we say either We can't talk about this for more than you know 25 minutes or
Rym: it'll require research and we're busy or It's an idea that we've been planning to do later once we have some factor that we haven't decided yet Or it's something
Scott: we don't know much about or something we don't care about or something we have nothing to say about or It's there's some reason that we pocket veto so many of the ideas people gave us.
Scott: well I've decided and I guess Rym has agreed that what we're gonna do is We asked for ideas.
Scott: it would be kind of assholish of us to just not go with those ideas.
Scott: also It would be much more difficult for us to sit around coming up with a new idea and a lot more time-consuming Then to just go with some idea that someone sent us for better or for worse.
Scott: Oh, that's another reason we used to veto ideas because we didn't think that they would be entertaining shows.
Scott: well We're just gonna follow your ideas and do exactly what you say and if it doesn't turn out good You asked for it You got it.
Rym: I don't think it'll be an issue.
Scott: I don't think it'll be such an issue.
Scott: also I think it'll be good for us to do shows on topics or things that other people have chosen sort of forcing us to Do some work and not just go along our usual course of thinking.
Rym: so of course the email We pick is one that only asks about us, so we don't have to do any prior planning or research whatsoever.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I think it'll still be interesting.
Scott: all right this email is from Christian.
Scott: his name is Christian.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's a guy.
Scott: He I don't know if he is a Christian, but that that's not a problem doesn't matter.
Rym: Okay, all right.
Rym: That was some pretty lame banter.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, that was really bad.
Rym: That was like the guy running the bingo event says something after he calls the number like b2 a bomber.
Scott: You just did all right.
Scott: so his emails.
Rym: really short so and grammatically incorrect.
Scott: It's very grammatically incorrect.
Scott: shame on you.
Rym: I don't see any punctuation.
Rym: I'm sorry dude.
Scott: I see some hyphens.
Scott: I see a question mark.
Scott: I see a comma another comma a slash.
Scott: There's no period.
Rym: oh there is a question mark But it's after a space kind of by itself.
Scott: There's an apostrophe.
Rym: I'll also point out and I find this funny that one Most of the emails we get are people sending them to us from work But more importantly this particular one.
Rym: I just want to note that the disclaimer that your work puts on the end of your email is Far longer than the email you sent.
Scott: I guess that's why we picked this one.
Scott: It's nice and sure.
Scott: of course I don't think our discussion That will take up the whole show will be as short as the email itself.
Scott: all right, so let me read this email.
Scott: There's only one sentence in the email before the actual questions, and he says Okay the topic of the email is an easy slash lazy Thursday episode.
Scott: Oh good Appreciate you may not know the answers to the following comma, but you could do a running dialogue slash argument haha.
Rym: on your views on the following the Alright, I don't think we need to read them.
Rym: I think we'll just go through all right the future of GeekNights.
Scott: see
Rym: We've been talking about that a lot lately Internal to our little geek enclave here partly because a few weeks ago Scott comes to me all high and mighty and starts talking about how we need to do something That's never been done with audio before and transcend podcasting and become something Beyond on a fundamental level anything that has ever been done before with audio.
Rym: Yeah, and I said Scott that silly audio by itself is pretty well understood.
Scott: Yeah the technology is understood, but in terms of the art That's what I'm talking about.
Scott: you know like you can go You can watch actually have any idea at all any because I'm not an artist.
Rym: It's like so I don't know that's like going to an athlete and saying yeah, just uh run Faster.
Scott: that's exactly what I basically said.
Rym: yes, not even that it's like transcend running.
Rym: Why are you running?
Rym: There's got to be a better way.
Scott: Yeah, and I don't know the better way, but I look at other mediums of artwork.
Scott: You know you look at movies right and there are just some movies that are sort of above and Beyond all other movies in.
Scott: Just you watch them And you get this feeling that nothing else gives you like you watch a citizen cane or a godfather.
Scott: see but something like that.
Rym: That's just a very well done movie a very well done podcast or a very well done radio show.
Scott: But it's not like.
Scott: it's just giving me the same feeling other movies give only better.
Scott: It's like on a completely other level.
Scott: You know it's like on the same level like you know Mona Lisa Compared to all the other paintings or David compared to all the other sculptures.
Scott: You know it's just.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't feel that I just it's a lot better very well executed very well done, but it's not Transcendent.
Scott: oh, it's like I read a will Eisner comic.
Scott: It's just so far above and Beyond every other comic like.
Scott: they can't even come close.
Rym: Yeah, but it's still just a comic.
Rym: It's like we're still just doing audio.
Rym: What what would you do with audio other than have a better show.
Rym: because the thing is.
Rym: the only reason I nitpick on Scott Here is that he brings this up alright alright.
Rym: So how are we going to do that?
Scott: if I knew that answer would I still be here or would I be a world famous?
Scott: Radio artist that would be but remembered in history books for centuries.
Rym: obviously The key component of something like that is that it is executed very well, so I say all right Why don't we put some effort into executing GeekNights better?
Rym: Let's listen to old shows.
Rym: do some criticism look at them.
Rym: fiddle with the audio fiddle with our format a little bit fiddle with our Pre-production and Scott basically said nah not gonna do any of that.
Scott: yeah Thus I don't have time for that shit.
Scott: Oh, oh Well somehow, I don't think that it's.
Scott: you know small stuff like that is what I'm thinking about.
Rym: But your small stuff like that David is just a very well sculpted thing.
Rym: it took a lot of practice a lot of planning a Lot of skill and it's not.
Rym: it's not transcendent or special in any way other than it was very well executed.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well.
Rym: How is it transcendent?
Rym: How is it different?
Scott: I don't know, but I'm sure if I went to art school.
Rym: I could come back and tell you see I don't think you can and I really think it's funny because usually this kind of argument Is the other way around but you're just full of self-history and rhetoric and little else at this point perhaps.
Scott: But you know it's sort of like I can.
Scott: I know something when I see it like.
Scott: I know I don't know shit about boxing But I just told you and I know watching it that that was an amazing piece of boxing by Muhammad Ali right there But I couldn't do it.
Scott: I couldn't tell anyone how to do it.
Rym: Do you really know?
Rym: or do you know because someone told you no?
Scott: You can.
Scott: you can tell by looking at it because it's just so amazing That you had to be an idiot not to see it.
Scott: you watch that and you just go whoa Holy shit, so I want people listening to GeekNights to go like they put their headphones on.
Scott: they should go whoa Holy shit.
Scott: the same way.
Scott: I do when I watch Muhammad Ali.
Rym: There's nothing different you can do with audio.
Rym: the only thing different we could do is be technically better.
Scott: Somehow I think there are ways to improve the show besides technical superior.
Rym: well you realize technical technically better includes format Editing pacing all the elements that come together to make the show.
Rym: So I really don't see where you're going with this.
Scott: if I did no one saw Muhammad Ali doing that before.
Scott: he did.
Scott: you know it.
Scott: you have to be yeah one thing to say man I'm gonna be like the greatest ever and then it's another thing to actually be able to be the greatest ever.
Scott: I don't think.
Scott: I don't really think we are capable of being the greatest ever But I want to.
Rym: but all we would have to do is be better.
Scott: It's so much better that it's unbelievable.
Rym: No I think it's just Incrementally better.
Rym: and there it's you little steps little steps little steps and then you see the one at the top and you don't see Or you're not paying attention to or you don't know enough about the history of the medium or the boxing or whatever To have seen or know about all of those steps it took to get them up to the Muhammad Ali.
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Scott: Regardless anyway the future of GeekNights.
Rym: See we think about this kind of random.
Rym: Well usually I bring it up and then Scott poo poos it or whatever.
Rym: Let's just do the show and go to bed.
Scott: Most because that's the thing is if the show was sort of weekly or bi-weekly or something like that We could do a lot more thinking about the show and a lot more doing stuff outside the show.
Scott: But but that's not what people want.
Scott: That's not what they want now.
Scott: So we do it every night and as a result thinking about the future and all sorts of long-term planning and doing things for the show outside of the show itself all by the wayside in Place of doing the actual show every night and then going to bed because I'm tired and I have a job.
Rym: Well in terms of the show itself I I can say with confidence and we've said this pretty much from the very beginning that We'll probably keep doing GeekNights for a very long time regardless of whatever else we do and GeekNights will always be free No matter what else we do.
Rym: So even if we make money off of other things we go into radio or we quit and no matter what We'll always keep doing GeekNights.
Rym: worst case We might cut back a few days at GeekNights or something like that.
Rym: But I see us continuing to do the show for many years to come.
Scott: Yeah, they'll definitely be at least Probably at the bare minimum two more years of GeekNights Probably more but definitely at least two because we renewed the lease for two which means we're living here for two more years.
Scott: We're living here.
Scott: it might as well keep making the show.
Rym: Well, if you decide as people keep listening if you decide to move away You'll just have to Skype into my podcast or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, that's pretty much what'll have to happen because I'm the only one who knows how to do the audio.
Scott: Yeah, it's not too hard.
Rym: Oh, then why don't?
Rym: why don't you do the post process?
Scott: I go to bed instead.
Scott: uh-huh, uh-huh, so Yeah, GeekNights will definitely be around for a while.
Scott: The show might change the format might change a lot of things about it might change.
Scott: Well exist in some form for a time to come and even if we both quit Entirely and we give up on the whole thing and we never speak to each other again or something The show will still be up on the internet for as long as the internet exists and humans Or even
Rym: for as long as one of us continues to pay for lips.
Scott: I'll pretty much pay for that forever Yeah, and like cost so little yeah, as long as human society doesn't crumble or anything like that.
Scott: The show will still be there for all time.
Scott: All right next what you'll be doing in one year two years, etc.
Rym: Uh, see that's really kind of an interesting question, but not interesting in any.
Rym: I don't know where I was going with that.
Rym: Yeah, I was just kind of rambling.
Scott: Well, I thought well I just got a new job.
Rym: I'm trying to get promoted in my job or I'll quit and get a job elsewhere.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm pretty likely to keep this job for at least one or two more years.
Scott: You know, it's much better than my previous job, which I kept for about almost two years.
Scott: I think so a better job.
Scott: I'll probably gonna keep for an even longer amount of time than that.
Scott: I could imagine.
Scott: But that being said in the long run.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I kind of want to do something awesome.
Scott: We keep coming up with crazy ideas like hey, let's make this kind of business.
Scott: Let's make that kind of business Let's run away to Europe.
Scott: Let's do something.
Rym: The thing is of all of our crazy ideas GeekNights is the first one.
Rym: we actually said Alright, let's actually do well other than take over the anime club.
Rym: Yeah, which also succeeded.
Rym: but then GeekNights.
Rym: Alright, let's just do a podcast.
Rym: every other ideas been just shit talking but every time we do one of our ideas They're always very successful in pretty short order.
Rym: The problem is all the ideas that make us money require us to already have money.
Rym: and if we already had money We wouldn't bother with the idea because we'd have the money already.
Rym: Yep, so if I had the money to open that I don't know the hundreds of really good business ideas We have I would use that money to live an awesome life and not bother with the stupid business.
Scott: Exactly, but yeah in one or two years.
Scott: I see myself still working still Go and do in the podcast still geeking out all the time Still going to conventions and still doing all the stuff and doing now only more.
Scott: Maybe I'll go on some awesome vacations.
Rym: That seems to be the trend in our lives pretty much right.
Rym: since we got out of college every year We constantly.
Rym: we keep doing the same things.
Rym: We keep living the same basic lives But we keep seeking out more of what we've got we making more money doing more things.
Rym: It's like we keep expanding in every direction as fast as we can while still having the nine-to-five Baseline job that provides us income.
Rym: So despite the fact that we're pretty big risk takers a lot of the time We're really not taking any financial risks at all in our lives.
Rym: Yeah, and I don't know if there'd be a point at which we would.
Rym: I don't know if we would ever Stake all our money on something.
Scott: I don't know if I'd stake all my money.
Scott: but in five to ten years when you know My car is paid off and my student is time to buy a new car and my student loan is paid off It's time to go back to school.
Scott: No, when all those things are sort of taken care of I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Rym: I might do something weird see but the thing is by then it's too late because all of history shows us that if you want To do something you got to start right away and just do it.
Rym: And if you wait until it's a better time or I have the resources now or I've done all that other stuff or now I finally out of debt.
Rym: I have a steady job.
Rym: I have enough money.
Rym: It never happens.
Rym: Then you end up being 45.
Rym: You did nothing with your life except work at a company you hated for 40 years.
Rym: Well, I guess not 40 years.
Scott: That's definitely not gonna happen.
Scott: I'm definitely gonna make some sort of move before I'm 30.
Scott: I can guarantee that.
Rym: see the thing is pretty much the last three or four years and the next three or four years in general We're pretty much seriously consolidating all of our wealth and consolidating all of our skills and all of our friends and Bit by bit making moves toward just banding together and doing something awesome.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right What do you think?
Scott: the show will be like hyphen same format slash?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't see the format of the show changing very much.
Rym: Well, everyone likes it.
Rym: We had someone steal the format.
Rym: Well not steal but ask us if they could use it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the format is sort of become like Like an old pair of shoes, you know, it's all it's broken in it fits.
Scott: It's comfortable.
Scott: The thing is, you know, and I don't see myself changing it because it's comfortable and I'm lazy.
Scott: But I do see us.
Scott: we decided we're gonna try to you know experiment outside of the show itself.
Rym: Well, yeah We'll get.
Rym: we'll talk about that at the end of this.
Scott: Yeah, so GeekNights itself the format may or may not change.
Scott: if you know things happen Like let's say, you know things the day dry up for some reason or you know We decide to do more of something or we come up with something new.
Scott: That's like just crazy popular.
Rym: or well one long-term format change which would probably come about if we got stupidly popular like if we hit the 50 to 100 thousand listener mark.
Rym: Then I could see just for the fact of expedience of the things we'd have to be doing and at that time It would be a full-time job and those sorts of things.
Rym: I could see the four nights of GeekNights always existing and yet it wouldn't always be just myself and Scott.
Rym: Yeah, like I could see it'd be like syndication or internal kind of like Mondays with Scott and Alex and Tuesdays with Rimming Scott and Wednesdays with blah blah blah something like that.
Scott: Yeah, because if the show is just that big and we're just doing it crazily which I don't see happening But if it does then it's gonna be sort of too big for two people to sit down and do the show Four nights a week plus.
Rym: at that point we'd have to expand.
Rym: we'd have to definitely have more shows more topics more things Which there'd probably be a whole cluster of GeekNights that would probably be every day.
Rym: at that point
Scott: I imagine we would go with the you know The whole front row cruise studios and we would produce many things and only one of those things the flagship would be GeekNights and We would make many other things that would be produced by the same studio that aren't GeekNights.
Rym: Yep, because that is one of the reasons a lot of people actually ask or at least you probably wonder how come GeekNights is At www.frontrowcrew.com and we've talked about the origin of the front row crew.
Rym: That's basically the catch-all name for the group of people We have surrounded ourselves with who we I mean we say we're friends But we're really more like family as a group and a lot of people external to us have pointed this out to us.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, that's how it is and we generally put all our stakes together and we generally are all together on any venture and I see us collectivizing more and more as time goes on creatively.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So that's the reason it's frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: and Yeah, all right.
Scott: So if you just move on, okay, all right I didn't.
Rym: I think there could be a more.
Rym: see we're talking about show format.
Rym: I think you could have handled all the segues a better way.
Rym: Yeah, perhaps.
Scott: Yeah, so this show will be like in terms of format.
Scott: There'll be better segues in the future.
Scott: Ah And not the kind where you stand on the stick with two wheels and roll around town with Steve Wozniak.
Rym: No, so so the next one I'll use Scott segue here.
Rym: Where will your career be?
Scott: Well, there was one before that.
Rym: Oh was there?
Rym: Oh, oh, I totally missed that and we're not gonna edit that out either.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Good job I'm actually a lot of people ask me about how we edit the show and that sort of thing And in fact, I do give props to anime pulse.
Rym: after we kind of reamed them on the show The Ichigo guy actually came to me was like, so how do I edit?
Rym: How do I do all these things you're talking about?
Rym: Yeah, I'm actually writing a not I wouldn't call it a book cuz it's not gonna be that long.
Rym: It'll probably be about 30 to 50 pages at most be like a PDF.
Rym: Yeah I'm writing a guide on how to podcast that I'm probably going to publish under the Creative Commons and probably actually Published too because it wouldn't cost that much.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's just you know, type it in with like a delay tech or the PDF Or something.
Rym: Yeah, I posted the barest barest like alpha alpha crap-o version in the forums But it's got a long way to go and I'm working out whenever I have time.
Scott: Yeah, I always give respect because quite often, you know, if I see someone doing something that's not so smart I'll go to them over like hey, why don't you do it this better way?
Scott: and you'd be surprised how often people say Asshole know it all don't be you know, treating me like an idiot blabbity blah and I'm like just trying to help you out.
Scott: It's like what the hell's your problem.
Scott: so when someone says, oh, you know something I don't know please share your knowledge.
Scott: I wish to be enlightened.
Scott: They are someone I can respect and it's like ah, I made fun of you and you say All right How can I do better?
Scott: then you get the thumbs up.
Rym: but despite all the talk I gave people on how to edit in terms of GeekNights we actually Edit almost nothing out of the show.
Rym: The only thing that is ever edited out of a show is Occasionally we'll stop talking for some reason and I just cut that out.
Rym: But even that's pretty rare and I shortened silences between words with the filters.
Rym: I don't even it's totally automatic I don't have to do anything.
Rym: and other than that The show is pretty much recorded live and it's very rare that anything more than a second or two is ever cut out of the show.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the next one your plans to break into mainstream media question mark.
Rym: Well, I think we would handle that more along because it's really a two-part question in terms of before We can get to mainstream media.
Rym: We need to break out completely among nerds and geeks Because I mean you all obviously like the show and we gained an average of I think one point six new listeners per day.
Rym: Every can't figure that out.
Rym: I figured that out a long time ago.
Rym: I think it's actually gone up since then.
Rym: All right, but literally like every single day we get new listeners and obviously everyone who listen seems to like us.
Rym: and Despite we never really advertise.
Rym: We never really do anything other than the show.
Scott: We promoted conventions but that's it
Rym: and even then promoting at conventions is a recent thing that we didn't really do partly because we weren't sure how to go about it and we've always felt really kind of odd trying to plug ourselves to People like hey listen to this podcast.
Rym: It's on the internet.
Scott: Also, I'm not confident that the promoting ethic at the conventions works.
Scott: I mean we gave all those CDs out of Katsucon.
Scott: How many people listen to the show now?
Scott: because the Katsucon CD if you discovered us via the Katsucon CD Please email us.
Rym: Yes, just we're curious.
Rym: This will help us out because actually I did see a spike on feed hits of fairly significant one after Katsucon But it wasn't as big as you would expect.
Rym: but then again, we actually promoted ourselves very little at the con.
Scott: Yeah, we could have done better.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, the way I see it right is that you know the mainstream media.
Scott: I'm kind if some like radio station came along and said hey Can we syndicate your show on our whatever right I'd be like.
Scott: well you can follow the Creative Commons license But since you're commercial you probably can't do that.
Scott: So if you want you will can make a deal with you and I would probably let them syndicate the show in exchange for money and I'd be more than happy to do so.
Rym: I've explored a few syndication options and it basically Comes down to the fact that terrestrial radio is right out because the FCC Yep, and we occasionally say the word fuck so they can't do that.
Rym: Fuck that then cuz we just we wouldn't censor ourselves ever.
Rym: Nope And I've looked into it.
Rym: It's not that far out of the realm to get syndicated on satellite radio for us Like honestly the more I've looked into it.
Rym: It's really not that far out of the realm.
Rym: however I think that we need a little more consistency in the show before we could do that and I'm not really willing to Conform the show into that kind of format.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the satellite radio.
Scott: your show has to be like exactly a number of seconds long and you need to put like this beeping noise like at the Ends that when you send the mp3 to the satellite radio guy He can run it through his thing.
Scott: and there's also a few.
Rym: when it comes to commercial syndication like that there are a few minor gray areas in terms of copyright because while we have permission from the author of the song we use in The beginning of the show the song is based on a commercial property and it's not a parody.
Rym: But it's really kind of this gray area.
Rym: Yeah, and we're never will obviously never get in trouble using it as we have but if we started selling the show straight up syndicated commercially.
Rym: There is a tiny chance of legal trouble and I haven't had a chance to have my lawyer look over it partly because that's really Not on the horizon in the next year or so.
Scott: Also, you know it says everyone seems to assume.
Scott: Oh you're doing this amateur deal to break into the real deal.
Scott: Well, you know what I say.
Scott: this is the real deal.
Scott: It might not be the real deal right now But in the long run the new media the blogs the podcasts the webcomics The YouTube videos in the long run it's that all that stuff is going to replace the current mainstream media.
Scott: the TV the movie theater the the Newspaper all that stuff is gonna go away and all the stuff that us geeks are doing is going to be the replacement.
Scott: So we might not be the mainstream now but we're basically on the boat that is going to become the mainstream and the old Titanic is going to sink.
Scott: and Why should we bother to jump onto the sinking boat while it's the happening place?
Scott: We can just wait on our nice happy boat until it becomes the happening place.
Rym: so thus the question becomes more importantly simply your plans to break into anything to actually break out and Starting this year.
Rym: We're really gonna start promoting ourselves, but not in the traditional way.
Rym: We're never gonna pay for ads or anything like that.
Rym: At least I don't see us doing that mostly because I'm not.
Scott: I mean mostly because I'm anti advertising and it's sort of hard to complain about ads and then buy some Even though I don't mind being hypocritical to the kind of people who would like GeekNights So the kinds of people who run ad block Yep.
Scott: And also I am not confident that the amount of money we would have to pay to get any sort of advertising Would actually give us any sort of return in listenership that we want.
Rym: So, I guess I'm not gonna give you our whole five-year plan.
Rym: So I got why don't call it that it'll fail.
Rym: I got Twilight struggle on the mind.
Rym: Yeah yeah, but the first phase of kind of the next wave.
Rym: because if you look at our graph of listenership we have Surges and then plateaus.
Rym: It's always surge plateau search plateau and every surge is after we figure something out or we do something different Usually with how people find out about us.
Rym: and this time around We're really starting to break out into the anime and gaming Convention circuit and not in the old way where we just put flyers around and we did like one panel on.
Rym: This is how to do a podcast on the internet at Sunday morning.
Rym: And now we're doing like ConnectiCon.
Rym: We're gonna run like eight or nine events there and this all stems back to ConnectiCon last year where we had You know, we were walking around and promoting ourselves made flyers and it wasn't really working.
Rym: So eventually we basically stole someone's artist alley table.
Scott: Well, it's good.
Scott: It wasn't really stealing an empty one It was we knew the person.
Scott: Yes, it was cool.
Rym: We still stole it from them.
Rym: But yes, not that they were using it.
Scott: No, they weren't.
Rym: So we're sitting there and we're just talking like we do on the show because he realized that we have conversations like this Regardless of whether or not anyone's here.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We're just angled a little more toward each other instead of toward you.
Scott: But if there's a third person toward you who's not here toward you who is a metal stick that cost about $80.
Rym: But we gave up on trying to promote our show and no one wanted our stupid little flyer.
Rym: no one cared.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if I go to conventions people give me flyers I throw them out.
Rym: Usually I get the big pile and I sit it on my desk and I think all right once I get free time I'm gonna go through all these because I obviously picked him up for a reason doesn't happen.
Rym: and then a month later I see this pile of papers.
Rym: What's that?
Rym: I throw it away.
Scott: Yep I mean once I was given a CD in our to Sally Otakon and I actually put it in my computer.
Scott: The thing is the CD was done in such a way that I couldn't actually explore the content on it with great ease and you know.
Scott: But I did put it in my computer when I got home and it had some flash Animations and things that they weren't so good, but I don't remember who made the thing.
Rym: So yeah, but the idea was there.
Scott: Yeah, it was actually.
Scott: hey, they gave me a thing and I actually checked it out.
Scott: Hence the audio CD at Casa con.
Scott: and apparently people did listen to that audio CD at Casa con.
Scott: I just don't think it translated into people subscribing to the podcast Because I've yet to see anyone say that they started listening because of the Casa con CD.
Rym: But then again, you know the percentage rule I mean maybe a tiny percentage of the people who listen will ever bother with the forums or emailing us or anything because I know how many people listen and I know how many people post in the forums and there's a big discrepancy between the two.
Scott: There's a lot of people sign up for the forums and ever post.
Scott: a lot of you will read the forums and they don't post Anything.
Scott: I'm like what?
Scott: All right Listen everybody whether you're the kind of person who posts in forums or not.
Scott: if you're just the lurking shy Nothing wrong with lurking Scott.
Scott: I know passive Listener who just listens to the show and doesn't do anything else.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: send us one email or make one post in the forums and then go back to your lurking ways.
Scott: I want to know you exist.
Scott: prove it to me because I don't believe it.
Rym: Yeah for all we know we have one listener with a thousand IP addresses Yeah, and he just keeps it in the side at all of them.
Rym: All right, but Basically, we're there and we gave up on promoting.
Rym: So we're just talking to each other and we start arguing and then someone at the table next to us starts arguing with us.
Rym: Not an angry argument, but a friendly argument.
Rym: I think we were talking about video games or something
Scott: something like that
Rym: and Two people were walking by and they stopped and they stand there kind of across the hall Just watching our little group and listening to us talk
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and then later other people start talking and someone walks up and they start talking to us and we're like, yeah At the end of the conversation like yeah, we do a show and they're like really well I really like to listen to that and we've realized that the best way to promote ourselves is To just do the things we do and to run events and to actually do awesome things.
Rym: and if people think that things are awesome They'll seek us out as opposed to trying to convince people that were awesome with a piece of paper that says our name on it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean tell me if I'm wrong listeners But I think the selling point of the show is our personality.
Scott: So the best way I think that we can promote the show Well, it's my personality right.
Scott: right is to put I'm not talking about personality in that sense talking about our personalities as nouns You know Not.
Scott: the right is to just put that out there for people to experience and if people like what they experience Then they will want more.
Scott: It's sort of like giving out free samples as a you know of the real deal live in person as opposed to a CD Which isn't really a free sample because the whole show is free.
Scott: Yeah, you get the idea.
Rym: Yeah, but we're starting to do this at cons.
Rym: I mean Katsucon.
Rym: last year We've wrote I guess this past one We ran the anime match game in the smallest panel room But we filled it to overflowing and everyone there really really loved it and they even went to the con feedback and said man those Guys were awesome bring him back.
Rym: Yeah, so next year I imagine we're gonna run a whole bunch of events and ConnectiCon there.
Rym: We're gonna run a whole bunch of events and anime next hasn't gotten back with me, but I'm working on that and Otakon.
Rym: I think we're gonna run a bunch of events.
Scott: Yep, so you seem to be doing pretty well with the promoting at the anime and we could also do the gaming cons Even though they're less panel oriented, but well ubercon will be fine at except there was no spring ubercon this year.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, but I think we need to need to find some way to promote more into the other geeky areas.
Rym: Yeah, and it's tough.
Rym: I mean I'd go to penguin Khan every year.
Rym: I'm sure we could rock penguin Khan.
Rym: Oh, we could totally rock penguin But penguin Khan's in Michigan and while driving to Michigan from Rochester wasn't so bad driving there from here Really sucks.
Scott: and all the other tech conferences are sort of not even accessible to us.
Scott: Really like.
Scott: they either cost a lot of money and they're meant for business professionals, you know on business trips and they're all useless.
Rym: I could do a show on how stupid those things are.
Scott: yeah, and There's other kinds where it's like a bunch of hackers get together for a weekend to code something and while those have pretty cool Atmospheres, I really don't have time for that.
Scott: You know, it's like I got to code my own stuff.
Rym: Yeah, well, I mean if we went to an event like that, we wouldn't be a Def Con or something We wouldn't be performers.
Rym: We just be press covering it.
Rym: Yeah, and as we've learned being press at an event while interesting for us is not interesting for anyone else.
Rym: So no one has any reason to remember us.
Rym: Yeah I mean what you're gonna remember the guy who shoves a microphone in your face and ask you why you're dressed up like Sailor Moon Despite the fact that you weigh 700 pounds.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it's definitely all about being the entertainer and not reporting on the entertainment.
Scott: All right, let's go.
Scott: the next question Where your career will be?
Rym: well see in both of our job, we basically have taken turns leapfrogging each other in terms of salary and Neither one of us has ever been satisfied with a job pretty much ever.
Scott: now I mean, this is the best job maybe the best job yet and it's I can't see doing this for the rest of my life.
Scott: Let me just say that much plus we.
Rym: we constantly make less money than we should be making and every time we get a new Job, we make more money.
Scott: Yep, so we'll see where this job goes.
Scott: I mean, I've only been here a month, but you know, I'll change it eventually almost definitely.
Rym: Yep I'm actually gunning for a promotion in my job because basically the job I do While fairly technical I could teach some high school kid how to do it in like a couple days And I could make at least 20k more doing the actual network architecture stuff.
Rym: So I'm actually pushing to get a promotion.
Rym: if I don't get the promotion.
Rym: I might just quit.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: I mean ideally I would very much like to do something I wanted to do like run a computer repair shop in town or oh Be a baker or I might dream job has always been so like be the high school Computer teacher, but that is not a possible job.
Scott: It just doesn't exist and it doesn't pay enough for me to live.
Rym: I mean even we lived in a high-paying school district like a really good school or even at a private school.
Rym: Yeah, we we'd make less money Working as a teacher like far less money than we make now doing our crap jobs for relatively little salary compared to the median in This area.
Scott: Yeah, I mean sure the teachers get summer off But even if you factor that in we'd still be making less money.
Scott: and also they won't let me be just a computer teacher And they won't let me decide the computer curriculum and they won't let me make all the important technology Decisions that I need to make.
Scott: they're just gonna say alright you teach math for periods a day a day And then you teach one crappy computer class on these shit computers these kids who don't give a shit and it's just not worth it.
Scott: but I know that if I was in charge of teaching computers, then that would be the best job in the world and Every kid who went to that school because it would totally be a mandatory class every freaking semester to be with me and learn about Computers.
Scott: every kid who came out of that school would be a computer master and could just go to RIT and walk get a degree in like six months.
Scott: So I'll know you're not six months.
Scott: It is kind of hard.
Rym: But yeah, yeah much less than five years It seems a lot easier because we always look back on it with our current experience.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I look back on sysadmin class and I remember having so much trouble making bind work in Red Hat.
Scott: and now The kids would be on the fast track to graduating and many of their early classes would be extremely easy pretty much our careers.
Rym: We're gonna continue to make more money and the moment we stop making more money or we have the resources do what we want to do.
Rym: We're gonna do what we want to do as soon as we can.
Scott: Yep, and unless something crazy happens like a lottery winning or So we're discovered by someone with a lot of money who decides they want to you know invest in us.
Rym: We need the old wealthy benefactor who has millions hidden in Europe.
Scott: It's called an angel investor.
Scott: I think is the is the current buzzword.
Rym: Oh, whatever.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, unless something crazy like that happens We're gonna keep working nine to five coming home and doing a show and having fun on the weekend until for the foreseeable future.
Rym: Alright, so this last one here because I just looked at the.
Rym: we've been going on this pretty long actually for an easy lazy Thursday Yeah, but Mary's easy married children, etc.
Rym: And in parentheses this one always makes me laugh about our Rym says he will never have kids, etc.
Rym: Well, I really don't plan to have kids and I in general any time.
Rym: I would look at it one.
Rym: I don't even have time to take care of a dog because if I had time to take care of a dog you can bet Your ass that I would have a dog right now.
Rym: I love dogs my whole life with dogs.
Rym: the fact that I don't have a dog right now bothers me constantly.
Rym: Yet a kid takes slightly more effort than a dog and cost a little bit more money.
Rym: so kids ride out.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I don't really care about animals.
Scott: But if I had time I'd have a fish.
Scott: I have a little fish in a fish tank.
Scott: I don't have time for the fish in a fish tank and all you have to do is shake some food in there and clean The tank like once a month and I have time for that and I also wait to say it.
Rym: But in general having a kid would pretty much remove About 70% of the options that I have now that I want to pursue in my later life Because the amount of money and the amount of time the amount of resources I would have to spend I'm not saying I wouldn't get anything out of that.
Rym: I'm not saying people shouldn't have kids But it would definitely take away from me most of the things that I actually want to do with the rest of my youth.
Scott: Yeah, it's like up.
Scott: Well, there goes all those conventions.
Scott: There goes all that geekery right out the window up.
Scott: No more time to play Pokemon.
Rym: Yeah, if I had a feed the baby, there'd be no more GeekNights.
Rym: I can tell you that much.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much a hundred percent.
Scott: be no more sleep.
Scott: Talk about not sleeping now.
Scott: imagine if you had a kid there'd be no sleeping at all buried.
Scott: Yes, I mean night screaming.
Rym: I generally have seen that most of the people I've known who had kids I mean, they're still cool people though But they don't.
Rym: they can't run in the same Circles that we run in and I don't want to stop running in these circles at all.
Rym: And we have actually two friends who are they're getting married very soon.
Rym: We're looking forward to that, but they are planning eventually on having kids and I wish them the best of luck.
Rym: But I wonder how much they're going to be able to continue to go to anime cons And that sort of thing at least for the first several years.
Rym: They have the kid.
Scott: Yeah, I mean once the kid is like, I don't know sentient.
Scott: Yeah, like 10 ish, you know, like later element
Rym: It'll be awesome because Scott and I can be those crazy Uncles who teach the kid the real business about the world like the Flying Spaghetti Monster and how to hack their parents computers yep,
Scott: but until then the kids basically just a big bucket that you have to fill with food and money and Empty out because all the food and money turns into piss and shit and vomit.
Scott: as for me No, I mean I'm constantly looking for some woman but Yeah, fine.
Rym: Yeah, you're looking so hard.
Scott: I know that's mostly the reason I haven't found anyone is because I spend my time doing geekery because Frankly, you know as much as I would like some sort of female companionship.
Scott: My geekery is more important.
Scott: But that also sort of precludes female companionship because any sort of the such would Reduce the geekery which I don't want to do except it really doesn't I mean.
Rym: Everyone I've ever dated in my life has been really geeky and really into all the things I'm into and I haven't found anyone like That that I want to get with.
Scott: so that's just how it is.
Rym: also consider the fact that all the women We know are very attractive and very cool and very geeky.
Scott: Yeah, and how many of them are like potential whatnots?
Rym: Here, I don't know what.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into that with you.
Rym: We've had this argument offline cuz I don't embarrass anyone But I would say that a good number of the people in our extended group of friends are pretty attractive and pretty much, right?
Rym: I don't know what your problem is with them.
Scott: They're all taken or I don't like them in that way.
Rym: Oh, you don't like him.
Scott: You just basically told I don't like him in that Way, ah, there's been liking someone and liking someone in that way.
Scott: So what would it take?
Scott: I like a lot of people.
Rym: What would your perfect girl be?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I know it's well, you know when you see it like, you know good boxing when you see Muhammad Ali beat someone up.
Rym: But I think we established that that doesn't end well because you can't actually ever find it or anything.
Scott: Regardless, I'm not putting that too much effort into looking even though it's something I'd like to find.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, that's the excuse.
Rym: I'm just not look.
Scott: what is true?
Scott: I mean when was the last time I put any effort into looking?
Rym: but you go to all these cons and what do I do?
Rym: Well, you could go be social and I don't do that really.
Rym: I guess you don't.
Scott: But yeah, so if I happen to find someone that'd be pretty cool getting married.
Scott: Uh, if I got married, it would be sort of like a financial decision.
Scott: Yeah, I really have no value in the institution of marriage.
Scott: The only value I would have is hooray we can combine our money into one bank account and pay less taxes.
Scott: That's really, you know I mean there might be some woman that I spend the rest of my life with and love more than anyone and all that.
Scott: But I wouldn't get married or have any sort of weird ceremonies or anything like that.
Scott: Yeah, I would just go to a courthouse and sign a paper if it was beneficial to do so.
Rym: well, I mean Emily and I have been together for many years now and Marriage really isn't on the docket at all.
Rym: but it doesn't mean that we're in any way thinking about breaking up or anything and I foresee us being together pretty much unless something happens for the rest of our lives, but I don't Really see if we'd ever get married.
Scott: Yeah, as far as I'm concerned like if I did have a wedding it would be going on to the courthouse.
Scott: Give the judge 10 bucks sign a paper go home.
Rym: Well, that's what my mom did when she got remarried She but they went to the courthouse.
Rym: They had a little ceremony and then they just had a crazy barbecue party at home.
Rym: Yeah, that sounds like a plan to me with a roast pig and it was pretty awesome.
Scott: I'd probably like get a party to Dave and Busters, but that's fine, too.
Scott: You know having kids I don't know.
Scott: see it's sort of hard because I'm sort of of the mind that like I would like to have kids you know because I imagine like having a kid and Raising him to be or him or her to be all awesome like me and then all that good stuff.
Scott: But it's like if I do it while I'm young.
Scott: I sort of ruined my own life in a way that Rym just said.
Scott: But I don't want to be like Penn Jillette and do it when I'm old because then you sort of it sucks for the kid.
Scott: You know, he doesn't have too much time with me and almost no time with grandparents and as a recent kid I valued that time quite a bit.
Scott: So it's sort of like I can either make a kid now and make him real well or But it'll suck for me or I can make it later and it'll suck for the kid.
Rym: Hence I decided to just not have a kid.
Scott: So if I if I did ever make a kid on purpose it would have to be at like this exact Perfect timing like where I had lived enough of my awesomeness that I didn't need anymore.
Scott: But it was still early enough in my life where I could raise the kid well and his life wouldn't suck either.
Scott: So you wouldn't have like a 40 year old 50 year old dad when he was like three.
Rym: I think that's one point where we're different where I don't think I would ever not continue to be ambitious Because I mean everyone knows the other person knows that I am continually and permanently ambitious and I'm always seeking more than I have.
Rym: and While I could be very happy with something Usually when it comes to you know life fortune property that sort of thing I always kind of test the waters that.
Rym: could I have more?
Rym: could I have a bigger house?
Rym: could I have more money?
Rym: Can I travel more?
Rym: could I know anything like that?
Rym: Can I have more power?
Rym: Can I get into politics?
Rym: if I was a congressman in the House of Representatives?
Rym: I'd be gunning for the Senate if I was in the Senate.
Rym: I'd be gunning for the presidency.
Rym: Yeah, if I was the president I'd be gunning for the UN.
Rym: if I was the head of the world I'd be gunning for Space King.
Scott: Yeah But I look and I see there are quite a few people in fact most people in positions much higher than we are Who have kids.
Scott: I mean Bill Clinton has a kid.
Scott: Got way ahead of was in terms of ambition.
Scott: So there it is possible to have a kid and still keep the ambition going strong.
Scott: The thing is I wondered like how did those kids turn out?
Scott: You know does that have a strong effect on them?
Scott: who knows well?
Rym: How much did she see her dad?
Rym: He was probably busy much of the time.
Scott: Yeah, it's like do I want to have a kid if I'm not gonna see them?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: those are decisions for a later time because right now there isn't even one to make a kid with.
Scott: So yeah, that's that.
Rym: yeah, I'm definitely liking the idea of a dink.
Rym: I remember I never realized when I was young watching Doug.
Rym: yeah, mr.
Rym: dink dink is actually one of those acronyms that came out when they're in the days when they're calling people yuppies and guppies and All those things.
Rym: and and no we are not guppies despite the fact that we've been called such more than once.
Rym: but dink stands for dual income no kids and Considering the fact that the household right now of Scott and I we make fairly significantly over six figures.
Rym: Yeah as a household and if Emily moves in with us We're making a fairly stupid amount of money, especially considering our expenses.
Rym: yep, and if I think how much money my parents made if they hadn't had to deal with me or my little brother or How much money I have if I don't have to spend it on something like a kid.
Rym: Oh I'll live in relative luxury for the rest of my life.
Scott: It's especially because we're not you know, we follow that If you don't have the money don't buy anything Don't buy shit you can't afford.
Scott: Yeah as we basically Don't bot live above our means we'd spend less than we make and we're always profiting.
Scott: every month I look at my checking account and no matter how much nerdy shit I try to buy I try to buy more comics I try to buy more video games and at the end of the month I go Oh, man, I think about too many video games.
Scott: this month I bought like 2ds games in a Wii game and I bought like a $200 box of comics.
Scott: Oh, this is this is gonna hurt.
Scott: and I look and every month without fail the balance of my checking account Increases by a lot every time.
Rym: mine's been pretty steady But I spend a lot more time and money on going out to eat and had so an entertainment and transient things.
Scott: I do quite a bit of those things as well, but checking account just keeps going up.
Scott: I don't know what's going on.
Scott: It scares me.
Scott: But yeah kids would just ruin that.
Scott: kids would completely ruin that.
Scott: I'd probably go into horrible debt.
Scott: But as long as I don't go into horrible debt as long as I stay employed.
Scott: We're doing alright.
Rym: Alright, I think we should wrap this up.
Rym: We've been talking for almost an hour just on this.
Scott: I guess that guy sent a good email.
Rym: I hope people actually like oh, oh, oh Basically, he said well Rym talk about yourself and talk about the awesome things you do and the awesome things you want to do That.
Rym: how long could that possibly take?
Scott: Well, let's see if anyone actually liked this episode or if they thought it was terrible.
Rym: Yeah it is gonna be one of those rare episodes that gets the meta tag which we used to do a lot early on.
Rym: when we Do shows like what the fuck are we gonna do with Monday nights?
Rym: We can't talk about science.
Rym: We got over that pretty quick Yeah, or how are we gonna fix the show?
Rym: or these microphones suck?
Rym: We kind of got past all that.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's a good thing that we got past all that because those kind of shows are so The beginning Podcaster.
Rym: yeah a little hint because this is part of that book.
Rym: I'm writing the word before we end.
Rym: if you're a prospective podcaster pretty much the worst thing you can do beyond You know actual bad serious problems is to constantly say the word podcast in your podcast Or to talk about your podcast in the meta a lot.
Rym: Yep I mean a lot of people.
Rym: they always call their show the blah blah blah podcast and if you call it that Word still stands out to a lot of people and it goes from this is just some show I'm listening to - this is a podcast those things on the internet.
Scott: Yeah, also people, you know If you spend your entire show talking about the show the people are listening to What's your show?
Scott: It's just something talking about itself.
Scott: It's just this inverse loop of nothing.
Scott: your show the vast majority of your show 99% of it has to be a show About something.
Scott: if it's a video game show you shouldn't talk about the show for more than 30 seconds.
Scott: You know, no matter how I guess if your show is five minutes long You shouldn't talk about your show itself more than saying the name and then talking about video games the rest of the time.
Rym: So on that note, we'll wrap it up and remember you can save the children, but don't save the British children.
Scott: God, he's coming.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.