Scott: It's Wednesday January 10th.
Rym: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight we review Initiality.
Scott: Let's do this Unless you've been living under a rock in the world of the interwebs.
Scott: There is one thing which has been dominating the news since yesterday or yesterday.
Scott: Yeah yesterday and We're not talking about it today at all.
Scott: I'm not even gonna mention it.
Rym: You mean that a fruit company.
Scott: It could be something having to do with that, but we're not gonna talk about it at all.
Scott: They made that phone whatever that you already said.
Scott: too much.
Rym: I Something.
Scott: let's talk about anime or manga comics or whatever.
Rym: I think we're mostly gonna talk about anime today.
Scott: That's I have a feeling that we will talk a great deal about anime today.
Rym: I mean if you couldn't gather from the Interesting opener we used up might be a little bit of a special episode.
Scott: Special isn't even begun to describe how awesome this episode will be and not special like the ballad boy down the street.
Scott: No Well, I guess depending on your point of view it could be special like that.
Scott: What are you talking about it?
Scott: but in a good way?
Rym: Yeah, that kids a maven.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, I'm gonna jump right into the news here cuz there was actually a lot of anime news a lot of it.
Rym: Not gonna talk about any great detail because I don't really care and I think you know My sentiments exactly as to how I would feel about this news.
Rym: For example Nana possibly Theoretically plans in quotes to air in the u.s.
Scott: Well at the end of every Nana episode they have this girl I don't is she like the voice actor or something or I don't know what she is.
Rym: It's not as room Yeah and she.
Scott: she sits in Nana's room and she talks about the show and she tells you what like.
Scott: Oh the soundtrack is available.
Scott: go buy it.
Rym: She tells you what to buy and when.
Scott: yeah, and she's like, oh there's a new Nana DVD.
Scott: go buy it and stuff like that.
Scott: So at the end of one of the recent episodes episode 31 Yeah she said Nana is gonna be on TV in the US holy crap.
Scott: and no US anime company or Cartoon Network or anyone has said anything about that.
Scott: So we'll wait and see.
Scott: and cuz you mean Japanese people wouldn't know if she was lying.
Rym: Yeah Maybe they mean by airing in America that they're going to broadcast it at high strength over the ocean.
Scott: That would be so awesome.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, so one piece.
Rym: how many movies do you think one piece is made?
Scott: I know they've made too many.
Scott: Well, the thing I don't know is are the one-piece movies Are they summary movies of the TV series?
Scott: because if so That's actually a good thing because now you can get the whole TV series and just like you know a few hours instead of watching hundreds upon hundreds of episodes or reading volumes and volumes of manga if they're not summary movies if they're actually like at Important parts in the TV series you have to insert a movie because that part of the plot is so crazy.
Scott: And that's bad because now not only is a hundreds of episodes, but it's a fistful of movies, too.
Rym: I have a feeling I mean once.
Rym: obviously you can tell her ignorance.
Rym: Neither one of us have seen a single one of these movies.
Scott: yeah, I've watched four episodes of one piece in my life and I've read about ten volumes of manga and that's that's way too much as much as I'm gonna read.
Rym: But I imagine it's a lot like the Sailor Moon movies, which I've seen all of in that or the cowboy bebop movie.
Rym: They don't.
Rym: I mean they take place Theoretically at a point along the actual TV continuity and I guess you could consider them Canon, but nothing in them Affected the the actual plot in any way.
Rym: like you could take him or leave him basically standalone story.
Scott: Well, it's obviously one of those three things We don't know which because we don't know anything about one.
Rym: of course That was a spoiler for every Sailor Moon movie because if you watch them all Sailor Moon dies But yet somehow she's not dead by the end.
Scott: I guess it wouldn't be a movie without doing that.
Rym: I think Dave and Joel were bitching about that in the Sailor Moon our movie where every movie is like don't use the super Extra power to save the day you'll die.
Rym: She says but I have to for the sake of the world and then she just doesn't die for some reason.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Rym: Yeah, Chevalier, which we've seen two episodes of and which my opinion of the first episode was a hundred percent awesome I opinion the second episode was 50% fail.
Rym: So it's still you know, right around to see.
Rym: a solid C is Coming to the anime network.
Rym: Regardless of whether or not it's a good show as far as I'm concerned I think Chevalier is gonna do real well in the US.
Rym: among the anime networks viewers.
Scott: It's definitely better than a lot of the other anime that came out this season.
Scott: So I think in this next round of upcoming shows is gonna be one of the top shows even though overall it might.
Scott: Who knows if it's a great show or not?
Scott: I think it's an average show even if it's not great.
Rym: I have a feeling that is gonna be fun.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think it's possible for that show to go into the realm of bad.
Scott: I think the worst it can be is average which is you know, if there's nothing else to watch.
Scott: I really
Rym: imagined myself getting the same enjoyment and the same type of enjoyment out of Chevalier That most people get out of say Fist of the North Star or giant robot shows, you know, it's bad You know, it's nothing to be proud of and yet you love every second of it.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: I put it on the same level as say Probably Gonkutsu or something like that.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think Gonkutsu was probably a lot better than Chevalier.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I actually kind of like the first episode of Chevalier more than I like.
Scott: You know the Gonkutsu I've seen.
Rym: well, you haven't read the Count of Monte Cristo One of the greatest works ever written in French.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I don't got time for that shit.
Rym: You can't even knock that book off in like two weeks.
Scott: Anyway, I knocked off a lensman book in three days and that provided crazy amounts of enjoyment.
Rym: Yeah, I don't really care about any of the rest of this other than a Bobobo Bo Bo Bo Bo Bo Season.
Scott: we seem to be the only people who can say that correctly.
Rym: I don't know how hard.
Scott: there's seven There's seven bows.
Scott: So you do four and then three.
Scott: Bobobo Bo Bo Bo Bo.
Rym: We showed that at our anime club back in Rochester when it first aired in Japan as soon as it was fansub.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: We said the name right.
Rym: even then how can people still be getting it?
Scott: How all these people like?
Scott: whenever they see the name on paper, they just go up Bobo Bobo, whatever it's called.
Scott: And I'm like, it's not that hard Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo Bobo, but I can't fail to say it properly Not difficult.
Rym: we did a tutorial before we showed it in the club.
Rym: We were like, it's Bobo Bobo pause Bobo Bo.
Rym: And we made everyone say it before we showed it to a guy who attacks with his nose hair.
Rym: God that show.
Scott: it's worth it to watch like one or two episodes for the like.
Scott: It's it's the wackiest of wacky comedies.
Rym: You gotta watch that show up to Don Pachi.
Rym: There's nothing left after that.
Scott: That's about.
Scott: I think that's about right because Don Pachi shows up and it's funny because all we got is Don Pachi.
Scott: But then after that, I don't think it goes anywhere At least not from what I saw.
Rym: Yeah, so if you haven't gathered it, I'm just reading off the anime news network.
Rym: But the actual news we want to talk about is in Scott's round.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I have the good news here.
Scott: So Viz who this doesn't really do DVDs?
Scott: do they?
Scott: they're mostly the manga, right?
Scott: I'm sure they do some anime.
Scott: But anyway, well, they definitely do anime because that's what this news says.
Scott: Viz has licensed the Death Note anime, right which is still on the air in Japan, which is kind of crazy.
Rym: Yeah, I mean usually the anime companies in Japan seem to have this deathly fear that someone in America will Resell the American cheap DVDs back to Japan's.
Rym: they never let anything get licensed and released over here Until long after they've sold their $70 DVD even though if Japanese people really wanted to they could just bit torn the shows.
Scott: Yeah, it's like or wait or wait.
Scott: Anyway, they have licensed the Death Note anime because they already putting out the Death Note manga which they're almost done putting out and But they haven't licensed it in the usual fashion.
Scott: They have licensed the download to own and download to rent rights Which means pretty much that you're going to be able to download the Death Note anime I assume with a dub of some sort in the United States Legally with some DRM's.
Rym: if only it weren't the DRM's I'd be all about that.
Scott: You know, we always say hey, how come you don't bring this stuff over faster bla bla bla bla bla.
Scott: and Viz is like Hey, we're bringing it over when you want like, you know, and you seem to like digital.
Scott: So here we're bringing it to you digitally.
Scott: But the DRM is the one mistake.
Scott: people have a hard enough time Bit torrenting and getting their codecs to work now, you're gonna want him to put some DRM shit in there.
Scott: It's just not gonna happen.
Scott: You know, I mean while They might have an advantage in that this license is gonna make the fan subbing stop at least the you know Open easy to get at fan subbing stop.
Scott: So it might be easier to get the episodes from Viz.
Scott: it's The DRM is gonna stop a lot of people and their underground fan subbers are still gonna end up winning.
Rym: see now if they were somehow doing it with iTunes or in some sort of DRM that people are already accustomed to or Some sort of DRM that was widely used or a service maybe that offered a lot more than just this They'd probably do a lot better.
Rym: Yeah, probably but if it's just that like I could see myself installing some horrible DRM thing if there was enough good stuff On it and the price was right.
Scott: I wouldn't.
Scott: but okay.
Rym: Well, like say there was a service where for ten cents you could get any anime that's ever been released in the u.s Keep forever for you.
Rym: It's just DRM too little so you can't give it to other people.
Scott: Well, you know, it's kind of weird.
Scott: It's like if it's on my computer, right?
Scott: It's like I don't want to install DRM software on my computer because that feels like.
Scott: you know I have my computer can do this thing and you've taken you know, you're restricted my computer.
Rym: Oh, you mean like iTunes right which you have.
Scott: no iTunes only screws you if you buy stuff from iTunes.
Scott: It doesn't screw you if you just use it to handle regular old mp3s.
Scott: true.
Rym: You haven't bought anything.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But if they sold like, you know a set-top box or some sort of pay-per-view on your cable box or something like that That would totally fly because they're not really restricting anything You can't already do you know?
Scott: if they had like just push buttons on my cable remote and pay a dollar to watch Death Note That would be pretty hot I don't know.
Rym: regardless of whether or not we'll use the service or anyone we know will use the service I think this is definitely a step in the right direction and I I hope it's at least at least they've Recognized that they got to do something and they're making a move.
Scott: They just haven't made the final move.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it just comes down to somehow getting the licenses early on.
Rym: Like maybe I'd say wait a little bit to make sure that the show is popular in the US by keeping an eye on the fan Subs license the shit out of that stuff right away and have it come out right away.
Rym: And if the Japanese companies won't let you do whatever they just did to let the jet to get away with this.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, honestly, I'll bet the reason they're getting away with this is that the system will probably not allow people in Japan.
Scott: Yeah, probably either won't allow people in Japan or people in Japan will be.
Scott: you know, Drm didn't have to pay money.
Rym: So it's not like they're you know, re importing anything Yeah, but it'll still charge so much less than a DVD.
Scott: I mean if it costs plus even though it'll still be behind what's on TV in Japan right now.
Scott: You know, it's not gonna.
Scott: it's not like they're getting a DVD.
Scott: You know, it doesn't compete with the DVD to purchase in Japan.
Scott: it competes with the TV to watch in Japan and it can't beat that because in Japan the TV's got episode 10 and over here.
Scott: We've got episode 1. so it you know It's not stopping anyone from buying DVDs or watching TV in Japan.
Scott: Even if Japanese people can access it.
Rym: Oh one last news before I get away from this whole news thing because I just noticed this and I actually read it and I realized That is something a lot of you'll probably care about even though it's barely related to anime.
Rym: Avatar apparently is going to have a number of live-action movies.
Scott: I don't think that's the.
Scott: is it the same avatar?
Scott: Yes, cuz I saw that very specifically.
Rym: This is avatar the Nicktoons cartoon.
Rym: This is not related to the other avatar movie.
Scott: Okay, cuz I saw some news today about an avatar movie, but that's where the confusion is.
Rym: There's a movie called avatar coming out from James Cameron.
Rym: independently of that Some guy got the rights to make a bunch of live-action avatar movies based on avatar the last airbender.
Rym: All right, we're gonna do a show on avatar once.
Rym: I've seen more of it But suffice to say I think that show is the top dog.
Scott: I haven't watched it and I remain skeptical.
Scott: things of the day.
Scott: My thing of the day is an animation, but it is not a Japanese Animation.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, really?
Scott: I'm following your trend from earlier in the week going with some Warner Brothers animations.
Rym: Warner Brothers a yep.
Rym: It's either one of two things.
Rym: My guess is that it's the Famous.
Rym: I know he has done it.
Scott: I don't know how he has done it, but I know he has done it.
Scott: Nope It's not what it is.
Scott: It's oh, he's hiding in the stove.
Scott: Hey, he's not he's not in his stove.
Scott: I did it backwards.
Rym: Good job.
Rym: Anyway, one of your most famous jokes ever one of the best bits and animation ever created as far as you're concerned And you messed it up.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: This is perhaps my favorite Looney Tune there is and this kind of shit isn't on TV anymore because well It shows a guy putting someone else in an oven turn it on the gas and throw it a match in there.
Rym: It's one of the.
Rym: I really I remember this as a kid and I remember it was not long ago.
Rym: We were before we realized it was on the internet and we could just watch it any time We wanted.
Rym: we were talking about all these moments and quotes from old cartoons that we remember so dearly.
Scott: When I was a kid Looney Tunes was on all the time.
Scott: You could always find it on some channel or another and this one no matter how many times they came on It was always funny just to hear him say.
Scott: Oh, he's hiding in the stove.
Scott: Hey, and also it has the famous line Get it dead net And It's just.
Scott: it's such a great cartoon and it's only seven minutes long and it's on YouTube.
Scott: I don't know how long it'll stay on YouTube.
Scott: Someone might find it and get rid of it.
Scott: But whatever you'll be able to find it Again, yeah, it'll come back up and it's actually a pretty high quality YouTube.
Scott: It's kind of scary when I look at it because this is made in 1954 or 55 54.
Scott: I was like, wow, it's old, you know I saw this on TV and like the 80s and 90s and I was a kid a hundred times and It was funny every single time just like the first time and it still is.
Scott: I can still watch it a hundred times.
Scott: It's that great.
Rym: so in the interest of not wasting any minutes before we get to the meat of tonight's episode initial My thing of the day is real simple.
Rym: This has been around the internet for a while But it was recently dug up and it's something everyone should read it.
Rym: I had never actually read it you'd think someone like me would have.
Rym: it is a very detailed graphical description of how ice rinks actually work.
Rym: and And Zambonis.
Rym: and before you think ruin Zambonis before you think Rym that's kind of lame.
Rym: You don't know how an ice rink works.
Rym: There's no way you know how it works unless you're from Canada.
Scott: You're wrong.
Rym: You don't know.
Rym: it doesn't work the way you think it does.
Scott: Yeah, how do they freeze all that ice and make it all flat and shiny and skate on it without killing people?
Rym: Yeah, and how do they make those lines appear?
Rym: They don't paint the stuff under the ice.
Scott: No, they paint it on the floor under the ice.
Rym: No, they don't.
Rym: you didn't even read it.
Scott: Did you that they have to?
Rym: no no, no, you know what they do what.
Rym: they layer a thin layer of ice Mm-hmm, then another thin layer of ice.
Rym: then they paint that ice white Uh-huh, then there's another layer ice.
Rym: then they paint the lines on that layer of ice and then they cover that with a whole bunch More eyes, huh?
Rym: The actual surface is kind of nappy.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Well, that's a word.
Rym: I haven't used since middle school.
Scott: Alrighty.
Scott: Oh Yeah, that's some good stuff right there.
Rym: see initial D didn't just get me interested in cars It didn't just give me a very high quality B anime to enjoy and yell and scream about.
Rym: it Didn't open me up to the world of racing manga.
Rym: it in addition to all of that It gave me eurobeat and super eurobeat music that to this day.
Rym: I can always dance to such energy.
Scott: See initial D. Let's see.
Scott: We first saw it at anime club and they showed four episodes.
Rym: Yeah bear in mind.
Rym: We weren't even Running the anime club.
Rym: We were just some freshmen sitting in the front row heckling.
Scott: Yep, and you know, I wasn't really paying much attention to it because we were all heckling and such so I didn't really get into It.
Scott: I was just like got a race.
Scott: Whoo.
Scott: We don't know if he wins or not.
Scott: Ooh, whatever the show was crap.
Rym: Let's help that.
Rym: It was just generally kind of a boring.
Rym: Alright, so car racing with bad PlayStation 1 animation.
Rym: What's this?
Scott: Yeah Not exactly the most best first impression made by an anime.
Rym: Yeah And the fourth episode because they only show four episodes of something at club Aided on the cliffhanger of well, does he win the race or not?
Rym: And we all thought I don't care.
Scott: Yeah, I really didn't give a shit.
Scott: I could have lived the rest of my life not knowing whether he won that race or not.
Rym: now I remember very clearly we were talking about how boring that anime was.
Rym: now much We disliked it now stupid it was.
Scott: and all that on the way back to our dorms and you know What most people who watch this show?
Scott: They stick with that opinion for the rest of their lives and you can't really blame them.
Rym: Yeah, even though we what I think it was me you asked So do you think he really wins or not?
Rym: And we talked about it a little bit before we gave up and went to play battle tech or something.
Scott: Yeah, that was good times But battle tech is definitely better than it'll be Now.
Rym: there is often the fallacy that just because the first impression of something is bad The rest of it must be bad Which has screwed a lot of people out of a lot of awesome things like Probably the best hockey game I ever saw where two of the people with us left before the crazy end.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people, you know They they don't like something or they do like something prior to experiencing it and they've already decided before they've seen it.
Scott: You know, they don't like it.
Scott: They go.
Scott: What's this an anime about?
Scott: cars screw that?
Scott: And then even if you show it to them, they already don't want to like it.
Scott: So they're never gonna like it and that's fine for them.
Rym: now for some godforsaken reason and to this day I don't know why cuz we know it's not like we had free time other than you know, the infinite free time We were already wasting playing battle tech and Dungeons & Dragons and board games.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We went to an initial D marathon.
Rym: I think we planned to show up Gather everyone we knew who was there skip out early and play a game or something.
Scott: That might have been the plan I don't remember but I do remember sitting there and watching all 26 episodes of the first season of initial D.
Rym: I remember.
Rym: I remember we decided we were all gonna go watch the fifth episode find out if he won or not and then leave Mm-hmm, but then it was kind of good.
Rym: So we wanted to see if he's gonna win the next one.
Scott: I think what happened?
Scott: I think part of it was sort of a peer pressure thing Like when we saw it at Anime Club, there were a lot of people there So everyone most of the people there had the vibe of and so we also had the vibe of it when we went to see the marathon.
Scott: there were very few people there and it was.
Scott: we were actually able to like pay attention to the Eurobeat music and you know feel the energy of the show and have it absorb into our bodies and Then it sort of melted us into the seats and we couldn't get away see.
Rym: several of our friends said All right He won the race great and then they left.
Rym: and they're like Rym and Scott Because no one called a scrim back then.
Rym: obviously no one calls a scrim now except are you listeners?
Scott: Can't be bothered to type anyway.
Rym: Yeah, his real name is Scott prime.
Rym: No anyway So they're like Rym and Scott.
Rym: Why aren't you leaving this terrible terrible show?
Rym: and we looked at them and said shut up.
Rym: I want to find out if he wins the gum tape deathmatch.
Scott: That's right fucking gum tape deathmatch for the win man.
Rym: This show went from 0 to 60 in about seven episodes.
Scott: I mean No one can say that the animation in this show is good.
Scott: In fact, it's ass in the first season.
Scott: The animation is as the characters are fugly.
Rym: I mean, how could no Buru Furu say who has done stuff for x-driver and You're under arrest and all these other great anime?
Rym: at least character design wise Make these characters.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Well, the answer is because they look like that in the manga and he had no control.
Scott: Yes, the manga of initially is by Shuichi Shigen.
Scott: Oh and it is almost identical to all the anime.
Scott: There is a slight difference in the first season of the anime in the chronological order of events Between the first season of anime and the manga and they're roughly equivalent.
Scott: It doesn't really matter.
Rym: Yeah the only if you're gonna read the manga.
Rym: all I'm gonna tell you is that what you must do is Get some eurobeat and play it in the background while you read.
Scott: I do that all the time.
Rym: If you don't do that, you're really gonna miss out on pretty much everything that makes initial Yeah, also like the third or fourth race in the manga is like the climax.
Scott: They save that race to the end of the first season and they took some races after it and moved it before.
Scott: So, you know you got to pick one or the other.
Scott: but after the first season of the anime Starting with the second season of the anime they pretend as if everything that happened was just like the manga and they forget that The first season changed the order of events.
Rym: So we're not gonna talk about the manga and I highly recommend you watch the anime first or just watch the anime.
Scott: Yeah, they're almost identical.
Scott: It doesn't really matter, you know.
Scott: Basically, all you really want to watch is the first season of the anime and possibly the movie.
Rym: possibly the movie is pretty good Yeah, but we're gonna talk mostly about the first season which begins great gets great ends Amazingly and it ends on a note where you don't need any more.
Rym: It didn't need to pull the one piece and keep going.
Rym: don't watch anything past that.
Scott: no I mean you could if you're really really like it.
Scott: keep watching because it's not as good after that.
Scott: after that It's mostly races and the other half of the show kind of fades away.
Rym: Yeah, cuz everyone.
Rym: here's the basic problem with people that they saw this show.
Rym: They thought it was about stupid car racing and made-up drift racing and they left.
Rym: But that's only half the show.
Rym: the other half of the show is funny high school romance kids Dealing at each other running around causing trouble
Scott: and there's definitely a story of you know Figuring out what you want to do when you grow up when you you know I mean and that how many kids in this country does that identify with?
Scott: where they're all like?
Scott: I don't know what I want to do.
Scott: I'll go to college and be undecided and blue You know, that's what initial D is about is figuring out what the hell you want to do and going for it.
Rym: I mean Starting to care about something for such a seemingly vapid and just silly show about drift racers in the mountains of Japan.
Rym: this ship the show actually has quite a few poignant moments and really actually and I'm not kidding has a Pretty good message that is executed very well and just a little bit moving.
Scott: Yeah after that though after the first season.
Scott: It's just drift racing.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: so if you like the racing part and you don't care about the fact that it katani likes this girl and Itsuki's a loser, but he's funny and then he gets into a car accident If you just want to watch Takumi race while music plays the rest of initial D is all for you
Scott: Yep, but if you're a normal person the first season is where the action is.
Rym: But like there's a scene near the like middling end like kind of on the rising tide of the show before the climax and everything We're talking me.
Rym: the main character goes out and washes his car Scene.
Rym: that is a that is probably I'd say in the top 50 scenes of anime ever.
Scott: Oh could be very well.
Rym: not top 10 No way, but it's animated so poorly.
Rym: then yeah But that's the power of the show that as dumb as it might seem the concept and as silly and joke ish and unrealistic as it might be This scene where he washes his car is actually really moving.
Scott: But I mean if you haven't seen you know the show and you you're not really paying attention to it Then that scene it just means nothing.
Scott: But once you know what has come before.
Scott: you know, you see this guy who didn't care about shit, you know He was racing because his dad told him well He guess he cares about girls and he was racing so he could get you know Free gas from his dad who would you know give basically pay him to race.
Scott: and then you know now here He is washing the car that no one told his dad didn't tell him to wash it.
Rym: He just washed up his own volition and then he stands there looking at it and he kind of has this look of.
Scott: I found my Way, yeah, it's good stuff.
Rym: Of course now I mentioned a bit, you know funny high school style humor.
Rym: It's not like all that other anime high school humor.
Scott: No, it's not like this isn't like a full metal panic thing where there's robots and then wacky anime high school.
Rym: It's realistic high school at least insofar as saved by the Bell was a realistic representation of high school.
Scott: Well, it's not so much saved by the Bell basically, it doesn't really concentrate on the school that much.
Scott: It's just characters who are high school age.
Rym: All right, let me put it this way It would be very very very realistic if it weren't for the fact that these racing gangs exist Yeah, and the fact that the way they talk to each other,
Scott: you know, it's actually more kind of like a happy days kind of thing.
Rym: Actually, yeah, I never really thought of it that way.
Scott: I just thought of that just now.
Rym: it kind of is.
Rym: I mean most of the scenes will show like a bunch of these guys hanging out at a diner along the mountain Yeah, or hanging out at the gas station where they all work.
Scott: Yep, and they're not really hanging out in the school so much.
Rym: So what is the plot of initial do you might ask there?
Scott: Okay ready get this.
Scott: there's a guy and He is the economy Fujiwara and his dad.
Scott: Him and his dad live alone and there his dad runs a tofu shop and he goes to school.
Scott: The dad sells tofu not only out of his shop, but he delivers tofu to many places.
Scott: One of those places is Akina hotel.
Scott: Well, Akina is where they live and there is a mountain Mount Akina.
Scott: at the top of this mountain is a Hotel for tourism to the mountain and the mountain has like a nice lake that you can go to if you go up the mountain And it's a nice touristy place.
Scott: Yeah but the the road going up to the mountain is kind of old and windy because it's a very steep very windy road that you have to go very slow and is very dangerous and There's lots of drift racing that goes on up there.
Scott: Anyway This dad, you know Fujiwara dad Boonter crazy Boonter.
Rym: Boonter is the best character in the show hands.
Scott: I was just gonna say that Boonter was the best character in the show.
Rym: Goddamn is Boonter great?
Scott: He doesn't want to deliver the tofu to the top of the mountain at the crack of dawn because well It's a pain in the ass.
Scott: So he makes his son do it.
Scott: when the sign his son was in middle school and not allowed to drive He made him do it because well, you know, it's on a back road in the middle of the night.
Rym: It's like four or five in the morning.
Rym: the Sun isn't even up yet and From what people have told me at least in places like that in Japan.
Rym: There's no one driving at night.
Rym: You're not gonna run into anyone.
Scott: There's no speed track.
Scott: I mean imagine if you lived in a tofu shop all alone and like the boonies and You had a you know a kid in seventh grade and he had a little tiny car and he could drive it Just not legally and you all you needed him to drive was up the mountain at night, you know at 4 in the morning.
Scott: I think he could I think he could manage.
Rym: so the kid does it Constantly every morning is to get up and drive this tofu up before he does.
Scott: now The thing is tofu sits in water.
Rym: Well, no, no, no, we can't get to that yet.
Rym: Okay, see Takumi doesn't like doing this.
Scott: Oh, he doesn't like doing it.
Scott: He wants to go to bed just like you and me.
Rym: So he starts driving as fast as he can and every day he gets a little bit faster.
Rym: He just got.
Rym: I mean he can't floor it.
Rym: Obviously he'd fall off the mountain and die.
Rym: But he drives the car as fast as he possibly can to get this done with and go back to bed on this incredibly dangerous mountain road.
Rym: and one day he goes a little too fast around the corners and Destroys the tofu.
Rym: you see now I can get to what Scott was talking.
Scott: So his dad beat him.
Rym: Yes, dad beat.
Rym: I mean it's not like the stupid live-action initial D movie Which you should ignore and avoid like the plague.
Scott: Yes, the live-action.
Scott: It's only movie is bad.
Rym: Very bad Yeah, I mean when bunta beats his kid in the live-action Chinese initial D he beats him half to death.
Scott: Yeah, now he just kind of whacks him on the head with the newspaper like, you know, funny anime style.
Scott: Anyway, so when he gets home dad's like are you messed up the tofu?
Scott: cuz tofu sits in water?
Scott: And if you disturb it too much then you can ruin it so you can't drive too recklessly.
Scott: So he puts a cup of water in the car and he says as long as the water stays in that cup when you drive Then the tofu won't be messed up because the tofu is also in water.
Scott: So Takumi's all pissed now because he has to drive slow again But he eventually learns to drive in a way that he can go fast without disturbing the water.
Rym: Now fast forward several years and this is where the anime begins.
Rym: Street racing gangs Roam the earth not really just.
Rym: there's mountains all over Japan and no one drives on him at night.
Rym: So punk kids with rice cars hang out and drift race around and have fun on the mountains.
Scott: Yeah, they form little gang and they take it in the anime.
Scott: The characters take it more seriously than people do in real life, but that's necessary Yeah, or else there's no point.
Rym: some of them don't.
Rym: the speed stars Until trouble happens, they don't take it that sir.
Scott: No, they don't.
Rym: but there's a bunch of little teams.
Rym: there's the Akina speed stars and there's the night kid yogi night kids and the Akagi red sun who will get to.
Rym: yeah now the red sons are a team that is run by two brothers Takahashi Ryosuke and case.
Rym: okay.
Scott: Yeah, they're the Takahashi brothers and their dad is a doctor a rich doctor So they have lots of money to buy fancy cars now.
Rym: These guys are also super bishonen and they have super fast cars.
Rym: one of them drives an rx-7 FC And one of them drives one of the best cars ever made the rx-7 FD.
Scott: There are awesome cars because they have Wankel engines not piston engines.
Scott: And if you don't know what that is, look it up because it's freaking on or watch the show and you'll learn a little bit About it.
Scott: Yeah, the closest thing you can get to it nowadays is a used rx-7 or an rx-8.
Rym: now think of this.
Rym: Here's a scale of how good this car is.
Rym: a used beat-up rx-7 goes for more than most brand-new cars today.
Rym: Yeah Like are and actually there was a guy at my work who had an rx-7 FD and he took me for a few spins in It.
Scott: and good fucking God It's quite an awesome car.
Rym: You would not believe how fast that guy could take it around corners.
Rym: Anyway anyway, so they're rich and the ryosuke the smart one.
Rym: You see Rose K is the smart bishonen one and case K is the wild and reckless emotional bishonen one.
Rym: But they're both really smart and they're both coincidentally street racers.
Rym: So he decides before he goes to doctor school.
Rym: at the end, you know, he's gonna leave he's gonna go to doctor school.
Rym: he wants to take his little team and Conquer every mountain in.
Rym: where are they?
Scott: Genma gun gun gun my gun my prefecture.
Rym: He wants to beat every street racing team on every mountain in the prefecture before he goes to medical school to prove that he is A badass.
Scott: Yeah, and he's already sort of famous for being a badass street racer.
Scott: So, you know and every mountain of course has a street racing team.
Scott: a mountain without a street racing team is unthinkable.
Scott: Yeah, so all he has to do is to go to every mountain see who's there Practice on that course a little bit and then beat them with his awesome fast car.
Rym: So the first mountain they pick they because it's in the middle of stick nowhere and they know that no one there can drive.
Rym: worth of Shit is Mount Akina and they have their plan, you know We're gonna start here and then we're gonna conquer the whole blah blah blah blah.
Rym: And this is where the cunning plan goes horribly awry and where the anime begins.
Scott: When one of them is practicing, you know learning the course because they you know The Akina speed stars are a bunch of schmucks and they can't really race at all.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they're just wannabes.
Rym: their leader Ikitani.
Scott: he gets and he's a good character and I like him But he can't drive for shit.
Scott: He's also a loose passed out in the third corner.
Scott: Anyway They're practicing on this course.
Scott: So one night case a case driving down the mountain and he sees some headlights in his rearview mirror.
Scott: now He's racing down this mountain.
Scott: So if he sees headlights in his rearview mirror that can only mean Someone is going as fast or faster than he is going.
Rym: so he speeds up, you know, whatever I'll leave this guy in my does.
Rym: no one's better than me except my brother and that's debatable.
Scott: and you know The only people around are people on his team and the Akina speed stars are a bunch of schmucks No one else would be racing down this hill.
Scott: So, you know, he knows it's not his brother because he can tell by the headlights.
Rym: so he's like, uh, well So he keeps going and going and this car keeps pace with him.
Rym: And finally he sees what kind of car it is.
Rym: He's debating what kind of car it is Like.
Scott: he's like oh is it this kind?
Scott: is it that kind?
Scott: all these fast cars?
Rym: and then he sees it and it's a Hachi Roku.
Scott: now Hachi Roku in Japan Japanese means eight six It's a toy.
Scott: basically this car, you know, it what do they call it the?
Scott: Train.
Scott: oh, yeah, it's a. it's a Toyota true a no 86 which really means that it's a Toyota Corolla.
Scott: effectively It's a Toyota Corolla from 1985 with a hatchback, but it's got this like 86 ae engine or whatever.
Rym: No, the ae 86 chassis.
Scott: That's right as opposed.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, because there's you can also get the knot.
Scott: It's the sportiest Toyota Corolla available in 1985.
Scott: It's actually a very famous Racing car in Japan.
Rym: Yeah, it's in fact It's still used today for a lot of nostalgic value and it's still a pretty good car if you modify it properly.
Scott: Yeah, I mean basically the reason they chose this car is because there's a guy called the drift King Who's like a famous drift racing guy in Japan a real guy and he actually comes up in the show once or twice.
Scott: Yeah, and This guy famously drove the 86 is car of choice for his drift racing.
Rym: Yeah, if you look search around for drift videos from Japan and look for actual ones on courses Not like punk kids burning rubber in a parking lot and you'll see what this is all about.
Rym: Yeah, it's half Racing and half showing off and another half.
Rym: I guess there's three halves rice.
Scott: Yeah, but I think it's a lot less rice than you see on the streets though.
Rym: Yeah Well, Japan is very different than America.
Scott: It is.
Rym: it is so He thinks what this crap old car?
Rym: and he puts the pedal to the metal and they the guys keeping pace with him.
Rym: He's thinking what the hell's up with this.
Rym: and then in the critical moment there's he knows there's a sharp corner coming up because it could bends around and then it bends back around and he slows the hell down because He doesn't want to die.
Rym: You can't go around that corner fast.
Rym: It's Carl to spin out I'll crash and this hot chiroku just goes on full bore and he's thinking.
Rym: Oh, no, this guy was an amateur.
Rym: He totally fucked up.
Rym: Now.
Rym: He's gonna die and I'm gonna have to watch it.
Rym: Oh, no, and then Now the anime slows down into slow motion at this point to show this car Drift a little bit to the one side lose traction and some of the tires and then rebound around the corner and disappear into the distance.
Rym: Kzk spins the hell out cuz he doesn't know what he just saw.
Scott: He says the words on side And then he says was that a fucking ghost?
Scott: Oh my god What the fuck.
Rym: and he just sits there doesn't know what the hell has.
Scott: he totally just got pulled by a Crap old car.
Scott: This is as if you were racing down a street in a Corvette and of Frickin you go past you.
Scott: that's what this is like.
Scott: That's why it's awesome.
Rym: Now if you haven't guessed Takumi's driving this car.
Scott: Yes It's sort of like the show keeps you in suspense like oh who's driving that car?
Scott: They don't let you know, but you're pretty sure.
Scott: oh, it's like in Trigun is he washed the stampede?
Scott: They don't let you know.
Scott: They try to keep it a secret from you for like four or five episodes, but you freaking know You know, it's actually pretty fun though, because if you act if I didn't just spoil it for you, which isn't the big spoiler
Rym: Oh god, no
Scott: now there are much bigger things to spoil.
Scott: an initial D like Shingo like Shingo, but You're you could.
Scott: actually if you've never seen the show before you could actually be in quite a bit of suspense.
Scott: Like is he driving the car?
Scott: How is he so good?
Scott: They don't even tell you all the stuff We've told you until like episode 3.
Rym: Yep And there's a lot of suspense among the characters as to who's driving this car.
Rym: Cuz the Akina speed stars suck and they know they're gonna lose and they take this really seriously.
Rym: and one day They're like, they don't know that Takumi can drive.
Rym: them even know that his dad really has a car.
Scott: They know talk to me like he's their friend who works at the gas station But they think he doesn't know shit about cars because he doesn't really know shit about cars like.
Rym: there's a really funny scene where they're watching some videos of this drift king racing and they're talking about Inertial drift and how to do it.
Rym: then Takumi's like but they're in Takumi's like, what do you guys?
Rym: this is dumb?
Rym: What you're talking about.
Rym: and they're like, you don't know anything about this.
Rym: talking me says Yeah, you just kind of turn the wheel like this and then like this and tap the brake and they look at him Like he's an idiot.
Rym: But the gas station owner who knows all about racing because he's friends with crazy boota.
Rym: We won't reveal much about boota, but you'll figure things out.
Rym: Yeah, but he knows about drift racing.
Rym: They both know about drift racing and he's thinking to himself.
Rym: That was the answer of a professional racer.
Rym: So we shouldn't really we've.
Rym: I think we've explained enough about the show I think we have.
Scott: if you if you're not already in suspense You're not gonna be so.
Scott: more importantly.
Rym: What are the important bits about this show?
Scott: I mean the music is the number one most important part of this show.
Rym: Hands-down, I mean every race has this music.
Rym: without this you are.
Scott: without this music.
Scott: The show is basically completely worthless.
Scott: We did it once even watch it.
Rym: I watched an of race on mute And it was just boring.
Rym: PlayStation 1 like watching someone play Gran Turismo.
Scott: Yeah, the graphics during the races are PlayStation 1 cars driving down like around some turns but with that music playing especially by the second or third race.
Rym: You totally forget that and as far as you're concerned, this is a hundred percent real.
Scott: That mute the music the Eurobeat music sort of like grabs you and fills you with like this certain kind of energy and you know Change the songs throughout the race depending and they always pick just the right one and you can totally you know Feel like the pressure and suspense of the race in you and as it goes down.
Scott: So you don't really care about what's happening or who's gonna win?
Scott: It's just sort of like, you know There's a race of cars and you're feel you're on this sort of downhill slope That's going around all these turns inside of you until the race is over.
Rym: now There's some amazing Scenes that you wouldn't expect.
Rym: I mean, there's the car washing scene, whatever.
Rym: but even in the races I mean, I can't spoil any of this but I think Scott remembers the scene where there happened to be three cars going down the Mountain.
Rym: Oh, man, and something happens to one of these cars and then there's the car in the back does something it's.
Rym: I Remember the first time I saw that I was like, it's really a show of great scenes.
Scott: It's like all the time they spend in the big like early parts of an episode or well not early parts of an episode.
Scott: But it's the show sort of follows a pattern where okay Here's the characters the characters are progressing in his great big storyline.
Scott: But there's also the you know intermittent races which take about like four to five episodes and usually it's like, okay Who's he gonna race god?
Rym: I just realized that the format of the show is a lot like the cycle of domestic abuse.
Rym: There's the calm right everything is great.
Rym: They're just you know, walking around town.
Rym: then tension starts mounting.
Rym: There's rumblings that someone's gonna challenge.
Rym: There's gonna be a race.
Rym: then there's the race.
Rym: It's coming up.
Rym: They build up the right.
Scott: they build up to a race for a couple episodes.
Scott: Then there is a race and then the races last like an episode or an episode and a half every race.
Rym: There's like the pre race where there's like everyone's getting ready and there's the tension of what's gonna happen.
Rym: Who's gonna race?
Rym: you wouldn't think that.
Rym: but half the early race is part of the tension.
Rym: is Who's actually going to be racing in what cars where and why and what stakes?
Rym: and then?
Rym: The like the first episode of the race covers like the first three quarters of the race Like one episode and then they'll cliffhang you and finish the race in the next episode.
Rym: God, this show is a bunch of cliffhangers in a row and then another calm after the race.
Scott: And the other thing the show does is every time you think you have it figured out they introduce some other doubt.
Scott: so, you know, it's like You'll be watching the races.
Scott: You'd be like I know who's gonna win this race.
Scott: It's obvious who's gonna win this race.
Scott: Why would I even watch it?
Scott: and then they put some doubt in there and they add doubt every time.
Scott: and like they've added Doubt a hundred times for every single race they add more doubt and you're like, there's no way.
Scott: they've done this.
Scott: every single race They've added doubt and I was right what the hell.
Scott: and then they add doubt again and you're totally fooled every time this.
Rym: And there's also the real street.
Rym: racers don't need women.
Scott: That's just a funny running game.
Rym: There's a lot of funny.
Rym: I mean, I think the charm of this show What really makes it goes that it's got the.
Rym: it's basically a fighting show with cars.
Rym: It's got the racing element.
Scott: Yeah, but the fights aren't like Dragon Ball where they last ten episodes and nothing happened.
Rym: Yeah, and they drive the plot very directly and they're very well done.
Rym: But that alone does not make a good show.
Rym: that makes a C anime by default with nothing else.
Rym: That's a C anime.
Scott: hell It's a D anime.
Scott: It depends.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, but it also has all a lot of characters and while the characters aren't as fleshed out as say Spike Spiegel from cowboy bebop They're very fleshed out.
Scott: they react even though they look ugly as hell.
Rym: Yeah, don't worry about their lips.
Rym: I don't know that there was some sort of chemical deformity in this town.
Scott: It must be.
Scott: But that Lake Akina full of boys.
Rym: but there's a large cast of characters and you'll start identifying with them and you'll see Kenji of like Kenji blah blah blah.
Rym: What are you doing here at the gas station?
Scott: He's such a side character Kenji, but you totally know him.
Rym: Yeah, and then Sako and Mako in the silady.
Scott: it's those two good people.
Rym: Oh man, plus they have good music, too.
Scott: Yeah, they have really good music.
Scott: So Initial D is The best B anime.
Scott: no one's gonna say this is a great anime of all time.
Scott: It's not even close.
Rym: It's not on the a-list.
Scott: No one can possibly argue that this is good, but it is fun.
Scott: It's sort of like playing a board game that you know, the board game is bad It's just rolling dice and moving a guy around the board.
Scott: But for some reason you have a lot of fun with this one.
Scott: I think those two other ones part of what it is.
Rym: They took what would otherwise be a pedestrian concept You know car racing and they took all the elements of a good show and they put them in there And they did every part of Initial D as well as you could ever have expected them to do it.
Rym: And as a result the the show is more than the sum of its parts and I Highly recommend this show.
Rym: if you were a fan of anime Watch the first five episodes.
Rym: just trust us if you don't like it after that.
Rym: You really don't like it whatever, you're just not a human being and we'll hate you forever, but But no seriously give this show a chance and this isn't like, you know.
Rym: give fist of the North Star chance.
Rym: Really give this show a chance.
Scott: Oh, there's one more warning.
Scott: word of warning.
Scott: If you get the DVDs of Initial D, oh Fuck you Tokyo pop.
Scott: Fuck you.
Scott: Okay, Tokyo pop licensed Initial D to be on DVD in the United States.
Scott: I think that license has been transferred and someone else is gonna re-release it correctly.
Scott: Oh, I think Funimation I don't know.
Scott: I forget but if you get the Tokyo pop DVDs of Initial D When you put them in your DVD player, it will give you two choices.
Scott: one choice will say classic and one choice will say Tricked out.
Rym: now now choosing the tricked-out option Will basically condemn your firstborn children to the fiery abyss of hell for all eternity.
Scott: Yes, what Tokyo pop did is they thought that they were gonna get Initial D on American television.
Scott: now Eurobeat music is sort of would have been a very expensive to get that on.
Rym: Yeah a vex track and move and all that that stuff was the hottest shit in Japan back then and it's still pretty hot shit all Things considered.
Scott: Yeah, it would be very difficult for them to get that music onto American television.
Scott: Also, they didn't think that music would appeal to Americans and such and they knew that the target audience for a show about drift racing Was more urban.
Scott: I guess they thought The kind of people who go and watch too fast too furious.
Rym: But their definition of urban wasn't what most people's definition of urban was.
Rym: their definition of urban was 12 year olds in suburbia, right?
Scott: So what they did is when they dubbed Initial D, which is an average of an anime dub, you know, actually Spike Spiegel plays David Lucas who does Spike Spiegel and Roger Smith, you know Probably the best voice actor in all of anime in America.
Rym: I don't think we should tell them who he plays.
Scott: Oh good point.
Scott: He plays a minor character who is very important and Hilarious, but also very bad also very bad, but he's the best voice actor in America ever anyway, um What was I saying?
Scott: Alright, alright Tokyo pop.
Scott: So what Tokyo pop did is they hired some people to make Terrible music.
Scott: We're not worst music you've ever heard.
Scott: I know Gerald drive initial D initial dream initial D. Yeah, it's really bad.
Scott: It makes you want to stab your eyes out.
Scott: I'm not kidding.
Scott: I almost did what do you want to stab your ears out?
Rym: If you stab your eyes out not only are you now blind and in pain But the music's still there and now you can't find the remote to turn it off.
Scott: Well, the reason you you do want to stab your eyes out is because not only Did they add change all the music and initial D thus ruining the show?
Scott: Not only did they dub it averagely But they applied base what amounts to 1980s, you know College punk kids special effects to all the races effectively.
Rym: I it's.
Rym: it's the modern equivalent of star wipes.
Scott: Yeah, they basically like during a race.
Scott: They would do like split the screen up into like four squares showing the same thing.
Rym: Oh Also in the dub, they rearrange a bunch of scenes cut out a bunch of controversial stuff and partly change the plot.
Scott: They also change the names of the characters.
Scott: Oh, I got to talk about that in a second.
Scott: So watching it Dubbed or tricked out on the Tokyo pop DVDs is a completely different show.
Scott: That's not worth watching ever.
Scott: It's like it might be the worst show ever.
Rym: I know Daryl Surratt played some bad American equivalent anime music.
Rym: when they try to redo that stuff and I'm not gonna do that here because I respect for you guys Yes, you really do not want to hear this music.
Rym: It is not even bad enough to be funny.
Scott: It's inhuman.
Rym: It's I'm sorry Tokyo pop but you need to force whoever did that to commit seppuku right now Right.
Scott: So if you watch the classic version of initial D, you will get the original subtitled unedited initial D With the original eurobeat music and it is on the Tokyo pop DVDs.
Scott: So it is worth watching just to get that.
Rym: However, if you like the show, you're probably better off Netflixing it.
Rym: I was just gonna say that and only buy it if you're the kind of person who would show scenes Over and over and over again.
Rym: to people like we'll periodically grab Key DVDs from initial D and watch specific races.
Scott: We should totally watch one right after the show.
Rym: I think we should.
Rym: I want to watch the one with the three cars going.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: Let's watch that one.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: That's my second favorite moment in the show.
Scott: It might be anyway, the other thing is in the manga and in the dub.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: in the dub they have changed the names of some of the characters.
Rym: Yeah, cuz apparently Americans can't say things like Takahashi Rios.
Rym: Okay, right Takumi.
Scott: so for example, the main character is Takumi.
Scott: they changed his name to tak and Let's see ikitani.
Scott: I think they changed his name or something.
Rym: No, I didn't actually read the stupid.
Scott: They changed his name to Cole and It's a key.
Scott: They changed his name to Iggy like Iggy pop.
Rym: Oh I'm not gonna say much about it's a key but suffice to say he provides a great deal of the humor in this show.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Oh and they changed Takahashi Keisuke's name to Katie.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, that's in in the anime in the original manga and in the anime They actually say the characters names like Takahashi Keisuke, Takahashi Riosuke Ikitani, you know and it sort of adds something to it the way they say their names.
Scott: they always say people's full names like You know Takumi Fujiwara, I'll remember that name, you know, and when they change the names it's like talk I'll remember you.
Scott: It's like what the fuck you weren't that casual before?
Scott: You were all serious and racing and that you know, yeah, that's well.
Rym: That's also something that I mean aside from the full name thing Which is cool that Japanese has various levels of honor and defer deference that we really don't have in English.
Scott: Yeah, but you could still do it properly without making the name silly.
Rym: yeah, I think the answer is just to watch the sub.
Scott: Yeah, watch the subtitled.
Scott: first season of initial D. It's worth your time if you don't get into it, you don't get into it, you know, but It's something you have to like Feel inside you in the third place Not the first place or the second place but the third place.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: If you don't feel it in the third place, it's not gonna work for you You know, so in the very least watch the first five episodes.
Rym: if you're a little more adventurous have a little more free time I'd say really watch the first 13 at least up through the salady race.
Scott: I think that's actually way after the 13.
Rym: It might be I don't remember.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: the gum tape race has got a really good moment in it.
Scott: Gum tape race is highest of quality.
Rym: I mean, it sounds so stupid if you explain to someone the concept of a gum tape race or gum tape death man.
Scott: That's the thing.
Scott: is they also like in in the original they called it like the gum tape death man, right?
Scott: Like oh shits.
Scott: and then in the manga, it's like yeah, it's like the duck the duct tape race.
Scott: I'm like what?
Rym: But really if you explain the concept to a person just out of the blue like hey How does this sound for an idea for a race?
Rym: they would say that's the stupidest thing I've ever heard.
Rym: But somehow watching them explain it in this anime makes it sound like the most awesome crazy dangerous amazing thing ever.
Scott: Yeah, and it works.
Rym: Well, it works.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Oh, it sure does man.
Rym: Alright, I didn't expect the show to go in some of the directions it did.
Scott: so that concludes the only time you will ever hear any anime podcaster praise initial D because I'm pretty sure everyone else hates this show and You might too, but we like it.
Rym: Yeah you yeah, you know what?
Rym: We don't make fun of you for your fist of the North Star or your great messenger.
Scott: Yeah Oh, I don't know.
Scott: I haven't actually seen those things.
Scott: I like the idea of them, but I don't know if I'll actually like them when I watch them.
Scott: Anyway, what are we gonna do tomorrow on the show?
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: I don't know what we're gonna do tomorrow on the show since we've gone long every day this week.
Scott: Well, whatever we do tomorrow don't miss it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.