Rym: So, you might have noticed that there's not one, but two episodes in the feed for tonight.
Rym: Well, the deal is, and this hasn't happened in a long time.
Rym: We used to generate a lot of outtakes, but now, not so many.
Rym: Scott and I, in the middle of the FPS key bindings show, got into a little bit of argument, partly that Scott started it.
Rym: I'll blame him entirely, because he's not here to defend himself.
Rym: And as a result, we argued for a good 15 minutes about moving furniture and putting spices and food and non-conformism and all this crap when we were just trying to talk about FPS key bindings.
Rym: So, instead of having an hour-and-change-long episode with that stuck in the middle of it, well, I just kind of cut it out like a little tumor.
Rym: And you know how when you go to the surgery and they cut out a gallstone or whatever, they always let you keep it.
Rym: At least, they used to let you keep it in a little jar.
Rym: Well, I kept that argument in a little jar, and I decided that, wait, we've always said, you know, we'll put in extra shows to make up for shows we've missed.
Rym: And this is probably the first extra show we've ever put up.
Rym: If this is your first time listening to GeekNights, I'm going to note, as we always note, that this is not a normal episode of GeekNights.
Rym: This is what we like to call a special.
Rym: So if you've never listened before, you're welcome to listen to this, but I would highly recommend you check out any episode in our entire feed that does not contain the word "special" in the title.
Rym: That's a much better picture of what this show is.
Rym: This is entirely unedited.
Rym: I didn't really do anything to it except apply my normal high-pass filters and whatever.
Rym: Enjoy it or not, a lot of you have been asking for more arguments from us, so I can say with certainty that this is pretty much a straight-up, unedited, exactly how Scott and I argue pretty much every day of our lives.
Rym: We just happen to have been sitting in front of the microphones when we started this one.
Scott: Yeah, but the way you have your things arranged, like your bed at the foot facing the desk next to the wall over there, this is not a typical furniture arrangement.
Rym: All right, so it's not maybe, you know, white-bred, American, midwest...
Scott: See, that's exactly what I'm talking about.
Scott: You always seem to have this attitude that if something is white-bred American, it's somehow bad.
Scott: Or if something is the accepted default, the way that a lot of people do something, then it must be bad because...
Rym: Now, now, Scott, I don't want to bring up logical fallacies here, but you are begging the question.
Scott: How am I begging the question?
Rym: Because you've jumped to the conclusion that because I somehow, in this one instance, used some setup that isn't somehow typical of standing...
Scott: You do this often.
Scott: You do often say, with food also, you're like, "Eh, it's such a white-bred American food.
Scott: It's no good.
Scott: You gotta, you know, you toss all sorts of weird spices in the
Scott: food.".
Rym: Wait, wait a minute.
Rym: You're saying that I'm bad because I put spices in my food.
Scott: No, not because you put spice in your food, because you are not a cook yet when you cook.
Scott: You just sort of pick spices and you toss them in there, not according to any recipe or any cooking knowledge.
Rym: Actually, I do it according to all the websites that I write about how to use all those spices.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It works pretty well.
Scott: You know, because you used to do that before you read any websites about spice.
Scott: You've been doing that since RIT.
Rym: When I started reading those websites.
Scott: No, you didn't read any websites.
Rym: Like, I read all the uses for dill, and I started using it.
Rym: I used dill and ham, and I used dill on grilled cheese sandwiches, and I used dill and eggs.
Rym: Any savory dish.
Rym: Then I looked up how to use oregano.
Rym: Then I looked up how to use cilantro and all those things.
Scott: You just like to do things that are not what is standard.
Scott: You are a non-conformist, in a way.
Rym: So wait a minute, wait a minute.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: This is what begs the question.
Rym: You seem to say that somehow I do it intentionally for the intent of being different, as opposed to, like in the case of my room, I had a rational reason that-
Scott: No, but you seem to, whether you admit it or not, you seem to have this attitude that the way that is not conforming is superior, or that the conformist way cannot possibly be the best way.
Rym: But that's not true at all.
Rym: Conforming or non-conforming has nothing to do with the end utility.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: And yet, you seem to behave in contrast with that very thing.
Rym: See, Scott, you seem to have this problem, because you accuse me of this a lot.
Rym: If I like a wine, Scott always says, "Ah, you just like the idea of wine.
Rym: You don't actually like wine.
Rym: It tastes like
Rym: crap.".
Rym: Or, "You don't actually like the taste of alcohol.
Rym: You just want to get
Rym: drunk.".
Rym: Or, "You don't actually like the taste of that fancy cheese versus that unfancy cheese or whatever.
Rym: You just like the idea of liking the fancy French cheese instead of the weird American cheese or
Rym: whatever.".
Scott: But I really do like those things, and I don't know- You came to like them after originally having the idea that you would like them.
Scott: See, not at all.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'd like you to back that up.
Scott: It's not something I can prove, it's just something I observed living with you, and there's no way I could prove it to anyone else.
Scott: Because- No one else has lived with you.
Rym: I like the taste of wine, so I buy wine.
Rym: I like the taste of cheese, so I buy the cheeses I like.
Rym: I like the taste of spices, so I buy the spices I like.
Scott: Why do you buy the fancy, weird wines that are not common?
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Rym: What fancy, weird wine?
Rym: Most of the wines I buy are the $9 specials.
Rym: The only special bottle of wine I have is a bottle of port that was given to me as a gift, and I haven't opened it.
Scott: Why don't you drink just like whatever most people drink, just like default stuff?
Rym: Like what?
Scott: I don't know, because I don't know anything about wine.
Rym: The default wines, I guess, that most people drink are, I don't know, Chardonnays and California wines and Merlots, which I drink all the time.
Rym: Most of my wine is super cheap.
Scott: But you won't eat American cheese.
Rym: Because American cheese is really bland.
Scott: You won't drink Budweiser.
Rym: Because Budweiser is really flavorless and watery and crappy.
Rym: It has nothing to do with any factor other than the fact that Budweiser, to me, tastes like crap.
Scott: What things do you like are super conformist as Budweiser and American cheese?
Rym: I really like Dr.
Rym: Pepper.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Pepper's, but see, that's not, Dr.
Scott: Pepper's the weird one out.
Rym: How is Dr.
Rym: Pepper the weird one out?
Scott: It's like Coke and Pepsi are the mainstays.
Scott: Those are the white bread mainstream ones.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Pepper's the third offshoot one.
Rym: Because those are colas.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Pepper's not really a cola.
Scott: I'm just saying, you don't like anything.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, because I like Dr.
Rym: Pepper instead of Coke, somehow I'm a non-conformist and I only like Dr.
Rym: Pepper.
Scott: What do you like, what do you do that could be considered conformist in any way?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I own a car.
Rym: I drive places.
Rym: Sometimes I take trains.
Rym: I like sandwiches.
Scott: You don't ever order like the normal sandwich, you always get a sandwich with as many extra things on it as you can.
Rym: What do you mean like a normal sandwich?
Rym: Today for lunch, I had a ham and turkey sandwich with mustard, lettuce, tomato, and onion on white bread.
Scott: White bread, you said?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Wonder bread?
Rym: No, it was the white roll that they had at the sub place.
Scott: Ah, so it's a roll, not a white bread.
Scott: When was the last time you ate white bread?
Rym: A few weeks ago when I bought some white bread.
Scott: You bought white bread?
Rym: It was white Italian bread and it had sesame seeds in it.
Rym: Oh, so the sesame seeds make me a non-conformist.
Scott: Zane, would you ever buy a white Wonder Bread?
Rym: Wonder Bread tastes like ass.
Scott: Ah, again.
Scott: You always buy the weirdest non-conforming bread you can buy.
Rym: Wait a minute, so buying the Italian bread is weirdest non-conformist as opposed to the nasty ass Wonder Bread?
Rym: I'm just saying, you refuse- Scott, Scott, Scott, would you eat Wonder Bread?
Rym: because I've had Wonder Bread before and I know what it tastes like.
Rym: There's a reason I avoid it.
Rym: How come you don't buy the Wonder Bread?
Scott: Because I don't like the taste of it.
Rym: Oh, so you're a non-conformist.
Scott: You buy the fancy weird bread because you don't want to- No, I don't buy wheat bread, but I don't go out of my way to get the weirder bread.
Scott: When you go to the bread store, you have to buy, I see you looking at all the breads and you go to the breads that are like the most oddball breads on purpose, intentionally.
Rym: Do you ever think that maybe honey oat bread tastes really good?
Scott: See, but that's the thing, is you go for it like, "Ah, here's the good breads," as to say that the plain old wheat bread is no good.
Scott: while the wheat bread is awesome, the plain wheat bread is hot.
Rym: But you're begging the question.
Scott: What question am I begging?
Rym: You're assuming a lot here and you're kind of skipping to the conclusion that honey wheat bread or honey oat bread, which is my favorite kind of bread in the world, I somehow like it for some reason other than the fact that it tastes like honey.
Scott: Well, the first time you bought honey wheat bread or honey oat bread or whatever, right?
Rym: You know what I thought the first time I saw honey oat bread?
Rym: I remember somewhat clearly.
Rym: I thought, "Wow, I really like honey and I really like oats.
Rym: Here's a bread made out of honey and oats.
Rym: Hot shit, I'm buying
Rym: this.".
Scott: But yeah, you always try, everything you like is a non-conforming, most out of the park thing.
Scott: Back that up at all.
Scott: What do you like?
Scott: Name a single thing you like.
Scott: that is a conforming thing.
Rym: I'm not sure what point you're trying to make here, because- While you agree that because something is- Beer, all right?
Rym: You brought up beer.
Rym: I think Coors and Budweiser taste like shit, but you know what?
Rym: I like Labatt Blue and I like Red Stripe a lot.
Rym: Red Stripe's one of my favorite beers.
Scott: I'm just saying is you, while you agree that something is not better because it is non-conformist, you behave and act in a way in where you tend to approve more of things which do not conform and you go
Rym: out of your way- But you haven't backed that part up at all.
Scott: To consume and patronize things and behave in such a way that it is as far from the norm or as far from what you believe is the norm of America as you possibly can.
Rym: But that's not true at all.
Scott: But that's what you do.
Rym: But you haven't backed that up at all.
Rym: In fact, I grew up in the Midwest, right?
Rym: I put ketchup on my eggs.
Scott: That's weird.
Rym: How is that weird?
Rym: You realize that everyone there does that?
Scott: Yeah, it's weird.
Rym: I put salt on my watermelon like people do.
Scott: That's also weird.
Rym: That's what you're supposed to do.
Rym: It tastes better.
Scott: No, you're not supposed to do that.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: No.
Scott: All right, anyway, let's go back to the FPS in there.
Rym: I don't know if I can because apparently I'm such a non-conformist.
Rym: I think I got to break the-.
Rym: if you're going to put this label on me, then I guess I got to go with it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'll be like Anime Pulse.
Rym: So go ahead.
Rym: Talk about your FPS-ing.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Chicken.
Rym: So- Interrupting guy.
Scott: An otaku generation.
Scott: that was an interrupting guy, I listened to it today, but I couldn't.
Rym: Why were you listening to Otaku?
Scott: Otaku Generation is like the worst podcast- I said that I would listen to any Otakon report.
Scott: I'll talk about this later.
Rym: That was a mistake.
Scott: All right, let's go back- You know what?
Rym: I think I'm going to review them first.
Rym: next time we do a Geekbot.
Scott: All right, let's go back now.
Rym: Back to what?
Rym: I'm a non-conformist.
Rym: I'm just letting it free flow here.
Rym: I'm like Fast Karate.
Rym: It's your fault.
Scott: Can we do the episode now?
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: We'll see where the non-conformity takes me.
Scott: Are we actually going to do the episode or what?
Rym: That's up to you.
Scott: Am I a non-conformist?
Scott: I'm ready to do it or are you going to be the interrupting guy?
Rym: Am I a non-conformist, Scott?
Rym: Yes, you are.
Rym: Am I a non-conformist for reasons other than the fact that that just happens to be the things that I like?
Scott: I think that yes, but you have successfully come up with a indefeatable argument in where I cannot successfully argue that that is the truth.
Rym: But you didn't even defeat my primary argument, so it doesn't really matter that you can't defeat my bullshit argument.
Scott: I'm saying that's the way it is, but your argument saying you are not is foolproof because there's no way to prove what is in your mind.
Rym: My argument- But that's not even my argument.
Rym: My argument was that you didn't have any evidence at all.
Scott: I have evidence.
Rym: All you did was beg the question and jump to conclusions.
Scott: You go out, you do, I observe that you go out of your way to do things in a non-conforming fashion and behave in a way that gives people around you the idea that you approve of things which do not conform more than you approve of things that do conform.
Rym: That's quite a statement and I noticed that you haven't backed it up with any single shred of evidence.
Scott: That is what I observe living with you.
Scott: That's all I got.
Rym: So all you've got is anecdotes and you don't even have anecdotes.
Rym: You have one assertion with no backing.
Scott: Because I don't remember my specific observations, but I lived with you long enough.
Scott: What else do you want me to do here?
Scott: It's not like a scientific- Potatoes!
Rym: Chicken!
Scott: Chicken!
Scott: Are we done here?
Scott: I'm tired of this.
Rym: Alright, go ahead.
Rym: Talk about your FPS crap.
Scott: Are you going to do your chicken?
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Just go ahead.
Rym: Let's see what happens.
Rym: Like I said, this is free flow.
Rym: Did I break you?
Scott: I just wanted to go back to the FPS show.
Rym: I don't even care about that anymore.
Rym: What the hell?
Rym: Because I already did my piece.
Rym: I already got my say out.
Rym: I already gave everyone my say.
Rym: In fact, I have more.
Rym: I could keep talking.
Rym: About that keyboard that I wrote stuff all over.
Rym: I had the overlay for my own keyboard.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Alright, go on.
Rym: Talk about your boring FPSs.
Rym: I don't want to win any more arguments tonight.
Rym: Scott!
Rym: Do the show!
Rym: How come you keep laughing?
Scott: Because I'm not done laughing yet and because I know you're going to interrupt.
Rym: I'm waiting for you to do the show.
Rym: I won't interrupt you.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Just don't laugh.
Rym: Can you keep from laughing?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Where are we going to cut off that and- I'm waiting.
Rym: Do the show.
Scott: Go on.
Scott: Why are you all intentionally trying to mess me up, Barry?
Rym: How am I intentionally trying to-?
Rym: Now I'll play those arguments.
Rym: All I'm doing is asking you to continue the show like you wanted.
Rym: I'm giving you everything.
Scott: No, but you're all like, "Come on.
Scott: Continue the show.
Scott: Come
Scott: on.".
Scott: In a way that implies that you are not going to continue the show as normal.
Rym: So what you're saying is that simply by my tone of voice, I can prevent you from continuing the show from both bits of laughter?
Scott: No, you can't prevent me from continuing the show.
Rym: Because you keep cracking up.
Scott: But I am hesitant to continue the show because I think that you are going to not go through with it and that I'll have to restart again.
Rym: But the thing is, you're reading into a lot of stuff because the words I said were that I will not interrupt you and I'll let you continue the show the moment you start.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So you're not kidding?
Rym: I'm not going to interrupt you.
Rym: I'm ready.
Rym: It's free flow, but I'm going to let you flow for a while.
Scott: I think you're going to screw something up.
Rym: Well, go ahead.
Rym: The onus is entirely on you.
Scott: The onus.
Scott: Well, you're looking- smiling.
Scott: How long has this been?
Rym: You don't have a problem here, Scott.
Scott: You're making a problem on purpose.
Scott: Did you take some drugs before I got home?
Rym: You just keep laughing.
Rym: Just do the show.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Wow, this hasn't happened in a long time.
Rym: I'm not actually doing anything, guys.
Rym: I'm really just sitting here.
Scott: And no, he turns around, looks at me and smiles.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: So I have the power by turning around and looking at you to completely derail you and prevent you from speaking.
Scott: No.
Rym: I have so much psychic power that with a mere glance, I can- it's like Tasha's hideous laughter that seventh level spell.
Scott: It's a Morty giggly right now, and it doesn't take much.
Rym: All right, Scott, I won't turn around and look at you.
Scott: You're going to do something.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: When was the last time we had a show where we got completely derailed and we had to cut it out?