Rym: It's Tuesday November 13th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight Scott finally airs all his grievances against achievement.
Scott: Let's do this Well yesterday.
Rym: We talked about the chairs that we've been waiting for and they weren't here when we got home.
Rym: So we're sitting in the living room talking about how much we want our chairs to come and you know I guess nominally I was really talking about mostly you.
Rym: oh Excited if you don't want your chair.
Rym: I'll take it well.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's you know.
Scott: I'm not really From ordering so many things online.
Scott: I know a lot of people that you know.
Scott: I've had the feeling in the past You know where you buy something online or you you know that someone mailed you something, and you're just anticipating it showing up.
Scott: You're like oh, man.
Scott: I can't wait for it to show up.
Scott: I'm gonna get home to be a package or oh man something's gonna show up and sometimes for certain packages I still get it.
Scott: You know like my Mario Galaxy should be coming this week or early next week from Amazon.
Scott: I'm kind of anticipating that but I no longer like get really excited when a package is coming because I get so many packages because I buy everything online that I can buy.
Rym: I see wasn't that it was more because this wasn't just a package.
Rym: from what we were told we'd have to be here.
Rym: We'd have to arrange it ahead of time like they'd email me and then FedEx is gonna come and Scott will stay home and sign forward or something.
Rym: and We they hadn't called us yet, so I'm wondering alright.
Rym: Are they gonna call?
Rym: are they not shipped him yet?
Rym: When are they gonna get here?
Rym: What's going on, and we're talking a minute and a Couple hours later you in the living room playing Lego Star Wars about to come up and do the show And I just kind of notice out the big Gigantic sliding glass door in our living room that goes to the back porch.
Rym: two gigantic Packages that have been sitting there obviously all day that neither one of us had noticed until just then I don't know.
Scott: They might have been there all day.
Scott: They might not have been it who knows?
Rym: um they were there I don't know.
Scott: They could have showed up at it.
Scott: You didn't see them before.
Scott: they could have showed up literally like a minute before you notice.
Rym: um FedEx doesn't deliver that late I don't know.
Scott: No they don't who knows when.
Rym: I know when they were obviously there when we all got home And none of us look out there.
Rym: cuz now it's cold out.
Scott: We don't go on the back porch, but not necessarily true.
Rym: Okay, there's no way Scott.
Rym: You know FedEx won't deliver anything after like five.
Rym: No.
Scott: I've had packages show up at 7. aha yeah Anyway the point is is that they were there And we brought him in the house, and we're starting to open him up and you have these gigantic boxes almost as big as well maybe half as big as refrigerator boxes, maybe a quarter of the size.
Scott: so really big big enough you could get inside of them.
Scott: and I open mine up And I'm like hey Cuz the guy at the store told me you take the wheels and you put the piston on the wheels and you put chair on The piston and I didn't see any piston piece.
Scott: I mean there was a thing in the middle of the wheels that stuck up and might have been a piston But it looked really small, and it didn't look like it would telescope enough to be the piston.
Rym: So I says I says to Scott are you sure that isn't it?
Rym: and he says look at it.
Rym: This can't be it.
Rym: It won't work.
Scott: I didn't look like it was it to me?
Scott: I was pretty sure it wasn't it.
Scott: and you know I'm going.
Scott: I'm looking around that it was no other pieces.
Rym: Now we probably wouldn't have been as confused except yesterday.
Rym: I got a phone call and the people were just like There's a note on your invoice that says piston.
Rym: Do you know what that's all about?
Rym: and I said?
Rym: I think one of the chairs comes with a piston.
Rym: I don't know why you calling me.
Rym: I ordered the thing.
Scott: yeah, this is obviously the guy who sold us.
Scott: these chairs obviously know what was going on.
Rym: He knew the score, but and he went on vacation apparently the next day.
Scott: well apparently whoever talked to Rym had no clue What was going on?
Scott: And this is this is a problem.
Scott: people should not be doing work that they do not know how to do.
Scott: so apparently these people had no clue what they were doing and So they didn't know what that note meant or anything.
Scott: and they're calling us to find out.
Scott: call the dude that's on vacation That's he knows.
Scott: we don't know.
Scott: So the fact that they called and mentioned something about the piston and then I got the chair And it didn't look like there was the piston I was like huh it kind of puts that seed of doubt in your mind.
Rym: like Way back in the day I got a text message out of the blue, and I don't get text messages ever.
Rym: I hadn't even used it.
Rym: It was on my old cell phone.
Rym: even so my phone makes a weird noise that look.
Rym: And there's a text message.
Rym: I can't see who it was from and it just says don't eat And I'm sitting there, and I had just bought a doughnut and the doughnut was sitting in front of me.
Rym: and for a second I thought is this doughnut poisoned what?
Scott: that's what I would think.
Scott: how would they even know?
Rym: Is this what?
Rym: was this the matrix?
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: that seed of doubt was planted by an unrelated event yep?
Scott: So we had the seed of doubt.
Scott: But I went online into the website of the chair And there was a manual and looking at the manual and that mostly the service and repair manual which is great that they put online And they damn well better for the price.
Rym: Well.
Rym: I mean think about it.
Scott: It's not like you can pirate the chair That's true, but yeah, they don't let you get service and repair manuals for cars.
Scott: Let's pay a lot of money.
Rym: Well, that's because it's a racket.
Scott: it is a racket however in the service and repair manual I saw no such part as the is the parts and service manual I think.
Scott: and in all the parts section I didn't see any parts.
Scott: that looked like a piston.
Scott: so I went and I put the chair on and it Telescoped crazily.
Scott: it goes so high my feet are off the ground, and I'm like oh, I guess it's fine.
Rym: So I am now podcasting to you semi live from my brand new solid black metal throne with a pellicle seat.
Scott: It's not all metal it is significant.
Scott: parts plastic.
Rym: Well a few parts are but the bottom parts metal.
Rym: the middle parts metal.
Rym: all the bits are metal and the rest is pellicle Or plastic.
Scott: yep, it is that pellicle is just plastic meshy stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but it's special.
Rym: Kinda my butt can breathe.
Scott: You're wearing pants, so your butt can really only breathe if you took the pants off and then sat in the chair.
Rym: ah That'll come later.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, let's talk about games of some sort.
Rym: so instead of a news I figure I should do a geek bite because you don't have any news.
Rym: well No, I had a few news.
Rym: They're not worth talking about and more importantly It's a game that we're never gonna review fully because there's no reason to.
Rym: I think we can cover it all right now.
Rym: All right Scott picked up the other day Lego Star Wars for the week.
Scott: it includes Star Wars complete saga for the week because there was previously Lego Star Wars and then Lego Star Wars again And it was episodes 1 2 3 and then 4 5 6. or was it 4 5 6 1 2 3?
Scott: I don't know, but this is 1 2 3 4 5 6 on one disc for the week.
Rym: It's everything and it works, and it works.
Rym: yes, and Lego Star Wars is not Really a game.
Rym: I mean it's a game in the same sense that gauntlet is a game.
Rym: Yeah, but there's no puzzles.
Rym: You're not gonna have to figure anything out.
Scott: Basically amount to use the force on every single thing.
Scott: you see you know It's basically you walk around a level and your widgets to push.
Scott: You know like it's like switches on all the walls and all you to do if you push every switch on every wall that you can possibly push and Activate everything you can possibly activate which occasionally requires.
Scott: do you know activating things in a certain order or an occasionally requires?
Scott: You know pushing a block onto some switches or something, but nothing it's.
Scott: it's e10.
Scott: ten-year-olds can play this game.
Rym: All right, you know what it's like.
Rym: this game is like those rides at carnivals Where it looks like the pirate rod.
Rym: you go in and you got a little gun?
Rym: And you can shoot at all these targets and every time you hit a target Something happens like the pirate jumps out and goes it was it was it.
Scott: that's exactly what this game Is.
Rym: the skeleton falls over in a bunch of pieces and then?
Scott: If you hit the nail on the head it's like all those shooting galleries where you have a gun and it's sort of like a laser gun and you shoot at these targets and When you hit a target it activates some animatronic thing for a second.
Scott: that does something funny And it's that it's that.
Scott: but it's Star Wars.
Rym: and now don't be turned off by that because while this is a game for kids And while there's not much gameplay.
Rym: I like those rides And as a result, I like this game.
Scott: this game is okay.
Scott: I mean you might get bored if you keep if you actually try to unlock all this because basically the game is like collecting gold.
Scott: But you there's so much gold everywhere, but you have to collect so much of it.
Scott: It's just crazy.
Scott: So just don't don't even bother Yeah If you ignore that stuff and just try to burn through the game and do is do all the funny things that you can do.
Scott: you know watch all the funny cutscenes and Make all the funny situations you can by mixing Star Wars characters together in interesting ways.
Scott: and you know unlock.
Scott: some of the things Are worth unlocking like I unlocked this Lego town.
Scott: So you go around the perfectly normal happy Lego town, but I'm Darth Maul and I'm destroying it.
Scott: That was good times.
Rym: Scott did that for a while.
Scott: Yeah now I'm done with that.
Scott: It expected me to do it until I got a million gold because every time you destroy stuff like a zillion gold falls out.
Scott: He got over 500,000 gold and then I gave up because I was like fuck this.
Rym: I mean, that's really it that I think the greatest joy in this game is.
Rym: Whenever I'm a Jedi and Scott's not a Jedi I can randomly just force choke him and then kill him.
Rym: There's nothing he can do about it.
Scott: You can't do that.
Rym: Yeah, I can you didn't.
Scott: you haven't done that at all yet.
Scott: Yeah, we don't even have any force choke able.
Rym: by first joke I mean the normal force power Because the normal force power makes you stand there like an idiot for enough time for me to walk over and kill you.
Scott: Yeah, it happens.
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: if you like River City Ransom and you like Star Wars you like this game also.
Rym: I'll admit that the cutscenes are actually really funny.
Scott: They are they're quite humorous.
Rym: There's this level of like.
Rym: they took every character in Star Wars, but they kind of caricatured them a little bit.
Rym: so Leia's really kind of rabble rousing and bitchy and Luke is just a jerk and Obi-wan is totally incompetent in episode one.
Scott: We got to beat a few more levels to get the Han Solo I think one more level and we should have I gotta see me Greedo shoots first.
Scott: I'm waiting for the wiki action.
Rym: The game's just and I'm enjoyable.
Rym: Yeah, that's about the best I think.
Scott: the only other thing to say about the game is occasionally there are vehicle missions and The vehicle missions are actually the most fun because they sort of have you know, like.
Scott: well, some of them are terrible But like the pod race was actually a really fun kind of race I mean, it wasn't actually a race but it was like a fun sort of f-zero kind of experience and not bad.
Rym: Plus it's one of those games where much like River City Ransom if you're just killing time hanging out with some people.
Rym: You can pretty much play this game and engage in whatever social interaction you planned on without losing anything.
Scott: Yeah but overall though it is the game itself.
Scott: once you've seen all their all the funniness there is to see is Pretty much a mindless waste of time a la World of Warcraft.
Scott: So there's only limited amounts You're gonna get out of this game.
Scott: You know what I would if it was if it wasn't let me say this it Star Wars.
Scott: the fact that it is Star Wars and the fact that it is Lego is all the game has.
Scott: if the game was Not Star Wars.
Scott: It would be not worth it.
Rym: And if it wasn't Lego, right?
Scott: But I think Lego is.
Scott: you know They're coming out with like Lego Batman and Lego Indiana Jones and I assume those will be similar in a way.
Scott: But I think I'm just gonna opt to watch the cutscenes from them online rather than playing buying them.
Rym: I think I would almost put this at least for us in a category of games.
Rym: I would call coffee table games.
Rym: It's the kind of game if you got a bunch of friends over you pop it in until you play it and everyone else Kind of talks and kind of watches.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's not a game you play for serious now.
Scott: I mean it has a multiplayer mode, but I mean if I pick r2d2 and Rym picks the Emperor I really can't win even though I should be able to.
Scott: but this you can't.
Scott: r2d2 can't do anything.
Rym: It doesn't help that there's really only one attack.
Scott: Yeah Lightsaber there's lightsaber and blaster and if you one guy has lightsaber and one guy has blaster guess who wins?
Rym: Not blaster.
Scott: You sure?
Scott: Let's try even if it's Boba Fett.
Rym: Boba Fett's got nothing.
Scott: I never bet the fat man.
Rym: Remember Boba Fett was never in straight-up single combat just with a Jedi.
Rym: He always ran away or something or he fell into the Sarla.
Rym: Well, yeah Don't bring that up.
Rym: I've missed that.
Scott: I hope they unlock that.
Scott: I hope I can unlock the Sarla.
Rym: Yeah What as a character?
Rym: Yes, B bites and a bites.
Scott: Well B opens up the hole and a close the hole.
Rym: Why would you ever close the hole?
Rym: just keep it open?
Scott: Well, no, okay Someone's trying to fly out with their jetpacks.
Scott: Ah, cuz you know his backpack has jets, right?
Scott: All right for my news.
Scott: I'm gonna talk about this new channel.
Scott: I'm in the Wii.
Scott: It's called the check me out channel.
Rym: It's the best game on the Wii right now?
Rym: I don't know about that.
Rym: Well because I haven't played Mario Galaxy Lee yet.
Scott: Oh Guitar Hero 3 made me something.
Scott: Ah, even though Guitar Hero 3 is problematic.
Rym: Guitar Hero 3 has already lost a lot of its pizzazz for me.
Rym: No, I think I kinda want to play.
Rym: It's still fun But the novelty is gone and now my choice is either put effort into becoming very good at it or never play it again except in social situations.
Scott: So you're shit talking because you did say you were going to become very good at it.
Rym: I'm already pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, I can play it hard now, which is something.
Scott: anyway Check me out.
Scott: channel.
Scott: This is a channel that is sort of like.
Scott: I Feel almost as if why is this a separate channel?
Scott: The things that this channel does should be part of the regular me channel.
Rym: You know why it's a separate channel?
Rym: Because they brought it out later.
Rym: Yeah, it was probably easier to do that than it was to integrate it.
Scott: Basically what this does is it lets it basically does things the me channel should have done in the past and way it works is Sometimes they have a contest like the current contest is Mario lost his hat?
Scott: So you make a me.
Scott: that I guess is it of the theme.
Scott: Mario lost his hat and you submit it to the contest and then I guess in a few days after submissions close We'll vote on.
Scott: you know Everyone will get to vote on which ones they think are the best.
Scott: and then I guess whichever one wins Wins and you get points I guess for winning or something and then they're gonna have more contests.
Scott: The other part of the channel is just sort of like a top me's thing where you make me's and you sort of submit them And you give them initials, right?
Scott: So like we submitted our Teddy Roosevelt and we said TR you and you know If you I'd said what you go to you say What is he good at and we say he's a male and he's good at speeches, you know.
Scott: So now people go through when they look at me's and if they see our Teddy Roosevelt me and they think it's cool They say yes That is a cool me and you can go through and you can see like the top 50 me's around the world You can see random me's you can just any me that anyone submitted to the check me out channels.
Scott: You know, it's sort of like a me fashion show in a way of everybody not Pete not just people who are in your friends Whatever now one.
Rym: I'm Generally, very impressed with the quality of some of these me's.
Scott: a lot of them Just people followed instructions on the internet on how to make certain me's.
Rym: but so those are obvious because you see ten of the same Thing yeah, but some of them are pretty good like that.
Scott: I'm on very good.
Rym: I don't know I liked the Robo cop not so much because he looks like Robo cop which he did but because the initials were RC Robo cop.
Scott: Yeah, those should not I gave.
Scott: I give people special points.
Scott: actually I will vote for things specifically because of people choosing the correct initials or at least clever ones.
Scott: Yes, for example, someone made Cyclops from the x-men and it was okay.
Scott: But they gave him the initials SS which means they knew that it was Scott Summers Which means they get my vote.
Rym: the one thing I can say I saw a lot of complaints on the internet.
Scott: Robocop's name is Alex J. Murphy.
Rym: So if see my new Murphy, I didn't know his first name.
Scott: Yeah, if they would have put a.m.
Scott: I would have voted for that.
Rym: So would have Dave Riley probably.
Rym: but uh I think my favorite thing about this is that I you know you go to the popular ones you look through the ones that people have voted up and People on the internet were complaining that it's just a bunch of random me's.
Rym: it's like a random me generator and it's stupid.
Rym: But I realized because I looked at it and it was all for the most part famous people And I think a lot of kids don't know who these people are.
Scott: It's possible.
Scott: But then how did they get voted so highly if because there's also people like us?
Rym: Yeah Still Jack Black.
Scott: Yeah, all the top means are you know famous people or famous characters?
Scott: Like there's a Naruto in there the Star Wars guys are in there, you know All that sort of stuff and I think the reason they only let you put initials is to avoid getting sued.
Scott: Yeah, like if you wrote say, you know, Jack Black that'd be like hey or whatever, but if you just put JB Yeah, it's just a me with the initials JB.
Scott: We're in Nintendo.
Scott: What can we do about?
Scott: plus?
Rym: it makes it a lot because I don't think I can express to you how many Hitler's there are In there already.
Rym: There's a lot of ass.
Scott: I'm our most popular me that we have submitted is our Mohammed.
Scott: I'm disappointed though because I like the Teddy Roosevelt more.
Rym: I like our Tessie Rose.
Scott: Clean our bill clean, you know get no play.
Rym: We didn't actually make our Teddy Roosevelt.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: Someone else did that's fine.
Scott: Yes, what do I care?
Scott: It's on my me.
Rym: I'm I we it's yeah, and our Bill Clinton is perfect But I my.
Rym: our Mohammed is my favorite one and I hope a lot of people see it.
Rym: I wanted to get voted up because I think it looks pretty close Close to someone.
Scott: no one knows what they look like.
Rym: Yeah, but you know what?
Rym: when you see it, you know What you're gonna think you're gonna think wow.
Rym: Yeah, they got him.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's him All right.
Scott: So yeah, if you have a we and you like the means at all You should probably check out the check me out channel.
Rym: Otherwise, yeah Things of the day.
Rym: so Scott team fortress - it came out, right?
Scott: Yep, and it was kinda cartoony, right?
Scott: You can forever is still not out.
Rym: I don't know that's gonna come out someday.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I mean at this point The fact that it hasn't come out in so long is probably the best marketing they could have ever got.
Scott: I saw a rumor that went farther than any other rumor.
Scott: I've seen before that was like pre-orders soon question mark.
Rym: I saw that in something that I realized was a spam.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, a Lot of you were probably aware that Team Fortress 2 took a long time to come out and there's a lot of reason for that.
Rym: I think we talked about it a little bit when we did a show on the history of Team Fortress.
Rym: But suffice to say Team Fortress 2 is really the sequel to Team Fortress classic Which is really the sequel to Team Fortress aka mega Team Fortress, even though that was actually a model, but I digress Team Fortress 2 as it was originally conceived was Nothing like the Team Fortress 2 that you got recently.
Scott: Well, it was conceived in the late 90s.
Scott: They couldn't even think the kind of thing that Team Fortress 2 is now is something that no one could even Conceive in their mind in that year.
Rym: neither was the original idea.
Scott: It would be as hard to conceive of the of the TF2 that we have now in 1999 or 2000 as it would be to conceive of computers in the year 1800.
Rym: See the thing is Team Fortress 2. the people making it Realized that Team Fortress and all of its brethren were pretty much Some of the best games ever and they got a lot of smart people together and said we are going to make Team Fortress 2. it is going to be the end-all the be-all the perfect team first-person shooter It is going to have everything is going to be the highest technology.
Rym: Most realistic best game ever Mm-hmm, and I've got here a video.
Rym: It looks like it's in German.
Rym: I think it looks like it's some sort of press conference at a con and obviously it's just a cam.
Rym: but This is a bunch of footage of the original Team Fortress 2 as it was slated to eventually come out in the year maybe 2000. yeah now you might think wait a minute.
Rym: This looks a lot like all those World War 2. whatever games people play today I point out that none of those games existed when they were making this.
Rym: This I mean the scene where it shows the guy fighting the tank and then they throw the grenade in the tank.
Rym: That was a wet dream for us back.
Rym: Then the idea of having a game and FPS that complex and that awesome Was too much to bear and that's why the game didn't get finished back.
Rym: Yeah because it was pretty much impossible.
Scott: it was ahead of its time.
Scott: too far so far ahead of its time that they needed more time to Get to get to get it and
Rym: by the time the technology got to the point where they could do that That was no longer what they wanted to do because that was what everyone else was doing.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And as a result, we got the great game we have today, even though I'm already sick of it Me too So much for that.
Rym: I waited ten years.
Rym: it comes out I play it a week.
Rym: Hey, yeah, okay You know Kid Icarus, right one of the best games ever and by best.
Scott: I qualify that by also saying hardest Yeah, well, it's sort of an infamous game.
Scott: I've never legitimately beaten it.
Scott: It's yeah, it's one of those I've barely beaten.
Scott: level two It's one of those few like infamous Nintendo games where you know Nintendo made it was a game way back in the day that was crazy popular But there was never a sequel and they never went anywhere with it and everyone's like, oh man, bring it back like earth pound.
Scott: They're like bring it back.
Scott: Bring it back.
Scott: You know Kid Icarus is the one that needs bringing back more than any other and Nintendo recognizes.
Scott: I think pit is gonna be is definitely gonna be in the next Smash Brothers brawl, whatever.
Scott: So they know the Kid Icarus is beloved and missed.
Scott: But here is something interesting.
Scott: I found this is the original Japanese television commercial for Kid Icarus.
Scott: now, there's two things important to notice about this.
Scott: one is a fucked-up commercial.
Scott: Maybe the guy turns ha Japanese commercial weird a. yeah I mean the guy turns to stone which is because of Medusa.
Scott: but like this kid runs by at the end Randomly and like I wish I knew what they were saying.
Scott: Maybe we should ask Emily to translate it, but it's a fucked-up commercial and it's pretty interesting.
Scott: But - at the end they're like all disk system because the you should go.
Scott: I'm not gonna explain what it was and everything about But in Japan they had the Famicom disk system and there were games for it on disks that you could get and it was nothing like anything we ever got.
Scott: and it was pretty awesome.
Scott: and You should learn about that because it's important Nintendo history.
Scott: That is not very well known in the US.
Rym: now regarding Kid Icarus I I'm curious how many of you out there actually really played that game.
Scott: So is it on the virtual console yet?
Rym: Yeah, it is but the is it?
Rym: the codes don't work really?
Rym: the old codes the broken codes Uh-huh, Kid Icarus was famous for having weird codes that gave you a lot of stuff And the reason for that was that there was basically not much check summing or check digits or anything in the password.
Rym: So it was very easy to make a legitimate password.
Rym: Hence Icarus fights Medusa Angel or packing packing packing packing or my favorite it ain't followed by an infinite stream of lowercase use Uh-huh, and none of those work in the virtual console version, apparently, uh-huh.
Scott: Well do any passwords work in the normal real passwords?
Rym: do I assume?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I gotta go look this up cuz.
Scott: uh, yeah, but anyway, it's.
Scott: it's a hard game has awesome music it you should probably play it.
Scott: Well,
Rym: I wonder one how many of you realize that not only is it a top scroller, but there's also a bunch of you know maze two-dimensional, you know up down left and right levels and There's some side scroll in Mario one kind of action in that game and at the end of the game It's a side scrolling shmup.
Rym: Yep Also, I really want to ask have any of you ever legitimately and by legitimately I mean without cheating or using someone else's code beaten that game?
Scott: Not many people have done that.
Rym: it's also His name's pit not Icarus.
Scott: I know I know his name is pit.
Scott: Did I say no you didn't.
Rym: I'm just saying that to all of you out there.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So today we're gonna.
Scott: we've been talking recently about a certain topic in gaming and me and Rym have differing opinions though I think a lot with us lately.
Rym: every time we introduce anything we start real generic like.
Scott: So I think I like.
Scott: I like doing it that way something so you don't get.
Scott: instead of getting to the point you sort of You know beat around the bush a little bit to drag people in so they wonder what you're talking about And then you hit him with it.
Rym: See it's a lot like how I was taught to write essays in middle school.
Rym: you start with a global statement And then you narrow it down to a thesis.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's like scorpion.
Scott: He's like he throws a little rope and he says get over here and then he says yeah Uppercut and the uppercut was really wall he wanted to do.
Scott: I mean if you were already next to me just uppercut you but now we got to do the get over here first.
Rym: see but At the same time when I got to 10th grade, mr.
Rym: Koval my but the best literature teacher I ever had And he taught me more grammar than anyone else in my life.
Rym: He taught us that and had us write a paper and then he failed all of us.
Rym: and then he taught us again how stupid it is to start with a global statement like that.
Rym: if you're saying something that's so Incontroversial and so nothing why even say it?
Rym: Why not just start with something important or something interesting?
Scott: Uh-huh Anyway, he knew about English but not about in literature, but not about radio, which is not literature.
Rym: See the thing is we're not radio in the some guys gonna flip past GeekNights in the middle And we got to try to get him to not flip to another thing.
Scott: No But we are radio in the sense that people listening to this are probably staring at their computers at work Not really paying full attention and by saying certain things I can get their attention like hey you hey, yeah you sitting there Yeah, right there looking at your computer screen not actually listening to the words of the podcast Just using it as background noise.
Scott: pay attention to what I'm about to say.
Scott: you suck.
Rym: Scott seems to have a bug up his butt about achievements and I am for the record.
Rym: I have Absolutely, nothing against achievements at all, and I don't know why he hates them so much.
Scott: Well, I think the thing is and you I guess are include is that I am.
Scott: I am definitely not pro achievement.
Scott: however, I think people are Misinterpreting and exaggerating and and misunderstanding my exact very specific position and opinion on achievements.
Rym: Do I could?
Rym: I could go to the forum and quote some things you've posted there about?
Scott: yeah But I never.
Scott: I was too lazy to actually post my entire full opinion in great detail.
Rym: Oh, so instead all those insults and all that that's a stupid idea and you're a stupid person That was those are true too.
Scott: But you know, they I didn't sum up the whole thing together.
Scott: I sort of doled it out in little bits never doling out the whole what we're talking about.
Rym: All right an Xbox I'm sure you all know but I know there's people who don't have Xboxes.
Rym: and now because this isn't a lot of steam games now Well, then it's in the orange box specifically.
Scott: Yeah, not any other steam games.
Rym: I Foresee a future where there is more of that.
Scott: Well as people, you know make more games that are for the 360 and the PC.
Scott: I've you know, they're doing achievements in one you leave them in the other.
Rym: It's not like, you know, especially since by and large people the world over love them.
Scott: Yeah, people seem to really like these things
Rym: and all they are is you can set When you make a game whatever kinds of carrot danglies you want Whatever kind of conditions of getting achievements and then whenever you meet those conditions in the game You get a little badge kind of like how in tie fighter if you get enough Secondary missions you get the extra little pin on the on the metal at the end of the mission.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So for example that you'll be playing I don't know Some zombie shooting game and there'll be.
Scott: there'll be an achievement for killing a thousand zombies.
Scott: So you're playing the game normally and suddenly you kill your thousands zombie.
Scott: You didn't even realize you killed your thousands zombie but you did.
Scott: and a thing pops up and says you killed a thousand zombie and it'll say thousand killer or something and it'll add to Your Xbox live gamers score will go up by a certain number of points and you'll get this little flag that says, you know You got X number out of X available possible achievements And if people look they'll see that you got the zombie killer achievement that you killed a thousand zombies in whatever game.
Scott: And that's what it is.
Scott: and my specific thing with this is that You know, there's nothing wrong with in it within a video game of setting goals, you know for people to achieve, you know For example, you know Metroid right?
Scott: It's like hey beat the game faster And you you you know, you'll see a different ending, you know that.
Scott: or hey, this is Tetris.
Scott: We're gonna give you a bonus level.
Scott: if you can beat this bonus level you get you know Stuff or like in portal there's like the challenge levels where the turrets are in cages and it's harder and it's like, you know Okay, that's cool.
Scott: But this stuff right these achievements They're not actually making like bonus rounds that are that are extra stuff.
Scott: They're just within the normal game like putting these things around that just pop up.
Rym: Well one I think one purpose that achievements can do which is it depends on the kind of game They'll use your thousand killer zombie example.
Rym: Yeah, let's say the first achievement of the game is you know killed a thousand zombie and it says thousand killer Wow, I got the thousand killer and then you find out that the next achievement is 25,000 killer.
Rym: suddenly you have this huge sense of scale that is just thrown in your face of.
Rym: It's kind of like a measure of how much of the game I've experienced or how much zombie killing I can expect from the rest.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: But that then my first.
Scott: that brings me to my first problem with achievements is that they are the meta.
Scott: now in some games Meta is not a problem.
Scott: but for example in my half-life 2 I had to turn those freakin achievements off.
Scott: cuz half-life 2 and you know It's sequels are all about a cinematic immersive experience and I'm playing it and then this thing pops up in the corner and it totally Throws me out of the game like, you know when you're watching a movie and you get thrown out of it and suddenly you're like Oh, I'm in a movie theater and you're totally not in it anymore.
Scott: That was not good and it sort of dulled the experience for me.
Scott: so I had to turn those achievement thingies off.
Rym: see at the same time when I was playing portal and I did the sad deed.
Rym: I did the bad thing and then Suddenly I get the achievement fratricide.
Rym: I busted out laughing.
Rym: That was the best thing ever.
Rym: No having that achievement appear at that moment actually added to the game.
Scott: Yeah, I guess in a way you could use achievements for funniness.
Scott: that there that is not you know.
Rym: and also in half-life 2 I don't think I would be thrown off by an achievement so much as I am by the fact that I'm stuck in a room And someone's talking at me.
Rym: Meanwhile, I'm jumping up and down on him.
Scott: Hey, I'm in the game when I'm doing that stuff.
Scott: That's what it's all about.
Scott: Yes, that's like natural selection when the gorges are making a pile on top of the cheese.
Scott: All right, my other problem with achievements is you know, this is not some rule of the universe here It's I guess you can't say it's the fault of the achievements even though I can make a case for it.
Scott: Is that whether you say you do it or not?
Scott: There are people and I've seen these people and these people say it outright They admit it is that there are people who are they're playing a video game, right and they are playing the video game More to get achievements when they would not have right.
Scott: so so here's the thing is someone is to play a video game Right, and now you're sitting there and they would if there was no achievement right?
Scott: pretend there's no achievements.
Scott: This person has no desire to play this video game again, right?
Scott: None whatsoever.
Scott: They they would not have fun doing it.
Scott: But now someone puts this, you know meta carrot of these points there Which is just nothing.
Scott: and suddenly they want to do it and it's like alright If it wasn't fun if it wasn't fun for you to do it now It's suddenly fun for you to do it because you're getting a number.
Scott: see one.
Rym: Why on earth does this bother you?
Scott: It doesn't bother me I don't you know, but it doesn't bother me really.
Scott: the thing is is that it's Wow Look at these people.
Scott: people can do whatever they want Hey can but I lose respect for them.
Scott: and when I see that silly
Rym: Scott now to
Scott: Someone who's gonna do something that is not entertaining Uh, you know in it because
Rym: you seem to be forgetting that part of what achievements do especially the fun the weird ones like Beat this with only taking a hundred steps or beat this game Carrying this object the whole way through
Scott: right?
Rym: It's okay Is it?
Rym: it's no different than a lot of like you to game.
Rym: facts.
Rym: for any game There's always like the challenges and someone's like hey, can you beat this game?
Rym: Without doing this or this or this or keep it this game with only one only one character.
Rym: and What the achievements do is instead of having to go to some stupid game fact and find some kid who said hey do this.
Rym: they give you a list of ideas like Check it out.
Rym: This is possible.
Rym: We are telling you right now out of the game We've already beaten it that this is possible.
Rym: if that means you can try to attempt it.
Rym: It'll give you the idea, huh?
Rym: I wonder if I have the skill to pull that off.
Scott: Yeah, and you know what.
Scott: back in the day without achievements people still did this all the time beating Zelda without the sword.
Rym: Not everyone a lot of people have never occurred to them and I think one thing the achievement.
Scott: They don't lose respect for those people.
Scott: They're dumb.
Scott: They're not paying attention to their games.
Scott: That's silly.
Scott: Not creative in their gameplay.
Rym: So even if you're creative What if you just don't think of one thing?
Rym: or even worse if you're the first one or there's nothing to tell you it's possible.
Rym: All right you're gonna spend a lot of time possibly trying to do things that the game will not let you do.
Rym: this at least gives you the.
Rym: This is possible.
Rym: Now.
Rym: It's a puzzle.
Rym: figure it out.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: However There are people out there who it.
Scott: let's say you had the same game, right and you put in a special mode.
Scott: For example, that was like the hundred step mode where once you took your hundred and first step It said game over on the screen and it put you back out.
Scott: You know, I had the hundred step mode.
Scott: Yeah, right There's nothing wrong with that.
Scott: But there are people out there where if you had the game with a hundred step mode They would do the hundred step mode just become frustrated and wouldn't play it.
Scott: But you put that achievement there and suddenly these people are playing it like crazy trying to win it and trying to get this thing Just to get this useless points thing.
Scott: Well, I mean anything one.
Rym: Why do you care?
Rym: Cuz you really really can't seem to let this go It's not?
Scott: you see you keep saying I care as you do is the fact that these people are doing something which otherwise Why do you care?
Scott: Because this people doing something since the same reason I care if I see people.
Scott: No, why do you get pissed off at people doing stupid things that don't affect you all the time?
Rym: because it does affect me.
Scott: No, there are plenty of things, you know You see like someone being fat even if they're totally not in your way and you're like, wow that person's hurting themselves.
Scott: Wow, that person's doing something is not fun for them.
Scott: Wow, that person's doing something is not good for them and you don't think For an achievement is hurting anybody.
Scott: It's something that others there are people who would are doing things which otherwise would not be fun for them.
Scott: But suddenly, you know because of this psychological trick Scott one of a of a immaterial one Where are you getting this information?
Scott: Just go on the internet and look everyone.
Scott: people are saying all man's, you know Look at all my mad achievements.
Scott: What's my game?
Scott: risk or so much higher than yours.
Scott: or yeah I'm getting this game on a 360 instead of the ps3 because it has achievements.
Rym: Well, that's a given because it's the same game with something extra if it costs something extra.
Scott: It's nothing.
Scott: That's the thing is guys and it's a nut it's a carrot but this carrot is nothing.
Scott: but like you get there You do you run you get the carrot you eat it and it's it's nothing.
Scott: It's the hollow Picture of a carrot.
Rym: It's the exact same game.
Rym: Plus if you want it, you've got the achievement system.
Rym: Why not buy the one with the achievement system?
Scott: because the achievement system is nothing.
Scott: It's nothing.
Scott: It's just little things that pop up.
Scott: That's not anything Scott.
Rym: Mario 3 is no different.
Rym: It's just little things that pop up.
Scott: what things that pop?
Rym: Goombas and stuff.
Rym: It's no different.
Scott: That's not pie.
Scott: It's you know, that's not what I'm saying.
Rym: What are you saying?
Rym: All you're saying Scott is that you think that someone who is willing to pay the same amount and have an extra thing even though You don't care about that thing is somehow stupid because that extra thing is nothing.
Rym: It's like if you're not it's nothing to you.
Scott: It's that is if it's something to you.
Scott: I did I don't I lose respect for you.
Scott: It's nothing.
Scott: That's just the same as World of Warcraft.
Scott: gold and World of Warcraft is nothing.
Scott: levels in World of Warcraft are nothing.
Scott: That's not an actual, you know, it's not an actual reward.
Scott: It's not so.
Rym: if you beat a game in a really hard way like say you beat Zelda without a sword Would you ever tell anyone?
Scott: I might but it.
Rym: you're saying if you beat Zelda 1, but I just saw it.
Scott: Anyone should be able to do that.
Scott: It's easy Sky.
Rym: you're missing the point.
Rym: Let's say you're a kid.
Rym: you beat Zelda 1 without the sword.
Rym: Are you just gonna go?
Rym: Wow, I did it and then just never say anything again.
Rym: Are you gonna tell someone?
Scott: I'm I have someone asked.
Rym: Aha you're just gonna never tell anyone unless they ask you by chance.
Rym: Hey Scott, have you ever beaten Zelda 1 without the sword?
Scott: Yeah, it's easy.
Rym: You're missing the point.
Scott: Do you see me bragging about my video game skills a lot?
Rym: Oh when we were doing the FPS shows when we were talking about Team Fortress 2 I think you are much more the braggart of your skills than I am.
Rym: Well, I'm a lot better than you So I think that's justified.
Scott: Yeah, I see you proved my point exactly.
Scott: and second of all I'm pretty much I am very honest with my statement of my skills.
Scott: I don't claim to be any sort of God in any way.
Scott: I'm just you know, and in fact a lot of games I suck.
Scott: I know a lot of our like wait three.
Scott: a lot of our listeners like it's our hero gods.
Scott: and I'm just like still you Know not passing every song on hard.
Rym: I was just saying Justin at the FPS world particularly the twitch FPS.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, the point is.
Rym: the point is someone else wants achievements or they like achievements Then obviously they should buy the one that has the achievements in it.
Rym: What do you care?
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: All right, I get when I play a game the reason that's you yeah who cares about you?
Scott: I'm not saying anyone has to care about me.
Scott: I'm saying is that I get my enjoyment from games because I actually feel like I achieve something real.
Scott: or I do achieve something real Or I decrease my skill or I get a real reward of some kind.
Scott: And when I see people getting enjoyment from nothings, then I don't respect that.
Rym: but Getting what reward you get from beating mario 3?
Rym: that's any different from getting level 70 in World of Warcraft?
Rym: There's no difference.
Scott: There is a difference in my.
Scott: to beat mario 3 actually requires skill.
Scott: you actually build up a skill over time.
Scott: to beat to get Level 70 of World of Warcraft only takes time.
Scott: It's not so.
Scott: unless you risk you're respecting somebody's Ability.
Rym: you got to have precision timing and button presses or skill at mario 3 is just as laughably useless.
Scott: See but there's actually a skill there and there's actually a feeling of accomplishment.
Rym: It's not a real accomplishment.
Scott: It is a real account.
Rym: Oh, it's a feeling of accomplishment is no different than an achievement.
Scott: No, there is a real accomplishment.
Scott: at the beginning You are not Physically able to do it and then over time you built up your ability to do it and some people are unable to write Ability to do it.
Scott: So World of Warcraft requires no increase of ability.
Scott: It requires only an increase.
Rym: Yeah, fine, so all right, what's the difference between beating mario 3 or beating the whatever video game in a hundred steps?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: there's nothing wrong with beating the video game in a hundred steps.
Scott: the thing that.
Scott: so why not?
Scott: the thing that's wrong Is that if you're doing it because you get this little flag to light up?
Scott: It's like basically imagine you're playing mario 3, right?
Scott: Okay, you play mario 3 you beat it.
Scott: It's fun.
Scott: Now.
Scott: What if I told you?
Scott: Hey, if you can beat mario 3 in an hour I'll turn this light on.
Scott: now suddenly you decide you want to do it really bad.
Scott: You want that light to turn on so bad so that someone's caring about a light turning on.
Scott: that is what I disrespect.
Rym: Why why do you care?
Scott: It's not because that's innate.
Scott: Do you care if some frickin light turns on?
Scott: No, you get the enjoyment from the game itself.
Scott: If you're getting the enjoyment from a light turning on what kind of person are you you enjoy something so meaningless?
Rym: Wow Scott way to take a little video game thing and try to get all self-righteous about it.
Scott: That's what I am Self-righteous about it.
Rym: I think you're right.
Scott: I can't get in.
Rym: at best perhaps I can't get.
Scott: I get a point of a game.
Scott: the point of games in general all games is to have some sort of Challenge without the risk and to build your skills, you know Challenge everything Scott.
Rym: there are games that involve no skill.
Rym: there again, and there's still a game.
Rym: There are games that are pure enjoyment.
Rym: There are games that don't build anything except enjoyment and relaxation.
Scott: But those games have some redeemable aspects like what actual reward like what well like apples to apples has a reward of humor?
Scott: Yeah, you get it.
Scott: You get a humorous social situation.
Rym: You know what's an effect.
Scott: you increase your social skills and you got on with other people.
Scott: There's an actual reward.
Rym: achievement gives you proof that you did something very.
Rym: that's not an actual.
Scott: or there's a light bulb turning on.
Scott: a light Bulb turning on is not a reward.
Rym: So basically what you're saying is anything you say is a reward.
Rym: anything you say isn't a reward isn't a reward and therefore I'm saying yes, you are.
Scott: No, I'm saying no, you're saying different things are rewarding to different people.
Rym: However, if you think a light bulb turning on is rewarding if that's rewarding for you I disrespect you and I just find that stance utterly silly and I think you take these at this achievement thing way too.
Scott: Seriously, I'm not taking it way too.
Rym: Seriously you freak out about it every time.
Scott: We I'm just saying what it is.
Scott: and the thing is people give us a huge backlash and I'm like, dude You're the one who cares about a light bulb turning on.
Rym: I think the backlash is because you're kind of a jerk about it all the time.
Scott: Yeah, I am a jerk about it.
Scott: cuz I if I disrespect someone now, I gotta be a jerk to them.
Scott: That's how it goes.
Rym: If you disrespect someone because they like one part of a kind of video game Then you don't happen to like that exact same part of a kind of video game.
Rym: That's really silly.
Scott: I disrespect anyone.
Scott: people who get enjoy like if people, you know get enjoyment from shallow things I disrespect.
Rym: you just said you get enjoyment from Lego Star Wars, which is a stupid shallow bullshit game.
Scott: I get enjoyment from the humor aspect and when that humor aspect runs out, I probably won't play it anymore.
Rym: But yet you walked around for 15 minutes destroying things in a Lego City and it wasn't entertaining.
Rym: It was almost it wasn't.
Scott: it was painful.
Rym: Then why did you do it?
Scott: because the psychology of it was too demanding and I couldn't.
Scott: I know you're saying time to overcome that.
Rym: Wait, so you're saying that you had no conscious control over the fact that you ran around as Darth Maul Destroying a tiny Lego City for 15 minutes.
Scott: I had control over it.
Scott: The problem was is I realized what was going on and I couldn't help it for a bit and I realized that's what happening to people thing is.
Rym: Came it and said you couldn't help it.
Rym: That means you didn't have control until you did overcome it.
Scott: I knew what was going on.
Rym: You're saying that Lego Star Wars was able to control your body for a small amount of time and you were unable Without effort to overcome that mentally.
Rym: and yet you're trying to disrespect someone who likes a light bulb.
Scott: Yes, because the difference is is that I knew what was going on and I stopped it in about a minute Whereas I see other people.
Scott: they're doing it for years and years and years and years on end without stopping or realizing or admitting It Scott that the psychology of the video games is controlling them.
Rym: Scott achievements haven't been around that long.
Scott: I'm not talking about achievements.
Scott: and look at World of Warcraft.
Scott: people are playing this thing.
Scott: It's the same shit.
Scott: Look at look at muds back in the day.
Scott: It was the same shit.
Scott: I eventually realized it and stopped doing it yet.
Scott: There are people defending this sort of, you know Invisible non, you know real carrot stuff.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with carrot and stick as long as it's a real stick and a real.
Rym: but Scott It's not a real carrot beating.
Rym: Mario 3 is a virtual carrot and so is beating.
Rym: so it's not beating.
Scott: Mario 3 is an actual carrot.
Rym: You don't get anything physical.
Scott: Yes, you do you ink you get the Satisfaction that your ability has increased.
Scott: Okay in yourself that you have bettered yourself in some even though it's a meaningless way you have bettered yourself.
Scott: It's the same feeling is if you just run and jump over, you know, you're doing the high jump.
Scott: You know you jump and you can jump higher and then you make you know, six feet and you go.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I can jump six feet.
Scott: It's that self of achievement that I have increased my personal ability, even it's something meaningless.
Scott: I mean the high jump isn't useful.
Rym: So it's got someone by beating all those achievements has increased their personal ability at whatever that game was.
Scott: But you can do that without those stupid achievements.
Scott: and but the time is that a lot of you wouldn't be doing it without the.
Rym: You keep saying that you don't know that.
Scott: that's what it's looking like to me.
Scott: go around the internet Look around look what people are saying.
Rym: you back that up.
Rym: You're the one making a positive claim.
Scott: I'm sad.
Scott: So what I've?
Scott: that's what I've seen on the internet.
Scott: So these people are saying so some guy on the internet Is your awesome guy in the air?
Scott: It's lots of people on the internet.
Scott: go to gaming blogs where there are articles about achievements and look at the comments.
Rym: So you read all those comments?
Rym: I think that's a much bigger waste of time than getting some achievements in portal.
Scott: I'm doing research for this show.
Rym: I'm sure yeah.
Rym: Imagine you just sitting there being righteously indignant fuming into your chair.
Rym: Ah, these people.
Rym: Ah, they're so stupid.
Rym: Why can't they all be perfect gods among men like me?
Rym: And you aren't the same way I'm sitting in my air on chair.
Rym: I have no cares in the world.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah I just see nothing wrong with achievements.
Rym: See the thing is your argument is one achievements are stupid and two people who care about them are stupid.
Scott: Yep That's my argument But all your.
Rym: the only argument you actually made effectively at all was possibly the second half Achievements in and of themselves.
Rym: There's nothing wrong with that at all zero.
Rym: You can't even make the argument.
Rym: There's anything wrong with it.
Scott: all it is, but they're just nothing.
Scott: if people know They're adding them is adding nothing to the game.
Scott: It's a waste of all they are.
Rym: space is a little system checked on doesn't take anything.
Rym: You don't have to buy into it.
Rym: You don't have to do anything with.
Rym: if you don't want to you can turn it off.
Rym: It's not gonna cancer.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you can't turn it off in the Xbox.
Scott: You can turn it off and you don't even own an Xbox.
Rym: What do you care?
Rym: It's not gonna come into your bedroom and rape you tonight like I'm going to know.
Scott: The point is it does.
Scott: I made the point that it does mess with games by putting you into the meta.
Scott: it puts this meta Thing over the games themselves.
Rym: Oh, yeah, Scott What if people like the meta?
Rym: a lot of people play games met.
Rym: when I play advanced wars I play advanced wars as a series of equations.
Rym: It is nothing but math.
Rym: It is nothing but the meta.
Rym: when I play German board games half the time when I win It's not because of the game or what I'm doing in the game because I'm watching what other people do and playing the meta.
Rym: Scott always in T&E for the longest time used to he'd always when he's fiddled with his tiles behind his screen and whenever he had Three or more he'd always fill from the top.
Rym: We ever had two or less.
Rym: he'd always fiddle from the side and he did it perfectly And I was able to beat him a lot before I finally pointed it out.
Rym: That's purely meta.
Rym: Are you saying that's just as bad as achievements in the Xbox?
Scott: that has nothing to do with achievements in the Xbox But it's meta.
Rym: I'm playing a game in a meta thing.
Scott: No The reason that the meta is bad is because it takes you.
Scott: it can has the potential to take you out of immersive experience.
Rym: What if someone doesn't care about the immersive experience?
Rym: What if they will only care about the skill of the game?
Rym: I mean the immersive experience in a game is oftentimes just an FMV or a scripted pseudo FMV.
Scott: If you care about the skill of a game Then you will get your enjoyment from the self of a comp the sense of accomplishment you get when you build your skill And you don't need an imaginary illusion of a carrot to convince you to keep playing the game.
Scott: if you are only playing a game because of an Illusionary carrot then why?
Scott: and you're not actually having fun with the game itself And you're only having fun in the pursuit of the illusionary carrot.
Scott: What are you doing?
Rym: There's a lot of hard video games where a lot of people don't enjoy them except the chat.
Rym: It's so hard or so difficult.
Rym: the only carrot they get is the fact that they stuck to it even though it wasn't fun and Then they beat it.
Rym: and that not fun translates into double fun, right?
Scott: And there's no reason you don't need these illusionary achievement carrots to have that.
Rym: I didn't say you need them However, and they don't help.
Rym: However, let's say it's a person who yeah, they are enjoying it All right Now if they're gonna enjoy it and they're doing these things because they want the challenge and for nothing more than because they enjoy the Challenge.
Rym: why not have an extra system if they want it that allows them to one prove that they did it and two Give them direction on what to do.
Rym: and three to make prove to themselves that they did it right.
Rym: in some games It's hard to tell or keep track.
Rym: It'd be easy to fudge it a little bit.
Rym: It forces you to keep honest with yourself and actually achieve it legitimately.
Rym: So when you do, you know without a doubt that look I did it.
Rym: even if you never show it to anyone You've got proof.
Rym: the game says you did exactly what you set out to do.
Rym: if you don't have that There's a chance that you might accidentally screw it up and you might not have done something as difficult as you thought you did.
Scott: It doesn't matter if you can prove you did what you did.
Scott: That's anyone.
Scott: all that matters is that you had fun doing it.
Rym: Yes, but at the same time what if you have more fun by knowing that you did it, right?
Scott: You have more fun because you prove that you did something.
Rym: No because that you'd know that you did it, right?
Rym: What if there was a bug in Doom 2 and I was playing and I thought I beat the game.
Rym: I'm playing to beat the game on the hardest difficulty level and I finally beat it and I had fun.
Rym: But it turns out that I was playing on the easiest difficulty level and I was just stupid and said it wrong.
Scott: That was just you being stupid.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So what if?
Rym: why not have a system that prevents that?
Scott: That the achievements don't prevent that.
Scott: Yeah, they do don't prevent you from choosing the wrong.
Rym: You can't get the achievement unless you actually accomplish the thing.
Scott: when you beat doom on hard It says you beat it.
Scott: You get a different ending than when you beat doom on easy.
Scott: No, you don't.
Scott: it says it doesn't say you know hard.
Rym: Do you don't get shit?
Scott: Somehow yeah, then that's just.
Scott: that's just something wrong with the game.
Scott: The achievement system is not a system that solves that problem.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: All the achievement system is is hey, hey, you've already beaten the game.
Rym: You already own it.
Rym: check out all these things you can do.
Rym: we guarantee that they're possible.
Rym: Good luck.
Scott: Yeah, you get it.
Scott: You can just why not?
Scott: just have bonus modes.
Scott: You don't need this achievement system Achievement.
Scott: you don't need this meta system outside of the game to handle it.
Rym: Just have why not?
Rym: why not?
Rym: It's it's just instead of having a why what do you say?
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Why why have it?
Scott: Why not just have bonus modes and games the way we've had them for years and years and years?
Scott: Why do we need this meta system outside of the game to handle that in some sort of organized scoring way?
Rym: Well, apparently because a lot of people want that.
Scott: they do Because it's an illusionary carrot and it works on most people and I don't respect that.
Rym: So your argument is that the quote illusionary carrot of an achievement is somehow Less real than the illusionary carrot of a princess that was kidnapped by a big turtle with spikes.
Rym: Yes That's ludicrous, oh it's not.
Rym: I think it is.
Rym: I think you take this way too seriously.
Scott: I basically take the illusionary carrot thing way too seriously.
Rym: Uh, yeah, that's it.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: I don't take the achievement thing It's.
Scott: it's just the achievement thing happens to be.
Scott: No, they're not.
Rym: How so I already explained how many times I explain this because I don't agree with what you said at all.
Scott: You're playing Tetris right.
Scott: beating Tetris is is actually you.
Scott: you're accomplishing something.
Scott: you're increasing.
Scott: You have to have skill in order to do it.
Rym: Scott to get some of those achievements You have to have a lot of skill to do it.
Scott: Yes But I don't need someone to tell me that I don't need.
Scott: if it was actually fun if there was actually some Building of skill that building of skill is enough to motivate me so all of my skill and it's enough to provide me.
Rym: You run a marathon.
Rym: what if you run a marathon?
Rym: or you run a marathon and at the end there's a guy who says wow You're at a marathon.
Rym: That's great.
Rym: Now doesn't cost you anything to have that guy there?
Rym: the guys either there or not If you're if you're going to run the marathon because no Scott I'm going to say that's a separate argument Because what I'm trying to say is your argument is a whole different thing.
Rym: The achievements themselves are not a problem They're just a tool.
Rym: I'm like any other tool in gaming that the achievements are just a guy at the end of the game saying great and Without that guy there.
Rym: It's still the same game.
Rym: There's just not a guy.
Rym: How does having the guy there hurt you?
Scott: It doesn't hurt me.
Scott: I'm not saying it hurts me.
Rym: How does it hurt anyone?
Rym: The reason you want to plays for just you know, the enjoyment of playing.
Rym: How does it hurt them?
Scott: If you're playing actually for the enjoyment of playing then you don't need the guy.
Scott: So why have him there?
Scott: but you're playing for the guy, but it's then.
Scott: if you're only playing for that guy Why are you playing?
Rym: but Scott if the guy is arbitrary whether he's there or not?
Rym: Then why it doesn't matter if he's there or not?
Rym: So why not have him doesn't?
Scott: why have him and he does hurt?
Scott: I already explained how it can hurt by taking you out of the immersion of a game.
Rym: But Scott if all people don't care about that Not everyone has the same taste in games you do yes, and I disrespect them.
Scott: how many times you had to go through this.
Rym: I just still can't get over the fact that you would disrespect someone because their choice in video games.
Scott: If I see someone putting effort towards achieving something I don't want to use the word achieving to make it confusing but I have to but achieving something that is not Worthwhile, okay.
Rym: So someone with a PhD in nuclear physics sees you playing Mario 3 and thinks why is that boy wasting his valuable time on this?
Scott: I may not be achieving as much as the PhD that is obvious, but not achieving any more than someone getting an Xbox achieve?
Scott: No, I am.
Scott: No, you're not.
Scott: Yes, I am.
Scott: My enjoyment is not coming from an illusion.
Scott: My enjoyment is coming from an actual building of skill within myself.
Rym: Want to think that Mario 3 is somehow nobler than some Xbox achievement.
Rym: you can keep thinking that it is Okay, if what the difference is is that if you're getting the enjoyment, what do you care?
Scott: It cuz it's all about where the enjoyment comes.
Rym: why you care if someone's into BDSM and that's how they get their rocks off Huh?
Rym: What do you care?
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: The point is is that if you get your enjoyment from the achievement Obviously care because you keep talking You keep basically I explain things already and you keep.
Scott: you're not getting my point.
Rym: Well, no I get your point.
Rym: I think your point silly and I disagree with it.
Rym: I'm gonna be with your evidence.
Scott: I'm gonna conclude with this so you freaking understand what I'm saying and stop confusing me and try it's trying to put words in my Mouth.
Rym: no, I understand it.
Rym: I just disagree with.
Rym: if
Scott: you're getting enjoyment from the actual sense of accomplishment of Defeating a challenge of overcoming obstacles Then you don't need some little light to turn on to get more enjoyment If you are getting your enjoyment from the light turning on and you're not actually getting enjoyment from the things that you're doing to get The light to turn on.
Scott: why the fuck are you doing them?
Scott: The achievement system is unnecessary.
Scott: You might say oh Well, it doesn't hurt anything.
Scott: Well, I just gave one example of where it could potentially hurt and I have shown that is absolutely not necessary.
Scott: Therefore why is it Scott?
Rym: I don't think that that hurts at all.
Scott: We don't need it.
Rym: We don't need video games.
Rym: We know video.
Rym: get this story.
Scott: You're gonna start arguing my knees It's just gonna get so cuz you said if you're gonna make the need argument We don't need it doesn't help and it has the potential to hurt.
Rym: I shouldn't got.
Rym: a lot of things don't help and have the potential to hurt and those things are bad.
Rym: I Think video games are the same.
Rym: No, a lot of people play video games, even if they just enjoy them They don't play for any reward.
Rym: They just sit there and play Tetris forever But you're getting some.
Scott: you're.
Scott: the source of enjoyment from playing Tetris comes from somewhere different.
Scott: It comes from an actual air.
Scott: It comes from actual accomplishment.
Scott: It comes from the sense of overcoming a challenge a fake challenge.
Scott: It's the same virtual carrot It's no it's an actual challenge.
Scott: You take my mom cannot play Tetris as well as I can.
Scott: I have overcome I can.
Scott: I can do the high jump or the pole vault higher than my mom.
Scott: A greater challenge regardless, I'm better.
Rym: I'm way gonna end the show cuz it's time to go to bed.
Scott: and yeah, this is you fail to understand.
Rym: No, I understand perfectly what you're saying.
Rym: I understood every word that you've said.
Rym: I just disagree.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.