Rym: It's Tuesday March 13th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight still without internet.
Rym: We talk a little bit about saving your game.
Scott: Let's do this Mmm.
Scott: Gummy bear.
Rym: yeah, gummy bears luckily.
Rym: I took the bag away from Scott, so you won't hear Crackle Crackle Crackle throughout the show tonight unless I get up and get him from the other side of the room.
Rym: I'm factoring in your laziness Damn you plus the fact that we're not taking a break because we still don't have the internet.
Rym: So we're not really gonna bother with things of the day.
Rym: You know what we'll still do things of the day But it'll be the best thing we saw in the last 24 hours.
Rym: Oh crap internet or no We got time.
Rym: we got time.
Rym: all right you can think of something I'm thinking.
Rym: But before we get to that in the news since we can only talk about News that did not come to us from any sort of electronic medium since we don't have access to any non-electronic mediums I'm not gonna go get a newspaper.
Scott: There's no way I'm ever gonna pay for a newspaper.
Scott: While Google News exists a newspaper will not Scott by.
Rym: I could have gotten the free newspaper in New York City.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I didn't see any people giving out free newspaper.
Scott: Oh you mean like the AM, New York or the Metro?
Scott: Yeah, okay?
Scott: Sometimes they do give away like the poster the times for free.
Scott: when when some advertiser puts in like a big Advertising section and that pays for the papers and no one needs to pay for.
Rym: well There's one pizza place I eat at often and they always have the New York Post just sitting there.
Rym: So I often read it if I'm not reading a novel.
Scott: It's basically a tabloid.
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Rym: I usually read the comics to remind myself how bad newspaper comics are.
Rym: So along those lines since this is the only thing I could observe about today that was it all interesting.
Rym: That was the shortest winter ever.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: it was warm as in shorts and a t-shirt until Early mid-february, and it's now early mid-march and it's shorts and t-shirt weather again.
Scott: It wasn't shorts and t-shirt was mid-february.
Rym: On February 9th was the last day I went running in shorts and a t-shirt at night And you hadn't been going in shorts and a t-shirt since like you know August I had been.
Rym: the only time I didn't is when I had to go to work And they won't let me wear that stuff there.
Scott: Well, you know it was cold and gray just wasn't wintery snowy stormy until like January and February.
Rym: Well, we had a cold snap or two But otherwise it was mostly what remember.
Rym: the day after New Year's all of us went on a long Shorts and t-shirt hike.
Scott: yeah, it was still warm.
Rym: then yeah, and now it's warm again.
Rym: I just went out running in shorts and a t-shirt.
Rym: It's gonna be almost 70 degrees tomorrow.
Rym: We got a rainstorm coming.
Rym: Maybe a thunderstorm.
Scott: I guess regardless of the actual weather it.
Scott: You know they think the winter Doldrums did last the usual amount of time.
Rym: Yeah, maybe just where you go or where you were going then because in Yonkers it was sunny almost every day.
Scott: Well now the feeling of winter is over has definitely overcome my Yes senses.
Rym: well the big difference today as opposed to any other day was today when I went outside to run It didn't smell like winter anymore.
Rym: I could smell things.
Scott: Yeah, I was able to open my sunroof, which I forgot.
Scott: I even had yep moonroof.
Rym: I guess technically and Also, I opened the windows and I was like ah Yep, I left my windows to my room open all day and my room smells nice.
Scott: Windows to my room.
Rym: turning the fan on Won't be long till we'll put the air conditioners in and then Al Gore's global warming will make it too hot and the power grid will Go out.
Rym: there'll be mass chaos New York will flood will all die.
Scott: But or we'll just stay cool in our rooms with our computers and our air conditioning.
Scott: that will hopefully have internet access.
Rym: It's also I realized now because I'm looking at computers that I had said I'm gonna get a computer By summer of this year and summers coming up, so I thought it was in Summer.
Scott: you were gonna get one not by summer.
Scott: Are you are you pushing it up?
Scott: Oh my god Rym the Luddite is gonna buy a computer sooner than he thought he was.
Rym: well Here's the thing.
Rym: originally my plan was I'm going to have a computer that would be delivered to my house One week before Team Fortress 2 was released.
Rym: That was my original plan and Team Fortress 2 got pushed back a couple times.
Scott: It's pushed back quite a bit.
Rym: Yeah, and I know when I made that original plan I expected to be making a new computer in like May give or take.
Rym: And now now if Team Fortress 2 is gonna come out and you know late fall I don't know if I want to wait that long partly because once it gets warm This computer made it through the winter mostly due to the fact that it's not hot.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: in the summer rims computer It has been known to overheat quite a bit.
Rym: well the thing is way back in the day I overclock this bastard A lot so as a result I had the hardware temperature alarm to warn me if I was pushing it a little too hard.
Rym: So and the thing is once it goes off You cannot stop it without rebooting the computer Which would force me to reboot it because otherwise I wouldn't and in fact there were many times.
Rym: I'd be playing counter-strike in colony with the super overclock motherboard going and it would start overheating and I'd keep playing counter-strike despite the noise.
Rym: because the game was more important than this you should have unplugged the VZ speaker.
Rym: I thought about that, but I didn't have enough time because there I only had six seconds between rounds, and I wasn't dying.
Scott: Well like before you start a game of counter-strike unplug it.
Rym: then when you're done playing plug it back in now cuz if I put That much forethought into circumventing my own protection mechanisms It's Chernobyl man.
Scott: That's what that is.
Rym: But the worst thing is as the computers gotten older.
Rym: it Started going off more and more because the fans are all frail And I'm not gonna buy new fans for this busted old computer.
Scott: That would be silly.
Rym: and also the video card was getting older and older and started overheating more and more and Eventually got to the point where I'd be asleep in the middle of the night in the summer, and it'd be like 75 degrees out And I hear Scott laughing in the other room as I wake up.
Scott: fuck god That's what you get for being a Luddite and you know being so averse to spending even a dollar on technology like Problem.
Scott: you'll spend all kinds of money on other crap you don't need but if it's a computer or something you will hold out until The last possible minute, it's not just a computer my car.
Scott: You'll hold out past the last possible minute like the time has passed where you should have bought one And that was two years ago, and you still didn't buy.
Rym: think of this.
Scott: this computer lasted me How long and I would argue that it hasn't actually lasted.
Rym: It's doing the show just fine.
Scott: Yeah, okay It's more like a zombie It's not.
Scott: it was dead and now it's sort of anything.
Rym: my computer can still play counter-strike with maximum FPS?
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: It's got a TNT - in it.
Rym: Oh yeah the TNT - that's right.
Rym: the video card died.
Rym: Yeah, that's right, but I could buy a $15 AGP card, and then it would be back to playing counter-strike at 100 FPS.
Scott: Yeah, that's all you.
Rym: but you see with that doo doo doo problem I solved that because it started getting bad now that I moved to this new house And I don't leave the AC on when I'm not home I just open the windows.
Rym: so I turn like I said the AC so it'll turn on in my room Maybe an hour before I get home from work.
Rym: You know just to save electricity There's no reason to cool a room when I'm not in here, and I'd always come home to the computer going.
Rym: So I went to the BIOS and I just told it to go off like four or five degrees centigrade higher And it stopped going off.
Rym: good job kind of like when the case fan started making all this noise.
Rym: I fixed that by unplugging it.
Rym: Good job, or when the CPU for the video card fan started making all that noise I just pulled it off of the video is enough about rims.
Rym: dead computer not dead yet.
Rym: It's doing the show.
Rym: Yeah, it's working.
Rym: You keep telling yourself that people are listening to the show.
Scott: so What were you doing the show on?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: don't you have some news?
Scott: no there's no internet.
Scott: um all right well I heard from someone that That Some guy at the game developers conference said the Wii sucked and then he apologized.
Rym: Scott I read that before we lost our internet.
Rym: I didn't or at least I read it.
Rym: Maybe I read it Friday morning?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I read it on the internet.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't have any details.
Scott: I don't know the guy's name.
Scott: I think he works for will.
Scott: right at EA.
Scott: on the spore game.
Rym: Yeah, you basically said that developing software for the Wii sucks because the Wii is weak.
Scott: Yeah, he's right, but at the same time the Wii doesn't suck.
Scott: no no in fact in fact He sucks.
Scott: the end of story.
Rym: the Wii is still Far away in my opinion the second best console out currently number one being the DS.
Scott: Yeah, it's just cuz.
Rym: the Wii like.
Scott: it's got everything it needs But the games aren't there yet.
Rym: Don't think I'm a fanboy because the Xbox 360 is right there at number three as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: Yeah, I think the difference between the Xbox 360 and the Wii is that the Wii has the higher potential.
Scott: the Xbox 360 had a great potential not as high as the Wii But the Xbox 360 has already pretty much completely fulfilled its potential.
Rym: Well, here's the thing that the Xbox seems to do that.
Rym: This isn't a big deal to us.
Rym: I think this is why we're not excited about the Xbox and a lot of Older PC gamers aren't excited about the Xbox but younger generations and people who didn't play a lot of FPS is back in the day.
Rym: They're super excited.
Rym: The Xbox is doing now for modern gamers What PC gaming with FPS is did back in the day with a lot more technological fiddling.
Rym: I mean we had team speak and you know headsets and we talked to our friends while we were deathmatching Online with all everything that they have now in the Xbox back in the day.
Rym: So when we see a console doing this we think why would I use that when I can do the same thing slightly better?
Scott: if not The Xbox existed.
Scott: those things were done on the PC.
Scott: Well, they are still done on the PC.
Scott: the Xbox has sort of killed PC gaming for the most part.
Rym: my point is just that to someone who never played quake 2 with a Team speak server or counter-strike at its peak or tribes 2 when it was and probably still is the best game ever made.
Rym: It's the best online FPS ever made in my opinion.
Rym: maybe I can't think of much better.
Rym: I mean half-life and single-player game.
Rym: that's different.
Rym: Mmm Yeah, but anyway, we'll argue about that on some other nights Maybe when we have access to the internet to look at a list of every FPS ever.
Rym: But to someone who's never did done all that because those things are really old.
Rym: those things came out a long time ago.
Rym: if you get an Xbox and you've never played FPS is before and someone says you can play these shooting games Online with your friends and talk to them at the same time.
Scott: Oh god is the best thing ever.
Scott: Yeah co-op.
Rym: I think that's really where the Xbox seems to shine.
Rym: is all these co-op games?
Scott: Yeah, they're definitely a lack of co-op games on the PC and on the Wii and pretty much everywhere except the Xbox 360.
Rym: granted I once played with my friend.
Rym: can we play doom 2 all the way through on ultra violence?
Scott: on co-op When we get when he finally get new computers, I definitely want to try to play the serious Sam with the co-op.
Scott: Yeah, that's just run around and shoot stuff.
Rym: Whoo We should play doom 2 all the way through just for nostalgia's sake.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway without further ado Things of the day now.
Rym: since we don't have internet access I suppose things of the day now have to be the best thing we've seen in the last 24 hours regardless of where it came from.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Have you seen anything?
Rym: Well, you want to go first.
Rym: you want me to go first?
Scott: You know, I work in the city so you'd think I would see something exciting.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I remember when you watch those guys take down that purse snatcher.
Scott: Yeah, that was like years ago though That was when you were working in the city.
Scott: Yeah last time the last time Um, I was walking to the subway on my way out of the office and a guy came up to me and he said like I Thought he was gonna ask for directions.
Scott: He had like an index card and like he was just like hey, what's up?
Scott: and then he showed me the index card and he was like Just a dollar and the index card had like a whole sob story on it and I was like not even bothering to tell me your fake sob story and The sob story that seems to be working that that's it seems to be going around.
Scott: that's super common.
Rym: Now is my truck ran out of gas.
Scott: No, no, no It's.
Scott: it's like I have two children.
Scott: my spouse is dead or lost or ran away or something kidnapped by the Yeah, I need money to take care of my kids.
Scott: I don't have a job.
Scott: Help me All right, and my question to these people, I don't know if anyone, you know Obviously a lot of these people are just lying.
Scott: It was kind of weird about this particular guys.
Scott: He didn't look like a homeless bum.
Scott: He looked like a normal guy.
Scott: Obviously had some sort of foreign accent, but he looked like a normal guy didn't look like a dirty homeless guy.
Scott: He wasn't carrying a bunch of crap.
Scott: He just had a sob story on an index card and he asked for money and I was like what the hell?
Scott: And I just walked away.
Scott: But all these people they have this sob story about having kids right and my question is obviously they're lying.
Scott: But if they're not lying, where are your kids?
Scott: Why are you they not with you?
Scott: Where did you leave them?
Scott: I should give money to someone who you know If you're really a widow with two kids and no money and your kids aren't with you right now Where did you leave them?
Scott: What you shouldn't be with someone who should give money to if you're not watching the kids that you supposedly care about so much.
Scott: Wow
Rym: Well, I got to say the scam that I've run into and this was funny way back Not a year ago a few months ago actually I was out by the laundromat and I was just standing around waiting and This guy walks up to me and he looks kind of scuzzy But not too scuzzy.
Rym: and he gives me this long sob story about he was driving a pick a tow truck to pick up a car Out here and something happened.
Rym: He couldn't find it and then his gas tank busted and he fixed it.
Rym: But now he's out of gas.
Rym: Can you have a couple bucks to get enough diesel to move his truck before the police have him towed because he's on a street?
Rym: Blah blah blah blah and I'm like man.
Rym: all I got is quarters for the laundromat to which he says quarters are fine.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Rym: It's not That's not the story.
Rym: I let him guy whatever I blew him off.
Rym: I did my laundry went home Not too long ago I was picking Emily up at the train station and I'm going back to my house and the Exact same dude comes up to me and tells me the exact same story.
Rym: Obviously doesn't recognize me because I'm not dressed all D shabby like I was last time
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and he tells me the exact same story like word-for-word And I just stared at him dumbfounded and just said I was polite, you know, no, I can't help you and I kept going.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: if a hobo came up to me if a homeless guy came up to me and he said hey, man Can I have a dollar to buy some alcohol?
Scott: I'd say here you go.
Rym: I had a guy do that to me once.
Scott: that guy's awesome.
Rym: I did give him some money.
Rym: Yeah Remember when we were in Rochester one day We were all wandering around downtown Rochester late at night just randomly and we ran into that beggar and we all gave him a bunch of money.
Scott: Well, he wasn't really a beggar He was.
Scott: it was like a guy and he we didn't know where we were going or anything and he kind of helped us out.
Rym: He told us where stuff was and he helped us not be lost Yep, and then we all gave him a bunch of money because he obviously was homeless.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He might not have been homeless.
Scott: I'm ready.
Scott: She might have just been poor.
Rym: Yeah Well, the thing is as we were leaving someone made the comments of he's just gonna buy liquor and there was a debate over now.
Rym: He's probably gonna buy food now.
Rym: He's gonna buy liquor maybe blah blah blah.
Rym: about an hour later as we're walking back to get our car in a big group we see him and his other scuzzy looking friend and they've got the Biggest bottle of the cheapest liquor I've ever seen.
Rym: he's like man.
Scott: Thanks for the money yeah, and we talked to him for like a few minutes and He tried.
Scott: he was he was willing to share his alcohol though.
Rym: So yeah, and he was so drunk though There is that little bit of of civility think.
Rym: I mean the fact that the guy Recognized us and knew that we had done him a good turn and offered us the fruits of our good turn back.
Rym: That's that's a very nice thing to do
Scott: yeah, and if you're gonna be a loser who walks around the street asking for money to get drunk and wash away your sorrows and Do that until you die someday in the distant future At least have the decency to say that's what you're doing And maybe I'll help you out if you come up to me with this lie.
Scott: I'll just be like wow you're a sad individual.
Scott: I'm gonna not help you out that way.
Rym: Maybe you'll die sooner an engine misery More quickly, but anyway my thing of the day this was the other night actually I was also at the train station to pick Emily up and as I'm talking to her on the phone Just cuz hey, I'm over here.
Rym: Oh, okay I see you.
Rym: this woman walks up to me and she starts talking to me.
Rym: I'm thinking first of all my bum sense goes off.
Rym: cuz whenever someone talks to me at a train station It's almost always a bum or a Jesus freak trying to convince me of something.
Scott: I haven't run into any Jesus freaks at the train station.
Rym: when I lived in the mountains up in poque Every time I was the train station in the morning to head into the city for something crazy old women Always different crazy old women would come up rambling about Jesus and give me pamphlets.
Rym: one time I told one of them I was an atheist and she totally freaked out, but that's a story for another time.
Scott: we should Get some pamphlets and go up to people with crazy red.
Scott: Have you considered Cthulhu?
Scott: Atheism.
Rym: but Cthulhu is 10,000 times better than that, especially if we do it with a straight face.
Scott: Have you considered we'd have we'd be all clean-cut with the snappy shirts?
Scott: That's not where the alligator goes would be like a Cthulhu head with some tentacles.
Rym: No, obviously the yellow sign that too.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So then I you know My bum sense goes off but I look.
Rym: and no this woman is actually well-dressed and she's obviously gonna ask me something.
Rym: and in somewhat Halting English the long story short is that she didn't speak much English, but she spoke French and Canadian French or France French I think North African French.
Rym: Ah Okay, she had an accent that I couldn't quite place at all and I've heard Canadian French.
Rym: Well Quebecois French.
Rym: I've heard French French different varieties and this was very different from all that but she spoke enough English and I know enough halting French That I was able to help her out.
Rym: I think basically she's fell asleep and got off at the wrong stop and had to go back.
Rym: So I was trying to show her where the taxis were and show her how to get back on the train to go back into Where she was trying to get and all that and that was very interesting.
Rym: I thought yeah, that's my best thing of the day.
Rym: That's all I can come up with without the internet.
Scott: The train that I take home goes from Grand Central to Beacon without stopping and there's a lot of places in between Grand Central and Beacon.
Scott: yeah, and People get on that train who don't belong on that train and they end up basically like they would have been home at 8 p.m.
Scott: Instead they're home at midnight.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Cool.
Rym: The thing is almost every train coming out of New York City going north stops in Harlem 125th Street.
Rym: It's like the alternate station in New York City.
Rym: There's a few trains that don't stop there and if you get on that train expecting it to stop there you're so boned Super boned, but the third I think the sixth train goes there also and the four well the four goes there I know.
Rym: yeah, pretty sure the six does too because I actually think the four or five six goes there.
Rym: The five doesn't go that far.
Rym: No, no, okay only the north of there only the four goes.
Rym: I know that.
Rym: Aha, well along the way I actually know the five.
Rym: Michael I don't know.
Scott: I know that the six goes all the way up into the Bronx because I'm on it and I can see where it goes.
Rym: The four does too because that goes all by where I work like Moshaloo and Woodlawn and all those places.
Rym: if the five goes up there It goes way off to the right where I never go.
Scott: I don't know enough that I gotta look at a map.
Rym: It's so rare that I take subways outside of Manhattan.
Scott: It's true.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Anyway tonight Since we don't have the internet We don't want to try to review anything since we can't pull up relevant information like who made the game what where is it?
Scott: What system was it for?
Rym: What's it called?
Rym: How do I play it?
Scott: What's this video game thing?
Rym: so I was thinking about One thing that has evolved very much throughout the years and also something that has affected me a great deal of the course of my video gaming days and that is Saving your progress, you know that.
Scott: actually I think it's a good topic because have not having saved games It's sort of like not having internet in a way.
Rym: Well, it's this so such a different paradigm of gaming.
Rym: It's almost like a different era of gaming before save games.
Scott: Well, let's start with the beginning of time when there were no saving at all.
Scott: It was just you played the game to play the game.
Rym: Yeah We'll skip arcade and go right to like the early NES days like Mario 1.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: cuz the arcade they had the high score saving which was something else.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think that's a different thing to talk about really.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think it's it's sort of like, you know, your high score is there forever.
Scott: It's like a machine most true Yeah But it's sort of like a save game.
Scott: in a way cuz it's like you know and you can record Your previous history or progress.
Rym: true But at the same time it's not like you can pick up where you left off and it's not like you can save you the state Of the game.
Rym: all you're basically saving is a record that you did at that time play that game with that level of ability.
Scott: Mmm, that's true.
Scott: But so actually there was a gauntlet game in the arcade like one of the later.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I remember that and you could save your game.
Rym: It was so lame.
Scott: and now they've got Arcade games that print out cars initial D.
Rym: Yeah at all.
Scott: Yeah, there are there other ones like that too and the neo geo.
Scott: you could cuz the neo geo is also a home system.
Scott: You could bring your neo geo memory cards plug them into the arcade and also plug them in at home and it would be the Same game.
Rym: so then yeah their early days.
Rym: There were just games that you played for the sake of the high score and/or beating them and you could save your high score.
Rym: And then there was kind of the the move especially with home systems toward games That had a beginning and an end a game that you could beat and that beating the game was the goal Usually more so than getting X number of points.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there was adventure for the Atari But you couldn't save that game and it was meant to pretty much be played all at once.
Rym: or Mario 1 You basically if you want to beat Mario 1 you had to sit down and play the whole thing through.
Rym: if you make a mistake That's the end of you.
Rym: if your mom calls you to dinner.
Rym: not beating Mario 1 tonight Didn't get enough lives in level 7 your bone in level 8.
Scott: Well actually weren't the super early PC games like some of the text adventures and stuff didn't those save Probably?
Scott: or like BBS games.
Scott: I assume those saved in some way.
Rym: I'm thinking we for the most part.
Rym: I'd narrow it down to consoles at least for this part.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's too broad mostly because I know of those games, but I'm gonna be honest I never really played the super early PC game so much I did.
Rym: I played a bunch of text adventures at school, but I never saved him.
Rym: I just beat him in one go.
Rym: there was nothing else to do at school.
Scott: like I didn't play muds until muds had reached the peak of mud technology I never played the Zork's.
Rym: I couldn't save Mad maze in prodigy online because my modem was only 2,400 bought and it wasn't fast enough.
Scott: Mad maze was great though.
Scott: I love mad.
Rym: I couldn't play it because I couldn't save my game.
Rym: I Was so slow I couldn't save.
Rym: so no matter how far I get I'd basically would have had to beat all of mad maze in One go which wasn't gonna happen obviously.
Scott: yeah I played it at a friend's house So I never really cared that.
Scott: I had to start from the beginning every time and actually got pretty far once.
Rym: it also took about Two minutes to load each screen.
Scott: see that's something there right we always talk about how we have a band and where to rescue old Games that have been lost.
Scott: mad maze is pretty much lost forever.
Scott: Yeah, there's no way to play that game.
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Rym: I mean people have got this BS Zelda working.
Rym: That's true, so Somewhere the code might exist.
Scott: hey BS Zelda people when you're done with that get working on mad maze from the original DOS Atari DOS DOS Atari DOS prodigy DOS Atari DOS.
Rym: that was a good game.
Scott: Yeah, DOS prodigy.
Rym: But I mean just think about how different games where you can save versus games where you can't are.
Rym: and not talking high score games They're just normal console games like Mario 3 versus Mario world.
Rym: I think that's the biggest.
Rym: they're.
Rym: they're effectively the same game Except for the ability to backtrack and save your progress.
Scott: Yeah, what ends up happening?
Scott: I think the most the major factor in having a game that saves is that if your game does not save The beginning parts of the game will be played very very frequently like the first world of Mario 3.
Scott: I've played that so many times, but world 5 or world 6. actually I've barely played world 6 in Mario 3.
Scott: I've played it Maybe 3 or 4 times in my life just because it most of the times when I played Mario 3.
Scott: I didn't get that far Yep, and or I would warp past it to world 7 or 8 or ghosts and goblins.
Rym: How many people in this world have actually seen any stage past the second one?
Scott: If you can save your game and you only play the game once through like say Final Fantasy 6 You see every part of the game pretty much once unless you die.
Scott: So you don't see the beginning of Final Fantasy 6 10 times.
Scott: in the end once you see every part Once and it's totally different now.
Rym: We talked about that a lot when we were talking about Mario world.
Rym: so to move on a little bit to something along the same lines it seems like the scope of Difficulty and the nature of the difficulty of a game is changed pretty much 180 degrees.
Rym: if you can save versus if you can't and Depending on the granularity or how often you can save or what cost there is to saving it changes even more.
Rym: Well, I guess you can't change more than 180 degrees without turning also to the right or to the left But we're going on Euclidean here.
Rym: So think of this.
Rym: Castlevania 2 Simon's Quest is a good example because I played through this game and beat it on the NES.
Rym: I also played through this game and beat it when I was living in the mountains on an emulator and the game was Entirely different.
Rym: it was so different that it was playing an entirely different game despite the fact that it was actually the exact same game Just with an added ability to save my progress at any point as opposed to you know Basically not being able to save aside from getting a password.
Scott: Well, I think using an emulator was a little different because you can also load at any time.
Scott: It's like if there's a hard bad guy, you'll save.
Scott: try to beat the bad guy.
Scott: if you die you load.
Rym: Yeah, that's what I was getting at.
Rym: But if you can save at any time, you can obviously load from any point at which you saved.
Scott: that's true.
Rym: I wasn't really a distinction there But my point was that playing Castlevania straight through is an incredibly difficult game.
Rym: And let's say you get to a difficult part and you try it and you die.
Rym: now You have to go through most of if not all of the game again to get to that point after you've lost all your lives.
Rym: So if a part is difficult, you don't get much time to practice it.
Rym: In fact, the most difficult parts of the game give you the least opportunity to try them and practice them.
Rym: So as a result, it becomes this monolithic insurmountable challenge like this mountain in the distance like in Hitler.
Rym: No, Fukatsu by the commando, you know that jump at the end is coming up.
Rym: You know, it's coming The whole game you're waiting for it.
Rym: You finally get there you jump you've got one shot you fuck it up.
Rym: It's over.
Rym: Yep Now you can save your game save my state every time there's a difficult part and instead of having the cost of Going back and playing through all the game again every time I fail there is no cost to failure.
Rym: I can play every individual issue every individual jump infinitely until I do it perfectly.
Scott: Well, I think what it does is it shows you that we used to think games were harder.
Scott: But maybe the tasks that the games required to you to accomplish weren't actually more difficult.
Scott: They just required you to do a whole bunch of stuff to get enough tries like they'll be a jump.
Scott: the jump itself isn't that hard, but it's a little bit hard and You're not gonna get that jump on the first try.
Scott: and if you have to redo a whole level just to get another try At the jump and if that level is maybe not the easiest walk in the park Just having to put in the time and the effort to go through that level Sort of you know wears on you and increases the difficulty of the jump when the jump on its own Isn't really so difficult.
Rym: Megaman did that to me a lot.
Rym: when you're playing through Megaman to get to the boss You know the robot master and along the way, you know, if you're not good I'm not good at Megaman games more damage you take.
Rym: make sure you can heal.
Rym: But you might get to the boss without all your health or in a non-optimal Configuration because you're not perfect at the rest of the level.
Rym: if you can't save your game You've got to deal with that.
Rym: So working on the being super good at the whole level becomes much more imperative.
Rym: Learning all the skills of avoiding each individual monster becomes a lot more critical.
Rym: Yeah, but you can save your state if you get through it.
Rym: once you save your state at the boss and just keep trying the.
Scott: Well, the thing is in Megaman if you die at a boss you reappear right before the boss.
Rym: Yeah, but even then yeah now you have to at least get through the level having one life left That's true.
Rym: or each life you have left is one more try against the boss, especially if it's a hard boss.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is you won't get back any of your weapons.
Scott: So if you need a certain weapon to beat the boss and you don't have enough of it left because you had to use it In the level then you could be in trouble because then you'll have to like you'll use the weapon on the boss.
Scott: He won't be dead.
Scott: You have to use the regular weapon or something.
Rym: It's like adding the ability to save and load to a game that didn't have.
Rym: it completely alters the risk/reward ratio Mm-hmm.
Rym: There is now zero risk in trying risky things.
Rym: so you're not as afraid.
Rym: you lose that sense of fear or that sense of if I don't survive this if I don't make it out of this cave and use this tent and save my game I'm not gonna have as tosses fucking crown.
Rym: I'm to go to that Marsh cave again.
Rym: Yeah, you know how many times that happened to me the moment in my life when I probably the most frustrating thing That's ever happened to me in my childhood playing Final Fantasy 1 I went in to the Marsh cave at far too low a level.
Rym: I killed those guys those wizard Whatever they were.
Rym: that because of the the mind flayer looking things.
Scott: I got the crown mean the mind flares.
Rym: I fought my way out.
Rym: I got to the exit.
Rym: I had a tent.
Rym: for whatever reason I walked a few steps before I used my tents.
Rym: I was attacked by six ghouls.
Rym: I only had two party members left alive.
Rym: They got first strike.
Rym: They paralyzed my two party members.
Rym: I sat there watching as they slowly killed the last two party members and I lost everything that I had done.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I was a little kid.
Rym: I almost cried.
Rym: Well, but at the same time you had such a fear of losing that progress that the game seems so much more intense.
Scott: Well, I think there's a big difference also between games, you know and what they're saving policy is You know I mean the saving policy of a game is huge and I used to think Why the hell don't they just make it so you can save whenever you want?
Scott: They're just assholes.
Scott: But really if you ask a lot of the game designers they chose their saving policy very carefully and very intentionally.
Scott: They could have made Final Fantasy save whenever you wanted for free.
Scott: They decided that you need to find a save spot or an inn or a town or a tent Because that's the way they wanted the game to be for they had reasons.
Rym: Yeah, and usually those reasons are pretty good.
Rym: I mean some games don't do it well but Final Fantasy games actually the distance between save points and the the level of frustration and fear you'd have and trying to get to a save point versus the ease of actually saving your game and not becoming too Frustrated was very well done at least in the Final Fantasies.
Rym: I played the good ones that I played Although seven actually did something really really clever with save spots that I'd never seen done before and it totally got me.
Rym: I don't even remember is this if this is not a spoiler because statute of limitations On this early thing in Final Fantasy 7 other than the fact that Eris dies.
Rym: Oh noes so Yuffie you run into her and When she pops up like she's standing there and like there's gonna be an encounter There's also a save spot in the corner of the screen.
Rym: so you think good I get to save my game before I deal with whatever this encounter is if you walk over there and try to save your game While the save screen is up.
Rym: It stays black for a little bit.
Rym: You hear a noise.
Rym: It comes back Yuffie's gone and you realize that she just stole all your money while you were busy saving your game.
Rym: Yeah, I was floored by that.
Scott: That's good stuff.
Rym: I was that was so great.
Rym: That's like if you put a secret in one of those save rooms or one of those rooms with the missiles in Metroid.
Scott: Yeah, and Metroid like, you know, there usually wouldn't be secrets in rooms that were saved spots, but I guess sometimes there were.
Rym: Yeah, of course also I've allowed a nostalgia just jumping back to remember.
Rym: I mean all you young kids.
Rym: there was a time when even if a game allowed you to save your progress You couldn't just save your game.
Rym: There wasn't any sort of battery or memory.
Rym: The game would give you a password that you had to write down and keep and then remember when you wanted to play that game Again, yeah, I mean the passwords weren't really saving your game.
Scott: it was just you know, there were only so many possible combinations of items you could have and only so many possible Places in the game where someone would tell you the password like in fact Xanadu.
Scott: You could only find out the password from talking to one of like these certain guys in towns.
Scott: So there are only so many places you could possibly get a password.
Scott: There are only so many combinations of items you could have and nothing else really mattered in the game Except what items you had and where you were.
Scott: So there are only so many possible passwords that you could have and the password was just you know Symbolic of what items you had and where you were.
Rym: well in fact Let's go to a little more detail on that because I think a lot of gamers especially people from our era might not realize Exactly what a password was.
Rym: Scott alluded to it.
Scott: I think people know what a password is.
Rym: No No I mean on a very basic level.
Rym: what a password did in those games was turn your brain or your piece of paper Into a very low capacity memory stick.
Rym: Yeah, the password was basically just the code that said how to configure the game for you.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I mean like if you opened up a game of Zelda 1 and you looked in the saves you know the stored the memory where the save game goes and you took that memory and you looked at it and say hexadecimal format, you know ABCDEF and 0 1 2 3 5 6 7 8 9 and You looked at it.
Scott: That would.
Scott: there would be a password wouldn't it?
Scott: if you just instead of having a save spot in the memory where that number would Be stored if you just asked, you know the player to type in the number then How is that any different?
Rym: granted some games had incredibly frustrating password mechanisms for some reason?
Rym: I often would mess up passwords.
Rym: in Metal Gear 1.
Rym: It's just the way it made.
Rym: you put him in.
Rym: I If I recall correctly, it's been a while.
Rym: I don't think you could backspace, huh?
Rym: So if you put if you made a typo it pretty much had to go through the whole process and try again.
Scott: Well, all the good passwords were games like Megaman games or Kid Icarus was pretty good and Metro it occurs and Metroid were okay.
Scott: But Megaman games in particular had the best passwords because there was a grid and all you had to do was put either In certain dots in the grid like the grid would be five by five So 25 possible dots.
Scott: you would put like a dotted a1 a dotted blue dot a red dot.
Scott: No, well that was Mega Man 3 and Mega Man 3. there are blue dots and red dots But a Mega Man want to know a trick.
Rym: a red dot was actually just a combination of two blue dots.
Rym: I figured out that system and I figured out where to put a combination of dots to give myself nine energy tanks Because there was no check summing in that Mega Man or at least minimal check summing.
Rym: See, that's the.
Rym: that's the reason why despite that the password just being a store of information for the game You couldn't just type gibberish and get something weird because a lot of those characters There'd be a check some where it would know if a password was valid.
Rym: Aha or at least it would have a good idea if a password was valid.
Rym: kid Icarus in some games You could totally mess up by putting in.
Rym: in fact kid Icarus and Metroid had weak check summing.
Rym: That's why there's so many passwords for kid Icarus that have words in them like Icarus fights Medusa angel or packing packing packing packing or all those other ones.
Rym: Because the check sum was so weak that you could very easily construct a password that you knew would pass the check sum.
Rym: Hmm and you just look for interesting words and then see what those words gave you.
Scott: yeah nowadays That we have actual save spots Unless you find some way to Like take that save game memory and modify it by loading it up on your computer and a hex editor Which was trivial in a lot of old PC games.
Scott: It was an old PC games, but not in modern console games Like.
Scott: I can't take my Wii memory card even though it's an SD card and I could load it up on the computer with a hex editor and try to edit it and Maybe increase my Wii Sports score or something, but that's pretty difficult, and it's it's probably not gonna happen.
Scott: But if the memory space is only so large I can actually afford to try all sorts of different stuff.
Scott: Figure out how to make my own save game, and I don't even need a computer to enter the save game because it's a password.
Scott: I just have to type it in with my gamepad.
Rym: Now also don't forget the games like Zelda that had the the battery save or you could just save your game.
Rym: That was a big deal.
Rym: when that came out in the US That was a huge deal.
Rym: like I was back then when games started you could just save the game.
Rym: I was a little bit dumbfounded by it.
Rym: It was such an amazing idea And I was so impressed by it.
Rym: Little did I know that the batteries if you don't keep playing the game and even sometimes just randomly only lasts about five years.
Scott: Pretty much everyone had their battery die, but if you open my Zelda 2 battery didn't die.
Scott: well If you open up the cartridge everyone you can look at the battery and it's a commonly available battery.
Scott: you can replace those things.
Scott: It's well known how to do.
Scott: the internet will tell you.
Scott: it won't tell us because we don't have internet But the internet knows how to replace those batteries.
Scott: It's not hard.
Scott: many people have done it you know and the only thing I think they could have done better is if the battery was easily removable instead of having to open the cartridge Which is a little bit tricky.
Rym: you know this just gave me a crazy idea Totally out of the blue.
Rym: I'm sure someone might have done it.
Rym: What if we just made an NES cartridge that had a USB coming out of the end and you could just send data to an NES In real time and play games that way?
Scott: it's called it.
Scott: It's called dev kit.
Rym: Yeah, well what if I could make one or get a hold of one?
Scott: you mean an emulator?
Rym: Yeah, but it's not cool unless I'm playing it on an actual Nintendo.
Rym: now a relatively Recent development in save games has come about that has really obviated.
Rym: one of the biggest problems in save game ideas Was that if you want to have a limited possibility of saving games for whatever gameplay reasons, and you're a game developer You have to balance that originally with letting someone save the game when their life is more important.
Rym: I mean how many times were you a kid and you were playing a game?
Rym: And then your mom says it's time to go eat dinner, and what are you gonna?
Rym: Do?
Rym: you can't just leave Mario pause?
Rym: sometimes the NES would crash if you left it pause for too long mm-hmm.
Rym: Or if it's a game like Final Fantasy you have to finish fighting the antlion and then get out of that cave Before you can save your game, and if your mom says you got to leave now Usually she just come over and unplug the SNES.
Scott: one other problem We've got is that we've got a lot of games that there is no saving no matter what because it's some real-time multiplayer game.
Scott: But there are also a lot of turn-based multiplayer games, and we can save them, but loading them is kind of tricky.
Scott: It's like whoa.
Scott: how do we load these things when there's multi multiple people playing possibly on different computers in different places?
Rym: Well the thing I'm going for is that this was solved so amazingly beautifully by the Instant suspend or instant save that has been or quick save that has been slowly being put in many many many games And the DS with its suspend mode does something similarly useful.
Rym: Castlevania is a good example of this.
Rym: the DS versions say you're playing and You have to save your game in a save spot.
Rym: You can't just save your game anywhere.
Rym: You have to get to a save spot to save your game But you can also do a quick save.
Rym: where a breath of fire 2 does this on the GBA - you can save the game in This weird quick save spot.
Rym: and the way it works is you save the game at any point any time you can save it But if you load that save game it gets deleted.
Rym: So you can't save your progress in the traditional sense of if I fail I could return to this point.
Rym: So the game the game developer loses nothing from his risk/reward ratio calculations.
Rym: He doesn't have to sacrifice the ability to make you sweat it But yet you can save the game if your house is on fire, and you got to deal with that business.
Scott: Mmm, yeah There are really two purposes to saving and that is if I'm going to stop playing and come back and continue playing later.
Scott: That's one reason to save a game.
Scott: the other reason to save a game is like you know aha I've just completed a difficult task.
Scott: click now.
Scott: I never have to complete that difficult task again.
Scott: It is accomplished and now I will march forth to the next task and I can always start from this point Where those previous tasks are completed.
Scott: yep and Separating those two I think is actually a really fantastic idea because when they weren't separated things really kind of sucks still.
Rym: Yeah, whiz I never beat Wizards and Warriors 3 because I couldn't save my game And I just it was too much hassle to play through that game.
Rym: Yep, plus the the furthest I ever got.
Rym: our parents made us go eat dinner So my brother and I took turns running over to the NES Unpausing it and pausing it and then at one time my brother ran out And then I hear him yell, and I run over and the game wouldn't unpause.
Rym: I was horrible.
Rym: That's a bad one but yeah This is the idea that you should be able to stop playing a game at any moment if your life is more important and by Allowing people to do it with something like a quick save.
Rym: There is absolutely zero cost to the developer in terms of his idea of how the game should work.
Rym: So you can't lose anything.
Rym: all you have.
Rym: just all you have to gain is everything.
Scott: Yeah It's like you still have to make it from point A to point B without dying or else the game will send you back to point A. However, you know if you don't want to do it all in one sitting if you want to do it in three or four sittings You know you go like half the way you quick save then you come back later.
Scott: You start from where you quick saved, but if you die you're going back to point A. You're not going back to this quick save spot.
Scott: You still have to accomplish the same goals take the same risks and achieve the same rewards and everything But you can go back to your life.
Scott: They separate those two things and a game is much more awesome now.
Rym: lately I'll finish with this I've been playing bionic commando a lot again kind of randomly and the fact that the GBA version that also has other games on it Doesn't add anything to the game at all.
Rym: You can't save.
Rym: there's no save stage.
Rym: There's nothing It's just an NES emulator.
Rym: The fact that it's that way and that I can't save my progress has in the end Greatly enhanced my enjoyment of bionic commando because by playing through the game in the old-school way I've gotten really really really good at that game now and I can play the end parts of the game with ease Where if I could have saved the game I probably would have gotten to the end once Difficultly early on saved it and then always just come back to my fully decked out game and just played the levels I liked occasionally.
Rym: I play the game more because I'm more restricted in how I play it.
Rym: It's kind of weird Huh?
Scott: Yeah, I do kind of noticed that like if I had a game of Mario 3 or more like Mario World.
Scott: Here we go.
Scott: Mario World, right?
Scott: Let's say I thought my goal is to beat Mario World 100%.
Scott: I'm still working on it, even though I haven't had a lot of time lately, but when I do it I'm gonna have this game that save a hundred percent Mario World.
Scott: So why would I play that game?
Scott: I can open it up and I can see.
Scott: aha Look at this hundred percent completed game and there's some levels that I like a lot like maybe the last level The world with Kuriboh shoe in it.
Scott: Yeah, the world of Kuriboh shoe.
Scott: in Mario 3 I would play that a bunch of times like in Super Mario all-stars.
Scott: You can save your Mario 3 game Yeah, and I may be on the GBA version of Mario 3.
Scott: You can also save it I'm not sure but I'm betting you can.
Scott: so I would go back and play these levels I like but I wouldn't go back and play hard annoying levels.
Scott: I wouldn't play the first level.
Scott: Like a lot of the game just would never get replayed ever Because I don't want to.
Rym: and it's almost one of those situations where filet mignon is great.
Rym: But if you eat it every day, it starts to lose its luster.
Rym: You start to get not sick of it necessarily because it's still great.
Rym: But if you have the choice of eating the same thing every day And it's really good or you have the choice of playing the five levels that you really really really like all the time You'll get sick of those and it's almost like by being forced to play all the levels which are also good.
Rym: You're forced to enjoy the game more than you would have if you just had the selective play.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean if there's a game you like, you know I mean, I'm sure there might be a game out there that has a bad part that you just don't like doing.
Scott: But for the most part like shooting Hitler's face-off in the end of bionic fucking commando Yeah, but I mean for the most part Yeah, most of you playing a video game most of the parts of the game are going to be fun in some way.
Scott: So if you are given the option to play any part of the game you want at any time You know because you've beaten the whole thing already You're just gonna play a few of the parts and not all of them.
Rym: So I guess it's kind of like with creativity in terms of sometimes your limitations can end up being your greatest assets and the limitations of a game.
Rym: Sometimes I mean not always.
Rym: we're not saying that all games should be this way But a game that's limited in those ways can often be a better game as a result of it Even if you don't see that right away.
Scott: Yeah, also, I like to I just realized you look at a game like Resident Evil 4 right or chrono trigger where all right You you can save the game and you can beat the game But you're never in a situation where you can just go to any part of the game you want and play only the parts you Want you.
Scott: when you beat it It starts you over from the beginning and like a plus better mode where you can have you can re-experience the whole game With your advanced skills perhaps on a higher difficulty level, but with you know your equipments from before.
Scott: So you can experience the same game again from beginning to end.
Scott: You know not just picking parts here and there like in a Mario world, but you can still save along the way But you still have to go through it and you're getting the same fun things that you had the first time as if it was A game where you couldn't save and you like buy on a commando where you had to play from the beginning every time or like The Zelda second quest.
Rym: All right, I guess we'll wrap this up.
Rym: It's still weird not having internet.
Rym: My teleprompter is still blank.
Rym: It's kind of creepy.
Rym: I can't just look at it.
Rym: I have the comfort of that glow.
Scott: Hopefully this will be fixed tomorrow.
Rym: Emily said she will not let the cable guy leave until the cable light comes on which I imagine might end with him tied up In the closet because I don't think they're gonna fix it.
Rym: I think this is gonna be this horrible ordeal.
Scott: I don't know what it's gonna be but I'm gonna do my damnedest to make sure it's repaired.
Rym: the internet will be back someday But suffice to say we've got to work around and GeekNights is gonna keep going up.
Rym: We're not gonna stop because of this.
Rym: so take that all you lazy podcasters.
Scott: Yeah, I don't see anyone else driving 10 minutes down the run not even 10 minutes down the road to upload their shows.
Rym: You can't upload 10 shows.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.