Scott: It's Tuesday, March 27th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight We talk about the amazing board game.
Scott: Amun Ray.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So of course over the weekend as we are often want to do the front row crew play Dungeons and Dragons.
Scott: Yep, we started a monthly game and I'm surprised that we're still keeping it up now.
Rym: Of course, the only problem with this is that as much as I love the front row crew I've basically determined Empirically mind you that our friends the front row crew as a whole are not in fact our friends the front row crew But are the Visigoths.
Scott: I don't know they might be some other type of goth or perhaps just plain old Huns.
Rym: now they're not Huns because the Huns just ravaged and the Ostrogoths had this whole other thing.
Rym: But the Visigoths would overrun Roman territory, right and they liked what the Romans had.
Rym: They wanted to use the Roman roads and the Roman aqueducts and the Roman government.
Scott: So I want to use Roman roads and aqueducts and government.
Rym: so they come in and they'd say alright We've conquered you ha ha and after a little bit of pillaging they'd settle down in the area Intermarry a little bit leave the social structure intact and while they would use the Roman roads and all that Roman infrastructure.
Rym: they wouldn't maintain it or take care of it and eventually it all collapsed.
Rym: so the front row crew comes in and To do a brief summary by the end of the weekend someone broke a glass and decided to not tell anyone.
Rym: I found it now fully intact yet shattered hidden behind a bunch of other glasses.
Rym: Someone ripped the handle out of the bathroom door.
Rym: it was kind of loose, but they ripped it like doubly out and bent it.
Rym: And during the weekend an unnamed individual just about set fire to a hot dog by trying to cook it on high on a Teflon pan on an electric oven.
Rym: ah No one did their dishes.
Rym: there's a giant mess in the kitchen.
Rym: I found bits of food hidden everywhere.
Scott: It was generally awesome At least- do people do this in their own homes?
Scott: I wonder because I mean I go to other people's houses You know and I might use a cup and then put it in the sink and not wash it.
Scott: I might I don't know Leave my stuff strewn about near my bag and then put it all back in my bag before I leave.
Scott: I might you know leave something somewhere and then put it back.
Scott: You know, but I don't break a glass and not tell anyone.
Scott: I don't break the handle on a door I don't set fire to hot dogs.
Rym: Well, I just remember.
Rym: because way back after the New Year's party we commented to a few people just kind of like not even like girl you people but Someone broke this and someone broke that and we kind of tallied off all the things that have been broken in our House over the course of the several days and it was funny how almost all of our friends immediately Would get all defensive like well, it wasn't me.
Rym: Well, it wasn't me and each one of them individually said it wasn't them.
Rym: and yet somehow collectively the damage was done.
Scott: Yeah, it's like we made it very clear that we were making a general comment and not singling anyone out.
Scott: yet Everyone was super defensive like I didn't do anything.
Scott: It wasn't me.
Scott: I'm cool and it's like hey, maybe you're all uncool.
Rym: I Wonder either either one or more of our friends I mean we're even back in colony.
Rym: when an unnamed individual broke all the eggs in the fridge I think and then put them back in the fridge That was particularly awesome.
Rym: Yes, at least no one peed on the floor this time.
Rym: Yes, so we're about halfway through cleaning up after D&D.
Rym: Maybe we should have it at the other geek house for once some one weekend.
Scott: Maybe we should.
Scott: of course they don't have room to play D&D.
Scott: Maybe we should rent a place out like a room somewhere.
Rym: Ah or a library or you just buy that house around the corner.
Rym: That's like twice as big as our house.
Rym: Of course None of that matters because as Scott is showing right now and I'm also showing we could wear shorts today because it was like 70 Degrees hot day.
Scott: I didn't actually wear shorts to work today because it wasn't that warm in the morning.
Scott: But when I got basically I was sweating all day.
Scott: I was sweating in the office.
Scott: I was sweating walking from the office to the subway.
Scott: I was sweating on the train home.
Scott: I was sweating walking Basically from the train to the house except for when I was driving in the car with the windows open.
Scott: So when I got home, I immediately put the shorts on.
Scott: The only time that pants were correct choice of clothing was on the way to the train in the morning.
Rym: See, I really can't wear pants or shorts to work.
Rym: I have to wear not even business casual business professional But I always bring shorts and a t-shirt whatever and sandals or something and I usually change in the drive home in that I Can wear a Metroid shirt to work?
Rym: Yeah, I can.
Rym: I got to wear collared shirts occasionally ties and sport jackets.
Scott: Speaking of work this new work that I have, you know, it's got okay people They're not the awesomest nerds in the world and we're geeking out all the time.
Scott: But you know, they're cool.
Scott: They're not bad And they actually give me work to do and they care if I do it and they talk to me about the work and that That's.
Scott: that's pretty cool because I've never actually had that before Surprisingly enough.
Scott: However, there is still one problem.
Scott: They gave me the work.
Scott: They said I said, all right, is there a due date for this?
Scott: and they said oh And eventually they're like, all right April 1st, when's April 1st?
Scott: Rym Sunday?
Scott: Uh, I believe so I finished the work today.
Scott: So I got three days of.
Rym: yeah Yeah I have the opposite problem where I could finish the work immediately except that I either have to wait for someone else to do something Or it involves paperwork that no one will explain to me or tell me what to what it is.
Scott: Yeah, at least so far all the works I've been doing have been sort of individual works but other people know about them so I can ask and get answers and they answer me because they're right there and They're not stupid and then I get the work done.
Rym: I should just be a freaking independent IT consultant.
Rym: I'd make a lot more money and I wouldn't have to rely on anyone.
Scott: Do whatever you want, man.
Scott: I'll be good where I am now for at least a year.
Scott: Maybe more?
Rym: maybe I don't know.
Rym: I think the 10-week mark.
Rym: every 10 weeks that goes by every one of us gets a little bit more Unsettled by our jobs.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: However, I was re-energized by the good weather.
Rym: Uh I feel great.
Rym: I'm wide awake like first time since I'm actually.
Scott: I'm actually thinking if I had managed to not quit the job I just had and Got through it until the spring then I probably would have not quit again until the winner when I felt shitty again.
Rym: It's like every winner I get all ahead and it's almost like I forget that there's a summer and then it's gonna come back.
Rym: Yeah, it's like during summer.
Rym: It's like wow these days could never end.
Rym: Let's pick up and move to the tropics, man You know, I would if it weren't for the fact that there aren't so many jobs for something like me at the tropics.
Scott: It's kind of weird.
Scott: It's like why did humans decide to build the great cities in places where the weather wasn't so great?
Scott: Built the New York City where Miami is the Miami where New York City is.
Rym: but no Remember it goes a lot further back in human history.
Rym: I mean historically the cultures that ended up Militarily dominating the rest of the world go over and over again tend to come from the colder climates where maybe life was tired.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: However, if they were any smart people that were came from the colder climates They would have gone to the warmer climate and conquered it and live there instead.
Rym: All right A lot of people did and those places ended up shitty for a lot of reasons because someone sucked along.
Rym: now part of it was Malaria.
Rym: a lot of those places had diseases that we didn't really have the technology to deal.
Scott: Well, we don't have the deal those diseases now.
Rym: Yes, we do.
Scott: We don't have to worry about them.
Rym: Yes, we do honey.
Scott: Only poor people have to worry about malaria, but there's a lot of poor people around there Are also.
Rym: malaria is not the only issue.
Rym: I mean Florida is great and all but there are a lot of fleas down there compared to up here.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: for one day conquer like a Caribbean island and build an awesome city on it.
Rym: Plus there are each there are in that city.
Scott: Not right next to Scott.
Rym: I put forth another idea that areas in the tropics tend to get hit by more severe weather than say New York City.
Scott: Well hurricane sometimes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah cities wouldn't do so.
Scott: Well there you just build a hurricane proof city a hurricane proof city.
Rym: Yep, right anyway in the news and this is about as Vague and possibly untrue of news as I would ever put forth as news.
Rym: and I bring it up more because I want to talk About if these things happen and why they should happen as opposed to oh my god they are happening, but the news is broken that both guitar hero and Katamari are supposedly coming out on the.
Scott: we also Knights into dreams.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That one is like the chances of these things being true.
Scott: It's like Knights into dreams.
Scott: It's already at 90% because there's like a cover of a UK magazine that's got Knights on the cover.
Scott: So that's probably true.
Scott: Guitar hero like 50 to 60 percent true.
Scott: Katamari maybe like 40 to 50 percent true I don't know.
Rym: I think Katamari has a big chance of coming over to the Wii.
Scott: Yes But I'm just talking about the right now.
Scott: how much faith you can put in believing it without looking like an idiot.
Rym: Well based on the evidence in terms of I see every reason why these companies should they all?
Rym: they should 100% and not even just for a oh to be nicer.
Rym: Oh for the fans, whatever.
Rym: but a lot of people who have PlayStation twos or You know more mainstream normal gamers or normal people out there seem to kind of assume that Everyone has a ps2 and everyone has these systems.
Rym: and as was illustrated in stark relief Over the weekend our friend Scott Johnson brought guitar heroes guitar heroes 2 and 2 guitars To our house and he pulls him out.
Rym: He's like look what I brought and we're like great hook up the ps2 and we'll go.
Rym: and he says I Didn't bring a ps2 and none of us had a ps2.
Scott: Yep, we might get one soon though because the slim ps2 is a lot slimmer than I thought it was.
Scott: Yeah, and I like we so far we've got a Mac Mini and a Wii under the TV.
Scott: So a slim ps2 is small enough that it can go next to those things.
Rym: Well, honestly, that's one reason why I don't want a ps3 because it's gigantic.
Scott: Yep It was only small.
Scott: things are going under the TV.
Scott: I found this amp.
Scott: it's gonna go and I finally, you know get back in financial straits.
Scott: It's actually bigger than any of the devices we have down there, but it's still really small.
Scott: But yeah, we're talking about the Wii.
Scott: I mean, it was just a story today that says that Nintendo might be holding back on the Wii's a little bit, you know, Ellie's GameStop seems to think so.
Scott: So who knows right?
Scott: but because they've met their projected, you know sales for Wiis In fact, they met it.
Rym: I'm very they met it early.
Rym: They already hit six million.
Rym: So anything they make beyond that is beyond expectations.
Scott: So anyone who wants a we now will just buy one when it comes out when the quarter changes.
Scott: So they might as well just hold those Wiis and then put those sales into the next quarters.
Scott: They can make sure they meet their projections then.
Rym: well also in terms of I mean people talk about not just the weed route But the game drought for the Wii.
Rym: it seems very simple that right now people are buying Wiis on the merit of basically Wii Sports and Twilight Princess?
Rym: Basically, yes, in fact mostly just Wii Sports Yeah and The while Nintendo if they were awesome would immediately start pumping out games that just made full use of the Wii.
Rym: or you know.
Rym: basically if they just listen to what we and probably Dave and Joel have to say about the Wii they just do that but financially sadly, they have no reason to because the Wii is making them as Goblins worth of money.
Scott: not only that that it's making them ask goblins worth of money.
Rym: I meant to say ask God I'm not sure why I said goblin but Too much D&D Cuz.
Rym: I killed that goblin.
Scott: Yeah, not only is it making them as goblins worth of money But they might actually not make as much money by releasing a shit ton of games.
Scott: because the Wii right now is not really a risk.
Scott: It's a profitable game console.
Scott: That's almost never happened ever and it's stupidly popular.
Scott: It's not a risk to make one more Wii and sell it.
Rym: It also helps the Nintendo unlike every other game company pretty much ever.
Rym: As always I had this philosophy that they will make a profit on anything.
Scott: if they can't make a profit on something They wouldn't even consider the idea making a game However, awesome that most people might think the game is, you know, even making another Mario game.
Scott: You got to think Super Mario Galaxy.
Scott: that's coming out, right?
Scott: That's actually a risk compared to the Wii.
Scott: So why would they make more games when their console is still going strong and selling like crazy?
Scott: It just doesn't make sense to start taking a risk when you're raking in the dough.
Rym: plus Nintendo has always done the thing of.
Rym: they Have like X games that pretty much everyone who has a Wii or a GameCube or whatever is going to buy and they spread Them out so that you never have to decide.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: Do I buy Twilight Princess or Metroid princess?
Scott: Yeah, I think what's gonna happen here is two things.
Scott: number one when the DS came out It was the same story.
Scott: there weren't games for a long time.
Scott: There's a few games at the start like Advance Wars and Mario whatever and then it was just drought.
Rym: Yeah, we both played our DS is non-stop for like a month and then I didn't really touch it for another five months.
Scott: Yeah, and now I look over there and I've got this.
Scott: I have a fistful of DS games.
Rym: I have a red solo cup that's just full of DS and GBA games that I play and I have like two GBA games.
Scott: So yeah, but I mean the DS is already like what two or three years old almost.
Scott: it's crazy, isn't it?
Rym: And the thing is the DS isn't even at its peak yet.
Rym: As far as I can see the DS is the steamroller of gaming.
Scott: So the same thing's gonna happen with the Wii.
Scott: right now It sucks because they're the games are not living up to the potential of the console.
Scott: There could be the greatest gaming experience in the universe on the Wii But there won't be for a few years because of business and we're losing out because of money.
Rym: Yeah Nintendo is smart because I get.
Rym: the moment the Wii curve starts to slack in and they have reason to They'll suddenly start ramping up the games.
Rym: Yeah cover it.
Rym: So they'll make constant money right up to the end of the life.
Scott: by this time next year There's gonna be plenty of awesome Wii games you'll I guarantee.
Scott: at least almost 10 awesome Wii games will be out by this time next year.
Scott: and Not only that but unlike some other Nintendo systems like the GameCube the Wii is actually selling crazily.
Scott: Therefore a lot of people will have Wiis in their house if a lot of people have Wiis in their house and not so many people have ps3s and You make you're a game developer or publisher.
Scott: You're pretty much gonna be forced to at least make your games for the Wii and the 360 especially like that non Grade a top tier franchises.
Rym: I mean top tier franchises.
Rym: They don't have to worry about that as much because they know the hardcore fans will do whatever they need to do to get the Game.
Rym: the game itself has this whole cache that comes with it But with lower quality lower tier third-party developers who maybe aren't well-known or games that aren't Some franchise that they know will sell you pretty much want to put it on the most popular system or as many systems as possible.
Scott: Yeah pretty much Because the Wii is actually selling compared to the GameCube.
Scott: you could ignore the GameCube because there weren't so many of them out there.
Scott: Publishers are not going to be able to ignore the Wii in the long run and no matter what.
Scott: even if people don't make games That take full advantage of what the Wii can do and live up to the full potential of the Wii They're still gonna make games and they're still gonna sell.
Scott: there's plenty of good DS games out there that don't take full advantage of The DS that are selling just fine.
Scott: I mean that puzzle quest is all the rage right now.
Scott: Yeah, and apparently though the PSP version I heard is better.
Rym: Yeah, uh, the PSP.
Rym: I still don't really worry about it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the PSP is still kind of crummy.
Scott: But lately it's actually because they've been concentrating on games It's getting a little bit.
Rym: Sony did say that they're shifting a lot of resources toward the PSP to bolster it.
Scott: Yeah, and it it's sort of working.
Scott: I'm looking at the PSP game shelf and I'm going huh?
Scott: There's a few games there that no one knew about because no one talks about the PSP.
Rym: Yeah, but if I owned a PSP, I would have bought those games in a second.
Scott: Oh instantly I would have bought the puzzle.
Rym: in fact if a Mega Man game over there if a PSP were a Reasonable price I would probably purchase it and then buy all those games.
Scott: Yeah, it's getting less crappy.
Rym: The problem is I don't know what a reasonable price is for me.
Rym: I don't know if I'd pay more than a hundred bucks for a PSP because the games are good But they're not that good.
Scott: Yeah, the PSP was a hundred bucks.
Scott: I'd buy it.
Scott: I'm sure they'll eventually one day maybe like a PSP revision 2 or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so I got some board game news here.
Scott: Well, it's not really all of its not news, but it might be news to me and it might be news to you.
Scott: some guy on board game news comm Did an interview with the Rio Grande guy?
Scott: I'm not sure what his name is.
Scott: Let's see It's.
Scott: uh, it doesn't matter.
Scott: He's the Rio Grande guy, you know the company that prints all the awesome games in English in America.
Rym: Yeah, so what is he this company spokesman the CFO the white?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He might be the head guy.
Scott: I didn't bother to read it.
Scott: What's important are the questions He asked him and most of the questions are about games that are coming out.
Scott: You ready for this?
Scott: I'm ready.
Scott: Most of these are re-released games you see and not Not new games.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So first of all lost cities.
Scott: Which is?
Scott: I played it lost cities like five times and it's a really good two-player card game.
Scott: It's just your deck of cards a two-player game.
Scott: There's some good strategy.
Scott: I don't know if it'd be fun infinity times, but it's a good game to own.
Scott: Well, there's gonna be a reprinting of it in Germany and they're changing like some art on it and the Rio Grande guy says yeah we're reprinting lost cities again - you know because they're reprinting it over there and I want to use the new art, but he doesn't like how the board and the cards aren't changed.
Scott: So it'd be like the old board and cards in a new box and he's like, oh that sucks.
Scott: So he's gonna try to get new board and cards to match the new box and reprint lost cities.
Scott: So if you think about lost cities, you should wait for the new reprinting.
Scott: also La cheetah or la sita or however, you want to say it is an awesome game.
Scott: I heard about but I was unable to buy and still am unable to buy because it's been out of print.
Scott: Well, they're gonna reprint it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm getting that one for sure.
Scott: There's pretty much as soon as that's available I'm gonna pre-order it and get it is it's an awesome game.
Scott: power grid.
Scott: That's a famous game.
Scott: They're gonna reprint.
Rym: Surprisingly one I've never played.
Rym: Yeah, I know all about it.
Scott: I know all about it.
Scott: I watched a video at board games with Scott where board gate where that Scott that's not me Sat with the designer of the game who looked like a cool German guy and they talked all about it And I said that's a game for me and I still never played it.
Scott: Cartagena which is a game I've always wanted to play where you escaped from prison because you're pirates and you're in a prison.
Scott: They asked the guy if he has a preference For Cartagena to Cartagena second edition or the original and the guy said he hasn't played enough of them to know which one he likes.
Rym: The that's the one.
Rym: we have to end up going down that long corridor and get on the boat at the dock.
Scott: Yes, that's that one.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I know which game that is.
Scott: I kind of want to play that game - someone said it was crap.
Rym: Did they?
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I looked at it.
Scott: I want to play it but without paying for it.
Rym: I don't remember who said it was crap, but I remember distinctly someone poo-pooing it a long time.
Scott: Well, if I ever see it at a convention, I'm playing it maybe a ConnectiCon or I'll definitely play it cuz I like the idea.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, here's the car gonna read this one at word for word.
Scott: any word on the Puerto Rico expansion?
Scott: Can you give us any hints about what will be expanding?
Scott: Andreas has given me no info yet.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: Oh Well, there's gonna be a Puerto Rico expansion, but we don't know anything about it.
Rym: I'm not sure how I feel about that.
Rym: Puerto Rico is still as far as I'm concerned and I state this with all of my vigor Probably the best designed board game in the world.
Rym: Yeah, probably I I mean a game at best could be the equal to Puerto Rico in my eyes And I say that after having played it hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of times.
Scott: Yeah That's about it for this fun little interview.
Scott: However, I do want to point out that the gathering of friends is going on soon or now or just now?
Scott: I don't I'm not quite sure.
Scott: but for anyone doesn't know the gathering of friends is this invite only gaming con that lasts a whole bunch of days and All the who's who's in the awesome world of you know?
Scott: designer gaming and such go there and you can play games that aren't out yet and all kinds of stuff and Like only a few hundred people go and it's crazy and I've seen pictures of it and like woo.
Scott: But we aren't invited.
Scott: maybe one day we will be invited but probably not for a long time because we're not really Big members of that community so much.
Scott: We just are in the hobby without being in the community.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people actually they ask us.
Rym: Oh, well, what's your name on board game geek or blah blah blah?
Rym: I have a name on board game geek, but I barely use it, you know, yeah and people like oh I'll buy those games from you But if I buy a game I'm keeping it forever.
Rym: There's only one game I've ever thought of possibly getting rid of and that's cuz it's crap.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta get rid of hell.
Rym: It's me Hell, this isn't that bad.
Rym: It's just the rules are ambiguous.
Scott: Hell is could be fixed, but it's it's not.
Rym: see we keep saying.
Rym: Oh, we'll fix it.
Scott: We got better things to do.
Scott: Yeah, maybe what our old man will fix hell is play it once you'll die And then I'll sell it and then I'll die Or I'll die and then they'll sell it at my estate sale Things of the day.
Rym: So I very rarely see a picture that's so perfectly characterized as everything that I would have to say about a given situation.
Rym: But this picture pretty much sums up everything I have to say.
Rym: it shows what you can get for the same amount of money and on one side of the picture is a PlayStation 3 and one bottle of cheap beer.
Rym: already on the left is an Xbox 360 and Several Cartons of beer more beer than any amount of humans could reasonably drink at a small party over several evenings.
Scott: a large amount and Both piles cost the same amount of money.
Rym: Yes, both files cost the same amount of money.
Scott: So you could either get a ps3 and one beer or an Xbox 360 and a whole shit Ton of beer for the same amount of money.
Rym: see I kind of expected them to use weed in the picture except for the fact They probably would have gotten in trouble Probably.
Scott: Oh, you could probably get like a big-ass Potato sack full of weed.
Scott: I don't know how much we'd cause But I assume you could get like a potato bag full.
Rym: Of course, I always wonder because they show beer and it looks like it's Foster's which is Australian for piss water as far as I can tell.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna have to try again with some real.
Rym: Well, let's see They could probably get two or three cans of one of those fancy hoity-toity beers Even though that recent study showed that in double-blind trials people can't tell if you add vinegar to beer or not Even if it's fancy beer, I guess they should.
Scott: maybe I don't know but Guinness or something is Guinness.
Scott: Oh, I don't drink beer at all.
Scott: It seems to me from what other people say that you know Guinness is one of those, you know It's a brand of beer that's everywhere, but it doesn't suck that much.
Rym: Well, I generally like either really really really really dark heavy beer like a beer That would be a meal like I could drink it and my would be full for the evening or I like red strife Mm-hmm.
Rym: I really like red stripe, but I wonder what the equivalent amount of Mad train would be to this amount of Foster's.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder those night shift podcast guys They always talk about Steel Reserve, which is like the cheapest beer in the universe.
Scott: I wonder how much of that you could.
Rym: Well, there's always the local beers from back at RIT That genny genny stuff.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, even though everyone actually drank lavat blue.
Scott: well that the Canadians drank the lavat blue and the Rochesterians drank the Genesee whatever.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's the Genesee.
Scott: It was made.
Scott: It's made in the area.
Scott: It's a local beer.
Rym: Yeah And also I'd like to point out to the person in the forums who thought that the chicken police was not a good thing.
Rym: One you can die on a fire and two that spider thing is ancient.
Rym: In fact, I buried it on dig for being old news.
Scott: Alright, so my thing today is a fun flash game.
Scott: It's fun.
Scott: Flash game will occupy exactly five minutes on your time.
Scott: What the fuck fungus festival?
Scott: No anyway, so, you know, I like to play a lot of flash games - you know Especially when I'm at work not working.
Scott: I need something to cure my boredom.
Rym: god damn it I don't know how you can be bored.
Rym: I would go read a book or go for a walk.
Scott: I can't just sit there reading a book is then someone will say why are you reading a book online?
Scott: I guess I could.
Rym: I did that often actually when I worked at IBM and I had downtime.
Scott: Anyway, this flash game is pretty cool.
Scott: It's actually on the Adult Swim website of all places Which I didn't realize had flash games.
Scott: Maybe you'll have to go there more often.
Scott: This flash game is called five minutes to kill parentheses.
Scott: yourself Parentheses.
Scott: What happens in this game is you basically have five buttons?
Scott: You can push up down left right in space and you start out as an office worker.
Scott: You pick which shirt you're gonna wear and which pants you can aware and the choices aren't Diapers.
Rym: so what the pink one or the white one for the shirt?
Scott: pretty much white or blue and what shade of brown?
Scott: And there are some that are off-limits because they're casual Friday only.
Scott: maybe if you played the game on Friday you can choose those I don't know.
Scott: and You start off sitting in your little cubicle and this guy says if I get one more meeting invite I'm gonna kill myself.
Scott: and he gets a meeting invite and he says that's it I'm killing myself.
Scott: and You walk around the office going up to various things Pushing the spacebar and then you when you go up to something to push the spacebar you will use it to kill yourself Or use it when whatever way it is used are there a lot of things?
Scott: There's a lot of things and you only have five minutes to do a hundred percent damage or else You don't kill yourself, and you don't die and you lose.
Rym: so the meetings.
Rym: in five minutes.
Rym: You're not dead you just go to the meeting.
Scott: I don't know, but you have five minutes to kill yourself.
Scott: That's how the game works.
Scott: so like you go up to the stapler you push space you take the stapler And you'll whack yourself with it a whole bunch of times and there's blood everywhere, and it says like three percent damage.
Scott: Staple something.
Rym: wow if I think about it if I had to kill myself in five minutes It wouldn't be easy.
Scott: without inflicting massive amounts of pain upon myself I would just get my car going really fast then get out of it and go under the wheels.
Rym: How are you going to do that?
Scott: What do you mean all right?
Rym: Drive my car into something really fast that might not kill you and you might.
Rym: you'll probably lay there for a while going.
Rym: ow Oh, it might take you more than five minutes to die But a potato in the exhaust and sit in the car that takes more than five minutes Damn it plus.
Rym: We don't have a garage.
Scott: You just sit there until you're right out of gas.
Scott: Maybe I'll just drink some gas.
Rym: You'd vomit and feel like crap and you probably wouldn't die at least not right away.
Scott: I'd had to go like stand a knife up on the ground and then jump out of the window and land on it.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: if you're gonna use a knife that would hurt why not just cut yourself open?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: it wouldn't be easy But pretty much it is a fun game because you're going around the office not only trying to do a hundred percent damage in five Minutes, but there's a lot of interesting things to do.
Scott: like there's an elevator that goes to different floors And there are combinations you can do like.
Scott: you can get the lighter and then the can of air and combine them to like burn Your face off and all sorts of interesting things.
Scott: you know and especially if you go to the second floor the first floor There's lots of weird humorous stuff, and it's it's sort of an exploration game in a way, but you only have five minutes.
Scott: You can't possibly explore everything in just one playthrough So you got to play it a few times if you want to see all the goods Does it?
Rym: I don't think it has my favorite method of suicide that a friend of ours always used to talk about.
Rym: which one where?
Rym: You walk into pretty much the most crowded part of a major city that you can with a soapbox And you put it down stand up on it.
Rym: There's a trigger at your foot that is connected to the squibs around your neck And then you shout everyone everyone.
Rym: could I have your attention?
Rym: get as big a crowd around you as possible And then yell tada and blow your head up.
Rym: Uh-huh, I really like that method.
Scott: Alrighty That's not a choice I don't think.
Scott: but many of the choices are humorous.
Scott: And it's also sort of humorous that like a lot of the ways you have of hurting yourself like Don't do nearly as much damage as they should.
Scott: Yeah, like he takes his face and puts it in a shredder, and it does like 3% damage even this blood everywhere.
Rym: It's like why if you really hard to get your face into a shredder.
Rym: I know I don't get it I couldn't even stick my finger in your shredder.
Scott: Yeah, I'd like if you go in the bathroom There's like a clown in the in the stall for some reason and if you go in there.
Scott: He'll beat the crap at him.
Scott: Like if you go to the second floor and try to go into this room like weasels will come out and bite you and You can put a pinata on your head and some guys will come and hit you with baseball bats.
Scott: It's it's a fun game.
Scott: It's worth playing.
Rym: pinata is good.
Scott: Yeah play this game.
Rym: so speaking of games.
Rym: You should play as opposed to I guess movies Where we're gonna talk about what I mean, it's definitely one of our top ten favorite games.
Rym: We play it often.
Rym: We really like it.
Rym: Rainer Canizia's Amun Ray.
Scott: Amun Ray is a game about pyramids.
Rym: Yes, now before we need you.
Rym: It's actually about bidding.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We didn't even realize that when we first got it.
Scott: No No, no, we didn't.
Rym: yes We've.
Rym: we've learned much from this game over time.
Rym: unlike some games you figure them out right away And then it's just a matter of who has the optimal strategy quickest or who can read the other person better.
Rym: Amun Ray was one of those evolving games where as we played it over time We started realizing different things about it and the dynamics kind of pushed the game in totally different directions.
Scott: It didn't help that for a long period of time.
Scott: We were playing the game slightly incorrectly, which completely changed it.
Rym: Yes And then we fixed that and then we were still playing it incorrectly and then we fixed it and then we were still playing Incorrectly due to some ambiguity.
Scott: They were small Ambiguities and incorrectness is but they existed and they did change the game significantly.
Rym: Yes However, even when we played it incorrectly it was.
Rym: it was such a good game that it still worked out.
Rym: it did Indeed worked out very well.
Scott: In fact, alright, so this is how this game works.
Scott: I'm on ray.
Scott: You've got this board full of provinces.
Scott: there's 16 provinces in ancient Egypt, right and You're gonna bid Money, you're gonna start with money and you're gonna get more money and you're gonna spend money a lot of it to get the province You want.
Scott: so in a four-player game or there'll be four provinces available and you're gonna get one and everyone's gonna get one and Then you build up the provinces and you do it two more times.
Scott: if you do it two more times in A four-player game then that's what for eight twelve provinces will end up getting bid but alright.
Rym: So everyone will get three provinces and you've built stuff on them.
Scott: Yes Here's the.
Rym: here's the one trick of the game the thing cuz.
Rym: you know every game that we like always has that Oh Mechanic like Tigers and Euphrates had the your lowest color is your score Mm-hmm, and this game's thing.
Rym: is that alright?
Rym: So then you score everything you've got.
Rym: Then the Nile floods and all the farmers die and everyone loses all the provinces.
Rym: But the pyramids everyone built remain and you play the whole game again Bidding on the same provinces.
Rym: only now there's a bunch of stuff already on.
Scott: well pyramid Yeah, so it's like if you build a whole bunch of pyramids somewhere in the first half of the game.
Scott: You might have to pay a lot of money and bid a lot of money to get those pyramids back under your control in The second half or else you might have just bought a whole lot of pyramids for a lot of money and someone else takes Them away for very little money in the second half,
Rym: but at the same time you might not care about that depending on your strategy.
Scott: Yep The other thing about this game is that there's this little meter.
Scott: it goes from one to four and in between every single round of play People sacrifice money to the gods.
Rym: Let's sacrifice them to our God.
Scott: And it's pretty fun to do this because you take an amount of money cards and you put them in your hand and you put Your hand out there And then once everyone's hand is out you turn your hand over and you reveal how much money you've got.
Rym: and it always goes like I'll go six and Scott will go negative three.
Scott: Ah Yeah, basically you can either sacrifice to the gods in which case you give them money and they make things better or or Jack the gods you can take money from the temple.
Scott: You can steal three money from the temple and then you don't.
Scott: they don't make anything better for you But you get money.
Rym: But unlike other games the gods are real and I'm on right and they'll in fact Depending on how much is sacrificed at the end They'll be more or less flooding which means farmers generate more or less money and traders may or may not be able to get to The province
Scott: and temples are worth more or less victory points and all sorts of stuff.
Rym: Now beyond that the other key things about this game or that you'll buy resources behind farmers and bricks to build pyramids and Power cards which are we'll get to all that little cards that do stuff.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is in every any given round you buy some amount of all three of these things But there's a little track that shows the effective diminishing returns of buying multiples.
Scott: Yep So on each turn you're gonna get a chance to buy power cards a chance to buy farmers and a chance to buy bricks.
Rym: and So bricks and pyramids are the same thing But if I buy one brick it cost one money.
Rym: if you buy two bricks it costs three three money.
Rym: if I buy three bricks It costs six four it costs ten and it just goes up from there.
Scott: Yep So to buy three bricks in one turn cost six dollars But to buy one brick each turn for three turns costs three dollars You see because you only have to pay more for buying more of one thing at one time.
Rym: Now this adds a very good mechanic to the game.
Rym: It prevents the common occurrence of someone just saves up a bunch of money and then blitzes somewhere because now The more you don't do in one turn the harder it is to do in any other turn.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Also, there are a lot of ways to just get stuff like, you know There'll be a province on the board and if you buy that province you get a free power card or there's a mechanic where?
Rym: Depending on how much money whoever gives the most money to the gods gets three extra goodies never gives the second most Gets two extra goodies that sort of thing.
Scott: So let's say I buy a place I bid to get a province that gives me a free power card And then on that same turn I buy two power cards, right?
Scott: So I got one power card and I bought two which cost three.
Scott: Normally, it would cost me six to buy three power cards in a turn But I paid three and got three power cards in a turn.
Scott: I saved three money.
Scott: Let's say I bought four power cards and I still got a free one, right?
Scott: Well buying four Costs ten and what?
Scott: buying five cost fifteen.
Scott: so getting one free one and buying four is like saving five dollars and by getting goodies beside in other ways besides buying them and Also buying them at the same time you can really get ahead in this game.
Rym: Now the other really interesting thing about this game and this is really the core before we talk more detail about the game is actually played By all appearances.
Rym: It looks like some kind of board game.
Rym: Maybe you'll call it a building game or a resource management game or diminishing returns game But in the end once you're smart and you realize what's going on.
Rym: This is primarily a bidding game.
Rym: It is a game where because in order to get properties you all bid on them and the mechanics of bidding are really really awesome.
Rym: but knowing exactly how much things are worth and how much you're willing to spend on them and how much you should spend and how much other people are spending is Critical and in fact probably the primary factor.
Rym: and who will or will not win this game?
Scott: Yeah, I mean nothing really matters.
Scott: I mean, it's not hard to figure out how much stuff to buy or how much money to spend.
Scott: It's also not that hard to figure out how much to sacrifice to the gods.
Scott: What matters the most is what provinces you end up bidding on and winning?
Scott: That is the number one thing determining whether you will win or lose.
Scott: Because for all the different stuff you can buy in this game There really aren't too many ways to get victory points and victory points are all that matters in winning.
Rym: Yep, the fact there are so few ways that you can have a turn where you can do a lot of stuff and yet None of those things will really generate you victory point.
Scott: you can eat direct fashion You can play this whole game from beginning to end and feel like you're doing really great.
Scott: You know, you buy a shit ton of farmers you buy bricks you buy power cards you keep doing stuff You're getting lots of money and spending lots of money and all sorts of stuffs happening But in the end you might only get like a handful of victory points and you'd be like how the hell did that happen?
Scott: Usually in most board games, you know If you're doing a lot of stuff.
Scott: You're getting a lot of victory points pretty much no matter what.
Scott: and settlers the more you do the more victory points you get.
Scott: That's how the game works.
Scott: This is the only game where the victory you can do a lot and feel like you're and not actually get a lot of victory Points or you cannot do so much and somehow get a bunch of points.
Scott: if you'd played smartly It's.
Scott: it's really tricky.
Rym: now the the actual bidding mechanism and I want to talk about this because I think it's neat.
Rym: There'll be X number of provinces out there and what you'll do is you'll draw one card Randomly for each player in the game.
Rym: So if there's four players, there'll be four random things out there.
Rym: So the game is different every time you play it and not just in terms of what comes up But in terms of what order it comes up which can matter a lot.
Scott: Yeah, cuz some of the plate like remember you play three rounds and then there's a flood and then you play three rounds.
Scott: Some provinces if they come up in the first of three rounds are awesome And if they come up at the third round they suck.
Rym: so but yet this is all mitigated and balanced Automatically by the fact that the players decide what provinces are worth by bidding on them.
Scott: Yep, so if you're gonna get stuck with the sucky province, you're probably not gonna pay anything for it.
Rym: You'll just get it for free unless you were a total failure when it comes to intrigue second-guessing and valuation Yeah valuation is key.
Scott: You pretty much have to not know what the provinces are worth to buy something stupidly.
Rym: But the way the bidding works to say I started first it's just a two-player.
Rym: Well blue three-player game me Scott and Joey Jojo Shabbat.
Scott: ooh, Joey Jojo Shabbat That's so.
Rym: we've got name.
Rym: I have a height.
Rym: So we got three provinces out.
Rym: each province have a little card on it and it has numbers on it with spaces for the chicklets.
Rym: Everyone gets a little chicklet with their color.
Rym: Yep, and it goes zero one three six ten fifteen 21 etc.
Scott: Yep 36 I think is nice.
Rym: and what you do is you bid how much you're going to bid by putting your chicklet on the amount Of money you were bidding.
Scott: All right, so there's provinces a B and C and I really want province a. so I start the bidding.
Scott: Cuz I'm.
Scott: I go first because I'm the governor slash Pharaoh.
Scott: I put my chicklet on the number three on province a. that means if no one out bids me and Decides they want to pay more than three for province a I pay three money and province a is mine.
Rym: So then now it's my turn.
Rym: I bid zero on another province because I really don't care.
Rym: I'm figure someone will outbid me whatever.
Rym: I'm up in the air.
Rym: Joey Jojo Decides he's gonna outbid Scott.
Rym: He bids six on Scott.
Scott: Yeah, he wants a more than I want it.
Scott: So he's gonna put his chicklet on number six.
Scott: So he's gonna have to pay six money to get a now.
Rym: So now we keep going around the circle.
Rym: it gets back to Scott.
Scott: I have to take my chicklet back because someone outbid me and I have to put it somewhere on another province.
Scott: I can't put it on the province.
Scott: I just took it away from.
Rym: aside from special cards, which aren't that common whenever you're outbid.
Rym: You have to move to another province, which is Incredibly critical.
Rym: you can plan intricate things.
Rym: Well, you'll bounce around or force other people to bounce around and raise the prices for everyone else And then get the last province for free in the end.
Scott: Yeah, it's really tricky.
Scott: cuz like, you know, if you want a province your instinct is just bid on it right away.
Scott: But if someone out bids you you might have to remove your chicklet move it to another province and then if no one outbids you Again, you won't have a chance to move it back.
Scott: So sometimes if you know that someone else really wants another province Maybe you'll bid on that one very low.
Scott: They'll outbid you and then you'll have a chance to move to the province you really want.
Rym: I really like the way this goes.
Rym: It's not like other bidding games where you can bid an arbitrary amount.
Scott: Yeah, everyone just keeps bidding until whoever wants to pay the most gets it.
Rym: I like how it forces a progression where each jump is a significant jump so you can't raise the bid by an insignificant amount which also prevents a lot of analysis paralysis because otherwise I Could account for all of my money and play very exactingly and bid Needly little exacting amounts and the game would take forever.
Scott: Yeah, I'd be like, I'll pay four for that real big.
Scott: I've hit five.
Scott: is it worth six?
Scott: Yeah, it's worth six and we just keep bidding back and forth.
Scott: so there's no bidding back and forth because you have to bid on something different when you get outbid and There's no thinking about one dollar differences because if I bid six your choices are to pay ten at least.
Scott: So it's not a very difficult decision.
Rym: so it comes down to where now when you bid any individual bid is a Momentous occasion and a big deal as opposed to a little deal.
Rym: bidding is like moving in a board game as opposed to just bidding.
Rym: That's why it almost doesn't feel like bidding.
Rym: Also the fact that it's handled in this very very elegant way with moving these chiclets around going clockwise around the players Really makes it smooth and I very much like it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So eventually Because no matter what it's eventually Everyone is gonna be bidding on only one province and there won't be any conflicts or out bids or anything.
Scott: Everyone will claim that province for themselves and pay the amount of money they have bid.
Rym: So if you've got five players, it's also good to note that this is one of those rare good five player games.
Rym: Yeah, it's pretty much good with three four or five But the fact that it allows five is a big deal.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And also that it allows five and yet doesn't suck with three or four.
Scott: It pretty much the game changes with different amounts of players But it's still great with different amounts of players sort of like Puerto Rico is.
Rym: So then for each time you get a province you just buy power cards, which are like the stiffy cards and settlers.
Rym: they're just cards that do things like bonus points.
Rym: if you have these provinces or Buy extra pyramid bricks for free or that sort of thing get a whole bunch of money.
Scott: Some of them are like, you know, they modify the way you bid.
Scott: They let you bid on the same thing Even if you just got outbid on it.
Scott: or you know There's a bid blockade where like.
Scott: if you remember how I said the bidding goes three six ten.
Scott: if I have the bid blockade Bidding card I could bid six use the blockade card and now you have to bid fifteen.
Scott: You can't bid ten because there's a blockade on the ten and I only have to pay six.
Rym: now then you buy farmers Which is fun because the way farmers work is.
Rym: you put these farmers on the board in the provinces depending on how many farmer slots Are available on any given province and then they generate income for you based on how much money was sacrificed to the gods.
Rym: which means the real fun of this game aside from the bidding is that in general the whole mechanic is that Some players will probably depending on what provinces they have have a vested interest in the gods being sacrificed to a great deal in Order to get more money from the massive numbers of farmers.
Rym: They have to get points from the pyramids Yeah, yet some players don't want the farmers to go up because they don't have any farmers They don't want anyone to make money from it.
Rym: and some players in fact have a vested interest in the floods being low and the Gods being stiffed because they have provinces.
Rym: they get more money if the gods aren't around.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So for example, let's say Rym has a province that has no farmers and all it has is eight money.
Scott: No matter what this province makes eight money.
Scott: There is such a province.
Scott: every turn that province will give eight money to Rym.
Scott: I have a province that has five farmer slots So obviously I'm gonna try to fill it up with five farmers.
Scott: now Let's say no one sacrifices anything to the gods and it they've gets stiffed a whole lot and we all just steal money from the temple.
Scott: I'm only gonna get one money for each of those farmers and rims gonna get eight money.
Scott: cuz he gets eight no matter what.
Scott: now Let's say we sacrifice a whole bunch to the gods I might get two three or even four dollars for each farmer at the end of that turn after we Sacrifice.
Scott: if I have got like five farmers that could be like $20.
Scott: That's a lot Yeah, so obviously if I have a lot of farmers I'm gonna sacrifice to the gods a lot and if Rym has no farmers He's gonna try to fuck the gods.
Rym: now that coupled with all the other things that are affected by sacrifice to the gods You'll sacrifice very precisely.
Rym: and it often comes to in fact the game.
Rym: We just played of this right before we did the show I would have won except that on three occasions the bidding ended up being exactly One off or if I had put the one more up to the gods everything would have been wonderful.
Rym: Yep, instead Alex won as he is often want to do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah And another in terms of the bidding and all this.
Rym: keep talking about how there's money in the game.
Rym: This game instead of using paper money or at something stupid just uses cards.
Rym: all the stuff in the game Other than the bits you put on the board are cards.
Rym: They're all the same size card.
Rym: You just have a hand your power cards your money everything all of the same back and they're just in your hand.
Rym: No one can see what you've got.
Rym: It's a very elegant system.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can have a fistful of cards.
Scott: No one knows how many power cards you got unless they were counting versus how much money you've got unless they were counting.
Scott: Because it looks like you just have a fistful of cards.
Scott: that way you can sacrifice to the gods.
Scott: People don't know what you're sacrificing.
Rym: one thing I used to do when we played that I haven't been doing for a while and I'm not winning nearly as much as I used to now that I don't is I used to keep track of within about five like kind of vaguely how much money everyone had By counting their income and then I would bid accordingly.
Scott: I just kind of have a general feel for how much money people have.
Scott: like.
Scott: they have a lot of money because they have a Lot of farmers and the gods drawn three, you know, and oh, he doesn't have so much money because you know He had to fuck the gods and everyone else bid way up and he doesn't have any farmers, you know.
Scott: And once I get that idea, I'll be like, okay, he bid three on that.
Scott: There's no way that he's gonna pay more for that other thing.
Scott: So I'll go over there.
Scott: and this he can't afford it, you know.
Rym: now in terms of production Quality, you know, you know, you know, you know, you know, you know, I Don't know how many times you said it.
Rym: just ten but good God.
Scott: I think you said it more times just now.
Rym: Anyway, the game is very high quality.
Rym: All the pieces are very well put together even though the bricks now that we've played this game a gajillion times Are starting to chip up.
Rym: I think just from use Chipping up.
Scott: They just got like these weird color changes on and there's something weird happening to the bricks.
Scott: But the pheromones are still awesome.
Scott: The farmers are awesome.
Scott: The cards are high quality.
Rym: that comes with nice cardboard bits that stand up.
Rym: So when you pass the Pharaoh around he's this big guy with a whip and that Egyptian thing standing there like oh the crook.
Scott: I think it's called a crook.
Rym: I don't know, you know that zebra Painted and the temple is very high quality and overall the production values of this game harken to the olden days where games were overproduced.
Scott: Yeah, I mean this thing comes like a sack of plastic pyramids and bricks.
Scott: What beats that?
Rym: not much Yeah, I mean Dracula didn't even come with a sack.
Scott: I know we had to go buy a sack for Dracula and it was a lot more money than Amun Ray is I think.
Rym: Yeah, of course, we got the cool flame sack.
Rym: So it's okay.
Scott: Yeah, the flame sack is essential for a game of Dracula.
Rym: But I mean in the end Amun Ray is a very very fun game and the only real problem I can see with it Is that for a beginner the first time player playing with experienced players?
Rym: They're pretty much gonna get almost no victory points lose horribly and feel bad.
Scott: Yeah, but you know we had the advantage of playing inexperienced against inexperienced and learning together and With that experience in this game It's actually pretty interesting because there's just so many like.
Scott: it doesn't seem like there's so many different ways of going about it But there really are a lot of different things you can do in this game And you know at first some of them might seem like good ideas and then things you never even thought of are the really good Ideas and you were just playing like an idiot.
Rym: for example the game We just played it ended up through various means that Scott and Alex both had a vested interest in their not being farmers and not being money around and not being good big sacrifices to the gods and I ended up needing a whole bunch of sacrifices to the gods.
Rym: So I was the odd man out and I got hurt by that.
Rym: pretty bad.
Rym: But in the four or five player game it'll often be two against two and one guy who will play whichever side will help him out or Two against three or one against one against three or all sorts of really fun combinations.
Rym: and while players generally don't Negotiate with each other very much There's very little meta play or deal making and there are no mechanics whatsoever in the game for that.
Rym: Even though there's no rule as far as I can see specifically prohibiting it the game ends up having a lot of implicit Apple orange prisoners dilemma defection going on it has.
Rym: a lot of people will end up helping each other Not because they wanted to help each other but because they both had similar goals.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like.
Scott: check this out.
Scott: Let's say you got three people right.
Scott: one guy has a problems with nothing No farmers.
Scott: one guy has a problems with three farmers and one guy's problems is six farmers.
Scott: Obviously the six farmer guy wants a bigger sacrifice.
Scott: Obviously the no farmer guy wants a lower sacrifice.
Scott: the guy with three farmers a good sacrifice might help him.
Scott: So if he sacrifices a lot to the gods, he'll get some free goodies and he'll also get a bunch of money.
Scott: But he's also helping out the guy with even more farmers to get him get even more money.
Scott: Now he also might want to if he screws the gods.
Scott: Maybe he's losing something.
Scott: He's not getting goodies He's not getting as much money as he could but he's sort of helping out the guy who was even less than him But he's also hurting the guy with more.
Scott: so, you know these in-between people who you know?
Scott: Maybe they have one province with a lot of farmers and one with not so many.
Scott: or you know They're not all one-sided in how much how much they're gonna sacrifice.
Scott: their decisions affect the game a great deal.
Rym: Also, it seems funny though Inexperienced players while they're not going to win they will often decide the game when playing among experienced players Just due to the fact that they will cause situations where other players can profit and the game then becomes to a great degree Mess with the newbie and everyone's taking turns trying to manipulate the newbie in order to making it to make them win?
Scott: Yeah, pretty much if I was playing against a noob and I thought they were stupid I would do the opposite of what they did because they would obviously do the best to help me doing the opposite of what they Did or I would try to.
Rym: I would try to position them to Say beat someone for most pyramids on one side, even though I know they're not gonna win from those five points.
Rym: Yeah, totally prevent Alex from winning.
Scott: But if they're smart, I would try to do the same thing they were doing because I know they're not gonna win.
Scott: But if I got a lot of farmers and they got a lot of farmers Maybe they'll be dumb and sacrifice a whole bunch of the gods way more than is intelligent and then that'll help me out a whole lot and I'll be able to save money and get the same effect because they did The sacrificing.
Scott: for me
Rym: this game's greatest strength I think is that despite the fact that the game setup and the way things come out is fairly random the game itself is very deterministic and To most importantly the game is self-regulating all the way through the bidding the diminishing returns Every factor in the game.
Rym: though what resources are on what provinces?
Rym: now everything's balanced the game Self-balances to the point that there is nothing that can really throw the game out of balance No matter how crazy everyone playing is except getting all the rules wrong that that'll do it and do it a little bit.
Rym: But even then the game was surprisingly still well balanced.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of crazy.
Rym: I mean it's unlike Puerto Rico where if you screw up Puerto Rico the game just breaks down immediately.
Scott: I think that this game really has going for is that you play most bidding games Like I don't know pizarro.
Rym: I like pizarro.
Scott: Yeah, but it's basically just bid on stuff.
Scott: You have money you bid on something you win stuff and then you know Whatever you win, whoever ends up getting the most stuff from bidding is the winner.
Rym: Yep Well this game one.
Rym: you're bidding against other people, but you're also bidding especially well in the second part of the game on things that have been modified.
Rym: so what you're bidding on is always changing and Some provinces are worth a lot early on or not worth a lot early on or they're worth a lot unless this other Provinces up for a bit at the same time.
Scott: and not only are you bidding but after you bid you with the same money you Bid with you're gonna have to buy stuff to actually build out what you bid on.
Scott: So even if you buy the best thing you still have to have enough money left over to get you know To squeeze the juice out of the fruit you just bought and then you have to have it up left to maybe Sacrifice to the gods if you want.
Scott: so it's like this three-stage thing that's repeated six times And the result it's a different game every time but it's still a deterministic game instead of being random.
Scott: It's just you know, it's sort of like having a random dungeon.
Rym: It's the exact opposite of raw.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much the opposite of raw which is another game.
Scott: that the only thing in common between that and I'm gonna raise the Egyptian Theme.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Rym: Yeah, I can't recommend this game highly enough And for the second night in a row, I'm going to bed.
Rym: Me too.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share a like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit.
Scott: don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.