Scott: It's Monday July 16th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight we give you our opinion on software piracy our.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, we're back from ConnectiCon and Surprisingly we can still talk.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's a little tired.
Rym: He's not actually sleeping.
Rym: you see one of the tricks in radio is that you can have sound effects But you can't see how we're making the sound effects.
Rym: So you see Scott's not actually asleep.
Rym: He's just sitting there going.
Rym: I guess that's more of a katsu snore, but you get the you get the drift.
Scott: I don't even snore.
Scott: so the sound of me sleeping is like this.
Rym: No, you make noises like why?
Rym: like?
Rym: Anyway As you might all remember last year at Otakon We only did one pet.
Rym: well two panels at Otakon and just from all the other yelling throughout the weekend We lost our voices to the point of I was coughing up blood and we both had to medicate ourself coughing up blood.
Rym: I cough up blood fairly often.
Scott: Yeah, you should go to a doctor about that.
Rym: No, it's it's a well-known.
Rym: It's just my throat and my sinuses and all that garbage.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, if I have come up coughing up blood I go to the hospital.
Scott: That's all I get.
Rym: No, I've coughed up blood as a kid and they said well your throat is irritated probably from talking too much and probably from a Post-nasal drip.
Scott: all of those factors combined suck time to get a new throat.
Rym: I'm working on that.
Rym: But I know we did seven panels at ConnectiCon and as you can hear I can still talk.
Scott: I can also still talk.
Scott: but that's cuz.
Scott: some of the panels did not involve much talking and Most of the con I was not yelling like Otakon where basically I'm constantly yelling the whole weekend.
Rym: Yeah, I think the answer is I don't account I'm gonna wear earplugs pretty much for the entire.
Scott: that really helped me out a lot at katsukan was wearing earplugs because if you Wear earplugs that reduce say all noise that you hear by 20 decibels or so.
Scott: You can still hear things.
Scott: I mean, I guess if a sound is under 20 decibels, you can't hear it.
Scott: but other than that, you can hear people talking to you enough and You don't you talk louder than what you hear.
Scott: So you're actually talking 20 decibels less, you know It's a psychological thing.
Scott: Like I will talk loud enough so that I think I could be heard over the noise I'm hearing.
Scott: so I'm hearing less noise I will talk less loud and thus save my voice.
Rym: but at the same time you wearing those headphones or those earplugs was actually pretty annoying because You pretty much didn't hear all the times when people called your name or needed you or talk to you And you just kind of sat there oblivious staring at things.
Rym: Awesome All right, yeah, so this might be a short episode partly because we've got both I don't and enough downstairs reading our comics.
Scott: It's gonna be short episodes all week.
Scott: people get used to it.
Rym: And Emily's making us some bagel pizzas.
Scott: This is the annual Calm down.
Rym: Yeah, you remember this week does not exist for us right now because we went to Connecticut last weekend And you mean yesterday and the day before yes, and this weekend starting Thursday morning.
Rym: We're driving to Otakon.
Scott: I only have to work two more days and then we're gone for ten day eleven days And then we're gonna be at the shore on our writers retreat until the Monday after that.
Rym: Yep, and These three days I'm at work in body But my mind is already on the shore.
Rym: not even Otakon.
Rym: it skips Otakon and goes.
Scott: my mind is in the ocean going whoosh And it's playing DDR also the best part.
Rym: There's supposed to be a Gigantic thunderstorm pretty much all through Otakon and Wildwood.
Rym: that's gonna end right about as we go to the shore.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: So that's gonna get rid of all the jellyfish.
Scott: It's also gonna get people wet at Otakon.
Scott: bring your umbrellas to Otakon people.
Rym: Yes umbrellas, especially if you're going to the gecky gop panel.
Scott: Yeah, you want to bring a tart poncho for that one.
Scott: yeah ponchos Oh.
Rym: and I do have to say I'm gonna mention this again on Wednesday, but Gerald doesn't have the high opinion of himself that I do apparently.
Rym: so I have to anti endorse what he's doing.
Rym: He's not doing anything special at the gecky gop panel.
Rym: In fact, he's planned 10 minutes of unfunny garbage for the end of our gecky gop panel.
Rym: Yeah, he's gonna sit there and be really lame apparently.
Scott: Okay Right.
Rym: So what he got in the news?
Scott: Apparently and this is this is New York Times here.
Rym: This isn't bullshit All right, and apparently because the New York Times is the paragon of unbiased journalism.
Scott: Yes Well, no some guys wrote a book and there these are guys from the Boston University School of Law.
Scott: So this is this is something right?
Scott: All right, the guys are named James Besson and Michael J Moirier, I guess M-E-U-R-E-R Moirier and The book they wrote was called do patents work question mark.
Scott: is the answer No, the answer is sometimes apparently in the pharmaceutical industry Right two-thirds of the revenues are attributable to patents.
Scott: So without Patents drug companies are gonna lose two-thirds of their money.
Rym: Take that whoever it was in our forum who was trying to argue some crazy conspiracy about the drug companies.
Scott: Yes however Apparently in every other industry Just about every other industry, especially the IT industry.
Rym: I wonder why?
Rym: because a patent takes X years to expire but technology is useless or needs to be built upon and improved by other People I don't know about six months after gets come up and especially the IT industry.
Scott: But also money of rest about every other industry.
Scott: it costs more to deal with patents than you earn from them all your patent lawyers and your patent workers and you're Spending money on filing the patents and dealing with them and licensing patents from other people Cost companies as a whole more money than they get from dealing with all that bullshit.
Rym: I could believe that because the one patent that I've got to my name that hasn't even been fully approved yet But it's still in the process and all that The amount of paperwork I had to deal with not even working at the company anymore Just to have my name on it.
Rym: It was kind of scary.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So what these guys say basically is that in many industries, especially IT Patents do not make economic sense.
Scott: However, their views are less radical than the guys at Washington University at st.
Scott: Louis The economists there who say the patent system should be abolished outright.
Scott: So they're not saying.
Scott: they're not saying get rid of patents.
Scott: They're saying wow patents are really fucked up.
Rym: What a rational and moderate opinion on the internet.
Scott: Oh, well, it's not on the Internet.
Scott: Oh, it's in a book of course by some professors.
Scott: Yes, so whenever you have to argue about patents with someone Or if you plan or argue about patents a lot get this book.
Scott: I'm actually gonna add this book to my wanted list on list all right now.
Rym: Yeah, so in other news I found this kind of interesting because I had no idea this was coming up and it frightens me that It's also the year of my birth, but apparently in July of 1982.
Rym: Hey, I wasn't alive then yet.
Scott: Yeah, no, I was more months.
Rym: I was already alive.
Rym: I had been for a while.
Rym: Oh, man, you should respect your elders.
Rym: No Anyway, the first computer virus was created at least the first known computer virus and all it did I didn't even know about what this virus was is if it saw you using a floppy disk it Copied itself to the floppy disk.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: and then I guess it would infect the computer and then try to infect any other floppy disks.
Scott: Did it do anything?
Rym: No, it was just annoying.
Scott: How is it annoying if it if it didn't do anything, you know how big that was compared to how little that floppy?
Scott: Ha ha excellent move.
Rym: Virus maker, I don't know but I must say that brought me back.
Rym: because viruses you see a lot of people say Oh a computer virus, but really there's a kind of specific nomenclature about viruses worms Trojans root kits all these different like kinds of malware now.
Rym: but back in the day they were basically just Trojans and Viruses.
Rym: and worms were like this mythical thing that everyone.
Scott: worms didn't happen until there was more networking.
Scott: You need networking to have.
Rym: worms didn't happen until Windows.
Scott: Well until Windows 95 and Internets then that oh and broadband Internet's not even with dial-up.
Scott: You didn't have worms yet, really Yeah, it wasn't until everyone had cable modems and everyone had Windows 98 or 2000 or XP.
Rym: But you see back in the day You couldn't.
Rym: the internet was a hundred percent safe.
Rym: Like you couldn't get a malware because there wasn't any.
Rym: there was no spyware out there.
Rym: There weren't any Trojans.
Rym: you didn't go to a website and they say download my thing, but it was actually a virus.
Rym: Viruses were usually things that hackers made that were funny and then they infected other people's computers with them.
Rym: I will note that I did this somewhat often because I actually had a virus collection.
Rym: Yeah I had a little box of floppy disk and each floppy had like the name of the virus and I had a little database of What they did and I thought they were really cool at the forum virus.
Rym: I had the ogre.
Scott: The ogre was bad news Back in the day when the original viruses are like the early viruses like Cookie Monster.
Scott: Yes, if you actually caught them for real like they actually infected you they would fuck you up.
Scott: They would.
Scott: the ochre virus destroyed your hard drive physically.
Rym: Well, what it did is it basically encrypted your hard drive bit by bit Also thrashing the drive as much as it could physically and that was it.
Rym: Yeah, there was no way out.
Scott: now You know everyone who makes these malwares is actually they're not trying to hurt you They're just trying to profit in some way with their spyware or their spam Zombies or something like that.
Scott: They want to take over your computer and use it for their own means of making money, which I can understand.
Scott: But I wonder like how come there aren't any viruses that fuck up your computer?
Scott: You think there'd be at least one guy riding a virus that would just format everyone's hard drive Of course at the same time with well at least on Linux that's really hard to do.
Rym: But yeah in Windows, it'd be really easy to do that.
Scott: I always wondered like remember What was that one that like you want to know why?
Rym: I think the easy answer is simply that Back when people were writing viruses just for the you know The hell of it there was no real financial incentive.
Rym: people wrote a virus to see if they could do it or to be a Shitcocker.
Scott: it wasn't for any other reason but there aren't.
Scott: you're saying there aren't shit cockers anymore.
Rym: No I'm saying that the shit cockers don't have the ability to ride modern viruses and anyone who has the ability to ride a virus Would much rather write spam software and make a pile of money.
Scott: Yeah I just really wish that one person would go out and write a big virus that will infect the world and format all the hard Drives that would actually know.
Rym: my idea for a virus like that is so much more sinister.
Rym: okay, I would make a worm or a virus that went around and infected everyone as subtly as possible and what it would do is look for any Excel spreadsheets access databases and anything
Scott: word documents and just
Rym: Randomly change a few numbers and a few words In all of them.
Rym: and that's it.
Scott: I would have it like slowly like degrade them over time.
Scott: So like at first it would change a word or a letter and then it would change some other things and eventually the whole thing would become a complete mess.
Scott: and it would like encrypt things.
Scott: and like if it saw a Word document being saved it would immediately like go and change like five words in the thing you just saved.
Scott: Yeah, or if it saw something being printed it would might.
Scott: it would put some spelling errors into it in between the software and the printer.
Scott: So you'd it would look right in your document, but when you printed it, it would get it would be wrong.
Rym: So I think part of it also was that a lot of kids back then who were into hacking and whatever would make Viruses to try to like bust up all their friends.
Rym: and then that's how it originated.
Rym: Yeah, and also most of the viruses.
Rym: while there were bad ones like the ogre Most of them were really benign or kind of funny like.
Rym: I actually got infected with a Virus way back in the day when I went to Starbase camp and I took a. someone gave me a copy of xcom mission UFO and on one of the discs was the form virus.
Rym: and you know the form virus.
Rym: did you know what it did to me?
Rym: And I didn't even know.
Rym: I had it for the longest time and I had the effects happen.
Rym: But I had no idea that such a thing as a virus existed.
Rym: on The 18th day of every month if you had a US keyboard, you know Like keyboard setting was set to us every time you hit a key.
Rym: The PC speaker would go click Huh?
Rym: Okay, that was it.
Rym: That was all it did.
Rym: I had it for years.
Rym: When I found out what it was I isolated I put it on a floppy and I kept it cuz.
Rym: I thought that was really cool.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty cool.
Rym: Then I remember I used to Saran wrap or dice up.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into this I'll do a show about it someday.
Rym: But I've uh, I used to make discs that were basically trojan horses to steal Documents from people and then infect them with backdoors so I could go steal the rest of the documents.
Rym: Haha, I only ever used him on my one friend in middle school.
Rym: Haha, and all I ever got were his homeworks.
Rym: Thing is he wasn't really that smart.
Rym: so it's not like I could steal his homework.
Scott: deleted his homeworks.
Rym: I wasn't.
Rym: I wasn't gonna be a griefer.
Rym: I was just I wanted to be a hacker.
Rym: hacking was cool.
Rym: I'd seen war games.
Rym: Oh, man, I really wanted to be a hacker, but I wasn't gonna decide.
Scott: I don't play tic-tac-toe.
Scott: What was your problem?
Rym: I wasn't good enough to really be a hacker.
Scott: They were good enough to win a tic-tac-toe.
Rym: I guess well depends on if I started Things of the day Things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, you want to go first?
Rym: Usually I go first.
Scott: Alright this thing of the day is sort of torn on because it's a really good idea and it is Successfully executed.
Scott: but it is a poor execution.
Scott: Basically what this is is the mashup of lolcats and dig not that those weren't mashed together already.
Rym: Kind of mash them more.
Scott: Yes, basically.
Scott: It's a website.
Scott: you are you go to the website and The website takes the dig headlines and for every dig headline it automatically generates a lolcat.
Scott: and it's sort of like it just takes all the headlines from the front page of dig and Makes a bunch of lolcats in the same order.
Scott: So you go to the website and there's a bunch of lolcats.
Scott: But that's a great idea.
Scott: That's like genius like super genius But it just chooses the cats at random and puts the text on there and the same font.
Rym: So it's just totally nonsensical and not in the good way that lolcats normally are but in this really kind of not funny way.
Scott: Yeah Because the thing about a lolcat right that you have to understand is that the words go with the expression of the cat for example Invisible invisible bicycle, right?
Rym: It's a cat and it kind of looks like he's riding an invisible bicycle.
Scott: or oh really the the it's not even a lolcat it's a lol owl, but it's Oh really an owl that looks like he's asking oh really so You know what?
Rym: I haven't seen him in a while and I just kind of cracked up because I suddenly remembered how awesome that owl is.
Scott: Yeah, is that owl actually dead or is it still a rumor?
Rym: I heard that the owl had died.
Rym: But then I heard that the hearing the owl had died was a rumor.
Rym: then I heard that it really died.
Rym: Then I heard that that was just a Damon Wayans.
Scott: So, I don't know I don't know but I'm gonna find an owl like that at some zoo or something and we'll look at it.
Scott: Just cuz I want to see one of those owls.
Scott: but like for example, here's a headline.
Scott: There's a headline on dig top 10 worst web app names and this is just a picture of a cat looking at you.
Rym: Now see what they would they should have had.
Rym: is that you're doing it wrong cat.
Rym: Mmm, that would have fit Yep.
Scott: So if there was some way that someone was like Manually choosing the cats from like a set of cats to go with the headlines This could be much funnier.
Rym: Maybe if we you someone did it manually for a while and you tagged cats based on categories and then you could have some sort of filter or Marginal AI that would look at the words in a headline and guess at the best lolcat based on an algorithm
Scott: Something like that, but as it is, it's a very great idea and it's it's ingenious But the humor of lolcats is lost.
Rym: So, uh riddle me this Scott Did you ever ever in your life up until today think that you would use the word genius and the word lolcat?
Rym: in the same sentence?
Scott: I Didn't think.
Scott: no I did not think in advance that you know I will never use those words in a sentence or that I will.
Scott: I Just didn't think about it at all.
Scott: It was not something that came to mind.
Scott: But if you told me in the if in the if five days ago you told me I was gonna do that I would say oh maybe That was.
Rym: I've never seen someone ruin a joke.
Rym: So thoroughly.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what I can say to that.
Scott: That's sort of like what this thing of the day is.
Scott: is that this great joke of lolcats is ruined.
Rym: now the big question Was that intentional or was that a save?
Scott: that was a save?
Rym: Oh, cuz you should have said it was intentional because then it would have been perfect.
Scott: No, it's intentional.
Scott: That means you planned it out.
Rym: Oh, we're so spontaneous and hip that we just kind of come up with things like that on the fly.
Rym: I see where you're going with this.
Scott: Yeah, I actually did just come up with a save, right?
Rym: So, uh in other news in my thing of the day all the ducks are swimming in the water.
Scott: Well, no some of the Ducks like fly around and some of them kind of walk around and those weren't ducks Those were other animals.
Rym: The Ducks were in the water right up until they start dancing.
Scott: What?
Rym: You've seen my thing of the day.
Rym: you can't pretend you haven't.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I know but I was gonna make some joke about duck Cut.
Rym: yeah, this is the week of me using things the day that other people have given me partly because oh, they're not on the day.
Rym: Did you do what?
Scott: did he do duty?
Rym: did it that's Hogan's Alley?
Rym: Oh, it's not.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it's not Good thing.
Rym: I didn't do that on a Tuesday where Dave and Joel would say something about that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right, so so Our dear friend I know who was downstairs right now watching Zazan Jotaro with an off and Emily If you haven't heard our show about that even you hate anime you should check that out.
Rym: Yes, yeah, really But but sex.
Rym: she told me about this video a long time ago, and I just never got around to rot watching it.
Rym: so now she's here.
Rym: she forced me to watch it and It's fairly awesome And I'd recommend that you not only watch this but watch many if not all of the related videos by the same person.
Scott: What is it like lemon jelly?
Rym: I think something like that.
Scott: It seemed I can't really tell what it is and I'm not gonna look it up because I'm lazy But it seems like it's a musical group and all their music videos are sort of Psychedelic animations of some sort which is cool.
Rym: I like those and I want to know from all of you when you watch the first one the one I'm actually linking to Who is that person?
Scott: isn't a?
Scott: Karl Marx be Santa Claus or see Alan Moore or D.
Rym: all of the above see from the wrong angle.
Rym: It could be Rasputin, too.
Scott: No, it can't be Rasputin.
Scott: Rasputin had a narrower longer darker beard.
Scott: Yeah, but it could have been.
Rym: He was shot stab poison whatever.
Rym: This is after the fact when he crawled out of the ladies all swollen.
Rym: See he didn't die.
Rym: He just crawled out of that lake and he became Karl Marx.
Scott: Yeah, you know that would explain a lot Right both of them actually lived at the same time.
Rym: So I think I'm just gonna point out at this point once again that it's been a long weekend And it's gonna be a long week If Rasputin and Karl Marx lived at the same time.
Rym: Oh anyway Anyway, it's so tonight Monday we were gonna cop out.
Rym: I didn't want to do a show cuz I'm tired and I got stuff to do with people over there downstairs right now Even though Scott seemed to question whether or not enough could actually use the man.
Scott: No, I just didn't think he knew the shortcut the keyboard shortcut.
Rym: Yeah, you're like hits face to make the movie go.
Scott: Okay, the beginning of Rasputin's life overlapped the end of Marx's life.
Rym: So therefore it is possible that with some trickery they could have been the same person.
Scott: They could have been.
Rym: anyway tonight We were gonna cop out and then we're gonna do a special but Scott agreed to take care of all the posting business on the website.
Scott: No, I didn't.
Scott: Yeah, you did.
Rym: very clearly I said we'll only do the full show if you'll do the post I have witness.
Scott: We're not doing a full show.
Scott: We're gonna do it short ready here Already.
Rym: a full show if we got things of the day and the news and a main bit It's a full show unless we stop right now.
Rym: It's a full show.
Rym: What if I just don't make the post then the show doesn't go off and you just wasted all this time.
Rym: So tonight we're talking about wares because it's come up in our forums a couple of times and it's come up in my life recently When I tried to wear something for the first time in many many years and I learned something about the wares industry.
Scott: Yeah, basically, uh, you know we talked about how our war is if you're a loser.
Scott: We talked about how we use Reza on for our podcast and we talked about how cool edit is the bomb.
Scott: and you know Someone said, you know Hey, I just wanted to let you know you can get cool edit pro from this torrent here, right and I was like, yeah Thanks That's great.
Scott: basically We have sort of a weird opinion of where is that?
Scott: I don't know how congruent it is with anyone else's But mostly because we are so open source granted.
Rym: I used to be real big into software power.
Scott: I used to not give two shits.
Scott: I used to feel about software piracy the way I felt about music.
Scott: I was like man, you can't be charged in this much for software.
Scott: people need the software to do stuff.
Scott: There's no there's no alternative.
Scott: I'm just gonna take it.
Scott: I don't give a crap.
Scott: It's so easy, you know, and I just copy my friends Wolfenstein disc and off we go.
Rym: Yeah, actually it's kind of funny.
Rym: the first wares I ever got Wolfenstein 3d we're a xcom mission UFO and tie fighter an x-wing and I think a couple other games and I Didn't even it didn't even dawn on me that it was in any way shady or illegal or anything.
Scott: Literally didn't realize it was illegal to copy the Wolfenstein 3d.
Rym: I've had this day camp like this.
Rym: It's like mini space camp at the Air National Guard base where I grew up and I'm there and I meet this really cool guy And he's all like computer.
Rym: hackery like he's on the BBS is a lot more than I am like.
Rym: he actually would die a long distance or he'd hop from BBS to BBS to do the long-distance call for free and I Pretty much just dialed like the two twenty four hundred BPS ones that were bought.
Rym: I guess that were in the area that I could actually connect to that.
Rym: My parents wouldn't yell at me for.
Rym: And uh, he says hey you ever play blah.
Rym: and I said what?
Rym: no.
Rym: and he says oh crap.
Rym: And he just gives me all these floppies.
Rym: He says just install these games.
Rym: One of them had a virus on it.
Rym: But other than that, haha I I didn't even think until.
Rym: like years later I went to a store and I saw games for sale for the computer and I was like, oh Oh When you put in the doom shareware and it said hey call this number Yeah, and I said, you know what?
Rym: I'm content with playing the shareware part.
Scott: Yeah me too.
Scott: And then I paid for doom - yeah I just borrowed my friends doom - Yeah, good days.
Scott: so back in the day when Open-source wasn't so awesome And I was mostly playing DOS games and using Windows 3.1 and you needed some sort of non free software to do just about anything I mean there was a day when you could buy Internet Explorer.
Scott: There was a day.
Scott: There was a day when you could buy Netscape navigator in a box for money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: and in those days when you know, even it was pretty much shareware or payware I didn't really have qualms about you know, pirating software because it was easy.
Scott: It was safe.
Scott: Everyone did it.
Scott: No one no one even knew it was wrong or bad or anything.
Scott: or they just didn't care or they just didn't Care, I mean it was just common.
Scott: Everyone would buy software and just install it on every computer of everyone They knew.
Rym: like for example, I've never in my life met a person who actually registered scorched earth Yeah, but I knew a lot of people who somehow had the registered version.
Rym: I wonder how or I think another one was.
Rym: there's the game called stunts 40 racing and had a bunch of different other names.
Rym: this game as far as I can tell was installed on almost every computer at every school in the Midwest and There's floppies of it everywhere.
Rym: It was a great racing game super 3d years.
Rym: Well 40 now and Every version of it I ever saw had a loading screen that said cracked by kill fit.
Rym: And then it is there and then every time I played it would pop up a screen saying like what's the fourth word on the Third page, but no matter what you type to let you play?
Rym: And I never.
Rym: I didn't really quite make the connect that kill fit didn't make that game.
Rym: Cracking was not writing.
Rym: software cracking was something far more sinister.
Rym: Yeah, I've never seen a legitimate copy of that game.
Scott: Wow Anyway, so in those days piracy was cool and then and I started doing the open-source stuff and Also other things started becoming free that you know weren't necessarily open-source.
Scott: web browsers are free You know, you can get a video playing software for free.
Scott: You can audio editing software for free Right, and it was all legally free.
Scott: and I was still pirating music and such.
Scott: but everything else was still pirate music Yeah, but everything else was becoming free Legally, so so I just it wasn't that I was still any any against software piracy You know or that I was for it.
Scott: It's just that the need to pirate software vanished and With it the caring about software piracy.
Rym: Yep I mean I used to really care about wares and I'd hang out on wares forums I'd look for new stuff and I'd upgrade my wares.
Rym: and actually I remember at RIT I pirated a lot of things just because The school had licenses for a lot of software that we needed to do our homework and our labs and or whatever in the labs All the way on the other side of the school and the labs there's plenty of space.
Rym: I just didn't want to walk over there in the cold But I could just pirate all the software and then I didn't have to walk over there and I could just do my homework in My dorm room.
Rym: so I had copies of like director 7 and flash 3 and fireworks 3 and all that.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is for me to do my homework in my dorm room actually required more free software more open-source software and Proprietary software didn't help me do my homework in my room at all.
Rym: So not that we did much homework.
Rym: That was a total cop-out job.
Rym: I played around with fireworks on my own a lot more than I ever did class work with it.
Rym: So I can't pretend.
Rym: Oh, it was for academic purposes only.
Scott: I mean a freshman year.
Scott: I pirated some games.
Scott: I mean technically actually my car.
Scott: I had a copy of half-life 1.
Scott: I got in high school from some kid who basically copied his CD and gave me his key For like 10 bucks.
Scott: I actually paid for it as opposed to buying you for 50 bucks.
Scott: See actually I was poor.
Rym: while I pirated a fair number of games when I was younger I other than like stunts and scorched earth and la checks and all those ancient ancient games for the company.
Rym: if I didn't even exist Anymore I actually did in the end buy legitimate copies of all of those games.
Scott: Yeah But then I had half-life 1 and I had this kids key basically and I played that and then I used that up until College and I got counter-strike and then when steam came along, right?
Scott: I because I had the legitimate half-life 1 it was automatically added to my steam and then I didn't need that half-life 1 or that Key anymore, so I just tossed it and now half-life 1 is permanently in my steam Even though I never actually Legitimately played for half-life 1. but I did pay for half-life 2 and a whole bunch of other games on steam.
Scott: So I I think I'm alright.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah See the thing is steam pretty much as much as a lot of people hate it.
Rym: It works pretty well now and more importantly it ended the idea of pirating games on computers at least those kinds of games.
Scott: Yeah I mean there's no need to pirate a game Because the whole idea of firing a game was I can get the game now I can get the game conveniently and I want to go to a store.
Scott: you don't have to deal with CDs I don't have to deal with keys and I don't have to pay money bullshit, right?
Rym: And you don't have to pay money and you have to pay money with steam.
Scott: All those problems are also solved except you still have to pay money but in many cases the money is trivial or the money is taken so easily that it doesn't bother?
Scott: you like for me to pay the 10 bucks to get like uplink and Darwinia?
Scott: it was like whatever click sure credit.
Scott: It was like getting Scott for free.
Rym: could it be that our perspective on the money in the software piracy is somewhat Formed or shaped by the fact that as we have gotten older.
Rym: We've had ever-increasing amounts of money at our disposal?
Scott: I think it has because let me get to my next example.
Rym: I remember when I like I tribes - I had to own it like there was no question.
Rym: That was.
Rym: that was the biggest fucking game when it came out and it was the biggest fucking game right up until they ruined it.
Rym: And I still look back upon the days.
Rym: I played that game as some of the best gaming I've ever had.
Scott: Yeah, but fifty five bucks was a lot of money and I didn't have became free and is now unplayable.
Rym: But even then I didn't have fifty five dollars.
Rym: I had to forego Necessary things to play that game.
Scott: I didn't but that's all right.
Rym: Well, I was a lot poorer than you were.
Scott: anyway to prove you right, actually nowadays, we don't need to pirate software because we use all this free software at happy times, but Recently, we have become very Productive.
Scott: we've been trying to make a lot of things and for most things we want to make we use free software.
Scott: I mean I could write programs in open source.
Scott: you know compilers and languages and Linux and I can use resound to make my podcast and upload it to my WordPress blog on my Linux hosting with my Apache web server and use feed burner, which is free and everything, you know Libsyn I pay for and the hosting I pay for but that's not software.
Scott: That's just a service.
Scott: But now we've actually said hey we kind of want to try to make some stuff with flash.
Scott: and well flash is According to the Adobe website.
Scott: when I checked this morning if I checked correctly $700 retail but I've got that copy of flash 3.
Rym: we could use that.
Scott: No, that's no good.
Rym: I've also got a action 2.1 and 3.0.
Scott: Yeah That's good.
Scott: So now I'm sort of torn here because it's like, you know for $700 that's like a shit ton of money right there even for that's like.
Scott: I could get a computer for that much money.
Rym: Well, the thing is that's more money than we paid for that fancy pants Marantz.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, here you go flash cs3 professional by us $6.99.
Scott: on the adobe.com product slash flash.
Scott: But then again upgrade from the previous version $1.99.
Rym: the way I look at that which previous version they won't accept flash?
Scott: It says upgrade from us $1.99.
Scott: Ah, yeah Oh download free trial.
Scott: Maybe I'll do that.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, I Forgot what I was gonna say.
Scott: Yes, but I think that part of our Willingness to pirate before was a need for software that we couldn't really afford in order to get what we needed done.
Scott: You know, it's like if you need to do something and there are tools to do it and you don't have those tools But you need to do that thing.
Scott: You need to get this job done.
Scott: You don't have a screwdriver.
Scott: You're gonna probably be willing to steal a screwdriver Especially when you don't have to physically steal a screwdriver and you can just copy someone else's screwdriver.
Scott: So then when you're able to get the tools for free legally You have no need to steal because you're getting everything you want done and you don't care.
Scott: so you don't even think about stealing.
Scott: But now when you want another job done and the only tool is a very expensive tool stealing comes back to mind and I'm not so sure if I think it's right or wrong to take it.
Rym: I think the real answer is going to be very simple and has nothing to do with ethics And I'm going to recount to all of you the story of when I went back into the wares world Kind of as an expedition when I made my new computer.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So back in the day wares was safe.
Rym: It was actually safe.
Rym: Never did a wares cause any problems and I would have known because I pay a lot of attention to the packets that come in And out of my computer some wares were unstable like you would get a wares and it wouldn't work.
Rym: quite right Yeah, but they were there were.
Rym: there was almost no malicious wares.
Rym: It was very difficult to find a piece of wares that had malware in it.
Scott: If I downloaded a free a game that was pirated in some RAR file and got the ISO burned it and installed it 99% chance that game was not a virus.
Rym: now I went on to the Pirate Bay and a bunch of other places that downloaded a whole bunch of torrents of like Audition even though I don't actually really like audition that much and I wouldn't have used it.
Scott: Audition only works if you have the fancy digital mixer and stuff to go with it to do the multitrack.
Rym: But I downloaded like eight or nine different programs from various wares sites and they were all cracked by different people in different like different groups and Every single one of them was chock-full of malware.
Rym: every single one compromised my windows box Horribly and like one of them.
Rym: I think the worst was I installed a copy of Audition.
Rym: this one was worse than all the others and I had my firewall and my ethereal everything ready to see what it tried to Do and it immediately tried to connect to like 2,000 different IP addresses.
Rym: Wow Like immediately it flooded our network.
Scott: See I wonder now is it companies like Adobe and stuff?
Scott: maybe they're the ones putting viruses wares out there to discourage people from pirating their own stuff?
Rym: No, because they have other software piracy prevention things.
Rym: I think it's very simple.
Rym: It's all.
Rym: it's all spam.
Rym: I think almost all of it are people paid to write software to infect computers Whatever way they can to become spam bots.
Scott: Hmm, and that benefits Adobe somehow.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much one of the Adobe and Microsoft and I guess, you know AutoCAD company with Autodesk or whatever It makes Studio Max and all such.
Scott: and then I remember Autodesk makes Maya.
Rym: Oh, I did have a pirated copy of Autodesk animator back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean there aren't too many companies left, you know Besides Adobe slash macromedia that are still selling the big expensive proprietary software to a lot of people.
Scott: It's pretty much Microsoft Adobe and who else makes Nero, but that's like 50 bucks That's that's worth it too, cuz it's good.
Scott: You can actually a Nero Linux for 20 bucks and it's awesome.
Rym: Well, there's things like the Lotus sweets and all the business II stuff, but no one uses the Lotus sweet.
Rym: Yes, they do.
Scott: Why?
Rym: Don't get me started.
Scott: Oh you worked at IBM, but where else?
Rym: Yeah, I could pull it up again.
Scott: It's Oracle is still selling it.
Rym: Actually Scott we had a list at IBM of all the companies that use it and it's a lot of big names.
Scott: Scary you sure it's not like.
Scott: they just have it on one computer so that they could be on the list I'm sure.
Scott: are you sure they don't?
Scott: they have a service contract?
Scott: They don't use I'm sure.
Rym: I'm sure I've also learned that a lot of law firms use a lot of really weird office suites.
Scott: Yes, they're actually, you know, there are lots of companies out there that do make proprietary expensive piratable software But it's not something anyone wants.
Scott: It's just something only businesses want.
Scott: so it doesn't get pirated very often and when it does you get caught cuz you're a business.
Rym: I Mean we talked about this in the first half of the show.
Rym: It just comes down to the fact that spam is the.
Rym: the fundamental problem of everything on the internet now comes down to spam As everything come down to spam.
Scott: I don't think so, but a lot of things.
Rym: well thing is spam comes down to insecure windows boxes.
Rym: Yeah, so that's the core of the internet right now.
Scott: It could be it could be I don't know.
Rym: I don't have any real point.
Rym: I'm just kind of talking to fill out this episode so I can go to bed.
Scott: Yes, I guess our stance on piracy.
Scott: Is that?
Scott: I guess it's kind of not okay.
Scott: but at the same time It sort of sucks that people need to be able to do things with their computers And the only way to do it is with an expensive piece of software that no one can afford And they don't have.
Scott: like his is there like Photoshop.
Scott: Photoshop is something a lot of people need to do things and there aren't really Alternatives that fit the bill.
Rym: Yeah, well you could use the gimp if you're a masochist.
Scott: and there there are cheaper versions of Photoshop but they're still really expensive and they're really hindered.
Scott: and Obviously, you know the people who are professional artists whatever they can afford and they need to afford and they will buy The full version of Photoshop and every upgrade for full price, right?
Scott: But by remarketing the product to those people which is I guess the correct market other people who need the same tool Right, but can't afford to pay aren't getting it at a price that they can afford.
Scott: it's like they had to pay the professional price or pirate and It seems like it the companies aren't doing enough to accommodate those people like sure sell your Microsoft Vista for $250 for every computer into a business, but let the home users pay 50 bucks.
Scott: All right, come on You're making already a zillion dollars.
Scott: You're not making it off the home users.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: But how do you set it up so that the businesses don't just buy the home user version?
Scott: Because what you do is you take you find those features Right that only the professionals are only the businesses use and that they desperately need But that the home users will never use.
Rym: but like why I take those features out like what like an audio program.
Rym: Everyone needs everything.
Scott: All right for Photoshop you could take out Cmyk right because home users don't need the CMYK.
Rym: I don't know a lot of hobbyists or what.
Rym: if you're trying to learn the software or you want to learn about that stuff You're in school and a much better way and What you could do is just you know you have the cheaper versions or the free versions even to get people to use your software, but Now maybe digital watermarking is one way.
Rym: but another way is simply a Contractual thing when you buy it and activate it stating that you cannot use it for commercial purposes.
Scott: But that's the thing.
Scott: is I wanna I kind of want to do semi commercial purposes?
Rym: Well, then you gotta pay.
Scott: but I'm not a big-time professional I'm just a small-time schmuck on YouTube and I want to make a little flash, you know I don't want to make a big fancy flash website for my mega corporation.
Rym: Yeah, but you know what?
Rym: To play the devil's advocate here the the company Adobe they made this program.
Rym: They put all this money into making it and it's their proprietary thing.
Rym: You can just choose not to use it but it is sort of a monopoly.
Scott: in a way like right now flash really has a monopoly as far as I'm concerned as far as multimedia Interactive web like highly multimedia highly interactive web content platform.
Scott: I mean Java isn't doing it.
Rym: But the other libertarian would say you can just make an alternative.
Scott: But no one can because it's it's even if you did make an alternative You can't get the plug-in on to all those computers.
Rym: Well, I guess in the marketplace of ideas your idea has failed.
Scott: Oh, no, because it is a monopoly a technological and economic monopoly.
Rym: Oh, so do we need someone to step in and break up the monopoly forcibly?
Rym: Is that fair to Adobe?
Scott: If it's a monopoly if it's a real monopoly is Adobe speaking.
Rym: Yeah is flash a real monopoly?
Scott: It's tough.
Scott: It's a monopoly of something very small.
Rym: All right, then what should be done about that?
Rym: Should an external force takes I'm not going to specifics here should an external force take some action to break that up?
Scott: Uh, I think that I would not have an objection if the government forced the flash file format to become open.
Scott: They shouldn't the flash application they can keep because that has you know stuff in it.
Scott: But the file format of SWF should be opened up so that anyone can go and make you know.
Rym: Just gave me an idea.
Rym: Yep in the physical world.
Rym: There is a concept called eminent domain Where the government can say this land for the public good will be appropriated We will pay the owner adjust market value price and this land will now be appropriated for the public use for the public good.
Rym: Kawai, I wish I think the government should have the ability now Of course, this has all of the power in the world to be abused.
Rym: Of course, I'm just talking about the idea of it the core.
Rym: what if the government could eminent domain intellectual property?
Scott: I think that would be awesome as long as of course as you said it wasn't abused which would immediately be horribly abused.
Rym: The thing is eminent domain has been abused But it's also been used for a lot of good and I think the good of eminent domain in America has outweighed the evil Fairly substantially.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Here's the problem though, right?
Scott: Let's say you start like we were just talking about how the patents benefit the pharmaceuticals a lot, right?
Scott: Well, it'd be hard to argue with someone who said eminent domain every drug they invent because it's for the good of the people Right.
Scott: No because the argument against that would be you put them out of business and then there wouldn't be any more new drugs for the good of the people.
Scott: So it would be a very tough balancing act figuring out when to eminent domain a drug and when to let it go.
Scott: Yep, you know which ones do the eminent domain which ones do we not, you know do of course obvious.
Scott: There's some obvious cases like there's an outbreak of a disease eminent domain the drug right away.
Scott: That's obvious, right?
Scott: But there are other cases where it's like, huh?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's a slight outbreak.
Scott: people are afraid of it like the bird flu, but it's not really an outbreak It's just something people are afraid of possibly irrationally.
Scott: Should we eminent domain?
Scott: that I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, well the thing is I have a lot to say about the drug issue in particular.
Scott: Yes I just happen to come up because you're just talking about it.
Scott: Software also like, you know, sure eminent domaining as shockwave file format would be good for the people.
Scott: So would eminent domaining the Microsoft Office file formats, but how good for the people?
Scott: Is it really you know, would it be worth basically destroying Adobe as a cause that would destroy Adobe as a company?
Rym: basically Yeah, but then again that also shows that the only I mean Adobe made a good thing.
Rym: But the only product Adobe has now well He's in the flash domain like in this whole flash macro media.
Rym: Whatever is that they have a secret thing and they keep it secret from you.
Rym: That way they can sell you things to manipulate their secret.
Scott: Well, actually the flash program is really good at animating and doing those sorts of things.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but it's the only reason it hasn't been duplicated is because you can't make the file format.
Scott: That's one thing about audio Photoshop Obviously, there's no secrets with the file formats there.
Scott: that just can't be duplicated easily because there's lots of algorithms that no one can Figure out but see like audio.
Rym: I think that's one of the reasons why there is a fairly robust set of open source audio tools.
Rym: Is that the algorithms are well-known math that have been implemented.
Scott: Yeah, you can go to the library and get a book that says here's the math type in this equation and you're good.
Rym: Hence, I use resound which is pretty awesome Yep, and honestly even if like even if I had audition because I've used audition and I don't like it and I really Would continue to use resound and audacity even if audition were given to me for free
Scott: Yeah, all I really want is flash and Photoshop.
Scott: just be you know, and I don't even really want flash and Photoshop.
Scott: I would much rather have something free that does the same thing, you know good enough for my purposes.
Scott: I don't need 90% of the stuff they've got in there.
Scott: I just need to be able to make as WFS so that I can do what I want.
Scott: And if an application does it well enough for me, that's well enough, right?
Rym: We've rambled for a bit.
Rym: Let's just stop here.
Rym: Okay, it's gonna be a long week to bed.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.