Scott: It's Wednesday January 31st.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discuss anime openers and closers.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So today we were gonna talk about one of our favorite animes.
Scott: well Maybe not in the super top, but it was a favorite anime.
Scott: Yeah But we got the DVD for Netflix so we could watch it again because we haven't seen it in many years.
Scott: And what do you know?
Scott: in the middle of the second episode this DVD was scratch.
Rym: Oh in the middle you mean exactly 45 seconds from the end.
Scott: Yeah, basically yeah.
Scott: So we had to send it back to Netflix and use the Netflix scratch DVD complaint form And I'm sure they will send us a non scratched one pretty soon, but until then We had to change our plans for tonight's show.
Rym: yep, so in the very least I'll tell you all this if you haven't seen dominion tank police I would highly recommend if you don't have anything better to do that you pick it up and watch it because We are going to review it in mostly glowing terms
Scott: Mostly it.
Scott: There's not much wrong with it really.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: I mean especially unless you're one of those people who just refuses to watch anything older than the year 2000.
Rym: well considering on For the era in which it came out.
Rym: I'd say it's a fairly stellar anime for what it's worth.
Scott: Yeah, let's just say it holds up today As well as it did back then and we'll leave the rest to the episode on it in the future.
Rym: So speaking of anime manga comics, what do we got in the news?
Scott: well three?
Scott: Conventions are now cancelled.
Scott: Let's check this out.
Scott: ready Gen Con.
Scott: so Cal which is a gaming con, but that's not the point.
Scott: It's a southern Cal that this gen con is a big gaming con and they have two conventions one in Indianapolis Which is the main one and they have another one in Southern California in Garden City.
Scott: Oh, no never mind not Garden City That's the second convention.
Scott: Anyway according to a letter from the CEO of Gen Con declining attendance and a lack of dealers room reservations caused the Convention to end.
Scott: but Gen Con indie will still happen.
Scott: that's so.
Scott: apparently gaming is less popular in so Cal.
Scott: That's kind of weird because I look in like the board game You know gaming community, and I see a lot of action in so Cal.
Scott: you know that board games to go podcast guy.
Scott: He's in so Cal and there's a lot of people on board game geek in so Cal?
Rym: Well, not just so Cal, but in the whole country.
Rym: I mean even when I was growing up there were a lot of gaming cons in Michigan all over the place and Even around here.
Rym: I mean uber con is always packed to the brim with people.
Scott: yep, so you think Southern, California Is a pretty big place for gaming relative?
Scott: you know maybe it's not as big as like some places in Texas like Austin or whatever, but it's huge and They can't support a gen con.
Scott: It's kind of weird.
Scott: Maybe it's just the gen cons are so big They need a lot more support, and they refuse to shrink it.
Rym: It might also have to do with how much more expensive convention space is out there.
Scott: that is true.
Scott: It is quite expensive to have a convention out there.
Rym: I mean we always forget that we live in the Northeast where there's a convention center in every major and a lot of minor cities But they're all relatively small which it means they're perfect for the kind of convention that you can reasonably pull off.
Rym: yep However, there still are enough big ones to have big cons.
Rym: there are indeed You know what I like the East Coast a lot like.
Scott: remember that convention center in Hartford that we that we went to for a ConnectiCon yep, I mean what if you had it you could fit.
Scott: if you had a big convention you could fit it in there.
Scott: Yeah, you definitely be Otakon big But it might be like the second biggest to Otakon.
Scott: if you filled up that whole place Katsucon would fit there Just fine.
Rym: Oh yeah, that might be a good idea too anyway except that Katsucon outside of DC is like I don't know a dog out of water with a bot.
Rym: There's really no metaphor.
Rym: I'm going with there, but Katsucon has to stay in DC.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Anyway, the second convention that canceled is the Garden City anime festival.
Rym: Oh, I never heard of that.
Rym: is it big?
Scott: I never heard of it either.
Rym: Huh, I wonder if that has anything to do with it folding.
Scott: apparently it's in st.
Scott: Charles Ontario, and it was canceled due to an unexplained conflict among the staff according to the CEO.
Scott: Well, this sounds like the typical case of political infighting bringing about everyone's doom.
Rym: yep I probably shouldn't mention any names, but I have been involved with or heard tell of or Staffed conventions that had similar problems.
Scott: Yes We see this problem all the time and we constantly warn people against it And we tell people how to avoid it.
Rym: god at the at the anime club summits We do at conventions.
Rym: probably the biggest advice we give aside from you know show this kind of anime Do.
Rym: this kind of thing is always don't let people control this club or dumb.
Rym: be smart Don't try to don't be idiot.
Rym: Just basically don't let politics get into it.
Rym: We warn people constantly that if you're not vigilant Idiots will take over any club and run it into the ground as fast as they possibly can.
Scott: yep, so you know we Constantly warn against it.
Scott: and here's an example of it yet again disappointing us because up We told you so and the third convention that decided to cancel is anime Express in Daytona Beach.
Scott: Well sex with us anime world order guys in Florida.
Scott: They're one less convention.
Scott: apparently Not quite sure because it's not very well worded But it sounds like the convention.
Scott: first of all there was a Christmas tornado.
Scott: I don't know if they're tall about a real tornado or not, but There's reconstruction from a tornado, which is causing them trouble, but also the Embry riddle aeronautical Aeronautical university's administration, so I guess I'm assuming that this is being held at the Embry riddle aeronautical university and some rooms there
Rym: ha
Scott: apparently several serious breaches of trust.
Scott: Er a you policy and the law itself were witnessed and documented by e ra you Safety over the past two years of the convention and that has unfortunately cast The AG anime club and a very bad light in.
Scott: e ra?
Scott: use eyes all right, so this is the classic case of people not What keeping control of the feet members of their convention and their club?
Rym: Basically it seems like claw.
Rym: anime clubs and anime conventions can go into two directions when they fail When they fail due to reasons beyond control you know like staff being stupid either There'll be some sort of split between two factions, and then one will try to spin off a con and thing will just collapse or This will happen now.
Rym: I said I wouldn't name names But this is just too close to what happened to me when I was a freshman at RIT.
Rym: I went to join the gaming club called our way the Rochester Wargamers Association and Guild and At the second meeting someone walked over to me and said hi.
Rym: What's your name?
Rym: And I said oh my name's Rym, and they said congratulations.
Rym: You're now the webmaster of Rudicon a gaming convention.
Rym: you are also a member of the board of directors, and I said who are you?
Rym: Wow, so I became.
Rym: that was the first convention.
Rym: I was ever staff on um.
Rym: To cut a long story short my first duty as a member of the board of directors Was to apologize to some of the vendors from the euro webmaster.
Scott: Why did you have to deal with vendors?
Rym: Well no like most small cons are run by a board of some kind and I was the head of the website Whatever group like.
Rym: I was the webmaster, but I was also just you know a staffer.
Rym: one of my first duties was to go with another staffer and Apologize to the previous year's vendors for the fact that the convention had effectively stolen money from them and Promising that it would not happen again.
Rym: mm-hmm I add to that about a thousand other problems ranging from Nobody could tell me the password to the hosting to no one could tell me who registered the domain name To no one could tell me when the convention was so I could set up the free registration.
Scott: Well, I think part of this unique situation I don't know if it's a unique Situation but is that you were actually trying to do the job that some random person came along and gave you in our typical Professional manner that we are known for while nobody else was.
Scott: therefore They were dumbfounded when they saw you actually trying to work, and they continued to not work.
Scott: in fact They counteracted your overworking by working less.
Rym: well you see I was excited about it at first because I had never that was before I'd Even been to an anime convention that I just.
Rym: that was the moment when I thought you know what I'd love to be staff of All this business.
Rym: I want to be a big shot.
Rym: This will be fun.
Rym: I'm gonna work hard and show these people I'm cool and confident and maybe someday.
Rym: I'll be the con chair.
Rym: well I quit being the webmaster after a few months and The con I guess happened.
Scott: I think it didn't happen.
Scott: then it happened the next time.
Rym: all I know is that that convention very shortly thereafter Folded completely for almost the exact same reasons that this convention has failed.
Scott: I say both of the reasons.
Scott: so except for the reason oh yeah all three reasons that con Didn't have enough people is it just like Gen Con?
Scott: it had infighting among the staff Just like Garden City anime, and there was bad stuff going on Just like the Express yep, well it was all three one.
Rym: I guess we should ask People who live in Florida if they've heard of the AG anime club, but um your anime club You know your anime club the club where you get together and watch Japanese cartoons and talk about them and possibly yell at the screen to make National news.
Scott: it's not really nationally.
Rym: It's national news in terms of the anime world.
Scott: It's not national news.
Rym: It's on the internet on a semi to make the anime news network.
Rym: It's national news.
Rym: It's anime Whatever of anime fans who care even more than a little bit as opposed to a naruto fan.
Rym: Yeah, it's out there for your anime club to be called out for being terrible and incompetent.
Scott: All I can say is if you have a bunch of people getting together to enjoy anime those people probably shouldn't be breaking the law Or making a safety nuisance.
Scott: This is you know.
Scott: this is why places like Otakon have all these rules like no signs no giant sticks No guns, etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: No don't end up like that.
Scott: That's why you should do what Otakon says and not complain about it because if you complain about it That means you agree with the AG anime club.
Scott: That's bad.
Rym: Wow I mean I've met some bad anime clubs in my day, but this really takes the cake.
Rym: unless there's something We really don't know about that happened, but somehow yeah the details I imagine would be very humorous and also very sad.
Rym: if anyone knows if any of our listeners know about the AG anime club or this convention.
Scott: If you know more details about the closings of any of these three conventions tell us because we will be entertained.
Scott: yes We don't really care about like spreading secrets.
Scott: You know we don't even know these people.
Scott: We don't really care.
Scott: Oh, we just want to be entertained by stories of people fucking up royal.
Rym: if we wanted to spread secrets about anime cards We could anyway, so what's your news?
Rym: Well, I'm sure you're all aware of free comic book day If you're not.
Rym: very simply it is a day once a year sponsored by the comic industry where if you go to any Semi reputable comic book store.
Rym: They will give you a pile of free comic books.
Scott: Yep, it depends on the store.
Scott: How many free comic books?
Scott: in which ones you will get?
Scott: but basically the idea is that since no one reads comics anymore?
Scott: They try to bribe people into liking comics by once a year giving away a few comics for free To try to convince you or to get you hooked.
Scott: well this year It's on Saturday like a drug dealer giving you the first cocaine for free.
Rym: It's on Saturday.
Scott: It's really weak.
Rym: Saturday May 5th 2007. now you might remember that last year we went to the comic book shop near us to get our free comics.
Scott: well a Terrible comic shop.
Rym: yeah, it's also the comic shop.
Scott: Well Dragon's Den is a comic shop.
Rym: Dragon's Den is a lot further away.
Scott: It was a lot further away, but it's also 10,000 times nicer than the place We ended up going to.
Rym: not the greatest election though No, not the greatest, but anyway We go to this comic should I can.
Rym: a good selection outside of the city and basically it was a scary fat nerd And his scary fat nerd staffer guy, and it was nothing, but like so ten-year-old kids Silver Age comics piled up Everywhere like under tables and then whatever new comics were out piled up everywhere.
Rym: I don't think they sold anything, but straight up comic books.
Scott: It was dank and Vile.
Rym: It smelled bad.
Scott: This is a bad place.
Rym: And we walked in and you know we ask hey can we have our free comic books?
Rym: and the guy seemed really kind of pissed Off that we wanted our free comic books, but yet we weren't buying any comics.
Scott: Oh, he handed us free comic books cuz it's free comic book day, and we left without buying anything.
Scott: It's just shady-ass store.
Rym: I mean they didn't even have manga other than there was a little bit of lone wolf and cub like in the bottom corner And it was way overpriced.
Scott: yep Like over.
Rym: the Suggested price was his price, and it was more.
Scott: that doesn't mean you shouldn't participate in free comic book.
Scott: No, why would you ever turn down free comics?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: I mean, I'll admit that last year.
Rym: I liked maybe ten percent of the free comics, but The free comics that I didn't episode about him didn't we?
Scott: we did.
Scott: we should continue that trend.
Rym: I think we will all right, but yeah I don't see anything particularly of note.
Rym: a gemstone is putting out a Walt Disney Mickey Mouse whoo.
Rym: There's gonna be a new Battlestar Galactica flip book.
Scott: I don't really care about that.
Rym: what?
Rym: what's wrong with you?
Scott: You can have that.
Rym: Archie comics is putting out Archie comics great and Apparently Antarctic is putting out something called pirates versus ninjas number one, which I'm buying that it's gonna be here We can.
Rym: oh I hate to say it But as much as I love pirates as much as I love ninjas and as much as I love anything that combines the two It's a bad comic.
Scott: I know one you.
Rym: I don't think you can make a good comic about that.
Scott: I got a comic recently cowboys vs.
Scott: Aliens.
Scott: It was so Generic and just cliche there was nothing to it.
Scott: It's like I could have made this comic.
Scott: Well, maybe not the art, but every other part of it was just yeah, it's exactly what it says on the cover It's not.
Scott: it's so shallow.
Rym: Oh good.
Scott: I imagine pirates vs.
Scott: Ninjas to be equally shallow.
Rym: That's what wild card is putting out.
Scott: What are they putting out Gumby?
Scott: Oh sweet?
Scott: Yeah?
Scott: Gumby and Gumby and owly are the most exciting comics they are.
Scott: that says something good and something bad.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't even mention owly because owly and corgi is.
Rym: We're gonna buy that anyway.
Rym: It doesn't matter if it's a free comic book.
Rym: owly is great.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, if you don't like owly you're not a human being.
Scott: of course owly is for nursery school kids.
Scott: Yeah, you know what but it's biggest fans are like college people.
Scott: It's like imagine if like all of a sudden c-spot run was all the rage in the college crowd.
Rym: You know I wonder if we could manufacture those dr.
Scott: Seuss books, man They're hot among the 40 year olds.
Rym: I'll bet we could put together some sort of meme viral marketing that would make that happen perhaps?
Scott: oh Man, you know what you want.
Scott: that just reminds me.
Scott: You know what other kids book.
Scott: I liked remember those mr.. Men like mr.
Scott: Happy mr.. Sad mr.. Grumpy.
Scott: no no you don't remember those books never even heard.
Scott: Oh, those are so great.
Scott: Oh, man, those are the most fun books in your little kid.
Rym: all right anyway things of the day Now if you haven't seen this movie called a 40 year old virgin.
Rym: It's worth seeing once.
Rym: It's pretty funny.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I walked into it.
Scott: You know I didn't watch it on purpose.
Scott: It's just other people decided to watch.
Scott: well I came in with and I just went along with it the lowest of expectations.
Scott: I went in with expectations so low I expected to turn it off in 10 minutes and go do something else.
Rym: well aside from the fact that the movie was actually pretty Good, okay, it had this one Ongoing gay where two guys playing a video game, and they eventually have a conversation along the lines of you know how I know You're gay.
Rym: You know how.
Scott: I know you're gay, and it's you know.
Scott: I know you're gay.
Rym: It's very good days like shit.
Rym: It's definitely two friends Ragging on each other in a very semi non-offensive, but slightly offensive yet funny.
Scott: nonetheless way yep And after we watch this movie anytime someone said something that could possibly be a homosexual innuendo like hi My name's Scott Reuben.
Scott: Yeah, everyone else would be like hey You know how I know you're gay.
Rym: in fact that is the joke behind the.
Rym: you know how we know Rym and Scott are gay Thread in the forums.
Rym: Thank you very much.
Rym: one of the most popular threads that god damn it god damn it anyway.
Rym: So someone decided to do something clever and reinvigorate this joke by taking various clips of Batman and Superman hanging out and Putting the audio from those scenes over this.
Scott: so Batman is like hey Superman Okay, and Superman fly around wearing your underwear on the outside.
Scott: It's really good It's really and you don't use your x-ray vision to look in the girls locker room often enough.
Rym: now Especially if you haven't seen that movie this my.
Rym: I don't know if this will be more funny or less funny.
Rym: I imagine it'll be more funny because you won't know the jokes that are coming up.
Scott: Hey Batman You know how you're gay.
Scott: one word bat to see.
Scott: Anyway, yeah Okay, so my thing of the day has a lot of links so anyone who goes to the show notes to click on this.
Scott: I'm gonna make a lot of links there for you because they're not just doing it.
Scott: I mean one thing.
Scott: my thing of the day is anime dance now not anime dance in general but specifically Dances created by anime.
Scott: now the earliest instance of this that I know of because I only know of Three instances and then the fourth instance is a music video.
Scott: It doesn't really count.
Rym: Well, we can't really talk about things that were before our time.
Scott: Anyway, right because we don't know.
Scott: however There are three.
Scott: there is a trend among certain anime shows to in the usually in the closer But also sometimes in the opener to have the characters of the show perform some sort of choreographed dance and then have a good song going with it and it gets it catches on and then People in Japan will just do this dance in the street everywhere and people dancing in the street Will create popularity for the show etc.
Scott: Now the first instance of this which is a show called Koto cha or was it child's toy?
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yep, and they think the second opener had a dance called the ultra relax.
Scott: Now you can go on the internet.
Scott: You could find a video of the second opener and you'll go.
Rym: oh that We actually we know this dance.
Rym: We used to do it a lot at anime music nights when that song would come up.
Scott: It's quite a fun dance.
Scott: now you will also note that there are videos of the guy next people doing this dance.
Scott: Yes in the street There are videos of random Japanese people doing this dance in the street and someone made a funny music video that combines the opener with Evangelion characters.
Scott: that is quite high quality.
Scott: Now that was the first time and you'll go.
Scott: that's the anime show that has a funny dance.
Scott: Well, that was true until mohoromatic came out.
Rym: Yeah, mohoromatic is not the best show.
Scott: No, it's really not.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about mohoromatic, but at the end there's the mohoromatic mambo And we didn't know and we showed the show in club and we saw this dance in the closing credits and we all looked At each other.
Rym: god damn it.
Rym: Now.
Rym: We got to learn this thing.
Scott: Yep I mean, we didn't really like mohoromatic.
Scott: In fact, I only ever saw One episode of it.
Scott: I read spoilers But the at the end of the show, there's a catchy song and the characters do a dance.
Scott: So what can you do?
Rym: the dance is actually pretty easy except there's this step in thing that it's real easy to just fall over.
Rym: Yeah, I fell over twice trying to learn.
Scott: you got to practice it a few times now.
Scott: after the mohoromatic came out some guy Who's pretty awesome made perhaps that one of the best anime music videos ever the mambo leo Which is a song that has nothing to do with anime.
Scott: You see me inside outside You hold me so tight, we'll dance and party all night, mambo mambo get ready, so kiss me in the moonlight.
Scott: You know it always feels right, we'll dance and party all night, mambo mambo get ready.
Scott: And it's a various music video with lots of different anime in it.
Rym: Yeah, the credits to the video are almost as long as the video itself listing every anime.
Rym: they pulled stuff from it to this day.
Rym: I can't find the actual frames where some of the anime they talk about are in this music video.
Scott: I know the Trigun one is the saxophone.
Scott: yeah anyway There's no real dance in it because it's just a whole bunch of clips of anime characters Moving in ways that may be interpreted as dance but fast fast forward backward to back rewind.
Rym: when we were at RIT anime and for various reasons para para was really popular back then and We decided to have some sort of you know choreographed thing.
Rym: that'll be our club thing and the president at the time Luke decided to put this together and he Choreographed kind of based on some other things.
Rym: There's a lot of influences to it this dance to the song and all of us on the executive board including the ultra relax Yeah, and we learned it, and then we performed it for club to the song at an anime music night or something.
Scott: We also did it in front of club while the video played.
Rym: well the club Fucking loved it first.
Rym: They just ate it up and whenever there was a dance party ever We would play that song about 3/4 the way through like there'd be that like the secret.
Rym: did it?
Scott: Well because the song starts at this clapping right so you can sort of if you start playing the song Everyone who knows the dance can start clapping and walking towards the area where they will perform the dance.
Rym: So we get to the point where every year there'd be you know ten people at the front of the dance hall Doing this choreographed skit dance while the rest of the crowd is just screaming.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: This is crazy.
Rym: What are they doing?
Rym: I don't understand.
Scott: yep now There is a new popular anime called the melancholy of Haruhi, Suzumiya And I did not watch it yet, but I know it is popular and some people say it is good.
Scott: I cannot comment.
Scott: I have not watched it.
Scott: however Unbeknownst to me until recently the closer of this show has a dance perhaps the most Complicated anime dance yet, and we may spend an entire day this weekend learning it as is our duty.
Rym: yes I mean we.
Rym: if you don't know us very well Or maybe you just found us from all these podcast directories or people that talk about us We like attention We like to dance - yeah, we like music and dance music.
Rym: So when we go to anime con especially back in the day before we did this Podcasting business or even back at RIT when we had anime dance nights Not only would we dance to anime music and techno and whatever But we always like to do some sort of thing that would put us at the center of attention.
Rym: Oh, no Rym and Scott trying to be the center of attention you say hmm.
Rym: Well.
Scott: Maybe that's why they podcast so much.
Rym: We really have no choice.
Scott: But to learn this dance and at some you mean learn you mean completely master and memorize every single step in this dance.
Rym: Maybe we should put a video up of us doing the mambalayo dance.
Rym: cuz we've got that thing down.
Rym: I could do it in my sleep.
Scott: I forget it's coming back to me now, but I don't remember all that.
Scott: yeah Cross cross yep, I remember most of it, but not you know what.
Rym: if there's enough interest We'll make a video at some point and put it on the website so all of our listeners can learn it.
Scott: Yeah But anyway go look at my thing of the day And you will see videos of all the anime dances in there you know and Animated and live-action and mixed-up forms.
Rym: so here's your mission GeekNights listeners if you can learn this dance before Otakon Otakon 2007 you not just learn it you have to keep it learned.
Scott: you can't like learn it right now And then forget it.
Scott: at Otakon.
Scott: you have to be able to perform this dance at the drop of a hat without missing a beat.
Scott: If you're one of those people you know who kind of messes up a little bit Yeah, you suck That's.
Scott: you might as well not have learned it at all.
Scott: you need to do it as well as the characters in the anime.
Rym: if you Can do that by Otakon you and you go to Otakon you will be able to be a part of something not fully planned Out yet, but guaranteed to be awesome.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It could it could be anything ranging from spontaneous dancing in the hallway to a Legitimately registered cosplay.
Scott: who knows?
Rym: now if any of you go to Katsucon And you know this dance by then Katsucon.
Scott: Yeah, we're not gonna make you learn the whole dance by Katsucon because we might not even have the whole dance learned by Katsucon.
Rym: But that will be the practice run, but if you can somehow do this dance for us at Katsucon I guarantee we will have some manner of renumeration remuneration Compensation for your efforts.
Rym: yes money or a prize or you already got the dance memorized.
Scott: You are awesome.
Rym: If you if someone sends us a video of them doing it before Katsucon I'll just cry.
Scott: well no because I'm sure if you go on YouTube you can find bunches of people already doing this.
Rym: Oh, it has to be a video of you and we'll know.
Scott: Well, we know we'll know.
Rym: Okay, we'll know all right Just like huh that looks like a bunch of Japanese people.
Rym: Huh, you're not Japanese.
Scott: Hmm all right.
Scott: anyway as I said before we were gonna do the show on Dominion tank police And we can't because the DVD was scratched, but you should watch Dominion tank police.
Scott: so anyway the idea of all these anime dances Gave us a good topic for today's discussion.
Scott: We're gonna talk about anime openers and closers now We're gonna.
Scott: We're gonna do this in separate parts first.
Scott: I want to ask a question What is the purpose of an opener and a closing now?
Rym: That's an interesting question?
Rym: I mean on one hand an opener especially for the first episode of a show or the first few episodes is The first thing you experience about the show.
Rym: that's the moment Are you?
Scott: I don't know about that because you know back in the day?
Scott: Maybe a show would come on and the opener was the first thing you saw.
Scott: but nowadays You know especially first episodes it seems like there's a short prologue before the openers start.
Scott: I true, so it's not really.
Scott: you know the thing.
Scott: it doesn't no longer has the purpose of letting you know.
Scott: Hey, the show's on.
Scott: you know it used to be Voltron starting right now, or GI Joe is starting right now.
Scott: You know or Transformers is starting right now, but it's not now.
Scott: There's a prologue, so that's not the purpose of the opener I don't.
Rym: but at least back in the day I mean there were a lot of shows where the first episode has the opener.
Rym: and Just by looking at the opener to at least a good opener or at least an average opener you can know Basically what kind of show it is unless it's one of those shows that pulls a 180 and the opener has nothing to do with It.
Rym: I mean you watch the Sailor Moon opener You know exactly what you're gonna get out of Sailor Moon.
Rym: you watch the big O opener You know exactly what bigos.
Scott: Oh, you know a big.
Scott: Oh is about big.
Scott: Oh, that's right big.
Scott: Oh, it's showtime Cast.
Rym: in the name of God you not guilty.
Rym: yeah, we have came to team big.
Scott: Oh well personally I think that openers have two main purposes.
Scott: the first purpose is Sort of a bridge.
Scott: you know it makes the prologue possible.
Scott: when you think about it It's like without the openers.
Scott: These prologues on anime totally wouldn't work because the prologues do is they kind of lead you into the episode like something something something suspense opener and it's like ah and that suspense carries over the opener and then the episode starts and That to me feels a lot smoother a start to watching a show.
Scott: then just opener get right into it.
Rym: Yeah, well it also definitely.
Rym: I mean say you do that.
Rym: You know you have the regular prologue like it was a sad time.
Rym: And then that thing happened and it fades out and then the show just fades in.
Rym: that's a totally different vibe from Blah blah blah and then the opening music fades in.
Scott: yep the other thing.
Scott: the main purpose I think of openers is to set the mood for the show.
Scott: You know it's like if you're about to watch I don't know like Love Hina.
Scott: right the opener is all sort of happy and jumpy and doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: You know that's sort of the mood of the show matches that opener, so you know if you just start watching it It's like you'd have to get into the mood during the show.
Scott: You know itself as opposed to you're set in the mood by the opener And then the show starts.
Scott: it gives you the correct feeling Before you know if you don't need to run up while stuff is happening.
Scott: Initial D.
Rym: Definitely did that well definitely put you in this kind of grooving.
Rym: Yeah, let's go mood.
Scott: Yep I think that's the purpose of an anime opener now?
Scott: now What about a closer though?
Scott: besides of course showing the credits at the credits is obvious?
Scott: But you know unless you're someone who reads the credits What is the purpose of a close?
Rym: it seems like there are two kinds of shows when it comes to closers and?
Rym: the first kind of the shows that they'll show you like clips from the episode or Really, just kind of nothing.
Rym: It'll be barely anything at all.
Scott: I guess the closer does actually let you know the episodes over.
Rym: well Maybe it'll be some screenshots from the previous episode Maybe it'll be a series of art shots that aren't in the show.
Rym: I remember one particular full metal alchemist closer that was just a Lying back winry being panned over and then various pictures of winry doing things.
Scott: yep.
Rym: And there are the rare shows that actually have a closer.
Rym: That's a lot like the opener.
Rym: That's fully animated crazy Well done beautiful whatever and those don't seem to be very common anymore.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I don't know some.
Scott: I Think one purpose of a closer is that if you're watching shows in marathon I remember at anime club You know I don't do it now, but at anime club We always showed all Openers and closers and marathoning shows.
Rym: this seems to be a point of contention in modern anime clubs and among younger anime fans.
Rym: I mean in the old days There was this idea that you have to watch every single screen second of every anime.
Rym: I mean when I got a fan sub on a tape it had the opener Then it had the show.
Rym: it had both Eyecatches.
Rym: then it had the closing credits and the preview.
Rym: at the end of every episode.
Rym: it would then show The opener and the closer again without the subtitles or the credit.
Rym: so you got the pure version so you could watch that too.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: they seem to have moved that to the extras, but yeah Yeah, I'm talking more about fan subs.
Scott: I remember the first time I saw anime at anime club.
Scott: It was so weird because okay.
Scott: We watch the opener.
Scott: I know what an opener is.
Scott: that makes sense you know.
Scott: and Then they'll be the eye catches and like what the hell.
Scott: and then at the end of the episode that'd be the closer.
Scott: Then they would show the preview for the next episode.
Scott: then they would show the opener that you know again.
Scott: So it's like if I watched four episodes of a show.
Scott: I saw the opener four times in the closer four times and two of the times the opener had the English Subtitles and two of the times the opener had the Japanese subtitles, and it was it's like whoa.
Scott: Why don't we just watch what the opener once at the beginning and once at the end and the four episodes in the middle?
Scott: But yet, why do we have those eye catches there?
Scott: Do we really need those?
Rym: we were kind of the bridge?
Rym: I mean it seems like the people just slightly more.
Scott: that was my thoughts originally.
Scott: now I sometimes I like to watch the open.
Rym: well honestly because I've been watching fan subs mostly Sailor Moon and Ava just whatever crap I Could get a hold of back then and I always watched every single thing on those tapes.
Rym: I think part of it was that they were hard to get.
Rym: so if you got an anime it felt so special especially if it Was something that wasn't just available in the u.s.
Rym: And you felt like it was your duty to get all your money's worth out of it And I would watch the textless opener and closer just marvel at them.
Rym: well And I think that's just from a bygone culture of anime.
Rym: is this rare and difficult to get thing?
Rym: and when you get it It's like a museum piece like ooh look how the openers animated.
Rym: Oh, I got to see it without all those Characters in the way without all that text blocking that art.
Rym: Yeah, but then all the younger kids in anime Club as we were getting older and getting closer to graduation would kick Constantly ask why are we watching the closer over and over again?
Rym: I want to finish the show so I can get to tape checkout.
Scott: yeah now I do kind of think that when watching a show in Marathon form you know episode after episode that the closers do actually provide sort of this nice transition between episodes of you know feeling.
Scott: I mean if you were just stayed in the moat in the mood for the show throughout 26 straight episodes without you know the closer to kind of bring you down and then the opener to bring you back in.
Scott: That can seriously fuck you up with some shows.
Rym: well Especially we used to do this a lot when we were in college where we'd pick a weekend We'd get a 26 episode show and we'd marathon the thing pretty much in one day.
Rym: Yep, now it seemed like the best way to handle it.
Rym: least the way that I liked was we'd watch the opener about half the Time like sometimes we'd watch the opener.
Rym: sometimes We'd skip it But we always watch the closer just at the end of whatever tape.
Rym: we were watching Mm-hmm, and then between tapes we had kind of this wind down period where we'd all just kind of sit there all Wistful.
Rym: yeah of course that might have been due to the fact that we were usually watching heavy-duty anime and not so much over long periods of time without rest.
Rym: I mean what we mostly marathon things like Ava and Eska and utenna.
Rym: we didn't really marathon anything funny.
Scott: Nope all right, so we know why openers and closers are important.
Scott: Oh, they're also important to market new hit music at least in Japan.
Scott: They don't seem to do that in America so much at least I don't watch TV anymore.
Scott: Maybe they started doing it But in Japan they always put hit music on like the big anime as the openers and closers so they can sell that music.
Scott: Well also a lot of Gundam seed sold a lot of records for TMR.
Scott: Let me tell you they also.
Rym: Not so much now, but especially back in the day.
Rym: the opener itself was basically a trailer for the show.
Rym: I mean before you could get digi subs or anything the thing that the commodity that was traded online were often just openers to shows You've never heard of and in fact I remember when I saw the opener to Eska flown a long before I had any way of getting Eska flown a and that got Me so hooked and pumped about that show.
Scott: yeah, that is true all right, so we know why openers and closers exist.
Scott: What makes a good opener as opposed to a bad?
Scott: Opener and the same for clothes?
Rym: there's a lot of different kinds of openers and closers.
Rym: I mean they range from the Generic animation made to be an opener along with whatever kind of music is popular in Japan at the time.
Rym: There's the ones that try to be like they'll have a song that's written for the show that Really fits or kind of reveals things about the show set to an opener that reveals things about the show or Shows you footage from the show that you haven't seen yet.
Rym: I guess like an example of the former would be all of the Fullmetal Alchemist openers There were really just kind of popular j-rock song with cool imagery Yep as opposed to say Evangelion where the show's opener was actually pretty relevant to the show in terms of the music.
Rym: and If you pay attention to the opener it Reveals a lot in really obtuse ways and definitely sets up that this is not the kind of show you think it is.
Scott: Oh wow the Ava opener is just kind of crazy.
Scott: it out there.
Rym: Yeah, I remember when we were first watching Ava.
Rym: We actually slowed it down and tried to look at all the frames in the opener and tried to figure out what was going on And some of that stuff was disturbing especially when you didn't know where the show was going.
Scott: oh, man Yeah, another good example.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: a related example is the antenna opener with the horses.
Rym: Oh god We knew this guy Dwayne I think we've talked about Dwayne off and on.
Rym: Dwayne is a bigger utenna fan than either of us, and that's saying a lot Now.
Rym: he had seen all of utenna before.
Rym: I had seen more than two episodes of it And I remember one day he was talking to me wall stone And he hadn't seen the end yet like he'd seen everything, but the last two episodes, and he tells me between puffs on his joint That he knows what's gonna happen because every scene from the opener happened in the show Except for the last one which shows two characters on horses in armor flying toward a castle And he was so sure that that was gonna be in the show because everything else was in the show.
Rym: Not gonna ruin whether or not it was in the show, but I think you can guess yep All right, so what do I think makes a good opener?
Scott: Well actually personally I think that the music is more important than the animation in the opener.
Scott: Not that animation is not important in the opener But basically you can have a decent opener if the music sets the right mood and the animation is kind of cheap as It's not you know Non-existent, but you can't have a good opener with bad music even if your animation is amazing
Rym: course But you do
Scott: something really artistic and you're all like a silent opener or something like that.
Rym: good and bad music is really subjective because Especially since openers more and more now are whatever music's popular at the time so a lot of older anime.
Scott: It's not so much whether the music is good or bad as if you like the song It's so much that does the music match the mood of the show.
Rym: well look back like look back in the day Tank police.
Rym: the opener in Japan is this Totally generic ladies pops 80s j-pop song and it's like hot dance and cherry moon hot dance.
Rym: It has so little to do with the show.
Rym: it doesn't mean it's even worse in terms of relevance than Fullmetal Alchemist Openers.
Rym: and yet the opener itself the way it's animated is super awesome And it's alright.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: Well.
Rym: This might be a kind of the greatest.
Scott: It's a lot of panning over stills as opposed to animation.
Rym: well It's also a lot of big o style a bunch of tanks a bigger set of tanks a bigger set of tanks Kind of tanks, but my controversial opinion.
Rym: Is that the redubbed?
Rym: re-musicked American opener is Vastly superior to the Japanese opener.
Scott: I don't know it wasn't on the DVD, so I can't really comment.
Scott: I don't remember it from back in the day so much.
Scott: basically remember a little bit.
Rym: They wrote a song that fits exactly with what's going on in the opening animation And it enhances it and makes it an awesome opener.
Rym: where the Japanese opener which has the same great funny relative to the time animation Totally doesn't set the mood of the show at all because it has this completely irrelevant song attached to it mm-hmm.
Scott: now What makes a good closer see I used to think that a?
Scott: Closer would be good if it took you from the mood of the show Back to like you know a neutral mood that you could live with in the everyday world.
Rym: I can name two shows that have really good openers, and I have a very specific reason Why.
Rym: yeah for Shiggy Yugi the first season which actually I really like that.
Scott: I don't I've never saw the opener, but I think I'd know the song if you played it.
Rym: Yeah on the closer Yeah, oh the closing and Nana.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's a good one.
Rym: now The reason I say these two is that both of them the shows use the closer in a very specific way.
Rym: The end of every episode would usually build to some sort of cliffhanger Climax or stopping point one of those three in every single episode.
Rym: but when I was a stopping point like a big stopping point and
Scott: even
Rym: when there was a stopping point that always leave you kind of hanging like just barely over the edge of a cliffhanger and You'd know when the end of the show was coming up because they'd slowly pan in the closers.
Scott: music Did that also.
Scott: that is that is one of the best things ever is when animes Start playing the closing music like 10 15 seconds before the end of the show.
Scott: They did.
Scott: a lot of shows are doing that now and even though a lot of people are doing it.
Scott: It's good to keep doing it.
Rym: There's no reason that most shows shouldn't be doing that because I'm not sure why but I guess it keeps the level of the like The energy of the show up and it pulls you out of the show into the real world.
Rym: But yet you don't get that sense of alright, I'm done you get that sense of something's happening and I gotta see it.
Scott: Yep, another a good example of a recent closer.
Scott: That is awesome.
Scott: is the gun could sue a closer?
Scott: Oh, yeah See now it's weird that one because the music doesn't start until the closer starts.
Scott: if the closer just kind of jumps out at you It's like, you know You know and the closer doesn't have much animation - it's just mostly credits But you know what?
Rym: It doesn't need it.
Scott: It doesn't need it cuz that song is so powerful.
Rym: God, I mean the lyrics to that song are probably the closest fitting closer lyrics to any anime ever.
Scott: I just I don't know.
Scott: I just love that so much.
Rym: I don't know why it seems like the hard-hitting closers Regardless of how they're animated.
Rym: just the use of music is more important than the use of animation.
Scott: And in fact, yeah, you know, actually there's a lot of shows that like.
Scott: I like the show a lot But the closers are just kind of like and and and and and and and and and it's the end of the show.
Rym: Like one or two still shots kind of slowly move from the bottom of the top like on the side or like a Naked ray spinning in front of the moonlight while someone sings fly me to the moon.
Scott: Yeah, like let's see.
Scott: Yeah Evangelion closer and not so exciting really.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not a fan.
Scott: What else doesn't have the greatest closer?
Scott: Cromartie high school not the greatest closer yet now.
Rym: now Gog mong of yori.
Scott: I was just gonna say Gog mong of yori cuz I had it in my mind.
Scott: you beat me to it.
Scott: That's the same moment.
Rym: That is another hard-hitting.
Rym: I don't think I need to play that one.
Rym: No Yeah, it seems.
Rym: but it seems like a lot of shows until very recently had just totally lame closers that you just immediately changed the Channel and I think part of the rationale for having these new closers might not be entirely artistic.
Rym: I'll bet the networks in Japan have something to do with it because if the closer is just like a stopping point like fade out With credits going by That's a real great time for someone to turn off the TV and go have a real life somewhere.
Rym: Mm-hmm, if the closer hits you hard full energy and keeps you pumped up You're gonna sit there to the end of the closer and then a new show is gonna come on.
Scott: Mmm Yeah, you know actually in the United States It doesn't seem like clothes like every show has a closer I guess but it seems like a lot of shows will.
Scott: just you know They just break the screen in half They start running ads immediately on the other half of the use to do that and the credits just kind of flow.
Rym: That's a new by new God.
Rym: That's a new development as in I don't know 15 years ago.
Rym: Yeah But in America, it seems like openers and closers just don't matter anymore at all.
Rym: I mean the average show is like a.
Scott: well, I think that this the cartoons still have.
Scott: the openers Yeah, but actual TV that normal people actual live-action TV in the u.s.
Scott: They don't seem to.
Scott: they seem to these really Short meaningless openers.
Scott: I haven't watched TV recently.
Rym: Every drama show is like Don't And like shots of the people standing there like I am the serious guy.
Rym: I'm a guy with a gun.
Rym: Look at us.
Rym: run past this car that's about to explode.
Scott: Yeah, I mean look at like The Simpsons has an opener, right?
Scott: That's there's a freaking opener.
Rym: Yeah But you know what?
Rym: as soon as Simpsons goes into reruns at least as long as I watch TV if you watch a Simpsons on Sunday night you get the full opener.
Scott: if you watch a rerun or a syndicated Simpsons episode in another episode on another channel or during the week it has the shortened opener and The closer to the Simpsons is just doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo and the credits there's nothing to it.
Rym: Well, the other thing I always noticed that in America closers have the an open.
Rym: You know the Futurama the same thing.
Scott: big opener no closer.
Rym: Well closers and openers have the same production values as a show.
Rym: but in Japan a lot of anime Especially older anime seem to put so much money and effort into the opener and closer.
Rym: I put forth Sailor Moon Especially the later seasons of Sailor Moon.
Rym: the animation in the openers and closers was beautiful and Phenomenal.
Scott: and well, I think it's when you know that that opener is gonna be played so many times You put a lot more effort into it.
Scott: when you're making animation that's gonna be shown in one episode.
Scott: You know, you're not gonna put as much money into it as you are something that's gonna reappear constantly.
Rym: Yeah, well, it's kind of like the Gonzo effect only applied to an individual episode.
Scott: It's like we're if we make a mistake here.
Scott: People are gonna see that mistake every week.
Scott: We can't make a mistake here.
Rym: You know the problem with this was that Sailor Moon beautiful beautiful opener and closer, right?
Rym: Then you're watching the show and it's just the only runs of the opener and the closer and especially in the middle.
Rym: I don't know Sailor Stars where they started hiring scab artists because they were running out of money.
Rym: and it's just.
Rym: It's like a different show comes on.
Rym: Yep, utenna same kind of thing almost Yeah, actually has a really beautiful opener compared to the show.
Scott: this it does with this one utenna closer, that's awesome.
Scott: Yeah, which one is it?
Scott: It's the one where it's like white and there's a rectangle.
Scott: So let's move on to the final bit about openers and closers.
Scott: What are the bests and the worsts?
Rym: Well, it depends on what you're going after.
Scott: I mean, I really like your favorites there.
Rym: Whatever Well, see I really like the Fullmetal Alchemist openers and the Gundam seed.
Scott: I really like the Gundam seed openers a lot And the Gundam seed closers, I don't think are as great But the way they pull the music in at the end of the episode is high quality.
Rym: with the Gundam seed openers A lot of openers like to have information about the show.
Scott: That is true But I do not like about them in there subtly.
Rym: The problem is Gundam seed.
Rym: if you are at least of average intelligence the openers and closers reveal to you.
Scott: you have to purposefully maintain and give yourself doubt in order to Disbelieve the information the openers are giving you even though all of it is true.
Rym: Scott had already seen the show and I had.
Rym: while we were watching it I picked out.
Scott: exactly like every single Romantics twist every single change of allegiance is based solely on the openers and closers and when I watched the show originally I saw the same things that Rym did in the openers and closers, but I chose to maintain doubt about them.
Scott: I would tell myself it's just the opener.
Scott: It doesn't mean it's gonna turn out that way.
Scott: It's just the opener It's gonna turn out that way.
Scott: and then it did anyway.
Scott: But I was able to purposefully maintain doubt for my own sanity.
Rym: See I just knew.
Rym: the only thing I didn't predict in that show was the thing that wasn't in the openers and closers at all.
Rym: Yeah, the thing that could not be predicted of course because it was kind of chintzy.
Rym: Yeah, just a little.
Rym: yeah It was a little too convenient anyway.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: my favorite opener is probably a cross between utenna just because the utenna opener There's a lot to it.
Rym: Just like the show.
Rym: There's a lot to it.
Rym: all the Sailor Moon openers Just cuz they're really really pretty and because there's a lot of nostalgia for them.
Scott: Mm-hmm, and I don't know it's hard to say I would say the best opener ever is I don't know if I could argue against it is cowboy bebop.
Rym: Cowboy bebop is very special because it has an opener that really Nails home the idea that cowboy bebop is a show unlike other shows.
Rym: That is kind of this news.
Scott: closer is kind of a. it basically has no animation whatsoever.
Scott: It's just the credits scrolling over.
Scott: You know a picture, but no it's the song is pretty awesome.
Rym: It's the credit scrolling over fairly relevant pictures.
Scott: Yes, but it's just a still picture, but the music in the closer is very good.
Rym: Well, that's that's part of it.
Rym: generally I can watch the opener to a show every time I watch the show even if I'm marathoning it mm-hmm But generally I can't watch a closer more than once and I only look at.
Scott: I can watch the konkotsuo closer every time Yeah, but most closers.
Scott: after I see those closers after I see them once I can't watch.
Rym: all I do is check periodically to see if the closer change.
Scott: Yeah, and there's some openers like Gundam seed like.
Scott: the openers are good.
Scott: I could watch them a bunch of times.
Scott: I couldn't watch them 50 times.
Scott: It's a 50-something episode show, but the fact that they changed the opener okay.
Scott: now I can watch every opener because they change it often enough throughout the show.
Scott: This is what like four or five different openings, so it's still cool.
Scott: What other openers are really damn good.
Scott: See the try gun opener has that really perfect awesome music, but the animation is nothing to it.
Scott: It's just still pictures.
Rym: try gun opener is garb.
Rym: of course.
Rym: They particularly gimped the opener of try gun in the u.s.. You see the opener changes Episode to episode based on what goes on in the episode and then the u.s.
Rym: Release.
Rym: they just pretended it didn't do that or maybe they didn't realize it And they just took the one from the first episode and used it for the whole show.
Scott: Yeah, because there's definitely like the opener is just a bunch of pictures and the camera pans over these still frames.
Scott: but there's one still frame that's relevant to the episode you're about to watch and It's always a frame.
Scott: That's relevant to the first episode.
Scott: so I must assume I don't know if it's a hundred percent true that in Japan that if you watched it on TV That it was a different still frame every opener.
Rym: It was.
Rym: I saw some fansubs that showed me that.
Scott: oh did you alright?
Scott: Well in the u.s.. It was just the opener for the first episode every time.
Rym: Also in terms of changing openers.
Rym: There's one show that the opener wasn't great Other than the fact that it set the mood for the show really well, but in gassaraki They did something interesting, and I guess I'll say it's one of my favorites Just because I thought it was really cool.
Rym: the opener was modular.
Rym: it effectively consisted of a whole bunch of fairly short Animated bits that were all kind of strung together in this like vague generic opener thing.
Rym: that kind of told you What was going on in the show?
Rym: Every episode or every couple episodes They would move around a couple of them or replace one or two of them and as you watch the show eventually the opener is totally replaced with completely different footage And if you pay attention to that it kind of enhances your understanding of what's going on in the show.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: Yeah, the gassaraki opener is very good at that.
Rym: I really like the song too.
Scott: It's an okay song.
Scott: I'm just.
Scott: I'm actually not the biggest fan of a lot of some of the gassaraki music.
Scott: It's really like half the songs.
Scott: I love them in half of them.
Scott: I'm like this crap.
Rym: I really like the music in gassaraki.
Scott: some of its good some is not.
Scott: oh both standalone complexes of awesome openers and well particularly the music is fantastic.
Scott: I Don't know what it is about people singing in that language But it's because you can't understand the words so you don't realize that lyrics are stupid.
Rym: well, that's not just that cuz I don't understand Japanese very well if at all either but Because it's a language.
Rym: I don't hear all the time like Japanese sounded exotic and cool to me.
Rym: I don't know 12 15 years ago now.
Rym: Japanese while I don't understand it doesn't sound special at all.
Rym: It sounds like English to me except.
Rym: I realize halfway through a conversation.
Rym: I don't know what.
Rym: I don't understand it.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just reading subtitles.
Rym: Yeah, like if I'm watching anime, and it's not subtitled I won't notice right away until I realize they have no idea what someone just said.
Rym: yep But I just totally don't even notice.
Scott: like it totally gets me.
Scott: I'll watch a subtitled show and I'll think the people are speaking in English like this the combination of the words and In text on the screen and people making Japanese noises sort of my brain turns it Japanese noise.
Scott: My brain takes those two things adds them up, and I hear that character speaking in English sort of in my brain.
Scott: It's kind of crazy Yeah.
Rym: But when it happens if you watch a lot of subtitled anime any like any language that I don't have any familiarity with at all especially when it's being sung tends to just sound awesome to me.
Rym: and Aside from that the animation even that the weird CG in the first.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the seed the first opener is cool, but the only thing wrong with it Is that the CG is a little subpar, but it's not initial d-bad It's another unpopular or controversial opinion.
Rym: But I actually really like the way that CG played out in that.
Scott: oh I do except for a few Specific things that you can.
Scott: I know you're not like sore thumb.
Rym: You're gonna say the majors teeth.
Scott: That's right the teeth They're just in.
Scott: you know what they just stick out so badly.
Rym: they didn't stick out to me as being weird.
Rym: They sticked out to sticked out.
Rym: They stuck out to me as being oddly Realistic and I thought no I don't think they were in the uncanny valley for me.
Scott: I definitely got a. those are just not even you know.
Scott: they really bothered me not because they were too real But because they were poorly rendered.
Rym: I don't think they were that bad.
Rym: I thought it was cool.
Scott: I think they looked kind of weird.
Rym: my favorite part in that opener is still the bit with the Tachi Koma.
Scott: of course Tachi Komas are always the master which is why he goes in the shells.
Scott: awesome closers.
Scott: It's just Tachi Koma Tachi Koma, and then at the last second they go to do to do to do to do And that's it.
Scott: There's no real closer on.
Scott: it is there.
Rym: I guess I could give an honorable mention definitely to tenku no eska flown a because that opener is one of those.
Rym: the openers.
Rym: That's just so perfectly describes Everything about that show in terms of style and mood and theme.
Rym: you watch that opener And you know exactly what you're gonna get.
Scott: I want to give an honorable mention to both openers for ko century beast.
Rym: oh god Oh.
Rym: Oh I You know we got to review those shows which means I got to get the DVDs.
Scott: yeah It's two DVDs right.
Scott: there's one for the first Kao century beast and one for the second.
Rym: I'll just look on Amazon and buy it.
Scott: you're gonna buy a kale century beast.
Rym: That's a great show to own one.
Scott: debate a bit of it up.
Rym: It's one of my favorite shows.
Rym: I mean the plot is totally stupid.
Rym: It's totally.
Rym: characters are totally one dimension.
Scott: OMG the earth broke in half.
Scott: everyone's a furry the end.
Scott: It's a funny show.
Scott: it's it's cute And it's it's worth the you know few episodes that they made of it.
Scott: It wouldn't be worth the whole.
Rym: see ball demand is the best character.
Scott: Oh go kudo didn't have a great opener closer I forget.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: Yeah, but there was a great song, but I just forget it.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, whatever tell us in the forums what openers and closures you liked and didn't like.
Scott: yeah That's what I'm gonna make a thread in the forum for this episode.
Scott: everyone post your favorite anime or TV Whatever openers and closers.
Scott: Yeah, we'll have a fun little date about it And why you like them or why you hate him.
Scott: or if there's it yeah is there anyone?
Scott: you really hate Rym a Lot you see.
Rym: the thing is all the openers.
Rym: I hate her two shows.
Rym: I also hate so I don't watch him.
Scott: Oh, it's true.
Rym: It's true I can't think of many shows that have an opener that just really don't do the show justice or really suck Or just really don't fit.
Rym: they all seem to work well enough.
Scott: I kind of don't like the initial d-closer where you see like the live-action people singing.
Rym: See I totally forgotten about that.
Scott: Yeah, I just don't like that one, but the initial the openers in the show make up for it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.