Rym: It's Wednesday, June 13th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about one of our favorite manga Eagle making of an Asian American presidents.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know it's kind of scary, but I'm feeling slightly more and more like a semi-legitimate journalist the longer we do this.
Scott: What do you mean legitimate?
Rym: well as in you know long ago before we were internet famous if I had any sort of Problem or difficulty or anything with anyone out there in the world other than asking them.
Rym: You know hey, what's up?
Rym: I really had no recourse, and I just had to let things go Now.
Rym: last week we went on a little bit of a rant about the difficulties We've had talking to Otakon and within an hour of uploading the show More than one staffer emailed us and answered most of our concerns.
Scott: Why didn't they do that before?
Rym: I don't know they're having some trouble But it looks like everything's back in order and a lot of the things that hadn't been announced yet will be announced shortly.
Scott: actually Yeah, it's still definitely too late.
Scott: I mean it.
Scott: I mean it's not too late like oh no the con is doomed too late but is definitely you know beyond the deadline of Announcing who's got what panels and when and that kind of business see.
Scott: luckily It's really you know this stuff like four months in advance.
Rym: Luckily normal people do.
Rym: we don't because we have pretty much a loadout of ten or so panels We can do pretty much on 24 hours notice.
Scott: Yeah, it still kind of sucks though and Hopefully it will not happen again.
Scott: Yeah, well it looks like any con.
Rym: It looks like everything's going okay.
Rym: so far though I did very specifically now And I think to the right people offer to have myself and Scott and the rest of our crew Handle the panels for Otakon next year.
Rym: We'll see if they follow up on that because they haven't answered me yet.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is if they let us do it.
Scott: It'll be a question of are they going to say Here's what you have to do do exactly this or do the panels the way you want?
Scott: because if they just let us do the Panels the way we want it'll be awesome, but if they make us do with the Otakon way It won't be as awesome.
Rym: I don't know what you mean by the Otakon way.
Rym: It seems like every panels person handles it differently.
Rym: the only real Concern is that you have to deal with.
Rym: You have to put in all the industry and the guest panels and all those things.
Rym: then you fit the fan panels around that.
Rym: other Than that you can pretty much I'd assume pick wherever you want.
Scott: Yeah, it just you know.
Scott: it seems like Otakon is a convention at least from my perspective.
Scott: That is a lot more group decision-making whereas some other cons are sort of Delegating the decision-making and then people can do as they wish with the power granted to them.
Rym: see I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I did get the impression that the panel's person was at least somewhat independent in years past.
Rym: yeah Yeah, but but at least in the very least we can't really reveal anything.
Rym: But remember one of the questions we had was so what's the musical act?
Rym: why has no to can't say anything about the musical act?
Rym: I really want to know because the musical act is often the highlight of the con.
Rym: for me I just that's the kind of thing I really love and We can't really say who partly because we don't really know, but it looks like from a confirmed source They're going to have two musical acts this year.
Rym: They had two musical acts last year Yeah, but they're gonna have two again this year and from what they say it looks like it's something that not everyone is probably going To expect but the words I expect it to be quite lovely are in here.
Rym: I'm really excited.
Scott: I gotta say I don't know I don't I don't know.
Scott: We'll have to see what it is before I can say whether I'm happy about it or not.
Scott: I don't just.
Scott: I can't get excited about these mystery things anymore.
Scott: There's a good rant someone had recently on a blog.
Scott: They were like stop with the fucking countdowns.
Scott: You know people go out, and they're like they make a website like coming soon this thing and then they'll have a timer.
Scott: You know what that says.
Scott: all you're saying is this thing is going to happen.
Scott: You're not giving out any information at all.
Scott: you're basically saying nothing.
Scott: Either say something or get off the freaking soapbox, but that's a basic PR.
Rym: I mean say you're running for I don't know.
Rym: It's relevant tonight.
Rym: president of the United States right now.
Rym: if you just one day Announce I'm running for president you get a big press brouhaha, and then that's it and you disappear from the limelight.
Rym: But if you follow the elections and the primaries and everything you'll notice that most candidates first They'll announce their intention to put together an exploratory committee to consider the possibility of being president.
Rym: Then they'll announce that the explore the exploratory committee is going to be created a week from X day.
Rym: Then they announce it was created.
Rym: then they announce it's working.
Rym: then they announce that they're going to make an announcement.
Rym: Then that announcement.
Rym: they usually announced that they've decided whether or not they're going to run.
Rym: then they announce the day They're going to say if they're gonna run or not and then Eventually they might say they're going to run.
Scott: some of them haven't really said it yet this this time around see But you can still maintain that you know build up of slowly releasing information and having many announcements.
Scott: But I mean you could still do that.
Scott: But actually say something each time like let's say I'm putting out a video game, right?
Scott: I can come out like a year before the game is gonna be released and say I'm going to make this game.
Scott: Then the next week I could say the game is going to be in this genre.
Scott: And then the next week I can say the game is going to be on these systems and I won't have some stupid countdown where I just say nothing and Waste everyone's time and attention and you know such with nothing.
Scott: But I can still by withholding information saying things fewer things over a period of time get the same PR effect.
Scott: But not be annoying with a stupid.
Scott: it's a clock.
Scott: yeah, I have a clock in my house.
Scott: Thank you very much.
Scott: get away that there's better news for me to read.
Rym: see well like take the example of Smash Brothers the new Game coming out on the way.
Rym: if I were Nintendo how I would have done this countdown is n Weeks before the game is going to be released or maybe n days.
Rym: it depends probably weeks as long as I get the schedule down.
Rym: And being the number of characters in the game exactly I would have revealed one character.
Scott: I would have done maps before that I would have done maps and then characters.
Rym: You know that really what you should do is just go pixels.
Scott: ah Have this big Screenshot and each day one pixel of the screenshot appears one random one.
Rym: Yeah Or actually I'd make it a dynamic ajaxi.
Rym: real-time like every minute a pixel appears And it's just a big image, and then once one picture is done Another picture starts up, and you keep the archive all the old pictures.
Rym: you got to do something clever like that.
Scott: Yeah, something that actually gives information.
Scott: I don't care if you're withholding information.
Scott: I don't care if you're releasing information Artificially slowly for marketing purposes.
Scott: that's expected.
Scott: It's sort of necessary.
Scott: Just don't make an announcement.
Scott: That's nothing.
Scott: don't make these.
Scott: announcement that you're going to make an announcement.
Scott: Don't do that.
Scott: don't say nothing.
Scott: say at least something so that I didn't waste my time Reading whatever.
Scott: the thing you just said is.
Scott: that's all I ask.
Scott: you know when you say something make it worthwhile.
Rym: But in the very least to reign this back over to Otakon.
Rym: Ever since our little rant we talked to some people at Otakon and for all of you who are wondering there It is very very likely that we are going to be doing a decent number of panels and shows at Otakon.
Rym: We obviously we don't know for sure yet, but it looks pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, so for anyone out there Let's let's do a quick rundown here On Let's see hold on.
Rym: I gotta fill up the calendar.
Scott: Yes on June 23rd we are most likely going to be at the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art Arts Festival.
Scott: We are not going to be doing anything there except attending.
Scott: the same way you will be attending.
Scott: Yes Oh, we're not.
Scott: we're really basically going to be incognito though if enough of you're not incognito We're just walking around from table to table going.
Scott: OMG.
Scott: You make that comic.
Scott: OMG You make that comic.
Scott: OMG your comic is well.
Rym: I just realized that if we were webcomic artists we could probably get away with that because just walking around No one's gonna recognize us unless we put our pictures online or go to cons a lot, but we're podcasters.
Rym: It wouldn't be too hard to find us at a con because we're usually doing exactly what we're doing right now just in person.
Scott: Yes Then in July, I'm not gonna bother saying the dates But we're going to Connecticut where we will be doing God some stupid number of shows.
Scott: We're gonna get to Connecticut late Friday night But we will remain there for the entirety of the con.
Rym: Basically if you want to see us do live shows Connecticut's where you want to be because we're doing most of the events we've gotten put together for this entire year at Connecticut.
Scott: Yep, then we're going to anime next but I don't know how much we're going to anime next because as far as I know We're not doing anything.
Rym: We complain about Otakon partly because we care a lot about Otakon and while I like anime next I'd never gone to it until Last year and it wasn't really big on my radar But I respect it as a con.
Rym: at least Otakon got back with us at all.
Scott: Yeah, anime next.
Scott: just didn't anime.
Rym: next just ignored all my emails and eventually I just said alright fine screw it I'm not doing shows for you.
Scott: If I go to anime next I'll probably pick one day of the con probably the Saturday or the Sunday and go Just that day probably because that is a day that'll have events that I'm interested in.
Rym: Yeah, well we did that last year with Katsu.
Rym: We just kind of wandered around and had fun for the day.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, we'll probably.
Scott: it'll probably be more fun this year Even if it is the.
Scott: even if they ran the exact same con this year as they did last year I think it'd be more fun.
Scott: Just because it'll have things like pokemons and such like that.
Rym: Ah pokemons.
Rym: I better finish training.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: No, I'm not even gonna bother her.
Scott: It's not yeah, but then Otakon.
Rym: Well, once we know exactly what we're doing at the con, we'll keep you guys appraised Yeah, and then in December the New York anime festival in the city where we're doing So.
Rym: we're kind of doing the game shows.
Rym: we're doing a ConnectiCon but bigger faster and more intense.
Scott: Yeah, we don't know yet either a hundred percent, but we know that we're doing them.
Rym: We just don't know how would the size of the venue will be doing them in?
Rym: Because part of that hinges on how well the new event goes at ConnectiCon where they're graciously allowing us to beta tested and then In February next year Katsu.
Rym: Oh, man I gotta say I can't tell you what's going on at Katsu con next year other than that The staff of Katsucon is already putting a lot of thought and effort into what's going on at Katsucon next year.
Scott: Katsucon went from a con that I know that's you know over there in DC and I know about it And I heard good things about but never bothered with - oh That's the con.
Rym: suffice to say There is an event that we are nominally planning that may or may not involve anime world order Despite the fact that we have not told them.
Scott: We'll see if they actually show up.
Rym: Yeah Less - yeah, or no, I think Daryl was at the one - ago you met him.
Rym: Yeah, that's what I was in a drunken stupor and I met him while he was interviewing people and I was like I'm a podcaster - yeah Well, we can't plan an event with them.
Scott: They don't show.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the thing is we haven't even talked to them yet So they're Gerald's fucking me.
Rym: listen to this.
Rym: be like what we're doing at Katsucon.
Rym: Ah shit.
Rym: But yeah, if this event which I think is going to go through goes through Saturday night at Katsucon is gonna be one fucking thing a fucking thing.
Rym: It's something I actually proposed to Otakon and kinetic.
Rym: on ConnectiCon it was too late to put it together Otakon It's too late for us to put it together So I rescinded it, but I think we can have it together by February and I think it's gonna be pretty hot.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right In the news Otakon they just announced that one of the guests is going to be Mario Asaka the Chobits director and a bunch of other stuff.
Rym: Nana Go look at the anime news network.
Rym: There's a crazy list.
Rym: as always They get the big name awesome guest and probably fun to see the panel.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know I'm not too excited about the guest.
Scott: I mean, I like Nana and I like some of the shows that this person is direct a mermaid scar Card capture Sakura.
Rym: Oh god gunslinger girls.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh god.
Rym: Yeah So it's like probably a cool monster Storyboarded monster.
Rym: Yeah, but that still matters.
Scott: Yeah, I think while I like some of those works a great deal I don't really don't know how interesting it's gonna be to see this person and most likely I'll won't go see them.
Rym: Wow, you're just the cynical convoy tonight.
Scott: Well, I think about yeah last Otakon.
Scott: I didn't see Anybody last year.
Rym: Yeah, honestly, the only reason I didn't go to many events know to come last year was I was too busy.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's like the con is entertaining enough.
Scott: You know with the music acts and the alleys and the dealers and the us doing stuff that I don't really need to go See like the industry panel with the guests like this.
Scott: Well for you other people out there who are not me This is awesome.
Scott: If you especially if you like these shows you can go meet the person who is probably the biggest part in making them and learn Something.
Rym: well, typically I like these sorts of things.
Rym: When is the show?
Rym: I like that.
Rym: I actually have a question about Sadly the director some of the directors I would really like to Touch in some way.
Rym: I don't come to the US so often or at least don't come near me.
Rym: They're all.
Rym: they're all hang out in the west coast at those cons.
Scott: We don't go to All right, so check this out, I don't know.
Scott: did we talk about this?
Scott: or to just every other podcast talk about the nymph et manga?
Rym: Actually, I don't know if it came up, but I totally forgot or didn't know or didn't talk about this.
Rym: No idea what it was.
Scott: Okay to sum it up.
Scott: There's a manga that's basically about.
Scott: I guess It's about like an eight-year-old girl who sexually harasses her like 30 year old teacher and it's just a pedophile manga.
Scott: It doesn't have any it's.
Scott: it's not like some things that have fanservice like ghost in the shell.
Scott: Yeah has fanservice and nakedness and lesbians, but it's not a perverted manga.
Scott: It's mostly you know a sci-fi kind of thing.
Rym: So I'll give it one out because I have.
Rym: no I don't know anything about it.
Rym: Is it Lolita?
Rym: Is it art or is it just porn?
Scott: It's just poor God.
Scott: Nymph et is does no redeeming qualities whatsoever.
Scott: So you ready to appeal to pedophiles?
Scott: No, but that's what I hear from every possible person Knows anything about it and every place on the internet says that.
Rym: okay So what you just said is some guy on the internet told me watch all we know.
Rym: This is Hamlet.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: No, it's pretty much the worst thing ever and Basically They're gonna make an anime of it this summer, right?
Scott: Oh god No way it gets worse than that It could.
Scott: you didn't think it could be worse than making an anime of a pedophile manga with no redeeming.
Rym: Well, I can't imagine his license for release in the u.s No.
Scott: No Well, actually the manga that's that was the news.
Scott: was that last week or a couple weeks ago.
Scott: Is that the company putting out in the
Scott: u.s.?
Scott: Is you know facing some trouble and whatever?
Scott: Oh, I wonder why.
Scott: anyway Here's the worst news ready.
Scott: one of the episodes in the anime that they've made is unerible for Reasons unsaid but easily implied probably full of naked little girls and pedophile.
Scott: in this I'm guessing What about you?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'd assume that it has a Grand Moff Tarkin doing something.
Scott: Okay, I mean obviously They're going to take this unerible Episode and which I don't yet to be a sick person to make something like that in the first place.
Rym: So what are they?
Rym: gonna?
Rym: take a boat and just row it out there and then broadcast it back to Japan illegally?
Scott: Nope, they're going to put it on a DVD and if you buy the fourth volume of the manga You're going to get this DVD with the unerible episode.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: So basically if you buy all the manga you get the child porn surprise at the end.
Scott: Yeah Now see, um I don't want people to be confused here because a lot of people seem to be confused about this position that we have When it comes to things like this, you know, I'm not pro censorship.
Scott: I think people have the freedom of speech and freedom of press and freedom of art expression and they should be able to make this sort of thing if they want to.
Scott: Yeah, read this sort of thing if they want to and I will never advocate, you know the government preventing anyone from reading purchasing or you know Erring any of these sorts of things.
Rym: however, well The only line I have when it comes to art is if the creation of the art is Demonstrably harmful Limitations you put on free speech.
Rym: Yeah I mean if if power word kill worked that word would be banned.
Scott: Yeah I mean if there was some magical spell a Video in which someone says the magical spell and that summons a demon I would not allow that video to be distributed because that would Bring many demons into the.
Rym: of course, you know the world that video would be on YouTube more than any other video regardless.
Scott: Regardless my opinion is that if you are someone who makes reads well, I guess if you read it, you're not necessarily.
Scott: but if you enjoy or Gain entertainment from this sort of work in any way.
Scott: You are a sick disgusting worthless.
Scott: This disgusting human very bad.
Scott: I would have No qualms about killing you.
Scott: in fact, I would think you were so That it's okay to kill you.
Rym: I thought you I thought try gun made you a pacifist.
Rym: What's the turnaround?
Scott: They're not a human.
Scott: if you're like this, you're not human.
Scott: I can kill.
Rym: that's dangerous talk because that I don't want to spoil anything But I don't think it's.
Scott: it's dangerous talk to see someone who likes nymph.
Scott: it is not human.
Rym: I was just gonna go so far as to say that they're pretty creepy and I probably wouldn't want to engage in Conversation or share a bus stop with them.
Scott: If you don't want to be hyperbolic then yeah.
Scott: Well, yeah But if I don't want to be hyperbolic Regardless if you like an infant you're a sicko and I don't want to talk to you I don't even like see you don't don't tell me that you like it because you're sick.
Rym: I'm just waiting for the first post in the forums.
Rym: I read it.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Well, it seemed like I could understand if you just read it like cuz if someone read it out of curiosity to find out Like what the hell was going on?
Rym: I could understand that It's kind of like watching MD Geist or Odean despite being told not to exactly exactly.
Scott: Well, it's the matter of if you read it and then you read volume 2 or if you read it.
Scott: I was it you think.
Scott: oh that looks interesting I think I think now.
Rym: now to paraphrase the words that were spoken by the official Giving the wedding we went to the previous weekend with great power comes great responsibility.
Rym: Now You're all out there and you're all listening to this and you now know the name of this.
Rym: this work and I. the word work Is definitely in quotes?
Rym: We all know that our favorite anime podcast out there is anime world order.
Scott: they review anime and Manga, they know all about this nymph ed thing.
Scott: Well, I've been talking about it as well.
Rym: Perhaps they need some sort of campaign to get them to review it.
Scott: Just send them a bunch of copies.
Scott: that way at least perverts won't be able to buy it.
Scott: It'll be in good hands.
Scott: I mean sure the company that prints it will get money.
Scott: But they already got the money because they sold it to the store.
Scott: You see they don't get paid when you buy it.
Scott: they get paid when the store buys it.
Rym: But now you're not punishing the store for buying it.
Rym: That's true But even so in fact, if anything all you're doing is all you're doing is punishing Daryl Surratt for existing.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: Then you're actually, you know doing it for a good cut Things of the day.
Rym: so there's been a lot of talk in the anime world recently about a Concept or an art style or genre or whatever you want to make it out to be called super flat.
Rym: Uh-huh, and it seems like every person I run afoul of on the internet has a different idea of what super flat is Or what super flat means.
Scott: it seems to be one of those things.
Scott: where?
Scott: People some people seem to know it when they see it, but there isn't
Rym: a much like pornography
Scott: yes, but there isn't a strict definition like this is what super flat is and this is what it not is and People have a hard time if you say hey, what's super flat?
Scott: No one could just say what it is in simple terms there.
Scott: It's always kind of vague Like is it a style of animation?
Scott: Is it a you know, I don't know some new art wave movement.
Scott: What exactly is it?
Scott: Nobody can really say.
Rym: well, I can say what it is now because it is I'm pretty well I can say by showing because I know when I see it partly because it's called super flat.
Rym: Aha, hi everyone there you go and a lot of people seem to link to this as kind of iconic of super flat.
Rym: But then again, that's just what the internet says.
Rym: What does it know?
Scott: it knows everything duh?
Rym: It was actually Emily who showed me this and it's really really cool Regardless of super flat if you care or not watch this video Which I guess is meant to sell Louis Vuitton goods But kind of gives me the impression that if you run afoul of these goods you will be eaten by a psychedelic monster and sent to a fantasy land where monsters will steal your cell phone.
Scott: and Yeah, so five thousand dollar handbags only exist in anime world.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Rym: Just watch it.
Rym: I I'm not sure how to explain it other than that it's really pretty and it's kind of weird and it's really well done.
Rym: and It's about all I can say about it.
Scott: All right well, I think it's time for yet another thing of the day from the wonderful world of Japanese television.
Rym: Oh Japanese television that has given us such wonderful shows as guy trying to pee gets Lofted out of the urinal or guy trying to pee gets shot down a mountain on a sled or guy trying to pee gets pulled Out to sea by a boat.
Scott: well Japanese television the infinite font of things of the day has provided one more thing for us to laugh at.
Scott: Basically, what they done is they set up a challenge.
Scott: the challenge consists of a giant I want to say treadmill, but it's more like a big conveyor belt like, you know those things at airports.
Rym: Yeah that when no one's looking I run down as fast as I can.
Scott: I'd run down as fast I can when people are looking.
Scott: well, usually when people have them at casinos, huh?
Rym: They didn't have them at the casino.
Rym: we went to.
Scott: yeah, they did where remember we used it?
Scott: no, it was there I don't remember it at all in a little tiny hallway.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: My memory is too clouded by all the money I want.
Scott: that much money.
Rym: compared to how much money I came with I'm doubled my money and then you spent it at the bookstore.
Rym: No, no, I didn't spend that money.
Rym: the bookstore spent other money.
Scott: Yeah that money.
Scott: I'm sure.
Scott: anyway they said of this giant conveyor belt really big and On the side of it there are like these four little platforms and each platform has I guess a cookie on it or something like.
Scott: one has a glass of water one has a glass of water and a cookie I think and they put someone on the treadmill and they have to run from one end of the treadmill to the other and Also eat all the cookies and drink the water.
Scott: and if they fall down or if they fail to eat the cookies or whatever They're done and they lose.
Scott: but not only that.
Scott: Something interesting happens to them when they lose and I'll let you see that for yourself.
Scott: The thing that bothers me about this particular challenge is I do not.
Scott: while it is very entertaining and amusing I am under the impression that it was not completely fair.
Scott: well, I think that they were controlling the speed of the treadmill manually and Basically as people, you know got close to victory.
Scott: They would turn it up more and more and more to make sure that nobody won.
Rym: granted.
Rym: That's really the only way to run something like this if you want if you made it fair.
Rym: You really missed out on a golden opportunity It is true.
Scott: But I do think what they should have just done is okay said.
Scott: This is the level that we will set it at.
Scott: set it at a high level that you know Maybe only a really awesome person could accomplish.
Rym: I see you're assuming the same every time that this was intended to be a test of skill.
Rym: You see I'm of the mind more and more that Japanese game shows are not game shows.
Rym: They don't the people on the show.
Rym: that doesn't.
Rym: they don't matter at all.
Rym: They are basically just saps and they exist solely to entertain me.
Scott: That may be true.
Scott: But at the same time, I think it's sort of you know It entertains me more when it's a fair competition and the people still get fucked.
Scott: then if it's a designed to fuck them and they get fucked because you know, it's like They're all day designed to get fucked it's not so funny.
Scott: Oh they suck.
Scott: Haha They suck.
Rym: so a funny moment one is when you realize that at the other end of the treadmill is a pool.
Rym: I was gonna are you gonna keep it secret?
Scott: I hit it, but now it's it's not hidden.
Scott: Oh, well, I guess they bail at the treadmill.
Scott: Then the treadmill pushes them into a pool and they go sploosh - the black dude is awesome.
Scott: The black dude is my hero.
Scott: He's gigantic - and they?
Scott: how do these Japanese people even expect to be able to win this?
Scott: They're tiny tiny legs.
Scott: only the black guy with the giant legs can possibly have a chance and even he.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil what happens at the end, but suffice to say it's a closely run affair.
Scott: He's also the only person who knows how to run me.
Scott: one thing the Japanese people have the tiny legs But they don't even know how to run.
Rym: No, the one guy did.
Rym: just the last person ran really oddly.
Scott: I don't know what is up with these people who don't know how to run ready.
Scott: Here's Scott's guide how to run ready Move your legs back and forth as quickly as possible Extend them as far as possible lift your knees as high as possible Bend your freaking elbows and swing your arms in time.
Rym: Not how you run.
Rym: That's actually a pretty piss-poor way to run.
Rym: That's kind of inefficient.
Scott: But what these people who like they walk with their art they run with their arms like straight at their sides not moving.
Scott: They don't bend their knees at all and they just kind of waggle their legs back and forth.
Scott: Those people are fucked up.
Rym: They didn't learn there a Seinfeld about that.
Rym: She just doesn't move her arms.
Scott: Yeah, people just don't know how to move it up.
Scott: motor skills That's like the most basic skill before even literacy moving your body in the proper fashion.
Rym: now I think in the trend of how I started talking about this they missed one final golden opportunity.
Rym: now if The final bit of the challenge had been in fact a urinal.
Scott: Yeah Yeah.
Rym: So we brought out the US presidential elections rather serendipitously for tonight We're going to talk about probably our second favorite manga of all the second favorite manga of all time.
Rym: Well in the in the in this kind of the two manga that are like this that we have It's the top 10 manga of all time for sure.
Rym: It's definitely number two because I love it.
Rym: I don't think it's quite as good as sanctuary But yet at the same time I hadn't read it in a long time and when I pulled it out to flip through it Before we did the show.
Rym: I Remembered how freaking awesome it was.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it's I don't want to read it again.
Scott: It's not as awesome as sanctuary Phoenix Buddha Akira, whatever but after all those this is the number one.
Scott: You've got left.
Rym: So tonight we're going to talk a bit about Eagle which Well Eagle colon the making of an Asian American president.
Rym: You see Eagle is much like sanctuary only without the eroticism and Without the Yakuza.
Scott: Yeah, and without the violence it has some violence, but not much very little very little violence.
Scott: it's pretty much just take the politicking and the human drama aspects of sanctuary and spread them out over 2,000 pages and You've got Eagle now.
Rym: Eagle is basically the story of a young man named Takashi Joe whose mom died and he works for some newspaper in Japan and for various reasons he ends up getting the shot of a lifetime
Scott: to head
Rym: over to America and cover for Japan the presidential campaign of Senator Yamaoka who is a Japanese American Democratic senator who is running for president?
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty cool right there.
Rym: and Suffice to say all is not as it appears.
Rym: for their hintings that perhaps his mother was murdered and didn't just die of her own accord and Perhaps there are sinister things going on and perhaps reveal any of them would be a huge spoiler.
Rym: Yes and perhaps in fact The man the senator has a link to the young Takashi Joe.
Rym: That may or may not be true or may or may not be apparent or may or may not be important.
Scott: Yep, it's all sort of the manga tends to carry you along with a lot of things like tossing out these possibilities All over the place about all sorts of different things.
Scott: it sort of feels a lot like a presidential campaign in a way which where there are many rumors and rumors and hints of information and then oh the actual information comes out dumb dumb dumb and then they do it again and again and again and again for many many many pages until it's over.
Rym: now much like if Sanctuary were true I would have joined the Yakuza as soon as I was able to get to Japan and if Horatio Hornblower were true I would have somehow constructed the time machine to go back in time and be some sort of seaman in the Navy.
Rym: if Eagle were actually a portrait of how American elections work.
Rym: I would be a politician.
Scott: I would also maybe be a reporter.
Rym: Yes, either one because apparently reporters and politicians are all consummate badasses.
Scott: Yep, well, let's talk about the meta of this for a second.
Scott: All right, it's made by Kaiji Kawaguchi the story and the art by one man and one man alone the way manga should be.
Rym: it was nominated for not One not two not three not five but for Eisner Awards.
Scott: That's quite a.
Rym: many eyes are a best new series best continuing series best writer artist best US edition of foreign material.
Scott: Yep, they actually this year they changed the best US edition of foreign material award and they have two of them now this best US edition of foreign material and Best US edition of foreign material Japan.
Scott: only because the Japan just kept winnings.
Scott: They split it off.
Scott: Basically this guy Kaiji Kawaguchi Went all around the US on this big trip Researching like how our politics worked in our country and all sorts of things in Preparation to write this manga and he wasn't.
Scott: it said that he was inspired to create the manga after watching some Documentary about politics or something.
Scott: I forgot.
Scott: I don't know but if you look and you read this manga it becomes immediately obvious to anyone who knows anything about the United States that this is a Parody I guess of the 2000 presidential election in the US.
Rym: Yes, it is definitely Al Gore who is the front-runner Democratic candidate.
Scott: Yeah, he's made.
Scott: they call him Al Noah and they have one of the campaign advisors.
Scott: it's George tuck based on dick tuck and I think the basic guy he gets.
Rym: he has these long conversations over the phone with Someone he obviously respects and trusts who gives him a political advice named just bill and
Scott: bill happens to be from Arkansas and he's also the current president and He has some scandals and he has a wife named Ellery and
Rym: Ellery.
Scott: Yeah It's sort of obvious.
Scott: It's sort of supposed to be obvious.
Scott: It's just avoiding I guess libel and lawsuits and things like that.
Rym: Yeah, well also Well, that way they get a lot of the setting of American politics.
Rym: at the same time all the events from American politics Don't end up overshadowing what's really going on because this is not about Al Gore versus George Bush.
Rym: it's about the primaries and Al Gore and This Japanese American senator and all the other Democratic candidates all vying for the presidency for the nomination And then the presidency which that part is actually not really quite as Climactic as the primaries are.
Scott: yeah the basically the thing starts out like as the primaries are just beginning like people are just deciding if they're gonna run or not and they goes as Far as it goes because we're not gonna spoil how far it goes.
Rym: Now there's some things that this has in common with sanctuary a lot of things.
Rym: The art is similar.
Rym: I think it's a little bit simpler, but I also really like it.
Rym: It's kind of charming and it definitely it's almost nothing but inspirational close-ups of characters talking Almost nothing pretty much every single panel.
Scott: not every single panel.
Scott: but most panels are like they really highlight the person's faces and Kawaguchi is really good at drawing like these powerful faces that stand out, you know.
Scott: So you just want to look at him and they're like BAM, you know.
Scott: It's like someone's face just sort of like explodes with like the radiant light coming from it in every single panel Like someone gets up behind a podium to make a speech and it's like their head is glowing and someone looks at someone with Like a look.
Scott: that really means something that you don't.
Scott: you don't need to put words around You know, you don't need to make them say something to get the meaning across because of the way he gets the expressions with the eyes You know and stuff like that.
Scott: So it's really just panels of faces for the majority of the art and I don't really have problem with that.
Rym: yeah, plus if you flip through whenever there are people in the background or extras or just other people around and If they're ever close up in scene many times They'll all have unique faces and be very specifically drawn differently from people around them instead of just you know Faceless people in the background.
Scott: Yeah, all the non faces are sort of drawn.
Scott: I guess normally I mean the proportions of the bodies are pretty accurate and you know, you don't go.
Scott: Hey, why is that guy arm half as long as the other arm and stuff like that, but it's not particularly Striking in any way.
Scott: It's it's pretty standard stuff.
Rym: But you know another thing that really makes it similar to sanctuary is the look.
Scott: there's an ad for sanctuary in the back of this Volume of Eagle really?
Rym: Yeah Wow But anyway there in sanctuary there was definitely this trend where anyone who opposed the main characters would eventually either die or Join them.
Rym: there seems to be this whole thing of like.
Rym: anyone who's smart will join the good guys in their quest and it's very difficult for smart people to Deal with fighting against the main characters.
Rym: and that sort of thing happens a lot in the early parts of both Eagle and sanctuary.
Scott: Yeah, there's a great part where one of my favorite parts is when Yamaoka goes to Texas.
Scott: Oh He's not very welcome and he goes to like you know a saloon where he's not very welcome because of his a gun control policy and then he pretty much Does awesome stuff to rally these cowboys and I won't say any more than that.
Scott: Yes I really don't want to ruin anything about this and I think it's good that I haven't read it very recently otherwise I can't ruin it because I barely The fact that I remember that scene says a lot because I don't remember many of the scenes.
Scott: I remember the basic plot and these scenes that struck me particularly.
Rym: I remember when what I thought was the climax happened.
Rym: I thought okay I know what's going on and then the manga did a 180 and then I remember sitting there thinking what the fuck?
Rym: Yeah, and then when I when they ended and I actually read the end I was quite surprised I'm not gonna say anything But there's there was.
Scott: there is a big twist at the very very end of Eagle that I did not see coming But it makes perfect sense and it's pretty awesome.
Scott: and I think without that this manga would be half as good.
Scott: and It's it makes it worth reading the whole thing Even though I think the earlier part of the manga has a lot more meat than the later volumes except for the explosive ending.
Rym: Now luckily while it's very deep politics I mean, there's a lot of talk about specific parts of the primaries or press relations and all these very very Deeply involved in politics things.
Rym: and yet you don't need to know a lot of politics to get it.
Rym: Because whenever it's kind of like when you watch a show like ER where there's a lot of buzzwords and jargon and Even if they're used correctly and even if you don't really know what they mean all the ER use medical terms correctly sometimes.
Scott: Yeah, and CSI is real detective work people.
Rym: I guess hornblower is a better example.
Rym: But you'll get the sense that you know what's going on and with the context you'll figure it all out.
Rym: There's really.
Scott: it's very accessible.
Scott: You can understand what's going on without being a political expert and for in fact without knowing anything about US politics.
Scott: I mean, this is a manga.
Scott: This is made for Japanese people who know a lot less about American politics than even like an American high schooler is supposed to.
Scott: So it's it's not hard for you reading this translated into English to know what's going on
Rym: But sadly the one thing that doesn't really bother me But definitely colors my perception of reading this is that it feels like it was written From the perspective of someone who saw events happening and understood how things work in politics But didn't really understand how things really work because it's so idealistic and it's so yes This good person will prevail.
Rym: Yes it if you give a good speech and you're passionate then people will care and it seems to.
Rym: I Wish American politics were like Eagle.
Scott: Oh god, you don't know how much I wish American politics are like Eagle.
Scott: cuz I'll be the president Book right here.
Scott: that tells me how to do it.
Scott: All right, so if you want to get Eagle, it's not I'm not sure.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: it's not in print I'm pretty sure of that but it is also not hard to find.
Scott: I actually see this a lot more often than I see sanctuary now.
Scott: It's printed by Viz back in the day and it reads left to right which is fine because you know sure I'd rather have it be right to left and I'd rather have but Was supposed to be facing the rising Sun but now he's facing the setting Sun.
Scott: Yeah, and I'd rather have it.
Scott: You know keep sound effects intact, but really there aren't that many sound effects.
Scott: So it's not you know, it's not the action book here It's mostly a political talking book.
Scott: But there's this printed as far as I know Eagle in two different formats.
Scott: in one format consisted of many smaller books like.
Scott: the books were maybe like I don't know 20 or 30 pages big and They're like 30 something of these books.
Scott: They're a whole bunch of them and you'll know if you see one because it'll say Eagle and it'll be about a centimeter thick Maybe or maybe even less than that don't buy those now.
Scott: You mean you might be able to get them all?
Scott: but because they're kind of like I see random ones all over the place and I'm sure if I had bought everyone I've ever seen In my life that now I would have them all or close to all of them and it probably could have picked up the missing Ones online.
Scott: but who wants 30 little tiny books?
Scott: because this later printed the entire thing in five giant books that are very relatively easy to find cheap especially at cons because people don't respect this manga and they put it on the discount rack.
Scott: and I even see them at New York comic book stores all the time and online.
Scott: I see them on Amazon and places all the time and you can just get them for like less than 20 bucks each.
Scott: five Giant books.
Scott: you can have all of Eagle all 2,000 pages for under $100.
Rym: I I can't stress enough.
Rym: if you at all have any interest in this Find the first one somewhere and read it and if you like that I guarantee you'll like the rest because it only gets better from There.
Scott: yeah, you're buying a giant book.
Scott: So, you know buy just one to see if you like it first because while we think it's awesome I don't think everyone would think it's awesome.
Scott: If you like the naruto Communist yes.
Scott: Yeah, if you like naruto and that's like your favorite thing ever.
Scott: I don't know if you're gonna like Eagle.
Scott: It's sort of the exact opposite.
Rym: I Don't know because this one fight does take most of the manga.
Scott: It's a lot of Well, his voting rating is over 9% 9%.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, he's up in the polls.
Scott: He's down in the polls OMG.
Scott: He gave a speech.
Scott: He had to eat two dinners and all the two dinners in one night.
Rym: That was one of the best scene.
Scott: That was all that I love that scene.
Scott: That was awesome.
Scott: two dinners in one night You're not?
Scott: I mean you think it's badass when I don't know someone pilots a robot with one arm and destroys an entire Battleship and loses their own physical leg and saves their best friend from dying But then the best friend dies.
Scott: Anyway, you think that's badass?
Scott: or you think it's badass when like Ken churro like punches a thousand times You have not seen someone eat two five-course meals in one night?
Scott: that is the most badass.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you Can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.