Rym: It's Wednesday July 11th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we begin convention season.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, there's no more denying it It is fully 100% con season.
Rym: Scott and I are not going to have a moment's rest Until the Monday after Otakon when we wake up on the beach and do not leave it For about nine days or so.
Scott: give or take yes something like that.
Rym: I might leave the beach after a couple of days to go play some DDR, but then it's right back to that Beach.
Scott: Yep, also might go away from the beach to just throw some money down a toilet.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I also come back.
Rym: Well the last time we threw money down that toilet a whole bunch of more money came back.
Scott: Well, you know it wasn't my fault that someone clogged up the toilet And all this other money someone else threw down there shoved right back up and into my wallet.
Rym: I gotta say anecdotal evidence doesn't mean much.
Rym: but from the perspective of the experiences of myself and Scott gambling is Awesome, and I'll just give you free money.
Scott: Well, I think I don't need to do.
Scott: we don't need to do a whole episode about this.
Scott: No, we have one thing to say about gambling.
Scott: gambling in a casino is no different than playing an arcade.
Scott: You spend money to get entertainment and then the entertainment is quick and over, you know It's like putting 50 cents in a time crisis machine.
Scott: isn't really that different from putting 50 cents in a slot machine?
Rym: Well, unless you're playing gigawing because then you can play for like an hour I know.
Scott: but the you know, the the time the entertainment you're getting is much less.
Scott: but the chance of winning money You know if you like that's.
Scott: if that entertains you then that's oh, man.
Rym: I just to this day and this has been a fantasy of mine as a kid Imagine a real arcade with real games where somehow no one will ever allow a game of skill to award you money.
Rym: I know I know but I can dream.
Rym: Yeah, I can dream Yes, but anyway cuz let me tell you Rampart world champion.
Scott: Oh, yeah the key to a casino is You have to assume that any money you gamble at a casino is gone.
Scott: You're just spend.
Scott: it's like spending money on time crisis.
Scott: You spent the money.
Scott: It's never coming back.
Scott: That's how you have to assume.
Rym: when I was a kid and I went to the arcade I had my five dollars are usually more like two dollars.
Rym: Yeah, and I put it in.
Rym: I get my tokens and I had to spend all those tokens.
Scott: So when you go to a casino you do the same thing You're putting money you turn the money into chips.
Scott: That money is gone.
Scott: Pretend the money's never coming back.
Scott: Then you go and play games with your tokens chips until you're done having fun or until you run out of tokens and chips.
Scott: and Then if you have any left over the casino just happens to be nicer than the arcade and they let you turn it back into Money.
Scott: now arcade doesn't?
Scott: that's.
Scott: that's how it works.
Rym: If you feel the urge to go buy more chips Hit yourself.
Rym: just hit yourself.
Scott: You never buy more chips.
Scott: Let's like you go to the arcade.
Scott: you put a 20 in the change machine and you don't get any more.
Scott: Same thing at the casino.
Scott: you take $200 and you say this $200 is going away and never coming back.
Rym: Now by the same you never put any more in if you get ahead by an amount of money.
Rym: That would be nice if you had yeah say a jackpot I. just if you get ahead to the point where getting that amount of money suddenly in cash would be a a Significant boon to your life.
Rym: Hey, fuck immediately.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Hey lose it all.
Scott: I just won ten grand That could pay off my car.
Rym: I will cash out now and not continue playing any games because the odds are always in the casinos favor if you have a good luck streak.
Rym: The odds are that will not continue.
Scott: because I'm if you just sit in the casino and play forever You will eventually lose everything.
Rym: That's why rich people gamble because if you have a lot of money to gamble you can ride out the bad luck.
Rym: and then when?
Rym: You have good luck Once you break even or get above you cash out as soon as you've broken even or gotten above.
Scott: Yep Of course a lot of you know, eventually you just won't get a good luck streak and you lose all your money.
Scott: Yep That's why I got us.
Scott: That's why guys who run casinos are loaded Man, we should run a casino.
Scott: We should anyway.
Rym: So so we've talked about this a couple of times in the last week or two and I like to bring it up one more Time.
Rym: we have already got two fine upstanding gentlemen who are going to hopefully put on one hell of a show for us.
Rym: We've got some guest hosts for next week for the Wednesday night show two weeks from now.
Rym: All right two weeks from now, right?
Rym: I keep forgetting that Otakon's next weekend.
Rym: Yeah, we have this other con ConnectiCon this weekend.
Rym: Yes, but yeah Our tradition starting last year was to get guest hosts of high caliber and high quality to do the show for us.
Rym: last year We had our Richard and Allison from movies.
Rym: You should see and they did a bang-up job.
Rym: This year we've got two unnamed individuals for whom I have nothing but the highest of esteem.
Scott: Well, I didn't give it away at all.
Rym: It could be Darryl and Gerald and not Clarissa because I said gentlemen.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, cuz I didn't say there wasn't a lady.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, it's definitely anime world order.
Rym: I can tell you that it has nothing to do with karate or yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, I guess I ruined it there.
Scott: Yeah, you did.
Rym: You know what though?
Rym: an ulterior motive and I'm gonna be Forthright and tell you all my ulterior motive.
Rym: All right now they can't back down.
Rym: Oh now they can't back out.
Scott: Yeah, I did.
Scott: while I am looking forward to what they come up with I did have a feeling that they would not come through and end up.
Scott: You know cuz I mean how long did it take them to do the valiant denims?
Rym: See I told them though.
Rym: They all they have to do is record the show.
Rym: They don't have to edit it at all.
Rym: I'll take care of all that.
Rym: All right, even better.
Rym: I know that they would have come through eventually because they're that way They'll always finish what they started.
Rym: eventually might take a year or two.
Rym: Yep Oh, well, so my last call if any of you out there now when I say any of you, you're all welcome to try but Seriously, we mean people who have podcast or audio experience or you think you can do a really good job with this.
Scott: yes, if you think you want to make a Monday Tuesday or Thursday episode of GeekNights and You want it to go up in the feed of GeekNights as you know the episode for two weeks from now?
Scott: Tell us don't go and make one and then send it to us because you might say no ask us first And then we'll tell you if you should make one or not.
Scott: Yes, if I guess you're free to make one if you want to but I don't want anyone to like do work and make an Episode and then us not use it.
Scott: That'll be kind of sad.
Rym: Yeah, now if you don't hear from us the answer was probably no.
Rym: that's just because we don't have time to check our frickin email.
Rym: Anymore good God you people.
Rym: The forums are beyond my control at this point.
Scott: Yes, if you sign up for the forum and you didn't get an email that said welcome to the forum Just come back to the forum and sign in.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but we water is poison has been a moderator now for a while.
Rym: He's doing a great job.
Rym: We're probably going to need some more Moderators because this is just getting nuts.
Rym: but don't ask because if you have to ask you're not gonna be a moderate and I think we Need a secretary to read our email to us.
Rym: Maybe maybe but however if we say no or we don't respond that in no way means that you were bad people.
Rym: In fact to the few submissions we've gotten already.
Rym: All I want to say is try next year.
Rym: All you got to do is have a year of experience and you'll probably be good enough.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's just a matter of experience.
Scott: Yeah, we don't want to put like, you know, so like memory we did that worst podcast episode.
Rym: Yeah, we wouldn't let.
Scott: what was that terrible terrible podcast?
Rym: what anime Paul's?
Scott: The one with the little kids, oh that one.
Scott: yeah, we don't want that to go in our feet.
Scott: I mean More power to you doing that kind of thing.
Scott: I mean, it's awesome that you you know care about us so much that you'll make a nice episode.
Scott: But yeah, we have standards.
Rym: Yeah, and I don't really mean to rag on anime Paul's you guys are cool.
Rym: It's just that You guys have been coming up in our forums a lot lately.
Scott: Is that people just keep mentioning them when they were probably one of the least worst even though in fact You still made the worst?
Rym: I would just.
Rym: I would contend that anime Paul's is better than a full majority of podcasts in the world.
Rym: Probably Sadly podcasts are usually not that good.
Rym: Yes, but I digress.
Scott: so that means they're in the top either in the top 51% Of podcasts which is bad because 90% of podcasts suck.
Rym: Anyway, oh, yeah times.
Rym: one other little quick thing.
Rym: I just want to get this out.
Rym: I'm not doing a news tonight partly because I'm really tired and partly because I have a really tired.
Rym: I have a very fancy new piece of equipment that we got air freighted overnight to us for Connecticut and Otakon And I really want to push all these buttons.
Scott: There aren't too many buttons on it I know but each one of them does a lot.
Rym: Yeah, they feel good when you press them, too.
Rym: They have that little funk of a high-quality device.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Anyway, so uh a while ago.
Rym: We did our show on Ava.
Rym: We reviewed Ava despite all inclinations that we probably shouldn't tackle something like that and We said we're gonna do a final thoughts episode complete with spoilers.
Rym: and I figured this time unlike with other shows We've spoiled.
Rym: I want to give you some time.
Rym: We're not gonna do this for a month or two.
Rym: So if you want to hear our final thoughts on Ava and you don't want to have to skip an episode of GeekNights sometime In September or October, I'd recommend watching Ava in the next few months.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta watch it again.
Scott: I haven't seen it in years.
Rym: I've seen it a good five times.
Rym: So I think I'm good.
Scott: two times maybe.
Scott: I think yeah The second time and all of those are freshman year at RIT, so I haven't seen it since 2000.
Rym: Wow God I think we did watch it twice at RIT.
Scott: I know I watched it once by myself and then once with everyone else.
Rym: we marathoned it at RIT.
Rym: I didn't stay for the whole thing.
Rym: Ah, I just subbed for someone.
Scott: I didn't do that.
Rym: Anyway, that's my news.
Rym: GeekNights stuff and to anyone who comes to the cons We're gonna talk about I'm gonna have something really fancy and I'm gonna be carrying it around and babying it and shoving microphones in People's faces.
Scott: great.
Rym: It's gonna be grand All right, so What?
Scott: two weeks ago was anime Expo and for those of you who do not know Anime Expo is the biggest anime convention in North America outside of Japan.
Scott: I think they claim to have 40,000 plus people in attendance, but we're not sure how they count those numbers.
Scott: So, you know, it could be that includes dealers.
Scott: It could be they count people for three days if they come for the whole week.
Scott: Well, actually it's a four-day con.
Scott: So, you know that that immediately adds because they have the Thursday only people coming in and stuff like that, right?
Scott: But anyway, it is the biggest con regardless of the accuracy of their attendance numbers.
Rym: granted Otakon is clear and far away.
Rym: number two It's not like.
Scott: there's any contention and I have never been west of Michigan.
Scott: I have
Rym: never been west of Chicago
Scott: yes, so neither of us have ever been to anime Expo and everything we know about it is from what we read of people's testimonies who have gone there and Things we read on the internet about the convention, that's all we know about it.
Rym: Yep this year's been a little bit of an exception just in that there was a lot of anime Expo news leading up to the con and I read it all and I was actually excited about it.
Scott: Yes, see our prior to this year Our general opinion of anime Expo was that it was a very industry convention, which is true.
Scott: it is a very industry convention and we tend to more like the Fan-run conventions than the industry convention, you know Otakon, KatsuKan.
Scott: Yes, that's why we tend to not like comic conventions because comic conventions are very industry but like mocha is very not industry.
Scott: That's why we like it so much.
Scott: So You know cuz also when you go to an industry con we could probably do an episode about industry for his fan cons.
Rym: Yeah, let's do that.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, we'll not talk about it then but our general opinion of anime expo Is that a it's big it's industry.
Scott: We don't really care about it This year.
Scott: looking at all the press releases from anime Expo online I actually thought maybe they were gonna clean ourselves up, you know Maybe they were gonna be pretty awesome this year because the programming they had lined up on paper was awesome.
Scott: They had that skin concert with I talked that was a news a few weeks ago Yeah, Yoshiki and gacked in the same band and it was crazy.
Rym: That's just that's absolutely unbelievable.
Scott: That's pretty much as big as the world premiere of a brand new band with like two of the biggest Rockstars in Japan in the same band.
Scott: That's just craziness.
Scott: So they had that.
Scott: they also had a whole bunch of other stuff.
Scott: There was like multiple concerts and and all sorts of other crazy awesome events.
Scott: I'm not even gonna list him because you can just go read the press releases.
Scott: anime Expo.
Scott: But I was very like I if anime Expo was closer I would have just gone.
Scott: be just for the programming that they said they were gonna have I would have as well.
Rym: I mean, it doesn't draw me as hard as Pax does but that's because Pax is very special in that It's really I mean while it is nominally the penny arcade expo, it's really the Rym has a nerdgasm Expo pretty much every year.
Rym: I look at packs and I just yearn for it.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, the best most enticing programming of any convention, you know for the cost of this Marantz one of us could have gone.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's cool.
Scott: Yeah, so Apparently according to the Internet's again because it's all I know about anime Expo.
Scott: So this could be completely wrong, but I doubt it.
Scott: Anime Expo did have all this awesome programming but they had big problems.
Scott: this year.
Rym: apparently these reports are Quite a bit more widespread than what you would normally get at a con because every anime con ever in the feedback and all the con Reports there's always that small percentage of people who bitch about everything.
Scott: Yeah Like oh the cosplay was not judged according to these exact rules that I wanted it to be judged by.
Scott: or the elevators were too Small for my bountiful body yes, or this panel ran five minutes short or my panel was.
Scott: we had to wait ten minutes before we could go in because The voice actors before us had a crowd around them and they would not disperse.
Rym: I love the people who are.
Scott: I can't get into this panel because I didn't wait in line early enough.
Rym: My favorite people are the people who complain about the AMV's over which the con has almost no control.
Rym: Yeah Well, I'm almost no control.
Scott: There's one thing they could do The best from the worst but they if the if the best are still crap, what can they do about it?
Scott: Yeah, not have AMV's more than what would people complain about?
Rym: the people who complain about the freaking weather?
Rym: What do you think Otakon is gonna do about the fact that it's hot in Baltimore in August?
Scott: Yeah, are they gonna move the convention to a different time of year?
Scott: Maybe when you're in school and you can't go you punk kids.
Rym: No, we'll just move up to Michigan granted It's still there.
Scott: Oh, so everyone will just complain about it being freezing cold.
Scott: or oh, it's not far away from my house I can't go.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, despite the if you'd subtract all the people who complain about any convention no matter what anime expos seem to seems to have had Huge problems.
Scott: that awesome concert we talked that I just talked about was delayed for multiple hours.
Scott: people had to wait in line outside not being able to enjoy any other part of the convention because they had to wait in line for Multiple hours before they could get in to see this concert.
Scott: and Some people reviewing the concert said while it was pretty awesome.
Scott: It wasn't super awesome, and it wasn't super long either.
Scott: It was kind of not so long.
Scott: Yeah, you wanted a concert to be.
Rym: meanwhile back at Otakon when Lark came not only did they do a complete full Just straight-up set at a concert like any arena concert and a gigantic encore, but everything happened pretty much right on schedule Yep, but that's kind of comparing apples and oranges.
Scott: Yep but also a lot of other things at this convention were constantly being canceled and delayed and moved around and We're not talking about just one concert It's it seems like the vast majority of the big events were canceled and moved and changed and delayed.
Rym: Not just that but a lot of people complain that almost all the panels got moved around or canceled or delayed.
Scott: Yeah, the biggest one at least the one that had the biggest talk going on about it.
Scott: Is there someone named?
Scott: Halkomomoe, I don't know if I'm saying it right, but apparently she's like the queen of Akihabara or something like that.
Rym: Oh, I forgot
Scott: about that I'm not exactly sure but what the story is is that she was very upset with how you know This is a Japanese guest and she was very upset with how you know her interactions with the convention staff and they basically You know weren't meeting her needs and and she like posted on her blog that she was upset.
Rym: There's something something and then obviously her PR wrangler got a hold of her and told her to retract it.
Scott: Yeah, but and whatever.
Scott: but the thing is is that basically she had to choose on like like one day of the con whether she basically had to decide between having her concert or Doing all her other events instead of just as scheduled doing all her events and her concert.
Scott: So she canceled all her appearances For one day of the con and only did the concert and didn't do anything else that she was going to do.
Scott: and she was All like apologizing to the fans and being like I will do my best in this concert for you.
Scott: These evil con staff fucked me over.
Scott: I hate them.
Scott: people were crying.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, see it's really hard to say how much of that might be a pampered guest verse I mean, I don't know anything about very hard to tell from a blog post across the world.
Scott: You know if this is a pampered guest who is upset or if con logistics dictor over or a combination or who knows what.
Rym: one thing I find interesting is that I was poking around in the Anime Expo forums and there's a lot of outcry there and people demanding answers and demanding an explanation and all sorts of things and I couldn't find many if Any responses from the staff.
Rym: in fact?
Rym: There's a bunch of people trying to get together To go over to where the staff is located where their place of business is and knock on the door and try to get an Answer.
Rym: Oh, I don't know if the responses are official somewhere else But I got the impression that the staff was kind of hiding from the con.
Scott: I don't know, you know impressions on the internet don't tell us anything.
Scott: I have no idea what the reasons were for all these problems.
Scott: I don't know who to blame.
Scott: I don't even know any of the staff.
Scott: I don't know anything.
Scott: but I do know is that the con had major problems with a lot of events.
Scott: that is absolutely true.
Scott: that is what happened and I thought poorly of Anime Expo before and I still think poorly of them no matter how awesome their programming is and they're Not doing too much to fix that.
Scott: and if someone across the country who's never been to your con and it's someone who likes cons Thinks poorly of your con.
Scott: That's pretty poor.
Rym: Meanwhile, I got to say I'm more and more impressed with Katsucon every year.
Rym: Oh, yeah It's fast becoming my second favorite or favorite con.
Scott: Katsucon was very awesome and I only went to one of them.
Rym: Yeah, I've been to three and I will admit though on the second Katsucon I went to I achieved for about six hours epic level drunkenness.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: It was quite an experience.
Scott: I think that's Katsucon's thing though.
Rym: It is that's why I like Katsucon.
Rym: There's a lot more people my age.
Rym: I can go to a bar and just chill with a bunch of older anime fans But it's not a hentai con.
Rym: no, it's not like that Rhode Island things gonna be.
Scott: yeah, we'll see about that.
Rym: I have high hopes for that.
Scott: I just I My cynicism low expectations, but a lot of hope.
Scott: cynicism greater than optimism exactly at least for that.
Rym: things of the day.
Scott: a long time ago, I had a thing of the day, which was Miotd.com.
Scott: it's a website that is mecha image of the day and every day they have a mecha image and it's.
Scott: it's a really awesome Site.
Scott: I subscribe to the RSS feed and it's really good.
Scott: Well, my thing of the day today is a Particular image from the mecha image of the day on July 9th.
Scott: They put up this picture and it's a picture I feel like I've seen before But I'm not sure where I've seen it before it.
Scott: I'm sure some nerd out there can tell me but this image is a mashup a really good mashup that looks a lot like.
Scott: Basically it combines like a Hildebrandt brothers Star Wars movie poster with a picture of a bunch of nerds in the front row of a concert and Star Wars and a concert where the Star Wars characters are Making a rock band of themselves and it's if you like Star Wars at all.
Scott: This is something to see.
Scott: but my only question is why is this a mecha image of the day?
Scott: I mean sure the droids are back there and Darth Vader's there, but it's not a mecha image.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I don't think it matters.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: Every geek should see this picture.
Rym: That's the three things I will point out about this picture that are awesome.
Rym: Number one.
Rym: Darth Vader is awesome.
Scott: It is always awesome.
Rym: number two Han Solo the way he is Engaging the crowd is awesome.
Scott: He's always awesome.
Rym: Yeah, and number three notice the guy in the audience with a lightsaber.
Scott: Yep Basically, if you're a geek of any kind, it's just a picture you need to see.
Scott: that's why it's a thing of the day Right.
Rym: So, uh, imagine a Zerg rush.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Now imagine a Zerg rush where the target is not a human or a Terran or whatever, but Some poor kitten.
Rym: that's a pretty scary image, isn't it?
Scott: I mean one Zerg can kill a kitten.
Rym: one Zerg could take both of us out from this room Handily, that's why I'm so afraid of real-world Starcraft.
Scott: Yeah, but remember if real-world Starcraft happens We'll have all those Terran equipments watch.
Rym: We don't we're just normal people.
Rym: the Terrans come from space.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, instead of the zombie apocalypse who's no different than alien?
Rym: no, yeah, you know what that would also kill us?
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I think I could take alien cuz I've As long as I had those equipments, you know, as long as you don't.
Scott: yeah, I played enough natural selection.
Rym: The problem is we don't have those machine guns that have a billion bullets.
Scott: That's what we.
Scott: if there's aliens we'll have those.
Scott: that's how it works.
Rym: All right, so now take you have flamethrowers I've just given you but replace the Zerg with eight an enormous number of Corgi puppies and it is one much safer.
Rym: They're much easier to take out.
Rym: but I got to say this is one of the most adorable things I've ever seen.
Scott: Yeah, it was all right.
Scott: The thing I don't like the problem is they don't zerg rush enough.
Rym: It's just yeah It devolves into just puppies playing and then puppies sleeping.
Rym: you can skip all that But the first bit you might think that's just like two or three puppies and that cat just looks mildly annoyed.
Rym: Just wait for it and watch until the cat gets away and you don't really need to watch the rest.
Scott: But not the best animal video.
Scott: not as good as turtle attacking cat, but I don't know.
Rym: I like.
Rym: I like this more than turtle But that's just because you like turtles more than me.
Scott: Yeah, it's not so not as good as rabbit attack snake.
Rym: No, it's not because that is still the baddest ass rabbit ever.
Rym: Yeah, like a rabbit that lives in a lion's den Why do you like that turtle?
Rym: It's not you I don't like to do.
Rym: Oh random cute animal.
Rym: But this one was particularly cute and the fact that they called it a zerg rush meant that I had to talk about it.
Rym: Okay, so it's con season.
Rym: like we said we're not gonna rest until The Monday after Otakon and then none of you are going to hear a peep out of us until the Monday after the Monday after Otakon,
Scott: so we're gonna spend this episode telling you what cons we're going to here and what we're doing at those cons.
Rym: I guess we'll go in chronological order sounds good to me.
Scott: So this weekend this weekend as in July 13 14 15 we are going to be at Connecticut 2007.
Rym: Connecticut is located at the what Hartford Convention Center.
Scott: I think that's if it didn't move willing to the website.
Rym: I'm sure you can find it.
Scott: I've got a convention center on Columbus Boulevard in Hartford, Connecticut on July 13 through 15th 2007. now
Rym: we are going to be there Friday But we're pretty much going to have a few drinks with friends and go to bed The reason being that over the course of Saturday we are doing six live shows and then on Sunday We are doing a seventh and that is the minimum that we will be doing at this con.
Rym: There's probably going to be more.
Rym: Yeah, this will be a big test of our voices because for those of you who saw us at Otakon last year by Sunday We had lost our voices to the point that we had to medicate and I point out that Scott doesn't fucking take Medicine ever.
Rym: well halls doesn't really count so much as we took the mentholated halls and we took far more than a doctor would have Led us probably.
Rym: Yeah, we had to drug ourselves to be able to do the let the panel on Sunday.
Rym: We had lost our voices so badly Yeah, and now we're doing seven.
Scott: Okay, so which seven are we doing?
Scott: Let's open up the cons kid.
Rym: well mostly pretty much all day Saturday if you want to have a GeekNights event, we're either gonna be in a panel or Outside of a panel preparing for another panel.
Rym: We're doing a podcasting and internet radio on Saturday from 12 30 to 1 30 in panel 2.
Rym: I don't we need to.
Rym: we don't need to say where they all are.
Scott: No, we don't need to say where they all.
Scott: you'll see The con schedule.
Rym: Yeah, suffice to say we've done this panel like three or four times.
Rym: There are in fact two or three examples of it in the feed already.
Rym: We're doing it partly because they were interested in it.
Rym: They haven't had anything like that before at Connecticut And I think Connecticut's probably a good match for it because there's probably a lot of people there who are really interested in podcasting.
Rym: I don't know a lot about it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Oh, we're doing the how to run an anime club right before that Yep Which we have run along with our friend Scott Johnson the legendary Scott Johnson as featured in new type.
Rym: We've been running this for like five or six years that pretty much every freaking con Yep, so if you want to know how to run an anime con or not an anime con anime club We run this everywhere.
Rym: It's mostly for people who haven't seen this panel already Yep.
Scott: All right after the podcasting internet radio panel that we're doing An hour and a half after that or so, we're gonna do the anime match game for two hours.
Scott: It's gonna be like the deluxe anime match game of super awesome at all time.
Rym: Not only is this gonna be awesome Not only did I write twice as many questions.
Rym: Not only did I get rid of the crappy questions Not only did we add so much to this, but we have got a lineup of celebrity guests from the con.
Scott: Yep, yes, whoever is the best guess at the con is who we're gonna get.
Rym: so we're not gonna.
Rym: it's not gonna be the usual Alright.
Rym: so Scott's on the panel along with Dave and Joel and whoever we could drag up five minutes before the con.
Rym: Yeah, this is gonna be some awesome guests.
Scott: Yeah These are gonna be like guests of honor at the con or official guests of the con are gonna make up our panel at the match Game worst case.
Rym: it's gonna be a bunch of cool webcomic artists, which is always hilarious.
Rym: Yes, so Scott Scott and I will probably take turns sitting as these six panelists.
Scott: Yeah, so we always seem to do.
Rym: That's always hilarious.
Scott: Yes, but this will be something you do not want to miss.
Scott: In fact looking at the schedule like it completely dominates everything running concurrent with it.
Rym: So yeah plus we've run this a lot over the years and I think this is going to be the best one because we have prepared more for this anime match game than we have for enemy Any anime match game we have ever run?
Rym: Partly because we're not running it at Otakon like we'd are offered to.
Rym: so we're gonna use all the Otakon awesome here.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right shortly after that.
Scott: We're gonna do the challenger on fire beta test.
Rym: Yes, I noticed this is also in the big panel room.
Rym: So this should be awesome.
Rym: We're not sure how this is gonna work and I haven't finished it yet.
Scott: Yeah, basically challenger on fire It was the thing of the day a long time ago some Japanese game show where you have to name a hundred anime characters.
Scott: Well, we wrote a piece of software there so that we are would be able to run this game in some in the best fashion we can without our own custom studio and We're gonna try to run this game.
Scott: This is gonna be a beta test though.
Scott: We've never done this before.
Scott: We don't know how it's gonna work.
Scott: We don't know how to run it smoothly.
Scott: Yeah, we're basically gonna practice running it to see.
Scott: you know Try to figure out how to make it work at other cons in the future.
Scott: So if you want to be a part of a first ever con event that will possibly become a very popular con event in the future.
Scott: This is something you don't want to miss.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Kinetic con has been very gracious in allowing us to test this So I'm really looking forward to it.
Rym: I think we're gonna get a lot of good feedback and it'll be fun because think of this Either we're gonna run it awesomely and you'll all love it or We're gonna totally fuck up and you'll get to laugh at us for an hour straight.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I'm glad it's only an hour.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, cuz I don't know how many of these I'm gonna finish by then.
Rym: I got a lot of work to do still.
Rym: Yep, partly because of my odd emergency room adventure over the weekend.
Rym: Anyway, then later on that night.
Rym: We don't have all the details yet, but we're going to be running guest interviews Ourselves.
Rym: so there's gonna be guests of the con who normally when a con guest has a panel They just kind of sit there and wing it.
Rym: or maybe they have someone from the con try to guide him.
Scott: Well, we're gonna do or they have people from the audience.
Scott: That's the same dumbass questions over and over what we're gonna.
Scott: How did you become a voice actor?
Scott: How do I become a voice?
Rym: What's your Inspiration?
Rym: probably the crappest question you can ever ask anyone at a con ever.
Scott: What's the favorite thing you've ever worked on?
Scott: Yep What are you working on now?
Scott: I?
Rym: Like to see the weird question, I like to see the questions where the guy goes what.
Scott: yeah Those are my kind of quest.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: But anyway, we are going to be setting up and it's not our panel.
Rym: Really We're just the moderators.
Rym: we're going to be interviewing some of the guests of the con in front of everyone and Probably recording these for posterity and hopefully our goal is that we can guide these interviews into being awesome.
Rym: We want to bring out the shine of these guests.
Scott: This is not a panel for us So imagine if you listened to like an episode of GeekNights where we had a celebrity guest like the and we interviewed Them all awesomely right now.
Scott: This panel is basically gonna be that only live and in person.
Scott: So if you like listening to an episode of GeekNights where we cleverly and awesomely interview a celebrity guest
Rym: I'd like to point out particularly the Luke Crane interview creator of burning wheel
Scott: because they haven't done too many interviews even though I got really good at them all of a sudden while interviewing Luke Craig.
Rym: Yes It was really amazing because Scott had never really interviewed someone like that before and he went from suck to awesome in about two questions.
Rym: And the rest of that thing is Scott did a really freaking good job And I really I've listened to that episode twice twice because I enjoy it.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good episode.
Rym: It's also because I was actually pretty drunk while you guys were doing the interview So I was pretty much just sitting there watching the levels the whole time.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not saying but if you want to hear some of that kind of awesome This is a panel to go to.
Rym: so after that kind of late night also on Saturday We are running the beta version of gecky guy putting the man back in manga.
Scott: Oh, yeah We've been thinking about doing this panel for a long time.
Scott: It's an actually what probably our only panel.
Scott: that's actually an anime manga panel.
Rym: Yes, and I will point out we'll talk about this in a bit But this is our prime time event at Otakon and we're running it at Otakon with None other than Gerald from anime world order
Scott: Gerald Rathcole
Rym: who assures us that while we're gonna coordinate the whole panel He has something special lined up for the last 10 minutes.
Rym: Oh, man, and he's hinted at what it is, but I'm really looking forward to it.
Rym: I think I know what it is, but oh man, so at ConnectiCon it's not gonna be that exact thing.
Rym: We're not gonna have Gerald.
Rym: I don't think he wants to fly up for this But I don't.
Scott: yeah, he's not gonna come from Florida to ConnectiCon.
Rym: Basically, if you've listened to our show at that rink eating long enough.
Rym: I like ConnectiCon.
Rym: it's actually bigger than you'd think Yeah, but it's not.
Scott: it's it's too small to be worth coming from Florida for.
Rym: yeah, I'm not gonna lie to you But anyway, what we're gonna be doing is kind of our half of this panel.
Rym: We're not gonna do the kind of 18 plus super crazy humor.
Rym: We're gonna do just more of a half history of manga half what this geeky guy is and more importantly We're just gonna talk about all those Genres of manga and all those manga that are out there that you probably haven't read that are probably really up your alley.
Rym: A lot of people maybe not you because you listen to our show and anime world order and you know all about this But there's a lot of people who don't realize that there's manga other than pretty boys and pretty girls and show Joe.
Scott: yeah, I mean you go to the bookstore and Basically what happened in the u.s.
Scott: And manga I just knew this really quickly is This is I'm gonna probably say the same stuff again at the at the actual panel is that they originally brought manga to the u.s.
Scott: you know you know all the crazy violent stuff the stuff that went along with the anime and Viz did it actually first and Dark Horse soon after and Most of it was ignored.
Scott: It didn't sell very well.
Scott: It sold to the comic crowd a bit and it didn't make a big splash.
Scott: So they only kind of kept doing it you know at a very slow pace and in the comic book in the u.s.
Scott: comic book format and such and Then someone decided they're gonna bring over some show Joe in the digest format namely Tokyo pop and as you know it exploded.
Scott: The thing is people realizing that hey We can make a lot of money by bringing show Joey and shown and jump type stuff shown in fighting stuff Over to the u.s.
Scott: In this format and make a lot of money off of it.
Scott: and there's so much stuff in that format.
Scott: They don't even bother to bring over anything else unless you know Because they can make plenty of money with just bringing over the same old stuff.
Scott: The end result of this is they'll go to the manga section of the bookstore and they think that manga is Girly-girly and shown in fighting and nothing else.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The true end result is that awesome manga I forget the name of it But Emily told me about it is by the same guy who did eagle and there's some natural disaster that splits Japan in two And it's nothing but politicians and Yakuza arguing and looking dramatic.
Rym: That's so up my alley.
Rym: I could cry.
Rym: the fact that that kind of manga almost never gets released over here is Probably one of the biggest tragedies of the manga industry in the u.s Yes, so we are going to tell you about as many of the manga or you know We're.
Scott: I think we'll go in depth on a few of them But maybe we'll probably mention a whole bunch of others.
Rym: We're gonna talk a lot about the history of manga and Tezuka and where the term gecky guy kind of came from and all that Stuff.
Scott: Yeah, you probably heard at an anime world order if you listen to them This panel isn't so well isn't for people who listen to podcasts for people at the con who you know.
Scott: Yeah, I put the man back in their manga.
Scott: Yeah, cuz basically the man back in their manga.
Scott: the read manga.
Rym: Part of the reason we named it what we did is for the ironic tongue-in-cheek Nature of because we expect a lot of people to come in expecting something very different from what we're going to do.
Rym: Yep, however, I will note that at Otakon they're going to get half of what we're going to do now and half Exactly what they expected.
Scott: But that's why that's gonna be 18 plus and that is why this Saturday at ConnectiCon is gonna be crazy because we're doing all that in one day.
Scott: We're going.
Rym: we're doing 12 solid hours of entertainment.
Rym: Wow from 1230 p.m.
Rym: Until 1130 p.m
Scott: Wow,
Rym: and then if we survive because remember the one cool thing about ConnectiCon are the awesome after parties and I might have to not go to them even though I know of some really cool ones, but Anyway, if we survive Sunday morning, we're running a panel on German board gaming.
Scott: Yep, basically the panel We're just gonna.
Scott: we're gonna?
Rym: no we're not.
Rym: No, we're not.
Rym: we're gonna croak miserably into microphones Cry.
Scott: we're gonna attempt to tell people who don't know anything about German board games and if only played Monopoly and such About the wonderful world of you know, Euro board gaming.
Scott: and it just so happens that ConnectiCon has an excellent gaming room But you can go and play these games.
Scott: So hopefully we'll be able to convince a whole bunch of people who don't who say German board game That sounds interesting and then we'll be able to convince them to go and play them right after the panel.
Rym: ConnectiCon has better gaming content than a lot of gaming cons.
Scott: It sure does.
Rym: In fact, I'd go so far as to say ConnectiCon is half gaming con And I'm probably gonna give away a board game or two because I happen to have a few board games laying around that are either Unopened even though they're awesome because I already own them.
Scott: or that you don't want or that I don't want.
Rym: Yep I'll make it very clear which is which.
Rym: yeah, so thus ConnectiCon this weekend is going to be awesome.
Rym: If you were fans of us, yep.
Rym: However, if you want to hang out with us I will warn you that we will probably not have time to say hi at ConnectiCon.
Scott: no, probably not.
Scott: I mean maybe Friday night depending on when we get there, which I imagine might be 9 10 ish something like that.
Rym: Yeah, give or take we're probably gonna show out of bed get our badges and go straight to freakin sleep.
Scott: Yep, and Sunday after the German board gaming panel, you know I don't know how long we're gonna hang around.
Scott: We'll see what our plans are.
Rym: Yes, because you realize that pretty much right after ConnectiCon we have not a single moment of rest.
Rym: And then we're gonna be at Otakon ready to run.
Scott: Basically three days of work after ConnectiCon is over and then leave.
Scott: don't go to Otakon BAM.
Scott: It's gonna be that crazy.
Rym: so, uh Otakon I'm not gonna get into the issues that they had with panels But partly due to the fact that we're friends with a few people on the staff Yes,
Scott: we'll see how this turns out and I'm tell I guarantee you despite our favor for Otakon and our enjoyment of it We will not be dishonest in our reporting if things go poorly.
Rym: However, we did despite the snafu of panels managed to secure four panels at Otakon as well as an artist alley table.
Rym: Now one of them is gonna be with all the other Podcasters because I submitted it and they apparently also wanted to submit it.
Rym: So I basically rolled them both into one and then handed it back over to them.
Rym: But it's no big deal.
Rym: It's gonna be all our friend podcasters.
Rym: We're gonna sit around and shoot the shit in front of a crowd for a while.
Scott: Yeah, that'll probably be an off-the-cuff kind of panel.
Scott: be a lot of fun.
Scott: You know, if you like anime podcasters, there will be a lot of anime podcasters.
Scott: They're talking about anime podcasting.
Scott: Yeah, possibly other anime manga topics.
Rym: We did this almost exact panel at sitcom and I recorded it.
Rym: the recording was unusable But now we have the Mirand so we're probably gonna get an awesome recording of it.
Scott: Yep, so this will.
Scott: even if you don't show up at Otakon You'll probably still be able to hear that panel on the internets in someone's feed.
Scott: Yep Maybe not ours, but someone's now.
Rym: the second panel that we are responsible for but we are not actually running is a panel entitled kendo exclamation point.
Rym: Basically, our friend katsunori Matsushita is a yondan.
Rym: I believe a yondan.
Rym: I don't know how to say Alright, let me put it this way.
Rym: He is a badass motherfucker when it comes to kendo.
Rym: He's a certified instructor.
Rym: He was the friend the kendo club at RIT.
Rym: He trains in kendo.
Rym: Last year there were some kids playing with bokuto and shinai outside of Otakon and they were trying to spar with each other And it was kind of dangerous.
Rym: so katsu walks over and says can I spar?
Rym: and the guy says sure you ever done this before?
Rym: and katsu says once or twice and I'll find the pictures whenever I get a chance to post him up.
Scott: We got to get a video the next time.
Rym: There are two frames of interest.
Rym: frame Number one is katsu standing there and the other guy looking very aggressive trying to hit katsu.
Rym: The second frame is a shinai one Nanometer away from this guy's eyeball and the guy screaming like a girl and falling over.
Scott: katsu didn't even hit him.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's really awesome when you see him swing the stake because it's like the other guys.
Scott: they sort of you know They don't know how to really sword fight or kendo or anything, you know They they just kind of you know feel like they're mimicking movies or whatever.
Scott: And katsu just swings the stick really hard and really fast and he moves right in on you Like wicked fast like he's standing there and the next second.
Scott: He's like swung the stick five times in your face.
Rym: We have both tried to fight with katsu and it doesn't end.
Scott: well Yes, but standing off to the side and watching it there is not much that is as amusing I believe.
Rym: the question.
Rym: the guy that he owned asked afterward and I quote what is he?
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so so if you want to learn about kendo a relative I mean, he's not the kendo master of the world.
Scott: his dad is yeah But he's effectively a kendo master of some level far beyond the vast majority of kendo people in the world.
Rym: So he's gonna talk about the history of kendo.
Rym: He's gonna talk about the techniques and all that and the schools.
Rym: He's probably gonna demonstrate a bunch of training and a bunch of moves and most importantly Safety because a lot of kids hurt themselves with their stupid swords that they don't know how to use at the con.
Scott: Yes, and it's gonna show you how to be less stupid.
Rym: if the con will allow it at the end of the panel There's a good chance that katsu and I will end a long-running feud.
Rym: The longest story short is that katsu was the president and ruler of the RIT kendo club.
Rym: that we all found it a bunch of Us not me.
Rym: Yeah, not not Scott but a bunch of the rest of us in some political subterfuge at the at RIT.
Rym: I Awesome because I felt a lot like sayonji and all that business from utana.
Rym: It was an honorary position that technically was supposed to go to the most skilled person in kendo.
Rym: So the president was elected.
Scott: You know the person who ran the president and the vice president be the same person.
Rym: if that were the case Then the vice president be the second best person.
Rym: Okay, but due to the fact that I founded the club along with all of them for a good year I was the vice president because the rule was you have to challenge the vice president and I never showed up to the kendo club practices.
Rym: so, uh, that was a dishonor that has been lingering for a long time and Katsu a long time ago challenged me for the title and I have yet to fight him.
Rym: So if the con will let us and if they won't we'll probably do not some sort of liability insurance action Yeah But if they won't we'll probably do it at some point in our travels.
Rym: Katsu and I will have a short sparring match to demonstrate.
Scott: basically Rym will hold the stick up in the air Drop the stick and run away.
Rym: I can't run faster than him.
Rym: That's my only power.
Rym: It's my secret attack.
Scott: Well, you can run fast to them as long as you turn around.
Scott: if you're sort of standing there He can like.
Scott: he shuffles really quick.
Scott: That's like the sword shuffle.
Scott: It's kind of surprising like you blink and he's right there Yeah, but like actually running like, you know in a marathon not so much but standing flat-footed and then suddenly being like 10 feet Forward like like snap you're 10 feet forward.
Scott: It's like whoa, it's like Pretty cool.
Rym: So then we're not running it.
Rym: But again, this is one that I've spoken on pretty much every Otakon I've ever been to is the how to run an anime club.
Rym: we're usually Scott sits in the front of the room and Corrects people who make mistakes and answers questions kind of willy-nilly and I said I'll probably just sit there going?
Scott: Ah, I won't even be there.
Scott: who might sit at the artists alley you are?
Rym: You should probably go because I really want to send our reporters out to report on all the other panels.
Rym: Yeah, because I we need some ammo for our proposal a modest proposal to Otakon But it's usually a good.
Scott: I really don't want to go to a lot of those panels though We need to send other people to get report.
Rym: I know I mostly want to spend my time like I usually do in the live-action video room Yep, but our friend Scott Johnson runs this every year and it's usually a pretty good panel.
Rym: It wasn't great last year, but there were issues and I think it'll be a lot better this year.
Scott: Yep, so if you care about running anime clubs This is pretty much the premier how to run an anime club panel ever so you should go to it now.
Rym: last and most Awesome.
Rym: We are running gecky guy putting the man back in manga.
Scott: All right, we talked about this already cuz we're running at ConnectiCon but we are running it at Otakon.
Rym: We are running it at Otakon as far as I can see on Friday night from like midnight to 1 in the middle of the panels and it's gonna be 18 plus.
Scott: Oh man, sorry for you under 18.
Rym: Yes This is gonna be one of those because we realized that at Otakon the 18 plus primetime panels are Standing room.
Rym: only hundreds of people turned away.
Rym: Yep So we kind of wanted this panel to be 18 plus even though it didn't really need to be.
Scott: However, we could have easily made it not 18 plus.
Scott: we're doing that at ConnectiCon.
Rym: However, the fact that Gerald from anime world order is involved.
Rym: I think by Fiat makes it 18 plus.
Scott: Also the fact that you know be by making it 18 plus be intent, you know, but we didn't have to.
Scott: we just Intentionally put some 18 plus stuff in there Which I think will not diminish the content of the panel because we will keep that content there But we will add extra content.
Scott: That will be Humorous.
Rym: in fact, I'm gonna let you all in on a secret because our audience is not you.
Rym: our audience is people who don't know About this stuff.
Scott: Yes most of the I gotta be honest a lot of the reason we're running so many panels at cons is To tell everyone who comes to our panels and enjoys it They should fucking listen to GeekNights because it's just like coming to our panels every day four times a week.
Scott: So we're gonna pull an Ava and if they're willing to pay money to go to a con to listen to our panel Then they'll sure as hell download a free mp3 four times a week to listen to our panel.
Rym: What we're gonna do is pull the bait and switch the panel.
Rym: Look, it's gonna be 18 plus putting the man back in manga.
Rym: People are gonna expect something horrible because the panels going at the same time are all hentai panels.
Rym: Yep, or yaoi or whatever.
Rym: Yep, so we're gonna be in the sea of yaoi and hentai and all these 18 plus people.
Rym: So they're gonna come in expecting the kind of thing that you get from an 18 plus panel and they're gonna get that.
Rym: But they're also gonna get a good half of the panel is going to be very informative And we're going to try to trick them in and then teach them about Real manga and history of manga and Tezuka and all that stuff
Scott: and hopefully industry people will be there Recognizing that.
Scott: look see how crowded this panel is.
Scott: there is a demand for the manly mangas.
Scott: freaking bring them over here.
Scott: You could probably get them real cheap because no one else wants them.
Rym: I will point out we are not actually sexist.
Scott: However, putting the man back in mom I think we're gonna have a big disclaimer at the beginning of this panel even at ConnectiCon because we're gonna say a lot of sexist things Just because a lot of the gecky guy is sexist and pretty horribly.
Rym: That's.
Scott: but while I disagree with the sexism It's entertaining and that's sort of one of the things that makes me like those sorts of mangas.
Scott: Yeah, it's like how I can like Death Note, even though I can't agree with Death Note at all.
Rym: I think what the moral is going to be is do not come to our 18 plus gecky guy panel if you are easily Offended by the knowing it by the ranch as know-it-all something.
Rym: Holy Daryl Surratt anything.
Rym: Yeah, Daryl Surratt.
Rym: Yes, if you're offended by Daryl Surratt do not come to our panel.
Scott: Yeah, at least not a gag that one come to the other one.
Rym: Yes come to the other ones.
Scott: Also at Otakon we have a table in the artists alley.
Scott: it's a table in the way back near the bathroom.
Rym: We actually traded with someone else who practically begged us to move.
Scott: Yes, but they were also near the bathrooms.
Scott: all our friends who have tables are spread out all over the artists alley.
Scott: I looked at the map.
Scott: So we're not gonna have like a podcast alley within the artists alley or anything like that, which is sad Maybe next year, but there will be things to do at our table.
Rym: Yes All I'm going to say basically
Scott: what we're gonna do is when we're not at an event or running an event We will be at the table and possibly we're gonna try to arrange it so that most of the time at least one of the front row crew will be manning the table and You can come to the table to get you know, talk to us or meet people or hang out or whatever.
Scott: we're also at Otakon going to arrange an informal meetup at some point probably like last year and More information on that once the Otakon schedule comes out and we know what time we should do that.
Scott: I Supercons This week is the last week of episodes of GeekNights.
Scott: next week is gonna be like three episodes Maybe and the week after that for specials and we need people to You know make episodes of GeekNights to fill in that week of four specials or else you're gonna get Episodes you're gonna get last year last year.
Rym: Yes Granted some people really like those episodes.
Scott: Some people did like those episodes.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I like it poked in the eye - yes They like the episodes that someone else made for us more than they like those episodes.
Rym: Yes, and I just want to say again that Richard and Allison from movies You should see did a really good job and they're really cool people.
Scott: Yep We'll see.
Scott: Hopefully people do just as good this year.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all The RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.