Rym: It's Wednesday August 15th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we explain how we would handle panels for a large anime convention.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So check this Multifaceted leader bit out.
Scott: you ready for this?
Scott: Okay, let me start a little bit before so I can lead into it.
Scott: So I'm on the train to work.
Scott: get to Grand Central.
Scott: I got a poop so I go to the bathroom in Grand Central and I poop and Bathrooms not the greatest there But it's better than the bathroom on the train basically have to wait in line to get a less smelly But also smelly bathroom.
Scott: so anyway I then go down to the subway, and I get on the subway train And I go and I go and I go and I go and then the train is pulling in to the station Where I get off and standing in front of me are two women.
Scott: They're they're obviously complete strangers and neither of them have any Acquaintances or accompanying people.
Scott: they're they're alone all right and One woman one of the two was fat and a dignit.
Rym: You know it's funny because when I got to work Scott messages me and basically says oh, man Why I got something to talk about on the show tonight, and he wouldn't tell me what it was But you said it happened.
Rym: you know something with this commute and all I could think was you know It's not my commute because I said it when I got to work.
Scott: Yeah, when could it have happened?
Rym: So all I can think is it's probably Either some like a shooting or something or it's some big fat indignant person.
Scott: So this fat indignant lady is getting in the face of the non fat non indignant lady.
Rym: I'm going to already declare.
Rym: Who is the right party?
Rym: Who is the wrong party right now?
Scott: I basically didn't hear anything that either of them said.
Scott: not basically no words right.
Scott: But I watched them because it was interesting and I was getting off anyway.
Scott: And they also got off and the fattening dignit woman was getting fatter.
Scott: Well, maybe not fatter, but more indignant and more crazy.
Rym: You know she probably was actually getting fatter.
Rym: I bet she had a scone or something for breakfast.
Scott: Maybe I don't know how you could lose weight when you're expending.
Scott: gain weight when you're expending that kind of energy But you eat that much food.
Scott: Maybe she wasn't super fat, but she was a fat person right.
Scott: so then you know We're going for the exit.
Scott: which of those you know this turnstiles that stupid people fuck up.
Scott: You know the ones that are open all the time because you can't jump over them.
Scott: They're they're straight through and the non indignant person goes through not saying anything Completely ignoring the indignant lady and just walking which is what I would do.
Scott: So I was like hey that lady's doing what I would do completely ignore this crazy lady and go to work.
Rym: was the indignant lady Still yelling or something?
Scott: she was yelling and doing whatever?
Scott: and then when the non-indignant person went through the turnstile the indignant person like Grabbed it to try to hold them in there and yell at them.
Rym: whoa That would have.
Rym: for me that would have been a punch to the face and a call to 911 Probably, but the the non-indignant lady just kept walking to work.
Scott: she just kept going.
Scott: nah, so I go through the turnstile, and I'm following behind and The indignant lady begins to assault the non-indignant lady like really yeah, she like grabs her hair.
Scott: Then and whatever right.
Rym: once again, I would like to stress that if a stranger grabs my hair They're getting a broken nose something like that, and then the police are coming, but anyway the non-indignant lady She just kept ignoring the indignant lady.
Scott: She was sort of laughing and she kept walking as much as she could despite being assaulted And I thought to myself should I do something?
Scott: I could do something it wouldn't be hard But should I?
Scott: and I thought back to the only similar incident we're at experience Which was the the purse snatcher, and I said in that situation Someone was being assaulted by someone else And it was perfectly legal and right for the people around who had nothing to do with it to detain The bad person.
Rym: I remember that story being great because more people came to stop and or in some way harm.
Rym: The purse snatcher then could hop possibly have helped so everyone ended up just standing around.
Rym: well like two guys got it
Scott: Basically I stayed close and I waited for the moment and The non-indignant person took the indignant lady cell phone and kind of tossed it into the street not like out into the street You know cars running over it, but like you know out on the curb.
Scott: That's a pretty good diversionary tactic and then just kept walking and then I sort of grabbed the indignant lady.
Scott: I detained her for like 15 seconds or so until the non-indignant person got away Just by walking.
Scott: she wasn't running or anything.
Scott: She was just walking and sort of going.
Scott: ha I didn't hear a single word that either of these people said at all.
Scott: I have no idea what was going on But I was watching them the entire time from on the subway when nothing was happening and no one was doing anything to One person clearly assaulting another person who wasn't doing shit, and then after about 15 seconds I just let her go and the only words I heard any of them say was after I let the lady go.
Scott: she said You see what she did to me, and she didn't say it to me.
Scott: She must because she wasn't looking at me.
Scott: I don't think she looked at me the whole time.
Rym: indignant people never seem to make eye contact with anyone.
Scott: They just come in there behind her.
Scott: cuz I was doing the old.
Scott: you know the full Nelson without applying for it.
Scott: You know the yeah full Nelson where you can't hit me, and you'd have to kick me, but you're fat So you can't possibly kick me.
Rym: She could have just fallen over backwards.
Rym: You would have been fucked.
Scott: No, I would have been fine, but you're in front of that gas station at the house did in Bleecker Lafayette over there wait Wait what did you say you were in front of like the only gas station?
Rym: Scott every time we talk about the city always ends up bringing up Yeah, there's no gas.
Scott: there are the number of gas.
Scott: there aren't zero gas stations But they are very very sparse.
Scott: and if you need evidence just go to this gas station and see how many Taxis go there because where else are they gonna go?
Scott: Anyway, so I gotta say the most disturbing part.
Scott: I mean that's not really an eventful story.
Scott: someone was indignant and was assaulting someone And I detained them for a short time, and then it was over.
Scott: and that was it right.
Scott: not very exciting But I got to say two things three things actually.
Scott: number one Touching that indignant lady was kind of disturbing.
Scott: I mean she was fat, and it really felt like she was just like I was holding her.
Scott: You know I had my arms around.
Scott: you know the under her arms and back around.
Scott: Her arms felt like they were just soft and flabby from skin to bone like there was nothing there And she didn't try to resist me either.
Scott: and if she did I didn't feel like thing Like not at all like not even a slight pushing, so it's like she was just accepting me restraining her there.
Rym: I don't know what maybe for all that blubber.
Rym: She didn't actually feel you.
Scott: Maybe I have no idea, but you know.
Scott: eventually you know.
Scott: after the other person was away She's like all right.
Scott: Let me go and just let her go.
Scott: I went to work And there was a guy at the get.
Scott: after that there was a guy at the gas station right just didn't you know?
Scott: a normal?
Scott: Gas-station kind of guy yeah, and he's like hey, man when people are fighting you just let him fight.
Scott: She could have had a knife or something.
Scott: that fat lady I was like.
Scott: I was like.
Scott: I knew she was all right, and I said you're afraid of her And he didn't say anything after that.
Rym: wow you own that guy.
Scott: yeah I should have said something like you're a coward, but I think no afraid of her is fine enough.
Rym: That's good enough.
Rym: Yeah, I think I would have handled the situation all told a little bit different.
Rym: probably.
Rym: The only difference is right way.
Rym: as soon as she touched the other lady I probably would have interposed myself and called for the police.
Scott: yeah the thing I realized though is like for something like this.
Scott: calling the police means I probably have to deal with shit.
Rym: Oh, no that seat.
Rym: That's fine cuz one.
Rym: I have an excuse to not be at work now?
Scott: No I don't want.
Scott: I'd rather go to work than deal with the be between the police and an indignant lady.
Scott: That is not where I want to be.
Scott: I want to go to work That.
Scott: I thought about that and also right.
Scott: I wasn't gonna wait around with these people for the police to show up when obviously the assaulted person didn't give a shit.
Rym: They just wanted to go to work and be done with this person as I could not blame them true But at the same time I feel like it's my civic duty to make sure that indignant people Get stripped of most of their dignity.
Scott: I think she was pretty undignified.
Rym: No Because you realize that people like that The dignity that they have left is pretty much just that they're still wearing clothes And they're not in jail Because they can't feel the shame of all the things that they do beyond that.
Rym: so unless you get them arrested or somehow naked There's nothing you can do anyway.
Scott: The last bit I want to add to this the meta bit that make that I think is more interesting than everything else is that While I was sitting there thinking about what to do right.
Scott: I was considering.
Scott: You know all the things I already talked about considering and then such you know and Basically one thing that entered my consideration was man if I do something that'll make a great opening bit Ah, this is our cast is gonna.
Rym: Get us killed.
Scott: I don't know so I Thought about that for a while, and I said hey whenever we see famous people doing crazy shit And you're like what the fuck is wrong with these people There's probably something a lot like what I just thought like hey This will make a great opening bit going through their minds And they might not be as insane as we all think
Rym: it's the.
Scott: hey when I get on letterman I can talk about this or something who knows, but it sort of adds a little bit of explanation to why?
Scott: Famous people or other such people do things that we would say wow they're fucking nuts What's wrong with them?
Scott: and they get all over tabloids even though half of that stuff isn't true, but the stuff that is true It's like why are these people doing it living these crazy lives?
Scott: well because they're considering things like this.
Scott: You know it'll make a great opening bit or similar things that normal people since you're not famous And you have no reason to ever consider those things.
Scott: They don't enter your mind, and they might even actually be thinking hey I'll do this crazy thing.
Scott: I'll be in People magazine or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I will say I don't think that that's Tom Cruise's motivation.
Scott: No, I don't think so either, but I do think that you know it made me realize hey famous people Slightly less crazy by a small amount than I thought.
Rym: I just want to reiterate that we here at GeekNights 100% dislike fat indignant people.
Scott: if you're fat and Indignant we don't like you.
Rym: you're pretty much at the top of the list.
Rym: you either You should either get unfat or get unindignant probably both at the same time because someone who's just indignant while they are very Very annoying they're not also fat.
Scott: and while someone who is like yeah The lady if it was an indignant lady and a non indignant lady, and they were both not fat it wouldn't have been Disgusting to have to detain one of them.
Rym: I think my order of hey of dislike of humans is pretty much at the top.
Rym: people who commit genocide And then indignant.
Scott: I don't know there are worse things you could do than genocide like well alright people who personally commit genocide.
Scott: Well, no you could just be completely indiscriminate and just kill millions of people for no reason with no nothing.
Rym: That's genocide just against humans.
Scott: well genocide is specifically when you're like killing one race or one.
Rym: yeah one race humans.
Rym: I'm just not good at it.
Rym: Okay, it's like in D&D when a ranger takes favored enemy human.
Scott: all right sure whatever.
Rym: But really it's like indignant people who are also fat and right under.
Rym: that is just indignant people.
Rym: and then fat people Oh, maybe people who smoke in the street in front of the building.
Rym: I'm trying to walk into it.
Scott: They're pretty bad.
Scott: They're usually also fat and indignant.
Rym: I always love the guys cuz there's always a bunch of them where I work smoking Right outside the door to the hospital that has a big you know law.
Rym: no smoking within 50 feet of the hospital.
Rym: sign right.
Scott: Why doesn't anyone do anything?
Rym: cops walk by and harass them periodically, but all right and they go away.
Rym: And then more people come and immediately start smoking.
Scott: they should paint a line around the thing that says you cannot smoke within this line.
Scott: Here's the best, and then if you smoke within that line They just take you to jail for a whole day.
Rym: the thing is Technically because of that you can't smoke anywhere in those city blocks cuz it's all hospital.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: Oh, yeah I'm fine with that too, but but they should draw a line and say if you smoke within this line You go to jail for 24 hours, and you know what in jail no smoking.
Rym: now I wouldn't jail him.
Rym: why not?
Rym: because there's a much better way around this and that is to one take away their cigarette And then to find them some ludicrous amount thereby enriching the city's coffers.
Scott: I think you could find them and put them in jail so that will be without cigarettes for 24 hours.
Rym: Anyway, what do you got in the news?
Scott: Okay, so this is actually a I guess a serious news if you care about this person Or if you care about people in general.
Scott: there's an artist for Marvel Comics I think for Marvel But it is a comic artist a famous underwear pervert comic artist named Mike Wiringo, and he died from a heart attack.
Scott: He was like 40 something or a heart disease and It seems like you know at least in my life.
Scott: I don't know about other people's lives.
Scott: There's a lot of dying of heart disease of middle-aged men.
Scott: It's sort of common, and you should watch out for it like my uncle and my friend's dad My other friend's dad, and yeah, and this guy so middle-aged men in America Heart disease dying not good I think it.
Rym: a lot of that has to do with poor diets lack of exercise sedentary lifestyle.
Scott: partially I'm a high-risk.
Scott: I think in my I am.
Rym: I'm quite certain that you are a moderate to high risk for heart disease related death Even though my cholesterol is just fine.
Scott: anyway for now.
Rym: You're young.
Scott: the thing is this guy's art is really not so bad.
Scott: Hey, I've looked.
Scott: I have a. I think I have one of his comics somewhere.
Scott: I think friendly neighborhood spider-man something.
Scott: It's it's alright It's good stuff.
Rym: So what's he done?
Scott: He did Like.
Scott: I think he started off working on the flash in like 93 And he did like a recent Fantastic Four miniseries And a whole bunch of stuff, and he's pretty good at the arts, but unrelated to this guy dying You know prematurely I guess if you want to call it that I Realize something else.
Scott: when you start looking at comic creators at least American comic creators You know artists and writers of underwear perfect comics from DC and Marvel.
Scott: most of those people I mean sure right some of them are not, but most of those people are middle-aged guys Who like underwear perverts?
Scott: I mean, I think I know one or two female artists or writers of underwear perfect comics from Marvel or DC And I know like if you look at some of the better ones like Brian K Vaughn he's younger than a lot of the other guys the guy who writes DMZ.
Scott: He's also younger than a lot of the other guys and I think that that is one of the main reasons now that I realize it It's sad that I realized it because a guy died but unrelated I realized that part of the reason underwear perfect comics are kind of stuck in a rut is because you have this one demographic of people Doing the large majority of the creative work on them.
Rym: Yep in fact I despite the fact that I mean the comic industry seems to really be trying to Kind of come back and take a stand against this manga business and actually sell some comics.
Rym: Regardless of their success or how we think they should do things differently It still just seems that there's unless they change something which might in the end just involve a whole new crop of artists and writers Coming in.
Rym: they're slowly going the route of sci-fi fandom.
Rym: Yeah, I mean sci-fi fandom not to disparage sci-fi or sci-fi fandom But it has definitely gotten into a rut a very deep ruts Yeah, and when I looked out me go to a sci-fi convention.
Scott: and I realize when I look at all the other comics the non Underwear pervert non Marvel non DC mainstream comics in America like the indie comics and the manga the creators are Sort of a lot mix of genders a mix of you know Different ages, you know, you got young people you got old people you got all sorts of in-betweens and it's not just one demographic of people.
Scott: and I think that's a One of the strong reasons that the other sorts of comics are coming up with all the better ideas instead of doing the same thing over and over again.
Scott: because Comics are one of those mediums where there's a lot more Making it for yourself than there is in other things, you know when someone in Hollywood makes a movie They're making that movie to make money.
Scott: They're not making a movie because the director really likes the movie He's making.
Scott: but in comics when people write or draw comic There's a good chance that they like the thing they've written or drawn and it's you know it's partially.
Scott: they really wrote it or drew it for their own enjoyment to suit their own tastes.
Scott: and When you have one set of tastes doing most of the creative work like 90% plus you're only gonna get one kind of comic.
Rym: So in other news, it looks like the New York Anime Festival is once again doing everything Right, or at least as far as we can tell because they've already announced at least one of their musical acts.
Scott: Oh so early I mean the cons not until December.
Scott: they must be on the fucking ball.
Rym: Well considering I mean, we're pretty much already set to go with the New York Anime Festival.
Rym: But yeah, they've got unicorn table which according to the anime news network a j-pop band of some sort or j-rock.
Rym: I don't know Japanese pop rock.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's a j-prock j-prock j-prock.
Rym: But yeah, I mean, I don't have much to say about that.
Rym: But what I do have to say is that if you live anywhere in the New York City area It really might be worth your effort in December to come check out the New York Anime Festival at least for one day.
Scott: Yeah in short I used to think that the I'm still skeptical and I thought that the anime the New York Anime Festival was going to be a Complete and utter failure because it's run by the same company that runs the New York Comic Con.
Scott: It's for profit.
Scott: It's in the Javits Center in New York in December and all those things are like, whoa That's not a good formula for an anime con.
Scott: The
Rym: only reason it's not a good formula It's just that if you've been to anime cons anime cons aren't like any other kind of convention and Just the things that people do at them and the way the crowds react to things and the things the crowds expect to be there.
Rym: If you don't know you don't have any sort of expertise as to exactly how to deal with these people You're not gonna have a good time running a con.
Scott: and the environment.
Scott: I mean in the winter bad weather in the Javits Center bad convention center for profit lots of money.
Scott: Things aren't gonna be run this the way they're run at a fan-run convention Pissing off a lot of the goers who are used to fan-run conventions.
Scott: It's not a good recipe, but They have gotten my hopes up because they have said apparently it appears to me from information I know that they are outsourced.
Rym: You know, we've already talked about this a bunch of time.
Rym: Have we?
Rym: Yeah, okay I wasn't gonna bring that up.
Scott: They're outsourcing a bunch of the stuff to people who know how to do it.
Scott: It's like, you know to other people.
Rym: Well, it's not just that it's more that they're also just looking Asking people who do run these cards, you know.
Rym: So, how do you deal with anime fans?
Rym: and they seem to really have done their research on this crowd?
Scott: Yep, so I think they're gonna do Maybe the best they can given the unavoidable circumstances.
Rym: I think it's gonna be a pretty good con.
Rym: I mean we're gonna be set up.
Scott: we have an artist that would be fun for me whether or not it's fun for you and worth Your money.
Rym: Well, we've got an artist alley table.
Rym: Dave and Joel said they want to come with us and do some stuff, but they haven't gotten back to me since then.
Rym: So, I guess I'll light a little fire under their collective ass, yep, and yeah, New York anime festival We're actually gonna go to it.
Rym: We'll talk about it a lot more as the event comes up.
Rym: I mean, it's It's many months away But suffice to say we are running our match game times two and we're running a panel somewhat similar to the one We ran at Otakon, but with a much more educational bent and a much less Rape.
Rym: tacular vents things of the day.
Scott: This thing of the day combines so many things.
Scott: I think it is the ultimate thing of the day in terms of things.
Scott: it has you ready.
Scott: It's from the TV in Japan blog, of course Japanese television always saving the day on Wednesday when I have no better thing of the day to go for.
Rym: yeah coach speak for if we're lazy search for Japanese TV There's gonna be something.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So get ready Don't.
Scott: this is it's a Japanese TV show that shows guys making stuff with Legos.
Scott: That's pretty crazy Alright, so you got Legos and get Japanese TV.
Scott: What else do you have here?
Scott: Well at the very beginning of the first video, I hear some Paul Paul Oakenfold music going on.
Scott: So you got some trance.
Scott: there's another geeky thing.
Scott: now you've also got the they're making one guy makes like a Like a otaku maid like a maid and so there you got.
Scott: you got otaku and moe going on.
Rym: That's kind of creepy yeah,
Scott: but most of the people make animals and robots and that sort of thing and it's a seven part video and I'm linking to where there's only parts one and two but then they have a link to parts three through seven on a YouTube channel that you can go do and If you like Legos Japanese TV and all sorts of nerdy stuff all in one.
Scott: This is quite a thing of the day.
Rym: So we talk every now and then about how anime music videos used to be funny.
Rym: You're awesome back in the day and we're sick of a lot of the ones we see at cons.
Rym: now here is one of the anime music videos that we showed at the RIT anime club a long time ago to raucous applause and Thunderous laughter.
Scott: This is one of the funniest and most creative Music video.
Rym: now part of the channel music video is that it was made really kind of craftily on bad equipment and poorly.
Rym: It's not the most technically well done.
Scott: The resolution is low.
Rym: I mean you think YouTube's making it look bad.
Rym: No, it looked that bad.
Scott: It's a pretty bad video.
Scott: I think I had a flash of it originally.
Scott: I don't really remember but it's a low quality video.
Rym: The thing is it it's proves that if you have the core idea for a video that's good enough and you do enough clever things With the music to make it match in a good way a video no matter how craftily it's made can be awesome.
Scott: So I mean people made videos back in the day like the Jeff de Teric with like two VHS decks and they were.
Scott: some of Them were great.
Scott: So there's no reason why a low resolution low production value video can't be awesome As long as the concept and the execution of the concept are awesome.
Rym: granted I still think and I've said this before that the only reason we say music videos suck today Is that due to the ways that anime conventions handle their anime music video contests?
Rym: It almost self selects against the good videos because they usually won't let you enter their contest if you've already won somewhere else.
Scott: Yes, if I was gonna say I said it before I'll say it again If I ran an anime convention ahead at any decision-making power over the AMV contest My anime convention would only allow you to enter your video if you had won a contest not entered But won a contest within the since the past.
Scott: is you know edition of my convention?
Scott: So if I had my convention on August one every year if you video didn't win some award
Rym: If you video
Scott: if your video didn't win an award at another convention, that wasn't mine since August 1st last year I'm not gonna let you show it at my convention because it didn't win an award.
Scott: It sucks.
Rym: I think there was an easier way to phrase that.
Rym: yeah, the video had to have won an award within the past year?
Scott: Oh something like that.
Scott: Yeah, I got to be real specific though because you know these people?
Rym: no You really don't because people don't really harp on you about things like that.
Scott: No, but they you just see people.
Scott: Yeah, you imagine if you're running an anime convention?
Rym: No, no your list of rules.
Rym: if I was running if I was actually running it then yes I'd write the rules that way, but if I was describing the idea to someone you got cuz.
Rym: yeah I mean we actually Alex and I actually laugh at you a lot about this just because whenever we talk about a board game and You like you find out about a board game that we don't know about and you want to tell us about it Instead of telling us the core idea first you go on for like 10 minutes about the minute details that we don't care about.
Scott: I got to be real specific.
Rym: No You don't tell people about you.
Rym: jump on me anytime if I if I leave something out or if it's vague you like oh But you start with the guy or you got to sell it on the car the sell the idea on the car.
Rym: like How about a music video contest that only allows the best music videos in the ones that won contests recently?
Rym: Not imagine you Within the last year.
Scott: Well, what if your convention was like a year and a week ago?
Scott: And I might convey my my video won an award in that week.
Rym: tough shit.
Scott: Uh-huh doesn't matter You see where I'm going.
Rym: Yeah, I see where you're going.
Rym: All right, but anyway Speaking of running anime conventions we've talked about doing a show like this for a while partly because I don't want to bother writing an email to certain interested parties as To how I would do this.
Rym: but you all know that Otakon had some trouble with its panels department this previous year.
Scott: and Not only did Otakon have trouble with their panels department But pretty much fan run cons all cons that I've been to anime cons at least Gaming cons to in general cons a million times worse.
Rym: Yeah We won't get into that.
Scott: but cons in general that I've been to in reason that how many years we've been going to cons?
Scott: a long Time.
Scott: they always either have panels that are run Sub-perfectly for whatever reason it might not be the fault of people running them but panel either panels that are run with some problems or the quality of the panels is low.
Scott: and while You can't guarantee quality of panels.
Scott: when the panels are run by fans you can raise the bar.
Scott: it is possible.
Rym: Well, I mean the real thing is I mean, I'm not.
Rym: these are people running things for fun.
Rym: They're like fan panelists.
Rym: I want to run a panel about Naruto and whatever and that's really what it's all about.
Rym: But at the same time cons don't really seem to worry about Checking these people out at all or making any effort to find out if these people are actually going to run a panel if they Even a shred of professionalism if they even know about the topic they're doing their panel on if they're even gonna show up.
Rym: and this isn't an indictment against Otakon because A lot of people think we're talking about Otakon.
Scott: We're not because it the recent problem, but we're not.
Scott: we're talking about all cons.
Rym: yes, because Otakon's problem wasn't really that there was a specific problem that happened before the con in the staff.
Rym: and Despite that all cons most of the fan panels are just really crappy and unprofessional and and they usually end up either being the one mumbly guy who shows up spends ten minutes in front of the assembled crowd fiddling with his laptop because he can't make It work and then mumbles about Resident Evil for an hour.
Rym: Or it's like the ten guys all sit up at the front and kind of make inside jokes at each other for an hour.
Scott: Yep, and while not all of the fan run panels are like that there are Too many that are like that.
Scott: and even if cons do do some of the things that we're gonna talk about To filter out some of the bad panelists and such they're not doing them well enough and they could be doing it better.
Scott: and we're Gonna tell you right now in this episode if we were the gods of running panels at an anime a fan run Convention anime or otherwise this is what we would do to make the panels awesome Guaranteed with such an incredibly small chance of failure like the convention center would have to set on fire to fuck it up.
Rym: now A bunch of the you know how we're gonna set this up for one.
Rym: This is not just like Oh pie in the sky.
Rym: if we had the resources This is what me and Scott together could do for an anime convention straight up without any impact on our lives.
Scott: Yep, you can almost consider this an offer To any anime convention that wants someone to run their panels.
Rym: Well, it's nearby any large anime convention.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not gonna run it.
Scott: I could run panels for a really small convention.
Scott: take me a day.
Rym: Well, the second thing is that we're assuming that this is a large anime convention.
Rym: What are the bigger ones?
Rym: because I mean if a con is really small and like 4,000 or 2,000 people show up You can't really pick and choose because you're probably going to get less panel applications than you have panel time.
Rym: Anyway, but I kind of like Otakon or Katsucon.
Rym: they're so gigantic and So many people want to run panels that you'd think they could pick and choose a little bit and at least get you know The above-average panelists overall over time.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I understand with something like the artists alley, right?
Scott: You might be thinking it's you know artists alley is first come first serve which is as it should be.
Scott: but you know, you might be thinking well if the panel should also become be first come first serve and Artists that you know, if you're gonna pick and choose for quality on panels You should pick and choose for quality and artists alley which sort of seems wrong But they're sort of different in that the artists alley is sort of like that you're selling tables so Choosing who you're gonna sell to is sort of like discriminatory.
Scott: Whereas choosing who gets to be an entertainer You know, it's it's not the same thing.
Scott: Don't make them equal.
Scott: I could make a better case, but whatever.
Rym: Well, it doesn't matter because we're really narrowing this down.
Rym: The other thing is we're not going to talk about industry panels guest panels any of that.
Rym: We're going to assume that either we'd had we can handle that on our own or that Another part of the staff body of our fictional con.
Rym: We'll call it con con.
Scott: Yeah Industry and guest panels are basically sort of this automatic thing.
Scott: if industry or guests want panels they get them that we schedule them before We schedule anything else.
Scott: they take precedence the end of story And we also we make sure that the industry and the guests don't screw up their panels.
Scott: But usually they're very professional and they don't.
Rym: so of course The first thing we have to talk about is communication because no anime con does this as far as I know and I'm really surprised.
Rym: Why don't they just use Google for domains and Gmail for domain?
Scott: I have no idea why they don't use that because I've noticed and I used to think you know There's so many overlaps between geekeries, you know It's like video gaming people.
Scott: they tell anime people tend to like video games video gamers tend to like technology and computers, right?
Scott: But it doesn't go all the way across and anime people are mostly not Technology people and they really have a hard time with computers.
Scott: I'm always surprised at anime people who like they don't know much about computers.
Scott: They know how to go on YouTube and 4chan and it more than the average person But for the most part they don't know shit and they should listen to ignites Mondays.
Rym: Yep Now I'm not gonna get into all the details of why we would do that.
Rym: We could do a separate show on that.
Rym: even you know exactly why I can't should use Gmail for domains.
Rym: But suffice to say we would set it up so that whatever, you know panels at con con comm goes to both myself and Scott and Goes to the head of our department and to the con chair.
Rym: now maybe in a separate folders or a separate tag So they don't see all those messages.
Rym: But if Scott and I suddenly die all those messages are still there are.
Rym: also if there's a problem Higher ups in the chain of command can look at what we're doing Because of course we are obligated to use our con addresses for any and all correspondence related to the con.
Rym: None of it so many cons.
Rym: they'll be like panels at the con comm but then whoever's running the panels will decide that they want To use their AOL account and they'll tell people.
Rym: Yeah, you should contact me this way instead and that's crap and unprofessional.
Rym: I'm not gonna say anything beyond that.
Scott: Another thing is that we would make sure Because whenever I send an email out Let's say I'm the panels guy and I get an email at panels whatever and I reply to it I will bcc it to panels at whatever.
Scott: that way my the people above me in the ranks of the cod can see the emails I am sending out as well as in and They will.
Scott: they should be monitoring me as they should be monitoring all the staff.
Scott: They are directly responsible for.
Scott: maybe Not actively, but if they see that I'm not responding to emails, you know within a day or two If I don't get on that I should be fired and someone else should replace me as should any Position that requires communication with the public.
Rym: now also along those lines very clearly and stated on the website everywhere we would say and in any correspondence we even have a little footer that would say if you email us the panels guys and You don't get a response within 48 hours Email us again.
Rym: If you do not get a response to that within 48 hours Alternate contact info that goes to someone higher up than us who can kick our asses.
Scott: yep, and if you know it pretty much the only way that system can fail is if the entire chain of you know command and the convention is irresponsible and doesn't check their email if you.
Scott: This goes for anything conventions or not.
Scott: If you have an email address that is public and is You're requesting people, you know to email it for whatever reason.
Scott: Let's say you're accepting job applications or your.
Scott: Yeah, you're asking for feedback on an RFC or who knows what.
Scott: you should be checking that email address all the goddamn time Constantly.
Scott: no one should ever email you and then be worried that you didn't get it or not Knowing if you got it or you get you got to put up the auto away messages.
Scott: when you go on vacation You have to do those things.
Scott: if people email you and that they don't know what the status is and they are forced to wait More than like 48 hours to know what's going on at least an auto confirmation email or something.
Rym: Yes, what?
Rym: I would do no matter what even if I couldn't respond right away say we're super busy with stuff Even though I'm reasonably certain that even for the largest anime con I could personally respond to any and all emails that came into the panel's email address.
Rym: I I also could within 48 hours with two of us.
Rym: we could do it super easily But I'd have a couple of boilerplates ready.
Rym: that basically said I've received your email.
Rym: We will get back with you within X amount of time.
Rym: If you don't hear from us within X amount of time email us again or contact this person.
Scott: the number one problem I have with pretty much all so communicating with people I don't know on the internet professionally is that I email them and they just never reply.
Scott: and I know I email them.
Scott: It's in my out.
Scott: It's in my sent emails box.
Scott: The address is correct.
Scott: What what's wrong with them?
Scott: check your email?
Scott: If you're not checking your email, you're not cut out for the job.
Scott: Do something else is not for you.
Rym: Well, like last year, you know We did all these cons and all our shows everywhere and the only con we wanted to do things at that We didn't is the.
Rym: it was anime next because I emailed them like four or five times.
Scott: I even one of the guys who runs amv's at anime next is a listener and I met him at Otakon And I know him and he he's kind of cool and even so didn't help anything.
Rym: Yeah, just no one ever responded to any address.
Rym: I sent anything to with that con.
Rym: So eventually I just said fine We're not gonna bother giving you guys our content and I like anime next.
Rym: But unless they contact us, I don't know if any of them listen.
Rym: They're never gonna get us there.
Scott: I told you one of them listens.
Rym: Yeah, maybe other of them should.
Scott: maybe they should but Respond to email all the email addresses that are on your website.
Scott: if someone emails any of those they should get some sort of response Very quickly.
Scott: You should not leave anyone hanging ever for any reason.
Scott: There's no reason email is so easy.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: learn to type now?
Rym: Obviously the exceptions to that are like the super high staffers like the con chair and the whatever the con chairs job is not to Respond to even the people who shouldn't be dealing with the public directly on a day-to-day basis.
Scott: and in that case But I'm saying it's so every email address.
Scott: It's someone's job.
Rym: No, I'm saying even with those It'd be pretty easy to have a boilerplate that basically says you should probably contact someone else for your concern.
Rym: Yeah, all right, even so all right.
Rym: The second thing is time now.
Rym: I don't think is out of the realm that I would say that say the con ended this past weekend and You know con con and the next con con is a year from now.
Rym: I would start planning the panels About two weeks after the previous con ended.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's not like if you know that you're going to have another con and it's not some question mark sort of thing Why not get started on panels immediately?
Scott: I mean, you know that you're gonna need, you know, many many hours of panel entertainment.
Scott: Why not give people an entire year to get ready for it?
Scott: There's no reason not to start right away.
Scott: in
Rym: the very least The first thing I would do is now we'll talk about How I would decide who to contact later when we talk about what to do at the con, but I would email Everyone who did a panel that was good in some way based on the metrics we had and basically say all right You did a good job get in touch with us Once you have ideas for what you might like to run next year and I can pretty much guarantee that will give you high consideration.
Rym: Yeah I'd maintain relationships Relationships with all the people who did good panels in previous years and I keep in contact with them throughout the year to make sure That if they want to do something and I think that what they want to do is good and I know they've done good things In the past that I am there to help them do the thing they want to do.
Scott: But on the same token if someone did a bad panel I would make sure to know who they were and not let them do a panel again Even if they ask and are very nice and professional.
Rym: Yes, we would definitely have the good list and the shit list.
Rym: now These would be private and internal and secret.
Scott: Yes You don't tell people that they're on the shit list of the good list, but you just you do it.
Scott: You know, there's no what's wrong with you.
Scott: The other thing is that remember we were just talking about Responding to emails in the same way that the con has to respond to emails very quickly and efficiently.
Scott: So do the panelists if I email panelists and they don't get back to me.
Scott: They're.
Scott: just forget about you.
Scott: If you're you know, you're not if you don't respond within the dates that I set.
Scott: if you miss the deadline by you know A day forget you.
Scott: I got other people Yes more people who want panels at this con.
Scott: it could do a good job.
Scott: Then there are is time for there to be panels.
Scott: Therefore I have no problem just kicking people off for the slightest reason.
Rym: now early on You know for the months after the previous car, you know kicking people off then because it's it's so early.
Rym: Yeah, the deadlines would pretty much be like I'd set a point like maybe a month before the con whereupon Panelists must maintain either semi constant contact like once a week.
Rym: I'm gonna email you to check on your status and I want you to respond to me.
Rym: Of course, we could set up considerations for I'm going out of town for two weeks before the con But I'm committing to being there and those kinds of people, you know, you make exceptions But I would know everyone's situation whatever that situation was.
Rym: the moral is be documented if I Cannot get into contact with a panelist in the month before the con and I try and I give and I don't know where they are.
Rym: They're not getting a panel.
Rym: and if they show up the con and say I thought I had a panel Well, they're not getting one.
Scott: Why didn't I hear from you when I emailed you?
Scott: I didn't hear from you.
Scott: I thought you let you I thought you died or I could.
Scott: I couldn't guarantee that you were gonna show up and do this panel So I just canceled you.
Rym: now Along those lines if a panelist, you know gives an application and the email address they give me is not valid in bounces I am NOT going to attempt to contact them again, and they do not have a panel.
Scott: Yeah, basically there's you have.
Scott: As long as I was at a big enough con where the demand for panels was less than the supply I would basically Well, I think you mean the other way around.
Scott: No, the demand for panels is less than the supply of time to do panels in.
Rym: oh you mean the demand of people.
Rym: What what demand are you talking about?
Scott: There are more people who want panels.
Scott: the demand I.
Rym: there are panels to give out because normally it's the demand.
Rym: as in how many panels does the con need?
Scott: I'm talking about demand from the people not demand from the con.
Scott: All right, so the con has a greater as Less of a demand.
Scott: whatever you get the point.
Rym: There are more panelists than panel slots to fill exactly.
Scott: Yes, then I would have no qualms about just canceling panelists and eliminating them for even What would some people would consider to be slight transgressions?
Scott: I mean if I say this is the application form to fill out to apply for a panel and someone fills out the form improperly I'm no second chances.
Scott: You're done.
Scott: Oh, no, I really throw those in the trash.
Rym: I mean it depends on how much how many panels we need.
Rym: it does because I would probably email them back and say All right, you did not fill the form out correctly.
Scott: try again, yeah, it depends, you know, but if it's if it's deadline time Oh, yeah, it's.
Rym: it's not enough all this, you know being harsh with panelists And if you're not in contact and you can't we can't talk to you and you don't fill things out, right?
Rym: Then you're done.
Rym: That is all reserved for the month before the con.
Scott: the point that I'm trying to make is that I'll be much more harsh Than conventions currently are Because if I was you have no reason not to be more harsh.
Scott: That's the way to up the quality is to cut the wheat from the chaff.
Rym: now in terms of the applications themselves I would probably set up if the con could get it.
Rym: I mean a lot of con websites are really piss-poor behind the scenes.
Rym: But some sort of panels application on the website I could make it because I have the knowledge to do so Yeah, it's just a matter of it could be integrated properly with the convention website.
Rym: Yeah But aside from that I would also in addition to that have a link on that page to a template in Various formats and that template you could just fill it out and then email it to us.
Rym: So there's two ways to apply for a panel.
Rym: now the template itself.
Rym: the way you have to apply for a panel Would be a lot more than most cons ask for.
Rym: I mean certain unnamed cons have in the past Basically asked us what our names were and what the title of our panel was and they didn't ever respond.
Rym: And then we showed up at the panel and sure enough there we were.
Rym: we had a panel listed.
Scott: just by telling them our names And our panel title they were able to decide which panels to have and which ones not just based on the titles and the names.
Rym: Now we're talking.
Rym: they didn't even respond and confirm.
Rym: We assumed we didn't have a panel.
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of better not even trying.
Rym: I showed up at the con.
Rym: I was like, yeah, we're guests and they just gave us guest badges.
Scott: great.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: Sadly a lot of cons are like that But that's again.
Rym: That's a totally different issue.
Rym: Yeah, and I can say that Otakon is good about that.
Scott: They are but Pretty much the application form would have your names and I would not allow you to put the names of you the contact person and their email address and your phone number and The names email address and phone numbers of all the other Panelists and I would never.
Scott: I would have a limit on the number of people you could have as panelists now Maybe like four.
Rym: I think four is the absolute maximum I would allow.
Rym: now, of course that is on the application.
Rym: Obviously someone could convince me this panel requires more whatever But I will say that it has been my experience that any panel that is more than four people on it is almost Invariably now again only fan panels not industry or whatever going to be shitty.
Rym: Yep, but again, that's a case-by-case basis thing.
Rym: But in terms of contact information.
Rym: one person is applying for the panel.
Rym: They will give me a list of all the panelists they expect or if they don't know that right away Then the number of panelists they expect to have.
Rym: yeah And they will give me if they can an alternate contact person in case I cannot reach them.
Rym: but suffice to say They're gonna have to give me contact info and if they don't respond They're probably not going to get a panel and two.
Rym: they have to apply with their real name.
Scott: Mm-hmm Not you know, Joey Jojo Shava dude.
Scott: That's not gonna work out Right.
Scott: next they got to give me the panel title or what?
Rym: They'd like the panel title to be or at least the topic of the panel.
Scott: Yep, then they got to give me a description of the panel and I'm not talking like this is gonna be a panel where I talk About Robo tech.
Scott: that's not gonna cut it.
Rym: You need I need some paragraphs here possibly essay quality stuff I think for this, I mean we're talking about the initial applications.
Rym: I need two solid paragraphs that describe what you want this panel to be what bases you want to cover how long it should run What resources you're probably gonna need or expect to need all that sort of stuff?
Rym: Yep, and then along right after that There's another section kind of your con essay where you have to tell me what cons you've presented for in the past What panels you have run what clubs you have run what the experience you have?
Rym: Maybe you have a public speaking degree or something.
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: basically I want to know what credentials you and or any other panelists have.
Scott: that Try to convince me with you know, your credentials why you're a good panelist.
Scott: if you say yeah I ran this robo tech panel at my local con for like 10 people and it was a huge hit Let me run it at your con.
Scott: I guess that's better than nothing.
Scott: but you're not gonna beat out the person who went to Japan and studied anime and is fluent in Japanese and wrote wrote a book on it and His public been a public speaker and etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: I'm gonna pick them before I pick you now Obviously you don't.
Rym: I mean it's not like oh if you don't put anything there or this is your first panel.
Rym: It's not like we're gonna discount you out of hand.
Rym: That's not from the truth.
Rym: The point is that you're.
Scott: I mean if you're asked if your description of what the panel is sounds awesome And I contact you and you're awesome It doesn't.
Scott: it's not gonna matter to me that you never did a panel before cuz I can tell that you're awesome.
Rym: This is all basically just the pre selection.
Rym: It's kind of a you're trying to sell us on the idea of I want to run a panel.
Rym: Is there any reason why we should give you this panel?
Rym: Is there any reason at all?
Rym: and even if you say, you know, I've never run a panel before but I've prepared this and this And I think I can run a good panel.
Rym: if someone runs arts a paragraph of why they think they can run a good panel Even if they've never run one before that's already a thousand times more than most cons asked for.
Rym: yep.
Scott: Also, I would make sure to advertise all over the place not just on the internet But elsewhere to make sure the people knew that.
Scott: you know Here's the panel application.
Scott: anyone can fill out this Application because if we're gonna be so much more harsh than other cons in deciding who gets a panel and who doesn't We're gonna need a large quantity of applications to filter through that way.
Scott: after our harsh filtering There are enough left over to fill out the con schedule.
Rym: Yes because I see this a lot in con forums where there'll be the thread about Panels for the next con coming up and there'll be a little.
Rym: PM me if you want to run a panel or something stupid like.
Scott: So only people who go to the forum for this convention and join that forum and private message one person get to run panels.
Scott: That's weak sauce.
Rym: even worse is that you look in those and a lot of times all the posts are things like man.
Rym: It'd be great if there was a blob panel or someone should run a blob panel.
Rym: or people say yeah I'd like to run a blob panel, but they don't actually apply.
Rym: They just kind of say it out into the ether.
Rym: You've got to make it clear that if you want to run a panel This is the only way you are going to be able to run a panel.
Rym: You must fill out this small form.
Rym: It is less than a pages worth of writing.
Rym: You're gonna have to write maybe five paragraphs.
Rym: if you can't write five paragraphs you were not cut out to run a panel.
Scott: Yep, and also, you know people suggesting to a fan run con what panels they should have.
Scott: the con doesn't decide what panels They should have.
Scott: that it's depends on what people offer to run as panels.
Scott: I mean if 20 if the con is sitting there and they have 20 panels and all they get are 20 Applications of people who are on Naruto panels and that's it.
Scott: It doesn't matter how bad those panels are.
Scott: the con pretty much is forced to have 20 Naruto panels or just cancel panels altogether.
Rym: but what I would do is I'd have a thread in the forum that basically after explaining, you know how to apply and link to The form and everything asking in general though.
Rym: What kind of panels do you guys want to see?
Rym: What do you like in a panel?
Rym: So yeah, at least I can kind of gauge to their interest.
Rym: I mean if people are really liking that hot new show Bicano or whatever and They really like they really want to see stuff about that thing and
Scott: I have to choose between a good panel about that And a good panel about something old that's not so popular I'll probably choose the equally good but more popular panel over the equally good less popular panel.
Rym: now don't get us wrong I mean we made it sound like this is gonna be really arduous and horrible.
Rym: But in this initial, you know apply for a panel thing Which is gonna start almost immediately after the previous kind thing it we talked about it.
Scott: Like it's some Bureaucratic fascist nonsense, but really when you think about it, what is it?
Scott: You fill out an application you type in some words Some guys actually read those words and pay attention to them to decide whether who should have a panel and in the end The best panels get panels and the ones that aren't so good don't get them.
Rym: now The thing is this little bit this little at least tell us why you're gonna run a panel is Already more of a hurdle.
Scott: that can even ask a question Like why do you want to run a panel?
Scott: or you know something fun like that?
Scott: And then you could sort of gauge the attitude of the people running the panel.
Rym: now granted a lot of the Information we're asking for might be gotten later and will definitely confirm later.
Rym: The idea here is very simple.
Rym: This is the ulterior motive.
Rym: There has to be a small but and admit not necessarily difficult But at least enough to weed out the stupid people barrier to entry.
Rym: Yeah And if you can't bring yourself if you're not willing to put forth the effort to write One page worth of why you want to run a panel and what you think this panel should be.
Scott: You're not willing to put in the work to run a good panel and I know your panels gonna suck.
Rym: So, you know, we'll have periodic updates and keep reminding people.
Rym: Hey apply for panels and we'll set a deadline.
Rym: not a deadline to apply but a deadline being that after this point We are going to start selecting and the likelihood of you getting a panel will diminish period from this point forward.
Rym: Apply by this date if you want to have a good chance of getting a panel.
Rym: But if you have a suddenly good idea you can apply after the date.
Scott: But it might not be as easy and then we'll have an actual deadline which is this is the schedule.
Scott: end of story.
Rym: Well the deadline.
Rym: as in at this date, we will no longer be accepting panel applications from this.
Rym: at that point We are only going to be accepting panels from the list of panels that have already been submitted.
Scott: Yeah, and that's pretty much all we would do before the actual convention itself, you know I mean what else are you gonna do before the convention besides?
Scott: take the applications and sort the wheat from the chaff?
Scott: Maintain contact with panelists and make sure that everyone knows exactly what they have to do at the convention.
Scott: make sure this Everyone has all the information necessary and if anything screws up make sure that it's never our fault and it's always their fault.
Rym: Now in terms of selecting the panelists, I mean, I'm not gonna go into super great detail But we could if people ask if any cons out there want some details I'm sure we can send you an email but basically it would just come down to one.
Rym: did the people spell properly?
Rym: Yep, was that was the application and the follow-up emails professional?
Rym: do they respond in a timely manner?
Rym: Do they actually answer the questions?
Rym: I ask them does their panel sound interesting?
Scott: is their panel different from other panels?
Scott: Is it you know?
Scott: does it not just interest me?
Scott: But does it interest other people that I tell about it?
Rym: if I bring up a concern can they answer to that concern?
Scott: Yeah, like huh?
Scott: I think your panel might have might go over time You know, can you convince me that it's only gonna be an hour long and then we'll see what they say?
Rym: Or I think your panel might be a little too hardcore for this convention and the audience.
Rym: Do you think you could tone it down a little or could we at least set a you know a set of guidelines?
Rym: Basically once we've narrowed it down to like the finalists like the panels that we're pretty sure we're gonna have We cut we'd start talking to the panelists that we know we want on a much more intimate basis Like, you know, we'd work with them and we'd come down to a consensus as to exactly how this panel is going to be run.
Scott: Yep Now at the convention itself, what are you gonna do?
Scott: You got all these people?
Scott: They may or may not show up.
Scott: You got to do something with them and you got to make sure everyone gets to their panel room on time runs their panel has The equipment they need knows what the score is runs their panels and then gets out of the room on time.
Rym: Now first off as soon as the schedule is finalized which of course is before the con But it'll also be double finalized at the con Every panelist has got to check in.
Rym: I mean during registration, you know, they get their con badge, whatever.
Rym: I'm sure the panelists are comped in some way.
Rym: We'll have a system for that.
Rym: it that varies so much by con that we can't talk about it.
Rym: Yeah, but when you pick up your badge, you must then immediately and you will be reminded.
Rym: You'll be flagged as a panelist in some way.
Rym: You will be told to go to panel ops where we are sitting and check in Personally with us.
Rym: if you can't do it for whatever reason you've got to check in at some point well before your Possible.
Scott: I would have a system where I would have a pre-made badge for each Panelist and they would have to come and get it from me.
Scott: that way I would know physically, huh?
Scott: These people aren't here.
Scott: I have their badges.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I will assume that they're not here.
Scott: if they bought a badge screw them now.
Rym: ConnectiCon did this really well.
Rym: when you show up like when we showed up we went to the panel ops.
Rym: they came over and they gave us an Itinerary.
Rym: it showed us any and all of the panels we were running.
Rym: it showed us all the contact info We needed all the rules all the room numbers all the times every possible piece of information We could need on this piece of paper.
Scott: It was a like a personal schedule for us at the convention.
Scott: I would have a personal schedule and personal information sheet just one piece of paper Per panelist so that if they had that I would say hold on to this piece of paper.
Scott: May I give them two copies each?
Scott: What is this?
Scott: a couple copies big deal?
Scott: Yeah, right This paper tells you what you need to do with this con you will do with this piece of paper says you will sign this Piece of paper in front of me.
Scott: I'll have a signed copy of this piece of paper.
Scott: So I can come and get you, you know your phone number.
Scott: I will have everything, you know I'll call your cell phone with you standing in front of me.
Scott: So I know it rings.
Scott: Well, you're not lying to me I'll do whatever I have to do to make sure you do what that piece of paper says because that's what you promise You would do in order to get this free badge I'm handing you and if you don't do it You didn't earn your free badge and I'm gonna come and get you
Rym: now.
Rym: depending on the scheduling and all that I mean.
Rym: if the schedule for the con for whatever reason couldn't be finalized until very close to the con Then I would definitely make some leeway or have backups that we'll talk about later for the panels for the morning on Friday Yeah, and the morning
Scott: would definitely be quite a few backup panelists ready to go including myself.
Scott: I could run a panel and just spur of the moment BAM if it ever needs to be.
Rym: but anyway.
Rym: So I mean we will skip on some of those details just because while we have thought of them In fact, we have thought of this in excruciating detail like we have the go plan ready But we really can't get into that much detailer.
Rym: This would be three hours long Yep but if a panelist did not check in within a Certain number of hours before their panel was due to go with exceptions for the first panels on Friday morning Which obviously no
Scott: one really goes to so much anyway,
Rym: except a ConnectiCon yeah
Scott: But for
Rym: those people we would have worked something out of head of time some sort of alright, dude Are you cool with running a panel at 10 a.m.
Rym: On Friday?
Rym: We're gonna make sure you get your badge right away.
Rym: You get right in.
Rym: You don't need to check in with me Just go to your panel do your thing.
Rym: Yep, but for everyone else if you haven't checked in Let's say three hours at minimum before your panel.
Rym: Your panel is canceled Period.
Rym: we will probably try to call your cell phone which you've provided to us And if you don't answer your panel is canceled.
Rym: if you answer and you tell us that you're going to be there You were just delayed.
Rym: All right, but suffice to say I'm gonna say that a lot because Jim Vowles doesn't like it.
Rym: Suffice to say yeah, your panel is canceled.
Rym: Yes Now a lot of cons.
Rym: they try to accommodate panelists who screw up or show up late or whatever.
Scott: Accommodating guests is different from accommodating panelists.
Rym: You accommodate the guests.
Rym: if a panel has to be moved because a guest needs a time slot We deal with that because the guests definitely have precedents.
Scott: Yes get whatever they want.
Scott: panelists get the short end of the stick.
Scott: You're a fan.
Scott: You're running a panel in exchange for a free badge if I screw you.
Scott: Oh, if I screw you over you're still gonna get your free badge.
Scott: Yes, if you screw me over you're you're getting in trouble.
Rym: So if a panelist doesn't show up and doesn't check in no panel now at that point the schedule change is going to be You know made at the room.
Rym: It's not going to be announced over the PA because most cows don't have anything like that.
Rym: but basically what we would do is for all the panels that were good, but we couldn't fit him into the schedule or Just for people who were willing to take on this responsibility who had a good panel who said I'm willing to be the backup panelist.
Rym: We would run a backup panel.
Rym: We would have a list of people who in a pinch maybe just staffers who you know could run a funny thing.
Rym: We'll be ready to be in that room.
Rym: at the time The panel was supposed to start announced that the panelists failed to show up and then either try to run an event Similarly themed to their event to the best of their ability which a lot of people could do.
Rym: I'm pretty confident that I could have run most of the panels that were listed at Otakon and Katsucon last year.
Scott: I mean I would have two or three awesome people who I know could run a panel at just any moment like hey you Can you run a panel right now?
Scott: I can because I don't suck and BAM.
Scott: they run a panel when everyone gets canceled and I really don't think it's gonna be likely even at the biggest of cons For there to be like four or five simultaneous panels all canceled.
Scott: That's just not gonna happen.
Rym: Now.
Rym: also if we can't do something like that, we just don't have someone who could run that panel.
Scott: We'll probably have a couple of predetermined straight-up backup filler panels that are probably Comedic in nature or I would have some sort of Videoed thing to show in the room because all panel rooms usually have a projector and such.
Scott: I could show a video of a panel in the room or something else interesting While instead of a canceled panel I could use a video as the replacement panel.
Rym: The point is if a panelist didn't show up Someone would be at that panel room from the con to say exactly what happened Yeah, and to say here's what we were going to do to make this up for you.
Rym: Enjoy the alternate events.
Scott: Yep, and the thing is there's a lot of complaining always about like con members and con guests who go around and they say Oh, I went to the panel.
Scott: It was moved.
Scott: I went to this.
Scott: Every panel at every con I've ever been to right has?
Scott: they've always had a staffer at every panel.
Scott: You know to con.
Scott: does it get a con?
Scott: does it they?
Scott: if there's a panel?
Scott: There's one staff person assigned to deal with that panel that staff person.
Scott: if they're doing a good job, but their responsibilities are Relatively few I mean they basically have to sit at the panel and make sure there's no hokey-pokey going on and such.
Scott: Right, I would make it so that they also if there's any change at all in that panel would be announcing it constantly saying The such-and-such panel that was originally scheduled for this room has been canceled.
Scott: This panel will be here instead blah blah blah just constantly as people are coming in so that everyone knows I would have them kick panelists out of the room as soon as their time is up.
Scott: I would have them make sure that they know how all the equipment in the room works.
Scott: They can deal with if there's a problem and if there's some sort of contractor who deals with the equipment that they would be In the room at the start of all the panels.
Scott: I would have that staffer Sort of keep track of what they thought of the panel and what they the gent what they thought the reaction of the people attending The panel was.
Scott: you know did the people at the panel seem to like it did?
Scott: were they upset?
Scott: did a lot of people leave?
Scott: Did a lot of people not show up and write down count how many people are in the panel?
Scott: When it's like the biggest and write it down?
Rym: yes ConnectiCon actually took our advice this past year and the staffers went around and counted the audience.
Scott: one staff guy who was awesome.
Scott: Oh, yeah, he had the con schedule in his hand and basically every box on the schedule That was a panel.
Scott: he wrote the attendance number in the box.
Scott: so at the end He had this schedule full of attendance numbers on every single event And it was pretty cool.
Scott: basically
Rym: just have the staffers who were in the rooms dealing with these panels Take them as much information as they can and even give them a means to do so and then that way we can go through That after the fact and find out like this panel was really popular among the people who went.
Rym: But not many people went maybe because it was alternate to the cosplay.
Rym: Let's let these people run the exact same panel at a better time next year or a Lot of people came to this panel and a lot of people walked out.
Rym: Yeah, I mean those people are never coming back.
Scott: It does seem to me like a lot of people that seems to be like these have truths about.
Scott: oh if you're running your panel Against the cosplay no one's gonna come if you're running your panel early Sunday morning.
Scott: That's a bad time.
Scott: This is a good time.
Scott: Well who really keeps numbers and who really knows what's a good time?
Scott: What's a bad time?
Scott: I used to think that like Saturday morning was a good time and Saturday afternoon was also a good time and Friday Morning was a really bad time.
Scott: But I've seen Friday morning panels that are packed and Saturday afternoon panels that are empty.
Rym: So dude are how to run an anime club panel at Connecticut was standing room only Friday morning.
Scott: Yeah, so I think a lot of those things are all are not really true And we need to.
Scott: it would be a good idea to collect statistics of some sort some sort of metric however Unscientific to help you figure it out.
Scott: plus if you see for instance Hey There were like four panels that start at the same time as the cosplay and one of them had a whole ton of people And the other ones were empty.
Scott: ha maybe I should put you know that really that panel must have a really big draw.
Scott: I'll put that at a different time not concurrent with the masquerade And I'll put four of these average panels from another time there and keep mixing it up until you figure it out to get the Highest total panel attendance across the board.
Rym: now to make this easy for those staffers I just make a little form that just has a bunch of little Boxes little checks and little things and little boxes to write quick things in and just make it really really simple.
Rym: You know how much did people clap like?
Rym: on a scale of one to five?
Rym: how much did people cheer when it was done?
Rym: Did the panelists show up on time?
Scott: did they leave on time?
Rym: did they start their panel on time?
Rym: Did they sit up on stage and mumble for five minutes before they were ready?
Rym: all that it?
Scott: was there any problems with the equipment?
Scott: If so, what?
Scott: if were they resolved you know etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: and I'd have a little piece of paper that and that would one of these Pieces of paper would be filled out for every panel and at the end after the con I can go through these pieces of paper And I'm not gonna use them as some sort of ultimate decision-maker like oh no one clapped at this panel.
Scott: It's gone.
Scott: But I will examine them all and add the math up and take the stats and use them in my Considerations for how to make the panels better next year.
Rym: like a fears down the road Let's say that there's one group of people who always run the same like kind of panels and every year a lot of people show Up to the panel no matter what time it is and then also a lot of people leave the panel early and the applause are pretty And a lot of people are disappointed with the panel in the forums.
Rym: after the con I'm probably gonna get rid of that panel or Obviously the panel idea is good.
Rym: I will not let them run that panel.
Rym: I'll try to find someone else to run a similar panel.
Scott: Yes Cuz if something like you can see something like that You know that the title of the panel or the description of it in the con book are very appealing and have a big draw.
Scott: But the way the panel is run or the content of the panel isn't interesting to people and they leave.
Scott: So I would keep the title and description and get someone else to run it or get the people who run it to run it Differently to get people to stay.
Scott: probably just change the people because it's pretty hard to get people to run something differently.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: no, I mean really we talked about people and I I'm not gonna go into the whole vetting process But by emailing these people I would try to get a sense of if they're they really care about their panel or not And if they're gonna do a good job for any big panels or panels that are going to be important for whatever reason I would probably try to arrange his time to call them on the phone and talk to them in person.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: I mean, I'm not doing anything else all year.
Scott: I mean if my panels more than once annually probably couldn't do this much probably to cut it back a little bit, but My panels once a year.
Scott: I got plenty of time to arrange all of this all year.
Scott: I'm not doing anything else.
Scott: I don't have any other responsibilities other than at the con itself.
Scott: So why not do as much as I can to make the panels as good as I can?
Rym: Yeah, I mean look at this.
Rym: basically all we've really said we do is have an actual definitive good and consistent year-to-year process for applying to panels.
Rym: Apply rigorous standards to panelists and not allow someone who is obviously going to do a crappy job to have a panel in the first place.
Rym: To have the con pay attention to who runs panels and how well they go over in order to determine How to let panels get run the next years and then to follow up with people who run good panels to make sure they continue To run good panels in the future and
Scott: repeat this process Every year and your panels will start out awesome and get more awesome.
Scott: the only way this this process can be screwed over is if no one good wants to run panels or if Demand and people don't want to run panels anymore.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Rym: something It's always the other.
Rym: it's a passive process with most most cons.
Rym: But in addition to you know soliciting hey you want to run a panel in general.
Rym: on the website I would seek out people who I had seen run good panels in the past or people who I know could run a good panel or People who are recommended to me by other people I trust and ask them Hey, we would like you to run a panel.
Rym: Would you like to?
Rym: if so you can skip the process and send me this information?
Scott: Yeah, I mean if I go I'd go to other conventions or go to other conventions message boards And if I see a lot of people saying OMG at you know something con two states away That this panel went over re crazily well and packed the house and everyone loved it.
Scott: I would find out who did it and call them up and see if they could do the same thing again from icon Which is two states away and thus more people would enjoy the greatness that is their panel.
Rym: Yep They might not be able to but it's worth a shot.
Rym: I mean it can't hurt Yeah, and also that's a good way to find better panelists.
Scott: It's same way you find better AMVs.
Scott: Did your AMV win a year before?
Scott: you know in the previous year at another convention?
Scott: If so, you can have it at my convention.
Scott: was your panel a hit at another convention this year You can run it again at my convention.
Scott: Yeah, that way my convention would sort of be the best of but in that way would also be the best Better than the others.
Rym: Anyway, all right I think that's enough about that, but I do want to say that everything we've said and I'm dead serious Scott and I alone could handle 100% of that except for the at-con stuff and honestly GeekNights as an organization.
Rym: We have the staff Personally to handle the at-con part as well as long if it's the conventions too big We might need gophers under those people, but the conventions have gophers Yeah, plus we could get some gophers if we needed to.
Scott: we probably got.
Rym: the point is we have staff now.
Rym: I'm not saying this to try to convince conventions to let us do it.
Rym: All I'm saying is it wouldn't be that hard to do what we just said?
Scott: No, it wouldn't.
Scott: and if it if you think that is too hard then Maybe you're lazy.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four Different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.