Scott: It's Thursday March 29th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discuss all kinds of weapons and other various armaments.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You might all recall that yesterday I brought up the visigoths aka our friends and the holy terror that they unleashed upon our house over the D&D weekend.
Rym: is there Want to do well?
Rym: today?
Rym: I?
Rym: Discovered one final insult one last injustice that I did not know about until I reached for the Thin Mints And I discovered that someone had eaten all of the Thin Mints yet Carefully replaced the Thin Mint box into its original location thereby deceiving all What.
Scott: you couldn't just throw out the Thin Mint box what I mean?
Scott: There's so much crap that they take out and just leave lying around living room or fill up the trash can and don't empty it But that they they take trash and they put it back.
Rym: well I guess luckily I'm too clever for them.
Rym: you see before they all came over I was up there looking for some peanuts And I realized that were I to leave the Thin Mints within easy reach of anyone they would all be eaten.
Rym: So I took one of the whole tubes of Thin Mints that are in there.
Rym: You know there's two tubes of Thin Mints in any box of Thin Mints?
Rym: yep And I hid it in the back behind a bunch of snacks that they wouldn't eat because I know they don't eat that stuff.
Rym: and Sure enough I threw away the empty Thin Mints box which was now I guess serving as a decoy retrieved the untouched Thin Mints and proceeded to eat half of them, haha Hidden Thin Mint for the win.
Rym: so to whichever of you Visigoths stole all of our Thin Mints Owned.
Rym: yeah, that's right.
Scott: I think for now on we're just gonna have to hide all the good food somewhere secretly.
Rym: Well, I remember the one time when we just duct tape shut all the cabinets and all we provided was the fridge the red Solo cups and the plastic plates.
Scott: duct tape the fridge next time.
Rym: Now cuz they luckily now that I stopped stocking soda and all we had was a bunch of juice and seltzer water and tonic water The drinking of our goods went down precipitously.
Scott: I think that had a lot to do with the big crate of yu-hu that was brought.
Rym: I can't drink that stuff.
Scott: I can't drink it either, but if we duct tape the fridge They'll be forced to bring their own beverages and cups.
Rym: well You see they'd come in and they wouldn't go for the yu-hu go for the fridge and they'd open it and I'd watch him cuz I'd always be in there doing stuff and they'd look and they'd See Tom Collins and tonic water and seltzer water
Scott: and love soda
Rym: and all these different carbonated waters and pomegranate juices.
Scott: And they didn't.
Scott: pretty much.
Rym: juices and waters yeah And they didn't find their coca-cola.
Rym: and eventually they gave up.
Rym: a few people poured various amounts of seltzer Decided they didn't like it and left it sitting out.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: seltzer is almost free.
Rym: I put it in there mostly as a decoy Yeah, but it's like.
Scott: how could you go get food and then not eat it?
Rym: What if you don't like it?
Rym: What if you think I mean at one point someone and this is a legitimate mistake?
Rym: Thought they had a one kind of soda soda water and actually had a different kind of soda tonic water.
Scott: Do you not know how to read the label?
Rym: hey if you're in a hurry?
Rym: And you grab something quickly plus they look the same when you pour them out.
Rym: They pretty much smelled the same.
Rym: It's not until you drink it you realize wait a minute.
Rym: this tastes like water plus quinine.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't have a problem pouring incorrect beverages.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: you go and like go to the store and buy some beef But it was really.
Scott: you thought it was chicken.
Scott: you see you didn't read.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I have occasionally bought the wrong kind of sausage.
Rym: Okay, that's all you I think is all sausages look the same when especially when you're buying just from some butcher We just got a bunch of meat and tubes hanging from things.
Scott: That's the one time I will mess up It's not.
Scott: sometimes I'll go to the butcher and I'd be like half a pound of Hebrew national salami And they'll give me half a pound of Hebrew national bologna.
Scott: because they messed up not me.
Scott: I asked for the right thing.
Scott: they gave me what I didn't ask for.
Rym: yeah But if you go to a butcher you don't know much about the kind of meat They've got like.
Rym: they've got ten different weird German sausages And you point at one and it might not be the kind of sausage you expect to come out of there.
Scott: I don't expect any sausages to come out of there.
Rym: Well because you deny one of the greatest kinds of meat in the world.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, what what do you got in the news?
Rym: nothing?
Rym: I know you got nothing cuz you were sitting here just now trying to find some news.
Scott: Yeah, I had a hard time finding news today cuz I was spending most of my time doing something else, but iTunes the you know provider of digital music that we do not enjoy Has done something that didn't even occur to me ever before.
Scott: Apparently on iTunes you know you want to buy a song.
Scott: It's a dollar.
Scott: right if you want to buy an album on iTunes.
Scott: It's a lot less than $1 per song.
Scott: It's not a lot less, but it is less.
Scott: so like maybe a 12 song album would be 10 bucks.
Rym: Well it had to be less otherwise I wouldn't even give the option other than maybe having a tag that links all of them together in case someone cares What quote-unquote album they came from.
Scott: so not buying things on iTunes.
Scott: this did not occur to me.
Scott: that there might be a problem Where you would buy one song from an album and later decide you want the whole album?
Scott: And you don't want to pay you know for the whole price again.
Rym: You know for the cheap price for the out How often that happened to anime fans in the mid to late 90s and early 2000s?
Scott: We buy one DVD, and then you get the box set.
Scott: you'd have this DVD lying there?
Rym: Or I remember at one point someone bought like three DVDs of a series.
Rym: Are you in the box?
Rym: that came out and the box set was?
Rym: About the same price as buying all like.
Rym: it was a little bit more than buying the rest of the DVDs normally.
Rym: Yet at the same time it was more to buy all the DVDs.
Scott: or sometimes you buy issue one of a comic book miniseries And then you won't buy the rest.
Scott: But then the trade paperback will come out and you buy that and then you've got this issue ones in there.
Rym: granted I solve that very easily by only ever buying either box sets or individual DVDs when I know I'll never buy the box set.
Scott: Well anyway iTunes has added a feature where if you have some songs on an album You can pay to get the whole album at the discounted album price And they'll give you all your dollars back for all the songs that you bought before see.
Rym: a lot of artists seem to talk about how the integrity of the album has been destroyed by the fact that you can buy tracks piecemeal.
Rym: and While that might normally be true in some ways I do point out that the way Music distribution is morphed over the years.
Rym: I would contend that the vast majority of albums released in the United States were not Artistic works created by the people who were in the band in order to convey something or not some sort of unified work.
Rym: They were in fact the chef around the two tracks You actually wanted thus forcing you to buy the much more expensive album CD.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I mean if someone actually is a Quote real musician and makes an album full of awesome songs perhaps even an a-side and a b-side which don't mean anything without vinyl anymore, but you know and It's a bunch of songs that go together and to form a larger Musical whole people are probably gonna buy the whole album
Rym: the prop.
Scott: the reason people aren't buying whole albums Isn't because they don't have to.
Scott: it's because you make one hit song and a bunch of crap And you just put it all in the same disc and people only care about your hit song.
Scott: the rest of your music is crap.
Rym: Yeah, it's a CD I got and I technically bought it, but I bought it with a gift certificate that I couldn't spend anywhere else.
Rym: So it's not like.
Rym: I wanted to buy it, but I figured out the hell.
Rym: mm-hmm when fastball They had this song like.
Rym: where were they going without ever?
Rym: no I don't remember what it was called, but I like the song a lot.
Scott: I don't even know your song.
Scott: you're talking about who fastball is.
Rym: Oh Well I really like that song.
Rym: for whatever reason I thought all right I'm gonna use this gift certificate and I'm gonna buy the CD.
Rym: and I bought the CD and the CD did indeed contain that song and Every other song on the CD was unmitigated garbage.
Rym: that wasn't anything like that song.
Scott: Yeah, go back and get yourself like a Rolling Stones album or u2 album or a Beatles album.
Rym: Queens Right Elvis album got anything by Queens like the song album.
Rym: the songs aren't even just all part of one work But I say Led Zeppelin album.
Scott: it needs to be said three times.
Rym: They all actually flow into each other where you have to listen to the whole CD at once or you lose it.
Scott: Yeah, get any album by a real band and put it in your CD player and turn it on.
Scott: you know Just get all the mp3s from wherever it.
Rym: the hell's a CD player?
Scott: Yeah, and they play all the mp3s on the album in a row.
Scott: you're not gonna find sucky songs.
Scott: I mean you get a Beatles album.
Scott: every song is a hit.
Scott: every single one.
Scott: This there isn't like you know.
Scott: you don't pick up like you know the white album just for one song.
Scott: man It doesn't like that today.
Scott: it is nothing to do with distribution has to do with songs and I guess it's good that I Apple is doing something to change the crappy iTunes, but this is not enough.
Scott: They need to do a lot more before they're getting a dollar from me.
Rym: all they need to do is remove the DRM.
Rym: I know that's not gonna happen not even gonna pretend that that's an option, but that is really.
Rym: there are a couple songs I would probably pay a little bit of money for but the fact that I can't just get an mp3 or a flack or Something that I can use I don't know on my Linux box or on a non iPod in case I decide to buy a non iPod someday yep,
Scott: oh well.
Scott: We'll see what happens.
Scott: I give it a year.
Scott: I mean there are places we could go to buy music with.
Scott: that are just mp3s like emusic.com Or that other place or that Russian site.
Scott: no that one's not totally legit.
Scott: super legit ones that are definitely legit It's kind of legitimate.
Scott: Yeah, there are ones that we can go to that are a hundred percent legitimate, and we just don't.
Scott: so we'll see.
Rym: well It doesn't help that.
Rym: I really don't like the vast majority of music that comes out anymore.
Scott: Well, that's the other thing is places like emusic.com That do.
Scott: the mp3s are mostly the indie musics and not the.
Scott: the real music is only comes out.
Scott: I mean the the record company.
Scott: music only comes out in iTunes and Yahoo and Napster.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of the indie music.
Rym: now I see their websites, and they just give enough of it away for free to save me.
Rym: yep, yep Yep, so anyway in China a bunch of people have gotten together with some 300 million dollars to build a 13 mile Long dragon statue 13 mile long.
Rym: it's 13 miles long.
Rym: It's a Chinese style dragon.
Rym: So it's basically a long long snake that from the picture so far is pretty shoddy looking.
Scott: Yeah, how big are they making it?
Scott: They're making like a little tiny thing.
Scott: that's like you know as far around as my thumb.
Scott: Are they making it big?
Rym: that would just be silly.
Scott: you can make a really long thin dragon.
Scott: That'll be.
Scott: I think they'll be much cooler.
Rym: it is pretty long and thin because the head is only 30 feet high and I thought this was really cool when I saw the headline.
Rym: Oh giant dragon statue and in China OMG I love that stuff, but upon reading the article it looks as though This is a gigantic scan a scam you say.
Rym: the investor group is trying to build this 13 mile Long structure as a tourist destination inside of the dragon.
Rym: they plan to house galleries where visitors can quote For a fee have their names or other messages inscribed.
Rym: Advertising space on the giant serpent will also be sold.
Scott: ah it is a scam.
Scott: You know China already has this other really long thing.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: it's pretty great.
Scott: It sort of looks like a wall.
Scott: it keeps out Mongolians.
Rym: It's also contrary to popular belief not visible from space.
Rym: god damn it.
Scott: No it is not.
Scott: however It is a pretty awesome tourist destination.
Scott: It is not sold out with advertisements.
Scott: There are no galleries on the inside for all you know.
Rym: There's just giant Starbucks all along.
Scott: Maybe there is but I'm pretty sure communist don't like Starbucks But I think the joke there was calling China communist.
Rym: Yeah, yeah anyway I think the really funny part here is that an investor group began the project in 2002 and abandoned it due to financial Difficulties and now they're out of money, and they're having trouble.
Rym: now They're trying to sell this to local people on the idea that it could block sandstorms from hitting their town.
Scott: I'll buy it for a dollar.
Rym: I'll give him a dollar 45. who you in?
Scott: it's not worth it now.
Rym: So I'm disappointed.
Rym: this could have been some sort of awesome news about a 13 mile long dragon But it's actually some really lame news.
Scott: so now that it's about a 13 mile long Corrugated steel tube filled with ads.
Scott: so now that you own this dragon for a dollar 45 How many power cards you gonna buy?
Scott: how many farmers you gonna put in there?
Rym: Things of the day which we should probably get to before we say something that they don't like.
Rym: an anime world order loses it shit Again, oh, yeah, I don't think it's annual.
Scott: I don't know more of anime world order might be losing their shit now that I've also insulted their video games.
Rym: Well you insult pretty much everyone's video games But anyway my thing of the day up in your crib insulted your video games.
Scott: what now?
Rym: so some of my favorite cartoons ever are the Chippendale versus Donald Duck's from Disney back in the day and the Goofy learning how to do something or goofy explaining how to do something.
Rym: things also from back in the day in Disney Like goofy teaches you how to ski or goofy tries to quit smoking.
Scott: Goofy golf I think was the best goofy sport.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I like to ski one a lot.
Scott: It's all right thing is.
Rym: one of these is Surprisingly relevant to modern times.
Rym: in fact while almost all of the other goofies especially the skiing one well They're kind of goofy are really kind of outdated like the jokes.
Rym: They make are not particularly I don't know relevant today.
Rym: I mean what goofy gets out of his bed in the skiing one And he's got a bunch of hot water bottles.
Rym: I don't think anyone listening to this podcast has ever used a hot water bottle knows what it is?
Rym: knows What it would be used for?
Scott: Keeping hot water around?
Rym: no no what would know?
Rym: a hot water bottle?
Rym: hot water bag I guess or a bed warmer.
Rym: Oh those.
Scott: well if you've ever watched Looney Tunes You know that when you're sick in bed you put one on your head.
Rym: Yeah, well goofy has a bed full of them Must have been cold.
Rym: however this one in particular goofy and motor mania Pretty much describes everything about me driving around the Bronx every day.
Scott: I'd say it's pretty accurate except for the old style of car.
Rym: I don't know how particularly relevant that is to the relevance of goofy.
Rym: I mean, it's not like a kid's gonna see that and go what the fuck is that?
Rym: It's obviously a car, but I know a lot of kids will look at other goofy stuff, and what's that bag goofy?
Rym: What kind of shoes are those?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: man I could see like a few years to now a kid will look at that and be like what the hell kind of thing is.
Scott: Cars used to look like that.
Rym: what the fuck It's just like.
Rym: in back to the future replays with that our old arcade game in the second one and those kids are like You have to touch it.
Rym: It's a baby game.
Rym: Anyway, what do you got for me?
Scott: so This is a puzzling thing of the day in that.
Scott: I'm not sure how true it is even though.
Scott: It's a video uh-huh.
Scott: Basically in Japan where everything crazy and entertaining comes from some guy has a deep fryer.
Scott: Oh, that's not the whole news.
Scott: Some guy has a deep fryer with a goldfish tank under it, and you know oil doesn't mix with water.
Scott: so you've got this aquarium and Directly on top of the water of the aquarium is the oil and then the oil goes all the way up to the top And you fry things in the oil.
Rym: it looks like it's water and goldfishes Heating element in the oil and oil on top of that.
Scott: yes So the oil is really hot I mean like it's a hundred and something degrees celsius.
Scott: So if the fish touch the oil they die, but wouldn't that heat be transferred to the water?
Scott: I don't.
Scott: can someone explain to me.
Scott: How you can put oil on top of water heat the oil And then the water remains cool.
Scott: I don't get it unless you have some sort of cooling mechanism.
Rym: well one He does rise it does as true But seriously to other was someone who did in fact explain it to you in detail.
Rym: the problem is you seem to be Explaining it in a crazy moon language otherwise known as Japanese Mmm.
Rym: That's two things of the day in a row where if we knew Japanese we would be more fulfilled by them.
Scott: I just went to the Japanese bookstore today.
Scott: Don't talk to me about that.
Rym: so Japanese bookstores Especially when they have manga are incredibly depressing to me because I have sanctuary and I have Eagle and I think that's a Japan.
Scott: I think that's depressing.
Scott: today I was looking for a Japanese novel.
Scott: you find a Japanese novel.
Scott: you look at the cover because the covers are all cool And he sees a little tiny book for like four dollars.
Scott: and the cover.
Scott: you look at that cover And you know there's something awesome inside.
Scott: you open it, and it's basically a book of scribbles And you're like fuck.
Scott: It's a book of scribbles.
Scott: It does me no good.
Rym: Well, it's when you look in the manga section, and you think all right There's only like four or five Yakuza Action political yelling at each other awesome men standing at the front of tank columns while the nukes fall around the manga.
Rym: No, there's like a million of them, and they're all a dollar.
Scott: I took a picture of the golf manga today.
Rym: There's a golf mom of course.
Scott: I took a picture of it.
Rym: Just to prove it of course.
Rym: There's a golf mom.
Scott: Yes, it was everything that is published.
Scott: I figured it out by like.
Scott: It's like weekly comic big spirits or something like that.
Scott: That's the one that has the good stuff.
Scott: That's the one that Naoki or Asawa's manga gets put in.
Scott: you know the master Keaton's and the monsters in the 20th century boys.
Rym: What about going a guy?
Scott: Yeah, gonna guys cool, and I'll if you haven't had any of Actually, I'll put forth a controversial opinion.
Rym: I think that going a guy is only cool in a in an ironic and retroactive sense.
Rym: in most cases I agree.
Scott: Anyway, the aquarium with the oil on top of it.
Scott: Yes, well that was.
Scott: the first question is obviously How does the oil not heat up the water?
Scott: Number two the goldfish are fed because the bits from the fried food fall down into the water and the fish eat it.
Scott: That's cool, but how did the fish not get obese from eating?
Scott: What is essentially fried?
Rym: I think the answer is pretty obvious.
Rym: which obviously they've made?
Rym: this contraption put water Goldfish oil in it set it up filmed a bunch of stuff Taking the oil out taking the goldfish out and been done with it.
Scott: that could be true.
Rym: This is obviously not.
Rym: some guys Maybe someone's selling it though I don't think it's the modern Japanese equivalent of the platform shoes with the goldfish in them know also Uh Apparently, how did the goldfish get oxygen?
Rym: I mean they probably don't keep them in there that long.
Rym: either that or they die.
Scott: It says at least from what I read that the goldfish stay in there for like a few years and then they switch them out.
Scott: And the only time the goldfish die prematurely is if they are stupid enough to swim up and touch the oil in which case they Go.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I Don't know.
Scott: I guess well, they probably only say Oh God once because goldfish can't remember anything that happened too long ago.
Rym: I'm gonna call you on an assertion.
Rym: You've made during the course of your thing of the day Yeah, you've assumed that goldfish are theists.
Rym: maybe Anyway More important than goldfish more important than goofy more important than anime world order our zombies.
Scott: Are we really gonna do it?
Scott: I think we should back out.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm feeling whether maybe we should ask the audience.
Rym: audience.
Rym: Should we back out?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes Zombies suck boo.
Rym: Hi, I guess we're not doing zombies.
Scott: Oh, well, what are we gonna do then?
Scott: zombies?
Scott: Okay, so let's let's do it.
Rym: on what to do in the event of the horrible zombie apocalypse.
Rym: we talked about probably the most important thing of gathering intelligence because Zombie outbreaks can range from the worldwide.
Rym: Hell is rising up.
Rym: There is no escape to die no matter what.
Rym: down to your roommate is walking around groaning talking about cerebral matter And in that case, he might be a zombie or he might just be high.
Scott: It's tough to tell.
Scott: Yes, is there really a difference when you think about it?
Scott: So again
Rym: when you're listening to this show Which is going to be on weapons to use fighting zombies Always bear in mind that pretty much every episode we do after this and everything we could possibly say all of our expert opinions all Rely on you knowing what kinds of zombies you're up against.
Rym: So make sure you have done your homework and your reconnaissance before you even attempt to chainsaw zombie.
Scott: Yes, and you know, you might just end up having to be unlucky.
Scott: I mean in any zombie apocalypse You might just be one of those first zombies who doesn't get a chance to figure anything out.
Scott: Just you're just walking down the hall at work.
Scott: You don't know this zombie apocalypse.
Scott: You weren't expecting it.
Scott: and then a zombie jumps out of the closet and is game over for you.
Scott: Well Sorry, it's just the way the cookie crumbles.
Rym: Yeah, who wants to be that guy that asshole that first zombie?
Scott: Granted what if it's usually the fault of some like voodoo shaman or something?
Rym: It is possible that being one of the early zombies will entitle you to having powers later on.
Rym: Maybe we become one of those zombie lords from the back of the second ed D&D handbook.
Scott: Well the monster book at least I don't know usually the zombie lord is usually a necromancer Not one of the zombies themselves.
Scott: being one of the early zombies is not always a great idea because then you know It's your job to spread the zombieism which kind of sucks.
Scott: You don't want to be a spreading zombie you want to be one of the distant off, you know on your own zombies Do you get a lot more people to eat.
Rym: if I'm gonna have to be undead I'd rather be either some form of lich Possibly a demilich death night for me skeleton.
Scott: Thank you.
Rym: granted though a ghost as I learned from the game we played way back with Alex is very nice because you can possess living bodies and Clawed some semblance of a normal life for short periods of time before your hosts go insane.
Scott: Skeleton is definitely the way to go.
Scott: I can't stress that enough.
Rym: I don't really like the skeleton.
Scott: take it out by a claw hammer readily Hence, you don't go near people with claw hammers.
Scott: Plus you ride down the street on motorcycles yelling in Spanish.
Rym: Anyway, we're talking about weapons here and we have to narrow it down a bit because weapons could range from full-blown siege engines Designed to prevent zombies from overrunning the last stronghold of humanity to nukes to the kitchen knife.
Rym: so I think we're gonna limit it to personal weapons things that one Individual or possibly two people at most would use in close to close or close to close hand-to-hand to short Maybe maybe medium range combat the thing you would carry during the zombie apocalypse.
Scott: I think we got to start.
Scott: if we're gonna start it off, right?
Scott: We got to start for the obvious choice chainsaw.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: the number one zombie weapon That is generally useful no matter your zombie apocalypse.
Scott: the shotgun.
Rym: You see.
Rym: the shotgun, especially if it's loaded with slugs unlike any other kind of gun You're probably going to have has readily available ammunition.
Rym: It's so easy to use.
Rym: I defy anyone who has at least one arm to fire a shotgun a few times.
Scott: Yeah, it could be a super powerful shotgun in which case you might not be able to hold it straight.
Scott: But that doesn't matter because unlike a gun that shoots bullets the shotgun shoots shot Which is not just one piece of metal going very quickly.
Scott: It is a lot of small bits of metal that spread out and cover an area But all those bits of metal still go really fast.
Scott: The reason this is essential against zombies because you have a zombie It's essentially a bag of flesh walking around if you poke a hole in it Really?
Scott: It doesn't matter how fast you poke that hole.
Scott: It's not gonna make a difference.
Scott: You've got to knock the zombie down You've got to break a piece off of it and to do that you need to spread force over a wide area and the shotgun Is the only weapon.
Scott: where of that uses a gun type mechanism that will do such a thing.
Rym: Now the shotgun has a number of advantages.
Rym: I mean, it's very easy to use.
Rym: they're readily available.
Rym: Anyone can use them.
Scott: get them at Walmart by like the bag full there.
Rym: eat.
Rym: The problem is there's already zombies at Walmart and pretty much already fucked at that point.
Scott: But if you're in Walmart when the zombies come, you know where to go, but there's already zombies there.
Rym: There's always zombies there.
Scott: You get my point.
Rym: I do.
Scott: That's why Walmart has shotgun.
Rym: But shotguns are very easy to aim if you miss a ton.
Scott: It's really hard to miss.
Scott: It's like it's shotgun depending on your range.
Scott: It's sort of like hitting a beach ball with the tennis.
Rym: if you're in the same room as anything and you have a shotgun and that Thing is not destroyed in one shot.
Scott: You fail as a human being.
Scott: I mean at least get the arm You're gonna at least hit the arm and blow it off.
Rym: Maybe now in terms of firing Shotguns even without slugs even with just their shot have incredible stopping power.
Rym: if you hit a zombie in the head Which isn't that hard to do you're probably gonna take the head out and that's the end of that zombie.
Rym: Most likely you're hoping here that they're the zombies that go out when the brain is destroyed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean considering anything is possible.
Scott: It could be some sort of zombie where the head falls off and immediately grows a new body and the body grows a new head.
Scott: You've just made two zombies
Rym: But then again even most zombies even if destroying the head is not key the shotgun will do enough massive trauma in such a short Span that even if you did not destroy the zombie entirely it will not be bothering you for any Conceivable time and you will be able to get away.
Scott: The other advantage of the shotgun is that it does spread wide enough that if there are multiple Zombies coming at you you can sort of like, you know in the Jedi will do like a force push against some stormtroopers And they'll kind of fall back a bit.
Scott: Firing a shotgun in a group of zombies is very similar.
Scott: that whole group will be set aback You know if they get hit with any shot at all.
Rym: now the key to remember there is you've got to understand how to set The choke on your shotgun which probably won't be an issue depending what kind of shotgun you get.
Rym: you can easily widen the dispersal By just shortening the barrel.
Rym: Yep, now a hand cannon is a good backup.
Rym: if you can get a hold of a shotgun and saw it down Especially a double barrel boy, just keep that in your belt and use that as the emergency.
Rym: the zombies have grappled me.
Rym: This is my last chance to get them off.
Scott: Just don't shoot yourself in the genitals.
Rym: I Think trying to avoid applying a weapon to your genitals will be a theme throughout zombie.
Scott: Now if you can they do make what are like really awesome shotguns.
Scott: I mean the shotgun you're gonna get at Walmart is gonna be pretty crappy relative to what technology we have today's.
Scott: you know It'll.
Scott: you'll put two shells in it.
Scott: You'll go.
Scott: You'll you know pump it.
Scott: You'll fire the two shells.
Scott: You'll take the shells out.
Scott: you put two more.
Rym: a lot of hold.
Rym: more than two.
Scott: No some of them, but you can get shotguns.
Scott: these days You might have seen them in counter-strike the the noob cannon the other noob can.
Scott: those things are real.
Scott: You can get those if you find a good gun store.
Scott: Or basically you load it up with like 12 or 16 or maybe 10 shells I don't know how many and literally it goes like boom boom boom boom boom boom and you just pull the trigger.
Scott: Maybe you'll have to pump.
Scott: it depends on the gun.
Scott: But you can fire a lot of shells real fast And then you can load them in by going click click click click click click click And you can get a lot of zombies out.
Scott: with one of those things You're basically invincible in a zombie attack if you have those as long as you don't run out of ammo.
Rym: Yes, you got to be careful though because it's very easy to waste multiple shots.
Scott: on one zombie it is you've got a very.
Scott: you Gotta conserve the ammo really well because the one advantage of bullets which aren't gonna really help you that much unless you have a really Powerful gun is that they're small so you can have a lot of bullets.
Scott: Shotgun shells are kind of big so you kind of keep them in boxes.
Scott: You might like if you if you're in a truck or on a motorcycle.
Scott: It's you're better off because you can have more shells on you.
Scott: carrying around shotgun shells.
Scott: Maybe you have like a belt and two bandoliers with a bunch of shells in them, but they're gonna run out.
Rym: Yes, shotgun is definitely a short-term to midterm weapon.
Rym: It's not an immediate term meaning what you would get immediately.
Rym: zombies come unless you have one.
Scott: if you've got one in your house Good for you.
Rym: Yes, but even then the thing is the shotgun is Mostly to be used in order to get past zombies or to get through zombies or to get away from zombies.
Scott: Yeah, like you're stuck in the mall.
Scott: So you grab a shotgun you get out of the mall.
Scott: You don't need the shotgun anymore.
Scott: You know now you got to use a different weapon.
Rym: Yes Now you don't want to use the shotgun to just generally take out zombies because while you can have a lot of ammo Ammo is limited.
Rym: you see if you're in your house Barricaded don't just stand there shooting all the zombies that try to get up the stairs, of course Hopefully you've destroyed your stairs, but that's beside the point.
Rym: That's from it.
Rym: That's for another night.
Rym: But say you didn't destroy the stairs and zombies are just shambling up your porch trying to get into your front door and eat your Brains.
Rym: don't just stand there shooting each one as they come up.
Rym: There are much better ways to handle the actual fighting of zombies.
Rym: The shotgun should be saved and used primarily for escape.
Rym: The shotgun is the last ditch.
Rym: The shotgun is the universal will always get you out of the situation.
Rym: weapon.
Scott: Well, I think that every weapon in a zombie situation is a situational type of thing.
Scott: There is no standard weapon that'll do it all, you know in every possible circumstance or anything like that.
Rym: Well, there is a weapon that in most cases no matter what is going on will always be useful.
Scott: Yes, there are things they'll be useful but depending on your situation There's always one tool that does the job sort of like, you know, and you're a carpenter.
Scott: Sometimes the hammer is what you need.
Scott: Sometimes the screwdriver and the zombie apocalypse.
Scott: This is a call for the fire axe.
Scott: This is a call for the Mack truck.
Scott: This is a call for the chainsaw.
Rym: So right alongside with the shotgun then which the shotgun is pretty much your best bet.
Rym: general purpose firearm long-range weapon.
Rym: You're gonna need a melee weapon to go along with this not necessarily because melee weapons are better Don't believe the video games?
Rym: Well, it's not in that respect.
Rym: but believe the video games in this other aspect that Use the shotgun when you need to use the Louisville slugger.
Rym: when you can get away without using the shotgun to save ammo Well get a metal one.
Scott: First of all Louisville slugger is made of wood.
Scott: What's not so bad What's not so bad?
Scott: The thing is wood is kind of heavy and even if you are super strong You can swing a metal bat a lot faster and a lot harder than you can swing a wooden bet and it does more damage Especially if you hit in the important bits.
Scott: So this if you can get a metal bat get one, but a wooden bat will work almost as well.
Rym: It basically just comes down to any large easy to wield blunt instrument.
Scott: Yeah, crowbar can work pretty nicely.
Scott: A nice big hammer as long as it's not too unwieldy can work.
Scott: What else is really good at bludgeoning a cricket bat?
Rym: I guess golf clubs depending on what they're made out of are okay.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta watch out for those like flimsy titanium and graphite type thing.
Rym: Yeah, we learned that from suicide Kings You want like an iron.
Scott: old-school golf club probably like a putter is actually really good Especially if it's from like putting green.
Rym: actually actually the problem is I have a really good putter.
Rym: I've used it for years.
Rym: I had to find my love and it broke kind of on its own one day randomly.
Rym: Yeah, so don't always trust the the putter.
Rym: the putter won't save you in the nick of yeah but in general you'll always have the choice between melee weapon and Firearm and you should always when you can revert to the melee weapon simply because it'll save your ammo say you're walking outside And you encounter one zombie Especially if they're slow-moving or don't infect you with blood sprays kind of zombies.
Rym: Just beat it over the head until it stops moving and keep going.
Rym: Yep, don't waste a shotgun shell if it's not coming right for you.
Scott: You're pretty much always gonna carry a melee weapon no matter what Because you never know when a zombie let's jump out from behind a tree and it's gonna be way too close and You're not gonna have enough time to pull out a gun and maybe load it maybe cock it maybe fire it Bludgeon.
Scott: you can just go whip BAM and whack it inside of the head and that'll give you the second you need to back Off and then approach it properly now before
Rym: we leave the shotgun the one thing I really want to tell you is that if you have a shotgun Anything like the ones that break into I don't want to go in technical gun terms.
Rym: I don't think many of you know much about them But you know those shotguns were Arnold Schwarzenegger and Terminator 2 reloaded it in that really cool way where you kind of flip it around.
Scott: I'm pretty.
Scott: I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Scott: I'm pretty called sure that's called a muzzle loader.
Rym: Don't try to reload one of those shotguns the way Arnold Schwarzenegger Reloaded that shotgun.
Scott: well only gonna hurt yourself unless you happen to be a Terminator.
Rym: even then you're gonna hurt yourself.
Scott: No, you're not yes.
Rym: You are if you're a Terminator.
Rym: You're a Terminator.
Rym: You don't need to worry about zombies Just stand there.
Rym: What are they gonna?
Rym: Do bite you ha ha ha ha.
Scott: I think enough zombie.
Scott: How many zombies do you think it would take to beat the Terminator if the Terminator didn't fight back?
Rym: I depends on which Terminator.
Rym: t800.
Rym: Normal zombies like human zombies all of them.
Rym: There is no number of zombies that could destroy a Terminator.
Scott: I think there would be so many Where the weight of them on top of the Terminator would be so great that it would just be squished and destroyed.
Rym: I don't think you can pile that many zombies up on earth before many of them started floating off into space.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: The gravity of the zombies themselves will keep the other zombies from flying.
Rym: No, cuz.
Rym: then they'll pull themselves out into space and form this zombiball much like one of the bosses in Castlevania.
Scott: You know what if you put that Terminator at the center of the zombiball the Terminator would be no more.
Rym: He'd probably be fine.
Rym: He wouldn't get out anyway to talk about a lot of Weapons because a lot of people think oh I'd use flamethrowers or I'd use Samurai swords or chainsaws always a big one.
Scott: I'm still laughing at some of all.
Rym: don't listen to the movies.
Rym: Chainsaws are almost always entirely ineffectual and for anyone who's never actually used a chainsaw You might wonder why so many people hurt themselves with chainsaws.
Rym: You might think it's real easy to hurt To not touch that bit on the end.
Scott: That's gonna cut you it considering its most of the chainsaws.
Scott: It's the dangers.
Rym: the deal is whenever you touch a chainsaw to any object you're gonna cut.
Rym: There's a small chance that it's gonna jump away and try to cut your arm off.
Rym: It happens a lot the few tiny chainsaws.
Rym: I've tried to use in my life tried to kill me every time.
Scott: This is why chainsawing big trees is a sport that you can watch on ESPN - it's also a fairly high-paying job.
Scott: Yep, it's also a dangerous job.
Rym: Never ever ever use a chainsaw.
Rym: It's just gonna run out of gas.
Rym: It's ineffective.
Rym: It's slow.
Scott: You're gonna hurt yourself, and if it's not gonna run out of gas that means it plugs into the wall.
Scott: How useful is that?
Scott: The only real use you have for a chainsaw is you cutting through the bodies of the fallen that and you can also use Chainsaws as traps as long as you don't fall in as long as you're not so dumb that you fall into your own trap.
Scott: a Chainsaw trap can be quite effective because if you keep fueling that chainsaw Or if it's one that plugs into the wall and keep in his power from the power plant or a generator somewhere you can have a chainsaw running and Trick a lot of zombies and just falling out into it, and you just basically make a zombie grinder.
Scott: that works really well But you don't want to carry a chainsaw around with you.
Rym: You don't want to make a chainsaw type on a stick or anything like that because anyone who saw the remake of dawn of the Dead knows why you don't want to mount chainsaws to vehicles.
Scott: Yeah, you're only gonna hurt yourself as much as you hurt the zombies.
Scott: remember It doesn't matter how many zombies you hurt.
Scott: you hurt yourself once and it's game over.
Scott: you got to hurt yourself zero times.
Rym: Now if they're the kind of zombies where any significant trauma to the brain will take them out.
Rym: while shotguns are nice Nice handguns assault rifles rifles anything like that solid gold if one blow to the head will take the zombie out.
Rym: Get as many small arms as you can and use them to great effect.
Rym: Yes
Scott: Assuming zombies are undead flesh as I already said bullets don't really help because they go in one side not the other and the zombie Doesn't know any different, but if you can somehow kill the zombie by getting it in the head then a nice Well calibrated rifle of some sort is very useful because if a zombies far away Or maybe a little bit longer range You can shoot a bullet through its head before it gets anywhere near close enough to do any damage at all And it'll fall over and never bother you again
Rym: like say You know you're in a building and you've got to break through and escape from the building and there's a ring of zombies around it ahead before you break out Have people with rifles stand there and pick off a bunch of zombies in one area and then attack that area right away.
Scott: Yeah now if they're kind of zombies that you might need to bash their whole head apart a Normal rifle is not going to do the trick.
Scott: you need something more powerful.
Scott: But there do exist many more powerful rifles, and you know they don't necessarily have to get the AWP.
Scott: You can get a lot of other things that are almost as good or good enough where they shoot a bullet But they shoot the bullet so fast and so hard and the bullet is such a high caliber That if you hit the zombie in the head or even in the arm that entire like limb will explode.
Scott: Like there are bullets that you could shoot out of guns and hit people in the head and their head will just explode.
Rym: Granted there's a big problem with handguns in general in that the vast majority of human beings do not have the ability to fire them Accurately, this is why I've been talking about rifles.
Rym: Well, I was thinking about you're talking about that kind of weapon.
Rym: the Desert Eagle 5-0 would almost definitely take out a zombie head.
Scott: Oh almost certainly, but don't try to wield it.
Scott: if you do not It's sort of like a weapon in D&D.
Scott: you need to be level 5 to use this.
Rym: So what do you need to be a level 5?
Rym: Bullet-toothed Tony I guess.
Scott: if you're good enough to have a Desert Eagle and you can aim it and get a zombie in the head And then good for you.
Scott: You just you have the ability to do a lot better than most people in a zombie situation.
Scott: But if you are not capable of handling a weapon such as the Desert Eagle Don't try it cuz again.
Scott: You'll just hurt yourself probably break your wrist.
Rym: now.
Rym: another weapon a lot of people really like is the flamethrower and the flamethrower Is not a general-purpose weapon.
Rym: soldiers in World War one learned that one if use a flamethrower Most likely it's going to set you on fire before it sets anyone else on fire.
Scott: Yeah, if I've learned anything from playing that return to Castle Wolfenstein game is that flamethrower is the coolest weapon to kill yourself.
Rym: But I remember when I made a flamethrower in Doom 2 and I learned that all it did was spawn more flame and then immediately kill me.
Rym: Yeah, but yes flamethrowers are useful really only if you're on the offensive as opposed to the defensive.
Scott: Sometimes they're useful for clearing out different situations Like if there is a wooden structure full of zombies that is being on the offensive I guess or perhaps if there are a bunch of dead zombies in the way You can set the pile of corpses on fire.
Rym: It doesn't making it harder to crawl over the pile?
Scott: Well, no like maybe behind you or and you're going the other way or to clear it out eventually Like there's no zombies right now.
Rym: But you can do that with non flamethrowers and having the flamethrower slows you down so much.
Scott: I think the biggest problem of the flamethrower assuming you're not stupid enough to set yourself on fire with it assuming you know how to use it properly is that you're
Rym: carrying
Scott: around this tank of highly flammable gas or liquid and
Rym: That provides
Scott: a very very weak spot for you.
Scott: You know in any video game you ever play anyone who's carrying around a flamethrower You know that you just shoot them anywhere near that tank and it explodes and they die.
Scott: if a zombie grabs that tank Or maybe one of your friends shoots a spark near it by accident You're going to explode and that is not good.
Scott: That tank is much more useful as a zombie killing bomb than as a weak spot on your back.
Rym: Also because it's heavy you're not gonna move very fast.
Rym: So once again, I stand by my.
Rym: it is primarily an offensive weapon.
Rym: Yeah, the situations where you'll use a flamethrower assuming that somehow you get a hold of a flamethrower little homemade ones are pretty much dick.
Scott: Yeah, it's full if there's aliens for instead of zombies depending on the alien.
Rym: What if the aliens are actually fire element?
Scott: talking about the horny wiener aliens so horny Weaver.
Scott: That's an old.
Scott: It's a horny wiener.
Scott: It's an old joke.
Rym: You mean Sigourney Weaver.
Rym: Yes, not so horny wiener.
Scott: It's a middle school joke.
Scott: Leave me alone.
Rym: outstanding.
Scott: Maybe maybe it's time to dump that joke.
Scott: I didn't even it was.
Scott: so it's such an old ingrained joke.
Scott: Think when I said it.
Scott: yes, it's just the natural saying.
Rym: anyway just remember flamethrowers are not really useful to defend yourself.
Rym: They're useful for cleanup for the extermination of the remaining zombies for the cleaning out of buildings for the storming of areas that sort Of thing.
Scott: I know there is one weapon that most people don't think of.
Scott: that I think is perhaps the number one weapon in any modern Western civilized zombie situation.
Scott: and that weapon is any motor vehicle?
Rym: Yes, preferably some sort of Jeep if possible something with some horsepower.
Scott: But mostly you want is torque.
Scott: you want it to be high off the ground.
Scott: you want good wheels that can drive off-road and you want something that can take a lot of damage to the front and Hopefully also the rear.
Rym: Yes, so very specifically don't go grabbing Lamborghinis and Porsches.
Rym: Those are pretty much gonna get gummed up on the first zombie.
Scott: But the Lamborghini the Porsche might be useful in a very specific situation of empty highway.
Scott: You got to get the hell out of this town something like that.
Scott: But other than that, it's just gonna get you killed.
Scott: Yes, you're looking for.
Scott: you know Ford f350s.
Scott: You're looking for Dodge rams.
Scott: You're looking for jeeps.
Scott: You're looking for land rovers.
Scott: You're looking for SUVs that are actually trucks and not cars.
Rym: if you need to get through a bunch of zombies You can sit there and go bit by bit with the flamethrower or you could fight your way out with baseball bats and shotguns.
Rym: But if you've got a good truck just get in it.
Rym: Maybe put some sort of thing on front of it.
Rym: if you can get a plow or a bulldozer thing to put on the front.
Rym: That's even better some sort of cowcatcher kind of thing.
Rym: Yeah One of those and just charge through the zombies and get away.
Scott: their motor vehicles aren't just cars either.
Scott: a train is awesome Even though it only goes one way.
Rym: trains I would submit are not that awesome as
Scott: long as those zombies
Rym: on the train If you don't know the situation along the train route to not get on a train because you might just take yourself into a tunnel and die or take yourself into Zombie territory with no way back out.
Rym: if there's anything blocking the train now, you're fucked.
Scott: Well, the thing is if you're on a train you can just you could detach all the cars except the engine.
Scott: So you're in the engine you go really fast No zombies.
Scott: If there's no zombie in the engine with you You're okay And you can go and go and go and go and no zombies gonna get you unless you stop and open the door or anything Like that.
Scott: and if you end up in a bad place You know You can see it way ahead of you and if it doesn't look like you know If the track is out or something like that Just turn the train around and go back.
Scott: But a train just might be the thing to get you out of there without getting killed.
Rym: So remember it's hard to drive a train.
Rym: You might think it's easy, but the first corner if you don't know how fast it can go around the corner You're just gonna derail and die.
Scott: Yes That's why you should make sure to get the engineer and hope he didn't turn into a zombie or learn how to use a train Which I maybe I should learn how to use a train if I always wanted to know.
Rym: now when you're using weapons to get zombies Remember that zombie intelligence.
Rym: This is key again.
Rym: You've got to be careful of Infection depending on what kind of zombies they are.
Rym: if they're normal Zombies that just kill you and maybe dead bodies come back to life and they can bite you and do whatever and you won't turn Into one.
Rym: then don't worry about it.
Rym: But if they're 28 days later zombies wear a speck of blood in your eye and suddenly you go crazy.
Rym: You best be wearing some armor when you're fighting and you best be using blunt trauma weapons as opposed to piercing stabbing weapons.
Scott: Yes Also, if you can find a hospital maybe even like those biohazard hazmat type suits.
Scott: that way even if blood splatters You're okay.
Scott: However in a duct tape is also good.
Rym: Clothing leather is key.
Rym: Wear as much leather as you can.
Rym: duct tape the things together.
Rym: So there's no way loves a mask of some sort.
Scott: Maybe a paintball mask could be good.
Rym: Yeah, if anything you want to protect your eyes You don't want to zombie blood in your eyes, especially if you haven't figured out how contagious the zombie whatever is.
Scott: Yeah as much protection and armor as you can.
Scott: but armor is not weapons, which is what we're talking about here.
Rym: So, how do you fight a zombie in one-on-one combat?
Rym: very simply again say let's say you don't know anything about it.
Rym: You're fighting the zombie.
Rym: You're standing here in our room right now doing the show the GeekNights studio and a zombie busting the door and goes I'm a zombie.
Scott: I'm a zombie.
Scott: How's fast is he going?
Scott: Is he a slow zombie or fast zombie?
Scott: He's a fast zombie.
Scott: We're fucked cuz we don't have weapons right now.
Rym: I might be able to push this keyboard into him while he's going after you enough to keep him away from me Long enough to grab something heavy and hit him like this mug.
Scott: I could maybe use this microphone stand as sort of a swinging bludgeon and then escape out the door.
Rym: I don't know if he was a 28 days later zombie.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: He appears he's already eating your face.
Rym: I'm fucked.
Rym: I'm trying to jump out the window.
Scott: Yeah, it's game over.
Scott: But if he's a slow zombie, right I can back up.
Scott: I can get it a little.
Scott: I can get a second to grab something.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: What could I grab here?
Rym: I'd pretty much have to grab my dragon mug or maybe the GeekNights' compressor.
Scott: There's a tennis racket there.
Scott: That could be useful.
Rym: Oh, I got a pair of scissors here.
Scott: Mmm I might just use this microphone stand or actually the microphone itself is really heavy and it's on this cable.
Scott: I could swing it around pretty good.
Scott: That might do it.
Rym: We'd pretty much have to throw debris at the zombie in order to get him contained now.
Rym: This is key.
Rym: This is the first time you don't have any intelligence.
Rym: We don't know what's going on other than that there is a zombie.
Rym: if We are able to subdue the zombie or in any way prevent it from leaving and also at the same time preventing it from getting To us then it's a good time to perform an experiment.
Rym: Try stab it through the eye and see if that kills it.
Rym: then destroy the head and see if that kills it destroy the heart.
Rym: See if that kills it.
Rym: figure out what it takes to destroy the zombie and then act accordingly.
Scott: Make sure Rym does all these experiments and figure out how Rym gets infected by the zombie.
Scott: then kill Rym in the same way.
Scott: He killed the first zombie and then escape.
Rym: Of course Your first priority is to make sure the zombie doesn't get you and your second priority is to make sure that Rym is the guinea Pig and not Scott before you do any experimentation.
Rym: if zombie comes into the studio and we take it out before we do anything One listen and see if there's any other noise in the house because how the fuck did a zombie get in?
Rym: the doors are locked To look out the window and see if there are zombies outside.
Scott: Three look on the internet and see if someone else already figured it out.
Rym: God I can just see Farky be like zombies invade something about Drew and beer and boobies.
Scott: There is the chance that that was the only zombie ever and now we're gonna be instant billionaires because we have the world's only zombie.
Rym: Yeah, except alright, so we kill the zombie again.
Rym: now It's dead that we call the police.
Rym: the police come and look at it.
Rym: So, uh, this hobo broke into your house and killed him.
Scott: no, it was a zombie.
Rym: It looks like you just stabbed this guy in the face like ten times then took his heart out and crushed it.
Rym: We swear he was a zombie.
Rym: We stabbed him in the neck and he didn't die.
Scott: Yeah, sure boys Police are all zombies.
Scott: Anyway back to the weapons that we were talking.
Scott: send more paramedics.
Scott: I Guess the best weapons would always be military weapons, but you're really not gonna get those.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I mean, maybe you live near a military base and you get on to the military base by fruit.
Rym: You're not a zombie.
Rym: the military base If the zombie apocalypse is great enough is probably going to arm any human who is in there.
Scott: Maybe you're knowing our military.
Scott: They just keep you in some sort of shitty ass shelter while they fuck up things.
Rym: not to use as weapons is very key.
Rym: Do not attempt to stab the zombie with a pocket knife.
Scott: No, pretty much.
Rym: if you're gonna use a knife, you're gonna want machete or better Yeah, if you're using a pair of scissors or some little knife That's pretty much the last resort because the zombies already biting your neck and you're trying to stab it in the eye.
Scott: Yeah I mean Machete is actually a really good general-purpose weapon because it cuts a lot of other things that might get in your way Like, you know fall in wires that aren't electrified.
Rym: if you like goal if you like D&D stuff or SCA stuff.
Rym: And you've got a bunch of pseudo medieval weapons laying around Unless you got them from a reputable sword dealer like museum replicas and you know that they're full-tang and good and Actually designed for at least some form of combat or stage combat.
Rym: Don't use them.
Rym: that sword from the Lord of the Rings might look really cool But it's either gonna break bend or somehow hurt you the moment you try to actually use it.
Scott: Yeah, your replica of the master sword is not a weapon.
Scott: You might as well use a stick.
Scott: I mean, it's not.
Scott: You're better off using the kitchen knife actually than that that thing.
Rym: BB guns anything like that.
Rym: Don't worry about it.
Scott: I can lately useless except maybe as a bludgeon if they're nice and heavy and made of metal Obviously aren't.
Rym: pepper spray and the like in 99% of zombie cases are not gonna do anything.
Scott: No, maybe if you had a super soaker, maybe you could get some sort of acid or something in there Maybe holy water maybe these are mystical zombies.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: it could be that a super soaker of holy water is the best option in some other universe besides this one.
Rym: Yes, however, if zombies come and they're not scientific zombies, or there's something we can't explain right away There's the tiny chance that there's other things.
Rym: So if you have the opportunity throw a bunch of holy symbols Adam and see if anything happens.
Scott: Yeah, you know keep like a crescent moon a juice star and a cross around just in case the yellow sign just All the elders sign.
Scott: also, you know, yeah just keep just keep a little.
Scott: we should sell that like a bag of holy symbols Just in case as every holy symbol like every religion and if a zombie ever happens You just throw this bag at it and then see what I see which one.
Rym: and of course if zombies come real quick.
Rym: If you ever had a memory from your childhood Where you thought you could cast a spell or a dream where someone said weird words to you try saying all those words just in case.
Rym: Yeah, can't hurt now you say those words while you're using your shotgun, yeah, yeah, don't don't say oh price I'll save me from the sound because he's probably not gonna unless he's standing there next to you with a shotgun.
Scott: Hey, what's up, man?
Scott: How's it going?
Rym: laying down in blue sparks?
Rym: All right, I think we're done.
Rym: We couldn't.
Rym: there wasn't so much detail to talk about since we avoided all the artillery or bombs or traps or any of that.
Rym: And the things you used to fight zombies are actually relatively simple.
Scott: I think that's cuz.
Scott: zombies are relatively simple enemies.
Scott: they're not complex enemies such as vampires where your weapons are like steaks and things or skeletons where only bludgeons will work.
Scott: or You know some sort of golems where you need all sorts of weird weapons to beat a golem because they're immune to just about Everything, you know a zombie it's a walking bag of flesh and you just need to beat the shit out of it.
Rym: Yep, you're pretty much in all zombie situations want some form of melee weapon preferably a bludgeoning one as opposed to a piercing or stabbing Or slashing one, of course the one that cuts really well like something really sharp like maybe a good scimitar a real Cut the leg.
Scott: Yeah, you get the legs off a zombie and then what's it gonna do?
Rym: Theoretically with a real Katana or a real two-handed crazy awesome great sword kind of deal You could probably behead some zombies.
Scott: if you're outside you can actually get room.
Scott: You can swing a claymore around that'll do the trick or a mall.
Rym: I like malls.
Scott: Yeah the thing is you want to avoid things like Flails unless you have specific trained skills because you're only gonna hurt yourself with that.
Rym: Yeah, unless you know how to use nunchucks and when I say know how to use nunchucks I mean someone cooler than you taught you how to use nunchucks and he himself has used them before.
Rym: Don't ever ever try to use a nunchuck.
Rym: I've owned nunchucks at several junctures in my young life Yourself in the nuts.
Scott: with them didn't you get out?
Rym: I proceeded to hit myself in the nuts until I threw them away.
Scott: Yeah, and we're not talking about your wiimote nunchuck.
Scott: Yeah, most ninja weapons kind of suck when it comes to.
Rym: yeah ninja stars Those are gonna.
Scott: stars aren't gonna do it.
Scott: little daggers aren't gonna do it.
Scott: You know.
Scott: those rings that are blades aren't gonna do it unless you can.
Scott: you know a hat with a knife in poison is not Gonna do it.
Scott: no shoes with knives in them not gonna work.
Rym: in general You want your melee weapon and your shotgun?
Rym: You want to have some shells and some slugs if you can get a hold of them to get as much ammo as you can and a vehicle and Beyond that depending on the kinds of zombies.
Rym: assault rifles and that sort of thing might be very very useful.
Rym: But again, it depends on what kind of zombies they are.
Scott: Yeah I mean if you have an ak-47, there's a bunch of people coming at you and you just let loose.
Scott: Odds are if it's a mob of people you're gonna kill quite a few people.
Scott: if it's a mob of zombies Depending on the zombie.
Scott: I might not do anything.
Rym: Yes, and of course be smart.
Rym: don't kill zombies unless one It's safe to do so and you won't expend under resources doing it or two.
Rym: You have to to either get where you're going or get away from where you are Yes, or to save another living human being.
Scott: yes Your goal is always to get away to get somewhere to escape somehow.
Scott: You know this isn't a game of kill the most zombies and win.
Scott: It's a game of you get to get to the chopper.
Scott: Yeah Don't kill more zombies than you have to.
Scott: if you can get to the chopper without wasting time or ammo killing any Then do that so like in doom if you can get to the door at the end of the level in doom You know.
Scott: grab the keys open all the right doors push the red button and then levels over without having to kill any imps.
Scott: Do that because then you just saved yourself ten rockets.
Rym: However, if you're in say a hospital and it's reasonably secured and you know There are other people in the hospital and you see a zombie You should probably go out of your way to kill it or at least alert everyone to its presence for the safety of all Because you don't know what kind of apocalypse this might be.
Rym: it might be limited number of zombies Don't worry about it, but it might be.
Rym: every single living human counts and is required.
Rym: I mean if there's a limited number of humans left You don't want to let anyone die.
Rym: if you see people under attack You might be worth it to go out of your way and save them unless you know, you can't.
Scott: yeah It mostly depends on the people.
Scott: I mean if you see, you know old people It's not it's sad But you really probably don't need to save the old people unless they're old people with mad skills.
Rym: or maybe maybe they remember things.
Rym: Maybe it's a World War two veteran who can teach you all about tactics.
Scott: Oh, that is true There are uses.
Rym: but yeah, don't just discount an old person out of hand.
Rym: But if you're running away with your small army of men and there's a horde of zombies Closing in on the one old lady.
Rym: You can't keep up.
Rym: I hate to say it.
Rym: You're gonna have to perform some sort of moral triage and let her go.
Scott: Yeah I mean plus if you got kids coming around kids are tough because you know.
Scott: Well old people in the end are just gonna.
Rym: but all anime tells you kids are the future.
Scott: They are the kids are the future.
Scott: The problem is the kids are also baggage.
Scott: They make you good they slow you down They don't help you out at all in the short term and it just kept.
Scott: picking up one kid might get you all killed.
Rym: So but at the same time if the number of humans is limited picking up one kid might be the most important thing you've ever Done.
Scott: it might be see now that you got to think fast.
Rym: We can't get into that.
Rym: That's a whole separate zombie episode.
Rym: the moral triage And also medical triage and all that sort of thing.
Rym: But one last thing I want to bring up with these weapons especially if they're zombies that can be taken out from a distance with headshots and two if They're the kind of zombies where if you were killed by a zombie you become a zombie.
Rym: in that case if you let the old Lady go you're pretty much unless you have no way to an asshole If you don't at least turn around and give her the mercy kill.
Scott: Yeah, you're pretty much saying Oh, yeah, we're just gonna let you become as I plus it's better.
Scott: It's easy to kill an old lady a lot easier than is to kill a zombie I assume.
Scott: So if you're gonna leave the old lady behind It's good to mercy.
Scott: kill the old lady because not only is it better for her not having to become a horrible zombie It's better for you one less zombie to deal with.
Scott: Alright, so you freaking fanboys.
Scott: We did it.
Rym: you ask for it constantly.
Rym: I get emails on a regular basis.
Rym: It's over.
Rym: We did it.
Rym: We did one.
Rym: you're gonna have to hold off a little bit before we do this again.
Scott: Quite a bit.
Scott: also send us Thursday.
Scott: show ideas don't involve zombies.
Rym: However, they might have figured out by you saying that that the reason we did a zombie episode is because we didn't have a better Thursday in which case they'll avoid sending us Thursday ideas.
Rym: What about our Thursday contest which they're all right the bad podcast contest.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We're still working on that.
Rym: We've got a lot of entries for it.
Rym: So it's over.
Rym: no more entries.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: I'm going through them.
Rym: now I'm listening to several episodes from every single entry you sent us.
Rym: I also am going to apologize right now to podcasts that may or may not have been done by people I know that were submitted to us.
Scott: Yeah, we did not Do any of these submissions or suggestions and it was completely up to people who listen to our show.
Scott: which podcast?
Scott: They thought were the worst ever.
Rym: granted I'm probably going to have my own submission even though I will not put it forth for a prize eligibility.
Scott: obviously I'll have to find a podcast to submit.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't really think about it.
Scott: Maybe we'll do just.
Scott: next week's show is like the results of the contest.
Rym: We'll review all these podcasts and yeah I'm not gonna promise though because it might be two weeks from now depending on how much time I put into deciding in the next Week.
Scott: Yeah, I got to listen to some of these two.
Rym: I don't want to let Rym make the decision on his own I don't want to have to make the decision on my own.
Rym: I mean, I can't.
Scott: I can't let you carry the burden of listening to all these bad podcasts and I'll listen any of them.
Rym: I Was about to say something and I'm not gonna all right.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.