Rym: It's Monday, August 27th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight fantasy cell phone.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Not much is happening lately.
Scott: Just a lot of video game playing again.
Scott: So I got a new video card today, which I have yet to install.
Scott: So I kind of want to hurry this show along so I can go install it.
Rym: Yeah the tide is kind of turned over the years.
Rym: Scott and I keep leapfrogging each other and computers and currently I Am way ahead and Scott's computer is old and slow and busted.
Scott: Yeah, basically I realized I could either get a new computer now or I could upgrade my computer something I've never really done before because it's always been better to just buy a new one.
Scott: and Since I use my laptop for most a lot of business these days anyway I could just upgrade the computer to the point at which I Could probably play the orange box games that are gonna come out really well And I won't have to worry about upgrading it again for like a hajillion years More like three years, but I basically I upgraded the RAM a while ago from half a gig to two gigs and now today I'm upgrading the video card from an Nvidia 5900 to a 7600 GT.
Scott: so That leaves me.
Scott: the only weak link is the processor but processor not so much needed.
Scott: I think it'll be fun.
Rym: Well, I mean the video card is not an optimal solution.
Rym: It's just that those super good high-end 79 hundreds that are also really cheap aren't really available anymore.
Scott: Yeah, uh, that's what people are saying.
Scott: But I think it's kind of like whatever because the 86 hundreds are like $100 or 200, you know, they're not expensive.
Scott: Yeah only the only expensive cards are the stupid crazy cards that nobody needs.
Scott: because from what I hear people are playing the crazy Bioshocks and things like the full-on settings would just fine Resolutions and things and they got no problems.
Scott: and those are like with 7,000 cards.
Scott: So the people with the 8,000 cards are already overboard and so the people with the $500 cards are double overboard.
Scott: I don't know what the hell game they're playing but Suit themselves.
Scott: I really don't care.
Scott: they fell for the hype and they got money to burn.
Scott: go nuts.
Scott: My computer is gonna last me a long time and I barely spent any money on it.
Rym: Yeah granted I'm just a not and I I really can't deal with any change in frame rate while I'm playing an FPS.
Scott: somehow I doubt I'm gonna have a change in frame rate.
Scott: from what I hear other people who have the same CPU as me Which is an Athlon XP 2500 have no problems with like the latest awesome game.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, we'll see.
Rym: I mean, I'm not sure benchmarks are all over the place.
Scott: I wasn't having problems.
Scott: So I'm not gonna have problems with even better video.
Rym: Okay, when I stood behind you watch you play Counter-Strike source It slowed down a lot when you went around corners or smoke grenades got thrown anywhere.
Scott: I think you're just crazy and you have a psychological issue.
Rym: No, it was a pretty clear drop in frame rate.
Rym: it go I Problems.
Scott: it's smooth for me.
Scott: I was playing it just fine.
Rym: Yeah, maybe you got that.
Rym: you're not so good.
Rym: I'm shooting people as I did a natural selection.
Rym: I was uh, kicking your ass.
Scott: You're even kicking my ass.
Scott: the team game first of all second of all is kicking quite a bunch of asses.
Rym: Yeah except I remember one moment when I was sitting there and I'm a little gorgeous and you ran up with the machine gun and You emptied a whole clip and didn't even hit me.
Scott: and first of all I hit you plenty and second of all that pretty much all that has to do with is your offense tower finished and We didn't have any upgraded weapons at that point.
Scott: Yeah, so what was gonna?
Rym: you know, you didn't hit me.
Rym: You just kind of shot near me and I just kind of my screen.
Scott: I was hitting you.
Scott: I had.
Scott: you were hitting me on my screen.
Scott: The gun was in your butt and those little yellow stuff going.
Rym: I was facing you and I wasn't taking any damage You weren't it?
Scott: when on my screen you were facing into the offense tower.
Rym: Uh-huh So well the fact remains that you died and I had full health.
Scott: Yeah, what are you gonna do?
Rym: kill you and then destroy the marine commander base?
Scott: Yeah, the thing is natural selection.
Scott: It's like FPS skills.
Scott: while they matter You know, especially early in the game You can't really say oh you died because of me and NS.
Scott: therefore I'm better than you.
Scott: FPS is cuz.
Scott: it's so much a team Game and so much depends on so many other things more.
Rym: Let's play some one-on-one counter-strike.
Rym: a counter-strike.
Scott: one-on-one is not an FPS of skill.
Scott: It's not a game of FPS skill.
Scott: if you want to play a game of SPS skill We have to play like some quake - let's play some doom - deathmatch doom - is not the 3d.
Rym: We can play that Jen mod of quake - we could do that.
Scott: That's a good - person.
Scott: it.
Scott: the thing is there really aren't too many good - people.
Scott: I think ricochet is the only good.
Rym: Oh, man ricochet was such a good game, but no one plays it.
Scott: It's the only good.
Scott: two people FPS out, you know what?
Rym: whenever we have a free weekend in free time I think we're gonna try to get everyone all our friends in steam all you listeners to play ricochet.
Scott: Why don't we just keep talking about video games and tech day?
Scott: We got no tech to talk about fine.
Rym: So speaking of pornography Perfect, I don't know how many of you know about Australia though.
Rym: I know we have a lot of listeners there so I'm sure you can attest to this.
Rym: but Government is a little bit puritanical sometimes a little bit right-wing sometimes They ban quite a few video games and movies and they try to block porn and make porn filters and all sorts of things.
Scott: But it's not so great for the freedom of creativity and speech and such.
Rym: There's a story here on slashdot.
Rym: now it links to a blog and I didn't really research the actual story So I can't say a hundred percent if this is actually true because I generally don't trust these blogs much.
Rym: But the point of the story regardless of whether or not this specific instance is true.
Rym: I'm pretty sure it is Is more that this will happen no matter what.
Rym: so Australia has this 84 million dollar internet porn filter that they paid 84 million dollars for and Apparently a year 10 Australian kid cracked it in about 30 minutes.
Scott: Oh, I read that story, but it didn't say it was like the Australian national filter.
Scott: He said it was like it was like a local school filter.
Rym: Yeah, but the article still says 84 million dollar internet porn filter.
Scott: Yeah, the point is is that Kids filter always get around.
Scott: a porn filter filtering the internet doesn't work no matter what period.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: think about it.
Rym: China can't even keep the internet completely locked down.
Rym: How is Australia going to?
Scott: it's not gonna.
Scott: people who have a school one school with one Single fiber optic cable leaving the school and all internet traffic going along that cable can't filter it successfully with only maybe like a hundred People in the school.
Rym: there's.
Rym: no there's a lot of technical reasons.
Rym: I mean one they're trying to filter based on content which because we don't have artificial intelligence worth a damn yet and Because there's really no way to have a computer look at a picture and decide if it's obscene or how obscene it is.
Rym: Or is that one boob or two or can you see the whole?
Rym: I'm not labia.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: or is this a picture of Michelangelo's David or a naked guy?
Scott: who knows?
Rym: Is that a penis or just a banana?
Scott: We don't know.
Rym: we really don't know.
Rym: maybe it's a guy with jaundice so I can't tell.
Rym: you have to base your filtering on other factors and those factors don't matter because you could have a site that was Like happy furry kittens calm and it's just hardcore pornography.
Scott: You could also have a site hardcore fucking Rym in the ass something something dildo something and it's just a site of happy little cats Huh?
Rym: I find it interesting that your example Well my example involved puppies and kittens and pornography and yours involved sex with me and dildos.
Scott: Yeah, what do you want?
Scott: Not that all right Rym riding the sex machine.
Rym: But the thing is with China It's a little easier because if you want to block like based on you can't get from this country or this place.
Rym: It's a lot easier.
Rym: I mean you can get around it with filters and proxies But it's generally much easier to block content going to and from specific places.
Rym: But as you all know on the internet porn comes from everywhere.
Scott: There is porn at every possible venture.
Rym: in fact remember when we reported on a bay image a while ago.
Rym: Yeah, and oh this is cool.
Rym: So I clicked on a random link and I clicked on.
Rym: I think Digimon and the first thing I saw was Digimon pornography.
Scott: Another thing is that a lot of like firewalls and filtering things right because of the way SSL works.
Scott: right if you want to like visit your banks website.
Scott: that doesn't go through the filters and things because if it does it won't work because SSL is designed to prevent men in the middle attacks and stuff like which is basically what proxy censorship is right?
Scott: So when you do that like let's say your work has an HTTP proxy And you want to visit your bank's website either?
Scott: They set it up where you're not allowed to visit your bank's website Or they allow you to make a direct connection to your bank.
Scott: So if someone says of a porn site that's secure and they like sell logins or something like that You could just totally visit it.
Scott: or if someone makes a tunnel and you go through the tunnel There's nothing you can do about it.
Scott: Absolutely nothing.
Scott: there is no filter in the world that can stop someone from making like an SSL tunnel somewhere Except for not letting them use the Internet's at all and not letting them do anything on the computer at all at which point They can't use the computer.
Scott: So what's the point of even giving them one?
Scott: They're not gonna be able to get their work done.
Rym: Yep, I mean it really just comes down to you're trying to block subjective content based on subjective moral bullshit and the only way to actually do that is to have a human being look at Every single thing that anyone tries to look at in all of Australia and have a big yes and a big no button
Scott: and that And then your entire law is based on that person's subjectivity.
Rym: the thing is the laws are really subjective and crap anyway.
Rym: Yep, I mean, I can't say specifically how it is in Australia, but you all know in America There's different hard and soft regulations.
Rym: Like uh-oh.
Rym: They said fuck more than once.
Rym: they showed one and a half tits.
Rym: We're coming down on Saw bullshit.
Scott: Yeah is technologically infeasible to filter.
Scott: just give up.
Scott: It's like DRM just give up.
Rym: I think a much better way is to teach children about what the Internet actually is and how to use it safe.
Scott: Hey, did you did you see any pictures and naked ladies in your kid?
Scott: Uh, I may have I may have as well Are you are you doing all right over there?
Rym: I think I'm doing okay traumatized.
Rym: Well, there is this one picture But you've seen that one too.
Rym: Yeah, I think we all know which one we're talking about.
Rym: point is, you know Give it up prudes.
Scott: Give it up.
Scott: All right, so Over the weekend when we weren't really paying attention Apparently some semi big news happened and I'm just gonna pretend it's true because it was reported in so many places and that's fine by me.
Rym: Well, there is an update on slash dot that Microsoft has identified and fixed the problem including posted instructions for people who had a problem.
Scott: So yeah, the point is Microsoft Windows and other Microsoft software has a new thing a relatively new thing called genuine advantage.
Scott: No, that's what they like to call it.
Rym: I like that.
Rym: That's quite a euphemism.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: It's a genuine they.
Scott: basically the idea of genuine advantage is that according to Microsoft you get an advantage if you use genuine Microsoft software as opposed to Pirated Microsoft software.
Scott: the advantage is that you get updates and your software works But my old pirated copy of Windows 2000 got updates.
Rym: just fine Yeah, but not not.
Scott: you haven't been using that since the genuine advantage.
Rym: Well, they didn't really do that with Windows 2000.
Scott: Yeah The way it works is whenever you go to Windows Update or whenever you turn your computer on.
Scott: I don't know if it happens every time you turn your computer on but whenever you go to Windows Update or do some other Certain activities on your computer that your wind copy of Windows will go and check with the Microsoft Genuine advantage server to make sure that your copy of Windows is genuine.
Scott: So let's say I install Windows on my computer and I update it.
Scott: It'll be cool if I paid for it.
Scott: It's a real copy of Windows.
Scott: It came with my Dell computer.
Scott: Then I give Rym my CD key and he installs that same copy of Windows in his computer and he goes and updates.
Scott: That server realizes the two people using the same CD key and they're both updating the same exact updates within like five minutes of each Other.
Scott: it's not stupid.
Scott: It goes.
Scott: Hey, hey You're obviously pirating one of you and then it shuts us both down and our windows is don't stop working entirely but it basically cuts our windows is down to almost no functionality whatsoever is that the basically useless and The only way you can get it to work again is either To basically you have to go to the windows genuine advantage server again and get it to say yes You're genuine as opposed to no you're still a pirate.
Rym: I still can't believe that my copy of XP is legitimate.
Rym: Yes, because I can we got it through a shade somewhat shady.
Scott: It's not shady.
Scott: It's perfectly real.
Scott: anyway, the point is is that they somehow say that it's an advantage to have a operating system where there is a Possibility that the operating system will just stop working.
Rym: now We've a lot of times open source people and I and Scott have both made this argument that you know with the system like this With the authentication on the server side and whatever it is possible for Microsoft to just fuck everybody.
Rym: Yeah, and there's nothing you could do about it.
Scott: They can just decide.
Scott: one day You know what?
Scott: We're gonna turn off every copy of Windows.
Scott: every copy of Windows is just turn off and that'll be if Microsoft goes out of business somehow or if there's a bomb and Microsoft and the servers get destroyed.
Scott: Everyone's windows will stop working.
Rym: or what if Microsoft just one day said all right world Pay us a billion dollars or we turn off windows everywhere.
Rym: yep,
Scott: and basically what happened over the weekend was a taste of that in that the genuine advantage server had an outage and a lot of people who tried to update during that period of time got fucked and they couldn't get anything done or Use their computers really until the server came back up and they restarted their computers.
Rym: take that all of our friends who said that that couldn't happen because it just did and Well, I gotta say is with Linux.
Scott: This just isn't possible.
Scott: I mean even if every person who currently works on a Linux kernel said fuck everybody double-deuce.
Scott: We have all the source code.
Scott: I have a copy.
Scott: Rym has a copy.
Rym: Yes, I do.
Scott: millions of computers everywhere have copies of the code to all this software.
Rym: We was that possibly apocryphal quote?
Rym: not really I guess apocryphal isn't the word but a possibly misattributed quote to Linus Torvalds.
Rym: That was basically.
Rym: I just back up my source code to the rest of the world.
Scott: Yeah There is no way that this could ever happen with open source and that is just one of the reasons why Windows sucks and Linux doesn't.
Rym: yeah now granted.
Rym: I mean a lot of people use Windows because they're not gonna deal with Linux which Linux isn't perfect at all saying that.
Scott: but
Rym: what I'm gonna say is that when it comes to governments militaries Anything big and important like that the idea of using a proprietary operating system like the fact that our military uses Microsoft Windows for a lot of things and our government uses Microsoft Windows and Microsoft Office in a Way our government and military basically said well you're going to give this Corporation this international corporation a lot of power over us that we have almost nothing.
Rym: We have no way to do anything against them if they decide to ever do anything bad.
Scott: Yeah, and it's basically comes down to trust in that.
Scott: we trust Microsoft so much not to just fuck us over.
Scott: I mean we could go to war like what if there's a real war?
Scott: that was actually like someone was attacking the u.s With like a bunch of planes and boats and then Microsoft just said haha.
Scott: We want the u.s.
Scott: To lose windows off What the planes would crash and tanks would stop working.
Scott: it'd be game over.
Scott: they could they could kill us all whereas Linux Can't happen.
Rym: So I guess the moral here is if you don't use Linux the u.s.
Rym: Might get invaded and we might all die Things of the day.
Rym: so I've been in recording studios before.
Rym: we had a recording studio at RIT that we got to play around in and At one of the hospitals I work at there's a bunch of hearing labs where they test people's hearing.
Rym: so they have super isolation sound Booths and if you've ever been in one of these rooms, it's really neat in that the at least if it's a good one There's no echoes in the room.
Scott: Yeah They've got all kinds of foam and stuff on the walls.
Scott: The only sounds you hear the sounds you make and you won't get like sound bouncing off the wall going back into the microphone a Second time or anything like that.
Rym: now you don't like it.
Rym: it's kind of eerie to be in these rooms if you're not used to it because there's just.
Rym: There's no echoes and your voice sounds kind of thin and everything sounds really kind of close and it's kind of neat.
Rym: But the thing is my thing of the day here this I did this partly because I'm really sick of just Using a video from dig every day and I found these pictures and they're pretty cool.
Rym: This is the largest Anechoic chamber in the world.
Rym: So it's a. it's a no echo chamber, but it's gigantic.
Rym: There are pictures of many many many many many fighter jets in this very far apart from one another.
Scott: I imagine.
Scott: they use it to detect the radar profiles of said jets things like that things like that.
Rym: In fact, it not only does it block sound but it blocks all sorts of RF stuff, too.
Scott: Oh, you could use that room for a lot of interesting things.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of want to just run around inside it yelling.
Scott: I kind of want to run around inside it with radios.
Rym: All right, that's all I got.
Scott: we could do some Doppler action in there.
Scott: That'd be pretty cool because it would actually work like it's supposed to in the science textbook All right.
Scott: So this is a thing of the day classic.
Scott: I can't believe this is never a thing of the day.
Scott: It might have been but I couldn't find it and Rym was actually the one who remembered it recently.
Scott: But I yoinked it because I couldn't find anything better and I also didn't want to use a dig video.
Rym: I was looking at this anechoic chambered.
Rym: I'm like, this will be my thing of the day.
Rym: and then randomly I'm like, wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: I have no idea what prompted me to think of this.
Scott: But yeah, so I don't know where to go.
Scott: But Well, uh, yeah of all the websites on the internet of all the websites All right.
Scott: This one is an old old old meme that is from the late 90s.
Scott: It must be and it's incredibly awesome and it entertained us back in the high school days And of course you got to RIT and everyone already knew about it.
Scott: That's how old this meme is.
Scott: And it's so old and I guess so unknown these days that like usually all the old memes come back around Like you go on dig and you see like all your base and it's like yeah We've seen that before but somehow it shows up again from all the people who didn't see it the first time.
Scott: This hasn't shown up again.
Scott: At least not in my memory.
Scott: This is just people have forgotten about this one and I'm bringing it back now.
Rym: Websites, I mean even today.
Rym: this is one of the most functional websites I have ever been to.
Rym: I mean it lets you do anything.
Scott: Yep Anything is possible at Zumblecom.
Rym: You can do anything.
Rym: The only limit is yourself.
Scott: The unattainable is attainable.
Scott: Welcome welcome to Zumblecom.
Scott: That's it Zumblecom.
Scott: Just I don't you gotta go to Zumblecom if you want to ever get anything done because you know You see anything there.
Rym: now as much as we often talk about Websites have to be functional like they got to be.
Rym: the text that does the thing and I want to get my information and get the hell out.
Rym: Website aren't websites like this because this is art as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: Oh, it's like it's like a masterpiece
Rym: and especially the fact that someone way back in the day Put this up with
Scott: flash like two or flash one paid
Rym: for hosting Paid for the domain and
Scott: they still have it registered and the dot domain registered until 2010 and the site is still up Good God
Rym: and never has it changed.
Scott: No, they never changed the site.
Rym: just it's really.
Rym: I like things like this.
Rym: It's very.
Rym: When I first found this I remember thinking wow that's kind of cool and it I almost would say it kind of epitomizes the idea of this internet culture of Sharing and providing back.
Rym: a lot of people make a lot of websites that do a lot of things That are really nice and really cool and they they don't make money off of that.
Rym: They don't get anything in return except knowing that they made someone smile.
Rym: Yeah, and they are in our case knowing that we pissed someone off.
Scott: This website is definitely I would say it's in in many ways.
Scott: You should you should visit it and keep.
Scott: just sit at the website for a while and you know until you realize that Anything is possible.
Scott: and then you know, just sit there.
Scott: Don't stop.
Scott: Just look at the website for a while.
Rym: Now if we were mean we could have said if you watch long enough something special happens.
Scott: Well, you watch long enough.
Scott: It does eventually end and you'll know when it ends.
Rym: Yeah, and then it loops.
Rym: Yep All right, so Cell phones.
Scott: Well, basically what happened here is we had a convergence of coincidences.
Scott: I guess maybe not coincidences on our GeekNights.
Rym: It's serendipity.
Rym: It's synchronicity?
Scott: No, it's not cuz that's all bullshit.
Scott: the on our calendar of what to do for the GeekNights episode It said what do we want in a cell phone?
Scott: And also by chance the Apple iPhone was recently unlocked.
Scott: So what better timing?
Rym: yeah now we're not gonna talk about the iPhone except possibly obliquely many times.
Rym: yeah, the idea here is because Scott always used to yell at me because I always had the Cheapest crappiest cell phone I could get.
Rym: I always got like whatever was free and to this day I still get whatever is free.
Rym: Yeah, and Scott would always spend a little bit of money and get a little bit nicer cell phone.
Scott: well, the main thing is is that you know, I I don't have a regular phone and So my cell phone is my only phone and I barely make calls.
Scott: But if I'm gonna have something that's my only phone calling thing.
Scott: I don't want the cheapest and shittiest phone calling thing.
Scott: I think I can have these slightly better $50 phone calling thing.
Scott: Well that has some features that even though I barely use them.
Scott: I might use them a little bit.
Rym: What features does your phone have that my free phone doesn't have.
Scott: I got mp3s.
Rym: mine can do mp3s It has.
Rym: it can take up to a 1 gig mini SD whatever card in the back.
Scott: Yeah, mine could take a mini SD card and I can look I can load it up with pictures on the mini SD card.
Scott: That was the main reason I went for this phone.
Scott: as opposed to like in my previous phone I had to get spent get softer from the internet and buy a Special cable in order to get the photos off of it without paying money.
Scott: on my new phone I can take pictures to the SD card and take them right out of there without any trouble.
Rym: See, I don't know if I can do that because I never take pictures of my cell phone But I'm pretty sure I could mess with this phone and unlock it to do what I want to do.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is I didn't have to do anything to this phone, but you can't do anything Anything if you can get your phone to Zombil com maybe also my phone has the Bluetooth and the Bluetooth dial-up networking is theoretically possible.
Scott: And while I don't do that I could you know in the middle of nowhere in an emergency pay for it and get on the net in the super emergency.
Rym: I can also do that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right, you know the thing is Phones now even crappy phones like the free phone for Eisner Sprint gives you Has all the basic functions of pretty much every normal cell phone.
Scott: Yeah, the problem is is It's sort of like this this tough thing because either a phone is going to do a phone is something I have to carry around With me.
Scott: it's just sort of the way it is, even though I barely make calls It.
Scott: that's just the way the world is now.
Scott: I need to have a cell phone.
Rym: Yeah, particularly like when I mean imagine the days before cell phones go into I don't know an anime convention or going on a Road trip in multiple cars.
Rym: Yep You're screwed.
Scott: So I have to have a cell phone.
Scott: no matter what I carry on me I have to carry a phone.
Scott: So in addition, I carry a lot of other gadgets.
Scott: and as much as I like gadgets I don't like carrying things.
Scott: I like to carry as few things as possible.
Rym: But yet I know that despite the fact that your phone can play mp3s You still carry an iPod and despite the fact that your phone can play games You still carry a DS.
Scott: and the reason is the phone sucks at playing games and the phone sucks at playing mp3s.
Rym: So what we're gonna talk about tonight?
Rym: because in theory I would love to have like a little super smart iPhone kind of thing that can go on the internet and make calls and go To my Google Calendar and take pictures and download and upload and Bluetooth and game and mp3 and everything.
Rym: But the reason I always get the crappy cell phone is that it's not a matter of money.
Rym: even it's a fact that no matter How
Scott: much money I'm willing to pay almost any amount of money no
Rym: matter how much money we're willing to spend There is not a phone on this freaking earth that does even a fraction of the things I want it to let alone for a reasonable price.
Scott: Basically what it comes down to is if my phone for example If my phone doesn't play mp3s well enough to just to replace the iPod or maybe an i-audio or whatever If it doesn't play mp3s as well as or better than a standalone at portable mp3 player Then it's effectively not an mp3 player.
Scott: I don't need emergency mp3 playing All right, it's you know, so if it doesn't do that, then it can't replace the mp3 playing device Which means I'm gonna use the phone only for its phone calling.
Scott: So I'm gonna have two devices anyway.
Scott: So what the hell do I care if the phone has better or worse mp3 playing on it?
Scott: It's either sufficient or not sufficient.
Scott: That's the end of the story.
Rym: So what we're gonna talk about is kind of a. this is almost like fantasy football, but for super nerds Fantasy cell phone right now.
Rym: what basically the idea is that?
Rym: Like we said we'd be willing to spend money like if there were I'd be willing to spend five six seven hundred dollars.
Rym: Yeah for a good
Scott: like that
Rym: I'll put it this way we're gonna talk about the kind of cell phone the features it would have to have for us to have reacted to it the way a Lot of people reacted to the iPhone the kind of phone that I would stand in line overnight to get one.
Scott: Well, there is one good thing to say about the iPhone and and that is that the interface of the iPhone doesn't suck.
Scott: Yes, and that is one major problem with current phones, especially in the u.s.
Scott: But also everywhere else is that the user interface is Horrendous and ass.
Scott: I mean I always you know I'm always kind of sad when I see old people trying to use a cell phone.
Scott: Usually I'm like, you know, I'll be like old people can't use a computer and I'm like you.
Scott: old people get with the times But it.
Scott: but when it comes to cell phones, especially part of it is that the cell phone has a really horrible interface.
Scott: Yeah, and you know even old people who try to learn how to use the phone.
Scott: It's not easy I mean, it's hard for me to use my freaking phone You know, I mean, it's just counterintuitive crap.
Rym: And I when I first get a new phone It takes me a while to figure out how to make it do the things I wanted to do.
Scott: I mean like for me to like even text message people.
Scott: the interface for like Choosing people from my contact list to add to a to add to a text message sucks goddamn balls.
Scott: It's horrendous.
Scott: It's useless.
Scott: So when I send text messages, it's it's painful.
Scott: I only send them when it's more convenient than calling which is rare.
Scott: So the first thing a phone has to have is user interface that it doesn't suck and the eye.
Scott: the one the iPhone has I'd say is bare minimum of goodness.
Rym: So that's the line.
Rym: if it it's gotta have an iPhone ish interface and I'd be cool with it It's got to be as good as or better than iPhone interface now.
Rym: do it's gotta make calls now?
Rym: That might sound stupid.
Rym: But I've seen people who have cell phones that just the microphone is crappy and you can't understand them when they talk.
Scott: Or the earpiece isn't loud enough or the speakerphone isn't good enough or you know The Bluetooth headset doesn't stay connected properly or whatever.
Rym: for whatever reason It just doesn't get service in places where it should.
Scott: also other than I think the iPhone actually is one of the nice things It does.
Scott: but for example, if you know someone calls me while I'm getting I'm while I'm talking it's got a. you know It's got to behave appropriately.
Scott: if I want to make a text message while I'm talking to someone in the speakerphone.
Scott: That has to work properly.
Scott: if I'm listening, you know If I'm using another feature of the phone and I get a call it has to react appropriately.
Scott: it.
Scott: basically everything involving calling has to be Slick and cool and work exactly as you would expect it to with no annoyances and I guess we can boil this down Before it does anything else.
Rym: It's got to be a phone and it's got to work as a phone.
Scott: It sure does All right, what else that to do?
Rym: Well beyond that it has to be in some ways a mini computer is via smartphone because I'm paying a lot of money.
Rym: I want a smartphone but blackberries and all those smartphones really suck to use.
Scott: Yes, and while there are things that they do well, for example, the blackberry does email pretty well I can't just install any application.
Scott: I want a lot of the applications for it cost money and there aren't a large assortment of free applications.
Rym: A lot of them don't work.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of them don't work properly.
Scott: A lot of them don't work the way I want them to work While there are dev kits to write my own software.
Scott: they suck balls and it sucks to write your own software for those things Linux phone really has.
Scott: would be it because then I can make I'd be fine with a Windows Phone.
Scott: No, they do have a Windows Phone, but that is all the same problems.
Scott: I know they didn't fix any of it.
Rym: Well, the problem is an actual Windows Phone a phone that was just running XP and I could install whatever I wanted on it And not only that but all these applications if they happen to use the data network.
Scott: I want true unlimited usage of the data network at the speed at which it is and I don't want you looking at what I'm using it for and I'm willing to pay like a lot of money a month.
Scott: I mean Verizon charges 80 bucks a month for unlimited data.
Scott: The problem is it's not really unlimited data.
Scott: They have like a you know a secret limit and they'll cut you off if they see you watching YouTube by your phone.
Rym: just be like Alright, here are the exact limits and here are the rules.
Scott: But I wouldn't pay 80 bucks a month for the limit that they have.
Rym: but I'd be fine if they just say it.
Scott: But the problem is and actually if they just say it I'm only gonna pay 40 for that limit.
Rym: ISPs do the same thing where they say check it out unlimited bandwidth But it's not really and they'll just totally screw you if you go beyond their secret arbitrary.
Scott: I want to be able to send any data I want on the full free open internet and do whatever the fuck I want with my phone.
Scott: It's my phone.
Scott: I'm on the internet.
Scott: I pay you for the connection to the internet.
Scott: Let me do whatever I want.
Scott: if I want to use Skype over the internet instead of using your phone tough shit.
Scott: if I want To send IMs tough shit.
Scott: if I want to download mp3s tough shit.
Scott: I'm doing whatever I wants my phone.
Rym: Fuck you now along those lines The phone's got to support 802.11 so I can just go on the internet.
Rym: if there's any wireless access point I should be able to just connect to that.
Scott: Yeah, and even better if it had the 802.11n Yes, but I'd be okay with G and speaking of which it also you can't be giving me no g2 phone.
Scott: It has to go on the fastest cell networks possible.
Scott: I need the ev dues.
Scott: I need all that action.
Scott: You know why she?
Scott: I don't want this slow ass Like 1x or a GPRS business.
Scott: I need the edge I need the HSDPA I need everything no matter where I am.
Scott: This is cell towers.
Scott: I'm on.
Scott: that's how if I go to a foreign country I got to switch out my SIM card and I'm on.
Scott: there can't be anywhere where there's cell service and I'm not on.
Rym: As I can go SIM card, I'd better be able to take that SIM card out and put it in a different phone.
Rym: Yeah, I put a different SIM card in that phone.
Scott: There is no way that I'm gonna have my phone tied to the carrier.
Scott: I mean right now I can sorta.
Scott: it's sort of understandable because the phone carriers in the US unlike other countries They give you.
Scott: they subsidize your phone.
Scott: when you buy say a trio from Verizon that trio only cost you like a few hundred dollars Whereas buying a trio on your own from palm directly is a lot more money.
Scott: and Verizon Subsidizes your phone in exchange for your extended contract.
Scott: However, the ideal phone for me would be a phone that I buy from the phone manufacturer for whatever price Whatever price they're charging.
Scott: I don't care and I own that hardware.
Scott: It's mine and I paid for all of it and then I can use it on any network I want.
Scott: you know may I guess I can understand the technological, you know problems with having a phone That's either on the you know, the GPRS GSM edge ages DPA type networks and the phones that are on the.
Scott: you know Evdu one X Verizon type networks, you know PCM.
Rym: well, I think the deal is we're talking about what we want in a phone and some of the problems are just people being Greedy and wanting money part.
Rym: Some of the problems are just technological.
Rym: some of the problems are.
Scott: So what I want is a phone that can do all the networks.
Scott: But obviously if the phone does one of the other I'd still be cool with it as long as it did all the high speeds.
Rym: Yeah now also I should be able to own the phone and do what I want with it.
Rym: now specifically I'm talking about GPS because a lot of phones even if they don't do it with the satellites or with the whatever They can do a weak GPS by looking at cell towers and figure out where you are.
Rym: Almost every phone does not let you get that data and you have to pay to get that day.
Scott: Well what that comes down to is the phone has hardware in it and the hardware of the phone.
Scott: just looking at the capabilities of That hardware it can do certain things like get GPS coordinates that are roughly accurate or play music out the speakerphone or Anything like that.
Scott: if my phone's hardware is capable of something I Want to not be limited at all and taking advantage of those capabilities.
Scott: I might not want to take advantage of all those capabilities But I don't want to be prevented from doing anything.
Scott: if my phone can get shitty GPS data I want access to that shitty GPS data.
Scott: if my phone can play crappy music out the speakerphone I want to be able to play crap music out the speakerphone.
Scott: Everything the phone can do I need to be able to do if I want to.
Scott: you cannot limit me in any way.
Scott: It's my phone.
Scott: I control it not you.
Scott: It's got to be able to play mp3s and all kinds of other audio formats if possible.
Rym: Yeah, I don't really need video.
Scott: But yeah, I don't really need video on the go.
Scott: cuz I'm not in personally interested in watching video on the go I mean I am now just on the train, but but I use my laptop or so Yeah, I bought a dedicated little DVD laptop player personally.
Scott: I don't see the point of the portable handheld video device.
Scott: I mean the iPod with video does nothing for me.
Scott: I don't I don't get it.
Scott: It's a small screen and a shitty experience.
Rym: It's not for you.
Scott: It's obviously not for me.
Scott: So I personally don't care about that feature.
Scott: I wouldn't mind if the feature was there Nah, but I probably wouldn't use it that much and if that wasn't available, I really wouldn't care.
Scott: But playing music I do care because I'm trying to reduce the number of devices I carry.
Scott: and if the phone is as good an mp3 player as say the cow on i-audio 7 or even the iPod I don't need to carry an iPod or a cow on i-audio 7.
Scott: That's one less thing for me to carry.
Scott: So all the better.
Rym: You know, I think that's it.
Scott: No, I don't know.
Scott: I think there's more where I'm concerned.
Rym: What else?
Rym: I mean, we've covered a lot.
Scott: like I could talk about most camera I could say the camera only because the only reason I want a camera in the phone is because I'm not crazy about the picture quality.
Scott: I mean I need good picture quality.
Scott: It can't be pixelated 640 by 480 business, but it's got to be good enough.
Scott: But again one less device to carry.
Scott: If I have a camera in my phone, that's as good as my camera.
Scott: I could just sell my camera and I'll carry one less thing.
Rym: I don't think you will though just because the lenses and everything no matter how many megapixel to get a good picture You need good lenses.
Rym: I'm not gonna get a good camera.
Scott: That is a problem.
Scott: But right now I carry my camera with me in my bag everywhere.
Scott: But if the phone camera was better not it doesn't have to be as good as the camera lens.
Scott: But if it was better enough and I had you know free access to the pictures the same way I have free access to the pictures on my actual I think the free access is a given at this point.
Scott: Yes, obviously Then I wouldn't have to carry my camera unless it was a special occasion where I knew was gonna take a lot of pictures.
Scott: So it would be one less device to carry on a day-to-day basis.
Rym: See, I don't really care about the camera But I don't mind.
Rym: having a camera in a cell phone doesn't have to be good just because every now and then Happens and you got a picture The crazy guy who just tried to attack you or whatever.
Scott: That's what it comes down to is that I only use a camera on a daily basis to take a picture of something random that Happens like oh man picture.
Scott: But if I only take serious pictures of something when I know in advance I'm gonna take pictures.
Scott: So that's all the phone camera has to be capable of.
Scott: you know, if I see something crazy I want to take a short video of it for YouTube or whatever and as long as the phone can do that The last thing that I could think of got another thing.
Scott: the only thing that's the only thing I think of right now is That I want to be able to communicate freely between my phone and my computer.
Scott: So I can back up my phone stuff onto my computer.
Rym: I think that's just a part of.
Rym: I own it.
Rym: I can do whatever I want with that is it is part of that.
Scott: But you know, it's not something a lot of people realize.
Scott: for example my old phone I backed up the contact list and on my new phone I sent the contact list to my new phone and I didn't have to sit there manually adjusting all the contacts.
Scott: and that's only Because I was really smart and I bought a special cable for my old phone and I knew what I was doing.
Scott: Most people can't do that and they manually switch their contacts and they get a new and a lot of phones.
Rym: Just don't let you do it.
Scott: Yeah so pretty much that functionality is limited only to crazy smart computer nerds and that should be Obvious and very easy for everybody.
Scott: It's it's a travesty that it's not people switching the contacts the way they do now.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: it's just not cool Anything else.
Rym: I think that's it.
Rym: at that point I'd buy that phone I'd wait in line overnight I'd skip work to get it.
Scott: I'd be really it was only one of them in the whole world.
Scott: I would I would try to become first in line and yeah, yeah That's.
Scott: if I have all those things Then that is a phone that could significantly change my life and it would become probably the most important device in my life.
Rym: I don't think that phone is gonna be around in the next decade.
Scott: No decade maybe five years Ten years.
Rym: it's tough because all the technological hurdles are gonna get overcome really easily.
Rym: the problem and notice.
Rym: We didn't say size.
Rym: a device they can do all those things can be bigger than a standard phone.
Scott: It could be big.
Scott: it could be big but there is a point in which I'd say.
Scott: All right to be.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if it's as big as like the monitor in front of me, it's gotta be.
Scott: it's gotta be DS light size or smaller because the DS light is like the biggest thing I'd want to put my pocket, you know bigger than that you're getting into sketchy territory.
Scott: Yeah, but I think a lot of course smaller is better though if it was really small like iPod nano size awesome.
Rym: I think a lot of these problems aren't technological They're just part and parcel with the cell phone industry in America Which yeah is making a lot of money and has no reason to change.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The other thing Well, I think part of what it is is that it's sort of like this oligopoly where they're just a few carriers and oligopoly I like that word.
Scott: That's that's a real word.
Rym: I know I just I find it funny.
Scott: All right oligopoly is a real world.
Rym: at me It's when there's a bottle I know I can figure out based on the not the meaning of the word Oligarchy and the meaning of the word monopoly.
Rym: what oligopoly me?
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's a word I actually learned in economics class was a prize.
Scott: You didn't know it already and you had to figure it out.
Rym: I've never run into huh?
Scott: It's bit.
Scott: That's what it's a bunch of companies.
Rym: Usually I just say oligarchy.
Scott: No, it's an oligopoly.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: All right and Together they form this evil group of companies that they all decide to do the same thing sort of like price fixing but in a way It's feature fixing.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's like if every television manufacturer in the world decided to only make black-and-white TVs.
Scott: That's sort of like what this is.
Scott: every cell phone carrier in the?
Scott: u.s decided to only sell lockdown phones and if just one of them would break away and say our phones are unlocked they'd beat everyone else's Ass into the ground one day because most people don't know what that even means.
Scott: That's the thing is they had to accompany it with a marketing campaign that makes everyone realize how much better that is than the other.
Rym: Can't they make more money by just doing what they're doing now?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: and I think the thing is everyone in the in who is in successful business is extremely risk-averse and If they just don't want to take a chance, even if you know what do I'm already making millions and millions and millions of dollars.
Rym: I'm not gonna take risks to make a few more millions I'm gonna keep making.
Scott: I would I would I would always take risk to make more millions at some point.
Rym: I would stop taking risks to make more millions.
Scott: I would never stop taking risk to make more millions.
Scott: That's the whole.
Scott: what's the point then if I'm not again if I'm gonna not take risks, I'm just gonna retire.
Rym: I'll take risks, but I'll use my money to do other things.
Scott: It's take risks until I retire But it's not take risks to make more money.
Rym: It's take risks to have fun Big difference.
Scott: if I was in charge of a business The only reason to be in charge of that business is to take risks to do better business and be more awesome.
Scott: And if there's a point at which I don't want to take risks in the business anymore There's no point in running it cuz it's just gonna sit there doing its thing and I'll just retire.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So yeah phone suck.
Scott: Oh, by the way There everyone usually says all phones in Japan phones in Korea.
Scott: They're so awesome and they are so awesome.
Scott: Oh, are they so awesome like in Japan?
Scott: You can get a phone that watches broadcast TV and stuff like that and it's it's totally nuts but a lot of those features like watching broadcast TV, I really don't care about.
Scott: and In some ways the phones they're still locked down and in some ways they're not.
Scott: and
Rym: while they're
Scott: a lot better than the US And if I was over there, I'd probably buy one and be like, oh man's it's still not perfect
Rym: Well, because partly they're really expensive
Scott: They sure
Rym: are talking on cell phones over there sucks as Emily is miming to me from across the room.
Scott: Yeah, but it is the network is awesome.
Rym: Both sides are bad.
Rym: I mean here it's really cheap to talk but they fuck us and there it's really expensive to talk and they fuck them slightly less.
Scott: Yep, only when the fucking is completely removed will the ultimate phone be purchased.
Rym: I don't see it happening anytime soon.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.