Scott: It's Tuesday July 31st.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we ramble a bit about the shoot-em-up games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know it wasn't too long ago We were talking about poke fatigue And how we were kind of sick and done at Pokemon.
Rym: that kind of got ruined over the week at the shore.
Rym: when?
Rym: Everyone had their pokemans, and they were showing me them.
Scott: well basically.
Scott: I was had super Pokemon fatigue.
Scott: I had no desire to play whatsoever.
Scott: all right I kind of wanted to have the team that I wanted, but I didn't want to play the game at all and so I Didn't play.
Scott: and then at the shore well actually at Otakon someone traded me a spirit tube Which is my favorite Pokemon.
Scott: and then when we got to the the vacation spot?
Scott: I we all went in the underground and I discovered that in the underground there are actual things down there that matter in the game As opposed to just useless spheres and crap.
Rym: however that fact kind of pissed me off.
Rym: I didn't want to have to go down there.
Scott: Yeah, well anyway.
Scott: I like getting the fossils because I like a lot of the fossil type Pokemon.
Rym: No, no you like having the fossils.
Rym: I don't believe you like the process of getting the fossils?
Scott: No, not really, but I do like the fossil pokemons like the omenites and the Kabuto's right.
Scott: so You know I was having a little bit of fun with the Pokemon again suddenly And then I had two spirit tombs and I started hatching spirit two megs.
Scott: Scott made a million spirit two megs and then I was hatching combis and Komi is the best Pokemon combis an awesome Pokemon, and then I said hey, I got spirits whom I got combi Let's get this on.
Scott: and I started playing a lot more pokemons.
Scott: And then I haven't played pokemons since I got home.
Rym: see I wasn't a little bit of different boat I was just stuck.
Rym: I didn't know where to go cuz I hadn't played it in a while.
Rym: I didn't remember what was going on in the plot.
Scott: well That's why when you turn the game on it.
Scott: Tells you what you did last.
Rym: yeah And what I did last was wander around trying to figure out where to go.
Scott: Awesome,
Rym: so as someone told me and I went up and I got my Gigantic special Pokemon and did all that and I'm nearing the end of the game And I realized that yeah, I want to actually beat this game however When I was playing around with everyone else and they were all in the underground and I refused to participate in that underground shenanigans.
Rym: I I realized that a lot of the things that I can do in this game But that I probably should do to have optimal Pokemon.
Rym: I'm not willing to do Evie training.
Rym: I'm gonna fuck it.
Scott: So I'm not willing to do those things either.
Scott: I'm just gonna.
Scott: you know basically the only other reason I started playing again is Because after you beat the game this island in the and the Northeast opens up to you, right?
Scott: so I explored that entire island before I got fatigued and There was a volcano on that island that I just couldn't get to somehow.
Scott: So I kind of stopped playing because I couldn't get to the volcano or figure out how.
Scott: and I figured out how to go up That volcano.
Scott: so that sort of brought me back into the game and I'm pretty sure even though I'm fatigued again I will un-fatigued enough to go up the whole volcano also.
Scott: We're just walking around the game like doing stuff while people were around.
Scott: I discovered like hidden places in the game I didn't know about before like the Fuego ironworks and stuff like that.
Scott: I also learned how to use the versus seeker.
Rym: So that's been around a while.
Scott: I know I just never knew how to use it properly.
Scott: It was like I'd push the button.
Scott: It would make a noise and it wouldn't do anything.
Scott: So I was like how the hell is this piece of shit work?
Scott: Cuz they weren't.
Scott: it didn't come with directions So I didn't know how to make it do its thing.
Rym: They kind of told you what it did and how to use it.
Scott: No, not when I got it.
Scott: when I got it It said you can use this to fight trainers again, and I'm like, okay how?
Rym: so didn't you wonder like?
Rym: Maybe I should go to where trainers are that I fought once.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I didn't even try really.
Scott: so Push the button.
Scott: it made a noise and didn't do anything once.
Scott: so I put it away And I could never get it to work in the older games either.
Scott: So yeah, basically because I figured out how some stuff works in the game and found some new places a slightly rekindled interest.
Scott: But that's about it I don't know.
Rym: I think for me and I said at the shore quite famously that I'm done with Pokemon to which people responded Well, then give me all your pokemons.
Rym: I'm not done with it in that regard I'm done with it in the sense that I am NOT going to put any effort into this game other than getting My perfect team maybe one like funny auxiliary team I'm thinking to make it an all anthropomorphic team great because there's actually far more than six anthropomorphic Pokemon at this point.
Scott: yep,
Rym: and That's gonna be it because while I realized I don't really care about a good 80% of the game And I've already gotten the whole Pokemon experience It is kind of fun to battle with other people in public and I need a team to be able to do that.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing is I really want to have a perfect team of six Pokemon I really like but I do not want to have to do the work necessary to get that team.
Rym: So I realized I'm gonna do the work to get a team That's good enough to sit at an artist alley table and play against you listeners But I'm not gonna make a team that's good enough to beat the kid with six legendaries in the tournament.
Rym: No, I'm definitely not gonna do this level one EV trains sub to hacked legendaries.
Rym: Yeah okay, so in the news I With we miss this since we were out on vacation But I find this sort of thing fascinating and it's the kind of thing we talk about a lot.
Rym: It's also the kind of thing that gets us hecklers at Connecticut on.
Rym: yeah But we've talked a lot about board games and German games and how a lot of times we get sick of a game once we Solve it.
Rym: You know when you realize you come to the core of a game and you read you now know the exact Optimal move to make at any time and beyond.
Rym: that victory is either predetermined or random.
Rym: Well, uh Some games particularly perfect information games can be solved in a very simple but not easy way.
Rym: now I say simple but not easy because it is simple.
Rym: There is it's a perfect information game.
Rym: You know every possible move.
Rym: you can't hide information from the other person.
Rym: Everyone knows everything.
Rym: So all you have to do is have a computer try every single possible move.
Rym: That's very simple.
Rym: It's not however easy because a game like say checkers or chess has a lot of possible moves Like a bajillion.
Rym: Well people have been working on these problems and a lot of smaller games have been solved in the past Like I believe five by five go is perfectly solved.
Rym: Yep, just recently the game of checkers a game that I very much enjoy.
Scott: you enjoy checkers.
Rym: I did it.
Rym: I enjoyed checkers more than chess.
Scott: I kind of like checkers, of course.
Rym: I think the reason was when I was a kid I had a friend named Adam who was actually a semi professional chess competitor And he was super super good and he was ranked.
Rym: and as a result Whenever I played chess, I always fucking lost and it was no fun at all.
Scott: I used to like chess more than like it now because Like when I'm just a kid and I got like little pieces that I'll move in weird ways It's like ooh wee fun times killing the other guys, you know.
Scott: But once you know chess sort of opened up and I saw what chess really was all about.
Scott: I didn't like that.
Scott: I'm not a fan.
Rym: Yeah playing against him like seeing the patterns and realizing that the game was not about tactics or strategy.
Rym: Well, I guess it was about strategy.
Rym: It's more about memorizing patterns long complex patterns.
Rym: Yeah, anyway The game of checkers which I thought was fun is solved completely and perfectly.
Rym: It turns out that the first player black is guaranteed if he plays optimally and the other person also plays optimally a draw.
Scott: Yep, it's just like tic-tac-toe if everyone plays perfectly and makes the best possible move every time the game is a tie Every time yep.
Rym: So by the same token no matter what player one does has his first move player two white can automatically if they make optimal moves from this point forward no matter what make the game a draw.
Rym: as a result the game of checkers is Completely and fundamentally and utterly broken and solved in every possible way.
Scott: Yep, playing checkers is basically the same as playing tic-tac-toe.
Scott: It's the same game now of course
Rym: this brings up the interesting point that the heckler at ConnectiCon wouldn't let us get to while checkers is solved and done and a Person who theoretically knows the solved state and the ways to all the patterns leading up to the solved state Can never lose the game of checkers.
Rym: most people don't know this at all And as a result the game is still relatively strategic and tactical for those people.
Rym: So what it comes down to is a game.
Rym: whether or not is solved is fun or not fun Depending on how much you have solved it relative to how much the other person is solved.
Rym: That's why little kids have a lot of fun with tic-tac-toe And that's why me and Scott and pretty much everyone in the world who's intelligent Had a lot of fun with settlers of Catan for you know, two three years before they eventually solved it.
Rym: Yep So I guess the moral here is just because a game is solvable or We're down on a game because we solved it doesn't mean that game isn't awesome.
Rym: It just means we're done with it.
Scott: Yeah, that's it the game over.
Rym: computers are done with checkers.
Scott: Computers aren't you done with checkers?
Scott: You know, they'll don't play checkers against the computer.
Scott: you the best you can hope for is to tie.
Scott: Yep, and that's if you play Perfectly with no mistakes one mistake you lose.
Rym: Yeah, apparently on this site.
Rym: They've solved a bunch of other things.
Rym: A worry is solved.
Rym: I don't remember body.
Rym: I don't remember if that's the game.
Rym: I know or if I know Mancala, but I know one of the Connect for learn how to play Mancala actually connect four has been solved by multiple people.
Scott: Oh, okay I'm pretty sure I play connect for pretty close to solved I'm close, but I'm not great because the Linux computer on hard beats me about Pretty much.
Rym: the only time I lose go is five by five solved and Othello is six by six solved.
Scott: That's why we play big Othello.
Rym: God Othello is a good game.
Rym: Yeah, I used to play that with my dad all the time.
Rym: I don't think I ever beat him.
Scott: I think of all the games of perfect information.
Scott: Othello is a non randomness.
Scott: Othello is my my favorite.
Rym: I really do like Othello.
Rym: Yeah, if I hadn't known Adam Cole as a kid, I probably would have liked chess a lot more.
Scott: Yeah, of course, I think if you disk if you include the random perfect information games, I like the backgammon's.
Rym: See, I like backgammon's but there is a lot of randomness and there is a lot of it.
Rym: It's pretty easy to make optimal move and it is easy to make optimal moves.
Scott: But I also like in backgammon is the risk-taking going on, but the other games don't have so much true.
Rym: But then again, it's just odds playing.
Rym: It's one of those.
Rym: All right I have a 60% chance of this move being off being good.
Rym: However, if I take this move, there's a 30% chance that it'll completely fucking own the other guy.
Rym: But a 20% chance that'll completely fucking own me and you know all these.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's exactly backgammon.
Scott: I kind of like it.
Rym: Well, yeah, I think part of that is that's kind of how life is it?
Rym: Life is not a perfect information game.
Scott: Life is like a backgammon?
Rym: Kinda I'd extend the analogy but I'm done with that.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I also like, you know, I mean, come on backgammon.
Rym: But seriously check out this site out.
Rym: and Lincoln Gannon if you think good God if you think this is pretty cool I'd recommend you try to read about game theory.
Rym: All right warning if you don't like math you won't like game theory.
Scott: Okay, so I don't really have much news really but there's a whole bunch of video games out really recently and soon.
Scott: You're ready for this?
Rym: Oh the video games.
Rym: We've got to buy them.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: Here's the video games.
Scott: I think yes.
Scott: - well, first of all, I bought Planet Puzzle League for the DS which came out in early June.
Rym: It's pretty freaking hot.
Scott: It's it's panel day pawn aka Tetris attack aka now granted Pokemon Puzzle League kind of bought it by accident.
Rym: We were trying to leave Otakon to get to the beach and do our things at the beach But Scott decided he had to go shoe shopping.
Rym: So we dragged me and Pete into the mall and pranced around looking for shoes.
Scott: I didn't.
Rym: I wait like an hour.
Scott: I went to Foot Locker for like two seconds saw they had no shoes I wanted and walked out.
Rym: So Scott was prancing around looking for shoes But he couldn't find any you liked and I guess he couldn't find a matching handbag to go with the shoes.
Scott: So he ended up not buying any.
Scott: Meanwhile, for less than 30 seconds.
Rym: Meanwhile, me and Pete being men went over to the GameStop.
Scott: I went to the GameStop immediately after like 30 seconds.
Rym: Yeah, because the handbag didn't match the frickin shoes you wanted.
Scott: Because they sell handbags at Foot Locker.
Rym: Suffice to say Scott shoe shopping made us about an hour late to the show.
Scott: It made us like It was not what made us late.
Rym: What made us late was the handbag not matching the shoes that you wanted.
Rym: The parking fee being an ass The parking fee might have been slightly less if you hadn't desperately and suddenly needed to buy shoes.
Scott: The parking feed was not a result of my 30 seconds.
Rym: We drove 300 miles to an anime convention.
Rym: We were about to drive another hundred and something miles to the shore.
Scott: And I spent 30 seconds in a Foot Locker.
Rym: And suddenly Suddenly Scott decides I need to buy shoes.
Scott: Yeah, I did because my sneakers are pretty much dead.
Scott: I'm probably gonna replace them this weekend.
Rym: If only the handbag had matched.
Scott: Right Anyway How long are you gonna keep this up?
Rym: You see you guys don't realize that Pete and I made fun of Scott along these lines for about four hours total non-consecutively.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: Pretty much until my voice gave out.
Scott: Right, because I spent 30 seconds in a Foot Locker.
Rym: Well, the handbag wouldn't match.
Scott: God damn it.
Scott: What the fuck's wrong with you?
Scott: Are you sure you didn't take drugs before the show started?
Rym: I might have.
Scott: Great.
Rym: I took a bunch of Sudafed and I had some Rym summertime lemonade.
Scott: Aren't you not supposed to make those?
Rym: No, you're not supposed to mix Nyquil and Rym summertime lemonade Uh-huh.
Rym: Because Nyquil has acetaminophen in it, which is bad for your liver.
Scott: But doesn't Nyquil also have alcohol in it?
Rym: I didn't take Nyquil.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So it doesn't matter.
Scott: Okay, so Pokemon puzzle- Pokemon puzzle.
Scott: Planet- Planet Puzzle League.
Scott: I got that, right?
Scott: So that's out.
Scott: Picross DS.
Scott: If you never played, there was original- There's a game called Mario Picross for the original Game Boy.
Rym: A lot of people haven't played it.
Rym: I'll admit that I had never heard of it or played it until Scott showed me about it.
Scott: You can actually- you can go online and Someone made a Flash game.
Scott: If you just search on Google for Wii Picross, P-I-C-R-O-S-S They made a Flash game that you can play on the Wii.
Scott: That's basically Picross.
Scott: And that's how you can learn what Picross is and how to play.
Scott: And if you like that, then you should probably buy Picross.
Scott: Basically, it's a puzzle, sort of like the ones you find in a puzzle book that you would buy in the newsstand.
Scott: And you try to basically decode this grid to create a picture that consists of pixels that are either on or off.
Scott: Another game you should pay attention to.
Scott: Oh, the first game for the Wii that I think is gonna be exciting.
Scott: Just today, or just tomorrow, I'm not sure.
Scott: Mario Strikers Charge for the Wii.
Scott: It's out.
Scott: US.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: Maybe we'll buy it this weekend.
Rym: We really should because we jumped on the old Mario Strikers bandwagon way too late.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: That game was pretty fantastic even though we both pretty much- Scott was better than me just because he played it more than me, but we pretty much dominated anyone else.
Rym: we played against just because we played it slightly more than the rest of them.
Scott: Yep, so if we get on this one early, it'll be pretty cool.
Scott: Worms DS.
Scott: If you don't know, there was a Worms for the DS already, and it sucked.
Rym: It sucked ass!
Rym: That was one of the most disappointing things in the world because Worms always has the potential to be awesome, much like Scorched Earth was awesome.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, Worms DS is supposed- is coming out on August 6th, the second Worms DS, and hopefully, it won't suck like the first Worms DS, and I guess we're just gonna have to wait and see on that one.
Scott: What other exciting games?
Scott: The Metroid game, I think, comes out towards the end of August, maybe.
Scott: I'm not quite sure.
Rym: I'm kind of excited just because I really don't like controlling games with the analog stick looking around, and if I can look around with a Wii stick, I'm all about that.
Scott: Yeah, we'll finally see how good the Wii is for FPSing and not with the stupid red whatever the the other one.
Rym: Yeah, that game just came out.
Scott: It's a World War II game.
Rym: Was it World War II?
Scott: There was a World War II game.
Rym: Because there was that Yakuza game, Red Steel.
Scott: That's the Red Steel.
Scott: Yeah, there were quite a- there are a few FPSes on the Wii, not so hot.
Scott: Hopefully, the Metroid will be hot, and yeah, there's some other games coming out.
Scott: You should probably go on the internets and look at the release schedules because it's gonna basically slowly build up until the holiday season when you're gonna get the explosion, mostly with the Smash Brothers, but, you know.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is, we've been a little bit behind on the video games, haven't been buying the new ones.
Scott: Oh, right, I forgot.
Scott: I think I said on the show before that Paper Mario is out on the- the original Nintendo 64.
Scott: Paper Mario is out on the Wii.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: For the Virtual Console.
Rym: There is, however, a much more important game.
Scott: And that's probably worth buying.
Scott: However, just yesterday, they released Dynamite Headdy for the Wii Virtual Console.
Scott: Now, Dynamite Headdy is a game I had as a kid for the Sega Genesis.
Scott: And it's not a very well-known game, and you might be thinking, "What the fuck, Dynamite
Scott: Headdy?".
Scott: I don't know, what the fuck is that shit, right?
Scott: Dynamite Headdy is a game made by Treasure.
Scott: If you never heard of Treasure, you probably should have, because they're a game development house that sort of makes all these awesome games.
Scott: They made Gunstar Heroes, which is also on Virtual Console.
Scott: Dynamite Headdy, I would say, is one of maybe the best 10 2D platform games ever.
Rym: Let me put it this way.
Rym: I really didn't like the Sega Genesis, and I hated most of the games that came out on it.
Rym: However, this game, when Scott showed it to me, I had to respect it.
Rym: I feel a little bit bad for everything missed out on it as a kid.
Scott: You know, it's the walking and the jumping, and you basically, you're this guy with a head that's sort of detached, and you shoot your head at things in eight different directions.
Rym: It's not as dumb as it sounds.
Scott: It's not as dumb as it sounds, and the theme of the world is like this big puppet world on a stage, and the things keep changing, and the music is cool, and the enemy, your nemesis, Trouble Bruin, is pretty cool.
Scott: He's like this cat thing, and he always, at first, you fight him with his normal cat body, and then he attaches his head to all sorts of robots later on, and you have to play the game just to get the experience.
Scott: Don't read any strategy guides or anything.
Scott: Just play through, and it's really cool, and it's not like any other platform you've ever played, and when you switch all these different weird heads, and you find all these secrets, and you interact with the environment in weird ways, and it's a load of fun.
Scott: Play Dynamite Headdy.
Scott: It's one of the only virtual console games worth your money.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: So I thought this was somewhat interesting, and while there's a tiny chance it's not true, I know enough about criminals and prisons to know that they are some ingenious motherfuckers, and they come up with some elaborate ways.
Scott: I mean, if you're- I think one of our earliest things of the day was the gallery of shivs, was it not?
Rym: Not shavs, shivs.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: You know what I like more than killing?
Scott: Stabbing?
Scott: Nothing.
Rym: Except maybe biscuits.
Rym: God, I gotta find that prison funnies again.
Rym: I didn't see it at the mocha this year, so I couldn't buy the next one.
Scott: Maybe you should look it up on the internet.
Rym: I probably should.
Rym: I didn't think of that until just now.
Rym: I was reminded of it just now.
Rym: But apparently, people in prisons, you know, they get a little bit of money, and they can buy little things sometimes to keep themselves company.
Rym: They bought PS2s occasionally and video game systems, but the one system that everyone hated when they bought and they tried to keep them from getting was the N64.
Rym: Because the N64's rumble pack could fairly easily be turned into a wicked awesome prison tattoo gun.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Quote, "It's actually pretty easy.
Rym: There's no workshops in maximum security.
Rym: They do it in their rooms with a battery power taped to a tube.
Rym: The motor from the rumble is then taken out and attached to the top of the tube.
Rym: A needle or pin is run down the middle of the tube.
Rym: When on, the needle will move up and down like a sewing machine.
Rym: The needle is then dipped in the ink.
Rym: The ink is made from the ink inside of a ballpoint
Rym: pen.".
Scott: That's a wonderful tattoo that I'm sure won't hurt at all or damage you permanently in any way.
Rym: I don't think that just-- I don't think there's any prison tattoo that's not going to hurt a lot and not going to be bad for you in some way.
Scott: Why don't they just have an actual tattoo parlor in the goddamn prison so that people could do it properly?
Rym: Because most of the tattoos people get are to affiliate with their gang whatevers, and the prisons don't want to encourage that.
Rym: Also, the prisons are generally kind of corrupt and broken in the US.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rym: But that's beside the point.
Rym: The point is, if you want to make yourself a custom prison tattoo, get yourself a rumble pack from an N64 and a ballpoint pen.
Scott: I think what it shows is that if you think that computer hackers or attackers in general do poorly in prison because they're weak and they'll get their asses beat and raped, probably not because they can come up with stuff like this ten times better than the prisoners can.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, think, these are not smart dudes in prison.
Rym: If they were smart, they wouldn't be in prison.
Scott: So imagine smart dudes in prison.
Rym: Thing is, I still don't want to go to prison.
Rym: No, definitely not, but-- Yeah, you know that whole rather rule in hell than serve in heaven?
Rym: I wouldn't really care about ruling the prison.
Scott: No.
Scott: All right, so, one of the hardest NES games I've ever played.
Scott: I mean, it's not the hardest ever, period, but it's a damn fucking hard game.
Scott: I mean, the game is basically a dick.
Scott: It's hard and long.
Scott: The game is Battletoad.
Scott: The game is Battletoads, and if you ever played Battletoads, you'll know what I'm talking about.
Scott: And if you haven't played Battletoads, you should go play Battletoads.
Scott: It's a classic game everyone should play.
Rym: The story behind Battletoads is very simply, Battletoads was a mediocre game, a little bit similar to like the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles arcade game.
Scott: It was a walk sideways beat 'em up game.
Rym: But it also had a couple of cool modes and a couple of neat things, but basically it was mostly ignored, and a marketing effort, hitherto unseen by the likes of man, was brought forth by Nintendo through Nintendo Power, complete with comics.
Scott: I don't think it was Nintendo specifically.
Rym: Nintendo Power had this gigantic blitz of Battletoads is the best game ever.
Scott: They didn't make Battletoads, though.
Scott: It wasn't a game made by Nintendo.
Rym: But they pushed Battletoads.
Scott: It was made by Rare, and Rare, I guess, paid everyone to push it off.
Rym: Regardless of who paid for it, Nintendo and Nintendo Power pushed Battletoads more than they pushed the average game.
Scott: It was a heavily pushed game, and there were ads in every video game magazine, and I think there was a TV cartoon, and there was a whole bunch of stuff going on with Battletoads.
Rym: The comic was particularly bad.
Rym: The only thing I remember from it is the bad guy had a bumper sticker that said, "I, Club, and then
Rym: Battletoads.".
Scott: Basically, the problem was that they wanted to beat Ninja Turtles, so they made Battletoads, and they pushed it as hard as they could, and it kind of worked, but it didn't beat Ninja Turtles.
Scott: It just also succeeded on some level.
Rym: The game had a lot of wacky, zany weirdness in it, and also a lot of really fucking hard jumps.
Scott: Yep, and it was a good game anyway.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't the greatest game, but it was a good game, and it's important to play Battletoads.
Scott: This video is a speedrun of Battletoads.
Scott: Hot damn.
Scott: It is not a perfect speedrun of Battletoads.
Scott: The guy dies a few times, he does a few things sub-optimally, but it's still wicked, crazy, stupid fast, way faster than I could ever do it.
Rym: What was it?
Rym: He beat it in like 25 minutes?
Scott: 25 minutes.
Rym: It took me as a kid, like me and my little brother, I think four or five hours to actually beat the stupid game.
Scott: Yep, so watch this.
Scott: It's pretty amazing, and play Battletoads, and also watch this video, and play Battletoads, and watch the video.
Rym: So, a genre of gaming somewhat underserved nowadays, partly due to games that call themselves these, but are actually something else entirely.
Rym: Gonna talk a bit about the shmups.
Scott: Well, actually, shmups, if you want to get, I don't know, depending on what facts you decide to agree upon, the shmup might be the oldest genre of video game, period.
Scott: I mean, space war.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Space Invaders.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: Galaga.
Scott: Galaga's a lot less old than Space Invaders.
Rym: Yeah, but even so, it's older than most people.
Scott: Galaxian.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You know, the prequel to Galaga.
Rym: You know, I've never actually played Galaxian.
Scott: You've never played Galaxian?
Rym: Nah, I've seen it, just never bothered playing it.
Scott: You know...
Rym: I've seen it.
Scott: With the bats.
Rym: I know, I've seen a lot of people play it.
Scott: I've played so much Galaxian.
Rym: I've played a lot more Galaga.
Scott: I've played a lot of Galaga too, but I've played so much Galaxian.
Scott: You've never played a single Galaxian?
Rym: You know what, I've played a lot more than all those games combined.
Scott: Galaxian on Windows 3.1 in the Microsoft Arcade Pack.
Rym: GigaWing.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Alright, so.
Scott: Shmups are pretty damn cool.
Rym: Should we define shmup?
Scott: You want to define shmup?
Scott: Alright.
Scott: The thing is, if you want to be non-so-strict with your interpretation of the word shmup, it's a shoot 'em up.
Scott: So you could consider something like, I don't know, Gunstar Heroes or... What's that name?
Scott: I forget the game for the Super Nintendo.
Rym: R-Type, Gradius?
Scott: No, no, no, those are obviously shmups.
Scott: The one where the guy walks sideways.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There was that prototype game that everyone has a ROM of, of a superhero that flies sideways or walks sideways, but...
Scott: No.
Scott: But depending on how liberal you are with your definitions, there are a lot of games that you could consider to be shmups that aren't actually space shmups, specifically.
Rym: Yeah, generally the way I take a shmup is a game that either topscrolls or sidescrolls, and you have some sort of craft, and the craft moves around, and you can shoot projectiles out of the craft and possibly power the craft up.
Scott: Oh, what about like, uh, Pocky and Rocky?
Rym: Uh, yeah, Pocky and Rocky looks like a mystical ninja kind of game, but it's actually a shmup, really.
Scott: Sort of.
Rym: The way it plays it is.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically a game where you shoot things, you move around in two or two... I mean, well, I guess, is it... Can you... Is any 3D game a shmup?
Scott: I mean...
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: You could make a 3D-ish shmup, but...
Scott: I mean, is Descent a shmup?
Rym: See, I wouldn't think so.
Rym: I'd call that an FPS, partly because you're in the first person there.
Rym: In shmups, you're always in the third person, straight up.
Scott: Oh, but what if you played Descent with the third person camera, which you can do?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I wouldn't... See, I personally wouldn't consider it a shmup, but I'm not the kind of person who would argue over the, uh, minute details of the term shmup.
Scott: Yes, but basically, a shmup is a game that involves moving, uh, something around the screen and having that thing not get hit by bullets while shooting things at... The primary thing you do in the game is shoot and dodge.
Scott: Shooting bad guys with projectiles while dodging enemies and the projectiles they shoot.
Rym: I think some of the best examples I can think of are games like Gradius, R-Type, uh, 1942.
Scott: Life Force, UN Squadron.
Scott: Ikaruga, Space Invaders.
Rym: Yeah, even though Ikaruga sucks.
Scott: Space Invaders, Einhonder.
Rym: Giga Wing.
Scott: Darius and all of its incarnations.
Rym: All those Raiden games.
Scott: Raiden, yeah.
Rym: UN Squadron.
Scott: I said UN Squadron.
Rym: I wasn't listening at all.
Scott: Oh, good job.
Rym: Well, Area 88.
Scott: At least I think I said UN Squadron.
Rym: You better have, I love that game.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I never beat that game, but I love it.
Scott: I never beat it either.
Scott: Raptor Call of the Shadows.
Rym: Oh, that game is like the best one ever.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: At least for me.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: I'll admit that I was never good at these games.
Scott: Oh, I'm good at some of them, but not all of them.
Scott: And uh, yeah, shmups are pretty cool because they're basically a test of pure dexterity.
Rym: Did you say Legendary Wings?
Scott: No.
Rym: You should have.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I like that game.
Scott: It's all about dexterity and hand-eye coordination.
Scott: You got a whole bunch of shit on the screen, you're moving a guy around to avoid it, but you're also trying to shoot all the things on the screen that are making stuff to avoid.
Scott: And, you know, depending on the shmup, this works in different ways because, you know, what if you shoot diagonally?
Scott: You got to move in such a way.
Scott: What if there's way too many, some like, look at R-Type compared to Gradius, right?
Scott: R-Type is actually quite difficult because it's all about precisely moving your craft and you have this sort of sub shield thing that you can shoot and move around the screen.
Scott: And it's all about when do you release the shield?
Scott: When do you call the shield back?
Scott: Use the shield in a clever way to kill a bad guy quickly, but bring it back quick enough so that the other bad guys don't get you.
Scott: You know, when the terrain of the screen moves around in such a way, you know, stand in the exact right spot and make very small precise movements not to get hit.
Scott: Whereas Gradius is more shoot the bad guys, be in the right position to shoot them, make them get a lot, a lot of power ups and use your options to kill everything really fast before you get hit.
Rym: Or then there's games like Ikaruga, which are basically a memorize the exact sequence of moves you must make to get the highest score on this level, then memorize the exact sequence of moves to get a high score on the next level.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, Ikaruga is interesting in that it has the mechanic of when you push a button, you switch from black to white and when you're black, black things can't hit you and your black weapon hurts white bad guys more.
Scott: And when you switch to white, white things can't hurt you and your white weapon hurts black bad guys more.
Scott: And when you kill bad guys, they release little pellets.
Scott: And if you absorb them because you're the same color as the pellets, then you power up your super weapon.
Scott: So you'll see R-type masters.
Scott: Usually what they do is they'll switch colors, collect a bunch of pellets, release the super weapon, switch colors, release a bunch of pellets.
Rym: I believe you mean Ikaruga.
Scott: Yeah, Ikaruga, right.
Scott: What did I say?
Rym: R-type.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: R-type masters are much better than that.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Thing is, it's kind of enjoyable to watch a person play Ikaruga, but I tried to play it a bunch of times and it wasn't fun.
Rym: I pretty much just have to play it and memorize what I had to do.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, basically Ikaruga on paper is an awesome shmup.
Scott: The problem is you can't play it the same way.
Scott: you play a shmup and it's not fun.
Scott: It lacks what makes the other shmups fun, which is just sort of trying to escape the bullets, not get hit, try to freewheel it, get to the end.
Scott: Because the way you get more points is to do these combos.
Scott: And the levels are exactly the same thing every time.
Scott: And it really does, the way to play and win is to memorize exactly what to do.
Scott: The game even has demo mode where it shows you what to do in a near optimal way.
Scott: And then you copy or memorize what the game did and you try to do it yourself.
Rym: See, the sad thing is I feel like that is the direction that almost all Japanese shmups are going these days.
Rym: Every video I see of the end of some shmup is something along those lines.
Rym: Like the absolute perfect precise, this is the one pixel of my ship that can be hit and I'm slowly moving it left and right to avoid the billion billion billion billion projectiles in the precise manner.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I hate that.
Scott: It's not fun.
Scott: It's much more fun for there to be a lot, but not too many projectiles where you can sort of look at the screen and react quick enough based on what you see.
Scott: You know, even if it's you need to have a very quick reaction to succeed, you know, to avoid things and also have a weapon powerful enough to destroy the bad guys.
Scott: I don't want my not so powerful and so large that you just kill all the bad guys without doing anything and it's boring.
Rym: I don't want my shmup to be like that stupid piece of pizza and turtles that you just can't get.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: I don't want there to be a piece of pizza that I could only have gotten if I knew to stay near the bottom of the screen exactly 27.8 seconds into the third level.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Now there are actually a lot of newer shmups that are sort of doing interesting things.
Scott: There's that Japanese guy, I forget his name.
Scott: He's the, he's sort of an independent shmup developer.
Scott: And the one game that he's made that's pretty popular is to Miki fighters, which is you shoot bad guys and they're made of blocks.
Scott: And then as the bad guys are dying, you crash into their broken ships and they become part of your ship.
Scott: And that sort of adds to your arsenal, but it adds to your size as well.
Rym: See, I love stuff like that in jet and shmups or any other kind of game.
Rym: I really like a good way to progress, especially an interesting way.
Rym: I think that's why I like Kirby so much because it captures some new bad guy and I get some cool new power to you.
Scott: That's why G Darius is so cool because in G Darius, you have the third weapon, which allows you to grab bad guys and bring them over to your team.
Scott: And you can have any bad guy pretty much on your team at a time.
Scott: You can only have one bad guy at a time, but pretty much anything that's not a boss you can grab.
Scott: So you always wait for those sort of mid boss enemies and you use them to destroy and then you carry them around with you for the rest of the level dealing insane damages.
Rym: I love that.
Scott: Yeah, but G Darius is a good one, but Darius games are fun because all the bad guys are big robotic fish and it's always funny.
Rym: See, I was just in general, never very good at shmups.
Rym: And the only ones I really played a lot were like the Battle of Midway.
Rym: I played a lot because I actually owned it.
Rym: And Legendary Wings, which I rented three times.
Scott: I never heard of Legendary Wings.
Rym: It was on the NES or SNES.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: Angels, Flying Wings, SHMUP.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Oh, there's, um, what's the one where it's half SHMUP, half like RPG?
Rym: Oh, you can't remember.
Scott: Guardian, Guardian Legends.
Rym: That game, I can't believe I forgot the name of it for a second.
Rym: The game was impossible, but at the same time, that game was like this wonderful mystery to me.
Rym: And as a kid, I spent so many hours trying to solve it and figure out what was going on.
Rym: And I never got very far because I wasn't good at the SHMUP part.
Scott: Does Sinistar count?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Sinistar is really kind of a unique game.
Scott: It is a unique game, and it's hard to say if it's a SHMUP or not.
Scott: Basically, I can't believe, have we ever talked about Sinistar on the show?
Rym: If we have or if we haven't, we're going to do it at some point in the future.
Scott: I don't think we should spoil it.
Scott: We should do a whole show on Sinistar.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All I want to say is I would love to see Sinistar remade.
Scott: Sinistar is a very old arcade game that is semi-unknown, semi-infamous, very awesome, easily turned into 4chan memes.
Rym: I hunger.
Rym: I live.
Scott: Run, coward.
Scott: Run, run, run.
Scott: Basically, Sinistar had this digitized voice of the things that Sinistar said, and Sinistar said some funny things like "I hunger" and "Beware, I
Scott: live.".
Scott: Yeah, Sinistar.
Scott: It's sort of a SHMUP, but not really.
Rym: Our friend Pete is probably the only person I know personally who's actually good at that game.
Scott: I'm okay at it.
Scott: I practiced.
Scott: I can get some Cinnabombs.
Scott: And yes, they are called Cinnabombs.
Rym: Not Cinnabons.
Scott: No, not Cinnabons.
Scott: Cinnabombs.
Scott: Like boom, but cinnamon.
Rym: Granted, that one lady we met at that rest stop back there could have used some Cinnabombs instead.
Scott: Yeah, she could have.
Rym: I think she was trying to build the Sinistar inside of herself.
Scott: I think she already was the Sinistar.
Rym: She was big enough.
Scott: So, what else is there to say about SHMUPs?
Scott: Uh, SHMUPs, I like them because it's sort of a game where I can use, I can just pick it up and play it at any time with no worries.
Scott: It's a lot of fun to keep getting power-ups that make my weapon bigger and bigger and bigger.
Scott: And it's a lot of fun to just dodge things and shoot things, you know, and where the simple controls of move around and shoot and that's it.
Rym: So, it's kind of the Jerry Seinfeld thing.
Rym: Moving around, shooting around.
Scott: Moving around, shooting around and it's a simple control, but the actual game is very advanced and complex.
Scott: You have to move in complex patterns and see what's coming up.
Scott: In a way, it's sort of like DDR and you have these arrows coming at you and you have to sort of push these very few buttons in a pattern, you know, in a correct way that you can match the pattern.
Rym: Actually, what I really like and what I want to see more of, particularly on the DS with the Wi-Fi or in the wireless, is some sort of versus or cooperative many-player shmuping.
Scott: Well, there's that, what was the one?
Rym: The one on the Xbox?
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: The one that's on the DS.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that nanostray game.
Scott: I'm not sure if that has multiplayer, but I heard that the second one might have some multiplayer.
Scott: So, that's pretty cool.
Rym: Oh, go ahead.
Rym: I just remembered something.
Scott: A lot of older shmups have co-op play, which is also something interesting because back in those days, the only games with co-op play were beat-em-ups and shoot-em-ups, pretty much em-ups.
Scott: You would either, two people would walk down the street beating stuff up or two people would fly through space shooting bad guys together.
Scott: And as time went on, the co-op shmups kind of went away.
Rym: Well, co-op gaming kind of went away.
Scott: Yeah, now it's sort of back and coming back, but...
Rym: I think the Xbox has a lot to do with that because a lot of the best co-op gaming was always on the PC and now the Xbox and Xbox Live...
Scott: Co-op gaming was always on the NES, where the shmups and the beat-em-ups were.
Scott: And then the SNES not so much and the Genesis a little bit.
Scott: And then when you got to the N64 in the 3D days, the co-op gaming was pretty much gone.
Rym: Too many games became just that player one, player two, player one.
Scott: And then all the 3D games on the PlayStation and the N64 and stuff were all 3D games that had split-screen multiplayer, but no co-op action.
Rym: What I just remembered is, and I gotta remember the name of it, but at Otakon in the far left of the video game room, we saw a game that was like this versus shmup.
Rym: Kind of like those puzzle-y fond games, but you pick a cute little girl and you fly the cute little girls against each other.
Rym: And depending on how well you shmup, it puts bad guys on the other person's screen.
Scott: Yeah, you know how you play like a puzzle game against someone and when you do better, it puts more crap on the other person's screen.
Rym: You set up the combo and then you blow it off and then they get screwed unless they counter it and all that stuff.
Rym: It was that, but it was a shmup with cute girls.
Scott: You picked, it looked like witches, basically.
Scott: And you picked a witch.
Scott: and I guess depending on which witch you picked, yeah.
Scott: Depending on which witch you selected, it would send different bad guys over to the other side.
Scott: And you played a shmup on your side and the more bad guys you killed and the better you played, the harder it made it for the other person.
Scott: And if they cleared out the stuff that they got sent over, then it sent worse stuff over to you.
Scott: And it was pretty cool and I kind of wanted to play it, but there was a line.
Rym: There wasn't a line.
Rym: I was about to say we really wanted to play it, but there was just this guy sitting there playing it.
Scott: And there was another guy there, too.
Rym: There's two guys, but there was no one else.
Rym: And those two just kept playing it.
Rym: And eventually we walked away.
Rym: Thing is, though, that's a wider gripe I have about pretty much every convention other than the classic gaming at Katsucon.
Rym: It seems like there's really no enforcement of any sort of etiquette of, all right, let someone else play the goddamn game.
Scott: Well, the thing is, when you go to an arcade or if you're in a place with like relatively few games, there is sort of an etiquette about getting up from the game.
Rym: But no one follows that anymore, at least depending on what people do follow it.
Scott: The problem is, is that when you have a big convention, most people do follow the etiquette of, you know, you play a game, you know, maybe the loser walks in a fighting game or something like that.
Scott: But when you're at a big convention like that, right, the people who do not there are people out there who don't follow the etiquette, the type of people who will play a demo game for an hour and not leave it right at an anime convention or any other sort of gaming convention with, you know, some sort of shared console game that is publicly and freely playable.
Scott: Those are the types of people who are going to go to the game room and stay there a long time.
Scott: Also, the types of people who are going to sit down at a game and not get up.
Scott: And when you have a big convention and not so many games, odds are those kind of people, you know, if there's 100 of them at the con, they're all going to be sitting at a game system, taking it up.
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't help that those people tend to be oblivious to other people.
Rym: I just think cons what they need to do in the very least, because there are disagreements over what the etiquette is.
Rym: I mean, I've been to arcades where I put a quarter up to play DDR and someone stares at me like, what the fuck are you doing with that quarter?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: You got to just have rules posted somewhere.
Rym: You don't enforce them.
Scott: I found out the name of the versus Shmoop.
Rym: What's it called?
Scott: Twinkle Star Sprites.
Rym: What systems is it for?
Scott: Neo Geo Saturn Dreamcast PS2.
Rym: I think we got to buy a PS2.
Rym: That's like four games I want now.
Scott: Yeah, but it's a versus Shmoop where you pick a cute girly character and you Shmoop.
Rym: And yeah, see, I love those puzzle games already for the same, almost the same reasons.
Rym: This game, I think, would be really cool.
Scott: And I think I think someone needs to make a versus Shmoop for the DS.
Scott: That's what we need.
Rym: I think someone needs to make some sort of epic versus Shmoop for the DS.
Rym: Some sort of Wi-Fi enabled leaderboard rankings.
Rym: I can dream.
Scott: So if you had to pick one Shmoop forever, Giga Wing, Giga Wing, Giga Wing.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think.
Rym: or after Call of the Shadows.
Scott: Yeah, I think I would just pick Galaga one because Galaga.
Scott: The thing is, Galaga is actually a really interesting game that people don't seem to fully understand.
Scott: Galaga, you're a little ship at the bottom and there's bad guys at the top.
Scott: And it's not like Galaxian or Space Invaders.
Scott: So the bad guys are there when you start the level.
Scott: The bad guys fly into the screen one row at a time.
Scott: So it's like you're sitting there with a blank slate and a row of bad guys comes in.
Scott: While they're coming in, if you position yourself properly, you can kill all or a lot of them very quickly because they're all in a line and they all follow the same path.
Scott: So if you shoot at the right spot in their path, you can hit a lot of them with bullets.
Scott: Then whichever ones remain alive line up at the top.
Scott: And after all the bad guys come in, they sort of go back and forth and then they'll take turns diving down at you the same way they do in Galaxian until you kill them all.
Scott: The thing in Galaga that makes it special is the ship capture.
Scott: See, there are these bug bad guys in Galaga and that when they dive down at you, sometimes they'll spray this like wave beam at you.
Scott: And most people go, oh, snaps wave beam and they dodge it or they kill the bad guy that's shooting the wave beam.
Scott: Little do they know, if you have a life remaining and you get hit by the wave beam, you don't die.
Scott: Well, you do die, you lose a life, but it captures your ship and your ship is now a bad guy.
Scott: But when you come back to life, you have a chance to shoot the bad guy.
Scott: And if you do not shoot your ship and you shoot the bad guy, you will now have two ships simultaneously.
Rym: On one hand, double the firepower.
Rym: On the other hand, double the surface area.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Your ship is now twice as wide as it normally is.
Scott: So it's much harder to dodge things and you basically sacrifice the life.
Scott: But you can shoot two bullets side by side at once.
Scott: And that's crazy awesome.
Scott: So Galaga is actually a very deep game and it plays forever the same way Space Invaders or Galaxian plays forever.
Scott: And it's way cool.
Scott: I like it a lot.
Scott: Yeah, awesome.
Scott: It's going to be out on the DS soon.
Scott: The Namco Arcade is coming.
Rym: I'm waiting for that.
Rym: I mean, weren't you going to buy the game on the virtual console until you saw that?
Scott: Pretty much it happened the same day.
Scott: I was going to buy Galaga for the virtual console for five bucks.
Scott: And the next day I saw Namco Museum for DS.
Scott: And I said, well, I'll just wait for that then.
Rym: I'm pretty much going to buy that the day it comes out.
Scott: I'm also going to buy it the day it comes out.
Scott: Do we really need two copies?
Rym: Yeah, because that's the kind of game that I'll just play on my own like Tetris.
Rym: I mean, some games like Bomberman or the puzzle game, only one person in your crew needs to own the game and then everyone download plays.
Rym: But for a game like that, I kind of want it for the single player to kill time when I'm standing in line at the bank or whatever.
Scott: Yep, that's what I need it for.
Scott: Hi.
Scott: Anything else to say about shmups or should we go eat dinner?
Rym: I think we should go eat dinner.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of shmups are an awesome game genre.
Scott: There's a lot of free shmups out there.
Scott: If you've never played any shoot them up games, you probably should play some Giga Wing and Raptor Call of the Shadows.
Scott: I recommend you start if you're going to play shmups at all.
Scott: You should probably play at least Gradius.
Scott: Any Gradius, probably Gradius three is probably the easiest.
Scott: Raptor Call of the Shadows of the PC.
Scott: It shouldn't be too hard to get that.
Scott: Galaga, you probably want to play Space Invaders at least once and also play something like Pocky and Rocky to see how a shmup isn't necessarily ships in outer space shooting a million bullets, but it can also be other things.
Rym: Now, of course, to all of our new listeners, if you're looking for the Otakon coverage, stay tuned until tomorrow, because tonight was video games.
Rym: Tomorrow night is anime and manga and comics and anime conventions.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: If we went to a gaming convention, we'd be talking about it today.
Rym: Yes, we would.
Rym: But actually, the next gaming con we're going to, I believe, is UberCon, which I don't even know when it is.
Scott: I'm going to start looking for other gaming cons because I really want to go to them.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.