Scott: It's Monday August 20th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discuss why streaming audio is not what it used to be.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know after all the harping we did the visigoths came this weekend and aside from a little bit of mess in the kitchen They didn't really destroy the house.
Scott: I think that's cuz.
Scott: we harped on them incredibly to not visigoth and they visigoth much less than previous times.
Scott: I would say they were not visigoths, but perhaps some other type of God.
Rym: Well, the thing is I'm really proud of him because nothing was broken.
Scott: This is the first time nothing was broken that we know of.
Rym: I have yet to find anything broken.
Rym: It is so far the first time we have ever had a Dungeons & Dragons weekend in our house where something of ours did not Get broken.
Scott: Awesome, but yeah It would.
Scott: it wasn't perfect though, so we can still do better next time guys.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: it was a good old weekend at D&D in and rock climbing and all that even though I gotta say it's kind of funny that we're a group of people where we'll play D&D for like six hours and Then the end of the session will basically be an hour-long arguing match about the nature of role-playing which ended up being The entire front row crew pretty much screaming at Scott and him yelling back at us.
Scott: Yeah, what do you want from me?
Rym: It was all in good fun.
Scott: Yeah Arguments probably just as fun as D&D game anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So you're just moved to tech news or what?
Scott: I mean, I'm so kind of bled.
Rym: I don't know Why why you like this a lot on Mondays and Tuesdays and Wednesdays?
Rym: Every day no, no, no, we sit down to do the show and then you're like, yeah, I don't care about it.
Scott: It's been feeling kind of blessed since last Thursday.
Scott: I don't know why.
Rym: I don't know you're bored.
Rym: Are you sick?
Scott: Are you tired when all the above?
Rym: Why we got plenty of sleep?
Rym: yeah kinda yeah sorta.
Rym: what have you been doing in there?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So all right captain What's your news then?
Scott: So last see August 16th, I think so that was Thursday and August 16th.
Scott: Skype Screwed up like whoa, it's it's not working for almost anybody.
Rym: You've noticed we haven't done many interviews lately So I haven't even had a Skype box ready as I didn't even notice.
Scott: I didn't notice either cuz I've stopped logging into Skype on a regular basis and I only log into it now and I'm actually gonna use it so sort of like.
Scott: I didn't know it was down other than the stories on the internet and podcasts who use Skype exclusively complaining they couldn't record over the weekend and Originally people were like, oh Skype is down.
Scott: Oh shits.
Scott: then people said Russian hackers took down Skype.
Rym: Did people say that or did dig say that there's a big difference between people and dig?
Rym: dig people like I said, there's a big difference between people and and now Apparently, I mean if guy if dig represents people that Ron Paul is like the dictator of the world.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so Skype.
Scott: the company says as of like today That the reason that Skype went down is because of Microsoft's patch Tuesday.
Scott: now if you don't know Alright every on the second Tuesday of every month is black Tuesday because that's when all the windows updates come out.
Scott: So if you can find a bug or a security hole in Microsoft Windows or office or anything Unlike the second Wednesday of the month immediately after black Tuesday You're gonna be able to use that exploit and so is everyone else for an entire month Unless it's some crazy super insane exploit that's ruining the internet in which case Microsoft might work faster than a month but most likely it's gonna take a month for them to get around to fixing it.
Rym: the side effect of all this is that partly because of the security problems they keep cropping up and partly because they get released on one day and partly because a lot of IT departments Really don't understand how to actually update machines.
Rym: So they'll just let all their windows boxes automatically get these updates on Tuesday and Microsoft is not known for thoroughly testing what its updates might do to people's windows box.
Scott: so the alternative to doing the Tuesday thing is to manually go and get every individual hotfix for every Individual bug from the MSDN and that unless you're a system administrator for some giant network, and that's your only job You're not gonna do that.
Scott: That's just not gonna happen.
Scott: Nor should it.
Rym: Well, there are a bunch of ways you can do it.
Rym: I mean the real problem is a lot of these patches are not super tested or not exactly like.
Rym: they'll often fix a problem and cause another problem and 99% of these problems are not going to cause any issue for anyone Unless you happen to be using X processor and you happen to be using Y program and Z program at the same time And you happen to be a werewolf and happens to be a full moon.
Scott: All right Now wait check this you ready.
Scott: Skype doesn't say as you would think as soon as you hear Oh patch Tuesday's killed Skype you would think oh, well Obviously something in the patches made Skype not work.
Scott: All right The software would crash.
Rym: because well, wait a minute.
Rym: if Skype wasn't working in Windows because of patch Tuesday What about all the Linux people in the Mac people?
Rym: Working for them.
Scott: No wasn't huh?
Scott: No, wait, so and also if it was a problem on patch Tuesday, right with those patches How come Skype didn't stop working until Thursday or Friday?
Rym: Well, a lot of that people don't often get the updates right away at home.
Scott: because apparently what happened is because you know Skype No one's actually a hunt other than the people who make Skype.
Scott: It's closed source.
Scott: We're not a hundred percent sure exactly how it works like a hundred percent.
Rym: the rationale for this is pretty straightforward Actually one.
Rym: they wanted to be proprietary because Skype actually wants to make money off all that crap and to they make it kind of Secret in a because they've set it up to where.
Rym: Often it'll just make it through firewalls and it'll just kind of get out to the internet and a lot of things like net.
Rym: Just don't stop it.
Rym: and the way to do that is to do some somewhat shady or strange things.
Scott: I don't think that's the motivation for keeping it secret.
Scott: I think the motivation for keeping a secret is keeping people from getting free phone calls.
Rym: Yeah, but basically all that stuff can be solved with their server things which mediate all the conversations.
Scott: But Skype says according to Skype I don't know how much I believe this right.
Scott: is that because Skype is so peer-to-peer?
Scott: because it is it's peer-to-peer?
Scott: Yeah, when you Skype you're not only you know Not only are you skyping to the people that you're skyping to but it's sort of also skyping to some other people's.
Scott: you know It kind of uses people's computers in a way to help the Skype network grow and make sure your packets get there on time.
Scott: And all that jazz, right?
Scott: not only is Skype peer-to-peer, but What happened on patch Tuesday is everyone had to reboot their computers?
Scott: Because they got patches from Microsoft and thus all these Skype clients that were just sitting online went offline and some of them didn't start up again.
Scott: and some of them did some of them didn't and as There were less and less people on the Skype network But more and more of those people were using it.
Scott: It sort of broke down.
Scott: so basically what they're telling us is that There need to be people signed into Skype and not using Skype in order for other people using Skype to make calls.
Rym: Well, if that's the case then fuck Skype, I'm not gonna leave the Skype client open talking my bandwidth.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: But so when a bunch of people sign off a Skype and then a bunch of people sign back in suddenly when you know the automatic starts up That sort of did a little denial of service on their server of all these people trying to log in at once
Rym: I'm still dubious of that because patch Tuesdays happen often and this is the first time this has happened
Scott: I know but that's what they say.
Rym: I call bullshit.
Scott: I also call bullshit.
Rym: I call bullshit on Skype and I call bullshit on Russian hackers.
Scott: Yep Skype is totally making up something here and it doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't smell like roses.
Rym: I mean theoretically it could be possible for a Windows update to cause a problem Whereby Windows machines would send data to the Skype servers in a way that caused a problem.
Rym: But the odds of that are pretty damn low and someone would have noticed Mm-hmm, because if honestly if I couldn't get Skype to work and I needed it I'd open up the ethereal and start looking at packet or the wire shark and I'd start poking around at it and looking at my Firewall logs and my nets and everything and
Scott: yeah Basically, they.
Scott: the only other thing they say is that the issue has been identified within Skype and I guess they fixed it.
Rym: maybe Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah It is my opinion that Skype just screwed up and they're trying to cover up for it by blaming the big old bad Microsoft.
Rym: and not that I love Microsoft but a lot of people blame them for a lot of things that you really.
Scott: It's not always their fault Yeah, but so Skype it had a problem in it.
Scott: It went down a little cover-up action and it's back up now.
Scott: What you gonna do?
Scott: There's no real alternative.
Scott: so much
Rym: So as you all know I used to work at IBM and one thing that was kind of cool about IBM is that there was a lot of community service and Things that we could do in the company that weren't our job But yet we could do them on company time and be paid just as much for them and a lot of it was like donations and charity work and community service stuff.
Rym: and There was an article on dig today about one of these things and I remembered it because I've actually done this a couple times And it was kind of cool.
Rym: So I want to talk about it a little bit because it brings up a lot of issues.
Rym: But IBM has this program called excite Exploring interest in tech site
Scott: like the website and
Rym: engineering like ex dot I dot T dot E
Scott: Okay,
Rym: and what it is is they get schools like schools for young kids not super young kids, but you know Like adolescent kids girls only to get the day off of school or the week off of school Come to whatever IBM site is near their school and have female engineers and female Scientists and female computer technicians and male ones who just know about stuff and also because there aren't that many women in Engineering anyway, maybe
Scott: that's why they're doing something like this.
Rym: well that is exactly why they're doing it.
Rym: but basically we'd set up science experiments and fun stuff and Try to come up with ways to get these kids to basically show kids like this that you know What physics is actually kind of cool.
Rym: check it out liquid nitrogen.
Rym: check it out exploding sodium.
Rym: Check it out pine box derby cars.
Scott: Oh, yeah pine box derby cars.
Rym: and Some people argue on the internet.
Rym: There's the flame war happens every time there's stuff like this.
Rym: that oh, it's sexist.
Rym: But I'm actually the opposite mind.
Rym: I think that programs like this in general not just the ones that are we have to get women into the sciences But just the trying to get any kid interested in anything that is in any way productive Especially when they're young is a good thing.
Scott: Well, I think that generally we have this problem where obviously look at the statistics, right?
Scott: There are less girls interested in science now than the guys.
Scott: that's just.
Scott: that's how it is now.
Rym: it's always been that way.
Scott: Well, no You look at like the early days like computer science to go to like those old univac computer labs and there are a lot more Ladies there percentage-wise.
Rym: Um, there are now, you know the reason for that, right?
Rym: It basically came down to the fact that most of the telco switching operator type people who ended up working with early computers happened to be women because that was a job that women did and Most of the other people who ended up working with computers early on were Secretaries and all the people who generally were women who did that kind of work and
Scott: I mean there were a lot of women Programmer computer scientists early on because
Rym: they got into that but there were a lot more men.
Scott: Anyway, the point is that we don't know why.
Scott: it could be some sort of genetic thing It could be a biology thing.
Scott: It could be a psychology thing.
Scott: It could be an environmental thing.
Rym: Mine that is pretty much entirely societal that's my guess.
Scott: It looks like a lot societal to me because other countries don't have this problem as much as we do like.
Scott: look at India.
Scott: You got just as many women doing the computer thing as the guy is the guys.
Rym: Yeah, and also to be honest I mean I've worked.
Rym: the women in the tech fields are just as confident as the men.
Rym: It's not like it's any different at all.
Scott: Yeah I had a lot.
Scott: actually a lot of my CS teachers in college were female and Didn't really think anything of it and they knew more than I did.
Scott: This way they were the teacher and I was paying.
Rym: but there's a much greater thing than this.
Rym: I want to mention that one.
Rym: Just you gotta get kids interested in science at all because kids generally these days aren't interested in these people.
Scott: people aren't interested in size?
Rym: Well, yeah, but I don't know how because it's really cool and I maybe I mean maybe kids who don't get like.
Rym: Oh books are crap and they don't want to read them and they don't want to be at school book Read a book read a book They don't think about the fact that you know, what black holes and all that business are kind of cool and scary.
Rym: Wouldn't you like to know more about black holes and space stuff?
Rym: I know her science.
Rym: or blowing things up.
Scott: or When I was a kid, we used to go to Science Museum like every year with school and Science Museum is always cool.
Rym: Science museums were like the best things ever when I was a kid even though all the exhibits like a zillion of them everywhere Every exhibit you could touch was always broken because kids just destroy.
Scott: only some of them were broken at the good science museums The fancy big ones the the stuff wasn't broken.
Rym: Well, I went to the Detroit Science Museum.
Rym: while it's big and fancy Things got broken.
Scott: often good science museums equal the Boston Science Museum high quality.
Rym: the Natural History Museum Oh the National History Museum is the only reason and they go there anymore.
Scott: Liberty Science Center high quality.
Rym: I've been.
Rym: I've spent many hours in that museum and I've looked at most things.
Scott: They've got it Liberty Science Center.
Scott: I heard from one of our listeners.
Scott: actually it just reopened like I went to it when I was younger and I guess it closed which I didn't realize.
Scott: and I guess it just reopened which I didn't even realize was closed and You should go there.
Scott: You can actually see the Statue of Liberty from it.
Rym: It's in New Jersey and it's a really cool science museum of awesome, but on a broader scale It seems like there are some companies like and what I'm talking about mega corpse like the big iron companies.
Rym: it seems like a lot of the very large tech companies end up doing a lot of community service and a lot of Projects that aren't going to make money for the company But they're gonna do some good somewhere and a lot of outreach and I don't see that in a lot of other industries.
Scott: Oh, how many other industries have you worked for?
Rym: just read and think.
Rym: like I read I look around the internet and I see like there's always the press release of this company's doing This and this company's doing this and maybe just because the tech companies are more hip to the internet So they have better internet PR and there's more press about the things they do.
Scott: Probably is it because if you look around Basically all big companies have sort of been sold on?
Scott: this idea may be true to some point.
Scott: I don't think it's entirely false that you have to sort of do all these goodwill charity sorts of things to get better public Opinion of your company.
Scott: so big companies doing that stuff all over the place.
Rym: But it's only like the super.
Rym: I mean little companies do a lot of local stuff and super big companies do a lot of stuff.
Rym: And I really like it because it wasn't just oh they're doing good for the community From a purely just money-grubbing Standpoint.
Rym: it really improved the morale at IBM when we did stuff like this.
Scott: the fact that I guys you get to do something It's not work Yeah, but the game is doing anything that wasn't work during work time and morale would have been improved just as much.
Rym: But I I feel like if companies if they do this I mean if they just let me go home morale would go up.
Rym: but if they let me do this morale goes up just as much.
Rym: and They still get my Google.
Scott: lets you do whatever you want 20% of the time.
Rym: Yeah Though I got to say.
Rym: by the same token my current company, which is not as big as IBM I mean, it's still like a big enterprise, you know IT whatever but it's not nearly as big as IBM.
Rym: the idea the sheer I Possibility of me being paid for a minute of work.
Rym: That is not a billable hour that is going to generate revenue.
Rym: It's not even laughable.
Rym: like they can't comprehend that Yeah, what they do every year is hey Donate a bunch of your check to charities.
Rym: Here's the form to fill out.
Rym: Yeah IBM is like this.
Rym: Friday We're all gonna go to inner-city schools and teach kids about science.
Scott: Well, cuz I the thing is is you know, IBM just has so much money.
Rym: Yeah, whatever I almost feel like we should get back to I don't know.
Rym: It's a really complicated idea.
Scott: I think it's like it does feel when companies do do that sort of thing.
Scott: I see the value and improve improving employee morale and the value in improving public opinion of the company.
Scott: But it feels kind of like your company does something bad.
Scott: So you're doing something good separate from what you normally do to cover up for it.
Scott: What would be better is if the thing your company did?
Scott: It's your main thing.
Scott: your company did like.
Scott: if you're a company that makes shoes Let's say if the making of shoes itself was a good thing and was awesome And you didn't have to do other good things on the side if your main goal of your company was good and awesome You wouldn't have to separately do other charity.
Rym: It's hard to say what the main idea is.
Rym: I mean, what's IBM doing?
Rym: They're making technology and selling it to people.
Scott: That's that's actually the topic of Douglas rush coughs latest book that companies don't know what they do anymore.
Scott: They don't do anything.
Rym: Uh, the thing is I don't think that's true for IBM.
Rym: Just I mean my experience is working there.
Rym: It's IBM is like a million tiny companies all stuck together, but all the different parts know exactly what they're doing.
Scott: Yeah, but other companies I've worked generally talking about companies that like, you know outsource absolutely everything and then what does the company do?
Rym: Well, you know That's really no different than like Scott and I always think hey we should open it to Bella sub shop because we know it'll make a lot of money out here because there's There outside of Manhattan and like the Bronx like actually down in the city.
Rym: There is no good place to get a submarine sandwich down here.
Rym: Not where I live fucking anywhere.
Rym: Subway we've looked.
Rym: we can drive up the road like 20 subways.
Scott: I get a generic boring delis that all have the same Boar's head meat and to be a quiz nose It's just a slightly more expensive subway.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's not like it's a good subway with a toaster.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much I think they give you a little bit more meat, but whatever it still crack It does taste better though, but I don't want to run a subway or about de Bella's or anything.
Rym: I don't want to manage it.
Rym: I don't want to have anything to do with it.
Rym: So what if I had money?
Rym: if I had money to invest I would buy the rights to a subway franchise I'd hire workers and hire a manager to run it and I just take all the profits.
Rym: Yeah, that's no different than these companies.
Rym: What am I contributing to the world at this point?
Rym: All I contributed was I had a bunch of money in the first place.
Rym: That's all I did Yep, and I get to benefit from that pretty much forever.
Rym: Yeah And a lot of companies like Scott saying and well I guess Douglas Rushkoff is saying do the same thing outsource everything and then what do you do?
Rym: make money?
Scott: And he says they should concentrate on the thing they do.
Scott: if you're a company that makes shoes You should try to make better shoes more efficiently.
Scott: if you're a company that makes sandwiches You should try to make better sandwiches more efficiently.
Scott: And if you do that, everything will be awesome.
Rym: The thing is don't worry about that other bullshit I gotta say most companies I've worked for when I I like I'll write a full-on business proposal Like if we did this we could save all this money.
Scott: and that's what Doug wants you to do.
Rym: And you know what happens?
Rym: I give it to my boss and he says hmm and he gives it to his boss who never looks at it.
Rym: And that's it.
Rym: They got they got to read this book, but they don't care because they get paid.
Scott: I know that's the problem.
Rym: Everyone just gets paid.
Rym: All right, I don't know.
Rym: I guess I brought this up because I think it's cool and because I did it and I really enjoyed it.
Rym: I almost if if I could make the kind of money I make an IT I'd really like to be just like a high school teacher.
Scott: Yeah, high school computer my the best job in the world would be like summer camp director person but the problem is that job not enough with the money and Summer only.
Scott: so yeah, what you gonna do?
Rym: But I spent an hour just teaching a group of like 14 to 15 year old girls What it's like to be an IT guy or an IT girl I guess and what you do in IT what my job is like.
Rym: granted I lied because I said that the job is rewarding and really fun and you get to do cool stuff.
Scott: Why did you do that?
Scott: You should've been honest.
Rym: Well, I I was somewhat honest Uh-huh.
Rym: The thing is I wasn't gonna come and say you sit in a cubicle all day Designing networks and then other people take those network designs and make them broken and stupid.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: See you ruined it.
Scott: You would have been the best person that they were sitting there all bored Like oh these old guys going blah blah blah.
Scott: you would have come in and been like, yeah, it sucks Don't work here.
Scott: and they would've been like dude.
Scott: This guy's awesome.
Rym: See they actually really liked what I talked about because I mostly just sold anic.
Rym: the thing is I didn't talk a lot about What it's actually like to be an IT guy other than the lie that it's really really fun.
Rym: I spent most of the time talking about the funny things that happen in the labs with computers and Like all the things computers can do and I should care about computers.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: That's good stuff to talk about right there.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I guess I could give the whole speech right here, but that's all right, I don't know.
Rym: I brought this topic up.
Rym: I have a lot to say about it.
Rym: I didn't really cover in depth anything.
Scott: I had to say let's do that for a show next Monday what it's like to be Whatever.
Rym: I can do that right now.
Rym: Let's do it.
Rym: It's really unrewarding.
Rym: It's if it weren't for the fact that I make piles of money.
Rym: I wouldn't do it.
Rym: Yeah, it's it's literally the only reason I go to work is because there's a gigantic check waiting for me.
Rym: Yeah, I can.
Rym: if I spend an hour doing something I hate I can at least think wow I made like 40 bucks just now.
Rym: That's the only thing that makes me go to work.
Rym: Anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Rym: So you might think Oh rims just linking to another stupid cat video.
Rym: It's probably one of those cats with extra fingers, which is what I thought it was.
Rym: So I was sitting there.
Rym: We're hanging out, you know weekend and I thought you were gonna do the the cats with the the box.
Rym: I wanted to because that's really cute, but I'm saving that.
Rym: All right.
Rym: However, if anyone there's a video of a bunch of cats playing with a box and It's mesmerizingly cute, but that's not my thing of the day.
Rym: So I see this video the cat with hands and I assume alright It's gonna be cats doing things with their paws like hey It's gonna be really cute and I ignore it.
Rym: and then later we have people over and I just click on it like alright Let's watch this.
Rym: We got nothing else to do Because that seems to be what the front crew devolves to as the night goes on.
Rym: no matter what we just sit there Watching videos on the internet until there are none left.
Rym: Usually it's the game of peep.
Rym: someone will say like read a book read a book and someone will go what?
Rym: Oh, you've never seen blah.
Rym: and then we all watch it and anytime there's one person who hasn't seen a given thing We all watch it.
Rym: But I click on this.
Rym: and it's not just a cute video about cats.
Rym: In fact, it is a really fucking creepy video about a cat.
Scott: It's a it's a short movie.
Scott: It's like a short film.
Scott: It's like a few minutes long.
Rym: Just watch it.
Rym: It's really cool.
Rym: It's really weird.
Rym: You'll probably predict what's going to happen at the end about 30 seconds before it happens Unless you're an idiot, but what you gonna do?
Scott: the thing I want to really point out really hard to make something That's unpredictable these days.
Rym: The thing is it's really what I like about it.
Rym: And this is the cut of one of those few things It's really I love craft in.
Rym: well, no It enters that that plateau of the weird or the shallow weird Canyon or all the different whatever that thing is where something's?
Rym: Realistic enough but not realistic enough.
Scott: You mean the Uncanny Valley?
Rym: Yeah, that's what I was thinking of.
Rym: Okay, because the the little kid in the flashback park is realistic But really creepily realistic and he's kind of just the way it's animated sort of like a puppety clay.
Rym: He's like a really intense shaking puppet and that's one of the.
Rym: that really unnerves me when I see that It didn't know me that much but it was.
Scott: it was kind of weird.
Rym: I just kind of get shuddery when I see things like that.
Scott: Uncanny Valley is when like if you try to make a CG woman But you don't make her so perfect that no one can tell.
Scott: but you also You don't make her so CG that it's obvious that she's CG and it's sort of like not quite human.
Scott: It's like this uncanny valley where they look uncannily realistic But obviously not real and then it kind of weirds people out.
Rym: There's actually a psychological theory that the reason Humans react to things that are so close to real but a little bit off is that it's kind of a defense mechanism against sickness And abnormal members of our species and that if someone's really sick or deformed or has a mutation or anything is wrong with them There'll be a little bit off There'll be something wrong with them and that sense of wrongness might be what we feel today like a vestigial survival instinct.
Rym: So I like how you know, if you've never seen someone with like elephant Titus or gangrene You'd be kind of like are also how humans tend to have a very strong uncontrollable aversion Reaction to anything that looks like yellow and puffs or anything that looks organic and rotting.
Rym: But yet we don't have the same aversion instinct to chemical looking things or glowing dangerous looking cuz.
Scott: back in the caveman days anyone who didn't have that aversion got sick and died and only the people did have the aversion stuck around and made babies and I
Rym: T where they showed us pictures of things and we had to react immediately as to how how scary it was to us.
Rym: and By and far things that were organic were a lot scarier than things that were dangerous and chemical looking.
Rym: Yep But anyway, I digress check this out.
Rym: That's all I got to say.
Scott: So do you remember like when you were in school?
Scott: Did any of your science teachers have like glass jars with like some water and a piece of seaweed in them and that and it?
Scott: Like you were wondering hey, what the hell is that?
Rym: We had a brain in my high school human brain like I just remember for some reason.
Scott: I don't remember specifically But I do remember there being like glass jars with some water and like a piece of seaweed in them.
Rym: I don't remember that at all.
Scott: Anyway, what those are if you wanted to know it's a biosphere in a jar and you can make one and it's pretty cool because you get a Jar with some water and a seaweed and maybe like I don't know a shrimp or a sea monkey or maybe nothing.
Scott: Maybe some rocks and a in a picture a plastic skeleton or a plastic pirate or something and you can get stuff to live in a jar that you put like on the windowsill in the Sun for a very long time possibly Forever's.
Rym: well, I've seen a lot of those things where they're sold in a store like a pre-made one.
Rym: It's like a glass sphere and there's some brine shrimp and a little bit of yeah Some kind of plant.
Rym: you got to put it in the Sun and all that business that well like that stuff.
Scott: Well make magazine which is possibly the only magazine that might still be worth buying even though if anything this tells you anything I still haven't bought it yet.
Scott: But there's a video that says how to make a tabletop biosphere and I think I might do this.
Scott: The thing is that the problem is here.
Scott: right if you already have say a fish aquarium You already have everything you need to make this and you'll barely use any of it.
Scott: If I want to make this I've got to go to like the fish store and buy like, you know Those chemicals they use on the water and stuff like that, which is enough to make like a thousand of these.
Rym: Luckily, there's a fish store right up the road.
Scott: No But I mean saying like I'm gonna have to the smallest amount I can buy is enough to make like a thousand biosphere.
Rym: We can always go to a store where they use that stuff anyway and just say hey, I'm making a biosphere.
Rym: If I give you five bucks, can I borrow this?
Rym: much of all these things?
Scott: I think I just might also buy a fish in a bowl.
Rym: Ah Actually if you're ever out, I mean there's some of these around.
Rym: but down in the Bronx I don't know if it's still there but at the Children's Hospital at Montefiore Medical Center in the lobby.
Rym: There's a gigantic one of these Uh-huh.
Rym: It's like four feet in diameter and it's just this big glass sphere and there's actually a really cool kind of Carl Sagan cosmos.
Rym: We're all star stuff.
Rym: Check it out evolution thing there.
Rym: That's really cool Nice.
Rym: and in the middle of it is this gigantic little biosphere.
Scott: All righty You sure it's not just an aquarium, but it's actually yeah, I'm sure cuz there's a big thing about what it is.
Rym: explaining it Pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah, and it's very.
Rym: it was when I last saw it very pointedly in the Sun.
Scott: Ah That's that's necessary for the biosphere without the Sun.
Scott: It'll just be like CB dies and you're done for right?
Rym: So well if you might have noticed we do a podcast and the podcast is not streaming to you live over the internet.
Scott: Well, basically what happened here?
Scott: The reason for this episode is that we did a podcasting panel at Connecticut Which I got to admit wasn't the greatest podcasting.
Rym: Well part of that was we didn't really care.
Rym: and well I think the real issue was that the entire audience already knew what podcasting was But didn't want to do podcast themselves and they couldn't tell us what they wanted.
Rym: Like they couldn't even tell us why they came to the panel.
Rym: Yeah, so we just kind of told stories and messed around on in the front for an hour.
Scott: Some guy was like hey talk about you know internet radio and streaming radio and we're like, you know, we said hey, that's irrelevant.
Scott: Now that's there's no reason for that.
Scott: You know it only has one or two purposes and then they're they're slowly going away and they're gonna go away big time and He was kind of grumbly.
Scott: and then afterwards he came on our forum and he was super grumbly and made a crazy Batshit argument and everyone was you know, yelling at him and it was pretty much everyone versus him And he didn't counter anyone's points whatsoever.
Scott: So we're lazy.
Scott: We'll do a Monday show to talking about the streaming internet radio.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Yep, this is I guess the one small drawback of being really active in the forums.
Rym: Is that if there's a really big conversation in the forums?
Rym: You're basically going to get the text version of GeekNights about that topic whenever we finally do it on the show.
Scott: Yeah That's all right.
Rym: also I used to have an idea when we first did this show that I would never say something in the forum if I was gonna talk about it in the show and the forums were just gonna be a Community and a breeding ground for me to get ideas for the show.
Rym: But now I can't know if I see an argument in the forums.
Rym: I can't just ignore it.
Scott: Yeah, I got to go in there and fuck people up all right, so Streaming internet radio started at least for me.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure technologically it started in some labs people figuring stuff out.
Scott: But it really started for consumers with real player real audio.
Scott: The way this worked was pretty much the same The.
Scott: the principle behind it was even though the technology behind it was a lot shittier than it is now.
Scott: The principle behind it was the same.
Scott: you have a digital audio file, you know, I guess in a real format.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: now people use mp3 or ogg formats or you know the same formats.
Scott: you download and Instead of letting you download the file you save it and play it whenever you want like you do with the podcast or an iTunes Music song or something like that.
Scott: They send it to you slowly not slowly But at a rate equal to the time it takes to play.
Scott: So let's say you have an mp3 that's 128 kilobits per second.
Scott: well If I send you over the internet 128 kilobits of data every second and you play it as it comes in You can hear the mp3 as you download it immediately.
Scott: so if I talk into this microphone right now and I have a Computer that turns that into an mp3 as fast as it possibly can and sends it to you as fast as it possibly can You can hear what I'm talking in relatively real time.
Rym: Now.
Rym: back then this served a lot of different purposes compared to what that sort of thing would serve nowadays or even a few years ago because back then you couldn't really have sound on a web page other than like a MIDI file and as a result if you wanted to play an audio clip for someone They had to download it and they had to download the whole thing before they could listen to on a
Scott: 14-4 modem
Rym: And they didn't want to save that file.
Rym: They wanted to listen to it once on their tiny-ass hard drive with their tiny-ass computer speakers.
Rym: They wanted to listen to it once because it was part of the content you were giving to them at that moment.
Scott: Or they wanted to listen to the radio when the radio was bad, you know, or in the radio safety the analog You know terrestrial radio is sucking.
Rym: they could listen to the terrestrial radio from around the world on their internet Even though you couldn't really do that in the early days of real audio, but you could kind of do it In the earliest days of real audio, all it was was alright.
Rym: I can go to this website and oh they have clips from I don't know Les Miserables like 14-second clips and instead of Downloading the thing for you know a minute and then listening to it you hit play and then you could just listen to it.
Rym: Pretty much right then.
Scott: also it was used early on to give you previews of CDs You were gonna buy so you'd go to like CD now, which I don't think exists anymore.
Scott: I think it got eaten by Amazon and Amazon and you say huh?
Scott: Do I want to buy this CD?
Scott: and since you couldn't download mp3s really in those days You would go and click and say let me hear part of that first track or let me hear that's you know Hit single and it would start playing it for a few seconds like 30 seconds or so.
Rym: Now this kind of streaming is still really important to the internet today because we consume a lot of media That we don't want to keep on the internet not in real time not live But just there's a file out there like on YouTube and I want to watch it.
Rym: I don't want to have to download the whole thing before I watch it I want to start watching it, but let it download in the background things like that.
Rym: And that is most things.
Rym: just do that nowadays.
Rym: It used to be a big deal back then But now like if you click on the mp3 link in our show on the website It'll probably just start playing in your browser long before it's downloaded.
Scott: Yeah, unless you right-click on it and say save as and then you'll download it.
Rym: Yeah, and that's not really what we're talking about because that is so ubiquitous that it's not even an interesting technology anymore.
Rym: It's not anything special.
Rym: That's just the way you can download files.
Rym: now It has to do with the way headers are and players are smart enough to figure out what the data is supposed to be.
Rym: in All that business and UDP that we're not gonna get into right.
Scott: what we're talking about is a technology that is actually pretty old and is now mostly unchanged and It's basically most of it is based on shoutcast Which is a thing that the winamp guys kind of know.
Rym: soft it really whips the llama's ass, right?
Scott: And what it is is you have a server a shoutcast server and whoever's running the shoutcast server can put mp3s into it.
Scott: they can put ogg into it and I think you can just plug a microphone into it and talk and They basically they're sort of like a DJ.
Scott: They're a DJ.
Scott: They set up music or audio and they put it into the server and you connect to the server with your shoutcast Client and the server sends you the audio that's currently being put into it in real time.
Scott: So if you stop and come back five minutes later You just missed five minutes of whatever was going on on that server.
Rym: now on one hand when this first was able to be done On the internet.
Rym: It was really cool because all right now I can listen.
Rym: course.
Rym: It was cool in the same way that when multimedia computers came out.
Rym: Oh shit I just watched a two-second video of Martin Luther King on my computer.
Rym: That was awesome.
Scott: It's the same reason.
Scott: Microsoft in Carta.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: I just saw like five minutes of Star Wars and incredibly low the resolution on my computer.
Rym: And when I say low resolution, we're talking like a hundred by a hundred.
Scott: Yeah So the thing is it did and still does serve a few purposes.
Scott: the reason it was it was kind of popular not super popular but kind of popular was that You didn't have many ways to get.
Scott: I mean mp3s were around but they weren't so easy to download with the ship modem.
Scott: and Because mp3s while low quality weren't no one was making them at stupidly low quality but streaming audio in those days was stupidly low quality.
Rym: part of the reason for that was just that Modem sucked that and it took a while to make an mp3.
Scott: back in the day It was not trivial to make an mp3 file Yeah, and people didn't have the hard drive space to hold mp3s for a lot, you know or a lot of them.
Scott: So you would go to a website and you'd say you'd figure out what genre of music you liked.
Scott: You'd click a button and Winamp would just start playing that genre of music.
Scott: You didn't have control over exactly what song.
Scott: You couldn't really pause and come back to it.
Scott: It was pretty much just the radio but it was better than the radio because you could choose What you wanted and you did.
Scott: there weren't commercials really and you know the terrestrial radio.
Scott: the signal would might not be coming through Perfectly and the audio quality be kind of shady.
Rym: You had the same problem with streaming audio back then and that the audio would often just cut out for a while and rebuffer and The server would go down with too many people connected and all sorts of crap.
Scott: Yep But it did have the advantage over.
Scott: the main advantage over radio is that you could click a button and get techno coming right in.
Scott: You still can to this day and there was no techno on the rail radio.
Scott: It just doesn't happen.
Rym: Now, of course when the mp3 bust happened meaning when the RIAA and all those people suddenly realized wait a minute There's an internet.
Rym: We better put a stop to this basically Napster kind of put down the shoutcast a bit Yes, and then the RIAA put down both the shoutcast and the naps.
Scott: They didn't really put down the shoutcast so much.
Scott: Yeah, they did is they sort of?
Scott: the problem is is that legally speaking they they've been pushing legislation and have pushed legislation in the past that forces the internet radio stations to be treated differently than terrestrial radio stations and they have to pay Royalties for every song they play.
Scott: whereas usually radio station like terrestrial radio stations Get paid by record companies to play certain songs as opposed to others.
Scott: It's the opposite with the internet radio or the internet radio station has to pay the record company all these royalties Most of which don't go to the actual artists.
Scott: blah blah blah.
Scott: It sucks.
Rym: Well, that's not really the issue because the thing is a lot of the you know shoutcast or whatever streaming audio stations back then Were just guys running them without any.
Rym: they didn't care know about the law and they just played the music they liked and the RIAA Yeah those guys got shut down.
Rym: so internet radio was started appearing run by the corporate types and a lot of actual radio stations started streaming stuff and just paying the royalties and it was basically just the radio but on your computer.
Scott: Yep, and I mean people.
Scott: there are people out there and there is a use.
Scott: I sometimes occasionally use streaming audio.
Scott: For example, I'm at work.
Scott: My iPod is full of podcasts or maybe it doesn't have that much music on it Or maybe I've listened to all the music on it.
Scott: I'm sitting at work or I'm sitting somewhere where there's an internet connection and I want music but the FM radio sucks balls And I just want to listen to music.
Scott: I don't care what music.
Scott: I just want to pick a genre and go and It's useful for that purpose, but it really doesn't have too many other useful purposes that I could think of.
Scott: I mean, do you use it for anything?
Rym: Well, I mean the only thing I would use it for is like Scott said the music thing because if I just suddenly want to listen to some music Unless I have a bunch of music on my iPod or something I'm just out somewhere or even if I'm at my computer and I want to just try out a bunch of new music or see What new things I can find I don't particularly feel like going out and downloading something just to see if I like it or not.
Scott: I don't know particularly feel like digging through my mp3 is trying to make a playlist and deciding.
Scott: It's a lot easier to just not decide and say give me music in this genre And I'll if it's no good.
Scott: I can just push stop.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So in that case, I really don't mind internet radio And I think that it's just a nice button that I can click on to make background noise at any time.
Rym: now granted There's an issue now with internet radio in that basically because the the content producers of the big, you know RIAA types have decided that they're afraid of this kind of streaming because people might rip the stream and get their MP3s without having to pay.
Rym: They're basically trying to destroy it by making the licensing fees So absurd that no one but them could possibly run an internet radio station and make money.
Scott: Some people still be able to run them, but only people with money it would.
Scott: amateurs will not be able to play RIAA music on them without paying the big bucks.
Rym: now granted.
Rym: I am of the mind It's not a very popular opinion on the internet that that's perfectly fine and they should make the royalties a billion dollars for all.
Rym: I care because if The market will decide and if they decide to make their music so expensive for people to play All the amateur DJ's out there are just gonna use non RIAA music.
Scott: and while that's awesome And I think that that's pretty cool.
Scott: I totally like that action.
Scott: It's right up my alley.
Scott: when you look at the numbers right on all the listeners of internet radio stations People are listening to like the genre stations like hits of the 70s hits of the 80s, you know metal Hits, well, I can't say they're listening to.
Rym: I actually at IBM and at my work.
Rym: I end up just dealing with computers.
Rym: I run into a lot of people you know who installed internet radio whatever on their computer and they listen to it a lot and I talked to him a lot about That way before we did podcasting or anything and those generally.
Rym: a lot of the people who listen to those things Don't know anything about Mp3s or they don't understand.
Rym: all they know is I want to listen to the radio.
Rym: I don't get radio inside.
Rym: My friend told me I can go to the whatever and listen to the radio.
Rym: I clicked on it and I listen to the right at RIT.
Scott: when I worked in that office as a part-time job the boss would just go to that and click on a genre and just listen.
Scott: and If they start here and weird Creative Commons, you know They're not gonna have a stations like a Creative Commons.
Scott: blah blah blah and there's all these songs The person's never heard.
Scott: they're gonna be like what the fuck is this shit.
Scott: and you look at the listenership on Existing stations that play only Creative Commons and free type awesome music.
Scott: and while I might listen to those stations The actual listenership is pretty low.
Scott: because I think my guess and I think it's a pretty educated guess The people who are savvy enough to know that that's a cool station to listen to are savvy enough to get podcasts.
Scott: They're not gonna bother with the streaming radio business.
Rym: well I think part of it is it really.
Rym: it still doesn't matter because if people want to listen to like the normal whatever Corporate RIAA music and that all those radio stations get added or Stupefied or destroyed by the fact that the content producers want to make the royalties huge That's a market that's destroying itself and I don't really care.
Rym: Yep, if they want it They're gonna have to pay for it.
Scott: The point I'd like to make though is that people who are savvy people understand how this stuff works.
Scott: people will understand what a pot You you provide.
Scott: you listen to a podcast.
Scott: you understand a podcast, right?
Scott: This stuff is not something you this could go away entirely and you probably wouldn't even blink.
Rym: I mean think about it for especially for things like talk radio Which is what most podcasts are these days and what a lot of the popular radio was to among geeks like us Just a talk show that isn't just Howard Stern talking for eight hours straight.
Rym: You don't really want to jump in in the middle and then leave in the middle.
Rym: You don't want to miss whatever they're talking about because if you get out of your car to get gas or because now you're at Work and you got to miss like the four hours while you're actually doing work before you can listen again Streaming anything like that.
Rym: It's just stupid
Scott: I think actually is that a lot of those radio shows like Howard Stern are designed in such a way where you would listen when you get into your car and stop listening when you get out exactly matter and that's sort of changing as people try to listen to the entire things from beginning to end like their episodes and That sort of format doesn't really work so well when someone's listening to your entire show.
Scott: and now people are podcasting making shows that are designed for you to listen to the entire thing and not designed for you to listen in and then cut out and listen and cut out.
Scott: and they're giving you the freedom to listen to Only the episodes you want only the parts of the episodes you want.
Scott: fast forward rewind stop play pause It.
Scott: they're getting carried around with you wherever you want Listen to it on any device you want in all sorts of formats.
Scott: send it to your friends.
Scott: They can listen to it to eat like, you know, you won't be like.
Scott: hey listen to Howard Stern yesterday.
Scott: You hear that funny joke?
Scott: No, I didn't hear it.
Scott: Oh, I guess you missed it.
Scott: No here.
Scott: I'll play it for you.
Scott: It's on my iPod.
Scott: we can listen to it till the end of time.
Scott: Once you have that you don't go back.
Scott: the same reason why you get a TiVo.
Scott: You don't go back to just watching shit on cable.
Scott: It just doesn't happen anymore.
Scott: TiVo game over.
Scott: when they get Netflix blockbuster is done.
Rym: now some somewhat misinformed people try to make the argument that if someone's not willing to make time out of their day to listen at a designated time to a stream to hear something then they obviously don't care about that and The very clear rebuttal that is again like Scott said TiVo.
Rym: the people who buy TiVo's watch more TV than anyone.
Rym: they love TV and they watch more TV Because now they don't have to schedule their lives around the stupid TV schedule.
Rym: They watch exactly what they want whenever they want and they skip the ads.
Scott: I don't understand.
Scott: So if someone is not willing to suffer and pay a higher price, it's basically like saying Hey, I'm selling this DVD for 20. if I raise the price to 30 and you don't buy it You must just not love it as that much.
Scott: so you don't really like it.
Scott: I was willing to pay 20 for it.
Scott: I like it that much, you know, it's like if someone isn't entirely devoting their whole life to something They don't like it at all.
Scott: that it's.
Scott: it's not an all-or-nothing thing.
Scott: people like something a certain amount.
Scott: some people like something enough to where they're willing to Cancel the rest of their lives at a particular moment in time to watch it Like someone likes the Super Bowl enough that they will schedule their whole day around it.
Rym: great at least I can say that for sports and Live events like the first time a human lands on Mars or whatever things anything that's Happening in real time.
Rym: that matters in real time and it matters if you know about it in real time.
Rym: Streaming is still really important for that.
Scott: Yeah But internet radio streaming isn't gonna matter for those sorts of things.
Scott: TV still handles those and while I'd like to see TV go away.
Scott: I don't see it going anywhere.
Rym: Yep, and even for radio, I mean if you want to listen to the sports game, let's do it on the radio.
Rym: You're not gonna get streaming radio in your car over the internet.
Scott: Actually, there is one thing I would if there was a way for me to like stream audio or video of live sporting events on the internet.
Scott: I am willing to pay a small amount for that service.
Rym: I would actually quite a bit to be able to stream in high-definition hockey games over the internet.
Rym: Well, I'd pay a lot of money for that.
Scott: Google video is putting hockey games up, but they were in low resolution and They were after the game.
Rym: So I already knew what the score was after the game is fine for me because I don't bother reading the score I know but it's live is just Something else, but I just want I mean for hockey.
Rym: I just want to see the game.
Rym: the problem is and I would rather see it live The real problem was the resolution because hockey at low resolution.
Scott: You can't see the puck.
Rym: I mean hockey on normal resolution on HDTV is the bare minimum.
Scott: Yep, the thing is I'm willing to pay for probably hockey f1 and baseball if I at least Mets baseball.
Rym: The problem is they actually majorly.
Scott: baseball does offer that they charge a fuck ton of money for it more than I'm ever willing to Pay.
Scott: good God, I'd pay like five bucks for the season.
Scott: There's selling like a zillion.
Scott: don't make a look up what it is.
Scott: I'm not gonna bother.
Scott: it's a lot of money.
Scott: I've looked it up before unless it suddenly dropped in which case I don't know but it's a lot of money.
Scott: I could get cable television for that money.
Scott: Why would I bother paying for streaming audio?
Rym: and plus I mean you look at all the radio stations that offer bits of their content as podcasts like Penn Radio or NPR or the BBC.
Rym: a Lot more people from all the statistics that get published Listen to the podcast then bother listening to the radio.
Scott: The other thing is that when you're broadcast in other an advantage for the person broadcasting.
Scott: when you put a podcast out.
Scott: You don't know exactly how many listeners there are but you know about for example, you won't know that you have exactly 1032 listeners, but you will know that you had between a thousand and fifteen hundred.
Scott: when you do Terrestrial radio, right, you know Jack shit, cuz you're going on Nielsen ratings draw crap.
Rym: Yeah If you look up sometime how the radio ratings work and that is probably the reason that most radio sucks I mean think we live in New York City where but right here We get so many radio stations that if you just turn on your radio with a normal antenna And you don't skip like to the stations that are coming in the strongest, but just skip megahertz per megahertz Every single step of the way is a clear as day radio station and most of them are playing the exact same music.
Rym: Not like.
Rym: they're not like.
Rym: they're the same station, but they're all playing the same kind of music.
Rym: They're all the same genres of music and it's just all kind of crappy.
Scott: Yeah You're not gonna find Unless you go to the way ends of the dial at the weird times any sort of weird music.
Scott: or you know the kind of stuff That's commonplace on the Internet.
Rym: My favorite thing is if you're driving somewhere in the middle of nowhere like like 3 in the morning Turn on a.m.
Rym: Radio and you're gonna find some crazy guy talking about something crazy.
Scott: You're not gonna find Derek the Bandit Sound Republic with South African Psychedelic trance.
Rym: see honestly, that's the other thing.
Rym: while I can see you know.
Rym: Oh, just hit an internet stream and get some music genre, whatever.
Rym: I Can't really do that in my car and the technology to let me do that in my car is still a long way off for The price I'm willing to pay.
Scott: yeah while streaming radio has that purpose, you know And it's good in an office or in your room when you're bored time-shifted media has the same thing.
Rym: There's genre podcasts that are just all the music you want all the blues.
Rym: you want all the techno.
Rym: you want all the rock.
Scott: You want all the classical you want.
Scott: and if it's in a podcast?
Scott: Well, you can just load up your iPod with a bunch of episodes of that podcast.
Scott: Let's do it in the car.
Scott: Let's say it.
Scott: It does everything streaming radio does and more.
Scott: So why do we need the stupid streaming?
Scott: It's just it's sort of redundant now.
Rym: Also streaming is really at this point beyond the reach of amateurs in the sense that if you get at all popular You're totally screwed because the amount of bandwidth it takes to stream audio Will pretty much crush any consumer level connection.
Scott: if you have more than a handful of listeners Yeah, I mean you need to it for every listener.
Scott: Like let's say you're doing 128 kilobit per second mp3.
Scott: You have two listeners.
Scott: That means you need enough bandwidth to send out 256 kilobits of data every second.
Scott: Let's see you have a thousand listeners.
Scott: Oh crap.
Rym: now theoretically with IPv6 and fancy networking things There are ways around that where you send one packet out and then routers send it to all the people who want it But none of that works in practice.
Rym: the way you would want it to know.
Scott: and the thing with a podcast Is while I still have to pay bandwidth because if a thousand people download my 50 megabyte mp3 as a thousand times 50 megabytes But it doesn't matter how fast they get it because they're not listening to it until it's done.
Scott: So if it's kind of slow, that's okay.
Scott: Also, they don't do it all at once.
Scott: They do it at different times.
Scott: Sure a lot of people are gonna Automatically download it when you put it up.
Scott: a lot of people are gonna tend to download it when they get home from work Or when they wake up in the morning, but it's not all at once and that makes a tremendous Difference like a ludicrously tremendous difference.
Scott: So, you know if at the time when a bunch of people are downloading it It'll be slower and the time when a few people are downloading be faster.
Scott: Hooray, whatever.
Rym: Yeah I don't know why we did a show selling podcasting to people who are listening to a podcast.
Scott: Yeah, that kind of it's kind of silly.
Rym: We used to have a lot better to do.
Scott: I'll be honest Yeah, and I just kind of wanted to.
Rym: you know We had an argument an argument that and I'm gonna say this pretty much openly and straight up We won that argument without taking a single point of damage.
Rym: if this was burning wheel We did not lose a single point of the body of our argument.
Rym: In fact, somehow we gained point.
Scott: Yeah streaming audio Kind of go in the way the dodo bird podcasting while not Guaranteed to be this lock in to the new media hedge a hegemony Hegemony hegemony.
Rym: I actually don't know how to pronounce that word Is probably not like the end solution to this but at the same time Even if the internet were ubiquitous and everywhere and your car stereo could just stream audio till the cows come home.
Rym: I love the fact that I used a phrase till the cows come home in reference to very high technology I know.
Rym: but even in that sense Why would someone bother streaming?
Rym: When they can just time shift and listen to the exact show they want to in their car and pause it when they get out Yeah,
Scott: and I know people are gonna say oh well you're you can grab the streaming audio and save it and blow But that's not something the average consumer can do.
Scott: and why bother?
Scott: why go through the extra effort?
Rym: I mean we and while we could offer the shows live periodically and we're thinking about doing that over Skype to see if people want To just listen to a raw GeekNights.
Rym: That's not it's.
Rym: we would do that because we wanted to for fun Not because it would help us in any way.
Rym: We're not gonna gain listeners or get anything out of doing that.
Scott: And think about it.
Scott: Would you live if you could only listen to GeekNights at say five o'clock at night every or you know?
Scott: I guess it's a late show eleven o'clock at night Monday through Thursday.
Scott: How many times would you listen?
Scott: how many times do you listen now?
Scott: And how many times would you listen if it was eleven o'clock at night Monday through Thursday?
Rym: And also as my final point to just hammer this down the person who made this little shitstorm of a crappy argument against us I would just like to say that we have a Solid four figures worth of listeners very solid and he has a solid one figures worth of listeners.
Rym: Also, that wasn't just his listeners.
Rym: That was the most listeners.
Rym: He'd ever had at once.
Scott: Also, it seems that he's now listening to the show.
Scott: So we win.
Rym: for someone who's not a fan of the podcast There's a possibility that he is smart and he is doing what we have done with other Crappy podcast in that we make fun of them or we try to start an argument with them.
Rym: we didn't.
Rym: we don't do this recently, but we used to and then they get mad and say something about it and link to us and Then all their listeners listen to us and just keep listening.
Rym: That might be what he's trying, but I don't think his cunning plan was thought out the way he thought it was.
Scott: Well, you just gave him the cunning plan.
Scott: So if he doesn't take advantage of it as a tool.
Rym: Well, we never linked to him and he never even really linked to himself.
Rym: So yeah.
Scott: Oh, well, whatever.
Rym: Granted if even a fraction of you guys actually listen to him.
Rym: I guarantee it would take a server down like that.
Rym: Yeah, all right audio not the greatest and before we go any further I don't have music ready for it.
Rym: cuz I haven't really bothered and I don't want to steal music.
Rym: I know a lot of podcasts.
Rym: just take music they like and put it in their show.
Rym: But we try to be you know, somewhat legal and legit here.
Rym: I Got a geek bite for you.
Scott: I don't know if that's the best music.
Rym: No problem But it's kind of like the music we used to do when we first did the show.
Rym: remember that the Original GeekNights opening theme don't tell people they don't know about that.
Rym: I'm not gonna tell him what it is.
Rym: I'm just gonna tell him that the opening theme used to be different.
Rym: It did and if they know where to look they can probably hear it.
Rym: Yeah anyway, our friend Kate decided that we had to watch this one day and She described it and she showed us the cover and all we could think and I'll admit we were totally wrong on this.
Rym: This is gonna be some crap like Jane Eyre kind of Oh Nobles and people talking to each other in the 1800s about the estate and whatever will I do if I have to marry that?
Rym: Dreadful, mr.
Rym: Simpson.
Scott: That's what I thought it was gonna be and thus while we watched the early parts of it I was busy reading some Tezuka manga, which I luckily had on hand.
Rym: I believe it was Oda Kira.
Scott: He don't really was But when I finished it before this show finished and thus I was saved.
Rym: now The thing is we decide.
Rym: we watched it because you know We well.
Rym: while it sounded like something we would hate we trusted her and we watched it.
Rym: and all I want to say is Throw out anything.
Rym: you would think about something like this and I'm gonna tell you straight up that this is one of the funnier things I've seen in my life.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty goddamn funny.
Rym: I'm not maybe not top 10 but top 50 easily.
Rym: This is this is Horatio level of enjoyment here.
Scott: It is somehow there's something about it.
Scott: where it is It's so it's based on novels, right?
Rym: it's sort of an the same based on a pretty damn good novel - from I look it's it's.
Scott: it's a 17 slash 1800s historical fictional but realistic miniseries of television movie things.
Scott: So it's very similar to Horatio and it gives me the same level almost the same level enjoyment.
Scott: It's not quite as good as a ratio, but it's the same type of enjoyment.
Rym: Though it seems like a lot of these British kind of say what it is.
Rym: yet No we haven't.
Rym: they have this formula of set up a situation where you like some characters and don't like some other characters and things build up and things build up and You kind of know how it's gonna end, but you don't know the details.
Rym: So it's not the end that matters it's the journey and then there will always be the point where everyone gets exactly what they deserve in the most epic and Hilarious and wonderful and satisfying possible way you could ever have it be.
Rym: that's what I love.
Scott: I love that action.
Scott: I've been right up my alley.
Scott: That's like 11 pins knocked down.
Rym: Nor if we even if we did a whole show atheist, oh my god.
Rym: Just there if we talked about Tom Jones, the reason we're not doing a whole Tom Jones by the.
Rym: yes This is an adaptation of Henry Fielding's Tom Jones.
Scott: I'm linking to the exact not Tom Jones with the giant penis.
Scott: No, not that Tom Jones the rake.
Scott: It is the story.
Scott: Tom Jones of the giant penis is also a rake Yes,
Rym: but it is the story of a young man who is a ladies man But he's also a really nice guy and you're really
Scott: like the Tom Jones lounge singer with the giant penis Who's a rake
Rym: and he likes a girl and the world just pisses on him,
Scott: but you
Rym: know what?
Rym: He never loses his optimism and let me tell you there are some funny fucking scenes in this show.
Scott: Good God The best is with the pistol.
Scott: That is the.
Scott: that is the highlight of the whole show.
Rym: and the second best moment is the duel with the same dude Who is in the pistol scene?
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I'll ruin this scene this one scene to give you an idea.
Rym: So there's this guy and you'll know him when you see him because you're gonna hate this character.
Scott: He's an ass like.
Rym: this character has no redeeming qualities, especially when you get to watch the rape of the Sabines.
Rym: And then he doesn't like this guy who is like the most awesome guy ever who's basically all alternates between drunken and raging and sometimes crying.
Scott: and He is like the most loving angry drunk.
Rym: and you really feel for this guy and he's hilarious.
Rym: But this evil guy is so just Francine empty pansy and he gets insulted.
Rym: So he's like.
Rym: I think I would like that kind of guy well Any kind of saunters over and pulls out this tiny little white glove and kind of like pops him in the face with.
Rym: he's like My honor and the guy just looks at him smiles hauls up and punches him across the room.
Scott: It's quite the hilarity now.
Rym: The only reason we're not doing a show about it is that it would be nothing but us Recounting hilarious scenes and laughing at each other for like an hour.
Scott: Hey, this thing starts off.
Scott: and like a little village in England somewhere, you know, there's sort of like hanky-panky going on, but he really likes one girl, but he's still hanky-panky.
Scott: and then Craziness in London.
Scott: OMG and oh god it pretty much won.
Rym: if you liked Horatio hornblower at all You'll like this just as much.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I'm serious.
Scott: Even if you only like to ratio for the boats This has no boats and the Navy is in it slightly.
Rym: Yes Pardon me, sir.
Rym: Have you ever considered a career in his majesty's Navy?
Scott: Well, yes, I gotta go.
Rym: Yeah but Even if you've never won you should watch Horatio hornblower because goddamn and you should also watch this.
Rym: I can't recommend this enough.
Scott: Good God Yeah, nice geek.
Rym: But also it's like 36 bucks on Amazon.
Rym: Oh sweet, and I'll point I might just buy it.
Rym: I'm thinking of buying it now.
Scott: I don't really want to watch it.
Rym: Oh, maybe I kind of want to own it to lend to other people.
Scott: I kind of want to get it to get some clips out.
Rym: Oh That'd be some good audio.
Rym: But and also I just want to point out there's no Amazon refer or anything in the link I'm making.
Rym: so it's not like we're trying to make money off of telling you to buy this stupid thing.
Scott: Yeah other people, you know Whenever you go to a blog and they link to Amazon If you actually click on that link and buy the thing on Amazon that blog gets money.
Scott: So instead you should go to Amazon directly and search for whatever it is.
Scott: They were trying to sell you.
Rym: and then the thing is I wouldn't be above doing that.
Rym: But if we ever talked about something on the show and link to it like that We would tell you openly that we did that in the link.
Rym: We would also say this is a refer link that will make us money.
Rym: You would never lie We would never hide it.
Scott: But yeah other blogs are just linked to things on Amazon and not say it's a referral link.
Scott: It just kind of.
Scott: you know, here I'm linking to Amazon.
Scott: You don't realize it because you don't look at that incredibly complicated URL and you don't understand what's going on.
Scott: But yeah people make money off of that.
Scott: Amazon gives the money to sell books.
Scott: So seriously, we're not making money from Amazon.
Scott: We're just trying to tell you to go buy this because it's awesome.
Rym: we stayed at their house a lot later than we'd planned on just to watch the rest of it and It was worth it.
Rym: there the scene it's like the climax is at the end the yelling and screaming.
Rym: It was Horatio level and the pistol.
Rym: aha the pistol.
Scott: It was funny cuz the pistol was so small.
Scott: It was so perfect.
Scott: Also the facial expression so perfect in like the first time being so perfect.
Rym: the show like goes in the direction You're like, alright I see the plot of this show and then someone fucking dies and the plot is not what you expected at all.
Rym: And it's just great.
Scott: It's the best.
Rym: Okay, I think we're done.
Scott: We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.