Scott: It's Wednesday December 5th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We review Samurai Crusader and the bug boy.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: You might have noticed yesterday that it wasn't One of our normal episodes.
Scott: well it was.
Scott: it counted as a normal episode.
Scott: It wasn't a special But it was by no means recorded last night as it usually is.
Rym: no and a lot of people have been asking about When it would come.
Rym: and I guess it was the good opportunity because while Scott was home I assume engaging in some sort of erstwhile pursuit though.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I know better.
Rym: He was playing game Very uh let's say interesting game A game that I'm avoiding for reasons that either make the game sound very good or very bad.
Rym: to me It's like the best worst game ever so I might stop playing though at least for a while I've been like pointedly avoiding this game Not like World of Warcraft where I want to play it just to tell you all how much I hate it.
Rym: But I really don't want to play this game because I worry about what will happen.
Scott: Yeah, something epic as in the olden days.
Rym: well I think the word.
Scott: then again I wish I had this game back in the olden days like in high school.
Scott: this god This is even the best thing ever.
Scott: so much for sieve.
Rym: - yeah but Where I was.
Rym: I'm not gonna dwell on this because I think I could do a. Sometime when Scott's out of town I'll tell a little story about this.
Rym: But I was sipping Bellini's in the Rainbow Room in New York City, and I have to say The Rainbow Room is quite a nut like.
Rym: I imagine I just had this like fast forward future to me ten years from now And we'll have like I don't know the GeekNights after party in the Rainbow Room after some kind.
Scott: the Rainbow Room is not the Nicest.
Scott: I mean, it's not an ugly disgusting room or anything, but it's not.
Scott: you know like there's nicer rooms not many.
Scott: I mean if you ever been up there It's this big circular room And it's got the chandelier in the middle And then it's like you know you can actually if you want if anyone wants to go to the Rainbow Room.
Scott: They have like Fridays and Saturdays.
Scott: You can just pay to go and have dinner and dancing up there.
Rym: well remember There's the Rainbow Room, and then there's the Rainbow Bar and Grill on the 65th floor.
Rym: Uh-huh, it's not the same thing all right, but yeah, I remember it was Emily and I walk in and we were just handed Bellini's not which is a Champagne cocktail.
Rym: all right if you're the kind of person who's like well, I've got champagne, but that's just not enough.
Scott: I gotta mix this with something Maybe because the champagne is actually ass and they need to cover it up.
Scott: But you can still say you're drinking champagne So you still feel really awesome like you're high class because my test of any sort of bar or anything like that is one.
Rym: I go to the bartender who had probably the third or fourth most awesome mustache I've ever seen.
Rym: uh-huh it was it was magnificent, and it was curled up and waxed.
Rym: Amen, and I said make me a Manhattan.
Rym: and he reached for all the proper things in the proper amounts and used a very good Whiskey.
Rym: yeah, that's what you get at a fancy place as opposed to say uber con where I got basically a tumbler full of whiskey.
Scott: That's a hotel.
Scott: It's an average.
Scott: You know usual hotel not some fancy place.
Rym: But yeah The only thing I really want to say is it was really kind of odd and wonderful to see the Empire State building From a similarly tall build like to see.
Rym: you mean about a half as tall building as in to see the Empire State building From a very tall building as opposed to seeing other not as tall buildings from the Empire State building.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of.
Scott: but the thing is once you've been on the Empire State building It's like well, I guess there are taller buildings in the world, but I guess not in the city anymore.
Rym: Well, I went to the Sears or the CN Tower.
Rym: way the tiles that it's one of the tallest like it was the tallest building In the world until recently, I'll look I'll look I'll look it up.
Rym: but You know what?
Rym: The view from the top was Nothing.
Rym: There were a lot of clouds under us.
Rym: I couldn't see a goddamn thing.
Scott: Yeah, that's about how the weather is lately.
Rym: Lately, this was like 10 years.
Scott: our looks like a Crappy space needle.
Rym: All right way to malign Canada.
Scott: Take that Canada.
Scott: your CN Tower is a crappy space needle like the CN Tower.
Scott: It doesn't look too good to me.
Rym: Have you ever been there?
Scott: I think I've seen it from the ground before but I don't think I've ever been in it, uh-huh Right.
Rym: But anyway, it is Wednesday.
Rym: I figure we should talk about anime a little bit.
Scott: You mean mostly.
Rym: well You know, we haven't done a show on any anime in a while.
Rym: since Scott won't watch eska flown a again I'm not like refusing you.
Scott: Hey, it's just what am I gonna watch this?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe you weren't playing dwarf fortress every day.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: I only played it for like three days so far.
Rym: Yes, and you'll have already for went things like sleep.
Scott: No, I haven't haven't?
Rym: you know?
Rym: I haven't.
Scott: I want to sleep my usual time now.
Rym: What about on the train?
Rym: You could have slept you could have read something but no you were playing dwarf fortress.
Scott: Yeah, I did.
Scott: I have for gone reading comics.
Scott: I this is actually the first time where new comics have showed up at the door and there is still old comics that were not Read me.
Scott: That's also because this is one of those short months where comics come and then three weeks later comics come Because the week the month before that it was like there was like extra weeks without comics, you know It sort of goes like that.
Rym: now It must be bizarro world because I'm reading comics out of almost the right.
Scott: Scott used to read them and I'm playing PC games And I have Wii games that are unplayed.
Rym: Yeah, what's going on?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: but uh, yeah this weekend as in Friday Saturday and Sunday It is December by the way, so December 7th 8th and 9th We are going to be guests at the New York Anime Festival in the Jacob Javits Javits Center in New York City, New York.
Scott: This is actually my news cuz I couldn't find any news and we need to talk about this But we don't want to do a whole episode about it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, we'll do a whole episode about it I imagine after it happens.
Scott: Yeah, probably next Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah, great But anyway at the convention we're doing about four events.
Rym: Yeah, just four and we'll have a complimentary four events.
Scott: That's all for well.
Rym: after I think the the epicness of seven seven event ConnectiCon.
Rym: Yeah And we're doing a similar amount of Katsucon and the thing is ConnectiCon was all like panels Katsucon Everything we're doing is like a main event.
Rym: Yeah, we'll have more about that.
Rym: Katsucon suffice to say is probably going to be the greatest live thing we have ever done.
Rym: All right, but until then I think the New York Anime Festival is going to be one of the greatest things live We've ever done baby.
Scott: All right, do you add a little schedule for us?
Scott: I think Friday at 3 like as soon as the.
Scott: I think the con opens to the public.
Scott: at 2 and at 3 the first Panel is at least in one of the rooms.
Scott: is us doing the gecky got panel without the prawn.
Rym: Yeah It's gonna be pretty much the same panel.
Rym: We did it Oda khan only without Gerald.
Scott: more more like the one we did at ConnectiCon more educational less Rapetastic.
Rym: Yes, I believe rape tacular is the word I was using.
Rym: All right, and that's gonna be fun.
Rym: Scott made a little powerful.
Rym: Well, not really a PowerPoint.
Rym: I made a Google presentation and we might we might act out a scene from one of our favorite gecky.
Scott: I'm pretty sure we're going to as we did before.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it depends on what scene.
Scott: Yeah, it's true Not a rape tastic scene.
Scott: Actually, that's it for Friday Which is probably good because we're gonna spend a lot of time getting stuff set up talking to people Out of the blue.
Rym: it turns out that three very long-standing and most excellent friends are going to kind of randomly be at the car Alrighty, so we're gonna get to see you not then we're gonna get to see.
Rym: I know we're gonna get to see C square at least half of C squared.
Scott: Hey, you got David Joel gonna be there.
Rym: Yep, Dave and Joel a fast karate for the gentleman are actually it's kind of weird Like we're guests of the con and Dave and Joel are guests of us of the con.
Rym: So theoretically, I guess they're at our beck and call since we control their badges But I don't think we're gonna make them do anything.
Scott: I think we'll make them maybe sit at our table when we're not sitting at it.
Rym: Yeah But Emily will also be at the table and she'll have the t-shirt designs that are probably going to be finalized somewhat in the near future Mm-hmm.
Rym: So if anyone really really wants to see the I don't know upcoming swag of GeekNights and maybe talk to the artist herself And get some feedback in before we actually send them to print now's your chance.
Rym: Alrighty, but yeah, that's it.
Rym: We'll be hanging out.
Rym: Just come to our artist alley table.
Rym: You can't miss.
Scott: I mean the con goes to a 945 on Friday, I think so the and I think like after it's like 645.
Scott: There are no events except for cosplay stuff.
Rym: So we'll just be wandering interview and hanging out.
Scott: Yep But yeah, we have an table by the way.
Rym: Yes, you can miss it.
Rym: Yeah, but Saturday from 3 to 4 We will have in anime fandom panel room 1 a 0 7 the anime match game, which was made Known at Katsucon last year and made famous at ConnectiCon last year.
Scott: Yeah, and immediately following that in the same exact room is the GeekNights live podcast Which is not something we usually do but the the Khan organizing guy requested we Record an episode of the show at the Khan as an event.
Rym: and also what I like about this is usually cons always make us Do the do a panel about podcasting and what podcasting is and talk about podcasting, but this isn't that.
Rym: this is just gonna be us Doing a show.
Rym: it will happen to be live.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know we're gonna talk about though I think it's gonna be pretty fun.
Rym: I mean we how rarely do we have a live studio audience?
Rym: That's more than just like Emily and Alex.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: But I would much rather Do you know a panel where I'm educating the audience about something specific like the a panel?
Scott: but oh well take what you can get.
Rym: And also on Sunday from noon to 1 we'll be doing the video game match game Same as the anime match game.
Rym: only the answers are all be.
Scott: I don't know Mario You know, I mean usually we do a match game for two hours.
Scott: So instead of that we're doing two one-hour match games.
Scott: I guess that's just as good.
Rym: Yep And for the video game match game I think most of the celebrity panelists are going to be people such as Dave Riley Joel white.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean this is an anime convention first and foremost.
Scott: I mean it has other stuff going on.
Rym: Yeah, I mean they're providing a bunch of celebrities for the anime match game and they said well We can get you people for the video game match game, but I don't know how video game they'll be.
Scott: Yeah, we need them to be video game or else.
Rym: It doesn't work though I will say I I cannot confirm 100% because she hasn't finalized it But she was very interested.
Rym: at least one of these celebrities We're going to have for the anime match game is none other than Lisa Ortiz the voice of Lena inverse.
Rym: Uh-huh She is one of those like.
Rym: it's funny if I went back to myself when I was in high school and watching anime and said Dude, you're gonna be running an event as a guest at a con where the voice actors of Lena cuz you know I watched dubs back then is gonna be on your game show.
Rym: I wouldn't have believed myself.
Rym: But here we go.
Rym: I'm gonna try to interview her aside from having her on the thing.
Scott: All right, whatever Voice actors, I mean like English voice actors really don't excite me like when I go to a con.
Rym: nothing excites you.
Rym: You're just down and glue things.
Rym: You exactly my room ain't so great.
Scott: Oh, it isn't.
Rym: dub actors ain't so great cons ain't so great.
Rym: I don't like doing my panels.
Scott: I guess it's like, you know, I don't look at them the way I look at some other famous people where they're like, oh my god amazing, you know, but I look at them like hey They're just normal cool people hanging out.
Scott: What's up?
Rym: Well, I very specifically said my high school self back when it was.
Rym: I guess anime was a bigger deal to me.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, my high school self.
Scott: I wasn't see.
Scott: that's the thing is until like very relatively very recently I didn't even think about the people who made anything I liked and I didn't care about them at all.
Scott: Like I didn't know directors or actors or authors or anything, huh?
Rym: Oh, yeah, we can't forget.
Rym: It appears that Daryl Surratt is going to be at the New York anime festival.
Scott: I think he has a press pass doesn't he I?
Rym: well the thing is if you're a guest of the con, there's a facility where the press can request interviews if you can sense.
Rym: and Daryl Surratt being cheeky requested an interview with us.
Scott: Well, he said he was gonna do it and he did it worked.
Rym: So I got an email from the con.
Rym: They're like, yeah this News-outlet called anime world order wants to have an interview with you.
Rym: Are you cool with that?
Scott: Yeah, I think it was.
Scott: it was cool to do this just to see how the system worked.
Scott: You know cuz if you're press at some convention, you know, and you want to enter, you know Get some time special with one of the guests or something.
Rym: Well, I think the real answer there is that Daryl Surratt wants some special time with you With me.
Scott: I think he was with both of us.
Rym: See the thing is I'm not worried about.
Rym: I don't know clown pistols because he's flying here and the TSA.
Scott: I'm trusting the TSA to take his clown pistols away.
Scott: We'll see how that come on TSA.
Scott: Don't let me down.
Rym: Those are famous.
Scott: last words, yeah, I know right but yeah, of course we aren't taking any airplanes.
Scott: We could easily get some clown pistols there.
Rym: clown pistols.
Rym: I'm thinking Roman candles.
Scott: It's all you It's all you.
Rym: but yeah other than that we're gonna be interviewing people and hanging out and I think it's gonna be a fun time.
Scott: Yeah, I've heard some interesting, you know I've gathered lots of information about this con over over a while and I'm not sure what to make of it all.
Scott: and you know The con, you know in all honesty, this is not guaranteed to be some amazing convention.
Scott: But again, it is not guaranteed to be some epic fail terrible convention either.
Rym: It's a new thing if they're trying something.
Scott: It's very interesting if you look at the history of geek conventions in New York City and they like the What happened with the Big Apple Anime Festival and you look at what happened with these people in the New York Comic Con?
Rym: But then you look at the people they've got running this con and you look at I mean Compare the first New York Comic Con where basically it was epic failure.
Scott: I see you look at all these factors And it's like you got this mountain of positive factors a mountain of negative factors and a mountain of unknown factors.
Rym: I think the positive out ways of a rationale is The epic failure of the New York Comic Con.
Scott: the two years ago is something No one could possibly be dumb enough to repeat.
Scott: Well,
Rym: no because when they ran the New York Comic Con the following year while it's not my kind of con Just cuz I don't I'm not the kind of person who enjoys a Comic Con they ran that thing pretty freaking amazingly Yeah, and a lot of people showed up and it went really really well.
Scott: Yep Well, I think that No matter what happens at this con everything we do as long as it happens and doesn't get like canceled or moved or anything we'll be awesome because I guarantee that.
Scott: and Second of all, I think it's going to be very interesting to see what happens Cuz.
Scott: yeah, I'm very I'm very curious as to see how it's gonna go down and I think it'll actually be exciting.
Scott: We're usually I go to an anime con and it's only the expected typical thing from an anime con, you know Like you know what I expect to see is what I see but I think at this con I'm gonna see some things that I haven't seen.
Rym: well, honestly more and more I think And that's why we're trying to do something a little different at Katsu con Just in terms of all anime cons kind of with the exception of Florida I guess are all the same like they all have their own character.
Rym: like every kind of zone.
Rym: things like Anime Central always had the awesome opening ceremonies and the best con suite in the history of cons.
Rym: But like Otakon was just awesome and gigantic and Katsu con has like people our age hanging out in the bar and just a very different vibe.
Rym: and like Animasements very like you get to hang out with the super big-name Japanese voice actors and directors.
Scott: as long as you're cool Cuz they're well, they're just.
Rym: they're walking around and it's very chill and awesome.
Rym: But like every cons different in that regard, but in terms of programming, they're all identical.
Rym: They got the cosplay and they got this and they got that in a bunch of fans mostly identical In terms of you never get see something unexpected at an anime con.
Scott: That's super.
Scott: not at least not if you've been to one before.
Scott: you've never been to one before.
Scott: I don't know if this is a good one to go to.
Rym: Oh God Remember our first Otakon?
Scott: I guess if this is the only one you can go to and you've never been to one before I guess it couldn't hurt.
Scott: But don't like.
Scott: take what happens here as an impression of what all anime cons are like.
Rym: because I'm who knows I think that anime cons need to I don't know diversify Branch out a little bit and like katsu-kan and Otakon each one of them should have something that really makes him stand out.
Scott: I think so, too, but I'm worried that someone will come to this and who knows what it'll be like, you know it could be who knows it's all over the map and They'll take that experience positive or negative and sort of apply that to you know And assume other anime cons are the same way.
Scott: and I know for one thing Good or bad to say this con will be different from all others.
Rym: See that's not a concern at all because think about how many people have never even heard of Otakon Like.
Rym: the only reason Otakon doesn't have problems with attendance is just because they kind of don't advertise.
Scott: Yeah, this play this these people are out to make a profit.
Scott: That's the other thing.
Scott: So the people running this con Otakon is by fans for fans, which has its pros and cons yeah, and this get on pros and Con.
Scott: oh, yeah, and this convention is by a company.
Scott: read exhibitions when that company all they do is run conventions of various kinds in order to make money and The industry is all over this con the anime industry the manga industry and whatever.
Rym: But at the same time the US manga.
Scott: at
Rym: the same time Peter who we were working with who kind of got us on board with this whole shindig very much was doing his research about how fan anime cons are run and there's a very good possibility that this con is basically going to have the weight of Professionals who care about like.
Rym: they have a vested interest in the con going well coupled with Actually doing things that they think the fans alike as opposed to I don't know Anime Expo, which I've never really heard a lot of good things about.
Scott: now it all I can say.
Scott: This is gonna be really interesting and I'm incredibly curious and actually sort of like excited to go to this con and see what goes Down where his other cons is sort of like going to a con.
Scott: This one's like, oh man, so what's gonna go down?
Scott: Let's see.
Rym: So I have some actual anime news here and holy crap really.
Rym: now the the moral I'm gonna let you all listen to this story.
Rym: I'm going to read Somewhat verbatim.
Rym: I'm gonna paraphrase a little bit the news.
Rym: It's not that long and Then I'm going to impart upon you what I think the moral.
Scott: Oh, I know this news It's on your.
Rym: delicious of this whole situation is?
Scott: I saw this news news delicious.
Scott: Did you read it?
Rym: Yes, go on good guy.
Rym: Okay, now this is I guess the closest thing to a press release that this got.
Scott: so yeah And who knows how true this is.
Scott: it's a post in a forum, right?
Rym: I'm gonna get to that.
Rym: All right Now this is posted by Kaito aced who has eight nine nine comma nine.
Rym: nine nine comma nine.
Rym: nine nine comma nine nine one comma zero zero zero comma zero zero zero comma zero zero zero dot zero zero points in this forum.
Scott: This is why our forum doesn't have points and he has made 12,417 posts.
Rym: so why do you been saying that?
Rym: Because while he and maybe people of his ilk might think one thing like they might glean one Type of information one opinion about him based on that number I hope all of you are gleaning the opinion that I have cleaned that number.
Scott: I hope so, too.
Rym: So begin quote and and the.
Rym: the.
Rym: the basis of this is so.
Rym: what happened to anime wallpapers?
Scott: calm Anyway, well papers calm that sites been around forever.
Scott: It's ancient super ancient.
Rym: Okay, this has been a long time coming But I wanted to hold off and tell the full story until things were a bit underway.
Rym: Now, please bear with me as this is going to be somewhat long, but I'd rather give more detail then less I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm not gonna point out any more typos or spelling errors or aircraft.
Rym: There's too many of them God Less in a manner such as this.
Rym: as some of you may know Anime wallpapers calm was started by Philip Mac PMAC Way back in the year 2000.
Scott: It was and that was the site to go to for anime wallpapers.
Scott: I mean, he didn't have a lot of wallpapers and he sort of posted them manually and people submitted them.
Scott: But he had him there organized by show and he had some quality ones.
Scott: There weren't any really ugly ones there.
Rym: since that time it has grown to be the largest anime wallpapers site.
Scott: It's pretty much the only Site that consists.
Scott: that I found that consists solely of anime wallpapers.
Scott: That's well organized easy to use and generally high quality.
Rym: Unfortunately on February 13th PMAC passed away.
Rym: how it was very sudden.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: See now this is actually a whole aside.
Rym: I think we should do a Monday's show on We're.
Rym: we're getting.
Rym: we're at a point in the world where a lot of people create a lot of content and do a lot of business II things without Companies or lawyers or business II stuff.
Rym: and like when we die, we're gonna die someday.
Rym: Well, at least Scott's gonna die.
Rym: Yeah Put my brain right after him dies, are we gonna be like Thomas Jefferson and Adams when Adams dies?
Rym: He's like damn it.
Rym: Jefferson still lives but Jefferson had died like five minutes before anyway.
Rym: So when people like us die What happens to GeekNights?
Rym: No one has the passwords but me and Scott.
Rym: No one has the accounts.
Rym: No one has any.
Scott: a lot of the things.
Scott: no one has the passwords with me.
Rym: Yeah, and then vice versa There's some things I have control over like all the archives.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, but that's an interesting question and a lot of those issues kind of come up in this continuing press release to allow me to.
Rym: I don't think I'll interrupt anymore until the end because otherwise I'll never get through this.
Rym: Mm-hmm it was all very sudden and the multitude of sites that he was running went down as the server payment stopped.
Rym: a server admin Hong Lee who was helping him manage the systems was able to back up most of his content and set the sites up on a new server.
Rym: When P Mac's mother contacted Hong Lee about her son's estate He decided that this was a prime opportunity And using his access to fake emails from P Mac to go daddy and Moved most of the domain names and sites that P Mac was running over to a nom.
Rym: I Guess these are all forum names.
Rym: Yeah, Hong Lee has posted in this forum as foobar widget Pretending he had a legitimate claim to the sites also.
Rym: Unfortunately during that time P Mac and I were not on speaking terms.
Rym: I thought he was - anyway due to the anime lyric situation.
Rym: I wonder what the anime lyric situation was.
Scott: people with their drama.
Rym: People fail with their drama, but I do want to point out does anyone else remember sailor bacon?
Rym: Which is that was a creepy.
Scott: It sounds familiar.
Rym: sailor bacon was a creepy, dude But he ran a website that was really the only place to get lyrics to anime songs back in the day.
Rym: I remember that yeah sailor bacon as far as I could tell was a cross-dressing like Sailor Moon guide something I saw pictures of him.
Scott: I'm looking it up right now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway to continue.
Rym: I don't know if this involved sailor bacon or not So my first knowledge of any of this came with the post from Hong Lee Being the suspicious kind.
Rym: I reached out to a few business partners of P Max whom I knew from our past dealings and was eventually Able to piece together what had happened Despite our differences of opinion here.
Rym: He was a friend of mine and it's also simply not right for his mother to have to be fighting a legal battle over the worker.
Rym: son spent most of his life on princess Minako and I Felt that we had to reach out to his mother and offer any kind of support we could try to correct the situation.
Rym: Both go daddy and anon weren't interested in helping.
Rym: as domains removed from one register to another and on was hiding his identity Behind their who is protection service.
Rym: each registrar simply pointed us back and forth yada yada yada.
Rym: He couldn't get the domains.
Rym: We spent most of the summer dealing with the registrar's.
Rym: after being contacted by our lawyer Hong Lee decided to register get anime wallpapers calm and redirect all the anime wallpapers calm traffic there Thus pretty much ruining the status of the domain.
Scott: if he if he had the domain, why didn't he just?
Scott: Move the domain like just point the domain directly at the server.
Scott: Why do you have to see name and that I don't get it?
Rym: I can think of a few ways for SEO purposes.
Rym: But anyway In the end we felt we had at least enough ground to file a motion with.
Rym: I can and try to recover the domain name.
Rym: After about a month I can rule than our favor blah blah blah.
Rym: They got the domain back After going through this and finally recovering the names.
Rym: kitty p mags.
Rym: mother was very kind and offering the domains to me with a very fair offer in the hopes that we can continue to build the site the way that her son would have wanted it as Opposed to going with an ad agency which could have paid her a larger sum but would likely have been unable to maintain the site correctly.
Rym: as Hong Lee was also running anime lyrics TV.
Rym: I Just wonder if one of these people is sailor bacon or even remember what happened to that guy Mmm, and because
Scott: we did send you a link
Rym: that having two sites with nearly duplicate content was unwieldy We took control of that domain as well and is currently being redirected to anime lyrics.
Rym: calm Right now I'm not I'm gonna skip the rest of this but that was posted by Igor bass aka kaito ace and I guess princess monaco Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah now wheel of morality.
Rym: Don't have drama.
Rym: Why does every freaking anime like fansite community every anime website even half the staff of anime cons?
Rym: because?
Rym: Being on the mailing list of a lot of anime con staff.
Rym: There's a lot of drama.
Rym: You'd be surprised like how much bullshit drama there is among the staff of almost every anime con ever People except probably the New York Anime Festival because they're all paid professionals.
Scott: Yes, if someone's not acting professionally drama will happen and most people, you know They're just you know doing things as friends and then they're not winners.
Scott: So that's kind of thing happens.
Rym: But why is it such like the anime manga video game role-playing like all day?
Scott: That's just where we notice that the drama happens in all in all different communities.
Rym: maybe it's just because these communities have a lot of Content creation and a lot of I guess undisclosed or verbal contract agreements that aren't very enforceable that a lot of people seem to Fight over like well, I control the anime club now because I blah blah blah.
Rym: I just don't get how there can be drama.
Scott: Stupid people the drama happens.
Scott: That's that's the rule the universe.
Scott: if no one was stupid There'd be no drama because everyone would just do what needs to get done.
Scott: BAM.
Rym: Now if you follow this link, I'd like to point out that there are two posts after what he said and I want you to look at the signature to content ratio.
Scott: Yeah of these posts I could talk about that in general.
Scott: What is up with people on forums?
Scott: at the gigantic signatures like full of images and crazy animations and whatnot?
Scott: You know what?
Scott: What do you what are you thinking when you're doing that?
Scott: What what do you know?
Rym: what they're thinking?
Rym: They're thinking the same thing.
Rym: I thought in like 1997 when I made Mephistopheles realm which was a ROM site on geocities and I had like 12 animated gifs of fire Everywhere, uh-huh.
Rym: and I mean I think it's gonna get to the point where there's gonna be two internets the internet where it's people typing text and saying things to each other and the internet where Every forum post is like a word like maybe plus one or lols and then an entire myspace page as the signature.
Scott: And so it's all gonna be our forum and fortune.
Rym: pretty much Things of the day.
Rym: so I guess because we didn't do a show last night.
Rym: We just put up the old archive episode.
Rym: We uh, we both have vidya game things of the day.
Scott: Well, I actually had a whole bunch of things of the day and I thought I had an anime one But I guess it disappeared.
Rym: so so I'll be real brief about this cuz I don't know what much needs to be said.
Rym: Pac-man the text adventure.
Scott: No, no need to make Dig Dug and Pitfall the text adventures.
Rym: I've always been a fan of that sort of minimalist text adventure kind of art like Some of you might remember the famous classic pick up the phone booth and die.
Scott: That's a great one.
Scott: Everyone should go play pick up the phone booth and die.
Scott: It's the best text adventure there ever was, you know.
Rym: I think I have to agree.
Rym: Yeah, but the pack text is a Pretty accurate.
Scott: I got as long as you don't cheat ram.
Rym: I turned on debugging mode just to see what was going on And you're the one who encouraged me to cheat and beat it and see what happens.
Scott: I tell you to tell you to jump off a bridge.
Scott: Does that mean you should do it?
Rym: I've been bungee jumping.
Rym: I'll do it again Without a bungee cord or a parachute Right, so what do you got for me?
Scott: You know, you know how Southeast Asian and I guess the rest of the world in general they like their knockoffs.
Scott: You know, they get their knockoff iPods or knockoff iPhones or knockoff Ps3.
Rym: well, we know how well that's been going in South Korea with the knockoff cell phone batteries.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: Well, of course, there are knockoff wheeze many many of them.
Rym: Well, I knock my we off regularly.
Scott: Yeah, so there's one particular one in China called the VV II the V and I got two links concerning the V. the first link concerning the V is a TV commercial.
Scott: it's actually more of an infomercial.
Scott: it's pretty long telling you to call this number to get your V now and it shows picked all these people playing the V and It's actually a pretty impressive commercial.
Scott: like it's professionally done it's like a real deal infomercial going on here to tell you to buy the V. and Well, I don't know if anyone's actually gonna buy it thinking it's the Wii.
Scott: They probably know it's a knockoff.
Scott: I can't imagine how.
Scott: Yes, maybe if you're just totally clueless when it came to video games you might buy it by accident.
Scott: But you know, I guess it's it's a system that works and they're showing you Actual footage from the V and not the Wii.
Scott: so all right The sec.
Scott: that's just to give you an idea of what the V is all about.
Scott: The second link is the real thing of the day.
Scott: in gadget the greatest website for tech news apparent currently, I guess Has a Chinese branch in gadget China and they got a V and this video Shows in gadget China opening up the V to see what's inside the V and what's inside the V is hilarious.
Scott: and In gadget China's reaction to what's inside the V is hilarious.
Rym: the noise they make when they actually get the cover off and see it Is is priceless and seeing what's in there also priceless.
Scott: so yeah you You know, it's one thing to see a knock a commercial for a knockoff game system.
Scott: That's just blatant.
Scott: It's another thing to see You know to sort of pull back the covers and see what's really inside that knockoff game system, right?
Rym: So we used to do this way Way back in the early days of GeekNights where Scott and I would each review something and it didn't always work So well, we always ended up either going really long or going really short on something.
Scott: And it was also sort of bland because instead of a show where both of us were talking back and forth It was one person talks a bunch then the other person talks a bunch and it wasn't really so exciting.
Rym: But I think we found the way around all this in that one thing we tend to do.
Rym: We tend to seem to have a pension for whenever we're at a comic store or at a con If there's cheap manga or cheap comics the cheaper they are the more likely we are to buy them and content is not a factor Something like that.
Scott: I mean if you're selling me the worst You're selling me MD guys.
Scott: I'll buy for a dollar.
Scott: Yeah, it'll happen.
Scott: Just because I Unless I've got it already.
Scott: if I've got it already I'm not gonna buy it.
Scott: But if even if it's the worst thing in the world if you sell, you know I'll buy it I guess I wouldn't buy like a hentai or something.
Scott: But if there's any reason to have it at all and the price is low enough I'll eventually if it's one cent.
Scott: if you got a manga for one cent it's rare the manga that I won't buy for one cent.
Rym: and We read these occasionally.
Rym: usually they just pile up then we give them away at cons or something.
Rym: But for whatever reason I ended up reading the thing Scott's gonna talk about and it actually was good.
Rym: We both avoided reading it because it looked kind of bad But it was actually kind of good.
Scott: and then Rym bought a manga recently and I sort of read it.
Scott: No, he read it.
Rym: Totally I bought it based on one thing and one thing alone.
Scott: I cannot blame you for buying it based on that one thing.
Rym: It was kind of expensive.
Rym: It was eight bucks.
Rym: That's more than I've paid for a comic in a long time.
Scott: Well, here we talk about it We were at.
Scott: we went to Hanley's universe, which is a famous semi-famous comic book store in New York City Right next the Empire State Building.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I see the Perry Bible ship.
Rym: God.
Scott: Yeah, very Bible fellowship was gonna be there doing a book signing and whatever.
Scott: But you know We sort of wanted to get on the train to do something because we were busy that day and he seemed to show up later.
Rym: Yeah, like it wasn't going we did.
Scott: we did have enough time.
Scott: You know if he was on schedule to sort of do go see him and do everything else we needed to do.
Scott: But he was supposed to be there from six to eight and it was six thirty and he wasn't there and there was a line And it wasn't moving and no one was and he wasn't there yet.
Scott: So we're like, okay screw this.
Scott: but we you know because to the situation we did hang out in Hanley's universe for some minutes And they had I found the road sick Adagio manga.
Rym: They
Scott: had they had a bin of old manga and I was gonna buy a bunch of stuff in there Like they had every volume of wounded man that I did not own already and I might have bought them But they were eight dollars each and I was like what the hell these are.
Scott: buy one get two free at most anime conventions.
Scott: So screw that.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I seriously considered just offer him a hundred bucks for the whole bin Yep, but I don't think they would have gone for that.
Rym: I think they keep that been there mostly just as kind of you know, a lot of old stores They'll have like old Nintendo's and stuff laying around.
Rym: they're kind of overpriced But they're more for I don't know browsing and style and making the place like check it out We got the most of.
Scott: the most of the things in that bin were like bent like not bent like all the covers You know has a crease in it But like the whole the whole book is warped and like leaning in one direction also.
Scott: It was mostly awful manga the vast majority if it was old awful manga But it was some of the first stuff that was published in the US in English, you know Not the first but some of the first.
Rym: well as Emily pointed out you can always tell because on the back of like every other One they're like from like from the same country that brought you Nausicaa.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: they're always because you know, there's very few manga and anime the people in this country actually knew about.
Scott: you know They knew about like Ghost in the Shell and Akira and maybe ninjas girl.
Scott: So everything on the back of it was like, yeah We're just like a cure.
Scott: Yeah We're just like ninjas girl by us where we're like that because you know You couldn't.
Scott: there was only so much Akira Ghost in the Shell had in just girl to sell.
Scott: you're gonna run out.
Rym: But I picked up I was flipping through and I saw something that looked a lot like sanctuary But obviously wasn't.
Scott: maybe because it has the same exact artist.
Rym: Well, yes, and then I look and it is something called samurai crusader the Kumo Maru Chronicles and art by rioichi Ikigami.
Rym: oh him from.
Scott: oh, you might know him.
Rym: You may know him.
Scott: Oh, I think you might know him But uh, somebody gonna get a hurt somebody did get hurt real bad Yeah, and it's written by a heroi Oh gee someone who I've never heard of.
Rym: he doesn't even have a Wikipedia page and I wasn't gonna dig deeper and figure out who He was.
Scott: let me check the a9 news network.
Rym: All right, but while you're doing that, what's his?
Scott: how do you spell his last name?
Rym: The way I said, oh I JI Oh OJI, okay.
Rym: Oh gee.
Rym: All right All right, all right, but the story here is.
Rym: I got a really.
Rym: I might just have to take you through it a little bit because it's hard to not start cracking up But at the same time I promise it's awesome.
Rym: So it begins with a young man whose name is Kumo Maru and you don't know what the deal is But he's sleeping on top of some sort of gigantic temple somewhere in Japan And he's wearing these pants and these suspenders and they're the most excellent pants I've ever seen.
Rym: They're pretty excellent and suddenly a bunch of monks attack him and he fights them off Epically and I mean very epically and kind of over-the-top Lee.
Rym: but no, they're friends and it turns out the monks raised him and he's this awesome fighting guy and Then it kind of lets you realize that when this is actually set is Japan in the 1920s 1930s, you know like kind of Japan's ascent to the modern world.
Rym: But before they ascended to the war like World War two world.
Rym: so, you know economic prosperity and industrialization and all that and there's a lot of style and setting and it's kind of Interesting.
Rym: at that point you think all right, there's gonna be some sort of Historical political drama set in 1929 Japan.
Rym: Well, then the robots come.
Scott: they look just like the thousand killers from Terminator 2.
Scott: They got the same, you know treads for legs triangular tank treads with the chain gun minigun arms.
Scott: it's the same exact freaking thing.
Rym: and then the Nazis and Then more Nazis and then more robots and then cat burglar.
Rym: who is so bad?
Scott: Nazis?
Scott: You got robots you got samurais you got cat burglars.
Rym: When this cat burglar is attacked by a vicious German guard dog that's about to kill this cat burglar I'm not revealing the gender of the cat burglar because it might be a spoiler Despite the fact that the manga kind of I keep saying epic but it epically gets rid of the old cliche of You can't tell who I am when you're wearing a mask because when the main character sees the cat burglar for the first time.
Scott: He's like take all that stupid mask Instead of the cliche ha ha ha I'm wearing glasses.
Scott: You don't know I'm Superman.
Scott: It's the cliche of aha.
Scott: The main character is so badass.
Scott: He sees through everything.
Rym: I don't know if anyone actually didn't see through it.
Scott: I just think people I saw right through it.
Rym: No, I'm high ready.
Rym: I think people saw through the disguise in the comic too, but they didn't know who the cat burglar was.
Rym: So it didn't help him now.
Rym: It's like oh, I recognize you but I don't know who you are.
Rym: But This cat burglar she is so badass.
Rym: spoiler that when the guard dog is about to kill her All she does is look the dark dog in the eye and the dog basically says whoa Never the fuck mind.
Rym: and just kind of skulks away with his tail between its legs.
Scott: I saw that that was quite the scene.
Rym: It's very.
Rym: it's drawn by our man.
Rym: So it's got.
Rym: the characters are all identical to the characters from sanctuary.
Rym: The main character looks exactly like Hojo just a younger Hojo.
Scott: Well, actually that's something that Tezuka started where.
Scott: if you read a bunch of Tezuka manga You will notice that even though each different manga has different set of characters, you know There's no characters in Astro Boy that are also in Phoenix.
Scott: But you'll notice hey that guy with a mustache in Astro Boy looks exactly like the guy with a mustache in Phoenix.
Scott: It looks like the same guy, but they're different characters in the story.
Scott: It's not like you know.
Scott: That's the guy from Astro Boy just happens to look exactly the same.
Scott: and that came from Tezuka.
Scott: You know he modeled his manga and his stories after he would go to this like sort of a theater called the I think The Takarazuka review with Takara's treasure.
Scott: I don't know what Zuka is, but it's a treasure something review.
Scott: and That was like in his near where he lived when he was a kid and it was like he.
Scott: just go see people put on Plays of all different kinds and it was.
Scott: you know There's one acting troupe that was there and they would put on all different plays.
Scott: So you see these different plays but every play has the same actors.
Scott: so Tezuka in his manga He tells all these different stories of different characters, but it's sort of like they're the same actors.
Scott: and I think Ryuichi Ikegami either because he couldn't draw more different kinds of characters or because he was taking some influence from Tezuka.
Scott: Also, you know every main character and every Ryuichi Ikegami work is the same guy.
Scott: Crying Freeman is the same guy's.
Scott: Akira Hojo is the same guy's.
Scott: the main character in this it's the same exact guy Even though they're different characters and different stories have nothing to do with each other, but it's beyond that.
Rym: I mean the the way characters look at each other.
Rym: everything is identical.
Rym: the only difference between this and sanctuary is that sanctuary didn't have the main character pull out a katana and Cut the barrel off of a tank.
Scott: So sanctuary was written better.
Rym: See that is where I might not agree Because the thing is this sounds all crazy and it's about to get crazier.
Rym: you see Right away.
Rym: They introduced a bunch of cameos.
Rym: I mean, you know, they're showing you like the streets of 1920s Japan and there's people dressed up in traditional gar But also people dressed as flappers and it's very, you know period commentary.
Rym: and then they introduced to you.
Rym: Mr Ropa and mr.
Rym: Enneken and I didn't know who they were But apparently they were famous comedians in the 20s and 30s in Japan.
Scott: now, perhaps they were Monza To say.
Rym: I haven't looked them up yet.
Rym: I don't know if they're Monza or not.
Scott: there I think they're like the avid in Costello of Japan.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: That's the feeling I get from reading the manga.
Rym: You definitely get that vibe now.
Rym: They're not just cameos.
Scott: over their names again Ropa and something else.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Ropa and mr.
Rym: Enneken okay, but Then later on we you know We meet a bunch of famous people along the way and I think the moments that makes this manga shine is first When we meet Pablo Picasso who's drunk off his ass and just like I'm the greatest artist ever
Scott: It's absolutely historically accurate 100%.
Rym: but also When first kidding the main character, you know, he meets Ernest Hemingway who is played apparently by Sean Connery.
Scott: That's also 100% historically accurate.
Scott: Sean Connery is just you know, Ernest Hemingway pretending to you know Not be dead pretty much because good God this is this.
Rym: I mean, you know, I say yeah It's just.
Rym: Ernest Hemingway is played by Sean Connery.
Rym: and in light of what Scott said about, you know Having care.
Rym: This is Sean Connery playing Ernest Hemingway.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: But so like they're all just you know, cameo cameo cameo cameo.
Rym: and then Ernest Hemingway is there He talks to him for a while and you think the scenes over.
Rym: Hemingway is gonna go on his way.
Rym: I'm not gonna see him again.
Rym: Well after the Nazi tank comes he tosses the ancient artifact of Japan to Ernest Hemingway.
Rym: And there's this beautiful hilarious panel of Ernest Hemingway Just kind of like don't do to do trying to walk away nonchalant while the Nazi robot tank is wreaking havoc behind him.
Rym: Ernest Hemingway then becomes a main character.
Rym: Haha, I think the second moment that is wonderful is when Ernest Hemingway shows up in a military uniform an American military uniform Outside of the prison that our main character boy has been locked up in in Paris With
Scott: a hand grenade and he's gonna go in and save him with the hand grenade.
Rym: and he does in fact save him with the head.
Scott: you think he is Spike Spiegel.
Rym: and then the scene that follows is because the whole like the gist of this is like there are people who symbolize the spirit of a nation and Some nations have multiple spirits that are warring internally with each other.
Rym: Japan has the true spirit of Japan as exemplified by this main character But it also has the rising military spirit of Japan as exemplified by the second most evil fucker in the manga.
Rym: Well, maybe the third most because there's also the scary Nazi doctor.
Scott: Oh great Nazi doctor.
Rym: Wonderful I don't know if he's a doctor or what but dude scary.
Scott: and he looks like cuz you call someone doctor doesn't mean they're a Real doctor.
Scott: I mean dr.
Rym: Mario.
Rym: Yeah, dr.
Rym: Mario not doctor.
Rym: He kind of looks like a clown but and his eyes point in different directions.
Scott: So doctor, whatever is just his clown name Apparently he's the man behind Hitler in this.
Rym: But like Japan has this evil militaristic guy and then the main character guy and it's kind of like the two did like the old spirit of Japan and the new Probably not as good spirit of Japan.
Rym: and they're fighting out their ideological battle through these characters And I think that is the intent.
Rym: this manga is a romp through history With just over-the-top action and great characters and cameos left and right.
Rym: This would make one fuck of a movie and I think it would be great.
Scott: I read I didn't read the whole volume.
Rym: We've only got you have to read the whole thing.
Scott: We only have one volume and Rym said there's two volumes of it.
Rym: I would buy.
Rym: I would pay a lot to get.
Rym: the second volume of this guy is awesome.
Scott: Well, I read part of the first volume and from what I read I mean it was everything.
Scott: Rym didn't really lie about any of it.
Scott: That's exactly what it is.
Scott: But the feeling I got while reading it was that it was sort of like the plot of a one of those terrible old Poorly dubbed kung-fu movies only with some wacky historical kind of Nazi stuff thrown in.
Rym: I think if you read the rest of it I mean you could take it that way.
Rym: But that's it.
Scott: That's sort of like the flow and the pacing I got was totally Kung-fu movie like at the beginning where it's like a guy sitting on a roof and then some people attack him and he fends them Off and then there's a guy saying oh ho ho you are so powerful.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I'm so powerful.
Rym: now We'll go out into the world and take my father's sword but you know what that stops happening and the tone and the and the Dialogue and the action scenes are very different from that first part.
Scott: pretty much once he is in Paris and actually on his journey Yeah, well, I will put it somewhere in my just now increase to read pile and then we'll see.
Scott: well
Rym: It is a romp I think that's the only word I can use and it's just him and Ernest Hemingway and Picasso and out of on Bismarck going around Fucking shit up and saving the world from
Scott: Nazis is by no means highbrow in any case but
Rym: at the same time it like I was you know, the spirit of Japan the spirit of Germany the spirit of France and Every like every nation has a character that is kind of like a caricature of the spirit of that nation.
Rym: So like G Gundam, but it's not stupid like G Gundam Unwatchable.
Rym: what I mean, I couldn't even enjoy it comedically when that stupid cactus whatever gun I can enjoy the idea and a still image of those crazy.
Scott: Yes, but that's all I could enjoy.
Rym: I was forced to watch more than five minutes of G gun.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because it was sent to us by the company and We were supposed to show it at some con that myself and Scott Johnson were running events for on behalf of the RIT Anime Club a long time ago.
Rym: Let me tell you we could not keep a single human being in that showing room for more than 45 seconds.
Rym: So in order to not get screwed by the company we sat there and filled out 400 surveys about the anime Awesome.
Scott: Did you say it was terrible on all of them?
Rym: I did.
Rym: he didn't.
Scott: okay, but Talk about my manga now.
Scott: All right, you can talk about yours but all I want to say is that it doesn't matter if we like or dislike this manga because it's gonna be Impossible for you to ever buy this thing.
Rym: I'm going to get it and I'm probably gonna have some sort of contest and if someone is worthy I'm going to give it to them.
Scott: Oh Samurai, but then we won't have it.
Scott: We need to get another copy.
Scott: samurai crusader.
Rym: This is gonna be like sanctuary or Eagle.
Scott: by the way I couldn't find anything about samurai crusader on the anime news network at all.
Rym: This is going to be like sanctuary or Eagle where pretty much whenever I see copies of it that are in good condition I'm going to buy them.
Scott: Mmm good call, but samurai crusader.
Rym: put out by Viz graphic novel the krumo Maru Chronicles story by Hiroi Oji, maybe I should look for cool Maru art by rio ichi ikigami.
Rym: I couldn't find ropa and enoki by the way, I recommend this highly if you are at all like me or if you like just over-the-top but kind of well-written and Kind of poignant but then Nazis.
Rym: Oh There's this.
Rym: this is the last thing I'm done.
Rym: So, you know the arts by the sanctuary guy and I don't know who their writer was but you know There's very much like young men fighting to like come out and save the world and like we're going to take over the government and blah.
Rym: Well Goebbels and Gering are young idealistic German young men who have joined the Nazi Party and they've just broken into government.
Rym: and now it's our chance.
Rym: We're gonna rise up.
Rym: We're gonna make the world a better place and they shake hands.
Rym: They're like, hopefully we'll go far together and it's so like sanctuary except that we know how that ends.
Scott: Who knows the second volume of this?
Scott: think of even crazier with Nazis turning to be good or who knows what?
Rym: I cannot recommend this highly enough.
Scott: I can recommend it less but it's not bad suck.
Scott: Anyway, I recommend this mug and much more.
Scott: see we went to not the comic book store in the city But a long time ago months ago We went to the local sort of general geek store Which has you know board games and miniatures and paintball and card games and video games and books.
Rym: It's no millennium I think there's only one millennium and that's in Rochester the best gaming store in the world.
Scott: It's just a general local geek store, right?
Scott: So he went there and we're just looking around waiting for board games or whatever to happen because we're playing with people whatnot?
Scott: And you know, even if you go to geek store you look at everything they got and I think the manga was like what buy one get one free buy one get two free something like that.
Scott: and And I look in and they it's not like a manga store.
Scott: I mean board.
Scott: There's a Barnes & Noble right there So they're not really competing there.
Scott: Obviously, they weren't buying any new manga at this place, you know.
Scott: But they had some manga sitting there on a shelf and I saw a Kurosage Corps delivery service volume one.
Scott: So I grabbed that and then I realized I got some free.
Scott: so I looked at what else was on the shelf and what I wanted for what I was gonna take for free and There wasn't much selection.
Scott: Let me tell you.
Scott: I mean the Kurosage Corps delivery service volume one.
Scott: That's pretty much all I wanted.
Scott: So of course instead of going for something Yeah, I mean instead of going for something like I think that as a volume of slayers I wanted to go for something completely unknown, you know If it's free might as well take something random and see what you get.
Scott: and boy did I luck out?
Scott: Basically, I picked this manga called the bug boy now and it part two.
Scott: It says on the side of it He know horror number two right from published by Coco row books and because it was number two I felt like I wouldn't read it until I got number one.
Scott: So it was just sitting on the shelf in my room, you know unread.
Rym: now I'm not gonna.
Rym: I'll let Scott talk about it.
Rym: But the only reason Scott read it is because I randomly was in his room looking for another comic and I saw it there And I was like, oh, yeah that thing.
Rym: so I opened up and I flipped through it like, oh, huh?
Rym: That's kind of weird.
Rym: I wonder what?
Rym: All right, fine.
Rym: I'll read it.
Rym: It looks short.
Rym: I read it.
Rym: It was awesome.
Scott: Yeah, so I wasn't gonna read it cuz I thought it was volume two and I was on the lookout for volume one.
Scott: but you know and Rym started reading it and he found out it was actually a Self-contained story beginning middle and end like this.
Rym: he know horror series of manga which I want to get the rest of now.
Scott: Yeah, is this guy named Hideshi Hino?
Scott: He's obviously a manga creator and he created these horror manga and He made each volume of the horror.
Scott: manga is a separate story having nothing to do with the other.
Scott: So is a picture of him in the back of the book that shows him standing there with you know The long samurai sword and then the short one and he's kind of scary looking dude here.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, like Richard Garrett something like that, but it doesn't matter because he actually this manga is Not like nothing I've ever read.
Scott: let's say that it's called the bug boy, right?
Scott: I guess the Hino horror number one was some different story.
Scott: and he know horror number three is some other story, right?
Scott: But he know horror number two is the bug boy.
Scott: and the bug boy is about this kid in Japan And he's he's a normal like a little eight-year-old kid.
Rym: if normal means you're you're basically like a young Edgar Allan Poe.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: He's he's kind of ugly like his eyes are all bugging out and Oh bugging.
Scott: you say yeah Something like that, you know, and he's not the happiest kid.
Scott: Well, he's not happy.
Scott: most of the time I mean his family sorta, you know, it's like.
Scott: they love him like you love They kind of do.
Rym: his family couldn't give it anyway.
Scott: Well, they're just.
Scott: they're sort of like, you know upset with him because you know, he doesn't get good grades He doesn't go to school and he's not.
Scott: he's not the greatest kid, you know.
Scott: He's sort of the.
Scott: the other two children they have are like, you know models of perfect Japanese children.
Scott: He's not.
Scott: they're always yelling at him, you know, and they wish he would do better, but he doesn't he just.
Scott: He just keeps sucking and you know as far as what they want at their kid to do, you know He sucks in gym class.
Scott: He sucks in, you know, all the rest of school, you know, he doesn't have.
Scott: he's not friends with everyone I mean, he has some memories of playing with his siblings, but not much else, you know.
Scott: people beat him up You know and his parents yell at him because he's not living.
Scott: he's not up to snuff But after school he likes to have fun and to have fun.
Scott: He knows the secret trash dump is and in the secret trash dump He's got some animals there and he goes and hangs out with these animals like his snakes and some bunnies and some other sort of cats.
Rym: and then huh fun social commentary.
Rym: all the animals treat him more like a human being than the human beings he Interacted with did.
Scott: but yes, I got in trouble once for bringing some animals home.
Scott: But then he stopped doing that, you know, he goes at any high right.
Scott: basically, you know after school he goes to this little secret hideout where all these animals are and he hangs out with the animals and Basically, I'm not gonna I'm gonna stop.
Scott: when I get to the point of spoiling right It gets this disease right or because something happens and it's not a spoiler.
Scott: It's called the bug boy.
Scott: I mean, there's no way you weren't seeing it coming, you know The disease turns him into a bug in quite the gruesome way.
Scott: He turns into a bug and I'm not gonna go into detail, but he turns into bug and turns into a bug.
Scott: Yep, a bug bug and he's the bug boy.
Scott: Not a bug ROM Nope a bug and he lives.
Scott: the life of a bug.
Scott: and the life of a bug sort of has its ups and downs and then That that's.
Scott: they're not gonna spoil anything more because I think everyone should read this if you can freakin find it.
Scott: I don't know where that's gonna happen.
Scott: and The thing that I think so great about this manga is that the story is very simple But the story is also very poignant and has a strong message at the same time.
Scott: I mean, it's Hino horror.
Scott: I mean it is pretty horrific.
Scott: I mean horrific things happen quite often.
Scott: There's a lot of gruesome stuff going on You know, I mean we're talking about like horrible deforming diseases turning people into bugs and you know all sorts of other nasty.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: This is a kind of comic that I never read a lot and I feel like now I'm more interested.
Rym: just straight up You know horror comics.
Rym: I mean, I like horror movies.
Rym: Yeah, I like horror novels, but at the same time it's also Terror novels more.
Rym: Yeah digress.
Scott: It's also sort of endearing.
Scott: It's like he got this bug boy and he becomes a bug and then you know He's sort of happier than when he was a person and he's doing all these things and you know Some of the parts are like Yotsuba like it's his bug.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: this is my favorite panel is just the bug.
Scott: he turns into a bug and he goes to the playground at night when no one will see that this giant bug at the Playground.
Scott: and he swings on the swing and he slides down the slide and he rolls around in the sandbox and he's super happy And it's like oh the bug boy.
Rym: He's so happy on the slide But then knowing again that it is a horror manga.
Rym: I wonder if this is going to end.
Scott: There's another one.
Scott: where he goes he sees, you know one day he goes to the ocean and it's just some happy crabs there And they're like happy crabs.
Scott: and then he goes over to the crabs and the crabs run away like oh no scary bug Let's run away, but the crabs are so cute.
Scott: But yeah, just this manga is simultaneously horrific poignant and you know as a strong narrative and Also cute and I totally love the bug boy.
Scott: It's like yay the bug boy, but then it's like oh The bug boy.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: I realize we did something that I guess we never vowed we'd never do but I almost feel bad.
Rym: We pulled a Gerald.
Rym: we just reviewed two things that there's no way in hell you're gonna find.
Scott: No, you're never if you find the bug boy.
Scott: Let me look on eBay for the bug Cuz.
Scott: I don't know how you're gonna get it.
Scott: I'll take eBay and Amazon.
Rym: if I ever get another copy of samurai crusader.
Scott: I will buy any copy of the bug boy I ever see.
Scott: but I will run a Bug boy on eBay, but who knows what kind of if that's legitimate or not.
Rym: It might be some other bug boy.
Scott: You know, it's definitely says, you know horror number two bug boy.
Scott: Ah five bucks.
Rym: You just search eBay for some sort of.
Rym: you know, horror set I did.
Scott: That's what I searched for.
Scott: there were other ones there, but they weren't as set.
Rym: Yeah, all right, but at any rate there may or may not be an episode tomorrow night.
Rym: It depends on how tired we are, you know, we have a weekend of not sleeping and then work on Monday.
Rym: Yeah, I'm actually going to work before the con on Friday.
Scott: I'm going to work before the con Friday, but maybe only for like an hour.
Rym: You don't have to take the 5 30 a.m.
Rym: Express train in today.
Scott: No, no, I don't I'm gonna be there.
Scott: I'll probably be at work for like an hour or two.
Rym: Yeah, we'll be at the con.
Rym: You know 11 noon ish, but you can't get in until 2.
Scott: So if don't show up early expecting to hang out because oh man, the bug boy is on Amazon You can buy it new for 10 bucks.
Scott: I would recommend you can also buy the other ones there.
Scott: red snake is volume 1. if you know horror lullabies from hell I don't know which volume that is.
Scott: living corpses volume 5 He Oh be no bow and the bugs from hell is he?
Scott: no hard number 3?
Scott: Yeah, all right, you know hard number 12. mystique.
Scott: Mandala of hell.
Scott: There's 12 of them.
Scott: Ah, yeah There's a lot of you know horrors.
Scott: Uh, if there anything like the bug boy, I want all of them.
Scott: That's all I got to say.
Rym: All right So if we don't do a show tomorrow Then we'll be back Monday unless we die at the con or something or if we just are too tired after the con.
Scott: Yeah, I really want like a scan of the bug boy.
Rym: But he's it's so hard with this, you know How badly I want to just scan in all of samurai crusader and just link to it.
Rym: Good God earn.
Rym: just I'll leave it at that.
Rym: to paraphrase Dave Riley fast cried for the gentleman.
Rym: Good night Internet.
Scott: Fuck you Internet.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.