Rym: It's Tuesday September 25th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: to all you gamers out there stop whining Let's do this.
Rym: So I was down in the Bronx as I often am working on stuff every day.
Rym: I'm not every bit.
Rym: a lot of days I'm just in Yonkers but I'm actually down in the Bronx and I finish up my work a little bit early.
Rym: I'm really fucking hungry But I don't want to stay where I'm parked because the parking right there is like five dollars a second.
Rym: So I get out.
Rym: I'm driving around and thinking what am I gonna eat?
Rym: I'll just stop somewhere on the way, you know park in the street.
Rym: Whatever food looks good.
Rym: I'm in no hurry and I passed by a white castle.
Rym: Oh man's I Can't eat most fast food.
Rym: I can Scott either.
Rym: we can.
Rym: The thought of eating McDonald's hamburger makes me a little nauseous.
Scott: I don't even know what they taste like anymore.
Rym: I know what they taste like.
Rym: it tastes like nausea Uh-huh, but well, actually they used to taste delicious before I realized that it was just chemicals.
Rym: All right Yeah, but anyway, I get like I can't eat that crap.
Rym: The only exceptions are I can eat Taco Bell pretty much any time.
Scott: Oh, that's I go bells disgusting While Taco Bell.
Rym: what you get is not Mexican food and I would not call it a taco.
Rym: What it is is good, but it is disgusting.
Rym: It's better than the tacos.
Rym: You got in like high school.
Rym: you get it like a college.
Scott: It's not saying much it tastes.
Scott: I don't eat those tacos either.
Scott: I have a high standard.
Scott: It's either good.
Rym: No, you don't.
Rym: those tacos taste about the same as the tacos.
Rym: We make at home.
Scott: No, they don't.
Rym: Yes, they know.
Rym: Anyway, and White Castle?
Rym: because White Castle is the bomb.
Scott: diggity castle is so bad.
Rym: Where else can I get four burgers for two dollars and twelve cents?
Scott: Nowhere and there's a reason for that.
Rym: You also got a fifth burger, but it was a jalapeno cheeseburger.
Scott: And how big was it?
Scott: like an inch wide?
Rym: You know how big a White Castle is.
Rym: like that big it's tiny.
Rym: It's not that time.
Scott: It's pretty tiny.
Scott: So anyway, it's like a bite.
Rym: as I'm walking in I see these a bunch of signs all around the White Castle and there's a bunch of video cameras and a bunch of like metal speakers and the sign says you're being watched 24/7 by the police and blah blah blah blah.
Rym: two-way communication something blah blah blah.
Rym: Don't do anything stupid.
Scott: No loitering Uh-huh, huh?
Rym: All right, so I go inside.
Rym: more signs the same.
Rym: apparently.
Rym: I don't know if it's a White Castle thing or a just a thing But it looks like this is a company that does this and inside the place.
Rym: There's a million more of them.
Rym: While I was sitting in this White Castle One person was arrested and two more people were forced to leave and told that the police were on route.
Rym: These people were related to each other in any capacity and none of these incidents were related to each other in any capacity.
Scott: What do they do?
Rym: All right, so I'm sitting there and it's next to a high school in the Bronx and it's around lunchtime.
Rym: So there's some girl and her two girlfriends like talking to each other and they're yelling and loud and you know what punk kids do and One of them's really loud and eventually suddenly I hear this announcement.
Rym: It's like will the girl in the blue sweater be quiet or else we will be forced to call the police.
Scott: It's not illegal to be loud, but you could just ask them to leave.
Scott: That's all you can do.
Rym: Well, yeah, and and the girls looking around like what all right, and then the cameras like look up at the camera I'm watching you be quiet or you'll be forced to leave and she's like whatever.
Rym: and then he says I Can't.
Rym: I heard that I am calling the police if you do not leave immediately.
Scott: Oh if you don't leave.
Scott: Oh, it's fine Yeah, all right.
Rym: So she's like what what what the fuck.
Rym: and she just leaves good.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So like five minutes later I'm sitting there and suddenly a different voice comes on and says Well, the gentleman in the purple shirt leave immediately.
Rym: the police have already been called What.
Scott: and I'm like, I can't call the police and someone didn't do anything yet.
Rym: Well, you can call the police and say someone's on my property.
Rym: I'm asking them to leave.
Rym: Please come in case they don't I guess.
Rym: Anyway, so I don't know if they actually call the police.
Rym: They kept threatening to call the police Constantly to various people and the second guy is like what I do.
Rym: Cuz he's sitting there with his friends and they were being really quiet and they're like You're eating non White Castle food on our premises.
Rym: you're trespassing.
Rym: leave immediately.
Rym: He's like I came in with my friends.
Rym: It's some fries from the McDonald's next door.
Rym: What the hell dude?
Rym: He's like don't swear at me.
Rym: get the hell out.
Rym: The police are coming.
Scott: So there's some Nazi who owns a White Castle, basically No, it's not.
Rym: I don't think it's the White Castle.
Rym: I'm pretty sure those people weren't physically in the White Castle.
Rym: It looks like I took a picture of it.
Rym: I got a look at this sign.
Rym: There's a company that businesses in cities can hire that will set up cameras and Basically yell at punk kids and threaten to call the police.
Rym: so you don't have to confront them They just have.
Scott: why do the people watching it just Nazis?
Scott: It's like how is that good for business if you just keep kicking everyone out?
Rym: You know how.
Rym: it's probably good for business because there's an infinite number of punk kids and the place will be full no matter what.
Rym: They could kick out everyone and the place would be full ten minutes later.
Rym: It's just.
Scott: I was kind of weird and you know what I would do though if I was a punk kid.
Scott: I would totally throw rocks at that place every night.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is it's open 24/7.
Rym: It's surveilled 24/7.
Scott: Oh, it's surveilled.
Scott: looks like the inside and the outside.
Rym: While I was outside they kept yelling at kids to move along or the police would be called.
Scott: We move along at the other on the sidewalk.
Rym: They were in the property barely.
Rym: It's like they'd walk in the property or start to cut through or like stop.
Rym: real close to the phrase.
Rym: You're like move along.
Rym: police are on their way.
Rym: The guys always just saying the police are on their way But the police only showed up once.
Scott: is it against the law to say the police are on their way if you didn't call them?
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: I did that remember when that stupid guy tried to attack me while I was riding my bike Mm-hmm.
Rym: I was basically I didn't call the police, but I had my cell phone out.
Rym: I'm like, dude I already called 9-1-1. the police are on their way.
Rym: You sure you want to stick around?
Rym: Yeah, of course that didn't work because his response was I know all the police they won't do anything to me.
Rym: Come here so I can kick your ass.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, it's just a weird Nazi kind of.
Scott: I get your a lot.
Scott: not it didn't sound like anything.
Scott: they did was illegal.
Scott: Definitely wouldn't go there if I knew the place was like that.
Scott: Yeah, the only if I approached the place and I said wow the person here is being a Nazi.
Scott: I'm not gonna go and shop there.
Rym: The only reason I went is because I fucking love White Castle and I wanted to eat a White Castle.
Scott: White Castle sucks and that place is like the worst White Castle ever.
Rym: It sounds like well The thing is the White Castle food was okay.
Rym: It wasn't the best White Castle.
Rym: I've ever eaten at.
Rym: the Cheesesteaks were a little dry.
Scott: What I would have done is I would have gone in and like You know talk to the the guy who you know, there's no one to talk to.
Scott: There's the guy who serves your burgers.
Rym: Those people didn't speak English.
Rym: those people didn't?
Rym: they?
Rym: Those people did not interact with you in any capacity and they were behind to tell them what you wanted.
Rym: They were behind bulletproof glass and there's no door to get to where they were.
Scott: Did you have to tell them what you wanted?
Scott: Yeah, couldn't you talk to them through that?
Rym: that I don't think they would respond.
Rym: I'm pretty sure they don't speak English.
Rym: I don't think anyone in that establishment spoke English.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, what if you went into the into the restaurant?
Scott: and what the White Castle?
Scott: and you?
Scott: you didn't.
Scott: let's say you're Chinese.
Scott: You only spoke Chinese But you knew how to order White Castles and that was it.
Scott: and you sat down eating your White Castle and they said leave Leave and you're like what?
Rym: I think that would be the same Situation as if a police officer tells you to do something and you don't understand what he says.
Rym: not all police officers speak Mandarin.
Scott: I guess so.
Scott: Yeah, what are they doing that situation?
Rym: I don't think is it kind of worked?
Rym: because despite the fact that there were with no exaggeration at least four or five Hundred punk high school kids like in a mess around the property of this White Castle just cuz it was lunchtime next to a high school I think that that system was the only thing keeping that White Castle from being just a madhouse of death and carnage.
Scott: see the thing is Though if I own the White Castle, I would let it be a madhouse cuz I would make so much money All those burger sales.
Scott: I don't know what.
Scott: in fact I wouldn't even I would have that be.
Scott: the way I would set up the White Castle is where no one could actually come inside.
Rym: There was graffiti in the White Castle.
Scott: I know I would set up the White Castle in such a way that it was just not drive-throughs.
Scott: Maybe one drive-through lane, but you couldn't actually get in.
Scott: It was just a building and you would come up to the edge of the building and do a window where someone would give you White Castles.
Scott: in the middle would just be a kitchen Yeah, and then when it got crowded around by a thousand high school kids I just throw burgers out and take money in Constantly.
Scott: if they graffitied the outside who gives a shit?
Rym: Well, I think part of the problem is that White Castles are not the classiest places And that's why who cares if it gets graffitied.
Scott: It's a White Castle.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's not like it's a French restaurant.
Rym: It's one thing to go into a building somewhere in the Bronx and there's graffiti on the outside.
Rym: But when there is graffiti on my table and on the floor and on the wall and on the security glass and everywhere in that building I just I Felt really out of place too because it's all punk kids and really scuzzy looking people.
Rym: I'm there in like a pair of chinos and a dress shirt with a Cisco book.
Scott: Yeah Hey, you didn't get asked to leave did you know?
Rym: but I got the hell out of there pretty quick cuz I was kind of Afraid they were gonna yell at me for violating the can't be in the restaurant for more than 10 minutes rule.
Scott: really Yeah, I would have been like on my way out I would just given a finger to the camera.
Scott: no that way That way they couldn't ask me to leave.
Scott: I was on my way out already.
Scott: What were they gonna do?
Scott: and all I did was give him the finger not illegal.
Scott: So an awesome game that has been out for quite a few years now, I guess.
Scott: yeah a couple years I guess that we love and most gamers seem to love is the guitar heroes and guitar hero 1 & 2 are out and available on Definitely the PlayStation 2 and I think some other systems.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I think the Xbox 360 has guitar hero 2 and whatever and they're good games And you should get them if you can.
Scott: and the rock band is also coming But I know less about that other than it will have more instruments than just the guitar.
Scott: which guitar hero only has the guitar?
Scott: But anyway, they have announced that in guitar hero 3 Legends of rock which has a really good song lineup just as good as the old guitar heroes All of the guitars are gonna be wireless.
Scott: it's about time.
Scott: Yeah, I know it was so annoying with the freaking wire You'd always have to like get it around your body in the right direction and pain in the ass.
Scott: Guitar hero guitar is gonna be wireless and they should be so awesome awesome all around.
Scott: The thing is from what I can see here.
Scott: It doesn't look like the guitars are gonna be Cross-platform compatible.
Scott: I mean the Wii guitar is white and has a hole in it for you to put your Wiimote in.
Scott: the Xbox 360 and ps3 Guitars look exactly the same from the outside But there is no information assuring me that the ps3 guitar will work with the 360 or vice versa.
Rym: I'd be almost certain they wouldn't and I never really expected them to actually work in any way like that.
Scott: Oh, I never expected it either.
Scott: However, I want to point out that as someone who currently owns no guitar heroes But would like to own guitar heroes and only has a Wii I kind of want to own If I'm gonna start buying guitars, right?
Scott: I don't want to get you know guitar hero for the Wii if I'm not sure that I'll be able to get you know Future guitar heroes for the Wii or that you know The Wii is gonna be the platform of choice for guitar hero and rock band for all my friends and you know We kind of want to all.
Scott: you want to get the most?
Scott: Guitar hero you can on one system with buying the fewest plastic instruments as possible.
Scott: Otherwise, it starts to become really cost prohibitive.
Scott: I mean if I want to play guitar hero 1 2 & 3 I gotta buy a PS 2 PS 2 guitars a Wii Wii guitars and then maybe like rock band won't even be on the Wii.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: I'll have to get a 360 and then some 360 guitars and instruments.
Scott: I only want to get one set.
Scott: I shouldn't have to buy more than one set.
Scott: and if they're gonna force me to buy more than one set of plastic instruments I'm just not gonna buy any plastic instruments and I'm gonna stick to playing this at conventions of my friends houses.
Rym: Honestly screw it I'll be I'll admit this.
Rym: I'm sure I'll get some Ravel from our friends, but I've kind of soured on guitar hero as a whole.
Rym: Like it was really fun when it came out because it was new.
Rym: but now I mean even in Wildwood We don't get to play it all the time.
Rym: It's not like I could get sick of it But anytime I played it I kind of thought to myself if I could play this or DDR.
Rym: What would I do?
Rym: and the answer was always DDR?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep Guitar heroes fun, but in the end it's not really anything.
Rym: at least DDR is really freakin good exercise.
Scott: Yeah, oh, you know guitar hero is still I think it's still pretty fun.
Scott: I mean, I'm not like holy crap You know, it's like any game when it's brand new.
Scott: It's all the crap and when you've played it or more It's less.
Rym: Holy crap I just feel like it didn't have the staying power with me like if I'd owned it.
Scott: I definitely did have less staying power than DDR.
Scott: I mean DDR.
Scott: how many years and it still has staying power.
Rym: I remember when we like every day we'd just kind of look around and search and call just to find out if there were DDR machines within.
Rym: I don't know 40 miles of yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean despite the lack of staying power compared to DDR You know, it's every a new release of guitar Hill were sort of reinvigorated, you know I'm sure when I play guitar hero 3 with all those new songs I'm gonna be all like all man's and it'll be like a refresher, you know, like a little bump, you know It goes up because
Rym: I just I feel like I'll always play it in that way.
Rym: But I almost think that if I actually owned it it would stop being fun because then I'd play it.
Scott: I do think that if I did own it that it would.
Scott: the fun would decrease more rapidly over time with my increased play.
Scott: however, there is also the added miss of Added miss that if I owned it, I would actually be able to get good enough to play the expert songs.
Scott: So it would also simultaneously unlock a new fun you sing.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I just maybe just cuz.
Rym: I don't have so much time to video games.
Rym: Those sorts of games are low on the list also because there's no clear-cut winner in terms of what console to buy.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: They're also gonna come out like a PC version and have some USB Guitars, I mean think that we haven't.
Rym: we have yet to buy a ps2 and it's still not worth it money-wise.
Rym: As far as I can see there's still 130 bucks ps2s.
Rym: Yeah until the five games I want maybe six.
Scott: Well, there's more.
Scott: there's a bunch of ps2 games that like non-obvious that you like.
Rym: what I mean what I want to play the Kingdom Hearts games.
Rym: Yeah, and I want to play the Guitar Heroes.
Scott: Yeah There's a lot of ps2 games.
Rym: You just don't realize I'm just not interested in a lot of them.
Scott: Yeah, you just don't know them.
Scott: It's like, you know you go because there's so many.
Scott: I'm not.
Rym: I haven't been much of a console gamer since I don't know the Super Nintendo.
Rym: Anyway, the Wii is what brought me back in the DS.
Scott: the point is is that if they don't make it economical to purchase only a Bare minimum number of plastic instruments and use them for as long as these kind of games that continue to exist I'm just not gonna buy any because it's totally not worth it.
Scott: it's worth it for me to buy a plastic guitar that I can use now and use on the ps2 and use in the future and Use forever and never have to buy a new one unless I break it.
Scott: It's not worth it for me to have to buy one now and then replace it when the new console comes out and then replace It three years from then and then replace it three years from then and then have to buy one to play at my friend.
Rym: The thing is my two sets of drums who aren't us and people who actually are into the game will do that Thus generating more income for them.
Rym: Plus, I mean look they're releasing this game on whatever consoles or platforms They can because they're just.
Rym: they're trying to sell.
Scott: it is good that they are letting it go on all platforms.
Scott: That is a good decision.
Rym: instead of forcing it because they'll make a ton of money They're trying to hit the broadest audience.
Scott: boss that is true But they should have made their guitars cross platform.
Rym: The people who want this game will buy it.
Rym: Anyway, we're what I think.
Rym: we're some of the few people who have the money and like the game but did not buy it.
Rym: Probably and all those people will just keep buying guitars till the end.
Scott: I guess I guess what it is is that I sort of demand that if I'm gonna buy You know a plastic instrument like this that I get the most use out of it.
Rym: It can possibly give you mean like with our $30 plastic DDR pads that broke in a month and we just kept buying them.
Scott: Yes, exactly You know.
Scott: I demand that if I'm gonna buy a plastic instrument or something that I'm gonna be able to you know, use it.
Scott: Yeah, think about it.
Scott: It's like why should I buy these useless piece of plastic, you know?
Scott: It feels really bad to spend like 50 bucks on a plastic guitar.
Scott: that like only works.
Scott: like one game or something.
Rym: I'd be much more inclined to buy the drums to rock band.
Scott: Yeah, but those better be freaking cross-platform.
Scott: No one's gonna be like having ps3 drums and Xbox 360 drums and a Wii drums and ps2 drums.
Scott: That's just not gonna happen.
Rym: I'm at another game.
Rym: I think we missed a good bullet on and now that I think about it was Donkey Konga.
Rym: That would have been really fun for like an hour.
Scott: Yeah It's a. I mean that game, you know.
Scott: While originally cool and probably a blast to play with your friends from what I hear I seen videos on YouTube of a guy Strapping four bongo sets together to make a big quad bongo set because the game it was too easy.
Scott: So he had to play all four parts at once on his own to make it interesting And even then it didn't look that hard.
Scott: no, it didn't look that hard.
Scott: it looked like.
Scott: with some practice I could have done it right.
Rym: So instead of a news, I got a gig back here All right.
Rym: So this is posted in our forums by Shane Four one two one six two.
Scott: Why do people put numbers in their names when there's no competition?
Rym: The only possible rationale I could see is if someone used that name on like AOL instant messenger back in the day Because you know you had to to get a name in most cases and now they continue to use that name just because it's a I guess.
Scott: but I mean if I go and log into like Facebook and someone already took Scott so I have to take Scott 32 I'll take Scott 32, but if I go somewhere else, I'm not gonna try Scott 32 before I try Scott again.
Rym: Well, it depends what if you were Scott 32?
Rym: Everywhere.
Scott: I wouldn't be because I would only be it in the places that forced me to what if you were Jean Valjean I'd be Jean Valjean two four six.
Rym: Oh one.
Scott: Yeah, but I got hopefully wouldn't be in jail anymore.
Rym: You stole a loaf of bread Right.
Rym: I ate it.
Rym: So anyway Right now it is 148 here in California and I just got back from a halo 3 release event.
Rym: washing the crowd.
Rym: I noticed a good percentage of people open their games before leaving the mall and wouldn't you know it?
Rym: most of them were scratched.
Rym: Well the news here.
Rym: I'm not really a new but I'll mention it.
Rym: It turns out that the collectors box whatever of the game Had a problem and scratched the ever-living shit out of the discs in it and I say you deserve it.
Scott: What the how stupid were you to buy the collector's edition?
Scott: Is that is the game somehow better if it comes in a metal tin?
Scott: is that metal tin?
Scott: You'd be worth something.
Scott: there was a time
Rym: when I felt that back there was a time in my life like maybe a four month span
Scott: where
Rym: if there was a box set of anime and Another box set that was the same anime, but also had a little piece of plastic I probably would get the little piece of plastic version.
Scott: Yeah, but Anyone intelligent realizes?
Scott: Hey, all they're doing is charging you extra money for the special edition.
Rym: That is not different in any way other than the word Like a little Master Chief helmet or something.
Scott: Oh man, the Master Chief helmet that I don't think about this.
Rym: when you were young Imagine if someone gave you the opportunity to get a Darth Vader mask a real one.
Scott: You can get them at Toys R Us.
Rym: No, I mean I were like a movie prop one like a super quality one.
Scott: It's no better than the one at Toys R Us for my purposes.
Rym: I'm just saying what if you were a little kid and someone like gave you Darth Vader's mask you'd freak out about it.
Scott: You can't really that when you're all right, you'd be too big and it wouldn't fit.
Scott: I'd be much happier with a little kid version for Toys R Us.
Scott: that makes me talk like Darth Vader.
Rym: All right, so you're just a jaded weirdo anyway Even though you won't be all right Right now for most of the people who are eager to get this game my advice to you would be to wait until December to get it Even though you won't be the first wave of people to play it.
Rym: Trust me when I say that right now the only people you would deal with are assholes and those people who like to scream fag While playing.
Rym: I'm not gonna rest of it, but
Scott: I would like to know funny even though I've read it before that
Rym: if you believe that the Percentage of Assholes and idiots on any game that has any sort of multiplayer is going to go down as the game is out longer You are sadly mistaken.
Scott: I mean come on counter-strike.
Scott: How long's it been out?
Scott: seven years?
Scott: Six years a long time.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: It hasn't gone down.
Scott: What makes you think that the number of people calling you a faggot in Halo 3 is gonna go down in two months?
Rym: Chances zero and the price isn't gonna come down and they've already figured out the whole scratch thing.
Scott: So pretty much if you're a Halo 3 fan and you want the game go by the normal edition.
Rym: right now There's a game that you really care about getting out.
Rym: get it on opening day.
Rym: You're not gonna lose anything for getting it on opening day unless they charge more for as long as you don't wait in a line.
Rym: Even then it might be worth it.
Rym: I would have waited in one hell of a line to get tribes to the day It came out.
Scott: Yeah, you didn't know until after though.
Rym: The only reason I didn't buy it right away was I didn't have any money back then you did buy it right away.
Scott: I told you to go buy me a copy.
Scott: You bought two copies on the internet.
Scott: They came in the mail.
Scott: No, I didn't and then I gave you cash for it.
Rym: Not for no not for team.
Rym: not team fortress Not for that game tribes - yeah, no No, I went to the store and bought it like three days later because I didn't have money when it came out.
Scott: Oh, but you did buy a copy on the internet and then gave it to me and I gave you money.
Rym: I went to the store and bought it with cash cuz my credit card was maxed out.
Scott: That's not what I remember.
Rym: I couldn't buy anything online.
Rym: My credit card was totally maxed out at like a couple thousand dollars.
Scott: That's not what I remember, but I had no money at all.
Rym: I've got some money and I went to the store.
Rym: I think it was media play and I bought the physical box.
Scott: That's not what I remember.
Rym: But okay That's a really weird thing to make up Scott.
Scott: That's how I remember.
Scott: it is cuz I remember I Wanted it, but I couldn't go get it for some reason.
Scott: I told you to get it things of the day.
Scott: So Rym yesterday that don't tase me bro with the Emperor.
Scott: You thought that was pretty funny.
Rym: I thought that was pretty funny.
Scott: Oh, well, I got something more funny than that.
Rym: Ah, you apply thinks I've seen this already.
Rym: I think Scott has played ace to my queen in the Trump.
Scott: perhaps.
Scott: So, you know the end of Star Wars Episode six where Luke takes off Darth Vader's helmet and he's like you were right.
Scott: Right that scene.
Scott: well in that scene after he takes Darth Vader's helmet off it looks like he has a harmonica.
Scott: we just it was.
Scott: you start watching this video right and Luke takes his helmet off.
Scott: It takes Darth Vader's helmet off and It it's the same scene is just right from the movie.
Scott: No editing and Rym.
Scott: we're watching it together and Rym says harmonica and I just kind of nod in agreement Like yeah, it's the harmonic is always a lot of lead-up.
Rym: like it shows the whole scene.
Rym: so, you know, we see we know it's a funny video something.
Rym: but After a few, you know, I'm watching and watching.
Rym: I kind of forget that This is supposed to be some funny video and all I'm thinking is man Star Wars is awesome.
Rym: Yeah, man, the scene was awesome.
Rym: And then I say out loud, you know, I always think whenever I see the scene He's got.
Scott: I think you just said the word harmonica, but I said something like that.
Scott: Yeah, but I nodded in knowing agreement like it looks like harmonica.
Scott: Everyone always thinks it looks like a harmonica.
Rym: I think the prop might have been a harmonica, but I digress.
Scott: it could have been.
Scott: they could have harmonica in that in that costume there.
Scott: and then the video happens and We lulled quite a bit perhaps even rofl.
Rym: it caught me off guard and that's kind of surprising.
Scott: Yep, even though we should have read the title of the video would have given it away.
Rym: I did and I just didn't put two and two together.
Scott: I didn't put two and two together till it happened.
Rym: then I was like and I almost fell over laughing.
Rym: Yes It's wonderful.
Scott: It is quite see I think.
Scott: let.
Scott: yesterday you had a. you had an example of the lateral thinking humor.
Scott: You take one thing you find another thing that matches and you put them together in a mash-up or remix.
Scott: What this is?
Scott: this is sort of like an inner thinking Discovery or realization sort of like an epiphany Humor in where you find something that everyone thinks in their mind, you know, everyone watching this.
Scott: Thanks harmonica.
Scott: when they see that, you know, that's what they think but no one says it.
Scott: It's not really like, you know, something that's loud and about but it's it's something everyone thinks when they see something deep inside of them.
Scott: This is what's on their mind.
Scott: So you take what's deep inside people's minds?
Scott: You know when they see something and you make it a reality and you put it right in their face Right up there into the conscious area right up front and when that happens people like oh my god That guy thinks the same thing.
Scott: I thought oh And then if a lot of people think that same thing that you think deep inside and you bring it you bring it out.
Scott: That's a big hit.
Scott: So it's a way to make the funnies happen.
Scott: Yep, and you don't see it too often because it takes a lot of cleverness and a lot of trickiness.
Rym: So I found this a while ago and I honestly couldn't find anything worthwhile today.
Rym: So this was kind of a backup thing of the day.
Rym: It's not the best thing in the world and mostly I make it my thing today cuz the goddamn song gets stuck in my head Anytime I hear it.
Scott: It's not even the best song.
Scott: It's okay.
Rym: Well thing is this is one of those things that it's a really good concept and it's executed really well Except for a few critical areas where it kind of falls short.
Rym: the shitty animation.
Rym: The animation is not that bad like.
Rym: parts of it are really dumb and parts of it are really really funny and awesome And it's kind of hard to place how good this thing is overall.
Scott: It's it's slightly above average.
Scott: You won't be like saying wow, this is crap and not worth looking at but it's not like some amazing thing Like oh man's like - yeah
Rym: Though the song is pretty catchy and the only problem with it is that they needed someone who was better at mixing I think to make all the different tracks sit volume wise relative to each other better.
Scott: But yeah There's definitely like.
Scott: you can't hear what the people are saying because the music is louder than the talk that the vocals and they got to Make.
Scott: they got to figure that out.
Rym: Also, it's one of those things where if you've played the game and while I haven't I am in tune enough with digi game culture to know to what they're referring and I get the impression that if you have played this game the reference they are making is one of those.
Rym: Oh, yeah I Remember that.
Rym: it's so true.
Scott: I can't believe you haven't played Super Mario RPG.
Rym: I remember once the Super Nintendo was kind of in his waning years I gave up console gaming.
Rym: a hundred percent didn't even bother with.
Scott: the n64 was a game that came out late in the Super Nintendo Is life but it is.
Scott: Pratt is like the only game made by Nintendo and Square together and it is an awesome game I don't doubt it.
Scott: I all the other games likes Paper Mario and Mario and Luigi Superstar Saga and all those games spawn from Mario RPG.
Scott: Originally, this is the first one.
Rym: It's just by the time that game came out.
Rym: I was playing PC games a hundred percent all the time.
Scott: No, you got to be got to be going back to play the Mario RPG, right?
Rym: So speaking of playing computer games all the time There's one game that we talk about every now and then called tribes 2 which I'm of the opinion was the best Multiplayer first-person shooter experience the world has ever seen.
Scott: Yeah The unmodified tribes 2 in the early days of its release before it got fucked over which we'll talk about.
Scott: Finally the whole details of if we haven't talked about it before Was perhaps the most fun most amazing FPS.
Rym: it was a game where the skill cap was beyond what many humans could achieve.
Rym: The strategy cap was to the point of rivaling actual real-world strategy.
Rym: Yep, the the scale of the game the number of players per team It was.
Rym: it was everything that planetside should have been.
Scott: yeah Basically, the only problems with the game is number.
Scott: besides, you know before it got fucked up Was that it was pretty hard to play for nubs.
Scott: You mean if you're a nub this game is pretty complicated and you were gonna have a hard time figuring it out.
Rym: Oh, if you had never played an FPS You couldn't play this game and not even if you had played net.
Rym: Never played a complicated FPS like weapons factory or one of those team fortresses you probably couldn't play this game.
Scott: Yep, but yeah other than that this game was pretty awesome.
Scott: I mean there are a few Deficiencies and like the way the vehicles worked that that games now like actually halo and unreal tournament have fixed the vehicles and those Games work.
Scott: the way vehicles should work in FPS is a half-life 2 also, but other than that tribes to the bomb.
Rym: So the game was awesome and pretty much from when it came out Until the thing happened.
Rym: I played that game more than I did anything else in my life.
Scott: Yeah, come home and play it Every day for our play between our asses and our skip classes to keep playing.
Rym: Yep And like I'd come home from a class and Scott was already home skipping playing the game and I just without a word I'd sit down at my computer drone every server He was on and start setting up a remote base for him to stop at before he throws the satchel charge in the generator.
Scott: Oh my sassle charges.
Scott: Alright, but anyway The game had one other interesting thing that not too many games before it had.
Scott: I think it might actually been the first game to Have this in which you know how you have a get a get you get a multiplayer game and in the multiplayer game There's an interface that allows you to find servers to play on.
Scott: Okay tribes to had that.
Scott: they also had forums Built into the game.
Scott: counter-strike had forums, but the counter-strike forums are at counter - strike net.
Scott: So not everyone who played counter-strike was on the forums.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the.
Rym: everything was integrated into the game.
Rym: You had your own little world.
Rym: You can make lanes were integrated into the game.
Scott: You can make clans in the game.
Scott: You could email other players within the game with your special tribes to email.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was a. you could customize your guy and a whole bunch of other stuff from within the game.
Scott: and that When I first installed the game and I saw that I said wow, that's freaking awesome.
Scott: That is freaking awesome.
Scott: I love that.
Rym: now here is what happened to tribes - So they had all this setup and people are playing the game and the game was stupid popular for obvious reasons.
Scott: I mean tribes.
Scott: one was stupid.
Scott: popular tribes - came out and sold out and People are playing it like crazy and people playing it like crazy.
Rym: Yeah This is one of the a PC game before you know steam really took off where it kept selling out.
Rym: You couldn't buy it in a lot of places for a while.
Rym: Yep, at least a short while a few weeks Yeah, but that was a while in the span of this game.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but as time went on the developers actually kept a close eye on the community.
Scott: Well, the community was sort of you know on their servers in their game.
Scott: So they they paid attention to what went on in those forums.
Scott: They moderated them.
Scott: They talked to people.
Scott: They they were all out and about within the game, which is pretty cool.
Rym: You want the developers to be close to the community like every game out there that has any sort of community about it.
Rym: Certain percentage of the people who play the game bitch about various aspects of it.
Scott: Oh, man, it's been fused to shoots too slow.
Scott: Oh, man, the heavy could go a little faster.
Scott: Oh, man, the one of the vehicles work this way.
Scott: Why doesn't that work this way in every multiplayer game?
Rym: The world is seen.
Scott: since internet communities came about I have isn't any multiplayer game Requiring skill.
Scott: I think I think there are some multiplayer games.
Rym: It also happens in World of Warcraft.
Scott: I'm just saying is that it all it does happen in games that don't require skill But you won't get this kind of bitching in some other.
Scott: there are some multiplayer games where you won't get bitching.
Scott: No one complains about how pac-man verse works.
Rym: I'll bet there are people who already are.
Rym: really I'll bet there.
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: Anyway, so they watched this community.
Rym: Hey, well first I should say that I'd say about a quarter of these sort of bitchy complaints are probably kind of valid.
Scott: I mean there were.
Scott: the game wasn't perfect and there were some valid.
Scott: You know things you could have done to the game to make it even better.
Rym: but in any game the majority of the complaints about a game are Really not legitimate.
Rym: and you might say but Rym it's a subjective thing.
Rym: If someone likes X in a game Then they could complain about X being not the way they want it to be.
Rym: and while that would be true I think the fundamental problem here is that a lot of people in all seriousness Don't actually understand what they want and what they think they want is not fun for them.
Scott: Yep, for example, you got someone right who's playing Counter-strike, right and they say take out the AWP.
Scott: It sucks, right?
Scott: Well, the what they're really saying is I don't know how to avoid getting shot by snipers.
Scott: Take them out of the game so that the game is now easy for me.
Scott: And if they let's say they did that Let's say they took the AWP out of the game, right?
Scott: If this person would either a their only weakness was that they couldn't avoid snipers.
Scott: now, they're gods of the game.
Scott: It's too easy and there's no point for then They'll get bored of it really quick as they'll just own everybody or B They actually sucked and it was just they suck so much.
Scott: snipers killed them for any of the other weaknesses were made aware to them And they'll die from some other thing.
Scott: and all they're really saying is I suck at this game.
Scott: Please make it easier for me so I can win.
Scott: It's not fun because I can't win.
Scott: and part of that comes from the fact you have a multiplayer game Where skill matters.
Scott: and if you have multiplayer game where skill matters unlike a single-player game, right?
Scott: Let's say you have a single-player game You can just if the single-player game throws the same thing at you every time.
Scott: It doesn't get harder unless you change the difficulty setting, right?
Scott: So once you figure out you raise your skill level up to beat the single-player game.
Scott: You can eventually beat it by just playing and playing and playing it.
Scott: so you get better.
Scott: in a multiplayer game.
Scott: Everyone is getting better at.
Scott: you know varying rates depending on how much they play and how what their talents are and how good they are and some people Will never be good enough to win again in a game and counter-strike.
Scott: There's some people just no matter how hard they try.
Scott: if they play counter-strike They'll just get killed right away and it will not be fun for them because they'll just constantly lose because they suck.
Scott: and The only way to make it fun for them is to make the game so easy that they can actually play.
Rym: So basically make it unreal tournament, right?
Scott: So they may all they make all these complaints, you know that are like take out the AWP Make the map like this and those are just you know Reactions to.
Scott: they can recognize that they law.
Scott: they stay died this time because of something in the game.
Scott: You know, it's like take out the goombas of Mario.
Scott: I just died on a goomba.
Scott: take out the pits.
Scott: in Mario I just fell in a pit.
Scott: take out the Koopas.
Scott: in Mario I just got hit by a bouncing shell.
Scott: When the real answer is don't touch the goombas don't fall in the holes and don't get it by the bouncing shells Well, if you give these people their way eventually Mario will just be a flat plane with no bad guys No holes, no nothing and a flag at the end.
Rym: Well the thing is I mean that that is definitely true to a degree but there are a lot of other.
Rym: I mean Sometimes people just don't understand what makes a game fun like they play a game and they think they like it.
Rym: Let's take Team Fortress 2 as an example because the primary complaint that people have on the internet about the game now At least the normal stupid people is that there are no grenades.
Rym: well, I bring back grenades like every other Team Fortress game and What they don't seem to understand is one that Grenades were taken out of the game because the way grenades worked in every Team Fortress style game hitherto
Scott: was
Rym: just a programmatic way to have things that are interesting in the game like the grenade object was all they had to work with and Those things that you're missed weren't really grenades or they didn't function the way you thought they were to the purpose they served in.
Rym: the game could be served in a better way and Like the unintended consequence of bringing back grenades.
Rym: I mean sure.
Rym: Oh the game will be more interesting.
Rym: I have more options as a character But now the game is all spammy like a lot of older TFC kind of games are.
Scott: yep This explosion is good or bad.
Rym: It could go either way.
Rym: I'm not saying it would be
Scott: bad, but
Rym: I think a lot of people who were saying hey they took out grenades don't realize the far-reaching ramifications putting grenades back in would have and the fact that it Might make the game less fun for them, even though they think it would make it more fun.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you added grenades back to tf2 just if you gave everyone normal grenades, right?
Scott: There's like a normal throwing grenade like well one.
Rym: There's no point being a demo man anymore, right?
Scott: There's no point being a demo man There's.
Rym: not everyone can do what you do because the game is so small as in all the maps are really tiny and all the Player-models are really big.
Rym: if you spam it up.
Rym: You can just kill everyone trivially and no one can get anywhere.
Scott: Yep, and another thing is That if you everyone has a grenade then the classes really aren't all that different.
Scott: I mean the scout is supposed to be a wuss who's not supposed to be able to do that much damage.
Scott: You just be able to move fast to get the intelligence or whatever if you give him grenades.
Scott: Now the scout is suddenly super dangerous because he can run in with grenades.
Scott: and if you give the heavy grenades Well the heavy can already do a shit ton of damage.
Scott: He doesn't need grenades, but actually it gives the heavy an advantage in that now The the heavy is really not so good at taking out turrets.
Scott: That's a weakness of the heavy.
Scott: if you give them grenades is gonna be taking out turrets, especially around corners.
Scott: In fact, everyone will be doing that and the engineer will be mad weak, even though he has grenades.
Scott: People don't you know, they're not game designers They're people who just play a game and they have sort of this gut reaction of what they think is Bothering them about the game something that's making it unfun for them.
Scott: Let's make an analogy.
Rym: say you're playing chess, right?
Rym: Yeah, and for whatever reason you think you know, this is boring the way it is.
Rym: Why don't we make it so that the knight can also move for like one diagonal space?
Rym: Yeah, and you think oh that'll make it fun.
Rym: It'll make it interesting It'll make it different.
Rym: But the the way that that will affect gameplay in the short and long term Will make the game so completely different that it's not even chess anymore at all.
Scott: Yep It's like people who play Monopoly and then they want to do the money on free parking business and they they just don't realize That that makes the game completely different, you know, well completely random Yep, and completely stupid.
Scott: and they don't consider the because they're not game designers.
Scott: They don't really know about game design.
Scott: They don't consider the ramifications of the things they demand.
Rym: So what happened with tribes?
Rym: - well developers watch this little community and they paid attention.
Rym: I mean, it's almost that they tried too hard to please their audience.
Rym: They would see people make a complaint and Almost no matter what if someone made a complaint at all They would look into it and they started making changes and they started making more changes.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: patches to the game didn't just improve, you know bugs in the game They and some things they change were for the better but a Lot of the patches to the game that were forced you had to get them in order to keep playing online because they had a centralized Meetup matchup server Would make change the rules of the game for the worse.
Rym: Yep, they made weapons faster slower and they changed vehicles and they changed damages.
Scott: They changed the way you moved.
Scott: They changed the way you did things.
Scott: they changed it.
Scott: So you couldn't do certain things.
Scott: They they made certain, you know items in the game useless or more or less powerful.
Rym: They pretty much listen to what all the people who played the game said without really considering The ramifications or think trying to think about.
Rym: okay Why would this person say that?
Rym: and what would happen if I did?
Rym: Go like cave to their will or maybe I should look into a way to make them have more fun without Changing that fundamental part of the game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they.
Scott: you make a game right and you you change the gameplay and you change the rules and you test it.
Scott: I mean this happens at any game.
Scott: even the best game designer in the world comes up with a game and they keep tweaking the Rules and they keep Playtesting until they figure out the exact right rules of the game to make it the most awesome and the most fun you know as far as they can see.
Scott: if You then release the game and then you just sort of change a rule on the fly You didn't test that change.
Scott: You didn't go through play testing.
Scott: You don't know the game developers.
Scott: It's like they change the rules of the game without Testing and having a lot of playtime with those new rules to see how that would affect the game.
Scott: They just implemented changes according to the demand of the the game players and didn't think about.
Scott: you know Neither the players nor the developers thought about how that would change the game.
Rym: kind of like if Alan Greenspan would you know?
Rym: Listen to what the Ron Paul people said about the economy and did like, you know people complaining.
Rym: Oh, we got to go back to the gold standards like yeah I'll try this gold standard.
Rym: people seem to be complaining about the current system that works perfectly.
Scott: Oh, no, it's recessions.
Scott: Yeah, you can vote for skin a little little if you want.
Rym: there should be a recession a little aside.
Rym: The gold standard is stupid.
Rym: if you're a proponent of it do some research and if you still think that it's a good idea You're stupid.
Rym: Yep, but I digress.
Rym: So the moral here is pretty simple.
Rym: game design is not an easy thing to do at all.
Rym: I mean, that's why in Germany It's such a big deal and the good board games are always made by the same group of people.
Rym: It's like those people are the Steven Spielberg's of board game making.
Rym: they understand it.
Rym: They're good at it.
Scott: Yeah, there's a reason that Rainer Canisia is like a professor and why most of his games are a lot of fun.
Scott: He has knowledge of how to design games in a way that makes them fun and interesting.
Rym: Game developers really have to walk a fine line because the game developer can't just go along with their vision a hundred percent Because if that doesn't jive with what the players want no one's gonna play their game.
Rym: Yep, but if they give the players Everything they want all the time The game won't end up being a game anymore and it won't end up being a good game Simply because the majority of players who aren't game designers don't understand what it is that makes a game good.
Rym: granted a lot of times Developers fall prey to this.
Rym: I think the most horrifying example in the history of gaming was Wario aware for the Wii.
Scott: Are you aware for the GameCube was just like this masterpiece game as far as well For the GameCube is funny because it's exactly the same as Wari aware for the GBA.
Scott: However it on the GameCube, of course You play it on your television and you could use a GBA with the link cable or a GameCube controller.
Scott: But it also had this multiplayer mode tacked on.
Rym: yeah I mean think about it.
Rym: Wari aware was a in my opinion pretty crappy game like single-player wasn't interesting.
Scott: It was worth the play, but it wasn't worth like paying full price and playing it a lot and it was moderately popular.
Rym: I think it was really popular in Japan.
Rym: I don't remember the figures off hand.
Scott: Well, it's a good, you know casual kind of game.
Rym: Yeah, well plus it was goonie and it was the kind of thing that sells really well in Japan.
Rym: Yeah, one of those kinds of games.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So alright, the game was popular.
Rym: Let's make a GameCube version.
Rym: Hey, why don't we throw some multiplayer in?
Rym: the GameCube version sold like crazy and was super popular and stupid.
Scott: amazing I don't know if it's sold like crazy, but it was.
Scott: it was a really amazing.
Rym: It was a really high selling game.
Rym: It wasn't like a. it wasn't like oh my god This game sold out eight times, but it sold really well a lot better than they expected.
Rym: Yeah, so alright.
Rym: Well that game went really well.
Rym: And now we got the Wii and the Wii has this controller that is perfect for that.
Rym: and look at the internet.
Rym: everyone's buzzing about Wario aware for the Wii and how absolutely awesome that would be and how they look forward to it with every breath because people were Really talking about oh man Wario aware for the Wii is gonna be the best thing ever.
Rym: and then they thought alright let's make Wario aware.
Rym: and They looked at it, and they said all right What made Mario Wario aware?
Rym: popular.
Scott: see there was no forum for Wario aware.
Scott: So they had to go basically on what they thought made Wario aware.
Scott: fun and try to you know Have more of that and less of the stuff that made Wario were not fun.
Scott: it to be honest Why are you aware for the GameCube as awesome as it was with its?
Scott: what like 12 multiplayer modes or something like that?
Scott: Yeah, only like.
Scott: three of those multiplayer modes were any good the turtles the disco and the Othello.
Rym: But those three were just.
Scott: ah they were amazing.
Scott: the jump rope was okay.
Scott: Yeah, the jump rope was just really fun Yeah, but other than that all the other multiplayer modes like the doctor and the balloon and I don't even know the other ones.
Scott: Cuz you know play.
Rym: this is actually pretty fun.
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: It wasn't as bad as the Wii one.
Scott: No wasn't.
Rym: but they thought that what made Wario aware popular and made it good was the minigames themselves and the Part of it that was.
Rym: see.
Rym: the thing is they thought that that was the important part when it wasn't.
Rym: the important part was the Minor add-on that they threw into the GameCube one probably just for the hell of it.
Rym: Like that was what made that game good and they didn't realize it.
Rym: So they didn't focus on that and as a result Wario aware for the Wii had crap multiplayer to the point that the game was Unplayable.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the multiplayer and Wari aware for the Wii.
Scott: I think we've said it before but you have the big but you have to pass around the remote And you're supposed to wear the wrist strap.
Scott: what the fuck were you thinking?
Scott: and second of all None of the modes are actually modes where skill determines who wins.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: it's most of the modes are you know?
Scott: I mean the one mode where skill matters if you win is single elimination They got.
Scott: people want to play a bunch of gay of games at the same time And they want to see who is the best at playing these games and whoever was the best should win and everyone should get to Play a lot of games.
Rym: They got the right things wrong and the wrong things, right?
Rym: Yep, and sadly the game tanked and there's a. there's a wealth of single-player content in the game.
Rym: gobs of it But no one gives a shit about that.
Rym: the one thing we all want it isn't in the game And as a result the game was hated and I still don't think they realize it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: think the developers in Nintendo thought why didn't Wario were sell in the
Rym: u.s.?
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: I don't think I think it did sell.
Scott: it's just that.
Scott: well it sold and then everyone who bought it Really everyone who bought it played it through and then stopped playing.
Rym: I was so disappointed that I pretty much stopped playing it after a week.
Scott: Yeah, I beat the whole game and like a couple days, and then I was done.
Scott: Yeah, and I haven't played it since.
Rym: That was one of the biggest disappointments in recent gaming history for me.
Scott: Yeah, pretty disappointing right there, but when it comes down to is that you have.
Scott: when you make a game You can't be listening to the stupid players who don't know what the hell's going on.
Scott: and stupid players Don't go whining about a game that you think you can make it better because you can't.
Scott: you're not a game designer You don't know shit.
Scott: You're just a game player.
Scott: What do you know?
Scott: You don't know anything?
Scott: Yeah, you're just gonna make your game crappy.
Scott: You got a thing.
Scott: if you really do want to make a suggestion as to how your game could be made better Don't just make your gut reaction like you'll play in a game And you know let's say you know in your feel something like oh this parts too hard, or I don't like this part.
Scott: well That's good thinking, but don't just go with the first thing that comes to mind like oh this part is too hard.
Scott: Because blah you know actually think what makes this game fun.
Scott: What do I like about this game that you mean?
Scott: if you're complaining about a game?
Scott: You must like it enough that you want to keep playing it and you know for some reason if you really hated it You just would stop playing.
Scott: So there's something about the game that's fun for you And if the game is not fun for you in some way right?
Scott: think about why it's not fun.
Scott: And if the answer is because you don't have enough skills, and you're losing all the time Maybe you just don't like games that require more skill than you have and you should play a different game.
Rym: It's not always that I think.
Rym: most of the time It's just.
Rym: it's much more benign.
Rym: people just they feel that something's wrong with the game.
Rym: there may well be something wrong But they don't understand really like what maybe like what's the important part of what's the core part of the game?
Rym: or what makes the game what it is or makes it good and They'll complain about an aspect not realizing that changing that aspect would completely change the game in ways that they would never even Expect.
Scott: and when you if you finally do come to a conclusion as to what you think will make the game better in some Way to fix what's wrong with it because you know game might have something wrong with it.
Scott: Actually think long and hard about what the whole game would be like if you change that.
Scott: one thing I mean like yeah Wouldn't it be cool if I could play Galaga?
Scott: Where my ship could shoot like a million bullets a second and I could just move back and forth killing all the bad guys.
Scott: Yeah, that would be pretty fun.
Scott: for like two seconds I would get the high score and then every level I just wouldn't be able to get hit and I would kill all the bad guys immediately because I shot so fast.
Rym: or maybe I Should have missiles and upgrades and all that.
Rym: Yeah, that's great.
Rym: But now Galaga is too complicated to play.
Rym: Yeah, there's a fine line.
Scott: You got it.
Scott: really think about these things.
Scott: game design is very complicated and is not for the faint of heart and a lot of people just go on forums on the internet and Spread their knee-jerk reactions around and good Game developers like at valve ignore what the fuck you say because they know they're better than you and they've proved that every time Again,
Rym: so what should valve do to make Team Fortress 2 better?
Scott: Cuz I got to admit I have a lot of opinions about the game and I like it but I think what it is is that they have designed the game in such a way where it is very fun and What they were going for.
Scott: I think they have gotten exactly.
Rym: I think one.
Rym: they're going for a console FPS and not a PC FPS.
Scott: Yep, they're going for a game where the skills of first-person shooting matter, but don't matter that much.
Scott: I mean fatality will not be any better at Team Fortress 2 than Rym.
Scott: Rym could compete with Fatality at Team Fortress 2, but if you were to say play quake one Rym would not get a single frag and he would be Oh god, I couldn't even get frags against my friend.
Scott: You probably couldn't even spawn Why.
Rym: I remember when like Dan would shoot me and knock me into the air and I would say alright And I tried to shoot at him.
Rym: I'd land on the grenade He had thrown I didn't realize it which knocked me into the air into the rocket He had shot at just the right time which knocked me into the wall.
Rym: then I landed on the other grenade.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I think there's not only is anything wrong with Team Fortress 2 as they have made it and as they want it.
Scott: The thing is is that I as Scott want a game that requires a great deal of skill in which there is a high skill Cap where fatality would own me and I would own any.
Rym: See thing is I want either a high skill cap in tactics or a high skill cap in FPS skills or a combination of the two.
Rym: I just feel like Team Fortress 2 skill cap is very low.
Rym: and the strategies I mean while it still works out in the beta in the pubs because almost everyone playing the game is a total noob and just Doesn't understand how to play.
Rym: There are pretty trivial optimal strategies for this game.
Rym: Yeah And it's not that hard to Make a team win all the time if you can get even three or four people to listen to what you say.
Scott: Yes on a public server You assume most of the players are idiots.
Scott: if you can get like three people to organize a little bit and actually do something Intelligent you can win.
Scott: I mean hell.
Scott: the people on the pubs are so dumb that I alone as a spy could capture the flag on a lot of servers all my own because I'm the only one who's actually trying and thinking about trying to win the game and the game we just played.
Rym: the enemy team was like super defense.
Rym: you had to capture the point and You know, they were like hammering hammering hammering and there were like three centuries guarding the capture point.
Rym: I just walked up as a spy Spot, you know disguised as an enemy soldier and I stayed there for like two three minutes getting healed by their medic all the time Every other than someone to shoot me once or twice, but I didn't react.
Rym: So they just ignored me and then the medic would come and just heal me again.
Rym: And I just kind of stand there, you know, hey, I'm defending I'm defending and I just messaged my team alright guys in 15 seconds every single century over here is going down and Then I just tapped all the century stabbed everyone and we won.
Rym: Yep, that shouldn't happen.
Scott: No, it shouldn't.
Scott: and I think the prop the thing is right now.
Scott: the the weakness of Team Fortress 2 is not so exposed because You're on these public server.
Scott: It will be when clans start playing people start actually playing this game seriously and you have an entire organized team against another entire organized team and you get pretty much near constant stalemates and No one can really beat anyone else.
Scott: because the only possible thing where if someone has a good strategy which is really easy to come up with it's pretty obvious and someone else is a good strategy and Their FPS skills don't come into play because everyone has the most FPS skill you can possibly have Who's gonna win out?
Scott: it might come down to chance.
Scott: It might come down to incredibly minute things that no one can control just sort of.
Scott: you know random bits here and there You know a quantum difference and it might come down to stalemates every time and it's it's really the the the problems will be exposed.
Rym: Yeah, and I could go on and on but I think the other that might.
Rym: my opinion about the game is that in the long Run the game is going to start being unfun for people because while they have done a good thing and made the class is Super specialized and made each one like so unique that is the different play experience.
Rym: all together Each class is limited to the point that I feel like everyone needs one more special weapon not a game breaker.
Rym: Not like giving grenades to someone or giving the rocket launcher to someone who doesn't need it.
Scott: Most of the classes I think I think they're the engineer doesn't need anything else.
Rym: yeah I don't even know if the medic needs anything else.
Rym: maybe plague Maybe because that was a big part of the old team fortress kind of games.
Rym: Yeah But I feel like the game if they made a little spy doesn't need anything else.
Rym: now the spy the spy is the best freakin Spy in any team fortress game.
Rym: ever though if the spy had feigned death I think that would not hurt the game.
Scott: But the the they need.
Scott: I think the heavy needs.
Scott: one more thing the pyro definitely needs something more than anyone.
Scott: the Demoman could use something the The soldier could use something the scout could use a little something.
Scott: all right because basically what happens is they're so specialized That you know you pick a class and I want to keep the classes super differentiated.
Scott: So the scout is still the fastest guy out there And he's still super different from everyone else and is still super weak against you know actually getting hit.
Rym: I mean that's the important part of the game.
Rym: the rock-paper-scissors classes can't disrupt that?
Scott: no But when you're the scout there's only.
Scott: really you only have a few one or two things you can do.
Scott: period that's it.
Scott: You can't do anything else.
Scott: And it would be cool if you could if you had one more thing that you had available to you.
Scott: You could you one more option that you were still different But you could come up with something clever to do.
Scott: you know there'd be more options in the game instead of oh he's a scout.
Scott: I know exactly what he's gonna.
Scott: If he doesn't do that I can ignore him because he'll be ineffective.
Scott: You know this way people.
Scott: if there was one more thing if the pyro had one more fiery weapon Then he could do something interesting and people wouldn't know.
Scott: it's.
Scott: you know.
Scott: the pyro might pull a clever trick.
Rym: Who knows and that my friends is how to critique a video game to the developers as opposed to?
Scott: Omg shotgun whores ban shotties fuckers Yep, ah Anything else to say about this stuff.
Rym: I think that's it.
Rym: Let's make some dinner.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.