Rym: It's Thursday, November 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about books.
Rym: You should read.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I was in a car accident today.
Scott: Were you really?
Scott: but wait you weren't.
Rym: well, yes Yes, I saved this cuz I want to get you drive somewhere today.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Where did you drive?
Rym: I drove the cold spring for what to go climbing.
Rym: Okay, and then since I was there I drove further south cuz from breakneck Ridge.
Rym: We'd always see this pile of what looked like a burned-down building like on this point and I always wondered what it was.
Rym: So finally I drove over there and found it and it was just a little tiny hill that The rocks just look like a burned-down building from a distance.
Scott: Well, but wait, but wait you your car is in the driveway and it looks undamaged.
Rym: Oh, yes it but so I'm in the parking lot outside of the nice like market down in cold spring and I'm sitting there parked like I pull out of a parking spot and I shift, you know from reverse into drive.
Rym: I'm about to go and then bump this SUV is backed into me pretty hard Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I just stop and I just sit there like.
Rym: ah, I got the phone out.
Rym: I'm about to call the police.
Rym: I'm all set to you know, take a picture.
Rym: call my insurance.
Rym: get ready to sue this person for damages.
Scott: I don't pay my deduct anybody to deal with indignity Possibilities like.
Rym: I'm fully prepared cuz I'm ready to deal with people like that.
Rym: I was already about to dial the police because I wasn't gonna let this person get away.
Rym: They were gonna pay for all the damages.
Rym: So I get out and I'm holding my cell phone and I look and the cars in there and the woman gets out.
Rym: She's nice and young and she has like a kid in the car and she could.
Rym: first of all she comes out Crazily apologetic like oh my god.
Rym: I'm so sorry.
Rym: I can't believe I did that.
Rym: That was totally my fault Mm-hmm, so that diffused me a little bit.
Rym: I turned off my whoops.
Scott: Amass my let's see I would be rolling my eyes at this point.
Rym: Well, I was like.
Rym: so then she.
Rym: now then I look at where she has struck me and There's a big dent and she says oh my god.
Rym: And meanwhile, I'm looking and I started laughing hysterically.
Scott: that dent was there before.
Rym: well I had a dent cuz I worked in the Bronx and there's a dent where someone just reared like bumped into my car while it Was parked and I wasn't gonna pay my deductible to get that fixed.
Scott: Yeah, yeah deductible and there was no insurance companies raking it on.
Rym: Well, there was no.
Rym: I could have zero deductible But there was no one to sue cuz I had no like.
Rym: I didn't know who did it.
Rym: like some for all.
Rym: I know.
Rym: Is some illegal guy just bumped into it with like his unregistered car?
Rym: Who knows for all.
Scott: I know like some guy came down the street with a hammer went wham There's a recon with an aluminum bat who knows?
Rym: or a scout as it were.
Rym: yep, so Her car like the bag bumper is sitting Inside of that pre-existing dent like perfectly.
Rym: it could not have been more.
Scott: Are you sure it's resisting?
Scott: Yes, all right Scott.
Rym: You've seen that dent.
Rym: It's been there for like a year.
Scott: I don't really inspect your car so much.
Rym: It's right there.
Rym: There's a big dent in the driver's side.
Scott: Oh, I've seen that dent.
Rym: That's the dent.
Scott: You said you were backing out and you got bumped.
Scott: so I thought it was the bag.
Rym: I was all the way backed out and then she backed into my side.
Rym: Okay, so It's it's like sitting in the dent and I look and the dent is not deeper or anything.
Rym: It's the exact same thing.
Rym: now for a second.
Rym: I think you know All I'd have to do is call the police anyway, and this woman would pay for all the repairs.
Scott: Yeah free debt, but you don't care about your car.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time I wouldn't mind my car to look nicer And I'd be effort though.
Scott: If not money.
Rym: No, you know how little effort it would be.
Rym: It was clearly her fault and in front of a witness.
Rym: She had said it was her fault.
Rym: So I was like there would be no trial would have been summary judgment and I would have gotten my deductible like without any effort at all.
Rym: but Because one she was apologetic and realized that she had made the mistake to Just the absurdity of the fact that she'd hit me in the dent.
Scott: Well, I think as soon as you start laughing Even if it was me, right?
Scott: I would have probably gone there out of trying to get the ductible if it was a car I cared about and I cared about Doing the effort which I probably I wouldn't with your car.
Rym: if it was a car I cared about I would have fixed the dent Right in the first place though.
Rym: She would have made a new day.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But the the fact that I would have seen her making a dent where there's already a dent My laughing uncontrollably would have prevented me from being able to do anything.
Rym: I was laughing show so hard.
Rym: She's like.
Rym: what's wrong?
Rym: And I'm like, all right And I tell her like the whole deal and she's like really like.
Rym: she didn't believe me.
Rym: Like I'm trying to scam her Seriously, I'm not gonna call the police.
Rym: just There's no damage to your car.
Rym: that I can tell and I really don't care.
Rym: and I shook her hand and I drove away laughing Alright, so this woman who ran into my car with her giant SUV was saved from the wrath of Rym when he's in the right And has a police ready to back him up by the sheer absurdity of the random chance.
Scott: Well, I guess that story didn't go anywhere.
Scott: We thought it was gonna go So I'll just add who was in the car besides her I don't know.
Scott: some kid didn't need that SUV.
Scott: get a real car.
Scott: Yeah small car.
Scott: That's all I'll say.
Rym: now I have a better bit, but I know different leader bit, but it was about a dream I had but I guess I could leave it at that but let that go.
Rym: I just want to say it involved saved by the bell.
Rym: What the fuck.
Scott: seriously the college years now.
Rym: now though I woke up.
Rym: I woke up and I laid in bed and I was thinking to myself wow And then I remembered the college years cuz I'd forgotten about that and I laid in bed Watch one episode of that.
Rym: I laid in bed for like 20 minutes And I was thinking so which was worse the college years or the new class?
Rym: Yeah, okay and screech was still there and yeah, what did he get held back?
Rym: No, he was like working at the school.
Rym: I think he was the principal.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: Oh, you know what he's doing now, but But yeah, I was Zach Morris and I'll and guitar heroes played heavily in.
Rym: Okay, I'll leave it at that sure.
Rym: so what do you have that can top that nothing?
Scott: really it's not.
Scott: I'm not topping something I just need to say something.
Rym: What do you need to say?
Scott: So I have not been a fan of the Facebook's or the Twitter's or the pounces or any of those sorts of things.
Rym: I'd be a fat You know what?
Rym: I would use Facebook if I didn't have my own personal forum that all my friends use.
Scott: Also, if I was still in college, I look at I've been.
Rym: oh god if I was still in college.
Scott: We were in college.
Scott: Facebook was around but it wasn't the business it is now.
Rym: now Facebook is amazing like seriously when we were in college like Facebook was barely an embryo and Orcutt was the hot shit among like the techie crowd and that got destroyed by the nation of Brazil.
Rym: But before that we all of us were using or cut like super hardcore and then it got ruined and we gave up.
Rym: but we saw that social networking was Awesome, if you're in college and now not so awesome for us personally, right?
Scott: Facebook is the business.
Scott: but You know, I have a Facebook account and I had a pounce account right, but I didn't really use these thingies.
Scott: I only use like dig and delicious and that's about it, you know, but for some reason for some reason I don't know why I had a policy where I wouldn't make anyone my friend on Facebook or pounds Unless I knew who they were.
Scott: and a lot of people would say be my friend and I say no be my friend No, and I wouldn't even I wasn't.
Scott: even I realized I'm not even freaking using these things.
Scott: What do I care if someone's my friend on these things or not?
Scott: I don't know what I was thinking.
Scott: I wasn't really thinking at all about it so much, you know, so I realized also maybe there's a chance, you know I mean these things don't really like.
Scott: I don't have a use for them, right?
Scott: like I'm poking at Facebook and there's like stuff to poke and it passes the time at work when I'm bored even though it Doesn't do anything for me.
Rym: I had to step up from draw square on the desktop with a cursor, draw another square Draw a square around like waste ink doodling on a piece of paper draw a square around like miss Otto's face on the desktop three or four times.
Scott: Yeah, so I Decided now I'm gonna change my policy and if anyone wants to friend me on anything I'll just say yes.
Scott: And I think if I do that it might make these things more useful.
Scott: and also there's one called Jaiku which is sort of just like Twitter only not Twitter.
Scott: and Basically, I wasn't interested in it and how Google bought it.
Scott: So I'm sort of interested to at least poke it for a few minutes.
Scott: But when Google bought it, they made it invite only.
Scott: so I want a Jaiku invite if anyone has one.
Rym: Ah Man, remember when we didn't have Gmail.
Scott: Yeah, and if you've ever tried to friend me on Facebook or pounce or anything and I said no try again.
Rym: I will now say yes, not just no but no no no, no, no, no, right.
Rym: So in the news, I have to say something about this and I want to do a fun episode.
Rym: so I'm not gonna complain about people.
Rym: but there's an article here on slash dot and the headline is anti-terrorism and the death of the chemistry set.
Rym: I'm not gonna say I'm not gonna say it all what you think.
Rym: I'm gonna say because a lot of people are trying to make the argument that Chemistry sets are killed by all this anti-terrorism stuff.
Rym: partially that is not true at all.
Scott: There's actually.
Rym: there is almost nothing.
Rym: you need for a fun chemistry set that you cannot just get if you want it And there's no reason you couldn't include those in the chemistry set.
Rym: The reason chemistry sets are not around so much anymore Is that they are actually really dangerous if they're old-school and you can make very carcinogenic things very easily.
Scott: Yeah, there.
Rym: Oh what I'm saying is that you can still make a chemistry set.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: See saws are dangerous.
Scott: You should have those for kids too.
Rym: I would argue that chemistry sets are far more dangerous.
Rym: Old-school kind of chemistry sets because you can make well depends how old-school we go in the radioactive old-school chemistry set.
Scott: Oh not radioactive.
Scott: They made those.
Rym: the only reason they're not cool the only reason they don't make chemistry sets like they used to is that companies aren't stupid and an old-school chemistry set.
Rym: if parents don't keep an eye on kids or Kids don't read the instructions kids can make super dangerous and possibly deadly things that it.
Scott: that is Yeah, and really had to keep an eye on your kids no matter what they're doing.
Scott: No, but dangerous it is.
Rym: but what I'm saying is that the Liability there is massive and I don't think any company should market a chemistry set because they're just opening themselves up.
Scott: Then again, I think that you know They shouldn't really be liable if they put warnings on something and someone does it anyway.
Rym: But even then there's not a big market for that either because parents would be afraid of a chemistry.
Rym: I mean as a kid I had a chemistry set a kind of dangerous one.
Scott: I had an a dangerous one.
Scott: mine was for the thing is I took when I was at the local hobby shop They could.
Scott: they sold any chemical for a chemistry set that you wanted on its own.
Rym: when I was in high school I took organic chemistry the local community college and I learned a lot and I went back to my old chemistry set.
Rym: I was sifting through it and I realized just how carcinogenic half of the crap I had was.
Rym: I threw the stupid thing away Awesome.
Rym: I guess the problem is that chemistry sets no matter what warnings you were to write on them The fact is that chemistry as a whole unless you're doing simple things But like the amount of danger that can be created is far greater in many cases than the apparent danger Kind of like how I don't think we need.
Scott: You know, you're messing with a chemistry set that there's a lot of danger going on.
Rym: No I think the problem is that society in the US is such that People assume that things are safe if they can be bought in a store.
Rym: Kind of like how you go to like an amusement park, right?
Rym: And you have the little.
Rym: you can drive the putt-putt car around the track and you can steer left and right But there's a rail.
Rym: so if you try to steer off the road It just kind of pulls the car back on the road.
Rym: as a result most kids I see on these things will Turn the opposite direction of the road every time because they know they can't go off the road and they just kind of go.
Scott: Yeah, there is it.
Scott: there is a case to be made that sort of.
Scott: we've trapped ourselves in in this loop.
Scott: You know, we make things are dangerous.
Scott: So it made them safer and So people started to feel safe because things were safer.
Scott: and then we sort of can't escape into a situation Now where people where things are dangerous, but people realize they're dangerous because people have been trained for things to be safe.
Scott: So we have to make everything safe or else the people hurt themselves because they've been made.
Scott: you know growing up to assume everything is safe because we made it safe so that it wasn't crazy dangerous like in the olden days.
Scott: and you know, yeah, I think we had to strike some sort of balance between Some things we need to let them be dangerous in terms of for freedom and education and learning and growth of your mind and some Things we need to make safe.
Scott: So but not everyone just dies horribly But regardless that are stupid and preventable.
Rym: My point is very simply anyone who tries to blame terrorism or anti-terrorism laws on the death of the chemistry set.
Rym: that is pretty much completely incorrect.
Rym: and it is you're politicizing something that is not political and That's such a stupid our.
Scott: it is a tiny bit true.
Scott: there are a few specific.
Rym: However, I want name something.
Scott: I don't know but Where were you read an article months ago that I could find if I wasn't middle of a podcast?
Scott: Yeah, so some guy on the internet a real like a scientist anyway Yeah Our get.
Scott: the thing I want to bring up about chemistry sets right is actually I think a large demise of the chemistry set is Greater attributed to the marketing of science to kids.
Scott: if you look at it.
Scott: go look at pictures of chemistry sets online.
Scott: Right, look at a really old chemistry set from like the 60s or the 50s.
Scott: Look at the picture on there.
Scott: in the picture is scientists doing serious business and you know with like cool metal You know lab coats and and smartness going on metal lab coats.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah metal lab coats.
Scott: It's awesome right and you you know, it's got all sorts of you know, like a 1950s sort of Like.
Rym: maybe that's because those chemistry sets were marketed in the 1950s.
Scott: exactly if you look at a chemistry set.
Scott: now though Right, the scientists are like wacky with like crazy Einstein hair like goofy glasses and all these multi colors.
Scott: and You market science now like it's some goofy kind of thing and not like a serious thing.
Scott: and I think that the change in the way we've marketed science to kids is Really what has caused the demise of the chemistry sentence, you know Kind of thing and it's not you know, no, it's not a serious thing.
Rym: I don't know if I agree with that.
Rym: I mean, I do agree that science is kind of seen differently nowadays.
Rym: But then again had the old way didn't get people into science any better than the new way It's really a long time ago.
Rym: I don't know all the scientists that are scientists right now Part of that just because it takes a long time to be a respected scientist.
Scott: I know I know.
Rym: so Plus, I mean how many of our friends are crazy?
Scott: There are decreasing numbers of you know people going into science majors at universities at least in the u.s.
Scott: Other countries are doing fine.
Rym: Honestly, I think one of the big reasons for that is that High school no longer prepares you for college.
Rym: I do as a result I mean when I got to RIT and I had to take like some like the crap is calculus.
Rym: It was like can you do basic integrals and derivatives?
Rym: I can you do basic discrete math like such rudimentary calculus and People coming out of high school?
Rym: We're failing this class Miserably and having to retake it at my high school by default.
Scott: if you are the average kid taking the average class There's no honors.
Scott: No, nothing special.
Scott: You don't learn any calculus at all.
Rym: So yeah Yeah, but the thing is it's not just that because people came into RIT was just they lacked base the basic ability to do Algebra algebra basic algebra.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So the calculus thing is like oh you can't do calculus.
Scott: So it's a multi-faceted process.
Rym: The professor was all like, all right.
Rym: Well, I'll break it down really simply.
Rym: So he goes into like some you know Basic algebra things like.
Rym: here's where calculus is derived from and he found that people couldn't do the basic algebra.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, well Yeah, why do you?
Scott: why are you here?
Scott: How did you get in?
Scott: Because all right, that is that is a multi-faceted problem going to high schools and college admissions and all sorts of things.
Scott: But yeah, I do think that the change in the way science is marketed is is said All right.
Rym: Anyway, let's do a show a Thursday on that at some point or a Monday I don't know.
Rym: I think I said everything I had to say now more about going into college and why people are so unprepared.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Scott: So I don't know which of mine.
Scott: both of my news things of the days are sort of both news and thing of the day.
Scott: So I'm just gonna pick this one to be the news.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: So, you know what Disney World.
Scott: they have that ride.
Scott: It's a small.
Rym: I wrote it once and I got stuck in it.
Scott: I wrote it I didn't get stuck in it and You know I had heard the song and I thought it was like this historic really important ride and it really wasn't so exciting.
Scott: I mean, it was cool, but it's historic.
Scott: I mean, you don't need to ride it more than once is all I'll say.
Rym: but anyway Much cooler is the troll ride in Epcot.
Scott: Yeah when they made this ride in 1963 they made that ride under the assumption that the average male rider would be 175 pounds and the average woman rider would be at about a hundred and thirty five pounds.
Rym: I see what.
Rym: I see what you did there.
Rym: I see where you're going with this.
Rym: I Don't know if we need to continue and that's why.
Scott: and that's why Rym It's funny that you say you got stuck because these days it gets stuck quite often.
Rym: I just have to say I also got stuck in the haunted house and I remember when I was in line.
Rym: I didn't even think of this until just now but There was a woman and her kid and the woman could not fit in the haunted house booth with her kid And she was complaining about how the ride was bleh as a result and she demanded to be let on.
Rym: and they're like We can't you don't fit Bottom but so that we get stuck in the ride, right?
Rym: You know, there's things that pop out and say boo Yeah, or scream or something.
Scott: the point of a haunted house.
Rym: So me and my grandma are stuck there for like 20 minutes, but the ride doesn't stop like everything's still going on Except we're not moving.
Rym: we stopped Exactly in front of like this box and every five seconds a witch popped out and went.
Rym: it was.
Rym: That was awesome.
Rym: Like if I could list some of the top ten things that happened to me that good fucking god.
Scott: So anyway So they made this ride The.
Scott: it's a small world after all right a long time ago in the 60s when people were less fat Averagedly in the u.s.
Scott: At least.
Scott: and well, they're closing it down to redo it.
Scott: They're going to make the flume bigger and wider and deeper with more water and bigger boats.
Scott: that fatter people can ride it without making the ride stop and making everyone wait on line.
Scott: and You know that the alternative is.
Scott: what they've been doing is like a fat person wants to ride.
Scott: They just put less people on the boat instead of filling it to capacity, you know But then it's longer lines because now they can do less people per boat.
Scott: You
Rym: know now that I recall cedar point had to do that on the two flumes like that a guy Who is always there and his job was to look at the people and dole them out into boats And you'd always see like a boat with a family of four boat with a family of four Four boats with four fat people that are obviously a family of four and another boat with a family of four.
Rym: Yep, of course what we always did is there's a there's a waterfall and there's a restaurant next to the waterfall.
Rym: So we'd sit there and wave at the people when they're coming around so they wouldn't see the waterfall coming.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I just want to.
Scott: I just want to throw that in as our monthly complaint about fat people and also Not like fat people not overweight people.
Rym: I think that the issue here is obese people.
Scott: Yes, there's you got to be obese to stop a ride.
Scott: There's a big buoyancy of the boat and your weight is conquering that.
Scott: come on.
Rym: There's a big difference.
Rym: That's a problem.
Rym: We just got it.
Rym: when we say fat people what we really mean are people who are like Obese to the point of where I would use the word morbid and people who did it to themselves.
Rym: Yeah, which is most of it if you got an extra 20 or 30 pounds, that's not What we're complaining about.
Scott: if you're not stopping the boat, I don't care.
Rym: I don't want to give the wrong impression.
Scott: No, I do want to use it though as some evidence that like look these people are you know doing.
Scott: they're hurting themselves And they are hurting others and they here is an example of.
Scott: I mean, it's not a big deal.
Scott: Oh, no, the line for the amusement park ride takes longer.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay is in Disney World.
Scott: good God it is but it's not a big deal in terms of our society.
Scott: But it is example of look these people are hurting themselves.
Scott: No, I think it's.
Scott: it's not good.
Rym: the people who say that oh people aren't getting fatter We're just measuring differently or all that stuff.
Rym: But I mean when you get to the point where the flume ride the flume just stops halfway down.
Scott: Yes bottom down and in the 60s it never bottomed out.
Rym: Yeah, I mean what the physical properties of water did not change in the last.
Scott: Yes, what the boat is less buoyant than it was there 40 years ago.
Rym: things of the day.
Scott: You know those biodiesel type people.
Scott: they think they're all green and cool, but they forget to fig.
Scott: You know calculate the fact of how much gas it takes to make the corn in the first place.
Rym: Well, it depends on.
Rym: I mean if you make biodiesel from cane sugar, it looks like it works great.
Scott: Yeah, it's all kinds of business with that.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: We might not even need all that business because there's a guy named Jonathan Goodwin this the kudzu guy.
Rym: What there was a guy who figured out a way to make biodiesel out of kudzu Which is kind of grows without doing anything to it.
Scott: Oh, I guess that good.
Scott: That's good, too But no work fully yet.
Scott: This guy is even better.
Scott: I mean this is the only guy we need.
Scott: as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: He's basically a genius when it comes to mechanics.
Rym: Like he is easy normal Norman Borlaug.
Scott: He might be he might be he.
Scott: he didn't really go.
Scott: I think he dropped out of school like in seventh grade it says and all he did was like buy old cars and repair them.
Scott: And you know, it's very much mechanic his whole life.
Rym: Wow, cuz you can't drop out of school in seventh grade now.
Scott: No, so he's 37 years old, right.
Scott: and it says he when he dropped out or now now It says he looks like Kevin Costner with better hair.
Scott: But basically he is a professional car hacker.
Scott: people like famous people send him their cars and he hacks them up.
Rym: I should send him my car.
Rym: No.
Scott: No, let me give you an example Right Neil Young just sent him a Lincoln Continental.
Scott: You know what he's gonna do that Lincoln Continental.
Rym: uh Put some nice spinners on it and an airfoil.
Scott: No, he's not gonna do that.
Scott: He's going to take that Lincoln Continental and he is going to modify it with his special Technologies.
Scott: and when he is done with that Lincoln Continental it will get how many miles per gallon a billion a hundred.
Rym: It's not too bad.
Scott: It will cut emissions by 80% and Double the horsepower.
Rym: Um, now I have to say one thing Is it possible that all he did was put a hidden tank full of rocket fuel and a special engine that slowly uses that rocket fuel?
Rym: and
Scott: unlikely because I imagine when he gives these cars back to these people after they pay him a lot of money and they try to Fill it up with you know grease from the local McDonald's They're going to expect it to have twice the horsepower and 100 miles to the gallon.
Rym: Oh, it does.
Rym: cuz the grease just like gets trapped somewhere to replace the rocket fuel That's slowly being used and when the rocket fuel runs out He says well, I guess your engine wore out here.
Rym: Let me fix it for you.
Scott: It's possible, but it's unlikely.
Scott: In addition, he's took.
Scott: he took an h3 All right, then one of the worst cars ever second only to the h2.
Scott: I guess he's doubled the horsepower from 300 to 600.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Because now it gets 60 miles to the gallon.
Rym: see that's the one thing that has always been known but people don't seem to do.
Rym: Is that you can use a turbo to get more horsepower and make a car better.
Scott: Oh, he's using a turbine.
Scott: He's got the electric motor and the turbine in tandem.
Scott: He's got it all going on.
Rym: It's what I was saying is you could use a turbo theoretically.
Scott: This isn't a turbo.
Scott: This is I know.
Rym: Yeah, I know while I was saying is theoretically you can use a turbo instead of increasing the power of a car Just making it more efficient.
Rym: Yeah, but no one ever does that.
Scott: Well, you could just supercharged it the same way.
Rym: Well, yeah, cuz it that's kind of beside the point.
Rym: Yes Anyway Cuz a super and a turbo are not that different.
Scott: Yeah, the point is is that for a long time?
Scott: You know, I don't want to be all conspiracy not here, right?
Scott: But you know people that like GM and Ford in places have all been saying Oh, you know, it's not possible to do these things, you know We can't make them any more fuel-efficient whatever.
Scott: if I was the government I would go and I would check this guy out.
Scott: if I was the congressman or a senator I would go and check this guy out.
Scott: Make sure it was legit.
Scott: bring some scientists with me, right?
Scott: if it was legit I would immediately make a law saying well all cars have to be 60 miles to the gallon.
Scott: now that hummer is 60 miles a Gallon all cars can be that way and you start seeing turbos and all your cars big ones.
Rym: I mean there there might be a lot of factors.
Scott: now I don't want to.
Scott: there are a lot of factors, but even well play the devil's advocate have it.
Scott: You have a phase in time.
Rym: Oh, no No, what I'm saying is that it's possible because there are a lot of technologies that you know.
Rym: They give you gains up front, but in the long run, maybe the engines are a lot less durable.
Scott: There's all sorts of things to consider like that.
Scott: But in general for a long time people like G you know car companies have been saying this sort of stuff is impossible where Just by changing the mechanics of a car and getting away from an old Standard piston engine with the standard mechanics you can get a lot of efficiency without changing
Rym: a lot else.
Rym: Well, you know what the car companies are actually 100% correct in the regard that it's impossible for them because possible for them.
Rym: well when the majority of your expenses go to your old pensions and your workers because you The unions are good and bad.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I don't have an opinion on unions.
Scott: I do a union show.
Rym: I'll just say very simply I think unions are a tool that can be used for good or for bad.
Rym: Yeah, and I have no opinion on unions in general.
Rym: I have opinions on specific unions Car industry Union.
Rym: Yeah problems in the u.s.
Scott: It was it had a purpose it at a time of the Henry Ford times and now if you don't need it anymore Well, no, I think you could still have a purpose.
Scott: I think it's more a matter of the unions kind of got scary and corrupt and something like any anything No matter what it is the scary and corrupt is a problem no matter what it.
Rym: so yeah, but still if this works I mean, yeah Maybe we should start using this.
Scott: I would very much like a car that gets better gas mileage and more horsepower.
Scott: I would not have a problem with that.
Scott: How about you?
Rym: So, uh What's cooler than an Armenian?
Scott: Armenian you mean our man.
Rym: it is a person from Armenia or Armenia.
Rym: the BBC pronounced it Armenia.
Rym: Okay, I might be a British.
Scott: what's cooler than a person from Armenia?
Scott: how many people from Armenia, how about a rep?
Rym: from our from an Armenian?
Rym: Okay, just check this video out.
Rym: There's a whole bunch of them with varying levels of humor and I got a kick out of it.
Rym: It's uh, it's about red meat.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I watched one of these and I was not impressed.
Rym: Well, you're adorable jade.
Rym: if you didn't even like that awesome Bioshock cosplay with a little girl the costume wasn't the greatest bow shot custom I've seen.
Scott: where?
Rym: where have you seen a better one?
Scott: on the Internet's?
Scott: where on websites?
Rym: I'm sure yeah.
Rym: Are you sure it was a website?
Rym: Are you sure it wasn't nothing?
Scott: I'm sure and even so the video was sort of like, alright, nothing exciting happening here.
Scott: move on.
Rym: Okay Well, you're just a jaded horrible person.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure I find this funny.
Scott: I think you're easily amused and simple-minded.
Rym: take that You know what easily amused means there's a lot more enjoyment to be had in the world a lot less brains Or a lot less Horrible tedious boredom.
Scott: I got my non horrible tedious.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Rym: You didn't do anything at work today, but putts around and be bored.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: I thought that for about a week and there's a reason I quit my job.
Scott: Yeah, that's the reason I quit the last job too.
Scott: But no I do do work.
Scott: I just finished my work yesterday.
Scott: cuz I'm so awesome.
Scott: They didn't give me new work.
Scott: Okay, so today on the show, what are we doing?
Rym: well actually we had we had see.
Rym: the thing is lately we've been doing a lot of shows where we talk about something that's bothersome to us or something where we have a strong opinion or a controversial subject and we ought to do our research or something and always it's not as fun to do.
Rym: and we realized that The question show was a lot more fun because it was just kind of we just it's really fun to do it.
Rym: so we tried to think you know, what could we do?
Rym: that could be fun.
Rym: and we looked in the calendar and the show for today was ADD and ADHD and medicating children.
Scott: and we realized we have a lot of opinion and not a lot of facts because there isn't a Lot of facts on that issue.
Rym: Well, it was also one of those we would have.
Rym: It's a controversial issue and we would have been fun to do and screw it.
Rym: And then Emily said why don't you do a show on books you liked and that actually works really?
Rym: Well, and it's really easy to do and really fun to do because I want you.
Scott: we could do a geek dance book club If you want perhaps we could maybe once a month.
Scott: I think I'm stealing that from someone else though.
Rym: Oh, no Yeah, anyway, so at least for now, I think cuz we talked we've done this a few times.
Rym: we've mentioned books we like but I think we're just gonna kind of Take turns talking about books that have affected us or that we really remember as being awesome and I'd say it That's that's as much as we thought about this topic.
Scott: Alright, yeah, I guess what it is.
Scott: We've been doing this for two years, right?
Scott: And you know, we've always said yeah book reviews fit into the show.
Scott: You know, if it's a sci-fi book we could do it Monday, I guess kind of yeah, there aren't so many sci-fi books We've both read.
Scott: we read like lost kingdoms or something.
Scott: We could do that in Wednesday.
Rym: I mean, I guess we've both read stranger in a strange land.
Rym: But yeah, I got to admit talking about that book would be boring to dry.
Scott: cuz pretty dry.
Rym: my opinions on the book are pretty straightforward and Yeah Enjoyable read.
Rym: I didn't read the lensman books yet.
Rym: Scott hasn't read the prince of nothing even though lensman.
Scott: lensman is the same race.
Scott: Horatio hornblower in space and double the badass.
Rym: You haven't even read Horatio, I don't need to.
Scott: ah, yes you do to take the TV show double the badassness put in space.
Rym: It's kind of like if you've seen the James Bond movies, then you read the books there.
Rym: It's the exact same relationship.
Scott: Okay, sure Whatever.
Rym: Ah, oh Well, I guess you want to go first here.
Rym: book boy.
Scott: Do I do I want to go first?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right The book I read most recently that was incredibly awesome, which I guess if you haven't read it Well, I guess you haven't read it.
Scott: Rym have you the the amazing adventures of cavalier and clay by Michael Chavon.
Rym: Um, this book has been recommended to me by everyone and I just haven't read it yet.
Scott: It won a Pulitzer Prize, right and I don't want to give any merit to.
Scott: you know awards and things.
Rym: I was about to say.
Rym: I thought you didn't care about awards, but there's a reason.
Rym: it's a major award.
Scott: There's a reason.
Scott: There's a reason it won a Pulitzer Prize.
Scott: Basically this book has Everything.
Scott: if Scott had a wheeled house if I had a wheelhouse, which I do have a wheelhouse This book would be spinning in that wheelhouse at a million rpms.
Rym: a wheelhouse wheelhouse.
Scott: You never heard of y'all.
Scott: you're getting in my wheelhouse.
Scott: No, I've heard that turn of phrase.
Rym: I've never heard that turn of phrase.
Scott: like you are in my wheelhouse You know, it's like when Sutton's.
Rym: yeah, you know, I've never heard that.
Rym: All right, I've heard up in your grill up in your Parliament similar similar.
Rym: I've never heard up in your wheelhouse ever.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well now you have so Basically this book.
Scott: I don't want to get into everything this book is about but if you care about comic books I mean, this is a novel by the way But if you care about comics at all, you got to read this book.
Scott: if you care about Jews Gotta read this book also.
Scott: if you care about adventure and Adventure like spy adventure during the war or New York City.
Scott: You got to read this book.
Scott: This book is all those things in one.
Scott: It's basically there's a Jew kid in Brooklyn, right and He's living a pretty a life and he's into the comics, but he's not so great, right and His cousin escapes the Holocaust.
Scott: right and comes and basically the book starts where he comes home to his Jewish mom And it's annoying and then his cousin shows up and he has to sleep in bed With his cousin that he doesn't even know.
Scott: he doesn't really.
Scott: he doesn't realize anything.
Scott: He's just some punk Jewish kid from Brooklyn but his cousin like escaped the Holocaust and with craziness.
Scott: and they tell you all that later.
Scott: and then They have amazing adventures making comic books, of course, you know and stuff and it's sort of a a fictional dramatized retelling of some true events that you know really happened when you know Jews created comic books in New York back in the day and you know dramatic retellings of you know, people escaping the Holocaust also and It's it's an amazing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: What else can I say besides just telling you the whole plot?
Rym: I've heard this from a lot of people.
Rym: It's been recommended to me highly and I plan to read it and you all probably should too.
Scott: It's cheap It doesn't take that long to read.
Scott: It took me like a week or so and see I got a problem here about magic.
Scott: if you care about Houdini if you care About you know old mythology like the golem and stuff.
Rym: I like me a lot of golems.
Rym: I there was a good escape pod about some golems not too long.
Scott: Like I'm talking about the golem, you know the Prague golem.
Rym: Oh, I'm talking about just golems.
Scott: No, not done.
Scott: Not those golems.
Scott: No, the golem as a capital T golem the capital the.
Scott: yeah This book has all of that and it's somehow it all works together in one thing and how it works together is is just crazy.
Scott: But it's uh, it's got everything.
Scott: Best novel of last ten years probably.
Rym: All right So this is a book that my professed liking of gets me a lot of crap Especially from a few of our friends who will remain name.
Scott: How about me?
Scott: Does it get crap from me?
Rym: Not so much, but it gets crap from a few people and They go on and on about how he's a terrible author and blah blah blah and his books are all.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into it.
Rym: But I Really like the Sun Also Rises by Ernest Hemingway.
Rym: like I it's one of my favorite books I own.
Rym: I don't own a first edition like I do with the ratio books But I own like the 1956 printing and had to read that for college I think in some class and it was okay.
Rym: I had to read it in like 11th or 12th grade and I Well, the thing is I'd read like someone with the people getting super drunk in Spain in the bullfighting.
Rym: That doesn't really narrow it down with Hemingway, you know, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's that one It's that's the one right where I was so amazed reading the early parts of it when I realized that people were drinking wine by The bottle.
Rym: Yeah, and especially because well, I mean if you tally up the amount of alcohol they drink it That would be like an ob7 test and burning wheel to not die something like that.
Scott: I was just amazed.
Scott: I was like, is this is this supposed to be believable?
Rym: See the thing is I I really dig this book.
Rym: I mean I in general I really like Ernest Hemingway is writing and I think a lot of people who just dismiss him as simplistic or I think a lot of people dismiss his works out of hand or because they're told to dismiss it by Teachers they get who are
Scott: yeah
Rym: I mean, I can't.
Rym: really.
Rym: I'm not certain kinds of literature teachers who will always say yeah Ernest Hemingway is crap.
Scott: I'm not a dismister of Hemingway.
Scott: The old man in the sea is the business, but I don't know.
Rym: I like farewell to arms a lot.
Scott: I didn't read that one.
Rym: See you would probably like that.
Rym: There's a lot of World War one action.
Scott: Anyway, Sun Also Rises kind of for me.
Scott: I mean, it's not like.
Scott: oh, it's a terrible book But it then again, I'm not like, you know jumping for joy over it like you see I guess what it was.
Rym: I'd read a lot of Hemingway's other works and then I read this.
Rym: so I kind of had the Hemingway context in place and as a result plus also one of my Witty moments in high school, even though I'm sure other people have made this joke but I said something to the effect of the Sun Also Rises.
Rym: I AKA at least the Sun rises and no one got it except like two kids in class and the literature teacher And I got bad props for that.
Rym: I was very proud and to this day.
Rym: I wear that as a tiny badge of witticism Partly because the I remember I had one kid who went on and on about the Symbolism of the scene at the end with the baton and I thought he was stretching it a little bit.
Rym: But then I read the whole book again, and I was like, wow I think Hemingway actually did mean that phallic symbolism and I don't think I can deny it.
Scott: No, it's really it's really hard to deny I mean if you if you ever.
Scott: I guess I've never met Hemingway, but from what I've known of him.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I guess it's just what I liked so much about this book was that on one hand I saw these characters is so jaded and cynical and ruined has like hulks of people.
Rym: and Yet at the same time Well, I remember when the main character goes off and he just stays alone in the mountains like fishing with his one friend fishing and drinking and doing nothing else and He's happy and color comes back into the world and I don't know.
Rym: it felt like you can escape from that like the Sun sets But it also rises.
Rym: The problem is the characters don't actually realize that and none of them.
Rym: Well, one guy is like.
Rym: I guess it's just I can't.
Rym: I don't want to go too long about this.
Rym: The story follows the main character, but he is not the real main character.
Rym: He's the one who doesn't escape from the jaded system cynicism of life.
Rym: that other guy the boxer escapes from that and has a real life.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: I remember this book.
Rym: Yeah the book was great because it would it followed one guy but the moral was about the other guy.
Rym: and if you read the book and You think it was about the cynical guy and it's a depressing book.
Scott: But I do remember that the boxer was the business and the other people.
Rym: that's it.
Rym: The story is about the boxer.
Rym: It's not about the main character.
Rym: I think his name was Jack.
Rym: I haven't read it in a while.
Scott: It's a favorite book.
Scott: What's the main character's name?
Rym: I've read it like ten times, but I haven't read it in like five years.
Rym: But seriously, the book is about the boxer and if you read it in that way Then it is a romance you want it to be about the.
Rym: well No I even I think Hemingway said something to where.
Rym: if you read it about him Then it's a romance story.
Rym: if you read it about any other character.
Rym: It's a tragedy.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much and the bullfighters kind of a cock and I'll leave it at that.
Scott: Bullfight screw you if you don't like this book, okay What book should I talk about next?
Scott: Let's see.
Rym: All right, I got a list here.
Scott: I got I got ready.
Scott: Okay, so, you know Roald Dahl?
Scott: Yes, yeah Roald Dahl He wrote books such as Matilda and James and the Giant Peach and Charlie the Great Glass elevator and Charlie Chocolate Factory and all those books that you enjoyed When you were a kid.
Scott: Well when I was a kid I pretty much read all his books because it was easy because all the books are published in the same format so I could recognize Them in the store and I knew which ones they didn't have.
Scott: it was great and You know some of his books were just sort of like Quirky sort of weird stuff like the twits, you know, and some of his books were serious business.
Scott: But there's one book of his that is overlooked I'd say more than all the others but it is the most serious business and it might be one of the best books there is.
Scott: Period.
Scott: the book is called the wonderful story of Henry sugar I think and some others and it's a book that contains a bunch of short stories.
Scott: but there's one relatively big story in the book compared to the others, which is the story of Henry sugar and it tries to make you believe.
Scott: it's about a real person which I don't believe but that doesn't matter.
Scott: and Basically, the story is this there's a guy he's loaded.
Scott: He lives in London, you know in a flat.
Scott: That's mad moneys.
Scott: He's got mad moneys and all he does every day is go to casino and he casinos people smoking cigars And it's big casino life.
Scott: and that's his living right gambling and whoo?
Scott: richness and drunken and sleeping, right?
Scott: and one day he goes to.
Scott: he's like on vacation somewhere I get your Visiting someone at their big mansion, you know, cuz that's what rich people do and there's a poker game But there's too many people.
Scott: so he has to sit out.
Scott: He goes to the library in this guy's mansion.
Scott: It's good.
Scott: He's all alone there's no one else picks up a book and he starts reading it and Then it cuts to this book and basically the book he reads is in the book.
Scott: you start reading that book and then you're done and it's back to Henry sugar and It.
Scott: I'm not gonna say anything more.
Scott: that happens But this book will teach you this.
Scott: just one story within this book of short stories, right which has a book in it will teach you everything you need to know about charity and money and Randy bullshit and gambling and living and everything and It's like one of the best books there is and you could probably get it for really cheap and it won't take you that long To read because I read it when I was in like fifth grade.
Scott: So I think you can read it now, you mean I don't think we have any fifth graders listening, right?
Scott: So you're older than a fifth grader.
Scott: You can read this easily quickly.
Scott: You should get it Right.
Rym: So this one is gonna be out of place, especially with all the other books I'm talking about.
Rym: but and I have a few friends who have read this and they agree with me.
Rym: So I feel not Too off base in stating this opinion.
Rym: But when I was a kid, I read all those like forgotten realms books and I avoided those books.
Rym: I read one dragon lads book and then I had started to read another one that I realized that I hate dragon lands and all that.
Rym: but I read a lot of those and some were okay and some were awful and some Some of them were particularly awful.
Rym: But of all those books there's one that stands out as though it shouldn't be in the same section.
Rym: I don't know why but this one book is just good like actually good Stands on its own as a good novel a really good novel a disturbing novel.
Rym: It is Troy Dennings pages of pain.
Rym: now It is set in the planescape universe and has like the planescape logo like everything else, but don't be fooled This book has practically nothing to do with Dungeons & Dragons and you don't need to know anything about it.
Scott: Why did they put the logo on there?
Scott: making me be skeptical.
Scott: putting that logo on there is like let's make Scott skeptical.
Rym: well, because it's nominally written in this universe and it's part of all these books, but the thing is it stands alone and like it.
Rym: it kind of takes some of the core ideas of some of the very basic ideas of planescape in this world and goes in a very I guess unexpected and interesting direction and
Scott: it's
Rym: kind of almost a retelling of the story of Theseus, but it's Really well-written and really disturbingly written and I don't know this is one of those books that actually affected me in a very profound way and I remember I got to a point where I just stayed up all night reading the end of it and I Don't want to ruin anything.
Rym: I just want to say If you like literature or fantasy or anything Just pick up Troy Dennings pages of pain and just read it Read it all the way through and tell me what you think about it because this book it Transcends what you would expect from a book like this and I hold it high on the list of books I have read in my life.
Scott: I'm just generally skeptical of any book that has some sort of licensed property logo on the cover because that tells me that this person who wrote this book didn't think it was a good enough to stand on its own and they needed to somehow sell It to fans of that
Rym: property.
Rym: the thing is But Troy Dennings, I mean he wrote a lot of stuff for D&D and he wrote under a bunch of pseudonyms And he's kind of big in that, you know industry of writing things.
Scott: I'm not saying that's like some law of the universe or anything.
Scott: I'm just saying that's what when I see that there.
Scott: That's what I think.
Scott: so I tend to steer away and I'm incredibly skeptical of like any book with a Star Trek logo or Star Wars logo or a battle tech logo, even if it's.
Scott: I mean, I love Star Wars But a Star Wars logo on a books tells me stay away.
Rym: This is such an exception.
Rym: I seriously cannot recommend this book highly enough though I will warn you this book is a tad disturbing and super depressing.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: If you couldn't tell from the title pages of pain Alright, so, you know that relatively new Miyazaki movie that ghetto Senki whatever.
Scott: Uh, yeah Yeah, it was based on these books and I think there was a science fiction channel.
Rym: Oh, this is a good call.
Scott: there's a lot of science fiction channel live-action miniseries, but I heard that it was terrible even though I never saw it and I never.
Scott: I haven't seen the Miyazaki movie yet Although I'm sure I will at some point and from what I hear while it I don't I'm not sure how good or bad it Was.
Scott: people didn't seem to say it was as good as other Miyazaki movies and the person who wrote these books It was based on said well, it was a you know, she didn't like say all was terrible.
Scott: She said well, it was something different.
Scott: It wasn't my story.
Scott: It was his story, right and up these books were based on these books these these movies and miniseries and things were based on a series of books Called the Earthsea.
Scott: whatever Chronicles whatever you want to call them it's Earthsea the tales of Earthsea by Ursula K Le Guin and I own like a zillion books by this lady and There's four or five of them and you really only have to read like the first three or four You know, you should be able to get them like in a set with all the same printing on them.
Scott: And these are I'm not gonna lie there.
Scott: They're basically, you know, they're.
Scott: they're fantasy novels written at sort of a children's level, you know But if you're reading Harry Potter, you should not be.
Scott: you can read these.
Scott: it's better than Harry Potter.
Rym: I just have to say the story of Harry Potter is all cool.
Rym: And I like the.
Rym: I like the characters.
Rym: I like the story.
Rym: I think Snape is like the best dude ever but That woman cannot write.
Scott: good god I don't like.
Scott: I don't like anything about Harry Potter except for funny flash videos just will make out of it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that can be funny.
Rym: just the way she writes like her use of English just bothers me and I can't get past that.
Scott: So you need if you need a point of reference to see how much Harry Potter sucks.
Scott: Earthsea is the business.
Scott: This is where you want to go All right.
Scott: You know how.
Scott: sometimes you read like some sort of epic fantasy trilogy or something and it always feels even Lord of the Rings Right, it feels like the real business went down before the books you're reading aka like in the Silmarillion, right?
Scott: But it's like whatever the story you're reading about now.
Scott: They always talk about the epic war of the past.
Scott: that is so much bigger and badder than the thing that you're wrong right now.
Rym: I think part of the reason for that is that Following the bigger better epic story is often not nearly as interesting.
Scott: That is true And I there's a certain amount of merit in that.
Scott: However This story of Earthsea at least the first three books right tells the story of this guy get right and It feels like when you're at the beginning of the book right when you're reading early on it feels like The awesome stuff all happened in the past when the world was full of dragons.
Scott: and look at the guy Mentoring the main character.
Scott: get he is like, you know the most Badassist wizard, you know there is and everything is all man's right?
Scott: But as you read on you realize that Ged is basically like the Merlin of this universe, you know, it's like yeah There was badass stuff in the past, but you're reading the story of the guy not like, you know You know Luke Skywalker, but in the past, you know, Yoda was really the guy, you know Not like Darth Vader was really the guy in the past.
Scott: No, this is the guy.
Scott: so as you read on this is this is so awesome this shit.
Scott: and You know, it's not like the deepest thing and he it's not shallow, but it's not like the deepest thing ever.
Scott: there's there's you know a nice poignant message towards the end of the first book and You know They start introducing different characters and like the second and third books and they get it and Ged sort of becomes like, you know You.
Scott: it's like you read the story of this guy in the first book and then in like the later books He sort of becomes this, you know, distant amazing powerful guy, but you're like wait, I read that story.
Scott: Oh my god You know it, you know, imagine if like, you know the first Harry Potter book, you know, it's okay.
Scott: And then the second Harry Potter book is about someone else and Harry Potter is like some you know, mystical.
Scott: Oh my god guy that like doesn't even show.
Scott: that's how awesome this is.
Scott: That's the feeling you get while reading it and It's high quality.
Scott: It doesn't take long to read at all.
Scott: They're like little books meant for much younger audience.
Scott: Why am I doing all these young kids books?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So I gotta say and I think I've made reference to this before but I think my favorite Novel ever like of all time hands down is the Count of Monte Cristo.
Rym: You only read that recently I know and you know, well recently God I read it when I was still going to RIT.
Scott: Oh, did you?
Scott: Yeah I thought you read it like, okay, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: And I'd read excerpts from it a lot of excerpts from it throughout, you know high school even in middle school like short like I guess simplified excerpts and Relatively recently like in the last many years.
Rym: I read the whole thing straight up Relatively unabridged and it's just.
Rym: it's one of my favorite novels ever.
Rym: I'm not gonna tell you the story of the Count of Monte Cristo other than that.
Rym: It is probably the best story of revenge ever written.
Rym: I Cannot name one better.
Scott: It is quite a story of revenge.
Scott: There is no doubt
Rym: I just I love it and to get into no great detail I think the reason I like it the mope beyond anything else is that partly because of the way it was written it Ended up that the like the pace of the story, you know a lot of novels like skip over a lot or the action kind of zooms in and zooms out and speeds up and slows down depending on what action is going on.
Rym: like a Scene where there's action will be described in like excruciating detail But then other scenes will be described in little detail and important details will kind of stand out.
Rym: Scooby Doo ish almost The Count of Monte Cristo keeps an even keel pretty much throughout to the point that Everything is described very kind of straightforward matter-of-factly and I don't know as a result and it's all like from the perspective of the count and You just kind of go through this story in a semi-realistic way and it just it draws me along in such this.
Rym: I love it.
Scott: I Say about that book though.
Scott: Is that it was from a time where they paid you by the page?
Rym: Oh, yeah, he was paid like by the word.
Rym: There's a reason why he was so circuitous in his eye.
Rym: Yeah, but Regardless of why it was written that way this book is fucking awesome.
Rym: And also I do want to say however if you were going to read it Read the translation by Robin bust and don't read any other translation because they're all pretty awful.
Rym: Okay and read an unabridged like the relatively unabridged penguin classics.
Rym: one is Like the best translation of this book and a lot of people say oh they dumbed it down.
Rym: No All they did was take because the thing is it was written kind of in colloquial French Which sounds kind of stilted if you translate it directly or you mean air it to modern French.
Rym: So a lot a lot of the translation so much end up translating it in this really stilted way But it was written in the vernacular.
Rym: So the the bus translation is really kind of a vernacular.
Rym: and also Okay Read the penguin classics one.
Rym: Don't bother with any other translation.
Rym: You'll enjoy it.
Scott: It's a public domain book.
Scott: So like anyone in their mother can print a copy in any form they want.
Rym: But the penguin classics one I just looked it up was actually written in 1996. so it's a recent translation.
Rym: All right, and read that one seriously forget anything else.
Scott: All right, I'm gonna do a double book combo.
Rym: You don't watch any movies because they're unmitigated.
Scott: Lee awful I'd never seen any.
Scott: they're awful.
Scott: Isn't there like incredibly old black and white there.
Scott: It's supposed to be gone.
Rym: No, it's not good.
Rym: Okay, it's awful.
Scott: All right, so I got a double book combo right ready one really small book and one really big book ready.
Scott: If you're playing civilization and you want the mad moneys, what do you build?
Rym: Well, what do I build?
Rym: Oh, I know where you're going with this because what I build are fanatics because that's all I use.
Rym: Before that I filled Marco Polo and then I build Adam Smith.
Scott: Adam Smith and what do they teach you in social studies class?
Scott: About how you know, we have capitalism.
Scott: Where did that come?
Rym: Well, they always they always dumb it down and say well capitalism is all Adam Smith and communism is all Karl Marx or possibly angles.
Rym: Yep,
Scott: and that's what they teach you in school and whatever truth may lie in that the fact of the matter is this I'm not gonna art make a communism versus capitalism argument right now but I'll say this
Rym: go
Scott: on Amazon and if you don't already buy a copy of the Communist Manifesto by Karl Marx and Buy a copy of the Wealth of Nations by Adam Smith and when you get these books in the mail from Amazon They're pretty cheap.
Scott: I mean, these are public domain books.
Scott: This is just so good.
Scott: one of these books is very small and one of these books is very big and I can tell you which is which.
Scott: but I will tell you that is obvious.
Scott: one person thought their clever plan through and one person did not.
Scott: Now I Only own one of these.
Scott: I only own one of these books.
Scott: the larger one because the smaller one is is not needed.
Rym: I uh, I own the smaller one.
Scott: Oh you I read it numerous times.
Scott: I never read it.
Scott: I thought it was worth it.
Rym: I don't think he thought his clever plan is the thing you read the Communist Manifesto and is basically blah blah blah the workers blah blah and Adam Smith is like Well, what if blah happens?
Rym: I was like, ah, well we do this.
Rym: But what about blah?
Rym: well we do this and a lot of people point out the failings of capitalism and Scott and I have come to the opinion that those are not failings of capitalism.
Rym: Those are failings of our Economic system because our Western economic system is not Adam Smith capitalism any stretch.
Scott: that is correct.
Scott: If you actually I don't read don't?
Scott: I don't suggest you read this book straight through because it.
Scott: But take this book and hasn't the printing I have which is like this golden paperback, right?
Scott: I mean at the cover that it's gold.
Scott: It looks golden.
Scott: I don't know who publishes it, but it's it's like The table of contents in the front and the index in the back.
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: if anyone makes any comment about economics whatsoever using that index you can find Exactly what they're talking about.
Scott: look it up in the book and there's your answer and it makes perfect sense.
Rym: every time for example We were arguing about a minimum wage I'm not gonna say which side either one of us wrong because it doesn't matter but we disagreed and Other people weren't sure with this big argument.
Rym: so finally We're like Let's just see what Adam Smith said and we'll agree that that's probably the way we should go.
Scott: and we were like Oh, there's a whole section on that and the whole chapter I think it's chapter four or seven called the wages of labor.
Scott: That is the best chapter.
Scott: Everyone should be that are you are a laborer or will be?
Rym: to summarize Adam Smith's position was basically that if a job is not worth being paid a living wage for then the job is not worth doing because if it's Necessary someone is eventually going to be willing to pay a living wage for it.
Rym: And there I mean, I think there could be modern exceptions because now we have the idea of part-time work and that sort of thing.
Rym: But
Scott: I'm gonna have to look up part-time work now,
Rym: but on average I feel like yeah if a job is that necessary then a Basic living wage should be provided the
Scott: job takes all day to do
Rym: or else the job Obviously wasn't as important as you think it is.
Rym: Yep But yeah, you can if nothing else if you argue about economics But you probably do.
Scott: if you're on the internet You would better have a copy of Adam Smith's wealth of nations And the thing is.
Scott: the thing that I think is most important about this book is that you learn in school like laissez-faire.
Scott: Adam Smith wanted everyone to leave economics alone and let it do what it wanted And that's true to a certain extent.
Scott: But if you actually read the book you'll find that many of the typical say libertarian laissez-faire stances and economics Disagree with Adam Smith quite a bit and you will find that Adam Smith thought his clever plan through and he knows.
Scott: he knows the business.
Scott: I mean he wrote this book ages ago, but he was a big businessman in a time when the world was crazy business and He wrote a gigantic book.
Scott: that is available now and you should not deny yourself access to this book.
Rym: It's very.
Scott: maybe you can get it for free on like project Gutenberg.
Rym: It's very to the point.
Scott: It is very to the point but also, you know, he's kind of snarky in some points.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not like, you know, this this, you know, like boring reference book.
Rym: It's not like reading translations of Greek.
Scott: No, it's very.
Scott: I mean he wrote he was he spoke English.
Scott: It was it was not that old You know is an English book.
Scott: It was in English.
Scott: You could understand what he's talking about.
Scott: It's not a translation.
Scott: It's very well footnoted all over the place.
Scott: You know everything, you know, sometimes it's a read a little slowly because it is, you know it's not old English in the in the literal sense, but it is ye old English in the jovial sense and You should only copy this book.
Scott: It's worth owning.
Rym: So this is something cuz you know, I've been on my 12 Byzantine emperors.
Rym: Now what do you what?
Rym: what book do you think I'm gonna bring up?
Rym: because I'm not gonna say the rock decline and follow the Roman Empire one of those penguins classics that ends in Clees.
Rym: Actually, no, I'm gonna talk a little bit about Plutarch's Roman lives.
Rym: Okay, because I picked this up kind of on a lark and I've been reading it and I've always liked reading like whenever I read About history.
Rym: I just I adore primary sources like reading a historical work written by a Roman about the ancient Egyptians is just fascinating to me on many levels, especially if it's annotated.
Rym: So I get the modern translator saying things like well, he was mistaken here because of blah or he obviously made this up.
Rym: But I recently picked up Plutarch and Plutarch lived in you know, like 50 60 100 sometime ad like kind of when the Roman Empire was doing pretty well and he wrote about Roman and Greek history and he was a historian and a writer and One of the.
Rym: the thing he's most known for are his parallel lives or his lives where he would basically Look find the history and write a story of a person who may or may not have been fictional but it's generally like He'll pick like a figure in Roman or Greek history and just kind of give an account of their life from the perspective of the Roman people or the Greek people.
Rym: and All I have to say is that reading primary sources about the Romans by the Romans gives you of and the Greeks gives you a very Interesting perspective on the Romans.
Rym: and I'm more and more and it's not just from Plutarch It's from other sources get the impression that before Rome was a large Empire and when they were just one struggling state amidst many in Italy the Romans were kind of funny and Overly to quote their neighbors
Scott: overly
Rym: obsessed with democracy and a sense of civic duty.
Rym: And they were kind of I don't know that the politics of Rome were very funny like a lot of times there would be disputes between the gentry and the peasants or the laborers or that's like the people living in apartments in the city and the people of the city would say fuck this and just kind of march out of the city and basically say all right you guys Are on your own and just march out to this hill and then the the patricians would have to like ride out to the hill.
Rym: Please come back to the city will forgive your debt and enact like judicial and social reform.
Rym: and they'd be like, I don't know.
Rym: The Romans were just very funny and a lot of.
Rym: I guess it's very easy reading history to forget that the people living in Rome or Persia or Germany or any place where there's kind of a historical thing going on especially ancient history To forget that the actual people who are living then we're not much different from us now and they had the same problems and they argued about the same things.
Rym: and Caesar went to war on dubious pretexts despite the wishes of the Senate and then came back and used that glory for political gain.
Rym: and the people were rallying against this like stupid and costly and wasteful war in a foreign land against people who were generally innocent.
Rym: and There's this the people in ancient Rome in ancient Greece were not that different from us and Often had the same kind of stupid problems that we have now.
Scott: Is that I gotta say?
Rym: the only other thing I have to say is that if you want to read history like this?
Rym: I generally recommend reading Latin or later Greek things because earlier Greek writings are often even translated Incredibly tedious to read.
Rym: good God do I like Xenophon's histories, but good God Can I not stay awake like and then so-and-so went off to so-and-so?
Rym: But many a thing happened when so-and-so went off to so-and-so because so and so said such as.
Scott: I think that's why the 12 Byzantine Empire's gets it ever.
Scott: his guy gets it So right because he takes the so and so he takes the boringness and he makes a you know The dramatic story out of it that it well.
Rym: I think what he does well too is he'll say things like very straight up like this happened.
Rym: But unlike a lot of the primary sources.
Rym: He makes it obvious when you should be reading between the lines Like he lays it on thick like and of course what.
Rym: what would be the obvious thing to do in such a situation?
Rym: Would be to do blah and it's like wow.
Rym: Yeah, sure, okay Go room.
Scott: All right.
Scott: You have any.
Scott: you want me to pull one out from under you here?
Rym: Yeah, let's each do one more All right.
Scott: I'm gonna steal American gods by me.
Rym: I was that I guess we'll end on that.
Scott: Just yoink that I knew that was gonna work.
Rym: All right, fine.
Rym: I'll yoink it.
Rym: American gods is fucking awesome.
Rym: Neil Gaiman It's like my personal hero.
Rym: I find him a little bit sexy This but it's very British and very well, he's rugged and he's cute.
Rym: What can I say?
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: So this book if you are a fan of anything No, if you're it's it.
Scott: this is this book is great because it combines so many things.
Scott: it combines mythology Right in the old sense mythology in the new sense.
Scott: it combines You know the the sort of story you get of like, you know, the the grifter.
Scott: it combines the story of you know one man in in sort of like very Americana kind of existence kind of story and Also sort of like the epic, you know defeat the big villain kind of story.
Scott: in a way You know guy in a quest meeting a bunch of people on the way kind of thing But also a little slice of life also a mystery.
Rym: Yeah, and then another mystery and then a surprise Mr.
Rym: You didn't realize was there unless you were paying attention super attention and just a cast of extremely interesting memorable characters that come back in ways you wouldn't expect.
Scott: and Yeah, it's a good time.
Rym: this is one of those books that I wouldn't say that.
Rym: oh if you like such-and-such a book you would like this book because this book is just Very for it's written for you and I don't.
Rym: there aren't many people who dislike this book.
Scott: if you're listening to this show It's for you.
Rym: I mean, I don't even want to say much about it cuz I don't want to ruin anything.
Scott: Well other than that, there's some gods in it and there's some Americans And that's about it American plus gods.
Rym: you want to read a book that is well written.
Rym: This book is so well written.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I know engrossing I haven't read, you know the mountain of Neil Gaiman.
Scott: stuff there is you know, I believe it's gaming but gaming whatever I you know, I've read 1602.
Scott: I have that.
Scott: well, we met the man and I met him and I fell asleep not because he was boring me but because I just been in a car for hours and hours And hours and hours and hours, but and that was sad.
Scott: Yeah, that was all that story.
Rym: Yeah, that was the best convention ever though in terms of like awesome versus expected.
Rym: Awesome.
Scott: Yeah But yeah in I haven't read any of his other stuff, but this this book is just so Quadruple the business.
Scott: I He's got you know the the mixing of the the the crazy stuff but the suspension of the disbelief.
Scott: that totally works for me.
Rym: the humor is Hilarious that the foreshadowing is good.
Rym: Just I said this before but the writing is so good.
Rym: if you want to see why I can't read Harry Potter read this book.
Rym: Yeah, yeah Just like the way he uses words and the way he alludes to things in the way He parallels think the the structure forget what he's writing about.
Rym: the parallelism between sentences is just like amazing.
Rym: All right I don't know.
Rym: I mean There's a bunch of books.
Rym: I could have brought up but I obviously didn't.
Rym: we're done.
Rym: I'm just gonna mop up a little bit.
Rym: Of course CS forester ratio hornblower The Temeraire books by Naomi Novik, even though they're pulp.
Rym: They're my kind of pulp, you know.
Rym: Napoleonic Wars dragons on ships.
Scott: OMG If you're if you're like Gabe from penny arcade or I guess Mike Krahulik from penny arcade.
Scott: Then you will.
Scott: you will enjoy the lens min which has rockets and planets on the cover.
Rym: you know, he's like if a book has a rocket and a planet and like That's a laser a laser on it.
Rym: That's just kind of book.
Rym: if there's a ship and a dragon I'm gonna read it.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.