Rym: It's Tuesday January 22nd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk about one of the classic games of our time Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Rym: Let's do this Lolo - it's there.
Scott: What about Lolo?
Rym: - Lolo - it's on the VC.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, how much do you like it?
Rym: You know, uh, I think a lot of people forgot about Lolo or have never played Lolo.
Rym: Lolo is a fantastic puzzle.
Rym: Let me clarify that.
Rym: Lolo is very difficult but fantastic Puzzle game.
Rym: Lolo - is a wonderful puzzle game.
Rym: Lolo 3 is garbage.
Scott: Yeah, I never played the low lows all the way through and I never really noticed a big difference between them.
Scott: I noticed that I think Lolo 3 had more that timing kind of stuff.
Rym: That was the problem.
Rym: Lolo 1 & 2 were logic puzzles.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: My brain is here.
Scott: What do I do?
Scott: in what order?
Rym: and then Lolo 3 you get to a point where it's like, alright I gotta hope that this randomly walking guy walks in front of that Medusa at the right time And I got a bump into him to stop him and then I got a run past while he stopped there.
Rym: And that's the totally different game and completely beside what was fun about Lolo?
Scott: Yeah, I guess the Lolo had the element of.
Scott: you know It's a game where like you're on a map and you want you got to open up an exit by pushing stuff around and shooting things and you only have limited ammo and you can get ammo in certain ways and whatnot and You also have to get out of that exit without getting killed and one shot from anything kills you.
Scott: So, you know you push like things in front of bad guys that shoot at you So they can't hit you and there's
Rym: a limited number of bad guys that act in like predefined known ways So that you kind of once you solve all the basic problems Then they take all those pieces together and make more advanced problems like, you know, good game design just great games Yep.
Scott: So did you buy this Lolo 2?
Rym: Not yet just because I haven't I've been playing punch-out.
Scott: I've been playing punch-out.
Scott: Are you gonna buy Lolo 2?
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Thing is I'd rather them just release all the Lolo games on the DS In like one cartridge.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Scott: You know when I had Fresh From the Air Someone found like my old cruddy website where I wrote a thing about Lolo Way back in the 90s and they asked me to like they were making a Lolo clone and they wanted me to make some levels.
Scott: So I just tossed together some like shit levels.
Scott: Yeah, and I guess they credited me and they put one whole world of the game is is my Lolo levels Praise Lolo world.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: I made some pretty shit levels.
Rym: That's what I always thought and I wish they'd bring the Lolo franchise back in a way of imagine if all right I got my DS right some sort of versus Lolo.
Scott: How would that work?
Rym: well I could either be you know put in a level designer and you have some sort of logic that figures out if levels are doable And constrain it so that you can't do too much with it.
Rym: Then you erase each other.
Scott: Well, you give each guy the same number of pieces Like you have this many pushing chests and this many bricks and this many Medusas and this many running guys And you know you.
Scott: or maybe you have some number of points and you have to buy the pieces of the map with points.
Rym: Or maybe you both take turns adding elements to a common map and then the two of you race together toward the goal.
Scott: That'll be okay.
Rym: something like I just feel like Lolo is not fully explored to explore the possibilities of multiplayer man.
Scott: Well, I think you know in Mario Party is that one minigame we had to push the goombas and then get the hotel goomba.
Rym: Yeah, the only problem with that was that one it brings memories of the hotel Mario Yeah, and two it was always the same math like once you know it you just I know.
Scott: but I'm saying Yeah, if you had the verses of Lolo sort of like how tell goomba is versus?
Rym: they could work out Yeah, or even just Lolo where you both race to beat levels together.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Scott: Also on the virtual console.
Scott: They came out with Super Street Fighter 2, which it was really stupid because I was wondering like Way back in the virtual console they released like the shittiest version of Street Fighter 2 like didn't have you know?
Scott: like Street Fighter 2 if you everyone realizes they came out with so many versions of Street Fighter 2 is ridiculous and The only ones that were really worth it were Street in the arcade the only one that mattered to me.
Scott: Well, there were two that mattered.
Scott: there is Street Fighter 2 championship edition Which is the best one for me as far as I'm concerned, but the the sort of ultimate edition was Super Street Fighter 2 turbo.
Rym: So, you know, I was indifferent because I pretty much always played guile.
Scott: Yeah But on the virtual console they came out with like Street Fighter 2 Crap shit edition and now they came out with.
Scott: and now they came out with decently playable edition And I realized something that was like I was gonna buy it, but I really not gonna play it that much.
Scott: So whatever and you know, maybe I'll buy it someday in the distant future.
Scott: You know if we like a need a sudden Street Fighter 2 tournament or something.
Scott: But on the I've noticed I've been playing punch-out a lot lately and part of that is because I can play it with the normal Wiimote.
Scott: I don't have to plug in a controller or use a game.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you need a different controller to play Street Fighter.
Scott: I need that extra controller and I realize I want to play games on the virtual console.
Scott: Like I'll be sitting there and I'll look and I have Super Metroid on the virtual console.
Rym: I'm like, I want to play point out that All you would have to do is reach into the same basket from which you pulled out the Wiimote and there's already Another controller ready to go and all you have to do is plug it into the Wiimote.
Scott: You're already holding what you don't even have to move I know but that small amount of effort sort of like.
Scott: but punch it's like.
Scott: it's not that so.
Rym: so I think the news here Is that Scott is the laziest motherfucker?
Scott: You said it was happening to you also.
Scott: Hello.
Rym: No, I didn't.
Rym: I never said that.
Rym: What game did I want to play other than punch?
Scott: I think I think that's part of it.
Scott: Though is that I see punch-out right there next to the Super Metroid.
Rym: I think the reason you play punch-out is because punch-out is a superior game.
Scott: No It's because punch.
Scott: it's like I could play two equally perfect games.
Scott: One of them does not require a small amount of effort of grabbing a an extra remote.
Scott: So I'm gonna play the one that doesn't require the extra remote.
Rym: Of course None of this matters because a game I've been looking forward to since before I knew it existed is finally out.
Rym: advance wars The real deal days of ruin.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much we did a show about advance wars But I you know every now and then there's a game that there's always that one not who just goes crazy about it and like It's every secret and like super beats the game and that was me.
Rym: in advance wars I beat like this the normal and the hard campaigns on every advance wars game to ever came out with Any entire war room except for the ones that were in previous advance wars?
Rym: Yeah, look at this way.
Rym: I beat with an s-rank every single war room in the entirety of advance wars one and two.
Rym: So when advance wars DS came out half them after the same and I didn't bother with them other than to beat ones that were Somewhat hard on the previous game really easily with some of the new characters.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but as a new advance wars There was a release party at the Nintendo World Store.
Scott: We didn't go to that.
Scott: We're busy.
Rym: I'm so about this game not one.
Rym: The main reason I'm so excited about this game is that Advance wars the three games that we got in the US pretty much played it out Like it got to the point where the strategies were known and perfect and there's really nothing you like.
Rym: the game boils down very rapidly to nothing and some of the characters were way over balanced and the maps and The game was getting to the point where you couldn't really play it competitively with a lot of people who are really good at it Which is something that happens to most games and I wondered, you know, what are they gonna do?
Rym: They keep adding more CEOs, which is makes the game more and more unbalanced and then this advance wars is basically a reset.
Rym: Yes, all new CEOs all new everything the game is gonna be awesome.
Rym: I think.
Scott: well, we don't know until we get it which is what could be like couple weeks.
Rym: Yeah, I pre-ordered on Amazon stupidly so I have to wait.
Scott: I don't think that's stupidly.
Scott: I mean, you don't have to go to the stupid GameStop and deal with their bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time I could have just walked to the GameStop near me at work and just bought it.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean having the game now is no different than having it.
Rym: I think you understand this is this is one of those rare games where once I get it I'm pretty much going to do nothing in my life outside of GeekNights and possible Extracurricular activities until I've beaten everything that there is to beat in this game.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean the game isn't gonna suddenly change in the next two weeks.
Rym: It's gonna be the same game now as it's gonna be but I thought there was a Wi-Fi I could play this online with people.
Scott: You can play it online with people two weeks from now.
Rym: Cuz you know now cuz you know how Nintendo Wi-Fi works.
Rym: if you play a game in the first week There's people playing.
Rym: if you try to play a game in the second week.
Rym: There's no one left.
Scott: Well, you can only get a plate with your friends anyway, so it doesn't matter.
Scott: You don't play with random losers.
Rym: Yeah, see I would I'd say oh I really want to have some sort of ladder ranking system.
Rym: play with people online.
Rym: But as we know Nintendo basically took the idea of online gameplay and just fucked it.
Scott: I mean base.
Scott: at this point I basically whether a game allows online.
Scott: a Nintendo game allows online play or not.
Scott: I just it's as if it doesn't exist.
Scott: It's like it doesn't even matter.
Scott: It's it they.
Scott: they have this feature there.
Scott: But the feature is so hindered by the friend code bullshit and all the limitations on it.
Scott: It's so bad and so painful to work around it.
Scott: It's as if it's not even there.
Scott: they might as well have not put it in.
Scott: cuz I don't consider it.
Scott: when I'm buying a game I don't use it.
Scott: It's just that shitty.
Rym: now I can at least conceive of playing this game possibly with my friends via the Wi-Fi because a lot of times I want to play Advance Wars.
Rym: Well, I always want to play Advance Wars.
Rym: The thing is no one else ever wants to play Advance Wars because when the front row crew is together We do something other than play Advance Wars.
Rym: We play T&E.
Rym: Yep, but Say I'm at home and Pete's at home and Alex is at home and Scott's at home somewhere in the house.
Rym: We could play Advance Wars with the Wi-Fi theoretically if it doesn't suck or not work or something.
Rym: So we can't and Maybe I can get some inroads and get these people off of the World of Warcraft.
Scott: No, I don't think Advance Wars is gonna get.
Rym: The problem there is that I'm pretty sure most of my friends could play Advance Wars with me online and have and continue to play World of Warcraft without skipping a beat.
Scott: Yeah, I think the only hope you have a beating World of Warcraft is I don't know something else.
Scott: It's not gonna be Advance Wars.
Rym: So speaking of World of Warcraft you have news there.
Scott: I do have news.
Scott: Oh my god, that was news.
Rym: by the way in the World of Warcraft, you know with computers There's always a limit, you know the matrix that's how they beat the things in the end is well There's limits that could what computers can do and you know integers run out and all that business.
Rym: You know in the old video games like in Civ 2 or Civ 1 you could edit the text file to give yourself more gold But there was a limit.
Rym: you couldn't get more than that and all that business.
Rym: It's the way computers work now World of Warcraft.
Rym: apparently you can never have more than two thousand one hundred two thousand two billion.
Rym: No 214 thousand seven hundred and forty eight gold pieces 36 silver pieces and 48 copper pieces and you cannot possibly have more gold than that Uh-huh.
Rym: Now the reason for this is of course, they use a signed integer because that's two to the 31 gold.
Rym: No one could ever have more.
Scott: now Why do they use?
Scott: they should use an unsigned integer.
Scott: that way you can have twice as much stuff with the same amount of memory Because you're never gonna have negative gold.
Rym: I have two thoughts about that.
Rym: one Maybe they thought of the idea of allowing people to go into debt or more likely They just defined in gold and just never look back.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I would have done unsigned in gold.
Scott: That way you could add twice as much gold as that.
Rym: but of course for people who don't play World of Warcraft You might think 200,000 gold.
Rym: It's not that much because like in the realm or a lot of other MMOs or you know Eve whatever people have millions and billions And billions of whatever.
Rym: One gold is actually a lot of money in Wow Like a lot of money like people were talking about.
Rym: Yeah, I've never like.
Scott: it's like it's supposed to be in the in D&D.
Rym: You know it is like that in D&D if you're if you don't have like PC class levels if you're just like Peasant four and maybe like I don't know local dude merchant one the old blacksmith You're maybe gonna see like five gold pieces in your entire life.
Scott: Meanwhile adventurers have like a thousand of them at level one where they're just like they can get killed in one hit with a sword.
Scott: They're so weak.
Scott: It's like what's so special about you get killed in one shot.
Scott: Why do you have a thousand gold?
Rym: Especially before third edition where it wasn't like.
Rym: oh well you have levels in those gimp classes like four levels of peasant or expert.
Rym: But in the old D&D if you didn't have player class levels you were a level zero commoner And it wasn't like.
Rym: oh well you'll level up in commoner.
Rym: No you can't level.
Rym: There's no such thing as experience for you It's not for you.
Scott: See what I really like to do is see it's.
Scott: I think that Maybe you should get like five NPC levels and then a real class level.
Scott: You know.
Scott: so like you know I was a blacksmith, and then I became a wizard, but now my blacksmithing skills disappear somehow.
Scott: What's up with that?
Rym: cuz blacksmithing is worthless?
Scott: What are you talking about?
Rym: it costs like a couple gold to buy a sword add?
Rym: 300. to that you get a master work.
Rym: the best a human can do without magic.
Scott: But I can craft a sword instead with magic myself.
Rym: It's easier to just spend 300 gold.
Rym: right.
Rym: My favorite thing to do in D&D.
Rym: you know D&D especially if you're playing it kind of here in pretzels ease.
Rym: You're an adventurer.
Rym: I got my thousands and thousands of gold.
Rym: whenever you're bribing some commoner just drop a platinum.
Rym: that's the equivalent of going to some dive bar in like Bolivia and Finding say making fun of Bolivia.
Rym: I find some dive bar in Botswana.
Scott: I make it fun of Botswana.
Rym: some dive bar in Albion all right and Dropping you know just walk it up saying hey I need some information on where fat Tony is and then given the guy a cashier's check for ten billion dollars Something like that.
Scott: all right that's that's your news there.
Rym: That's all I got.
Scott: some loser got so much gold in World of Warcraft.
Scott: He he discovered the size of a 32.
Rym: I'm assuming that is not in fact some loser who spent every waking hour playing, but someone who was smart enough to game the system.
Scott: Well what they could have done is they could have said hey, I wonder if there's a limit on gold.
Scott: Everyone give me all your gold and make a bunch of people all gave their you know.
Rym: If that's the case then that person is the most brilliant scammer to ever scam scams.
Scott: Or maybe there's a gold farmer or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe there's.
Scott: maybe someone just bought gold from gold farmers to get to the limit.
Rym: You know how much money that would cost.
Scott: good God a lot more than well less.
Scott: Hopefully less than two to the 32 Money dollars, okay, okay, so Brazil a country where there are many good and many bad thing.
Scott: It's very weird.
Scott: It's like in the US.
Scott: all we do is bitch and bitch and bitch, but we have some good things here But all we notice are the bad things and we always look at other countries and say all those other countries are so much better But every one of those other countries is like so much better in all these ways And it's so much worse than a whole different set of ways.
Scott: And it's always interesting to see which countries have what is really good there, and what's really bad there.
Rym: I'm really curious where you're going with this.
Scott: well in Brazil They have a lot of really good things.
Scott: for example Creative Commons is huge.
Scott: Like they're like what is?
Scott: he's the culture minister of Brazil is like a famous Brazilian pop star Who's also a super creative comments and awesome, and they're there.
Rym: wait a minute wait a minute.
Rym: so so Okay, but the previous part of that.
Rym: He was a famous pop star now.
Rym: He's a important government minister the culture minister.
Rym: Yeah, I guess that works.
Scott: It makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it kind of makes sense right.
Scott: so they're big creative comments.
Scott: There's Linux action going on there.
Scott: There's there's all sorts of all.
Scott: they use the or cut big time down there.
Rym: I know they use the down there.
Rym: That's the reason I don't use the or cut.
Scott: yeah I like the or cut right, but you know Brazil's pretty cool, but part of Brazil not so cool.
Scott: They just banned.
Scott: get this.
Scott: this is so ironic.
Scott: They banned some video games counter specifically Counter-strike and EverQuest.
Scott: these two games are no longer first.
Rym: does anyone still play EverQuest?
Scott: I guess Brazil.
Scott: I mean Brazil.
Scott: I read a thing a while ago So I don't know how true this still is.
Scott: but in Brazil like when we were playing like ps2 and Xbox and one and in those days Brazil was like all about Sega Genesis.
Rym: Well, I've read that pretty much in most of South America at the SNES Genesis era of video gaming is huge for a variety of reasons We don't need to really get into.
Scott: I mean you don't realize it.
Scott: But like Sega is like way huge around the world outside You know the US and such outside the US and Japan for like like they're building like Sega Amusement parks in places around the world, you know, like huge Sonic the Hedgehog huge.
Rym: Well, I mean think Sega did a lot better in like the UK in South America when it came out than it ever did in the US.
Scott: Yeah, I mean when I was ten age-wise, I guess not absolutely.
Scott: I mean when I went to when I went to Israel in the year 2000 right.
Scott: the every arcade that we saw was a Sega arcade and all the tokens had Sonic on them.
Scott: and When I went to a this dude's house, he had a master system and I was like, whoa The master system that was so that was a generally worth this piece.
Scott: So they're you know, they're generally I I you know, I think they're playing older video games in that part of the world You know, so banning counter-strike in EverQuest is not you know, I guess those are popular there.
Rym: But I guess I mean I still.
Rym: I can't imagine anyone's playing EverQuest.
Scott: but the ban was ordered in October o7 by a federal Brazilian court federal court and But they implementing it now they're taking those games off the shelf.
Rym: So so one why did like?
Rym: what was the reason?
Scott: well Okay, you're ready for this.
Scott: This is the greatest part.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: Um, let me try to find the exact quote from the judge.
Rym: I'm waiting for something epic here.
Rym: I'm waiting for some sort of just the judge Carlos Alberto.
Scott: Simoes ruled that the games encouraged quote The subversion of public order were an attack against the Democratic state and the law and the law and against public security.
Scott: No, no EverQuest EverQuest.
Scott: How does that follow?
Scott: Right, here's the thing that counter-strike.
Rym: I could kind of understand even though I look you could look at it from the other perspective Of yeah, but half the players are counter terrorists fighting for justice.
Rym: They're on your side, right?
Scott: They also said they incite violence and are harmful to consumers health.
Scott: now the thing that really gets me about this is he says we're an attack against the Democratic state.
Scott: I Think censorship is an attack against the Democratic state.
Rym: I also find it interesting that they didn't ban first-person shooters or violent video games or MMOs.
Rym: They banned two Very specific game.
Scott: That's the thing.
Scott: They're really good.
Scott: I mean they.
Rym: EverQuest - I'm okay if I play Asher ons call and I'm apparently also mentally damaged.
Rym: It's okay.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it's okay to play World of Warcraft So I can play counter-strike source, okay to play Call of Duty, but it's not okay to play counter-strike.
Scott: I'll play counter-strike source.
Scott: I know game.
Scott: Oh, I guess I can play.
Scott: You know NS or insurgency or any of those besides, you know, what if they're playing old games?
Rym: I'm sure they're all still playing action quake - which is arguably the best game ever to include an mp5 Navy, but I think it's.
Scott: it really shows just a lack of understanding.
Scott: knowledge foresight The problem of the legal system.
Scott: not understanding technology in the modern world is not exclusive to the United States of America.
Rym: Anyway things of the day.
Rym: now the wiimote can do all these interesting things.
Rym: And I still think the power of the gesture based wiimote whatever has not even been close to have been tapped.
Rym: I mean now a lot of the games that have come out and tried to use it have just done it horribly and Just crapily but at the same time games have come out that has shown that there's a lot of potential.
Scott: Yeah, much like Apple Nintendo creates products capable of a B C D and E But only create software to do a B and C.
Rym: and much like Apple Nintendo doesn't care what you want because Nintendo can laugh all the way to the bank.
Rym: Yep, but this dude, I'm not gonna go through all the details because the interesting part is watching this video, but Messing with.
Rym: you know the gesture based stuff and whatever.
Rym: you set up a camera thing computer whatever and it's entitled Hand-guided Mario.
Rym: This is what the power glove should have been.
Rym: now what he has made is not a good game by any stretch.
Rym: It might be fun to play something like this once but this would not be a good game.
Rym: It is not polished It doesn't work really.
Scott: this is a this is a novelty and a a cool sort of like proof of concept.
Scott: But it's you know in terms of technology It's not something you would actually play for fun for awesome, but basically watch the first half and you think oh, that's a good idea.
Rym: It's as good of an idea as like Kirby's Canvas curse.
Rym: I'd love to see someone take that idea and make a really polished game with it.
Scott: Okay, I think Kirby's Canvas curse is a better game than that.
Scott: Oh, but the idea like the how they should make a sequel to the frickin Canvas curse got to make it on the Wii They should make they should make a DS sequel and on the Wii.
Rym: But I'm just talking about like the idea of a platformer where you control characters.
Rym: something like this is pretty cool and I think it's a solid idea, but Keep watching after you think oh I get this because after he beats that the second half of the video is basically alright.
Rym: I've got this idea, and I showed you what I was thinking about it.
Rym: now I'm gonna do something crazy and silly just for fun, and it's pretty crazy and silly.
Scott: yeah, it's good stuff Alright, so you know when you go to the craft store There's that whole section of the craft store.
Scott: This is well.
Scott: first of all the most popular part of the craft store nowadays seems to be the scrapbooking.
Scott: I don't know what the hell's up with those people.
Scott: all right.
Scott: But the other second most popular part of the craft store is I guess it's a tie between the cake Decorating and the flower arranging.
Rym: right I think flower arranging is a lot more space at most craft stores.
Scott: Yeah, well, I think that's just cuz it takes more space.
Scott: You know the cake decorating is smaller bits.
Rym: Well it also depends on what craft store you go to.
Scott: that's true different craft stores at different stuff.
Rym: but I mean regardless there wasn't so much cake decorating at the Pirates booty.
Scott: no, but you know the the Pirates booty.
Scott: remember that craft store that was called the Treasure Island.
Scott: Oh, yeah, yeah I don't know where I thought pirates booty right, but anyway.
Rym: I've store.
Rym: We didn't know it was a craft store.
Scott: They did have cake decorating them, but not a lot.
Scott: Yeah, there's a store called Treasure Island.
Scott: We're like what the hell's that story.
Scott: final pass.
Scott: We finally went to it.
Scott: It was a craft store.
Rym: Yeah, we I don't know what I was expecting some sort of amusement.
Scott: Too many craft stores you have like three.
Rym: yeah, it's something so that well that one's gone now right, but the Cake decorating is pretty popular.
Scott: And you know cake decorating is not is mostly for old ladies except for when you make nerdy cakes.
Rym: It's not the way it goes with everything.
Scott: I mean yes knitting old ladies unless you knit a blooper head exactly, so The here are some of the best cake decorating I've seen and it is cupcakes.
Scott: actually and it's an array of cupcakes that when you put them together One of them makes a Mario scene and these are his pictures and the other one makes a pac-man scene.
Scott: And you know I mean okay deck cake decorating a scene of a pac-man.
Scott: You know that's cool little ghosties little little pellets little you know map little power pellets a little pac-man, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's not really that exciting, but the quality of this cake decorating.
Scott: This is like expert.
Scott: Well.
Scott: It's not expert cake decorating.
Scott: I've seen professional cake decorators make crazy shit.
Scott: That'll just blow your mind, but this is you know as good as it gets without being professional And it's it's really just the level of detail that goes into this is the highest quality.
Rym: and to speak for how I guess.
Rym: Good, this is I did see it.
Rym: You know today and Scott told me about yeah I've already seen that and I didn't see it on some nerdy blog.
Rym: I didn't see it and like whatever Scott found it on I saw it on Google News while I was looking for something unrelated.
Scott: Are you sure?
Scott: yes?
Rym: I'm absolutely sure there was a link to it on Google News.
Scott: Wow cuz it was just.
Scott: it was just flicker galleries.
Rym: Yeah, granted.
Rym: That's not saying a lot because Google News links to a lot of interesting news sources, but I did find that.
Scott: yeah So check these out.
Rym: you will be impressed if you like Mario or pac-man, but yeah, I think on that note We have something much more important to talk about.
Rym: so we've been doing gig nights for years now And I can't believe we never thought to talk about this.
Scott: well It it's sort of rough because what's the real point of like reviewing something so old?
Scott: I mean I can tell you very clearly I think what it is is that you know It's.
Scott: it's tough to think to review or talk about something if it's to the point where if you don't know everything that we're already Going to say in this episode then how the fuck you a listener.
Scott: It's like you're not even someone I would look at.
Scott: well then again like an unlookable.
Rym: there are different.
Rym: I mean I think we'll get to it but you can definitely tell what a video game era someone was from by what they might remember about this game.
Rym: because There is one era of video gamers who remember this game is that game that used to have Mike Tyson in it.
Rym: And there's another era of video gamers who say yeah, that's that remake of the other game, and then there's the era of video gamers.
Rym: So yeah, that's that game.
Rym: That was the only one ever to use the MMC to memory manager.
Scott: I was waiting to see how long in the episode would take for Rym to bring up his favorite piece of obscure Nintendo knowledge.
Rym: it's not obscure.
Rym: pretty much everyone from our generation knew if they subscribed to Nintendo power because Nintendo power one day had an article and they were like History of the Nintendo and how the Nintendo worked and had a page that showed what the Nintendo is capable of Before the MMCs the memory manager chips.
Scott: Yep, think about think about all the Nintendo Entertainment System games out there.
Scott: Oh, I'm gonna introduce the game now.
Scott: watch this all right all the Nintendo Entertainment System games you could think of.
Scott: right Now a lot of what a Nintendo game is is actually in the cartridge more than it is in the system itself.
Scott: Right because look at like the Super Nintendo was the same way Star Fox had the FX chip You know and even the Sega Genesis was the same way.
Scott: We're like Virtua Racing had this big cartridge on it Because you could do a lot more in the cartridge.
Scott: you could get more out of the game system by putting more chips in the cartridge.
Scott: so in The olden days all the cartridges use the same chip and you got games like Super Mario Brothers Duck Hunt ice hockey right sort of low resolution not very big games.
Scott: You know I mean some games really pushed it like Metroid really put Metroid using MMC.
Scott: Oh did it?
Rym: yes Okay, then let me put it.
Rym: I'll put it in much more.
Rym: These 7800 the Atari 7800 came out after the Famicom.
Rym: the NES came out After they were similarly powered the rip the reason the NES was capable of doing Mario 3 Eventually with the MMC 3. well basically the NES could address very little memory so you could have very very small games.
Rym: That was it so in these cartridges.
Rym: They were clever, and they said wait a minute.
Rym: What if I had a chip in each cartridge that would manage the memory for me?
Scott: So better than you know the other cartridge is good.
Rym: So say I can like right now to say the cartridge can hold 16 bits.
Rym: That's gonna be a shitty game, but my cartridge has 16 bits.
Rym: I can only access 16 bits of stuff.
Rym: So that the whole letter A and the letter B the whole game has to be in that 16 bits.
Scott: So there ain't letter B.
Rym: But what if my computer can only access 16 bits, but I have those bits?
Rym: instead access a chip and that chip accesses hundreds of bits and it swaps through Sets of those bits in 16-bit increments and feeds into the Nintendo Via that 16-bit bus or that 16-bit interface What it can.
Rym: so you can have a much bigger game coming through that little interface?
Scott: Yep So games like I guess Metroid and others Mario 2 right and so pretty much every game anyone remembers from the NES used a memory Manager.
Scott: right, but they were.
Scott: those are games using the MMC one games like Kirby's Adventure and games like Mario 3.
Scott: We're using the MMC 3 the most superior chip Don't?
Rym: I don't think you want to get into the the talk of which game used which because there's a bunch of Surprises in there.
Scott: I know I know but there was only one game to use the MMC to the MMC.
Rym: The thing is that the MMC chips each one had different capabilities And if you remember that Nintendo Power article Then you'll know exactly what I'm talking about.
Scott: some of you might even remember Exactly which chips could do what and there are articles on the internet that explain this in much greater detail than we're going to because We want to talk about this game.
Rym: But the thing is basically the MMC 2 is the punch-out chip because it the way it allowed you to have sprites on the screen And the way it allowed you to do things Was exactly what they needed to make a game like punch-out.
Rym: That's why punch-out is so great.
Scott: I mean look at punch-out look how different it is from every other NES game.
Scott: the characters They're so big and they have lots of different parts to their gigantic sprites with lots of you know not necessarily high resolution, you know, but high quality and Varying and very quickly animated sprites.
Rym: There's a lot of stuff moving on the screen.
Rym: I mean the audience is moving in the background.
Rym: Mario can come out little mags jumping up and down.
Rym: There's also the bar at the top with you know the score and the status and the health and everything you can wipe screens to the the other shots in the between the periods or the rounds.
Scott: you got the bicycle action you got the Anyway Yeah, and that was only possible with the MMC 2. and really though the MMC 2 wasn't too useful for if you weren't making a Game that was kind of like that.
Rym: Well, there are other reasons why it wasn't used more widely.
Scott: But yeah, no, they didn't make punch-out to like they should have for the NES.
Rym: Suffice to say the The.
Rym: if you didn't know that that this is kind of one of those pieces of trivia that every Nintendo fanboy knows.
Rym: So yep now you can stand tall stand proud and say yes.
Rym: Why did you know dear friends that Mike Tyson's punch-out was the only game ever to use the MMC 2 chip in the Nintendo?
Rym: Entertainment system lovely bloody blur.
Rym: and they'll either say well, yes, obviously, you're one of us or they'll say what?
Scott: What what the so?
Scott: Mike Tyson's punch-out greatest boxing game ever.
Scott: No question.
Rym: Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Rym: I mean I For this game as such nostalgic value for me an independent of that.
Scott: It's still good.
Scott: Great game.
Rym: I mean if you take a kid today and have him play it They'll probably enjoy it a lot probably a lot more than any other boxing game out there.
Rym: Yeah, Aki for the Sega.
Scott: But I mean even like brand new boxing games that they're coming out with today that are super realistic in 3d They're all suck their complete shit compared in the face of Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Rym: now Very briefly Mike Tyson's punch-out is a game where you're a little Mac.
Rym: little Mac is apparently three feet tall.
Scott: Well, he's not three feet tall.
Scott: He's normal height.
Rym: So you're your little Mac and you're like five feet tall and You want to become the heavyweight boxing champion of the world and
Scott: you train really
Rym: hard and it turns out that every other boxer in The world is 12 feet tall
Scott: even the shittiest boxer in all of boxing who is only he was never even won.
Scott: Or maybe one once glass Joe from France.
Scott: last Joe from France.
Scott: Even though he's a wuss and he's like old and weak.
Scott: He's still like twice your size.
Scott: Maybe three and a half times your size And he's the first guy And you got to beat him up without getting your shit kicked out of you.
Rym: The game was just so perfectly put together and gameplay aside the I think what really makes this game stand out is just the charm and the style and how each character is.
Rym: just so I mean racist.
Rym: maybe You cannot help but look at soda Popinski and sing that think damn there's a man who likes his soda.
Scott: There's a man from Russia.
Scott: That's what I think.
Rym: I think in the original arcade game.
Rym: He was he was not so much the soda He was about something else some Beverage that perhaps Nintendo was not too keen on promoting the Vodak Right, but his head is shaped like a bottle of soda pop.
Scott: so Anyway, the game is great basically for two reasons.
Scott: You only need well, I guess the music is great, right?
Scott: That's a good reason.
Scott: The controls are dead on.
Scott: I guess, you know, I had a little problem with dodging when I was a kid But I don't know.
Scott: I don't have any problem with it now.
Rym: So I guess that was just like ten times better at this game now than I was as a kid.
Scott: Yes for sure But basically the gameplay itself was great.
Scott: You had both the offense and the defense.
Scott: you had to both dodge the opponent, right?
Scott: You had to but you also had to hit the opponent and you know, the hitting was fun.
Scott: The dodging was fun, but it was very simple.
Scott: you only had five moves jump up hit high with the left high with the right low with the left low with the right and The super attack which is press start which is.
Scott: it was sort of annoying to have to push start.
Scott: They should have had it be like a and B at the same time.
Scott: I think start it's nice it works just fine, but it could be a little bit.
Rym: I think that was a limitation of the.
Rym: I mean remember Part of the revolution of the Super Nintendo was that they added some goddamn buttons.
Scott: They sure did.
Scott: they sure did but yeah The other moves you had were like dodge left dodge right duck and block and that was it.
Scott: There's so few moves in this game and your opponents each opponent had crazy different moves and they do all sorts of weird stuff.
Scott: and really the gameplay is just learning the patterns of the enemies and then figuring out what you had to do to defeat those patterns and then Looking for the visual cues and perhaps audio cues as to what you know pattern move They were going to start doing so you would be able to counter it.
Scott: And then the other half of the gameplay is push the buttons fast enough because like you fight piston Honda And he's pretty dangerous.
Scott: if you suck You fight him again, and he does mostly the same moves changes them up a little bit But he's twice as fast and it's twice as hard because you might know the pattern, but you don't push the button fast enough He's gonna make you right in the face.
Rym: Okay, so uh soda Popinski's original name from the 1985 punch-out arcade game.
Rym: you know what it was.
Rym: you want to know what it was what it's?
Rym: uh, it's kind of epic all right vodka drunkenski?
Scott: Yeah, you know Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Scott: vodka drunkenski.
Rym: I'm not making this up.
Scott: Mike Tyson's punch-out for the NES is the game that everyone has nostalgia for.
Scott: but there was a punch-out a plain old non Mike Tyson punch-out that came out in the arcades before that and I've seen this machine.
Scott: I've never actually played the machine because I've never seen a working one or one that was working well enough But it was.
Scott: it's a very strange machine I don't know.
Scott: maybe we can find a picture of it online or something, but it's not like other arcade machines.
Scott: I don't know how well it plays but Apparently it still had the charm of the racist stereotype characters from around the world.
Rym: Oh, yeah Well, there's see there were actually two of them 1984 1985.
Rym: The characters in Mike Tyson's punch-out and mr.
Rym: Dream can die in a fire.
Rym: Yeah We're drawn from both of these.
Rym: punch-out in 1984 had glass Joe piston hurricane bald bull Pizza pasta.
Scott: Oh, I want to fight pizza pasta kid quick.
Rym: and mr.
Rym: Sandman.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Sandman is a fucking dangerous motherfucker.
Scott: He will put you out.
Rym: and the 1985 one had bear hugger dragon-chan or dragon-chan Who is actually Bruce Lee and apparently is a kickbox bear huggers the second guy in super punch-out, which we'll talk about sooner.
Rym: No, well, this is super punch-out the arcade game.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Okay vodka junkins key Grey tiger and super macho.
Scott: I played super punch-out in the arcade and it was pretty much identical of the Super Nintendo one But it was the arcade.
Scott: so that must have been a much like a 90s super punch-out.
Rym: 1985 When this was come this came out.
Scott: Well, I didn't play that one.
Scott: I must have played a different super punch-out arcade that came out in the 90s.
Scott: But anyway, there was a. So Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Scott: the gameplay is great because it's just these simple patterns the your reaction times.
Rym: It's so simple, but so elegant and so beautiful like it's a game that once you have Mastered it once you are able to beat all of the opponents then there's not really fun to play anymore.
Rym: Luckily Not many people have mastered the game to that degree.
Rym: So it's fun for pretty much everyone.
Scott: Yeah even though I'm really good at it like I can get to like the Second bald bull fight and then it starts getting hard and sometimes I'll lose.
Rym: I think everyone who had this game as a kid remembers that you'd fight and fight and fight and you'd always do Okay like you'd get over a hump and then you'd beat a bunch of people like nothing and Then you'd hit piston Honda the second time and that was the fucking end.
Scott: no, no, I know a secret to beating him now.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but before you knew that secret.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah When you get to Sona Popinski is when it starts to get a little bit difficult.
Rym: Of course, I think the funniest thing was I Scott apparently did not know until Yesterday that you can be Don Flamenco pretty much without having to do anything.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I just kind of beat him up.
Scott: Normally, you know, it's it's weird.
Scott: I like that's.
Scott: the other great thing about this game is that you know there there's patterns You can follow to beat guys.
Scott: But there's actually for the easier guys in the game and some of the harder guys in the game.
Scott: There's sort of like other clever things you can do.
Scott: like for example, who's the German guy you fight right away?
Scott: Oh Von Kaiser right when you fight von Kaiser, right?
Scott: He does this move where he'll duck down into the left and then he'll do an uppercut, right?
Scott: So the the the the moron who doesn't know how to play will just get hit by the uppercut or block it.
Rym: Maybe they'll be smarter and they'll duck it or dodge it.
Scott: But right or dodge it the slightly better player will dodge it then immediately hit him in the face.
Scott: Thus stunning him allowing you to hit him in the face a few more times, right?
Scott: The super advanced player will actually do a low punch to the left while he's ducking to the left.
Scott: You can hit him while he's ducking down there and that will get you a star and which you can then dodge his next uppercut and use the star on him and knock him down.
Scott: and It that's it's really good.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: You know you have it's.
Scott: it's not just one of those games.
Scott: you memorize the pattern and then react to the pattern.
Scott: quickly enough The pattern you can actually mix it up.
Scott: You can choose different moves get a little bit of strategy in there Try something more clever and usually the more daring the more difficult patterns usually give you the better rewards.
Rym: I think I mean that's what makes the game great.
Rym: is that and I think a lot of game designers forget this fact and a Game does not have to be terribly complex to be a great game.
Rym: What you have to do is Figure out what you want the game to be.
Rym: Make the game complex enough to provide what you wanted and then perfect that.
Scott: yeah I noticed this is really really evident in a lot of sports games across the board, you know, look at ice hockey, right?
Scott: What are the buttons in ice hockey?
Scott: shoot pass?
Scott: Hit somebody right that.
Scott: what else do you need?
Scott: modern hockey games?
Scott: They give you all these extra buttons.
Scott: hit them this way.
Scott: hit them that way go faster.
Scott: You don't need those buttons all you need.
Rym: I think this is why the pass and shoot Nintendo sports games always seem to come out on time for.
Scott: look even today Even the crazy Madden people if you ask them was the best football game ever.
Scott: they will all say like Tecmo Super Bowl for the NES because it just it had Enough of a football game in there to be a football game.
Scott: Recognizedly football and fun.
Scott: as football I mean if you know they're putting in too much, but you know how to play football.
Rym: Even if you barely know how to play football you can sit down and play that game and have a good time.
Scott: Yeah Now you play like Madden and you have to know all these extra controls like dodge to the left dodge to the right spin Dive all these different things.
Scott: Just give me run away from the guy or lateral.
Scott: Those are the really only buttons you need, you know.
Scott: Making it more complex than that makes the game You know less accessible and less fun and punch-out is still better than any, you know People have come out with these super realistic Boxing games.
Scott: or you can throw punches exactly where you want to and do all sorts of different crazy moves and actually control walking around the ring in 3d and None of them respond as punch-out not even close by a mile.
Scott: yet punch-out is the much simpler game And I really think we'd be very well served if somebody made another game That was not any more complex than punch-out.
Scott: just throw in new characters and different patterns.
Rym: I think punch-out has enough complexity to work.
Rym: I would love to see people on the internet to start hacking this ROM.
Scott: Of course the people keep hacking all these other ROMs like making you know why they're probably not.
Scott: yeah, damn you MMC - damn you MC - but yeah people hack the mario 3s and they make new levels.
Scott: No, it'd be like Super Nintendo games.
Rym: It would be easier just to remake this game.
Rym: I've already reverse engineered it in my head.
Rym: I know how it works.
Scott: Yeah, it's not difficult.
Rym: I Interesting characters.
Rym: it would take me years to get bored with it.
Scott: Yeah If you just kept give coming up with new characters with new moves and new racism's and new racism's Then you could just play punch-out forever and ever as long as the new guys aren't lame.
Rym: Yes, I mean think this is the game that brought us king hippo.
Rym: Yep, a lot of people don't remember that this is working.
Rym: hippo came from.
Rym: they watch captain n and king hippo was there.
Rym: He was just some fat Filipino guy Filipino really?
Rym: I think he's Hawaiian.
Scott: He's Hawaiian.
Scott: I think no.
Rym: hippo island Pacific.
Scott: he's Hawaiian whatever.
Rym: He's from hippo island.
Rym: He's hippo.
Scott: I'm sure Who is everyone?
Scott: They're fat.
Scott: Anyway, you're my I think he's.
Rym: uh, if you live on hippo island, you'd better be fat.
Scott: I think the guy who played king hippo is the same guy who played the chief and star traffic.
Scott: But yet so there was also.
Scott: So punch-out is perhaps the greatest is no it's definitely the greatest boxing game ever because excellent gameplay excellent music Excellent characters and and bald bull because pretty much every kid would die on bald bull the second times.
Rym: you even the first time When you never feels dangerous the first time if you didn't know you're doing.
Rym: what I'm saying is a new player like you're.
Rym: you're playing This game and like I'm gonna beat this game.
Rym: Don flamenco is a was some.
Rym: king hippo is easy once you figure them out and great tigers pretty easy.
Scott: But great tiger used to fuck me up because I didn't know what to do about his Crazy spin move, you know, see I knew exactly what to do as long as he had enough life.
Rym: I was okay, but bald bull The thing was when you beat him that laughs.
Rym: the way he reacts when he wins is frightening.
Scott: I suggest if you're if you think you're really good at punch-out and you might be right go play it again But on purpose.
Scott: lose to everyone.
Rym: lose every fight except glass jokes doesn't do anything, right?
Scott: Lose to the lose to Don Kaiser then beat him and lose to piston Honda then beat him and lose to Don flamenco.
Scott: Because they do funny races things.
Scott: when they beat you they like they do their taunt like ha ha ha I'm better than you and they're all really funny and you don't want to miss any of them.
Scott: Alright, so you want some a super punch out?
Rym: Sorry.
Rym: I'm just.
Rym: I've been staring at this animated gif of Soba soda Popinski's face And he's just drinking and it says pop on that bottle.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Alright, so super punch-out for the Super Nintendo was Technologically superior to the first punch-out, right?
Scott: You had that.
Scott: the guys you were fighting were now like ten times the size of you instead of like three.
Rym: Would you like to have some punch to drink?
Scott: Yeah, the star meter works a little differently.
Scott: like yet this power-up meter on the bottom and you know It's kind of it was a little different.
Scott: You had a lot more a few more moves you could do even though it was generally the same set of moves.
Scott: You know, the gameplay was basically the same, you know dodge then hit the guy.
Scott: dodge and hit the guy.
Scott: only it got much harder And basically, you know, it was the graphics are superior.
Scott: The audio was better.
Scott: The guys would say things occasionally like, you know, the first guy you fight is not glass Joe It's Gabby J and he's like Gabby J. Yeah, like he says his name when you fight him and it's it's good stuff.
Scott: It's not a bad game.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it doesn't have sort of that retro charm of the original punch-out.
Scott: Of course, it was weird that the original punch-out had retro charm even when it was brand-new.
Rym: I think part of it is that the way it's presented is like the Super a lot of the newer boxing games.
Rym: They always have like a transparent generic guy as you.
Rym: but Punch-out Mike Tyson's punch-out had little Mac and he's this little guy and you're so little and it's not like this first person.
Rym: I am playing a boxing game or I'm a wireframe dude with green hair.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: I am watching Little Mac and Little Mac's gonna win.
Rym: cuz Little Mac's got guts.
Scott: I just had to.
Scott: I just recalled that Perry Bobble fellowship.
Scott: I'm ready to take on the world doc.
Scott: I feel ready.
Scott: I'm ready to take on the world pop.
Scott: And then doc just do this mouth open.
Rym: but there's just this feeling from punch-out that Little Mac can do it and the fact that his body blows he punches and If you want to hit him in the face He jumps into the air and puts his little fist up and pegs the guy.
Rym: and when that little dude knocks down someone eight times his size You feel something there.
Scott: It's it's like a miracle.
Rym: also the music god damn Did that game have some great music for the NES?
Scott: All right.
Rym: I think there's a reason that the music and punch-out has been so remix.
Scott: Yes, super super punch-out doesn't really quite have the same epic music.
Scott: It just kind of has average SNES music as better sound effects though, you know.
Scott: But it's it's also less racist in some ways.
Rym: The characters just weren't as Caricatured they weren't as awesome.
Rym: I don't know it didn't.
Scott: yeah I mean they had like, you know bear hugger they had super macho man was still in there and they were kind of funny guys.
Scott: But they were less racist I guess which I guess could be a good thing in some ways, but they're also just less Appealing less awesome you don't remember.
Scott: I mean seriously Do you remember the guys who were the bosses in any of the boxers some super punch-out?
Scott: Not too many of them because they're not memorable.
Scott: Every guy in the first punch-out was memorable very memorable and very hilarious in their own way except for the kids who never Got past the second ball bowl.
Rym: Yeah, cuz they never saw soda popinski.
Rym: I had a lot of friends as kids who didn't even know soda popinski existed.
Scott: Well, well they had to.
Scott: you had to know that Mike Tyson's the last guy.
Scott: so oh, yeah or mr Dream, but yeah and super punch-out.
Scott: basically you fight in these like, you know, there's different, you know Championships and like each one is for guys and after you beat all of them a new one opens up and the the ones Before the new ones opens up are actually kind of playable.
Scott: But the one that that last one is like freaking impossible without cheating.
Scott: I cheated to beat it and though this basically the last two guys like these two brothers and You first fight one brother and then the even harder brother and damn they are fucking danger.
Scott: Like you can't beat them.
Scott: Basically, it's it's close to impossible And yet it's not.
Scott: it's a good game.
Scott: still.
Scott: I mean if you like punch-out and you need more super punch-out is where you're gonna get more but at the same time It's not as good.
Rym: It's not gonna do it for you.
Rym: You're gonna play that game.
Scott: You're gonna go right back to Mike Tyson's punch-out, which is available on the virtual console, but they changed Mike Tyson into mr Dream.
Rym: they changed it into mr.
Rym: Dream on every iteration.
Rym: There's a lot of talk about why they did that But from what I've heard it had nothing to do with anything Mike Tyson did.
Rym: they just didn't want to re-up Probably because he wasn't the champion anymore by the time they did Whatever.
Scott: Mike Tyson, you know for all the bad things that Mike Tyson has done in his life You have to respect his boxing talents that he had in the past.
Rym: I recommend I think we've said this before But if you don't know anything about boxing Go search for some random boxing videos on YouTube just to you know to get a sense of them.
Scott: go
Rym: watch a bunch of random ones right and then go watch a Mike Tyson video
Scott: and then go watch Muhammad Ali and
Rym: Mike Tyson's scary because it's like no normal box is like ding and then they start boxing Mike Tyson It was like ding and then the other guy is just against the ropes being pounded on.
Scott: yeah, I mean as Gruesome as boxing is and whatever you have to say about it as a sport like watching the great boxers do their thing.
Scott: It's like the way their bodies move is like this amazing thing That is like not to be a great boxer is is not even in the same class as other boxers.
Rym: like great boxers boxing Against normal boxers is like me trying to do kendo against katsu.
Scott: Yeah, seriously There's a this.
Scott: if you search for Muhammad Ali on YouTube There's gonna be this one black and white video that shows up and that's like the best boxing ever seen in my life.
Scott: He just oh he throws so many punches so quickly.
Rym: It's Kind of frightening.
Scott: it's incredibly frightening.
Rym: cuz then you see if like Scott little Mac is 17 years old He's four foot eight 107 pounds.
Rym: Go little Mac go from Bronx.
Scott: Go to Mac.
Rym: He's from the Bronx.
Scott: represent Both day guy.
Rym: I can't win doc.
Rym: He's hurt me doc.
Scott: Oh There's also the Selectric.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you know what?
Rym: There's a note about that in the instruction book.
Scott: What does it say?
Rym: The Selectric wasn't really a trick.
Rym: It was part of the game.
Rym: all right, you can hold select between our rounds of a boxing match and Doc Lewis will massage you faster to get your health back.
Rym: Yeah, it also weakens your punches.
Scott: Yeah Yeah but yet the Well punch out.
Scott: I think it's another thing about punch out is the way in which the controls Like sort of matched what was going on?
Scott: like you push B the left-hand button right to punch of the left hand and a to hit with the right hand and Then when you got knocked down you would push a and B a whole lot to try to get back up.
Scott: You know in that rapid pushing of the buttons while you were trying to get up made you it sort of brought you close to Little Mac like get up.
Rym: Come on There is also this kind of end game.
Rym: where are?
Rym: you can beat the game now beat it better because you can get TKOs.
Rym: You can knock people over three times, which is how you beat most people but you can knock out every single person in this game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean most of the guy.
Scott: like I was saying before, you know when you fight guys there's ways to beat them up in which you know you just sort of dodge and then beat them up and Then dodge and beat them up and that's sort of like the basic strategy and it works.
Scott: You'll beat most of the guys that way but you won't get knockouts.
Scott: You'll knock them out three times in a single round and then Mario come out and just say TKO Which means you still win.
Scott: it's a technical knockout, right?
Rym: But
Scott: if there's a way to actually knock every guy out in the game to make him stay down for ten whole seconds And then you win and I only know how to do it for maybe like five or six guys
Rym: No,
Scott: oh, you can't fail to knock out King hip-hut now.
Scott: Well, unless you die I guess if you beat him if you knock him down, he can't get up.
Rym: He's so fat now, uh, hmm, I Have one very important warning for all of you.
Rym: I mentioned Captain and the game master a little while ago.
Rym: if you don't know what that is Don't look it up.
Rym: And if you do know what that is, and you haven't watched it since you became an adult don't not Do not go back and try to watch that show.
Rym: That's like he-man.
Scott: like when I was a kid I loved he-man and then when I was older I had forgotten what he-man actually was.
Scott: But I remembered liking he-man as a kid.
Scott: So I tried to re I tried to go back and when the internet finally gave me the ability I got some he-man and I went back and I saw the he-man that I remembered loving as a child and I wish I had not Because he-man sucks.
Rym: see She-Ra was actually far superior.
Scott: It was far superior, but it still wasn't that good.
Rym: No.
Rym: No, but Captain N really really takes the cake for being bad.
Scott: Oh, it is so bad.
Rym: I mean watch that and the Super Mario Brothers Super Show suddenly becomes a whole lot better.
Scott: Super Mario Brothers Super Show becomes Shakespeare compared to Captain N.
Rym: Oh Wow someone made Little Mac's diary.
Rym: Wow, wow The 16-page diary, okay, okay, okay, so get punch out.
Scott: Oh, it's kind of cute.
Rym: Oh, it's kind of never mind.
Rym: It's not.
Scott: they should make punch out DS.
Scott: Yes, they should versus Versus punch out and I don't know that would work.
Rym: thing is versus punch out would only work if One you have to get a little bit more control.
Rym: You'd have to be able to like at least Like say hey get this.
Rym: say you could take your guy and customize and pick the nose pick the face You make a caricature stereotype for your dude.
Rym: All right, and then You have a list of kinds of moves and you can like set them up.
Rym: So like if I do a right like the controls wouldn't be any different you set it up.
Rym: So if I do a like a right body blow It does the Kaiser body blow or it does the mr Dream body blow and you can mix it up and make your custom character and then box like you choose from a set of moves.
Scott: You know, the problem is right.
Scott: How would that work?
Scott: Cuz what?
Scott: oh, you know, I think it has to be Little Mac.
Rym: You know, I'd make it work.
Rym: I see my screen.
Rym: on my screen I'm Little Mac and I just box like normal.
Rym: and on your screen your Little Mac and you just box like it's just.
Rym: it's just Skinny.
Scott: that might work.
Rym: It's just Little Mac versus Little Mac.
Scott: It might work.
Scott: It might work for five bucks.
Rym: I'd play that.
Scott: yeah for sure.
Rym: Thing is in the end.
Rym: You really we just need more.
Scott: Stereotyped characters need to come out and be a don't have to be racist But they do the cat what.
Scott: this game really wouldn't work if the characters themselves weren't so endearing and memorable.
Scott: You need to really get awesome characters like.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.