Rym: It's Tuesday, May 6th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is a geeky knives tonight.
Rym: Do we talk about to the Mario counter for the Wii?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I feel bad saying it again, but I'm really liking River City Ransom again.
Scott: Hey, when did you stop liking it?
Rym: I never stopped liking it.
Scott: How did you like it again?
Rym: It's more that it's a game that I know Possibly more so than most other games.
Rym: I've ever played a game that I've.
Rym: I've probably put more hours into that than many other games.
Scott: I actually I like River City Ransom a lot, but I haven't put that many hours into it.
Rym: Well, did you own it?
Rym: No, no, there you go.
Scott: I emulated it pretty much until now what I'm I guess Legally emulating it But I played it at a friend's house and I actually bought it like we got it when it came out.
Rym: It was expensive and that game was like the best game ever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that was the kind of game that was sorta, you know under the radar in my neck of the woods In my childhood days, which is pretty sad.
Rym: cuz what the hell games were you playing?
Scott: I probably would have played the hell out of it if I had it.
Rym: What were you playing?
Rym: Like what was your hot game then?
Scott: probably like Kung Fu Heroes wide series, which is good But it's not River City Ransom.
Scott: It's not so great, but it has the good music.
Rym: Doo, doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: compared to River City Ransom's music It's a little worse than that, but it's not bad.
Scott: I mean just because your music isn't as good as every city ran.
Scott: So doesn't mean your music's bad.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I might have to.
Scott: that's like just because you're not worth as much as gold.
Rym: You're poor pretty much at this point now.
Rym: Yeah But tell us over the weekend.
Rym: We had the visigoths over played some Burning Wheel.
Scott: well anyway except for Scott I didn't play burning.
Scott: well I worked on shit for you people and for me.
Scott: so yeah you make a video yet um I'm getting I'm getting to it.
Rym: yeah we'll see.
Scott: hopefully this weekend this weekend for sure if it doesn't like rain or something.
Rym: but it was kind of like we had this sudden explosion of dungeon mastering or I guess.
Rym: I guess we've outgrown the term dungeon master.
Rym: I think we really have to say GM now because we play games.
Rym: in fact we still say yeah it's D&D weekend even though we're not playing D&D.
Rym: we'll probably never play D&D again except to try out kind of maybe fourth edition so I can make the inevitable review if I don't have to buy the books.
Scott: you know I could do like D&D one-shot kind of deals if you know the time is right.
Scott: of course I'd rather do inspectors lacuna paranoia something else.
Rym: well it's funny because suddenly Scott's all about running a primetime adventure.
Scott: well I realized well cuz I finally got all the books.
Scott: I just went out and I bought all the books for all those indie RPGs like and you know dogs in the vineyard.
Scott: I'm a little tired night tonight.
Scott: dogs in the vineyard puppies for Satan kill puppies for Satan which is you know famous.
Rym: well kill puppies for Satan is one of those games like Hall where you don't actually want to play.
Scott: playing that at least once.
Rym: oh everyone says they'll play Hall at least once too and then they realize that there isn't really a game in there playing at least once.
Scott: if we played kobolds eat my babies once in a half times we're gonna play this getting something.
Rym: kobolds ate my babies had a rudimentary game system within.
Rym: this is a relatively short system yes but it's much longer.
Rym: of course it's not nearly as long as Hall no but anyway and if any of you want something fun to read you're into tabletop gaming.
Rym: I'd recommend picking up if you can find at the old source book for Hall.
Rym: it stands for human occupied landfill.
Rym: anyway you get one of those cameras on your head that blows up if it sees anything obscene.
Rym: good luck peeing.
Scott: I'm gonna search for that on eBay right now.
Rym: but we realize that primetime adventures is pretty much the best way to run a besom game.
Rym: ever forget besom.
Scott: yeah I mean basically besom is an old role-playing game called it's B. it's called besom because it's B e SM big eyes small mouth and it's sort of it's the anime role-playing game like there's a try gun supplement and slayers supplement and a tenchi supplement.
Scott: right and the idea was that you buy this and you be able to roleplay as your favorite anime characters or in your favorite anime universes or in a generic anime universe like there are rules for giant robots and rules for magical girl.
Rym: now used to be.
Rym: I mean you know there's all the different kinds of I guess classes of role-playing systems.
Rym: it was the tristad system which wasn't that bad kind of simple but simple in the kind of AD&D way where there's a simple core mechanic and then a billion piles of shit all around it.
Rym: but I actually played a new tenant online role-playing game that used the same system and it worked okay.
Rym: but it was kind of like why I guess I didn't realize it way back then.
Rym: but yeah if you want to play an anime game you got to use besom and if you want to play a dungeon II game you got to use D&D and then now wait a minute.
Rym: why don't we just use primetime adventures to play an anime game present besom socks and d20 besoms?
Rym: even worse.
Scott: yeah primetime adventures is designed to be a role-playing game where you create a serial television show of either five or nine episodes.
Rym: huh television show.
Scott: why can't we just do an anime?
Scott: well the answer is there's no reason.
Scott: you can't absolutely can.
Scott: in fact that will be awesome.
Rym: besom didn't really create.
Rym: like an anime like game.
Scott: besom created an anime show but like stereotypes to 11 besom created basically a D&D game where you happen to be anime characters.
Rym: no you've ever played besom.
Scott: I read the book.
Rym: which book?
Rym: d20?
Scott: I don't know I don't remember.
Scott: it was a book I said besom on.
Scott: it was in the bathroom.
Rym: well besom you realize that people a lot of people play d20 besom which is just the same old crappy D&D three-point whatever edition but they skin it with anime cliches.
Scott: the original besom system at least the Star Wars d20 changed some shit up.
Scott: not much no but it added some shit on like the force and the ships and the such but it was all just for combat.
Scott: I know of course.
Scott: yeah well it's d20 but they don't have any other non rules for non combat.
Scott: what man?
Rym: at least back in the a D&D days they didn't pretend I mean what you had proficiencies and then you had non weapon proficiencies.
Rym: yeah but the original besom was just.
Rym: it played up the anime stereotypes but it did it in kind of a crappy way.
Rym: so why not just use a system that plays up stereotypes in general and run with it?
Scott: yeah yeah apparently hall came out in 94 but there was a reprint a newer edition in o2.
Scott: oh we we yeah and I had no idea me and this looking pretty.
Scott: maybe we should get it.
Scott: it's weird.
Rym: it's like me and Scott Johnson were the only people in the crew who remembered hall because I forget which one of us but one day I was like one of us said blah blah blah blah blah haha.
Rym: that's just like hall and the other one went haha and everyone else went.
Scott: what all right eBay.
Scott: old version $2 not bad.
Rym: new version $9.
Scott: by now $13.
Rym: I think I prefer the old version.
Scott: crazy Igor is selling one for 23 21. great anyway all right you want to go to the news action?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: my story was just that we had this explosion.
Rym: cuz Scott wants to run that game and I was.
Rym: I've been planning in building this gigantic Horatio horn blower style Napoleonic Wars burning wheel game.
Rym: but I've been running into the fact that because I'm not using medieval setting I'm kind of having to write a lot of game mechanics and make you know an entire working balanced system of life pads.
Rym: I got about a third of the way through that and said fuck this and I'm just gonna run a standard burning wheel game.
Scott: yeah you could do blossoms are falling.
Rym: I'm telling you no because one most of the people in our group have just barely barely gotten to the point where they're not completely just blindsided by burning wheel.
Rym: I'm not gonna introduce a completely different system on top of that.
Scott: yeah it's not completely different.
Rym: it's burning wheel plus plus a bunch of stuff that people aren't quite fully together with the whole doula witch thing.
Rym: so I'm not gonna introduce language mechanics all right but suffice to say I totally copped out.
Rym: and yeah my setting is yeah if you read the prince of nothing yeah holy war we're marching on shimmy go nuts.
Rym: great three to five life paths.
Rym: let's see what happens.
Scott: okay so news time I guess.
Rym: oh you're really dragging.
Scott: yeah wake up I saw the sleep on the choo-choo.
Rym: how could you be so tired?
Rym: you wake up hours after me.
Rym: you go to sleep early.
Scott: I gotta sleep way after you.
Rym: how about you?
Rym: how much sleep did you get last night?
Scott: less than six hours.
Rym: I get less than six hours almost every night.
Rym: anyway I'm on my mind.
Rym: my a penis is bigger than yours.
Rym: my stay up late college penis.
Rym: look how big it is.
Scott: that's not a good thing.
Scott: it's like a hideous hideous.
Rym: you know it's funny.
Rym: it's like that thread in the forum where people are talking about yeah I pulled an all-nighter and I thought back to yeah I used to pull all-nighters.
Scott: I used to pull all-nighters for when like something gets like you know when like your skin is swollen it's small it's hideous swollen mess.
Scott: but yeah all-nighters are not so much the funny to talk about but for real not funny.
Rym: anyway I remember we used to pull all-nighters for the hell of it in college like hey you want to watch cowboy bebop until we're done hells.
Scott: yeah well it was just like hey let's watch some cowboy bebop.
Scott: oh shit we watch it all fuck yeah.
Rym: but sometimes we say hey let's just stay up all night for no good reason and very rarely did good come of that.
Rym: no usually you know what came of that.
Rym: I missed the next three days of classes and I felt like shit for another week.
Scott: alright so news time what do you got?
Scott: oh boy there was the news a long time ago like Steven Spielberg's making a game.
Rym: I'd completely ignored it because why is Steven Spielberg's name on a game?
Scott: to sell it up of course because even if the game is terrible people might buy it based on the name and they could charge more for it.
Scott: oh you moved.
Scott: and then the news is like oh Steven Spielberg making an EA game like okay whatever it seems we're making an EA Wii game.
Scott: I'm like oh whatever it'll be interesting to see what it is.
Scott: well it's out.
Scott: now you can buy it in the store.
Scott: it's called boom blocks but the arcade was about.
Rym: yeah this game had completely fallen off my radar until I read penny arcade I was like oh yeah the game showed up.
Scott: I like two weeks ago or so.
Scott: I first realized that it existed and I was and I saw a video of it and I was like you know that actually looks like a really fun game.
Scott: and then I went an Amazon.
Scott: I said I'll buy that game.
Scott: it's at $50 and I'm like okay it's fun doesn't look $50?
Scott: fun you know and it'll be just as fun later as it is now.
Scott: so when Mario Kart is sort of worn out when Okami is worn out when Smash Brothers is worn out and there's a game trout I'll probably try to pick up bloom box for hopefully less than $30.
Rym: it's definitely one of those.
Rym: you got a bunch of people over I'd say a party and half the people will kind of crowd around the Wii and play that game.
Rym: will the other half the people?
Rym: I don't know go do whatever other people at parties do?
Scott: you aren't me sitting in front of the Wii but if you're if you're looking for a Wii party game this one looks like a high quality that will hold you over for quite a while.
Rym: one could almost say pry epic.
Scott: yeah after the Mario Kart and the Smash Brothers are worn out.
Scott: this is where to go.
Rym: I don't know if Mario Kart is gonna get worn out any time.
Scott: I didn't say soon.
Scott: I said when it could be next year like four years.
Scott: I mean it's gonna take a long time for the price of this game to go down from 50 to $30.
Scott: right?
Scott: so you know that's you know in Mario Kart and Smash Brothers are gonna last a lot longer than that.
Rym: so anyway oh well so there wasn't much gaming news I really cared about.
Rym: but now I realized something by going to Kotaku because I needed some news and there was nothing.
Rym: Wolfenstein the original FPS and someone's gonna mean Wolfenstein 3d.
Rym: well someone is immediately going to nitpick and say I wasn't the first F yet.
Rym: no it was the first FPS.
Rym: as far as anyone who cares is concerned that's right.
Scott: it's also the best FPS ever but it wasn't.
Rym: it was barely an FPS was awful shut up even when it came out.
Rym: I remember playing it as a kid.
Rym: it's beyond and thinking bad.
Rym: Wow this is almost a good game.
Rym: good and if only someone would take this idea and make a game with it.
Scott: go to see it's a great game.
Rym: play it well I'm gonna go play Wolfenstein right after the show.
Rym: no you're not.
Rym: yeah how you gonna change the controls?
Scott: I'm gonna use my little gamepad or use the mouse and keyboard.
Rym: I will see anyway box.
Rym: so Wolfenstein whatever it was the first FPS.
Rym: I can.
Rym: I contend that doom was the first I guess modern FPS.
Scott: I think quake 1 was the first modern FPS.
Rym: I don't know because the thing is doom was almost ahead of its time and that it was.
Rym: they couldn't really have the technology to make a fully 3d game yet.
Rym: so they made basically a three-dimensional game where it was actually two-dimensional and then the third dimension was just an integer.
Rym: and then they use clever tricks to use that integer to determine height and it it works really well.
Scott: you didn't have to game up and down.
Scott: it was not a modern FPS.
Rym: all right all right it was the precursor to them.
Rym: it was the first good FPS Wolfenstein 3d.
Scott: well the thing is Wolfenstein 3d was just a maze game.
Scott: it's amazing game fighting an FPS really.
Scott: I mean I had an FP and s-ing but it was mostly a maze.
Scott: find the secrets collect the treasure game.
Rym: yes go up to every picture of Hitler in its spacebar.
Scott: they go every slide along every single wall there possibly was and push the spacebar.
Rym: they do made the much better mechanic of jousting by wall running along the walls.
Rym: deathmatch yeah see it's the first real FPS because it was the first game that had deathmatch.
Scott: no no no you know.
Rym: actually I realize now that there are really make death matches anymore.
Scott: I played the half-life 2 deathmatch this week.
Rym: plays it though I try looked and there's like hardly any server.
Scott: I played in there.
Scott: plenty of servers we talking about.
Scott: there's plenty of people playing.
Rym: oh yeah but not as many as you'd expect.
Scott: no that not a whole bunch but there's plenty.
Rym: and you know what really saddens me though.
Rym: I turned on ricochet.
Rym: there was exactly one server that a ping of like 800.
Rym: I went there there was one bot and the bot was broken.
Rym: it was like the saddest experience of my life.
Scott: sad we should play some ricochet with the foreign peoples.
Rym: yeah ricochet is a damn good game.
Scott: you have half-life 1 you have ricochet.
Scott: it's in steam.
Scott: it shouldn't be cost any money I don't think.
Rym: but yeah today is the 16th anniversary of wolfin Stein 3d.
Scott: I'm 10 years older than Wolfenstein.
Rym: Wow I'm also 10 years older than Wolfenstein.
Scott: I guess Wolfenstein came out in 1992 something like that.
Rym: yeah wow it's amazing how quickly these things advance like that was then and it wasn't that long after the doom came out and then doom - well think about this.
Scott: Wolfenstein was 1992 right.
Scott: the end 64 I think was 1994.
Rym: by then 1996 I think by then pretty much from 1994 and a half was when I basically became a full-on PC gamer and I gave up on consoles and I continued to be given up on consoles right up until the end of the GameCube era.
Scott: yeah the end 64 was 96.
Rym: no you don't know I didn't really get back into console gaming until the DS came out.
Rym: when the DS came out I bought it.
Rym: it was the first console I owned since the SNES and the PlayStation was 94.
Scott: the end 64 is 96. so think about that in relation to Wolfenstein 3d in 92. whoa things in the 90s gaming basically within the span of 10 years went from - holy shit.
Scott: and it was really fast like it really felt like the.
Scott: you know the each system like lasted forever.
Rym: you know the only thing that didn't last forever was quake 1.
Rym: I remember playing quake 1 and then someone was like here's quake 2 the first good real.
Rym: finally it's here.
Rym: this is what an FPS should be.
Scott: yeah but yeah that's the in the night and like the 90s or remember it changed so fast.
Rym: that's dire battle between all that and Duke Nukem 3d which was actually when he damn good game.
Scott: when quake 1 and Duke Nukem 3d came out there was actually every game magazine was like Duke Nukem 3d or quake 1 which one is.
Scott: Duke Nukem 3d was infinitely better and technology wise it wasn't really but the deathmatch was game wise it was.
Rym: the only problem with the deathmatch was no one else owned that game.
Rym: so despite my cable modem I was pretty much forced to play against bots.
Rym: and I can tell you one thing in that game bots were basically insta kills if they saw you.
Rym: it was not fun yeah.
Scott: and then unreal sort of came along.
Rym: it was like this you know the second runner for a long time like my brother and I would start up a Wolfenstein 3d game and it'd be us and a bunch of bots and it would degenerate immediately into the game.
Rym: yeah Duke Nukem 3d?
Rym: yeah.
Rym: it'd be him and me like hiding in the bathroom praying to God that the boss didn't find us.
Rym: yeah but that's you hear him walking around.
Scott: that's why Duke Nukem Forever gets all this hype.
Scott: you know it's because that game didn't come out when it was supposed to.
Scott: it was probably the only reason that quake succeeded so much.
Scott: if that if Duke Nukem Forever would have come out on schedule quake 2 would have met with actual serious competition.
Rym: what if team forgers 2 and come out when they said it would have?
Rym: holy shit that would have.
Rym: I think gaming would have gone a different way FPS wise because that game was a lot more like the weapons factory mega TF kind of game than what we got instead.
Rym: yeah alright anyway that's all I got.
Rym: I don't know Scott's tired and there wasn't so much gaming news.
Rym: the matters are not really so.
Rym: what else to do?
Rym: but things of the day.
Rym: it's not really a cop out here.
Rym: but quest for glory - oh if you like those old man it's just old dogs day with you isn't it?
Rym: if you like those old kind of point-and-click or type what your character does games.
Rym: I think that quest for glory - really perfect as an Asterix quest or quest for asterisk yeah those kinds of game any game.
Scott: with the word quest in the title I mean King's Quest.
Rym: I'll admit this.
Rym: I thought King's Quest one was pretty pretty poop.
Scott: King's Quest one is pretty poop and this quest is not poop police quest.
Scott: however King's Quest 4 was actually pretty good.
Rym: it was okay.
Scott: space quest is okay please.
Rym: quest games had the the one flaw of.
Rym: I had to drive my car everywhere in real time and it was really hard because that was I think that game at the worst interface between a human being and a vehicle that any game has ever had.
Scott: the only thing I love about police because he had that elevator in the police station that would only go to certain places.
Scott: it could go to other places I know but like you knew that when you could get to those other floors that would be the business you'd go up there.
Rym: the doors locked you knock they're like no one answers.
Rym: you try every item you have and everything in the room.
Rym: finally the game is like listen dude you're supposed to come back here when the plot advances now go out and arrest that drug dealer who if?
Rym: or that the drunk driver who if you'd handcuff him in front instead of behind he kills you and drives away in the police car.
Rym: that game was procedural but anyway quest for glory - in terms of the games of type what your character does.
Rym: maybe not the kind of better click interface they had later but like drink the blah.
Rym: ask about the blah.
Rym: I think this was the best one from that era.
Rym: it's super fun.
Scott: it's the best one maybe with graphics.
Scott: there are a lot that didn't have graphics.
Rym: oh no text adventures are a different genre altogether.
Scott: this is the same game.
Scott: it is a text adventure.
Scott: the only difference is that this has pictures.
Rym: there's a lot more than that.
Rym: you actually also controlled your guy.
Rym: wait like on the screen graphically in combat was actually super fun uh-huh.
Rym: and real-time okay now like quest for glory 3 where they play text adventures the real-time combat yeah but this was better believe me believe me plus I remember moon missed.
Rym: all I do is type kill so-and-so I killed a butler and it would say but you don't have the aerosol device to which I think wait a minute aerosol device.
Rym: of course I don't have the aerosol device.
Rym: where can I get me an aerosol device?
Rym: yeah use aerosol device on Butler but you don't have the aerosol device.
Rym: damn it all right.
Rym: but quest for glory 2 is is the best of these games.
Rym: and if you don't want to go through the trouble of playing this game because you can it works perfectly in DOS box.
Scott: I took Rym's old floppy disk and I ran them in DOS box and it worked perfectly and the game is really fun.
Rym: like if you like that sort of thing this game is great.
Rym: but if not I submit to you a video that includes the somewhat famous or infamous dance scene and the panel kinda gamers that I remember.
Rym: people met on the bbs's.
Rym: people made a big deal about that dancing but then also it's just all the cup scenes and kind of the coolness from the game.
Rym: but really this game is actually good.
Rym: so I recommend playing it if you really want to get a feel for like what games were like back then and I'll leave it at that also.
Rym: I really like that music.
Scott: ok so last week I did a thing of the day about a webcomic that I never read and you know I read it and it was ok.
Scott: it was.
Scott: it's a good it's good comic.
Scott: you are so little.
Scott: the colors in the art are really great the arts a little off but it's still really pretty awesome and I'm glad I made it a thing of the day.
Scott: so because that worked out so well I have no problem doing yet another thing of the day of something that I have never read.
Rym: how this is gonna be great.
Scott: so someone who I trust their opinion one of our listeners on the indie RPG scene right told me about this RPG called fate.
Scott: right and I think fate stands for something I forget.
Rym: yeah way to go fantastic adventures in tabletop entertainment alright alright I'll go with that.
Scott: and the third version of the fate system is available completely for free.
Scott: just go to the website you get it a whole RPG a whole indie RPG an award-winning indie RPG.
Rym: what awards did win?
Rym: because there are awards like most unplayable game out there.
Scott: well ok the second edition of fate right one third place for indie RPG of the year.
Scott: for first place for best support.
Scott: Andy's choice what year?
Scott: and it was the best free game of the year in.
Scott: oh three this is version two that we're talking about.
Scott: huh and this is version three and version three is free.
Scott: it's based on the open gaming license version of fudge I guess fudge with some other RPG and it is a free indie RPG.
Scott: so like if you don't have monies to buy like all these little indie $20 RPG books or if you're not sure like if you want to really get into the indie RPG scene with the burning wheels and that sort of thing.
Scott: right this is totally free it costs nothing.
Scott: and I'm pretty confident even though I've never read it that this is a better RPG than Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: so if Dungeons & Dragons is all you know of tabletop role-playing game or if you nothing of tabletop role-playing game go download this and read this one and it.
Scott: I'm sure it has some of the redeeming qualities of quality RPGs and you will you will learn something from it without having to spend any money whatsoever.
Scott: and there's actually a couple of actual games you know built on the system like they had this spirit of the century game.
Scott: that's like a pulp action thingy.
Scott: it's like sort of Indiana Jonesy like on the cover there's a. it's a spirit of the century a pulp pickup role-playing game.
Scott: there's like a guy hanging on to a biplane that's being flown by a gorilla.
Scott: I feel like a flaming zeppelin and a guy with a jetpack.
Rym: I feel like two things.
Rym: one you know what I'll save all that for.
Rym: when we talk about some of these indie RPGs on another show mm-hmm partly because I want to despite everything we talked about prior let's talk about a video game that was released in the last decade.
Scott: yeah I know but yes that's my thing of day all right.
Scott: so hate RPG.
Rym: speaking of a video game that was released in the past decade give or take Mario Kart.
Scott: you want to talk about just the new Mario Kart.
Scott: you want to talk about Mario karts.
Rym: uh I think we can talk about him real quick.
Rym: more than a decade ago in fact in 1992 Mario Kart appear Mario Kart.
Rym: there was never a Mario Kart whatever on the SNES and you know what.
Rym: it was a pretty mediocre game.
Scott: see the thing is right nowadays you try to play that game and it's pretty painful.
Scott: I mean they had the picking up coins on the track.
Scott: business dude.
Rym: I rented that game like right after it came out.
Scott: it was actually they had the.
Scott: you know the power slide but it was really hard to do and you know it wasn't really easy to control or that useful.
Scott: you're a lot better off actually letting go the accelerator and turning a lot of times and we
Rym: did with my brother and I played the battle like three times tried to raise decided the game was pretty poop and just it actually sat there unplayed until my parents took it back to blockbuster.
Scott: I played it at a friend's house.
Rym: all right I'm sorry mammoth video.
Scott: yeah I went.
Scott: I played it at a friend's house.
Scott: he had it and at first like I was just falling all over the place.
Scott: but he had figured it out and then eventually I figured it out and then it was good times.
Scott: but you know it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't easy.
Scott: the controls were very unrefined.
Scott: but for what it was you know an actual racing game that nominally worked with the items.
Scott: it was pretty hot in those days.
Rym: thing is nowadays pretty unplayable while lacking the items.
Rym: even then I would have rather played stunts 40 racing.
Rym: anyway that game was great.
Scott: so then the GBA one was the next one.
Rym: oh no Mario Kart 64 came out in 96 if I was a freshman in high school.
Scott: so when did the GBA one come out?
Rym: 2001 while we were all in school.
Rym: oh wow yeah.
Rym: so anyway yeah Mario Kart cuz I remember you all got it.
Rym: I didn't have a Gameboy Advance yet.
Scott: yeah Mario Kart 64. actually it had a lot of interesting maps and it actually had you know decent driving mechanics.
Scott: but actually I think it's actually actually I think it's the worst Mario Kart I don't know.
Scott: yeah probably because first of all the AI just cheated like.
Scott: it's not like now where they get you with the blue shell and then catch up.
Scott: they just cheated.
Scott: they were just faster than you to make it hard because they sucked all right.
Scott: and not only that but like the actual power sliding mechanic I mean in the DS it was pretty bad with the snaking but the n64 was really really bad and there were a lot of broken maps like you could jump over the wall and it was like it's not like it was supposed to be a shortcut.
Scott: it was like just bullshit and just broken and it was kind of hackneyed.
Rym: yeah and I never.
Rym: I've never played that Mario Kart.
Rym: cuz remember by 96 I'd given up on consoles I had my rockin game in PC and I was just playing nothing.
Rym: but like I don't know whatever game I was playing it made for a good multiplayer party.
Scott: but in all honesty if you want a multiplayer party on the n64 you want Goldeneye.
Scott: no Diddy car in racing Diddy Kong racing as far as superior far superior you can race in Goldeneye.
Scott: I guess I guess I guess the GBA one came out and I played that GBA Mario Kart like a fiend like I don't think you people understand how good.
Rym: I have no idea this way this game Scott is to this game more so than I am to Advance Wars like like.
Rym: I picked it up one day I borrowed his card and I've went to raise one of his ghosts and I was like all right go his ghost was gone.
Scott: I never saw it again and then it let me yep I think like I played that GBA Mario Kart on my GBA so much I think I honestly think I might be the world champion of that game.
Scott: like it had all the SNES maps and it had a whole bunch of new GBA maps.
Scott: so there's like a ton of maps right.
Scott: it was wicked awesome.
Scott: and the other thing about that game is that I don't know why they changed.
Scott: they had the formula perfect right.
Scott: the game had the blue shell right but the blue shell didn't fly through the sky and then land on your head.
Scott: the blue shell just followed you and if you didn't mess up like if you kept driving and didn't like slow down by driving in some like dirt or if you stayed on the track it would never.
Scott: it would always stay right behind you but it wouldn't actually hit you and if you were able to keep driving perfectly long enough it would go away.
Scott: the same thing with the red shells and this resulted in a completely skill-based Mario Kart that still managed to have all the fun of having crazy items without having them ruin the skill based gameplay because people could use items on you all they wanted but if you were awesome you could dodge pretty much all of them.
Scott: I mean sometimes there'd be something like a blue shells coming your dot.
Scott: you're staying out of its way you're staying out of its way and then lightning.
Scott: you got small and now it hits you but you already got lightning so it's like our whatever.
Rym: yeah but it was.
Rym: it was a solid game all around it was.
Scott: it was pretty much the perfect Mario Kart as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: a shit ton of tracks excellent character selection perfect controls almost entirely skill based in determining the winning and losing and I played it so much that I can pretty much get like amazing times and all the tracks especially scary especially like there's some like Bowser castle tracks.
Scott: I'm just like like going around like and that's also the first one that had the blue sparks.
Scott: I mean the n64 had like the power slide.
Scott: this one had it where you would do sort of a normal slide around the corner and if you took the corner like on the line that the game wanted you to take it on.
Scott: it would just like blue sparks out of nowhere.
Scott: it's like you do a turn you go to the straightaway and then boom blue sparks just poop and I liked it that way because it wasn't like.
Scott: you know try to hold the power slide as long as you want it wasn't?
Scott: you know?
Scott: you know try to rock back and forth to build anything up.
Scott: it was take the turns as best as you can and if you take the turn in the best possible way then you'll just get a boost.
Scott: and it was only on the turns and I don't see how it could be better than that.
Rym: so then double - which I'll admit.
Rym: I'm glad Nintendo tried an experiment like this but I didn't enjoy double - at least not the kind of two people in one cart mechanic.
Rym: basically whenever we played it was either Scott's driving or I'm driving and whoever's not driving will never drive because the other person is never gonna switch.
Rym: there's no reason to ever switch.
Scott: pretty much all that going in the back.
Scott: I mean they did give the person in the back of the car.
Rym: yes they gave me the power to knock you off the track whenever I got bored.
Scott: pretty much that person is in charge of the drift controls and the items which is good but it's not enough.
Scott: it's sort of like the person driving is the real play and the other person sort of bored.
Rym: it was really the.
Rym: the one thing I can really say about that game though is that they polished a lot of other things.
Rym: it was nominally fun if you're playing by yourself but it does have the benefit of if you have a group of like.
Rym: like say you got two couples because you could do the land mode on that too like a gamer guy and a gamer girl and then they're two not so gamer girlfriend and let's just say both girlfriends now sexist.
Scott: how so saying the girlfriends are like not able to play the quality game.
Rym: I said a gamer girl and a gamer guy and then both of their respective girlfriends who are not gamers.
Scott: I was I'm tired.
Rym: I very pointedly did not go into the realm of girls suck games.
Rym: I went into the realm of lesbians but anyway.
Rym: so the non gamers could at least you know you could.
Rym: you could put the non gamer in the backseat and they could enjoy themselves.
Rym: of course they might screw you up though yeah but both people at an equal handicap and it was kind of this that is a good game to get people into gaming.
Rym: you aren't so hard car.
Scott: the thing is you could play.
Scott: if I'm not mistaken you could play Double Dash where each person drives and does the items and the drift out.
Scott: they control the whole vehicle.
Rym: oh yeah but I just I had other things to do.
Rym: that was when we were in college and we had much more important games to be playing like Counter Strike.
Scott: I get a lot of GameCube games pretty much most of the big ones but I don't have that one.
Rym: so yeah well with Counter Strike and tribes to and other things to do that that was much earlier than Double Dash.
Rym: yeah but I'm saying like that level of game yeah.
Scott: and yes yep that was around Double Dash times.
Rym: so we don't need to say much about the DS show on the DS one.
Rym: I think we did.
Rym: it was great except for the fact that one day I was playing against Scott.
Rym: you know he beat me all the time and then I was like wait a minute I beat him all the time because I was playing it the same way.
Rym: I played the GBA one and I was trying to take his lines and then I was like huh wait a minute I could boost twice around that corner.
Rym: oh I wonder if I can boost three times.
Rym: I wonder if I can boost down the straightaway.
Rym: and I learned independently of other people how to snake and then I realized online that oh people are talking about snaking.
Rym: they had a name for it and people wrote an uproar about it.
Rym: and then I realized that the way to get the best times was to hurt my thumb and kind of shake my DS and then I stop playing it.
Scott: yeah cuz pretty much.
Scott: the problem with that game is they wanted to continue the the thing for the GBA version of you know rewarding you by taking the turns really well and by power sliding around the turns right and taking a good corner and drifting by giving you a boost right and that's all well and good with the blue sparks.
Scott: that's how it should be.
Scott: that's what makes Mario Kart Mario Kart.
Scott: the problem was is the way they programmed.
Scott: it was you got the sparks by sort of rocking the stick back and forth while drifting.
Scott: it's on a turn.
Scott: it didn't matter what.
Scott: so you would just do that wherever there was enough room on the track.
Rym: I was just I'd go drift rock rock rock and I got into this rhythm and I remember I finally raced against Scott doing this and we were on think Luigi's Mansion and it was like go and I just disappeared and I laughed.
Rym: it was just crazy.
Scott: and you know that's that's you know?
Scott: I guess that's okay.
Scott: the problem was that this technique pretty much meant if you want to win this game you have to hurt your hands like going.
Rym: it's kind of like the old fishing game in the original Mario Party.
Scott: who wants to play a game where it's pretty much win by shaking your hand back and forth and hurting your thumb?
Scott: that doesn't really make for a good game.
Scott: I mean and you can say no snaking.
Scott: but then it's like what the fuck?
Scott: so what how many?
Scott: what's the line?
Scott: how many boosts do I do before it's snaking you know?
Rym: yeah I mean if it's a long corner am I only allowed to slide once?
Rym: what if I slide twice?
Rym: what if I get hit with something?
Rym: I got a slide again.
Scott: so I mean the thing is the DS version in all other respects is really awesome except for that one thing just sort of ruined it and it was really sad.
Rym: so Mario Kart Wii.
Rym: so far I have almost nothing bad to say about it.
Scott: yeah Mario Kart Wii right.
Scott: well people talk right.
Scott: first of all there's a few bad things that they got the battle mode in there.
Scott: the battle mode is stupid.
Scott: you should never play.
Rym: I haven't even played it yet.
Scott: it's battle mode.
Scott: it's lame.
Scott: it's by definition lame.
Scott: the game is about the racing.
Scott: also in the battle mode I've heard you can only do team play in it.
Scott: you can't do every man for himself.
Scott: but yeah the actual single-player mode right is sort of annoying because you have to unlock all this shit to beat all these courses and everything to unlock all the carts and the characters and the extra courses and all the different cc's and all the bikes and all that stuff and that's just sort of annoying and time-consuming.
Scott: but it serves the purpose of allowing you to build your skills and by beating that single-player you have the skills to compete in the multiplayer which is like I guess okay.
Scott: in the single-player there's also this rubber band AI of you know and it is there.
Scott: it's like all.
Scott: there'll be blue shells and bullet bills and all sorts of other things that pretty much make you lose even when you're winning.
Scott: so it's like why should I even stay in first place if I fall behind I can easily catch up because I'll get an awesome item.
Scott: if I pull too far ahead I'll be pulled back by other people getting awesome items.
Rym: but who cares about the single-player?
Rym: right?
Scott: so the multiplayer.
Scott: you can turn off the bullshit items.
Rym: you can choose what set of items you want.
Scott: choose exact?
Rym: well no but they have the settings you can say like strategic and it pretty much only gives you mushrooms and green shells and occasionally a
Scott: banana
Rym: peel a block a triple mushroom I think a red shell but not that frequently and it it's a lot more skill based and a lot more fun at least for us.
Rym: yeah you can also which is equally fun in the right setting turn on crazy items.
Rym: yeah everyone's getting bullet bills.
Scott: in the normal mode right if you're in like last place you'll get more powerful items to get you catch up and if you're in first place you get weaker items to sort of.
Scott: you know you can't really do much.
Scott: you'll just have to keep racing until you know.
Scott: but in the aggressive items mode everyone gets the crazy items as if they were falling way behind.
Scott: so even if you're in the front you get blue shelled.
Scott: you probably have like a bullet bill.
Scott: so it's like oh no you blue shelled me.
Scott: now I'm in second place bullet bill.
Scott: oh shit take that bitches.
Scott: yeah and they got a lot of tracks in there.
Scott: they don't have as many tracks as I would like.
Scott: I mean I think the GBA one sled more tracks but there's plenty.
Scott: there's enough to keep you interested.
Scott: they got the bikes.
Scott: so the fact that the bikes are in there it's sort of like every track is actually two tracks because driving the bike is completely different from driving the cart.
Scott: so doing one track with the bike and one track with the car it's almost like there's two tracks going on and the fact that you can compete cart against bike is actually really sort of interesting.
Scott: but it also comes down to sort of I know that the bike is faster on this track and I know the carts faster on that track.
Rym: of course there are ways around that by agreeing to do certain tracks or like bikes only carts only.
Rym: there's a lot of ways to handle that.
Rym: yeah but I mean overall playing actually playing the game is super fun.
Scott: oh super fun.
Scott: and the thing the we've got to talk about the wheel all right.
Scott: so it comes to the wheel and the wheel is just a piece of plastic you put on the Wiimote.
Scott: you can just drive with the Wiimote you know turning it back and forth like you didn't excite.
Rym: you can also use a GameCube controller you can use up.
Rym: you can use any controller.
Rym: pretty much you can use any available except the Wii Zapper.
Scott: you can't use the Wii Zapper now but you can use any available Wii control except the Wii Zapper and it's it works with all of them.
Scott: it's like every single driving mode works and works well.
Scott: the thing is with the Wii wheel with the you know the tilting it back and forth mode you're at a disadvantage because if there's like especially on the higher cc's you just cannot turn back and forth that quickly.
Scott: so if it's like right turn left turn you're not going to be able to like actually get good power slides on both the quick turns at high speeds with the Wii wheel because the response just isn't quick enough and you're not going to be able to take the turns super tight you know and you're not going to be able to like sneak in between two really close banana peels like you can with the nunchuck or a GameCube controller.
Rym: now I'm glad they included the wheel and I'm glad that they also let you use a normal control scheme because it feels real nice to use the wheel and for casual play it's really nice.
Scott: but the wheels really fun.
Rym: but if you are if you're got one of those people who wants to be like super good at the game don't even bother with it.
Rym: just go straight to the analog stick and ever look back.
Scott: is the advantage of the wheel?
Scott: when you use the wheel it puts a wheel logo next to your guy on the screen.
Scott: so everyone knows you're using the wheel and if you do really well with the wheel it becomes a golden wheel and that's sort of like a big insult.
Scott: it's like if you're using the wheel and you lose.
Scott: you say I was using the wheel.
Scott: of course I was at a disadvantage.
Scott: it's why I lost like it's.
Scott: you know it doesn't feel so bad if you win with the wheel and other people aren't also using the wheel.
Scott: it's like I beat you with the wheel.
Scott: that's like beating you in a race but I was wearing a ball and chain on my leg.
Rym: so using the wheel it's a common strategy.
Rym: I do this often because no one will ever play against me in advance.
Rym: for us I'll be like alright I'll give everyone else double money or something and we'll play and if I lose it's that anytime you want the kind of trash talk all like of the gods like it's like the carte blanche of trash talk.
Rym: put yourself at a disadvantage willingly.
Rym: you cannot be faulted for losing and everyone else is so screwed if you win.
Scott: yeah so it.
Scott: basically you know.
Scott: the fact that the Wii wheel puts you at a disadvantage for actually winning.
Scott: they make up for it in that because they're losing doesn't feel bad if using the Wii wheel because you feel you're at a disadvantage anyway and winning is double awesome.
Scott: so you know I really don't mind using the Wii wheel even though I know if I use it I'm probably not gonna win if the other people are actually good at playing the game.
Rym: now I think I mean there's not much else to say but I think we should at least mention the fact that this game unlike many other game unlike every other game on the Wii didn't completely fuck up the multiplayer online.
Scott: well the online is bad but it's satisfactory.
Rym: it's playable.
Rym: it mainly is once.
Rym: unlike Smash Brothers which really really was a mistake two people can play online from the same way together.
Scott: yes so me and Rym can go online together on the same way and race against people on the Internet's and but we're both using the same way.
Scott: whereas with Smash Brothers to do that we would have needed to wheeze in the same room to the way to go online.
Rym: so you go online and just book track voting and all that same kind of stuff but it'll find a game that's already going and kind of put you into it for the next race.
Rym: yep and then every time a race ends it depending how many people drop out during or after that race it takes other people who are looking for games and puts them in.
Rym: so once you play one or two or three games you've got a group of people that you've been playing with.
Rym: you see their names they're there and eventually distills into only the people who actually want to play and aren't just gonna quit when they lose.
Scott: yeah and the thing is unlike the Mario Kart DS or people quit.
Scott: I mean you have to quit and start a new one right?
Scott: this would you just kind of?
Scott: even if everyone quits just keep playing and the game.
Scott: the service will just put new people into your existing game.
Scott: just keep playing and every race is gonna have people in it and even if they drop out you just finish the race and then there'll be more people who just do just joined.
Scott: so this it sort of solves the problem of people leaving the race doesn't fuck everything up and it's actually fun.
Rym: I could see myself doing it periodically.
Rym: I could definitely see myself doing this with friend codes and formites.
Scott: yeah they give you this we channel.
Scott: actually that I didn't Mario Kart channel.
Scott: I didn't install it yet but basically it puts the Mario Kart thing on the front of your you know we menu or ever and you can sort of get right into the multiplayer from there and you can see what's going on and and all sorts of good stuff.
Rym: we'll probably kind of geek bite that after we use it enough to figure out if it's good or not.
Scott: yeah I didn't install yet just because the Wii menu is kind of full.
Scott: I gotta like uninstall some games and do some other stuff on there.
Rym: now they definitely cleaning cut down on the frame rate and some other things when you play online but that's good to be expected.
Scott: well it's like they.
Scott: they cut the frame rate right so it's not as smooth but there's no lag as a result.
Scott: it's like we made the game.
Scott: it's like the cards go just as fast but the frame rate is slower so it feels jaggy but it's jagged Lee.
Scott: the jaggedness is even across the whole race so you're never getting those more.
Scott: it's not like we is smooth.
Scott: oh it's completely stopped.
Scott: it's smooth it stopped.
Scott: it's just slightly jaggy the whole time but still playable and I guess that's if.
Scott: that's what they had to do technologically.
Rym: that's what you got to do and I think in the end the easiest thing to say is simply that Mario Kart Wii is one of those.
Rym: if you own a Wii you'd better damn well own Mario Kart.
Scott: you had better damn well be owning this game if you got the Wii action going on.
Scott: I mean well this is it's this and Smash Brothers are pretty much the the Wii awesomeness that you if you those are there's two games you're gonna have for the Wii.
Scott: that's it.
Scott: I mean even more so than like the Zelda game because you can get that any old time and it'll be the same forever.
Scott: but this game right now it's hot you gotta strike while the iron top people.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: you can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.