Rym: It's Thursday September 4th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is dick knives tonight.
Rym: We talk about Seattle Seattle.
Scott: let's do this.
Scott: So the last show we're all bragging about the fact that we are not shit talkers.
Scott: We said we go to PAX no matter what.
Scott: he went to PAX no matter what and we came back Talking averted we're going to fax next year no matter what.
Rym: and East Coast fax Yep well To even out we're definitely going to acid next year.
Scott: no or not Even though I'd like to very much To even out the shit.
Scott: talking here comes some shit.
Scott: talking you ready.
Scott: we said We said that this Thursday show would be the snow crash show.
Rym: you said Ambivalent.
Scott: it is not.
Scott: it is not the snow crash the snow crash.
Scott: She'll be one week from today.
Rym: granted I'll admit sadly as much as I love snow crash I'm not that excited about doing a snow crash show because of how few of you actually read the book.
Scott: Yeah, and I have to actually skim the book a little bit to refresh the memories and get the jet.
Scott: I think once I do that.
Scott: I'll be more excited to do the snow crash show.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I the only.
Rym: basically I'll say this if you guys actually want the snow crash show tell us because so far people seem to not Actually in any way care about the GeekNights book club, and we're getting like a 1% return right here I've got.
Scott: actually here's my idea right.
Scott: we're gonna do the snow crash show and of course in the snow crash show We will announce the next book.
Scott: I have an idea for the next book, and it's a really easy book.
Rym: Is it gonna be?
Rym: I can think of a few.
Rym: the little prince?
Scott: no no no it's not that easy.
Scott: It's not see spot run.
Scott: all right.
Scott: It's a worthwhile book, but it's easy wait wait Wait.
Rym: are you saying the little prince is not worthwhile?
Scott: I'm didn't say the little prince wasn't worthwhile, but the little prince is not not see spot run.
Scott: comparing it to see spot run here No, I'm saying the little prince of my favorite books ever.
Scott: But this book we're gonna do is slightly harder than the little prince.
Scott: not that easy all right It's all right.
Scott: It'll be okay It'll take.
Scott: I can read the book in a day.
Rym: That doesn't say much cuz I read the prince of nothing in like a week and apparently that's the thing is I figure Right.
Scott: I read these books in a week and other people have take a month.
Scott: if I can read it in a day Maybe the people can read it in two weeks.
Scott: Maybe we'll see all right, and then if that doesn't work maybe we'll either Really shame everyone who didn't read and call you out for being doofuses or something I don't know.
Rym: Maybe I like kind of like doofy even though it's incorrect.
Rym: I know doofuses is kind of like that whole argument about how they they're gonna pluralize Paxis Paxis even though that like hurts my ears to hear.
Scott: yeah well paces.
Rym: Yeah much cooler all right.
Scott: anyway Do we want to do news or not?
Scott: I have a news that can stir some discussion even though it's pretty old.
Rym: I've got three bags news.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: the cupboard is freaking bare.
Rym: We haven't been to the grocery store in forever.
Rym: It's been con season for as long as I can remember.
Scott: I think we're gonna go to the grocery tomorrow - actually do you want to go to the fancy Newberg grocery?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: not it won't be open tomorrow late like that.
Scott: who knows when it's open.
Rym: It does not open that late I don't think.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I can look it up especially you get them late, but there's no food in this house.
Rym: I was eating and drinking things that I never expected to eat or drink.
Rym: I don't even know why I own them.
Rym: They're in the kitchen.
Scott: I guess they were emergency like an emergency lasagna or something.
Rym: Oh, God actually I saw the emergency lasagna, and I threw it away.
Rym: It was frightening looking.
Scott: It's pretty scary.
Rym: No I ate third tier ramen Third tier as in top ramen top ramen That's the third tier fourth tier being March on why don't we have separate itchy bones?
Rym: I ate it all I did.
Rym: I had a ramen, but I ate it where the kitchen is.
Scott: I ate them.
Scott: Are they yummy?
Scott: I did.
Scott: you grow them on the stick over the fire the little spinny steak or what?
Scott: I don't know what?
Rym: Whatever, I see where you're going with that, but if measure is unceasing that joke is dead right anyway.
Scott: So check this out right.
Scott: This is a little old.
Scott: This is from like a week or two ago.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: That's like ancient some august 26th right, but I don't think we discussed it on this show even though It was actually discussed in so semi mainstream medium.
Scott: anyway in Connecticut right there was a kid named Jericho Scott.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Scott was his last name.
Scott: He's nine years old Okay, and he's in a little league.
Scott: Did you hear the story yet?
Rym: No.
Rym: I have no idea what you're tall this story.
Scott: He's going to infuriate you.
Scott: I'm so glad.
Rym: wait a minute.
Rym: this involves helicopter parents.
Rym: I'm going to guess possibly Religion and or a closed-minded town.
Scott: no religion Not really a town that's closed-minded helicopter parents though perhaps Helicoptering it could be easily interpreted as helicopter parents.
Rym: Maybe maybe some coddling.
Scott: Definitely coddling.
Scott: so what's going on?
Scott: the situation was this?
Scott: Jericho Scott this nine-year-old kid can throw a 40 mile an hour fastball right over the plate every time.
Scott: He's pretty awesome.
Scott: Whoa right you know.
Scott: and this this kids like this all the time.
Rym: I can't be good for him.
Rym: pitching's not good for you.
Scott: Let alone You know in kids who are like this in a little league?
Scott: You know maybe they win the little league world series.
Scott: who in the who's won?
Scott: Where the big major league stars that were big little leaguers?
Scott: They don't exist.
Scott: you know it's major league players the people who developed.
Scott: you know.
Scott: later This kid's probably going to throw a 40 mile an hour fastball his whole life.
Scott: He's never going to really throw a 90 mile an hour ball.
Rym: I don't think I could have thrown a 40 mile an hour fastball.
Scott: now It's really.
Scott: it's all in the wrist like when I was at summer camp once they had a scout come and teach the kids How to throw and stuff and I actually paid attention because I was older and wiser by that time.
Scott: I was a counselor not a not a camper, and you know I could throw But I could never you know throw hard and the guy was like look here's the technique.
Scott: And I basically tried it like a whole.
Scott: I just played catch of this dude like for like you know 10 minutes And at first it was just like eh, eh, and then eventually it was like.
Scott: you know where it's like.
Rym: And I'm like oh Well you can only because I was trying to throw kids who play catch with their parents or brothers kids who don't because the kids Who know how to throw can actually make it back to home base from at least second base?
Scott: Yeah, I mean It's like you don't.
Scott: the trick is actually like a trick to throwing a baseball where you snap your wrist and such.
Rym: I was doing slow permanent damage to your body, but well it depends.
Scott: not pitching But just throwing like field throwing you know not damaging your body And you know it doesn't take that long to learn if you have you know adequate motor skills And it's really fun once you figure it out.
Scott: It's like oh shit.
Scott: I can throw hard awesome anyway, so Alright, this kid exists and what happened was his team was eight and oh of course Right eight games one no games lost and they are preparing for the playoffs And they went up and they were gonna play this game and the other team just forfeited.
Scott: right all right The team was like oh shit They tried to take the mound and the other team quit because they were they were afraid I'd first off that other team.
Rym: Totally lame however was however while they are wusses and while I?
Rym: Can say one thing at back in quiz bowl because we were kind of the bad boys of quiz bowl And we were like we were pretty good, but a lot of times.
Rym: We would lose on purpose just to go dick around.
Rym: We would we sometimes like?
Rym: a couple of times We actually like use rules or had someone stay in the bathroom too long to force a forfeit Just because our coach couldn't accuse us of quitting.
Scott: yeah, so What happened next?
Scott: well?
Scott: They told the kid he couldn't play.
Rym: well wait a minute right and who told the kid he couldn't?
Rym: the league What grounds?
Scott: And grounds that you know.
Scott: no one to play against him.
Scott: And they were afraid right and then wait the team coach refused to break up the team.
Scott: so basically yeah The team isn't gonna play.
Scott: the team coach for the win.
Scott: the team is banned from the league and it and the.
Scott: the coach says He's never heard anyone.
Scott: He's on target all the time.
Scott: How can you punish him for being too good?
Scott: Said the pitcher.
Scott: the kid says I feel sad.
Scott: I feel like it's my fault.
Scott: No one can play.
Scott: the league says he's a very skilled player a very hard thrower.
Scott: the league attorney Says there are a lot of beginners is not a high-powered league.
Scott: It's a developmental league whose main purpose is to promote the sport.
Scott: So basically they kick the team out.
Rym: What kind of league was this then?
Rym: little league like?
Rym: what kind of little league?
Scott: There's a lot of the youth baseball league of New Haven, Connecticut.
Rym: So publicly funded I don't know.
Rym: I'm just curious.
Rym: I Don't know about that.
Scott: that does make a difference.
Scott: I didn't think of that angle before I was funneled once.
Scott: yeah I didn't I didn't think of that angle, but you know.
Scott: the thing is I'm gonna repeat What was said on.
Scott: you know the ESPN show PTI?
Rym: I can.
Rym: I can sum up everything I feel about this in two words.
Rym: hmm Harrison Bergeron?
Scott: exactly No, but on PTI right the the sports show I listen to.
Scott: you know it's a TV show But I listen to the podcast.
Scott: you should too.
Scott: The guy was like.
Scott: he told the story out when he was a kid And he was in the league.
Scott: there was one pitcher on one team who is wicked dangerous.
Scott: He was always afraid of him, but eventually he got over it, and he actually hit off the guy.
Scott: he was like oh yeah, oh yeah, and You're taking away that you know valuable youth experience from the kids of having to go up and hit against this Terrifyingly good pitcher and getting over it instead you know sort of the the wasifying No child left behind.
Scott: Harrison Bergeron action.
Rym: Case in point.
Rym: if anyone here is not read Harrison Bergeron read it into the quiet required.
Scott: Okay, if you can't read a book all right you can at least read Harrison Bergeron, and if you can't read Harrison Bergeron There's a movie.
Rym: It's actually a really good movie.
Scott: can watch the movie and if you can't even watch the movie you can read the last question.
Rym: at least I can say one thing Harrison Bergeron the movie is Very much like V for Vendetta Like it's kind of like the movie to the book is the same difference like V for Vendetta versus No, Harrison Bergeron's a short story kids.
Scott: You can read it.
Scott: They probably make you read it in school.
Scott: They made me read it in school three times.
Rym: All right, all right, so uh as many of you know I hail from the land of Detroit, Michigan.
Scott: I was born Detroit, which we saw from the sky.
Rym: Yes from the sky and Scott pointed out that and we look out the window.
Rym: It's basically a giant lighted grid of roads with like two Diagonal roads going across the whole thing.
Scott: there are also some angled roads near the edge.
Rym: Well near the edge because the water's there.
Rym: so the grid kind of turns to follow the road go right.
Scott: it Just you know extend the roads out into the water with little bridges that there's still a grid
Rym: Yeah, and still the thing is if you go away from the water It's just a perfect grid all the way down into like Ohio and Wisconsin all the way crossing to Canada.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, but anyway Detroit is a is a is an interesting place.
Rym: now I point out that the only people who say Detroit are people who are not from Detroit or People on the radio.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: like a lot of radio personalities in Detroit will say Detroit, Michigan But everyone who lives in Detroit.
Rym: We just say Detroit Detroit or Detroit Just more of a day day.
Rym: that's why Detroit, but of course there's always salt st.
Rym: Mary up on top.
Rym: anyway Detroit.
Rym: I have a love-hate relationship with the city of Detroit because on one hand Detroit is a really cool place, and there's a lot of cool architecture, and it's one of those Really important cities.
Scott: it was a world city a global city that fell into decline when in industry and all these sorts It's sad to see anything awesome become less awesome like it's like the World's Fair in New York only a lot bigger.
Scott: It's like oh, man, but now It's just a. it's just a park.
Rym: But one thing I can say about Detroit is that the politics of Detroit which are a microcosm In many ways of the politics of Michigan as a whole well They're you know look at the ancestors of modern Detroit politics Al Capone right.
Scott: That's the ancestor Scott.
Rym: where was Al Capone based?
Rym: Chicago, okay?
Scott: Yeah, Detroit was close.
Rym: Okay, yeah, there are better people to make fun of for Detroit.
Rym: There's a notorious Detroit Turian's.
Scott: Anyway, Al Capone owned a mall.
Rym: I'll come on.
Rym: wasn't even that good?
Rym: Ma Baker's the way to go.
Scott: It's all about a Capone's vault.
Scott: I Wait in Detroit gold.
Rym: Are you making a Geraldo joke?
Rym: what on GeekNights you realize the whole Al Capone vault thing came out of Geraldo Rivera.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Scott: all I know is that it was some weird TV special.
Scott: Yeah, they Geraldo Rivera.
Rym: He said I found Al Capone's vault.
Rym: so he don't know what's in there.
Rym: He built up to this business.
Scott: I'm over as a person.
Scott: yes Okay, so it's just a guy.
Rym: so finally the moment comes live TV.
Rym: this crazy build-up.
Scott: They've got all.
Scott: any was empty.
Rym: There was like some dust in there and a cobweb.
Rym: Maybe a dead mouse.
Scott: I didn't stay up to see what was in there.
Rym: But Michigan the only state in the Union to have a shooting war not a long one with another state Mr.. Rebellion the only state.
Rym: well not actually.
Rym: I think Texas had it incident to where it's militia Independent Texas.
Scott: that's an international war.
Rym: that's not a state Independent of any orders from the Union invaded Canada on at least one occasion.
Rym: Yeah They caused some mischief and eventually were pushed back over the border because the Mounties were actually very competent.
Rym: Michigan militia not so much.
Scott: Well.
Scott: You know mounted units always beat non mounted units.
Scott: This is this is a lot less.
Scott: They have pikes and there were no pikes.
Scott: They were just muskets.
Scott: But the thing is the other guys had muskets too, so it muskets on horses beat muskets not on horses.
Rym: But to skip a bit Detroit is that many shall we say colorful?
Rym: Personalities in its political machine political machine that I think.
Rym: Tammany Hall is what I would say.
Scott: I go to Chicago you go all the way to New York all right, and you're yelling at me fuck you.
Rym: Anyway, here's the deal.
Rym: One of these colorful people the mayor of Detroit after I left mayor Kwame Kilpatrick And I thought it was Kwame Brown what?
Rym: No No, where would you get that?
Rym: I don't know that borders on racist is it?
Scott: Anyway, there is a person named call me Brown always a basketball player nevermind.
Rym: Okay, anyway.
Rym: I got confused.
Rym: kill Patrick He he's almost my hero because you see The United States one of the reasons we've been such a stable nation for so long and why our nation is generally so Ascended in the world is the tradition of the peaceful transfer of power.
Rym: and let me tell you Kwame did everything he could to disrupt that process.
Rym: This is a man who when told to leave office said no Wow one not here.
Rym: I don't want to tell the whole story about this.
Rym: all I want to say is that he's finally in jail hooray And I think it is at an end, but all right.
Scott: well It doesn't get was the mayor?
Rym: now allow me to point out one thing.
Rym: there are two-thirds of his Wikipedia page are called political career and Controversies.
Rym: okay, I'm just gonna go down through some headlines.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: but but uh the Manoogian mansion party Nice.
Scott: the murder of Tamara green not nice.
Rym: the motorcycle squad Harley Davidson awesome.
Rym: the whistleblower trial not so awesome.
Rym: text messaging scandal, okay?
Rym: There's a whole separate Wikipedia page about that.
Scott: nice.
Rym: criminal charges the red Lincoln Navigator Yeah, the city choice of car.
Rym: the slander suit the recall campaign The funneling of state grant money to his wife.
Rym: Why DC police deny him after-hours protection the preferential hiring of family and friends a preacher a prostitute and the mayor the death threats against the prosecutor allegations of assaulting a police officer jailed.
Rym: FBI begins investigating.
Scott: See isn't that?
Scott: understand right?
Scott: look at a place like Connecticut.
Scott: right in Connecticut There was a governor Roland right and governor Roland basically what he did.
Scott: is he?
Scott: you know?
Scott: cuz governments often You know take bids for things they had to go with the lowest bidder.
Scott: You know how that works, right?
Scott: Basically he helped his contractor buddies You know win the bids and such so that he could you know get some monies and funneled some monies and like Extensions onto his house.
Scott: something about that.
Scott: I remember the exact details, but it was a typical kind of corruption bidding thing.
Scott: He did one thing like that.
Scott: You know what happened.
Scott: He went to jail.
Scott: It was was jail, but he went to jail and he was out Immediately.
Scott: that was it.
Scott: It's calling brown the basketball player.
Scott: No thing has been going on.
Scott: this may call me of Detroit, right?
Scott: How many corrupt things did he get away with before now?
Scott: He's in jail.
Scott: Why does it take so long in Detroit when in Connecticut took five minutes?
Rym: Detroit you've never been to the store.
Rym: You've been to Novi Yep, you drove near Detroit.
Rym: You've never been in Detroit.
Rym: You've never lived in Detroit.
Rym: All I have to say is I found this thing hilarious For as long as it's been happening, and I just wanted to point out that it finally came to its hilarious and bitter end.
Rym: so things of the day.
Rym: from packs.
Scott: I Can't help mines not from pegs.
Rym: mine is however because I was I was gonna do something else.
Rym: I got a bunch of you know saved up things.
Rym: you can look in my delicious and find them.
Rym: if you're really desperate of course Then you'll just be very disappointed and some GeekNights episode far in the future.
Rym: But I mentioned that it packs.
Rym: the audience was Rick rolled in perhaps the most epic Rick rolling I've ever seen and there's a YouTube video of this Rick rolling.
Rym: I pointed out.
Scott: telling them that the videos are Rick rolling sort of ruins the effect of the video.
Rym: No, it doesn't.
Rym: because you're gonna know it's a Rick rolling.
Rym: you go to YouTube.
Rym: It says packs 2008 - Jonathan Colton.
Rym: Rick rolls the audience.
Rym: Well I guess that's Jonathan Colton tricks the audience into clicking on a suspicious link.
Scott: I fell for it.
Rym: We all fell for it.
Rym: now The reason I want you to watch this video is because if you didn't listen to our packs coverage because you're an idiot because any Human being could enjoy packs And you probably should want to listen joys.
Scott: GeekNights would enjoy packs not any human being I thought my grandma would enjoy If you're my grandma would have.
Rym: if you're listening to this you probably either enjoy packs or someone is trying to Rick roll you with GeekNights.
Rym: very nice, but Watch this video one to understand how epic this Rick rolling was.
Rym: but more importantly Listen to the way the crowd reacts.
Rym: the shifting volume really says it all.
Scott: yeah, that gives me an idea.
Scott: Why don't we start a campaign of geek role where we say hey everyone?
Scott: Go to forums and blogs and places and post comments that link to GeekNights episodes and such But you make it look like you're linking a spore to or whatever it is you're deciding to Rick roll that day.
Rym: That's like saying hey go punch people in the face and then say GeekNights sent you Do it Alright, so what do you got?
Rym: and I just want to point out before we go any further than everything I said about Mary Kwame Kilpatrick was taken from Wikipedia, and I hold no veracity to it.
Rym: anyway.
Scott: Yeah, all right and call me Brown is a basketball player.
Scott: Yes that I just got confused with Kwame Kilpatrick, okay?
Scott: So Mary Blair, do you know Mary Blair is?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: Mary Blair is the.
Scott: it's a small world.
Scott: Afterall.
Scott: illustrator it.
Scott: once you see the art.
Scott: You'll be like oh Alright, it is art where when I was a kid I did not appreciate and now that has been brought to my attention yet again.
Scott: I suddenly appreciate it times a billion.
Scott: I don't know why I don't know why but it's amazing and Basically this person on flicker made a small arc.
Scott: I mean let me just read their little description of their set.
Scott: their flicker set a Small archive of Mary Blair images I've culled from the internet including some from animation art dealers and auction sites.
Scott: I started saving the images because I had no clue if I would ever see them again.
Scott: once certain items were bought for private collections Collections I got hiccups or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You got some Alice in Wonderland, which I think is the best part of the collection here.
Scott: You got some Cinderella's.
Scott: you got some Sleeping Beauty's.
Scott: you got some just like greeting card shit.
Scott: It stuff is a pretty freaking awesome stuff here, and if you have any appreciation of Illustrations, and you know that sort of Disney arts you need to take a look at this.
Scott: Yeah, I enjoyed it immensely.
Scott: memorize these funny place names Walla Walla Keokuk Kookamunga So Seattle that's one of my favorite Clips.
Scott: I've been hey I can't believe.
Scott: it's like I've been looking for that clip for a while not that I actually tried hard to search for it But as soon as we decided to put it in the show It just we found it on Hulu immediately, and it was the perfect clip exactly.
Rym: we were walking around Seattle the whole weekend going Seattle, nah, Seattle People were kind of looking at us, but yes GeekNights Rym and Scott the residents of the East Coast Went to that other coast.
Rym: we went to Seattle.
Rym: it was the first time Scott had ever been west of Novi, Michigan.
Rym: It was the first time I had ever been west of Benson in Arizona.
Rym: yeah, no other than flying to Benson kind of not that long before packs.
Rym: I'd only never.
Rym: I'd only been as wet far rest as Chicago.
Scott: up to that point I've decided I want to be Magellan and you know pass through every possible longitude.
Rym: Do you really yep?
Rym: There's some longitudes that aren't that fun?
Scott: I know, but I just have to make it pretty much from Seattle to Israel.
Scott: somehow I'm the other side of the world so flying to China will help a lot.
Scott: right That the hard part is gonna be between China and Israel.
Scott: That's that's the hard longitudes to get.
Scott: maybe I can go to Perth Australia.
Scott: that would get pretty close.
Scott: Anyway in India then Italy.
Scott: there we go.
Rym: if I go from Japan to Australia to India to Italy I'll have it covered all right, so you know because packs is so crazy and gigantic And we're gonna do like seven or eight shows about it at this point or things relating to it.
Rym: Yes, we decided very pointedly to kind of excise out all of the not directly related to packs business.
Rym: So like when we tell the story of Otakon it's got to the point where we'll talk about.
Rym: you know stuff We did in Baltimore and all that kind of business and Katsucon and all these things.
Rym: Now We're gonna do a show kind of all the stuff that we did at packs that had nothing to do with packs.
Scott: Well most of it was eating at restaurants.
Rym: I guess we'd call it a go west young men something like that.
Rym: Yes, first thing.
Rym: I want to say is that you know the Odyssey of us going to Seattle Began with jet blue, and you know we did.
Rym: our business actually was kind of sad because Emily was gonna like see us off And she had to get for me at the.
Rym: but then we we caught the shuttle at like the perfectly wrong time And then we got to the jet blue terminal and JFK and only to discover that basically we're in line there's like 20 people in front of us to check bags and then the line stops moving for a while, and then we discover that the computers have crashed and One by one you see people around us get more and more panicked.
Scott: I'm just chilling cuz I'm like whatever I'm gonna get on my flight.
Scott: You know this computer failure cannot possibly keep me from getting on the plane.
Scott: as long as the plane works This doesn't matter.
Scott: so yeah, well partly only because we were there like three hours before our flight all told yeah But even so it's like no one ever misses their flight because computers mess up Don't you know you?
Scott: eventually they're like oh shit this flight is leaving real soon.
Scott: Hey, who's on this flight?
Scott: That's leaving real soon, and you raise your hand and they say come here come here come here.
Rym: Same time though they were not.
Rym: I mean it kind of bothers me that It seemed like there's no sort of way to work around this at all.
Rym: and jet blues.
Rym: I guess way of dealing with it was to have a young woman yell really quietly Into a roaring crowd which people should come up, and it really wasn't working.
Rym: and I'll bet some people miss their plan and intercom.
Scott: They weren't using.
Scott: I know it was right there right there Yeah, but it didn't cause me a problem so and our flight was delayed by 30 minutes anyway, so whatever.
Rym: yeah chilling in the airport We actually had to go to that kind of creepy other Temporary terminal with a little shuttle off in the car.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't even know that existed.
Scott: people at JFK Airport, right?
Scott: There's this famous terminal.
Scott: terminal five is the old TWA terminal and my dad keeps talking about it all the time.
Rym: because yeah If you're curious just Wikipedia TWA right it's an interesting story.
Scott: basically this terminal opened up to much fanfare and from above It's in the shape of an airplane.
Scott: It was real fancy But it's been for as long as I've been going to JFK.
Scott: the thing has been empty because TWA gone right no more.
Scott: But jet blue basically ran out of space and their terminal which is the next-door terminal which is terminal six.
Scott: So they bought terminal five, but they needed more gates right away.
Scott: So they actually built sort of a temporary terminal behind Terminal five and they have a shuttle bus that takes you there, and I didn't even know it existed.
Scott: But we took it and it worked.
Scott: It was just fine.
Rym: It was totally cool Yeah, the sad thing is though much like how Pax's Wi-Fi wasn't so hot.
Rym: the airport Wi-Fi was real strong But didn't work at all.
Rym: and there's what is this?
Scott: What is this lately with the free you know little local not Wi-Fi networks right having a strong signal?
Scott: But not actually working when you connect to them.
Scott: What is trivial?
Rym: its interference?
Rym: It's actually very difficult to put together a large-scale Wi-Fi network that works well.
Scott: Why don't we sell like a package that people can set up that will work?
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: a package?
Rym: you basically have to put the things in the exact right location right?
Scott: We have a little thing where you walk around with the access point, and then it beeps when it says I'm in a good spot.
Rym: That's not.
Rym: that won't really help you.
Rym: now I won't tell you where to put it.
Rym: also a lot of people don't realize how the antennas should be oriented.
Scott: People don't realize you can change the channels on these things.
Scott: well everyone leaves them all on the same channel.
Scott: They don't change it to like you know 11 and stuff.
Rym: It's not just that I see people point the antennas and dumb.
Rym: well let me put it this way I took an entire class at RIT.
Rym: That was basically where to put access points.
Rym: Yeah, we walked around RIT with detectors, and we oh my god That was a fun class, but the funny thing that was a very popular class to every single quarter.
Scott: I would always see kids with a little push carts walking around doing that.
Rym: but the funny thing was Basically we're sitting there, and there's this cluster of nerds all sitting around with laptops.
Rym: cuz there's an other some holes some outlets.
Rym: They're in a power strip.
Scott: Everyone's got their laptops at me and Rym didn't need the holes cuz we had Fujitsu.
Scott: Hi, everyone else is desperate for the holes.
Rym: one guy's like my battery only lasts an hour.
Rym: this laptops brand-new.
Scott: Yeah, one guy was obviously a PAX guy running Linux.
Scott: Yeah, one guy might have been a PAX guy.
Scott: Yeah, he was an old business man.
Scott: Who was talking too much?
Rym: that old businessman was clearly very drunk.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, he was real.
Scott: He was real talkative.
Scott: He was halfway to drunk.
Rym: Maybe you could smell the liquor on him.
Scott: I didn't smell any liquors.
Rym: man was drunk.
Rym: But whatever we took a late flight.
Rym: so basically we left it like 945 and we got to Seattle at like 1 30 in the morning And then we you know went to bed.
Rym: yeah pretty much collapsed right.
Scott: so we woke up.
Scott: And what do we do in Seattle?
Scott: well we ate food.
Rym: well first you know we got up.
Rym: We had plenty of time before the console.
Rym: we wandered around.
Rym: we went over to the famous by accident the Pike Place Market.
Scott: Yeah, apparently on the water there right cuz you can walk towards the water or away from it And it's not the Pacific Ocean sadly but it's water and there's a lot of boats and ferries and cruise ships and things in that water.
Scott: right and You know there's like this big market like right up on the water there It's it's all sorts of stuff going on.
Scott: It's like this is one fish fish cellar there And he's he's got like people singing and dancing and you know selling fish and throwing fish.
Rym: And I didn't realize what the place was until I saw this monkfish hanging there.
Rym: There was a sign that said hi I'm a monkfish, and I had seen that exact thing on FARC like a hundred times.
Rym: So I suddenly realized wait a minute now.
Rym: I've been the place.
Rym: what where that monkfish has also been.
Scott: It's really touristy down there, but there's all sorts of cool stuff.
Scott: I mean there's a hat shop, right?
Rym: Yeah of all the things we're walking we find this hattery.
Scott: So I have a dasher if you exactly.
Rym: and they hate.
Rym: and the thing is this guy had like one of every possible Kind of hat.
Scott: yeah, I mean you named the kind of hat he's got.
Scott: he got Panama top.
Rym: You had some really classy bowler hats.
Rym: yeah bowler I need one of the.
Rym: I need a new because they used to have this really good Australian leather hat that Eventually shrunk and no one cowboy no longer fit so much.
Rym: I can't head so I need to buy a new Kind of Stetson style.
Rym: I'm a cowboy.
Rym: I'm an Australian awesome, dude.
Rym: I need a leather hat kind of thing beanie Beret.
Rym: the only reason I didn't buy one right then and there in Seattle is the Seattle is that I didn't want to fly At home.
Rym: I can't think of any other kinds of hats yeah, but we walked around and you know Trying to figure out where should we eat breakfast because we never get to eat breakfast anywhere And I'm not gonna linger on this now.
Rym: We went to some random hole-in-the-wall was kind of average-looking and that was one of the best breakfast sandwiches I've ever eaten.
Scott: I mean I really wanted like a big you know waffles pancakes kind of thing But I couldn't find such a place easily.
Rym: I don't think there are diners in Seattle or if there are there was no way for us to find them with.
Scott: He's not like the diners.
Scott: We have in Jersey, New York, Connecticut You know where even the diners in the Midwest there was.
Rym: I couldn't find anything like a diner.
Rym: It was mostly like the course met about the area we were in but was mostly like tap houses and bar and grills and There were a lot of like crepe places and breakfast places that were basically glorified coffee shops selling like scones.
Scott: And there's a lot of coffee shops.
Scott: I mean Seattle's the home of Starbucks.
Scott: It's also the home of Seattle's best coffee.
Scott: It's also the home of like a hundred other like individual independent coffee.
Scott: This is fucking everywhere like I mean in New York.
Scott: You might find like a Chinese restaurant like every few blocks in freakin Seattle.
Scott: There's like two coffees on the side of every block.
Scott: That's like eight coffees per block.
Scott: It's ridiculous.
Rym: The thing is New York City.
Rym: I feel like the density
Scott: of New York City has a lot but only half as many as see how
Rym: I don't think so you see yeah, maybe just I'm in Midtown, but there are I Exactly eight Starbucks within a trivial walk of my office and I've gone to all of them more than once Yeah,
Scott: but
Rym: I feel like despite it being the whole like everyone says yes, Seattle Starbucks blah blah blah.
Rym: The I guess proportion of Starbucks to other coffee shops was actually real low.
Scott: Third a third maybe at most with Starbucks.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: it's hard to tell.
Scott: Yeah, I know a lot of Starbucks, but there are a lot of non Starbucks - anyway Yeah, but so we walk around with this.
Rym: really good, but we couldn't find like yeah We couldn't find like a diner or anything.
Scott: So we just find a place It's like, you know cafe whatever and we go in and we say make me you know Bacon egg and cheese on an English muffin and it was bacon egg and cheese in an English muffin.
Scott: But yeah, it's like.
Scott: it wasn't like this so amazing breakfast But it was like they put like an extra care into making it and it was actually really sad.
Rym: It's like they spent like imagine if someone just makes a sandwich, right?
Rym: Imagine if the same person spent five more seconds on that sandwich.
Scott: that makes a lot of difference Actually, and they put a little bit of care into it and I was like, oh that was real.
Scott: And then as soon as you take two steps, we see a place.
Rym: This is breakfast on the window and I'm like, ah We just talk about all the breakfast we had right now.
Rym: All right, so Place what a show this.
Rym: is that Seattle?
Scott: Yeah the place that we saw that said breakfast on the window.
Scott: We ate there for breakfast the next day.
Scott: Also, not a diner basically a coffee shop basically a coffee shop and you know, it was over.
Rym: It was weird.
Rym: They didn't have Sausage or bacon?
Scott: Yeah, no, you couldn't order it.
Rym: I was like like.
Rym: I'm looking at the menu and I'm looking for like because I don't.
Rym: I wanted like I don't know Scrambled eggs and sausage and bacon and some pancakes, but no I couldn't get anything like that.
Scott: Yeah, what did I get?
Scott: I get a waffle.
Rym: I think yeah like a waffle.
Scott: I think I got the Belgian waffle and I think I was slightly disappointed.
Scott: I think it was slightly overpriced.
Rym: Another thing I can say that's right.
Scott: I got a good beverage though.
Scott: And but yeah, you didn't you didn't you picked a bad?
Scott: Well, I failed.
Scott: you failed.
Rym: another thing that there's a lot of juice bars and a lot of hippie Randy BS in Seattle.
Scott: Yeah, it's not so much hippie Randy BS as much as it's just general hippiness a little bit of Randy But a lot of you know, sorta the Randy was more diffuse Yeah, definitely different.
Scott: there was a lot of Randy there was there was he was sort of hidden a little bit.
Scott: It wasn't surface Randy.
Scott: It was like, you know, take a step in, you know beyond the you know Just typical hippiness and then the Randy is, you know back there.
Rym: Yeah there I mean I saw a lot of reflexology people walking around with signs now.
Rym: But anyway, it was just weird that in at no time in Seattle Was I able to get a breakfast likening to what I would eat in New York or Michigan?
Scott: Well, you know people on Twitter right and Twitter is actually helpful in this respect to find a place to eat.
Scott: they said to just go eat it like, you know, the.
Rym: You know the Pike place bar and grill for you know breakfast Yeah, and it turns out actually a lot of those bar and grill places during the day just serve breakfast But again, not a diner breakfast.
Rym: kind of weird not quite.
Scott: No Well, I mean, I got French toast and bacon and that was actually really good bacon's.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta talk about one thing though because we're we kept walking past this New York style bagel place And you know, I keep it's kind of.
Scott: it's funny wait there on Labor Day.
Rym: I think it's kind of like someone who say you're I don't know you're in you're live in Chicago You go to Florida and you see like Chicago style pizza.
Rym: I definitely got that kind of Bob.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: It's like if you go to somewhere in Jersey or even farther.
Scott: you like, Florida and they're like Philly cheesesteak.
Rym: You're like, ah, no, no, no, no, however, I can say one thing bagels taste the same everywhere.
Scott: It depends.
Rym: now it is the thing bagels taste the same.
Rym: These were actually bagels.
Rym: if they make it the way you make a bagel it tastes the same Tasted exactly the same.
Scott: It was an okay bagel, but it was identical to the bagel.
Rym: I get it.
Rym: the hot and crusty.
Scott: No, the hot and crusty isn't the isn't the best bagel in the universe either, but it was identical to that.
Rym: What better bagel?
Scott: Yeah, we got to Queens.
Scott: I'll get you some big.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: I don't think there's any difference.
Rym: There's a line.
Rym: there's a line beyond which a bagel is a bagel.
Scott: Yeah, there there are some really good bagels out there.
Scott: I don't know You don't have to do mouth.
Rym: So you don't you wouldn't know I don't have the Jew mouth.
Rym: bagels in Seattle Tastes the same as bagels here.
Scott: No, that bagel was you know, did the?
Scott: it would tasted different than a hot and crusty bagel But it was about equivalent quality level.
Rym: No, anyway, this is you got it with capers and stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it was awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I got I got.
Scott: they just didn't give me just you know, we're on that.
Scott: We're on the water.
Scott: There's this fish.
Scott: There's a fish market where people are singing and dancing fish fish.
Scott: So I didn't just get a bagel with lox and cream cheese.
Scott: I got a bagel with lox and cream cheese tomato onion and capers.
Rym: I got a bagel with extra lox and cream cheese.
Scott: All right, it was good times.
Rym: Yeah enough about breakfast.
Rym: Let's talk about Seattle.
Scott: No, you only want to talk about lunch.
Scott: Let's talk about Seattle a little alright, so Seattle is kind of weird at least the part that we were in one.
Rym: It felt like this is my sound strange Maybe just cuz we're from New York, but it felt Really really small and really really uncrowded like.
Scott: it also felt sort of like a shopping mall Like even you're on the street, but it felt like you're in a shopping mall.
Rym: now granted we wandered You know, we didn't wander around all of Seattle like I really wanted to go to Fremont, but we didn't have time but We wandered pretty far and everywhere felt kind of the same in the streets Like the sidewalks are really wide and even on like Friday.
Rym: There really weren't people in the streets.
Scott: It was weird because I saw these huge buildings, right?
Scott: And I said there must be a bajillion employees in that building.
Scott: and I could understand those employees not being in town Saturday Sunday Labor Day, but in Friday, it didn't seem like those employees were around.
Scott: even around five o'clock.
Scott: I didn't see them spilling into the streets, you know, that building must have like thousands thousands of desks in it.
Scott: I didn't see thousands of thousands people come pouring out of the building, you know.
Scott: And there are a lot of those buildings.
Scott: and I was like where the hell are all the people?
Scott: it never Felt crowded.
Scott: that just might be because they've got the traffic down, you know Even though I doubt it cuz anyone who's from anywhere will always complain about traffic no matter what.
Rym: well one thing I can say That might just really good.
Rym: Walking around on Friday and even after the con I saw more people who were there because of packs than I did people who live there.
Scott: Yeah, really walking around even like going far away I would say one-third to one-half of the people I saw Outside of the convention center at any moment in time where Pat were packs people.
Rym: now, you know I was really wondering about that.
Rym: and finally, you know, I looked on Wikipedia I'm on Wikipedia right now to to remember the number the population of Seattle is only like 600,000 people.
Rym: Really yeah, there's.
Rym: I mean, there's like four million people in the greater metro area, but in Seattle is Basically two and a half of the suburb.
Rym: I lived in in Michigan Whoa, and as a result think of this packs was like a 12th of the population of Seattle.
Scott: So one in 12 people.
Scott: that that seems about right.
Rym: that does seem about right all things considered because packs people would be more likely To be outside as opposed to in a building because we didn't know where to go or wander and walking around looking around Walking around looking around.
Scott: it was the streets were a nice grid.
Scott: I mean at first I was a little disoriented but I sort of used the water and away from the water as guides and You know east and west of the convention center as guides and my hotel.
Scott: the red line is pretty tall So I can sort of figure out where it was.
Scott: and I learned where I was going pretty quick And I had a lot of landmarks and it was sort of like, you know Learning your way around a map in a video game.
Scott: you walk around a little bit Just not knowing where you're going.
Scott: you just keep walking and then within a few minutes You only passed by a place twice, you know coming from two different directions and you've got to figure it out.
Rym: But impressions of Seattle.
Rym: this might be stereotypical but and I think I mentioned it on the Tuesday show, but I'd like to mention it again No one in Seattle.
Rym: jaywalks Like they just don't.
Rym: there'll be no traffic in either direction like not like not a car as far as you can see lights red Crowd of people just stand there just stand and wait Yeah, and then we walk and then sometimes when you walk someone else will follow you.
Scott: but I don't think anyone Instigated a jaywalk other than us.
Rym: and even then people who followed us and not just us.
Rym: when I say us I mean Everyone from New York because you could pick out the other New Yorkers
Scott: easily
Rym: You'd see him in the distance walking twice as fast as everyone in the street
Scott: Actually had trouble readjusting to New York walking after Seattle walking I'm bumping into people and I'm like, oh, yeah, right people I have to actually, you know walk properly.
Scott: Yeah cuz yeah, I got real lazy with my walking in Seattle.
Scott: You can just walk all willy-nilly on this big wide empty side.
Rym: Yeah, it was cool.
Rym: Like if I want as fast as you want like we saw this map store, right?
Rym: So when we saw the map store, like we stopped outside of it like just in the sidewalk I just stopped and was looking at it.
Scott: if I did that in New York, I'd be dead Wouldn't be dead but two people would have bumped into your ass and go an asshole.
Rym: I Actually, I want to talk about that map source.
Rym: That was really cool.
Scott: So we see this map store.
Scott: and the second time we see the map store We decided to go into the map store as a store.
Rym: They sell maps globes and related Cartographical items at live perhaps charts all those sorts of things.
Rym: now There's a map store near where I work in Manhattan, but it's basically one of those hagstrom kind of you know Useful modern maps of things and nautical charts and GPS.
Rym: is not that BS?
Rym: This was the map store equivalent of like a geek gamer store for gamers, it was like map geeks would come here.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and the thing is the guy the proprietor of the store was the old man.
Rym: Obviously he was.
Rym: this dude was a mad geek and you could totally tell.
Rym: so we walk in and the guys like Can I help you?
Rym: and he's like, you know, he's nice, but he's not excited He's.
Rym: he's probably like the game store guy.
Scott: who's thinking Imagine if you run a video game a regular board game store.
Scott: Right, you sell the CCG's and the D&D but you also sell the good stuff, right?
Scott: Some kid comes in and says I want you geocards.
Scott: So here you go.
Scott: kid kid walks in says he wants magic cards.
Scott: Here you go kid kid walks in says he wants World of Warcraft miniatures.
Scott: Here you go kid Guy walks in says he wants some Warhammer minis.
Scott: All right.
Scott: All right, this guy's gonna make some big money here.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: guy comes in.
Scott: He says hey, I heard about this burning wheel and you go, ho ho ho Did you now?
Scott: We were like that.
Scott: No, did you now to this map guy?
Rym: It's basically I had no plan.
Rym: I walked in cuz a cool store.
Rym: I'm bored I got plenty of time and then the guy, you know, can I help you?
Rym: and I don't just say no, I'm all right.
Rym: I think a minute I consider the question and then I turned to him and say Actually, do you happen to have any period nautical charts or military maps from the Napoleonic War era particularly of the English Channel?
Rym: and he's pauses and he looks up thoughtfully and Then like he seems to get really excited like he starts moving his fists up and down like uh, I don't think so but but hold on bear with me bear with me.
Rym: and he starts going through all these maps and things and he's looking in this reference book and like trying to cross reference and then he's like, no, I don't have any.
Rym: no one's really asked for anything like that before.
Rym: but Tell you what.
Rym: What you should do is call the library of.
Rym: and he starts giving me all this crazy advice about How to get a hold of like nautical charts period nautical charts of the English Channel.
Rym: and he's super excited and like ten minutes He tells me the business.
Scott: How do you open up a map store if you're not a map nerd?
Scott: I mean, come on.
Rym: I have a feeling that we made this dude's day.
Scott: It's weird cuz in New York City, there's a store of every kind right but everything's crammed in and tight, right?
Scott: So and unless you know where a lot of these things are because a lot of them are not in the crowded thoroughfares, right?
Scott: They're off to the sides and the villages or whatnot where you don't go too often.
Scott: You're not gonna know about them.
Scott: You have to sort of look them up and then specifically go to where they are.
Scott: You know, I mean, I'm sure there's a map store in the city.
Scott: I could find if I searched for it, but I had to search Seattle.
Scott: We actually walked around I'd say effectively all of downtown Seattle at least where there was stuff.
Rym: now only downtown.
Rym: We clearly did not get to all the other off.
Scott: We didn't go to the residential areas or say the college area Seattle itself is sitting on the borders of the city of Seattle were big but the downtown Seattle.
Scott: You could actually walk around all of it.
Scott: You know at least you know, most of the important parts.
Scott: pretty quickly.
Scott: if you don't you know Go like a slow Seattle person according to Wikipedia.
Rym: Seattle was originally called New York.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yes The only members of the party that did not migrate to the Eastern Shore Established a village they initially called New York after Terry's hometown.
Rym: Oh They eventually renamed it alkie a Chinook a Chinook word.
Rym: Sorry I'm reading from Wikipedia quickly meaning by and by or someday blah blah blah blah blah blah Eventually Seattle.
Scott: What does Seattle come from?
Rym: comes after chief seal of Duwamish and the squamish tribes Go him.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: Maybe we should call it, New York.
Rym: Yeah Now anyway, but yeah, you know we walked her out We went to.
Rym: we went to this weird store and all I want to say about it is one.
Rym: it had two items of note items of interest Item.
Rym: the first a really really big and scary statue of Mark Twain.
Scott: Oh this door item.
Rym: the second a miniature version of that a version of that exact same Creepy-ass hot dog in Wildwood.
Scott: They also had these cool Uncle Scrooge statues and some cool pirate statues.
Scott: It's basically one of those, you know Asian import stores, but they seem to specialize in like, you know big statue things Especially Disney ones, however, I kind of wish about.
Scott: they got that uncle Scrooge statue at the same time.
Rym: The smell the store smelled vaguely of incense used to cover weed and I could not find a proprietor.
Scott: There was a proprietor.
Scott: I saw them go into the back as we came in.
Scott: Ah Possibly to burn some incense possibly to run away from us crazies from New York.
Rym: Yeah at that point I think we still look like New Yorkers cuz I kind of had my gate going again.
Scott: Yeah, we also went to this toy store, which is pretty much just old-fashioned toy store You know doesn't sell modern toys sells real toys and they had some good stuff in there But nothing I haven't seen anywhere else really.
Scott: It's not that I can remember.
Rym: one thing I can say though That was cool.
Rym: Was that a row you had?
Scott: they had a horse head on a stick?
Rym: Oh, yeah, they did but our row are you know, our listener was taking us around her and her boyfriend and her Asian posse.
Rym: More on them later.
Scott: Yeah Asian posse.
Scott: What's up?
Rym: Yeah, I got to respect them in a big way because Inverse wizard hat is one of the funniest things I've heard in life.
Rym: But anyway, so, uh, you know, she kept saying yeah, we should eat at the food court at the Westlake Mall.
Rym: It's the best food court ever.
Rym: Yeah, let's go get lunch there.
Rym: and I you know, we were polite but I was thinking the whole time Mall food court.
Scott: I was kind of okay with the mall food court cuz we'd ate at basically every other meal Except for that breakfast sandwich was at a real restaurant sitting down getting a real meal.
Scott: So I'm like, okay We should eat more food court once.
Rym: Yeah, but you know, I was still like, I don't know mall food court Especially cuz I got a while I was expecting it to be like, you know The mall food court at Otakon in a little mall there.
Rym: So when they said this is the best mall food court in the world.
Rym: They were not kidding.
Rym: Oh my god This place was exciting.
Scott: I mean it had a McDonald's.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Okay head of Sbarro's Everything else in there except the McDonald's and the Sbarro's was awesome.
Rym: I had to choose between the really good-looking Thai food the really good-smelling Indian food and the Awesome-looking Greek food.
Rym: I ended up eating and the crepes.
Scott: Oh my god The crepes their crepes everywhere and in Seattle for some.
Rym: I ended up eating a pile of falafel and hummus and baba ghanoush and dalmati.
Scott: I got the Thai food which came with the mango lemonade.
Scott: Take that.
Rym: I got a dr.
Rym: Pepper because I had to wash down the the mass of falafel larger than I should have gotten.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically a mall food court and except for the McDonald's and the Sbarro's every place in there was like a good Interesting clean and awesome looking kind of food.
Rym: Yes speaking of clean I gotta say I love New York and you know, you can't you don't get ever accuse me of disliking New York City.
Rym: But Seattle really didn't smell like pee at all except everything was really clean except for there's one like one Side like one Street between two kind of intersections smelled like pee and had this dilapidated Johnny Rockets.
Rym: But everything else was awesome and clean.
Scott: It was one area was sort of weird, but everything else was really clean.
Rym: Yeah And the weird thing that area was like between the two nice areas that area was like dilapidated Johnny Rockets Scary pawn shop that Johnny Rockets freaked me out cuz I never saw it open.
Scott: It was dark inside.
Scott: But if I looked in the window Now first of all, there's no indication that it was supposed to be closed or anything.
Scott: But if you looked in the window, everything was set up all the napkins are still in there and everything It was just never open.
Rym: Yeah, but right across the street was like the scariest looking hobo alley I've ever seen?
Rym: Yeah, partly because alleys are a rare thing to find in New York City.
Rym: They're not that.
Scott: No, there's plenty of alleys in New York City Manhattan.
Rym: Not so many.
Rym: Well, there are.
Scott: they just sort of closed up Not alleys anymore.
Rym: They've been converted into other things.
Rym: They're not open alleys that go to that area behind.
Rym: That's all cool.
Scott: No, the area.
Scott: usually if you live in the building you get to the area behind real easily.
Rym: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: I mean when I lived usually the alleys just have like a door.
Rym: When I lived in Detroit, there was a functional old-school alley Behind my house and that is how we all got access to our garages.
Scott: Yeah I mean my grandma lived in Queens.
Scott: basically it was you know 169th Street the next street was just an alley with garages on both sides of it facing inwards.
Scott: then 170th Street.
Scott: there was you know, there was an alley between every row of houses.
Scott: It was like a little mini street that was wide enough for one car and had garages and backyards on both sides.
Rym: But there's one thing really really cool about Seattle and that is the the catenary bus public transit.
Rym: It is kind of like it's like And a bus which could be awesome if implemented properly.
Scott: I mean not every bus was using the catenaries.
Scott: people don't know.
Scott: catenary is the overhead electric wires, right?
Scott: Because like express buses that went out of town and came into town were like hybrids or motors or whatever.
Scott: But all the buses that sort of stayed in town use the overhead electricity To power themselves rather than you know A gasoline engine or whatnot.
Scott: and there was actually on Monday when we were walking around when the convention was over We went to the bus terminal where there was like crazy wires all over the place and like tunnels and all sorts of weird Shit, and they actually they had a special tunnel for these buses to go in where there was electricity down there.
Rym: Yes, basically anyone who says buses don't work as mass transit and buses suck.
Rym: You're right.
Rym: They suck everywhere except Seattle.
Scott: I think they still suck in Seattle, but they suck less But they're still Better.
Scott: not
Rym: only did I see a lot of people using them and not only did they look like they made a lot of sense But the everyone I talked to where buses came up basically, you know, if I mentioned yeah from New York They said something along the lines of the buses work pretty damn.
Scott: Well, yeah, they're not perfect, but they they work the catternet.
Rym: I think they really cool.
Scott: Yeah, I think they work as well as buses work.
Scott: The only problem is you can't carry around tall sticks in Seattle.
Rym: No, I was actually until I got used to it even though they were like 10 feet above my head I was real nervous about them because I wasn't nervous I didn't notice them both.
Scott: I was nervous.
Rym: It was more that I'd be walking around walking around looking around and like suddenly I'd look up and suddenly like oh shit They're right there.
Rym: Yeah, especially when I was upstairs in buildings.
Rym: I'd seem like right out the window like looking at me.
Scott: Yeah, I'd be scared if I was like the second floor of a building on a balcony.
Scott: I'd be wicked scared.
Scott: but on the sidewalk I didn't even really notice them at all except when a bus came down the street and it was actually pretty cool.
Scott: the buses You know that to connect to these wires.
Scott: somehow They were at these intelligent things that moved around and always connected to them and I never saw them fall off.
Scott: So the technology worked really well.
Rym: So speaking of mass transit in Seattle, obviously There is no subway.
Scott: No, it's not that I know about but there is a monorail.
Rym: now Here's what I knew about the monorail before I went to Seattle.
Rym: one relic from the World's Fair leads to the Space Needle
Scott: You know did a whole bunch of things but also Took you to the Space Needle and that you know, I was like, oh well If we're gonna go to the Space Needle Monday, we might as well use the monorail.
Scott: it exists, right?
Scott: So we go near that mall with the awesome food court and to get on the monorail.
Rym: first discovery Oh the monorail only goes to the Space Needle.
Rym: Okay, that's cool.
Rym: Yeah Okay, so we get on the monorail for $2 right $2 Yes and I point out this is where we ran into for the I think the second time and then we finally kind of Semi-hooked up with.
Scott: there was this cool Scottish do.
Rym: awesome Scottish, dude.
Rym: So if you remember GeekNights and you you know, you're listening to this right now We lost you about halfway through the side the sci-fi museum.
Rym: you were totally cool and it was totally cool hanging out with you for what we did.
Rym: and Scotland's awesome and I'm glad we got to talk to you and I hope to talk to you.
Scott: Yes This is awesome Scottish shooting.
Scott: I think we met him around our panel and a little bit afterwards then he was staying in our hotel And we happen to bump into him a bunch of times going into the hotel.
Scott: He also stuck around Monday to do tourism.
Rym: So we were sticking with him Monday doing terrorism and it was great because basically at one point we're talking about politics and he was not in any way shy about his political views.
Rym: and Basically, he was like, yeah, he hates the Bush administration He hates.
Rym: he was the complain ability's like yeah, but I can't complain because Tony Blair was just as much as a cock up.
Rym: But then we start with like.
Rym: he was like, how did this happen?
Rym: So we were explaining like, you know, what happened in America and all how it is real simply and like You know how the government works.
Scott: You're sort of like, oh, that's how it works.
Scott: Alrighty.
Rym: He was really interested.
Rym: Then he started telling us about Scotland and it was also really interesting.
Rym: So dude, I don't think we're gonna mention you again But you were totally cool.
Scott: send us an email and join our forums or something.
Scott: If you join the forums Just go to the identify yourself there and say I'm Scottish dude and don't be offended if I say Scotland because I like saying it Boy Even though it's Australia that says oh and I mean, uh, Scrooge McDuck.
Scott: I mean, come on.
Scott: Anyway, that's Scottish, right?
Rym: So I'm the man.
Rym: So one monorail, you know monorail.
Rym: What's that?
Rym: Monorail, right?
Scott: This monorail was pretty lame.
Scott: I don't remember the monorail trip.
Scott: It was so quick.
Rym: I do I actually got a really good view of the place the way we walked back.
Rym: basically Here's the deal.
Rym: So we get off the monorail and it felt like it was going real fast.
Rym: We get pretty far and we're all right space needle, but let's just come back to the monorail.
Rym: So I see the space needle and first off, you know, this is definitely Rym the turtles coming out.
Rym: But scholars the same way and I think a lot of people have never been to Seattle.
Rym: Every depiction of Seattle is that the the space needle is like this looming edifice.
Scott: I mean the Seattle supersonics no longer exist.
Scott: They just moved to Oklahoma City, but their logo right the space needle had a prominent position on their logo.
Scott: It's like a part of the skyline in every depiction of Seattle every illustration, right?
Scott: I mean when the Empire State Building is part of the New York skyline Frazier crane the Seattle thinking like it's big.
Rym: it's there when we got to Seattle I didn't see it at all.
Rym: And eventually I was like, where is it?
Rym: locals were like, oh, no, no It's just really far away.
Rym: It's big if you're over there.
Rym: So we finally get there and I'm not making fun of you Seattle because I think the space needle is awesome.
Scott: I mean, basically it's.
Scott: I mean we have our World's Fair shit in New York and we let it rust.
Scott: So mad props to you for not letting it rust.
Scott: but it's not that tall.
Scott: It's only 500 feet.
Rym: I've been on roller coasters that weren't that much smaller than that.
Rym: Well, no, it's 500 and it's 600 feet tall, but you can only get 500 feet up.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: All right All right, even so that one dude, it's not that speed up because he has to climb out there and change that light bulb.
Scott: Yeah, that was that was pretty cool.
Scott: There is a cool fun facts about the Space Needle and it's a pretty cool structure and you know, it's not that bad But it's not that impressive either.
Scott: I mean I paid $15 to go up at once.
Scott: I'll never pay $15 to go up it again.
Scott: Let me just say that much and I was sort of disappointed.
Scott: There's a revolving restaurant in a Space Needle that we didn't eat at cuz it was ultra overpriced like quadruple the price of normal food.
Rym: It didn't look that good either.
Rym: but for anyone who thinks that the Space Needle rotates and then you can sit in the restaurant No, the restaurant floor rotates.
Scott: Yeah, I was disappointed by that.
Scott: I thought at least like one floor or like one section of the needle rotated.
Scott: But no, it's just the floor in this one restaurant rotates in it.
Scott: I was saddened by that, too.
Rym: Okay I've read the Wikipedia here.
Rym: I gotta read this because obviously someone is messing with Wikipedia Space Needle Wikipedia.
Rym: Three people have committed suicide by leaping from the Space Needle's observation platform.
Scott: How could you?
Scott: they had so many wires I couldn't even get out if I wanted to blah blah blah.
Rym: two of them jumped in 1974 before a safety grid was installed around the platform.
Rym: Okay now I'm sad because the safety grid was kind of annoying and it was a little bit.
Scott: It made it hard to take pictures.
Rym: Blah blah blah blah blah now.
Rym: No Tell me if you can figure out when Wikipedia is being gamed.
Rym: The only known person to survive and jump from the Space Needle was Alexander Gucci a student from Canada Who afterwards ate a 72-ounce steak in 15 minutes and walked around on his hands for three days.
Rym: Okay, there's a citation.
Rym: Talk I'm gonna follow.
Scott: this thing is the real deal it could be.
Rym: anyway the citation doesn't go.
Rym: Alright, you keep talking.
Scott: I'm reading this citation here So the Space Needle us, you know You got a good view from there because everything around it was sort of low down Meanwhile mean going around is a Space Needle was you know a park?
Scott: because there was a World's Fair there at one point.
Scott: so there was still a park there and The park had this sort of Bumbershoot music festival going on Which is pretty popular and there were a lot of people hanging out going in.
Scott: We thought about going in.
Scott: it would have cost us 40 bucks to get in there if we didn't have to fly out that night.
Rym: We totally would have stayed and seen some popular music concerts, right?
Scott: But you know, I didn't know any of the bands and I wasn't too interested and I you know I only had one day there before we had to go home that night.
Scott: So we didn't go in but we saw what was going on from up above and it looked like a pretty happening.
Scott: You know the citations a lollapalooza kind of music festival.
Rym: I realized something though.
Rym: We could have just gone up the Space Needle because it's right there.
Rym: We could have totally seen the concerts and heard them pretty well from the Space Needle.
Scott: Yeah There was one concert going on the main stage and we could hear it kind of okay from up there and the main you pay To get up the Space Needle.
Scott: You can stay up there till it closes It's not?
Scott: you just pay a price to get up and it's free to stay there and go down when the main stage is like Right there.
Rym: It's like you could easily listen.
Rym: But uh, you know I think the Space Needle is awesome because I like it when people take things that are old and cool like World's Fair stuff and just keep it around.
Rym: but we get to the top and I look out and I see where we got on the stupid monorail.
Rym: It's right there.
Rym: We could have walked in in like 15 minutes, maybe 10 minutes.
Scott: Yeah, so the monorail is for stupid really lazy people and it's sort of useless.
Rym: it was right there Like and then you know at the top and the Scottish guys like you couldn't walk there Referring to this high school at the top.
Rym: I think Queen Anne's Hill, but you could totally walk there.
Rym: You can walk like everywhere.
Rym: It was all right there.
Scott: Yeah pretty much for the Space Needle.
Scott: We can see all the different parts of Seattle and to most of them We could have walked easily.
Scott: Like you.
Scott: look at the Queen Anne's Hill with this fancy building at the top and I look at it And it looks like it's pretty steep hill and I guess it is kind of steep, but then we walk down.
Scott: I look I look closer at it.
Scott: It's four city blocks tall.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's just four city blocks up the hill.
Rym: So we know we walked to the base of it and we could have just walked up.
Scott: I didn't want to walk up because I really didn't want to walk around where people's houses are.
Rym: I kind of did I wanted to see but Scott wanted to see people's houses.
Rym: I wanted to walk around the different neighborhoods.
Rym: get a feel for it.
Scott: It's just people's houses.
Scott: I can understand walking around, you know, non Maine neighborhoods, but not just residential neighborhoods.
Rym: I had a lot of fun walking around New York City just random places like through the brownstones and things but those aren't.
Scott: You know, it depends where you are.
Scott: a lot of the places in New York, you know There's always stuff at the bottom even though it's residential up top not in the midst of like the brownstones in Brooklyn Yeah, anyway, which I've wandered around because I think they're cool.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, we walked around Scott looking Scott's flicker I don't know if you uploaded yet, but we took pictures of all the kind of cool and weird stuff We saw.
Rym: we found this awesome donut place.
Scott: Well, we went to up before you're getting ahead.
Scott: He went to the sci-fi museum.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we should probably save that for a separate show cuz we're already going on kind of long.
Scott: Oh, do you want to say we're separate show?
Rym: I think we should.
Rym: there's a Monday.
Rym: Basically.
Scott: There's a sci-fi museum and it's okay It's.
Scott: I heard bad things about it, but we went anyway because we're kind of unjustified.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't super amazing, but I had some good stuff that was worth seeing.
Rym: Yeah, there were some really neat artifacts in there including a Death Star.
Scott: Yeah, I mean museum wise it, you know has it definitely had some negatives.
Scott: But actually there was this temporary exhibit temporary meaning like six months about you know They had a bunch of toy robots and I was liking that action, but I enjoyed it and we'll talk about it some Monday.
Scott: All right, but you know we wanted around.
Rym: all I want to say about this donut place is oh my god She's one of them.
Rym: one of those needs to be in New York City and that donut place had more.
Scott: Fill up your shelf with books.
Scott: You're never gonna read books that I've ever seen.
Scott: in one place at a time even more than like big furniture stores.
Rym: They had real donuts.
Rym: Hey, we're not.
Scott: Krispy Kremes Cinnamon sugar blueberry donut.
Rym: I had a real sour cream dough.
Scott: It was like a blueberry muffin, but donut Yeah with cinnamon sugar, you know, we wandered around saw a bunch of other weird stuff and it's not this place.
Scott: It was like Wexley school for girls.
Scott: I don't know what it is.
Scott: I should look it up.
Rym: I kept meaning to yeah, we didn't look it up, but we took a picture of it.
Rym: It was so weird.
Rym: We were trying to figure out what it was.
Scott: I'm looking it up right now.
Scott: Wexley school for girls based in Seattle is.
Scott: there's a flash loading.
Rym: flash loading Hold on.
Rym: All right but one thing I'll say well see how it talks about that is that Seattle is really vertical like not in terms of buildings or anything cuz there weren't that many skyscrapers and things.
Rym: but in that like all the parks we went to were they were more like terrace gardens and like Everything was multi-leveled and you'd enter and exit buildings on different floors.
Rym: It was kind of cool that way cuz you know It's built like there's hills about and there's steep streets and things.
Rym: but winding through all this parks Really made clear the fact that parkour is real big in Seattle.
Rym: And in fact one of the cool dudes in the Asian posse Really into parkour is like in this parkour club.
Rym: and I was thinking alright I guess Seattle's where the cool parkour people are now.
Rym: I know why you walk around any park in Seattle and you're like, oh Shit here's where the parkour be.
Rym: Oh my god, if I if I were a parker dude, I could totally jump over that.
Scott: Yeah, dad I know I didn't was listening to you because I was reading about the Wexley school for girls, which is just a Really awesome and quirky marketing agency.
Rym: Oh Yeah, but I guess it worked.
Scott: There was this awesome park attached to the convention center that went like all the way down the highway And it was pretty big, you know relative to Seattle, you know, it's like multiple city blocks and it Basically was all these ups and downs and lefts and rights and circles and benches and concrete and trees and it was really kind Of funky and definitely, you know the kind of place where you can go and film a wicked movie and do some parkour.
Rym: Yeah, so we wanted around there.
Rym: We we kept saying how do some parkour?
Rym: we didn't do any parkour.
Rym: Oh my god We would have died.
Rym: No Yeah, but die out, you know, we wanted around.
Rym: Seattle was a pretty fun place.
Rym: I'm stalling for time because I'm gonna end this show kind of soon.
Rym: Talk about the game works though.
Rym: We should review the game works on a Tuesday.
Scott: Let me just say what I'll just tell this real quick.
Scott: when I was younger on TV When game works was a new place I saw this story like oh my god game works, right and it was basically like we're opening up an awesome arcade in Seattle and a bunch of other places but the flagship one is in Seattle and I saw that and I was like, oh man I want to go there right and You know later on a place like Dave and Buster's opened up and Jillian's and they were sort of the restaurant arcade Places, you know, they were
Rym: all right.
Scott: They went downhill over time though.
Scott: Dave and Buster's is cool got uncool You know, the VR was big back then, you know, and they showed off all sorts of laser tag and battle tag and all that business.
Scott: So I wondered when I was going to Seattle does game work still exist?
Scott: and yes Yes, it does.
Scott: But it's just a Sega arcade now.
Scott: The VR is gone.
Scott: It's pretty much just a sports bar and a bunch of arcade games.
Scott: But the prices on the games are reasonable unlike Dave and Buster's and Jillian's.
Scott: Every game fifty cents Yeah, and they had you know, like indie racing to the big indie racing machine, which is wicked old-school But wicked awesome now despite the fact that I've only ever played it, you know once before at Epcot Center in Disney World.
Rym: Well, here we'll sum it up.
Rym: It was the best arcade I've walked into in like nine years, but it was still And not the greatest.
Scott: yeah had many flaws, but it was better than any arcade I've been to in a long time.
Scott: They actually had the f-zero game, even though it was somewhat broken.
Scott: They had initial d4.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Oh, yeah They had three DDRs, but the only good one was a supernova which it wasn't even that good.
Scott: They had the The the newest version the ninth version of the the drumming game.
Scott: Yes, taiko drummer taiko drum master super fun to play On the right drum.
Scott: One of the sensors is a little broken.
Rym: Yeah, we were playing that with some other packs.
Rym: guy We ran into.
Scott: yeah, I finally figured out how to play it and I'm actually kind of good at it.
Rym: Yeah, I got up to the high did the hardest song in the highest difficulty.
Rym: I played the hurry theme.
Scott: That's how I knew it was.
Scott: Yeah They had classic games, you know, they had really bad air hockey to use multiple pucks.
Rym: Oh, yeah There's a point.
Rym: there were like five pucks out and we each had two paddles and the giant goal.
Scott: It was really bad.
Rym: I point out I won by like 18.
Rym: It was really bad Yeah, but I point out that bad or not.
Rym: I won anyway.
Scott: important thing is that I what happened to this doesn't mean shit Cuz it's such a bad air hockey.
Rym: unless I win then it means you win.
Scott: It's only a means.
Rym: But one thing I don't want to talk about all the restaurants I was playing for serious because it didn't matter.
Rym: Well, one thing I want to talk about is that you know We kept kind of just randomly picking restaurants and some were good and some were mediocre, but whatever somewhere,
Scott: you know Some were good, but they were overpriced, you know, like we ate at one place the Daily Grill and it was okay.
Scott: It was good food, but paid too much for it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean cuz at one point I was eating there.
Rym: Then I suddenly thought you know for like seven bucks at the Alumni Grill I could have a burger with cheese sticks and onion rings instead of cheese.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you got a burger for the Daily Grill and you know, it's like what 20 bucks something like that.
Scott: But for seven bucks at the Alumni Grill in Wildwood, New Jersey, you could have had all man's.
Rym: but at the same time You know, finally we're like, all right and instead of trying to use a food thing or a website or just winging it People on Twitter apparently kept talking about Vons.
Scott: Well, I think a couple of people mentioned Vons and I saw Vons and we tried to eat there once and the dining room was Closed for the night because it was late.
Scott: So we ate there on Labor Day during the happy hour.
Rym: I you know, maybe just because of my life, but I've never actually been in a bar during a happy hour.
Rym: They had this big wheel, right?
Rym: So we're sitting directly under the wheel and they say first of all, seat yourself.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, and all I'm gonna say is I ordered like This was one of the biggest pieces of meat I've ever eaten.
Rym: It was a gigantic prime rib.
Scott: It was I ordered the special that you could only order on Monday night and it was.
Scott: it was.
Scott: it was Monday afternoon.
Scott: ish I got these like beef ribs.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Rym: This was.
Rym: I would say that this is probably finish the final rib.
Rym: It was probably you get the prime rib third or it was.
Rym: I got some cooked properly.
Rym: Prime rib on a big piece of bread on a giant piece of fried cornbread.
Rym: Ah Yes, and the cornbread?
Rym: by the time I finished the steak was filled with fat and grease And oh my god, it was.
Rym: it was like 30 bucks.
Scott: It was expensive, but it wasn't nearly as expensive as some of the other ones.
Scott: in terms of dollar per value.
Rym: It was totally the third or fourth best prime rib I've ever eaten.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it was really damn good.
Scott: It was like the best food ever eaten, but I would totally eat there again for maybe two meals next time we go.
Rym: I wanted a root beer that had some boutique root beer on tap.
Rym: It was fantastic.
Scott: Yeah, I got a lemonade.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Rym: And then I got to say this so we're sitting there and then you know happy hour or whatever.
Scott: They spin the wheel and the wheel basically has different drinks on all the different spots.
Scott: So it might come up on like, you know You know like $4 Grey Goose whatever.
Scott: Yeah so that means that everyone can.
Scott: if you want you can order that for $4 which is less than the normal price.
Scott: or it might Come up at like Bartenders choice or it might come up at choice of table 401 and then whoever's sitting at table 401 gets to pick.
Rym: now I didn't really care and I was like, alright, whatever.
Rym: It's happy hour.
Rym: I don't want to drink like whatever kind of shots the frat boys drink But it happened to land on the Manhattan my favorite drink.
Rym: It was like makers something man It was.
Rym: it was a Manhattan with makers mark.
Rym: now lately, you know a non from Apple geeks.
Rym: No, I I like a Manhattan.
Rym: I like whiskey and that sort of thing and I drunk a whole bunch of different whiskeys.
Rym: I never really paid attention, but he turned me on to Jameson.
Rym: I've been a Jameson man ever since.
Rym: Jameson is my favorite.
Rym: Oh my actually knew about Jameson cuz I saw ads for it in the subway But he turned me on to it in a big way.
Rym: So For the first time in a long time I decide, you know, alright, it's 250 I'll order the stew in Manhattan with maker's mark, whatever.
Rym: Let me tell you the food was good.
Rym: That was a terrible Manhattan.
Rym: Yeah maker's mark is ass.
Rym: Oh my god I barely finished the stupid thing.
Rym: I choked it down grudgingly because I wasn't gonna give up my whiskey.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't.
Scott: it seemed like they had a good selection of alcohols.
Scott: They did but not that what I would know.
Scott: But it seemed like a lot of their alcohols were get drunk variety not like that other place that the tap house Have the fancy beer variety.
Rym: Alright, you want to learn about packs and I followed up with this online.
Rym: of the beer houses around packs Pretty much all of them ran out of almost all of their interesting beers Because of packs.
Rym: awesome you go in pretty much.
Rym: it was the cool thing You know, we're talking about everywhere you went packs.
Rym: you go to any restaurant anywhere packs.
Rym: people go to a bar a grill all night long.
Scott: It's like all packs people and like one businessman going what the fuck dude, no It's pretty nice that we could get into anywhere shorts and a t-shirt But we didn't try to eat at the Capitol Grill or the Ruth Chris.
Rym: So there's a Capitol Grill at a Ruth Chris like all over the place exactly gonna eat.
Rym: It's like, you know, a lot of you went to like the cheesecake.
Scott: Yeah, it's like those places are good When you don't have another choice, it's like, okay, there's nowhere to eat.
Scott: I know that place is safe and good.
Scott: It's sort of like, you know your safety net.
Scott: it's not the place you choose to go.
Scott: I mean not that it's not awesome Capitol Grill, but you know It's a safety net because I can always eat it it whenever I want.
Rym: Yeah, and also if you go to a city multiple times, you know, you go there like Baltimore.
Rym: I've already eaten in a lot of the places around there and I know what's there.
Rym: so I go there so often.
Rym: I know what's good.
Rym: I'd make an informed choice.
Rym: if you're in a new city Eat at the places that you can't eat anywhere else.
Rym: go to like the weird restaurant.
Rym: Go to the things that aren't chains or chains.
Rym: You've never heard of in the very least.
Rym: Yeah, but you know, I could see.
Scott: now there's a chain you never heard of.
Scott: you'll you won't know it's a chain.
Scott: You'll think it's just a restaurant.
Scott: Yeah, but like imagine this.
Scott: imagine if you saw Cheesecake Factory, but you didn't know it was a chain.
Scott: You thought it was just a place called Cheesecake Factory.
Scott: That was in Seattle only.
Scott: Oh, man Totally gone there, but because I knew it was the shit cake factory No need to go.
Rym: but I've kind of learned, you know I think I have a good appraisal of the restaurants in the in the vicinity of packs And I think I'll eat it at least one of those places again.
Rym: Yeah, definitely, but we didn't need at the elephant castle.
Rym: I kind of wanted to.
Scott: yeah It was just.
Scott: that was the elephant castle was the bar under our hotel.
Rym: It looked just like a bar But the theme was great.
Scott: It was the elephant with a castle on its back.
Scott: It was great.
Rym: I just like I really dug the theme.
Scott: really good marketing on that.
Rym: So I gotta say, you know, we checked in late at night On Thursday before the con and the dude who checked us in was actually like, you know When you're doing some sort of Transaction with people in a service sector.
Rym: most of the time it's all business like they do their thing.
Rym: you do your thing but every now and then like the person will be funny with you and It's rare.
Rym: and sometimes they're annoying.
Scott: funny with you like they're trying to be funny, but they're just being annoying and stupid.
Rym: But also sometimes like you both have to be in the mood to be funny Like if I'm not in the mood to like have banter with some stranger and he starts banter.
Rym: It's like oh my god banter.
Rym: Look.
Rym: why must we go through the charade charade?
Rym: I was quoting something Scott.
Rym: Anyway, yeah Anyway, but the confluence was right.
Rym: I was ready for some silly talk.
Rym: He was fishing for some silly talk.
Rym: We had to go home.
Scott: He just got off a plane.
Scott: It was like the best silly talk at a hotel check-in ever.
Rym: cuz I was like Blah blah, I'd like to check into the hotel under GeekNights and the guys like well I'd like to help you with that.
Rym: and then there's this pregnant pause and then I say well Then I think we can come to some sort of business arrangement.
Rym: all serious Like.
Rym: and he looks at me and he smiles and I smile and then he was totally awesome.
Rym: And he starts talking about packs and tells me all the good bars and it was a good time.
Rym: Yeah, you know on that note.
Rym: What else can I say?
Rym: Oh, there's probably a million things I forgot a bunch of cool people I met that I forgot about.
Rym: I Want to say
Scott: dude
Rym: who met us in the dragonfish, which was pretty cool
Scott: Oh dragonfish is a good plan
Rym: to join the forum and I'm glad you said that
Scott: Scottish guy also
Rym: I don't know and I'm glad you said that you joined because of the dragonfish because now I know who you are.
Rym: Okay, he joined the forum.
Rym: He said I'm the guy.
Rym: he said blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: by the way dragonfish I was like, oh, right.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Cuz I told him tell it remind us You're the guy from the dragonfish now, I remember who he is.
Rym: All right Yeah, he was the guy who knew he was probably the most knowledgeable guy outside of us Jared Sorenson and Luke crane at our panel.
Rym: Yeah and he had a lot of cool things to say and I really would like to hear his impressions of burning wheel once he's tried it Cuz he's one of those knowledgeable guys who just hasn't played burning whale.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, but yeah, I gotta end dragonfish is a good restaurant.
Rym: Yeah, I mean a lot of fun things Experience a new city through his food.
Rym: Well, you know we there was a lot more.
Rym: I mean we walked around the city a lot Like we walked into some weird neighborhoods and some weird places like the bus terminals God was talking about totally abandoned and closed because it was a holiday.
Rym: But like we were parent like we climbed up as high as we could and repairing down into it and it was kind of cool and artistic to see it empty like that.
Rym: and There was this really like neat moment where the periodic PA that says things like don't leave bags unattended.
Rym: blah blah blah Was still going but there was no one there.
Scott: Yeah, it's freaky.
Scott: There's also the pink elephant car wash.
Rym: Yeah, there were also all these awesome sculptures all over the place.
Scott: There's that gas station that had a teriyaki place in it, but the teriyaki place in the gas station was closed.
Rym: Yeah, it was like gas station and our awesome teriyaki burgers.
Scott: Well, we don't know it was awesome.
Rym: They said they were awesome.
Scott: Alright they said they're right.
Rym: I got some Red Bull and said but yeah, yeah But you know that we did a lot of the Red Bull truck at PAX.
Scott: Oh my god I guess they didn't want to lose money.
Scott: Usually those things make money.
Rym: No, no, you know what?
Rym: They don't make money.
Rym: They give it away.
Rym: They're not gonna be at PAX because who are they who at PAX does not drink Red Bull or already?
Rym: No Red Bull exists and has made.
Scott: Other energy drink was there because they're trying to be Red Bull not gonna work.
Rym: But we did a bunch of stuff that we didn't talk about here.
Rym: But Seattle was really cool and I'd like to go.
Rym: but well, I'm going back cuz I'll be at PAX next year.
Scott: Yeah, baby, would you go back to Seattle if there wasn't packs?
Scott: I mean, it's a good city.
Scott: It's not a bad city.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's not like one of those places where I'll be like It.
Rym: would you go back to Seattle without packs?
Rym: is like saying would you go to see go to Chicago for no reason?
Rym: Yeah, I'd been to Seattle or Chicago.
Rym: I'm not gonna go back unless I have a reason I could.
Rym: there There's a lot of things that could cause me to go back and I mean, I wouldn't say ah Seattle I'm not going back there.
Rym: Like I say about much of Jersey, but yeah, Seattle's an okay place.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: It's nice and modern and fancy and clean and it's a good place to have a little convention.
Scott: and it's it's pretty Convenient for walking around and the hotels are cheap and I kind of like it.
Scott: I wouldn't live there.
Rym: but you know we had to take a car service back to the airport because the shuttle totally sucked ass and the Hotel guy was like no dude.
Rym: The shuttle tastes like an hour.
Scott: seriously Yeah, because it's not one of those shuttles that goes from your hotel to the airport It's a shuttle that goes to every hotel than the airport.
Rym: so on the way back right we're in the car service.
Rym: very good sir and all the business and the guys chatty and we're Telling what we were doing.
Rym: He's interested and we see this weird elevated thing.
Rym: We're trying to figure out what it does and scouts like it's a monorail.
Rym: I'm like, it can't be a monorail because why would it not go to Seattle and it from the airport?
Rym: Where else would it go?
Rym: And if it went to Seattle we would have taken it.
Rym: and then we see the sign that settled the argument.
Rym: it says Light rail to Seattle from Airport coming 2009.
Scott: We're like, oh So I guess car service guys gonna be in trouble next year?
Rym: Yeah, cuz I'm gonna take that monorail whatever it is light rail.
Rym: so we took the Late night flight home and we got back to New York City after a fitful sleep.
Scott: It was 6 a.m.
Scott: New York time.
Scott: We got there.
Rym: So, you know, there's this place and I'm gonna end on this in New York City.
Rym: It's if you go out of the 42nd Street entrance under Pershing Square from Grand Central.
Rym: It's called either the central cafe or the Pershing Square cafe.
Rym: Don't even square central cafe Don't don't even try to figure it out.
Rym: You see it.
Rym: It's right there and I've eaten there for dinner.
Rym: I've eaten there for lunch.
Scott: I don't eat there for lunch.
Scott: I never dinner twice and it was really good.
Rym: The dinner is really really good.
Rym: The lunch is also really really good and we always see they have this sign New York's best and busiest breakfast.
Scott: And yes, like I always saw the sign outside this place and I used to always think oh man, that's the place I got to eat breakfast there sometime.
Scott: It's like man.
Rym: I want to pay money to get like a really good breakfast Like this could be cool someday.
Rym: I'll eat the breakfast there someday someday The those Tuesday after packs was that day we go in we sit down But they're kind of early and it's weird because it was a work day.
Rym: on a normal work day I would have already been at work.
Rym: In fact, I was sitting right next to the building I work in but I was not working at it that day.
Rym: Mmm, and you know, we get seated and we get the menu Really shit menu uninspiring crap.
Rym: It's like the menu that a crappy little diner has but I think yeah It's not like you know I've had.
Scott: the best breakfast ever had was at a place called Leo's which has changed his name to Kings in Connecticut.
Scott: in I think is I think it's technically Newtown, Connecticut And when it was called Leo's this guy owned it and you could go in there and order the wheel of fortune.
Scott: Let me explain to you the wheel of fortune.
Scott: Are you ready for this?
Scott: Cuz it puts the tremendous 12 to shame.
Scott: we were talking about a combination of waffles pancakes French toast eggs bacon sausage Bananas mixed berries whipped cream and a cherry on top.
Scott: Oh my shit for less than $20.
Rym: Alright now is the thing but I was thinking alright benefit of the doubt the lunch and dinner menus are both very sparse.
Rym: They have very few but very well put together things.
Rym: I'm thinking alright Maybe these are just you know Like the the the best of these kinds of breakfast and outside they actually had a sign like famous pancakes famous.
Rym: so uh That was one of the worst breakfast I've ever had.
Rym: it was terrible.
Rym: I didn't even leave a tip.
Rym: it was so not good.
Scott: I mean, I ordered a banana pancakes, right?
Scott: It was basically three pancakes three syrup undercooked pancakes.
Scott: They were slightly undercooked.
Scott: It's in some parts of them and there was like.
Scott: I Don't even know they were.
Scott: so not that the banana right?
Scott: I ordered a banana pancakes I expect like a mountain of bananas and whipped cream.
Scott: on the pancakes.
Scott: it's like they took a quarter of a banana and sliced it up and put it on the side and that cost me a dollar a Dollar.
Scott: and for a quarter of a banana sliced up on the side the eggs were mushy.
Rym: The toast was we.
Rym: it was.
Rym: it was like the breakfast that I would.
Rym: I would have been happy if I had paid like five Bucks for that at a diner in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: Yeah, that would have been good.
Rym: So I'm just gonna say this right now never eat breakfast at that godforsaken place.
Rym: That was that like the dinner there.
Scott: eat dinner there But that was.
Rym: you know what though because the breakfast is so bad despite how much they hype it up.
Scott: You want to.
Rym: you want to boycott the dinner to feel like I should never eat there.
Scott: I mean the dinner is good, but I do feel like you could.
Scott: you could get an equipment.
Scott: It's not like an amazing dinner.
Scott: You can't get anywhere else.
Scott: So maybe because the breakfast is so bad Maybe we shouldn't eat there for dinner, but that was like it was so bad.
Rym: central cafe.
Rym: You suck.
Rym: There's a reason.
Rym: I left no tip.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, we left like I think a dollar.
Rym: I left a dollar because I didn't want to figure it out.
Scott: Yeah, and whatever goes to Corning, New York I don't know if it's still there.
Scott: There's a place called boomers.
Scott: go there in the morning cuz it's like mostly a burger place like at night.
Scott: You'll go there right if you go there for breakfast and ask for the pancakes.
Scott: if they tell you right Order a short stack.
Scott: I swear to God cuz they'll be like, are you sure you want a full stack?
Scott: They're big.
Scott: they're big.
Scott: get a short stack.
Scott: Oh my god, but go there.
Scott: Okay pancakes.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.