Rym:
Rym: It's Wednesday June 4th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We give the first four of toshikon sense.
Rym: Oh aka library war.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So what could be better than the best anime podcast in the english-speaking world going once a week?
Rym: How about uh going once every other week?
Rym: Yeah pretty much All right people because I know Wednesday probably gets the most listeners who don't listen to any other nights.
Rym: So I figure we should bring it up right at the beginning For various reasons partly because we haven't made our swag yet and because we're actually trying to do that whole.
Rym: I don't know video thing and it's summer which is pretty much the biggest Confounding factor here.
Rym: We're go.
Rym: we're enacting the GeekNights originally planned for season three half sabbatical schedule.
Scott: Yes now instead of GeekNights being four nights a week It'll be two nights a week, but there is still be four shows.
Scott: So instead of thinking of GeekNights as one podcast where you get four episodes every week Think of it as four podcasts for completely separate podcasts and each podcast comes out once every other week.
Scott: Oh my gosh, so next week there will not be a Wednesday episode But the week after that there will be a Wednesday episode.
Rym: next week There will be a Tuesday and a Thursday.
Rym: You see what we did there Monday Wednesday Tuesday Thursday.
Rym: now Occasionally, I mean if the muse bites us or there's something we really got to talk about or we're just bored There's a chance we might just do a normal episode in between all that.
Rym: but don't count on it.
Scott: No, most likely instead of doing those, you know, since you're doing half as much GeekNights We're probably gonna be you know, putting out other things that are not GeekNights but are related in some way.
Rym: Yes, and in the very the very least of those will be you won't get a GeekNights special on a normal day anymore.
Rym: If you get a GeekNights special, that means it's kind of extra on top of what we're doing Normally, so you won't get those cop-outs like we used to do whenever we got tired.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: One example of such spin-offs Is Scott's box.
Scott: Oh Scott's boss Scott's box.
Scott: Scott's box would have been tonight But it's not gonna be.
Scott: and you know Scott's box has been actually pretty popular.
Scott: a lot of people like it.
Scott: I was quite surprised.
Scott: I didn't think too many people would be interested because I didn't think that many people actually bought comics who also listened to us.
Scott: so Scott's box though I think I'm gonna take it out of the GeekNights.
Rym: take it out of the box.
Scott: take it out of the GeekNights And people are probably like, oh no, don't take it out the GeekNights.
Scott: No, it's still gonna be around Scott's box.
Scott: I'm announcing right now.
Scott: It's gonna be its own thing on its own what I'm gonna do.
Scott: The box is in my room.
Scott: It's sealed.
Scott: after the show After we eat probably I'm gonna go and I'm gonna turn on the camera and without editing anything I'm just gonna open the box.
Scott: I'm gonna do the same.
Scott: I'm gonna show you all the goodies that are in there and I'm not gonna cut it up or anything.
Rym: now we'll probably record the audio too and we'll probably put it in this feed or in the experimental feed because I Don't you guys definitely I imagine want the audio to listen to and the video would just be like an extra touch.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna put the video on YouTube and whatever other sites and you know Now I'll put the link up.
Scott: It'll be up, you know, probably today or tomorrow as soon as I you know, compile it I'm gonna shoot for the weekend here my estimate.
Scott: No, I'm gonna do it cuz I'm not gonna edit it at all.
Scott: I'm just gonna stand in front of the camera open the box and do it.
Scott: I can't do it twice once the box is open.
Scott: It's open.
Scott: I can't like pretend.
Rym: Well, the audio component will not be in the feed right away because I have to do stuff to that.
Scott: No, well But the video of me opening the box and showing you all the stuff inside Will be a monthly thing and perhaps, you know, then I'll make addendums to it as well.
Rym: Well, you know remember the debate we had way back.
Rym: where is Scott's box gonna be when he orders or is it gonna be when?
Rym: He gets it eventually.
Rym: Scott's box could be both.
Scott: It could be both.
Scott: no reason not to but for now It's gonna be at that.
Scott: for just to start It's gonna be once a month less than 10 minute video of me opening the box and showing you the goodies.
Rym: And so expect that really soon, but don't worry You're a weekly bi-weekly Multi-weekly, however, you want to call it GeekNights isn't gonna change.
Rym: just Scott's box is there.
Scott: Yep So instead of Scott's box, let's let's do some news here.
Rym: What's the anime news?
Rym: Oh my gosh.
Scott: Well, it's not really so much anime news.
Scott: It's sort of manga comic news.
Scott: Yes, Tokyo pop the sort of you know company we have to thank for the you know, the manga boom in the u.s Company.
Rym: we have to thank for the specific kind of manga that has boomed.
Scott: Yes is Restructuring.
Rym: they're calling it a quote progressive Reorganization unquote which I'll translate that from business speak.
Rym: Yeah, we're trying not to go under in the long run.
Scott: Yeah I mean this isn't like.
Scott: Oh knows manga is in trouble because actually vis is growing Dark horse is kicking some ass verticals doing pretty well, you know.
Scott: So don't think some don't think this is a sign of oh no the end times for manga.
Scott: the same way You know, it's sort of the end times for anime in the u.s.
Scott: But basically what it shows is that Tokyo pop is sort of playing a different game.
Scott: you see Getting the licenses for these mangas are real expensive and this sort of has a lock on all the really popular ones.
Scott: dark horse has a lock on a bunch of others and vertical has a lock on a bunch of the classics and Tokyo pops having a real hard time getting any good, you know, manga licenses of Japanese things to translate and bring over.
Rym: Well, plus they seem to have always used the shotgun approach.
Scott: yes, the quantity is better than quality and we'll throw everything against the wall and see what sticks as opposed to Trying to pick out the stickiest poop and then throwing.
Rym: but then they keep putting out.
Rym: It doesn't stick and they just keep throwing it.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, so actually what it looks like is they're gonna split apart because people don't maybe not realize this.
Scott: Tokyo pop used to put out Like anime DVDs like they put out initial D. I have all those eggs now.
Rym: No, I don't think it needs to be said.
Rym: but in case lest we forget Tokyo pop really sucked at putting out I wouldn't say that they sucked.
Rym: they were very good.
Rym: What they were is they were very good at taking an otherwise Okay show and doing their best to ruin everything that was holy good and pure about it before releasing it in English.
Scott: Well, they also put out DVDs of rain the Conqueror that show.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I didn't see enough of it.
Scott: You only had to see like 10 seconds to know.
Scott: that is terrible.
Rym: You know, I can't say cuz it for all.
Rym: I know it might have been okay.
Scott: What are the odds of it being?
Rym: Okay, I give it a 5% chance of being worth finishing the first episode.
Rym: I saw the first half of the first episode and I didn't turn it off in disgust.
Rym: I turned it off to play counter-strike.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Anyway, didn't we try to watch that on TV?
Scott: Yes, cuz it was on right after Lupin.
Rym: I remember we had to find a coaxial cable and then we plugged it into the wall Wondering if we had cable and finding out that we did.
Rym: Yeah anyway.
Scott: So Tokyo pop restructuring here.
Scott: What does this mean?
Scott: It means first of all Tokyo pop I'm guessing is gonna be doing a lot less, you know bringing over of Japanese manga, you know and translating it.
Scott: a lot more Publishing of you know suckering us kids into writing comics.
Rym: that they were not going to talk about their Licensing policy for new artists that they get from the u.s.
Rym: That's a whole separate discussion.
Scott: But the point is is that they sort of realize that it's a lot cheaper and a lot more profitable for them to you know.
Scott: Get you know, really pay kids in the u.s A lot less money than they'd have to pay a Japanese company and then sell but got these, you know Sell the books for the same amount now Beyond that regardless of what they're gonna be putting out.
Rym: It says here that they're pretty much cutting their distribution or it Distribution in terms of number of titles published not number of individual title of items in a publishing unit put out.
Rym: Yeah, but they're cutting it in half right.
Rym: half as many volumes a year, right exactly so it.
Scott: That means all right.
Scott: first of all what would happen is they would put a whole bunch of different volumes of manga on the shelf and people would end up choosing between a Tokyo pop and a Tokyo pop.
Scott: so by doing that they sort of were competing with themselves, you know It's like if I sell three products that are all sort of the same at once But people can't afford all three.
Scott: then they're picking one of the three things and I'm basically paying a lot more money.
Scott: I'm spending three times as much money because the biggest cost is you know, either buying the license or you know Creating the original work.
Scott: the actual printing is not that much.
Scott: now, you know take heed Tokyo pop They're doing.
Rym: they're basically doing what Nintendo figured out a long time ago Everyone's gonna buy Zelda everyone's gonna buy Mario.
Rym: Let's release Zelda until everyone's bought it and then when sales start flagging we release Mario.
Rym: that way Everyone buys every game.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So by putting out less volumes they're gonna sell a lot more of each individual volume and therefore make more money and That is that is their intent.
Scott: Yes, and also by putting out less volumes Hopefully they will you know, put out more quality and less.
Scott: All right.
Scott: The thing is I don't really want to malign Tokyo pop.
Rym: No, they're not don't like most of their manga.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is I really think about it, right and it's like yeah You look at Tokyo pop and you look at their entire body of work and you kind of go.
Scott: But I buy to Tokyo pop titles regularly back and initial D. Right, of course, both of those titles are almost done and when they're done, I probably won't buy any more Tokyo pops at all.
Rym: I worry that Tokyo pops gonna get hit by a minor version of the Dragon Ball syndrome where Dragon Ball stops and then half the people disappear.
Scott: I don't think that initial D and Beck Oh Beck is a pretty big seller, but I don't think initial D is like their biggest seller.
Rym: No, but I feel like initial D is.
Rym: it's probably a very solid franchise for me.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: We don't know.
Scott: No one tells us no But it apparently was worth it for them to keep publishing the volumes right up to the end.
Rym: D is a pretty big follow.
Rym: it like it's not this widespread following but there is a strong cult following in the u.s.
Scott: I wouldn't be surprised though.
Scott: Beck was their biggest title though But it's only got like a handful of volumes left before it's done.
Scott: But yeah, I mean me buying two comics regularly from a single publisher.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Scott: I mean there are other other publishers that I don't buy, you know, two regular titles from them and you think that those are better.
Scott: You know, I mean like I don't buy to visit titles regularly not since Phoenix ended But viz.
Scott: I look at their body of work and I think it's better than Tokyo pops.
Rym: So I figure it would be a little bit self-serving, but I should mention it because well while we'll probably be around It's very unlikely We'll actually be able to be at this event, especially since we were at the Kinokuniya last weekend for Hal Cali and the Tokyo FM samurai beach radio thing.
Rym: but basically Kinokuniya won.
Rym: the manager of the Kinokuniya in New York City in Bryant Park is a pretty damn cool, dude And we're hopefully going to have him on the show sometime soon for an interview.
Rym: Yep, Scott's barking up that tree, but this guy's story is pretty and pretty cool.
Rym: but anyway, one thing that the Kinokuniya is doing very well is that they are Catering to the fact that there are a lot of anime and manga fans Independent of that a lot of Japanese culture and Japanese music fans in the u.s.
Rym: Especially in New York City.
Scott: I mean if you pick any, you know demographic no matter how targeted there is at least you know At least ten of those people in New York City.
Rym: Yeah, and now but the cool thing is what they're doing is they're having more and more of these events where there's an event at The bookstore.
Rym: so you go to the bookstore in one right by there not too far away You can get beard poppers and all that stuff and the book off is not too far from there.
Rym: but in Kinokuniya you get people going in any way to buy anime and manga and comics and plushies and Kitaro things that we're gonna be using a lot more in our video.
Rym: But they're also having these events, I mean we had TMR.
Rym: we interviewed them along with Brian.
Rym: Well, I guess Brian Nishi interviewed him along with us.
Rym: Yeah, and samurai beat radio.
Rym: and now they're having this weekend on June 7th.
Rym: I think that's Saturday a gothic Lolita and made fashion day.
Scott: Well, I guess if you're really into gothic Lolita and made fashion, that's something you should go to except There's something better.
Scott: You should be going to this Saturday.
Scott: Oh Especially if you're in New York City.
Scott: Oh is that as you see this weekend Saturday and Sunday in the puck building on the corners of Lafayette and Houston Street in New York City is the annual Museum of comic and cartoon art arts festival now greatest comic convention in the entire world.
Rym: now a lot of people refer to this as the mocha but be careful because the mocha is a museum.
Scott: and then there is the Mocha arts festival, which is their annual fundraiser, which is where they get most of their monies.
Rym: It's also basically the latter which is what we're talking about is a super awesome Comic-con and it's not like the underwear pervert comic cons.
Rym: This is basically all the awesome indie art and web comic people and all the cool stuff from comics around the world.
Scott: This is a comic convention where you will see like an uber professional Sitting at a table next to some kid who just came from the kinkos with his photocopied You know doodles right next to famous webcomic person Right next to the guy who does Ally right next to the guy who does Scott Pilgrim.
Rym: now We're definitely going to be there along with you going to Knopf and Emily and hopefully a bunch of other front row crew people not On Saturday only though.
Scott: It's not as good as this con is unless you're sitting at a table Which the tables are actually really expensive.
Scott: There's not really a reason to be there both days.
Scott: you walk around and look at all the tables and they go Ah, that was awesome.
Scott: And you walk out with two sacks full of comics and you don't need to come back the next day unless you're rich.
Rym: now We'll be there interviewing and hanging out and checking people But we generally we avoid being there like we don't want to get a table or anything partly because one I want to spend my time walking around
Scott: Yep
Rym: And two I don't want to deny even the kid with kinkos from having his table.
Scott: then the kids with kinkos of some of the Best comics there.
Rym: a teen boat.
Scott: I mean taught your teen boat.
Scott: You're talking like little tiny like Comic.
Scott: that's like.
Scott: could you know the like?
Scott: an inch by an inch that is little pictures of monsters in it.
Rym: What was the name of that comic or the people who gave us those little custom free ghosts?
Scott: Oh the people who make the woodcraft every year.
Scott: I we saw that I have their business card.
Scott: I know what they are, but it's in my room.
Rym: They had the best promotion ever.
Rym: They just gave away free unique Pac-man.
Rym: Pac-man ghosts made out of wood and I remember taking one thinking wow, this is a really good idea.
Rym: and then I got home and immediately forgot who they were because I still have their business card.
Scott: I know who they are when we talk about the mocha.
Scott: probably two weeks from now we will.
Scott: We will make a point of mentioning these people because they're pretty sure I mentioned them the last mocha episode but you know last year.
Scott: look in the Wednesday episodes from around June of last of 07 and you will.
Scott: you will find possibly me man.
Scott: But
Rym: anyway, if you're gonna be in the city for the mocha on Saturday You'd might as well also go to the Kino Kunia for the Lolita and made fashion day a del Rey Samurai beat radio who I mentioned repeatedly only because we're getting more and more involved with them as time goes on.
Scott: and if you live In the city, right?
Scott: Why not go to the Lolita fashion show Saturday and the mocha Sunday?
Scott: Yeah, not been not bad.
Rym: So I got one more quick news.
Rym: I just want to bring this up because not too long ago.
Rym: We mentioned the strange occurrence whereby Jojo's Bizarre Adventure ran into some difficulty.
Rym: Uh-huh, the I'm not gonna get into all the details, but I'm sure you all Wondered what was up with that because we wondered what was up.
Rym: was that with that?
Rym: and the answer came out Pretty quickly and then there was a follow-up, but the deal basically is that in a particular Episode of the anime there was a book.
Rym: That's a care I'm trying not to spoil anything either is reading from this book and while he's reading from the book He's vowing to kill another character.
Rym: now apparently in the manga.
Rym: It's just some unintelligible book, whatever.
Rym: I didn't ever read the manga, but in the anime and I don't know who Noticed this let alone decided to make a ruckus about it.
Rym: You can read the news if you really care about who made a ruckus about.
Rym: it Happened to by random chance.
Rym: They just took pages from the Quran and stuck them in there because they needed something.
Scott: Well, maybe they were making a funny commentary because someone was vowing to kill someone and the Quran is full of vows to kill.
Rym: Indications are that it was just completely.
Rym: Hey, that looks good.
Rym: Throw it in.
Scott: All right, like a lorem ipsum supplement Yeah Something like that.
Rym: and as a result that was pretty much the reason behind the issue With Jojo's Bizarre Adventure.
Rym: and in fact wait.
Scott: So because one episode has that this company that the entire company all they really did was was put out this anime Stop putting out the whole anime.
Scott: Why didn't they just edit that one?
Rym: I don't think that company was doing too Well.
Scott: anyway, I know I know and you know, I mean the only even if they I Guess they could have stood up to their guns that we're gonna put it out on.
Scott: edit in any way.
Scott: freedom of speech But if you don't have the money to fight, you know in court Even if you're gonna win then just you know, they could have just edited the thing.
Scott: What the hell?
Rym: Yes, but the the trouble got even further because apparently basically Japan's foreign ministry Apologized for all of this.
Rym: This I don't want to get into it because it's Wednesday's anime night.
Scott: Obviously, we're on the side.
Scott: if they should have just put it out unedited and given these people the finger.
Scott: Yes That's obviously our stance.
Rym: explain what happened.
Rym: I'm even okay with apologizing because it was clearly an accident that there's not a lot of indication that there was any Actual or true malice behind it.
Scott: now sure not like our our friends who make the Dutch cartoons Awesome.
Rym: that was also blown way out of proportion.
Scott: I didn't say it wasn't but they were deaf, you know, that's a little different between.
Rym: that is but the fact that this was probably an accident and If they just apologize, they should have just continued publishing.
Rym: and that bothers me.
Rym: But in case you wondered that's the deal.
Rym: But moving on to things that are not nearly so sad things of the day You see how I said that things that aren't so bad things of the day great.
Rym: It's poetic.
Rym: It's almost prose.
Rym: Anyway, so this is a little old but it really bear.
Rym: if you haven't seen this you need to see it.
Rym: because this I think It's relevant.
Rym: one because it's animation - it's remixing which is a very big part of the anime manga culture both in the US and Japan.
Rym: and Three it's very very very well done.
Rym: Basically what this is?
Rym: there's someone named pogo a quote electro musician who took.
Scott: I'm a fan of the electro musician I am too.
Rym: But what he did is he took scenes from the original animated movie Alice in Wonderland and How original was it?
Scott: was based on a book?
Rym: Well, I don't know if there I worry that there was some knockoff anime or something I don't know about.
Scott: we're talking about the Disney one people.
Rym: Yes If you've seen some other Alice in Wonderland that might have merriman out of in pornographic.
Rym: We're not talking about that.
Scott: Yeah, we're not talking about Alice in Looking Glass either.
Rym: No different thing Anyway, so Alice in Wonderland He took this.
Rym: he took footage from it and remixed it together to make a video.
Rym: then he took Sounds and samples from the movie and made a techno song.
Rym: He put them together and made a dual remix.
Scott: Yeah, he took.
Scott: he didn't.
Scott: actually it wasn't a mash-up.
Scott: He didn't take materials from two separate things and combine them.
Rym: It was like a man or a mash-out or a mash together.
Scott: He took and he wasn't like the phantom edit where he took a movie and just you know edited it.
Scott: You know the audio and the video together removing and scenes or reordering scenes.
Rym: Someday one of my crazy project is still to make a phantom edit of Sailor Moon.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: What he did is he took the audio From the movie took sampled it created a song then took the video from the movie Sampled it remixed it and made a music video for the song.
Scott: So using the source material of a full-length animated, you know motion picture feature animated film.
Scott: I totally missed that.
Rym: I was fantastic.
Scott: He made an animated music video.
Rym: This is super high quality And if nothing else I think that this alone if you have never been convinced by anything else and I guess if you're I don't know what's wrong With you if you're listening to GeekNights while having this sort of opinion This is why we need fair use.
Rym: this is why copyright needs to allow for the creative use of other people's works.
Scott: Yep, and also watching this, you know I realized wow that Alice in Wonderland movie was really well animated.
Rym: actually I didn't realize it, you know earlier in my life kind of randomly out of the blue today I was also watching a YouTube clip from the Aristocats Also super well animated.
Scott: Yeah, that was a good one.
Rym: I actually really really like that movie as a kid, but it's okay Seen it.
Rym: in two decades I cannot vouch for how good the Aristocats is but I liked the Aristocats as a kid.
Rym: It was okay.
Scott: I'm more of a great mouse detective.
Rym: Oh the great mouse detective.
Rym: That's going in the Netflix queue so hard.
Scott: Maybe it's on the road to talk about the Roku.
Rym: We might have to watch it tonight.
Rym: Maybe fuck sleep.
Scott: All right, so Check this shit out Somebody.
Scott: someone awesome named otaku king.
Scott: He's the king of otaku.
Rym: Otaku king or otaku king?
Scott: Oh right it is otaku king.
Rym: Otaku king is like people who say conservativism when they mean conservatism.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Otaku king is from something something that if you don't know what it is, you're not old-school, right?
Rym: It's not even that old-school anyway.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: He actually is otaku king.
Scott: I'm messing everything up tonight aren't I?
Scott: the otaku king from the UK made a Documentary.
Scott: could this perhaps be you know a Documentary no video or something.
Scott: But no, no, it isn't This guy the otaku.
Scott: he's actually a professional as in that's what he does for his job like video game and Animation translator at adapter person, you know, like he's the guy translating Japanese video games into I guess UK English which is not the same as our English and He's a UK.
Scott: I believe you mean Albionic, yeah, actually, I think he's actually from the UK would do whatever.
Scott: Anyway, the point is this dude right is pretty good at the translating and of course being named otaku king.
Scott: he's a fan of a nimes and He's pissed off about the state of anime fansubbing.
Rym: Before you go out one of those people because you know those people the people who don't even understand any Japanese But we'll watch a fan sub in the whole time Exclaim how bad the translation was or or or.
Rym: the people who will watch a dub and then the subtitle track is also on and They based on the subtitle track assume that the dub is wrong, but assume that somehow the subtitles were right.
Rym: Yes, the people who prefer one subtitling group over the other because of these minutiae that they don't even understand You know those people right now.
Scott: this guy actually knows that he's talking about.
Scott: he made a documentary and it's in five parts.
Scott: But it's only in five parts because it's on YouTube and I'm working with him.
Scott: Actually, I'll tell you this I'm working with him to try to get him on the show But he says he's a little shy.
Scott: so you can email him and encourage him to be on the show.
Scott: Also, I'm working with him to try to get like a high-quality version of the documentary That's all in one piece to make it easier to watch it.
Scott: You know say conventions and stuff and in this documentary he brings up an issue and he and it's an issue I didn't even realize it was an issue but watching the documentary I've pretty much come over 99% over to his side of things.
Scott: and Now that I was watching a fan sub which we're going to talk about on the way to and from work today Oh good.
Rym: God the fan.
Rym: So that was a bad fan.
Scott: So right and you know watching it and Thinking back to this documentary.
Scott: I was like wow, this dude is totally right.
Scott: and now I'm really bothered by fan subs.
Scott: It's like you're looking at something bad and you didn't realize it was a bad.
Scott: And now this guy in his documentary comes out and points out how bad it is.
Scott: And now all you do is see the badness all over the place and you're like, no you're right It is terrible.
Scott: These fansubs all suck ass.
Rym: Really the only things I disagree with him on are did you watch the whole thing?
Rym: I watch a bunch of it I got to watch the rest, but I disagree a tiny bit.
Rym: but I don't.
Rym: I realize I don't fully disagree and I can't say that I disagree because While I I see value in a very tiny number of the things he talks about as being bad.
Rym: Though that value is only there for I guess advanced anime watchers or people who are kind of very used to watching anime and It really does a disservice to anyone who is not like that to try to watch a fan sub that does that.
Rym: Yeah, and I feel like if anything the far far future of translation I could see having Multiple subtitled tracks for people who aren't familiar with versus people who are that sort of stuff.
Scott: but maybe so I think that really the one thing I learned from this documentary is that Fansubs being sort of the primary way of new shows being introduced to the fandom in the u.s you know, whereas it used to be sort of after-school television is.
Scott: Then the fact that fansubs are done in a terrible way that they're done is Really hurting and making it difficult for new people to get into anime watching anime.
Scott: It's making it very hard to be a new anime fan in you know in in respect of pleasing Existing anime fans sort of similar to the way that you know.
Scott: You try to read like a Marvel or DC comic book and you can't understand what the fuck is going on because you haven't been reading them for the past five years and you don't know all the history of all these characters and the crazy universe and what's Going on in all the hundred books makes it very hard for new superhero comics fans and you know.
Scott: but at the same time if you tried it to please the new fans you had pissed off the old ones.
Scott: and He points this out very well, and I didn't even realize it and I'm all for it.
Scott: And we might be discussing this more in the future.
Rym: Oh, we will definitely be having a show or something about this.
Scott: if we don't have if we you know We can't get him on the show.
Scott: We might even just have a show, you know discussing it or who knows.
Rym: but yeah, so One thing watch the documentary.
Rym: one thing that you can always Do to make either something great or something horrible is to take two things that you wouldn't expect to be related together and relate them Together part possibly in a single show or manga or comic book.
Rym: For example, you take x-men you take zombies throw them together You get something that is both more and less than the sum of the parts.
Scott: Yeah, man You know, they're coming out with a third Marvel Zombies comic miniseries.
Scott: They came over.
Scott: they made Marvel so dumb Well in the story with Marvel Zombies, right?
Scott: is that they in the ultimate one of the ultimate Marvel comic books, right?
Scott: They had this zombie thing for a little bit.
Scott: They're like, oh, this is a zombie universe.
Scott: Okay, and then They made Marvel Zombies.
Scott: it was a miniseries about two issues of it and it was kind of bleh.
Scott: Then they made that sold so well They made Marvel Zombies 2 and apparently that sold well enough for them to make Marvel Zombies 3.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: so anyway What if you took?
Rym: Libraries and mix them with guns, isn't that just read or die?
Rym: Well, that was libraries guns and superpowers.
Rym: Okay, so that's a three-way.
Rym: this is only a two-way, yeah, so it's not quite the same thing.
Rym: But no tonight we are talking about toshokan senso aka Library war.
Scott: Yes, toshokan means libraries, you know that fit that bit.
Scott: torrent site Tokyo toshokan.
Scott: It means Tokyo library.
Scott: I'm learning Japanese with the GeekNights.
Rym: now I don't know how many of you have watched any of this show yet and I'll say straight up that we're not doing a full review.
Rym: We're doing.
Rym: I'm thinking of kind of renaming because we used to say, you know We have a preview and then a review.
Scott: I don't think we should name it at all.
Scott: I think we should just when we talk about the show We should say if there's gonna be spoilers and say how much we've seen and say how much you know.
Scott: We should say how much we've seen and how much we're going to discuss because I could have seen a whole show But only discuss the first episode.
Rym: so at the same time I feel as though any of you you do that up to a point.
Rym: but a Review can only occur when you have seen the entire show and you really can't call something a review before that Because you don't know
Scott: but a review isn't you know, unless someone is gonna think unless the show is already all done I mean, what if someone wants to watch the show as it comes out this there is a purpose to sort of discussing a show.
Rym: Yeah, before that is not a review.
Rym: and at the same time I really like calling the shows where we fully spoil and tell it till I tell the full on all The shows where we don't really talk about what happens we talk about the why and all the all the things that you don't like.
Rym: You assume that we already watched the show that I definitely like calling that.
Rym: final thoughts.
Rym: Oh, yeah, separate thing.
Rym: You don't go into that expecting us to explain the plot.
Rym: We assume you know the plot and we talk about how so-and-so totally got shot.
Rym: Mmm I was thinking about calling this the first four.
Scott: maybe that's not bad because but I've watched six.
Scott: Oh How many do you watch for?
Rym: Here's the thing at the RIT Anime Club the thing that worked really well and to this day every anime club.
Rym: This is the way to get people into new anime.
Rym: Every week we would show the first four episodes of a different show and except for the very first week of anime club We would show four first episodes of four different shows or occasionally three first episodes and one fifth episode.
Rym: That's yeah, but anyway I've.
Rym: it is I can think of so few times where I have watched the entire first four episodes of an anime and Not been able to figure out if I like the show or not.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty rare that after the I mean Gonzo shows you sort of know that at the end they're gonna go to you.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: But other than that, you know where there's a trend that you can sort of target an association with a production studio or director.
Scott: You watch the first four episodes of a show and if you're not hooked on the show by then You sort of know if you're going to watch the show to the end or not And you sort of know what kind of person is gonna watch the show to the end.
Rym: I mean the acid test for us way back was when they showed us initial D. We saw four episodes and we thought it was the stupidest goddamn thing ever made.
Rym: It was.
Rym: we just made fun of it the whole way through.
Rym: we thought it was dumb and then on the way home from club the whole front row crew as it was is walking and someone turns to someone else and says so uh You think he wins the next race and then it had a marathon.
Scott: who he sat there through the whole goddamn thing.
Scott: Yeah, and I own the whole thing.
Rym: So Library Wars the plot is Possibly what you might expect.
Rym: I would almost say that it's a lot like full metal panic.
Rym: But no, no, no like the.
Rym: the aesthetic of the the raw bear Super zoomed out aesthetic reminds me a lot of that show.
Rym: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: However, if once you zoom in I hated full metal panic and I really like this show and there's a lot of reasons Why.
Scott: well, here's the thing right.
Scott: on the one hand the actual Sort of universe that this story takes place in is preposterous.
Scott: it is absolutely.
Scott: it is absolutely makes no sense and it's incredibly difficult to suspend my disbelief.
Rym: I know you have in 1989 the Japanese government after much pressure from various groups past the media betterment act.
Scott: But they also passed the library act.
Rym: Well, the media betterment act was basically the Fahrenheit 451 burn all the books law that there's actually a copy of Fahrenheit 451 in episode 6 spoilers.
Rym: So apparently one thing led to another and the intelligent people of the country got together and made sure that an anti MBA military force was founded based on the freedom of the library's law.
Scott: and basically a country made two laws.
Scott: and These two laws Basically set up so that there would be two private semi.
Scott: Well one public and one semi public military force Fighting against each other within the country of Japan now, which is absolutely crazy.
Rym: This was after.
Rym: that was the name of that Incidents.
Scott: Oh the the Hino.
Scott: Yes the Hino library incident It always has to be an incident right?
Scott: Gundam seed you have the bloody Valentine bloody Valentine.
Rym: It was something Valentine, I'm pretty sure is bloody bound the bloody Valentine that was like the bloody eye.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, you know all these animes.
Scott: they always have that incident in the pad Seven y'all as Junius seven, right?
Scott: That was the that was the name of the colony and it's always that same sort of shtick.
Rym: but basically the government busted in with this.
Rym: basically a bunch of people who are dressed like M bison go around trying to burn books and meanwhile the Librarians are all armed with a full military.
Scott: Yeah, they're not allowed to burn books that the libraries have.
Scott: So the libraries go around buying books and protecting them from the people who are M bison Which
Rym: is great because there is a scene where this isn't really a spoiler where something happened outside of a library in some other building and the police are like will handle it and the library corps basically say Hold on a minute and they buy the building declared a library and then bust in with guns.
Scott: Yeah, because they're not allowed to go if it's not a librarian.
Scott: The thing about this show right is that on the one hand you've got sort of like this.
Scott: The big setup is this whole library war thing, but they don't really go and investigate This whole.
Scott: you know Obviously, they want to give a message about.
Scott: you know censorship.
Scott: It's the say.
Scott: it's the same moral as Fahrenheit 451, but they don't ever actually explore that Moral very much at all.
Scott: They just sort of use it as an excuse for military Set, you know action in a civilian setting now.
Rym: That is why one of the reasons why I was originally comparing it to Full Metal Panic because Full Metal Panic was half Alright, let's have military stuff going on in an otherwise totally normal world.
Rym: Yep, and The problem with that was that that show tried to be two completely different shows at the same time and as a result neither one.
Scott: Now the thing is the thing that saves Toshikata and Senso, right is The characters in the show.
Scott: It's almost like it's a separate show.
Scott: It's like there's a perfectly nor.
Scott: It's not like a great show, but it's a perfectly normal above average Anime character drama and this other.
Scott: they just happen to use this crazy ludicrous backdrop of library wars behind it.
Scott: but the character drama itself is Perfectly fine and it's actually really great.
Scott: and I like the characters and I like the way they you know develop and how they work With each other and the situations they get in and the whole thing.
Scott: It's just they happen to put it in ludicrous land.
Rym: But the the cool thing now again, we have.
Rym: we've only seen the first four episodes.
Scott: I saw six.
Rym: Okay, you saw six.
Rym: We have seen on average five episodes But It wasn't that funny.
Rym: But we don't know that this might be one of those shows that later on pulls the.
Rym: oh no now We're getting into the plot business.
Scott: The I think is gonna be plot II but I'm pretty confident that that it might go in that direction.
Rym: But I could also see it going in the concentrate on the characters direction or in the very least it seems for now to be going in the.
Rym: It is not about the setting is about the characters and the setting is just an excuse to have all this go on.
Rym: And as a result, it's very obvious the good guys want to protect books.
Rym: They are clearly the good guys.
Rym: the bad guys want to burn books.
Rym: They're all dressed like M bison.
Scott: It's a little similar to cowboy bebop in that respect and the cowboy bebop had this world.
Scott: That was really just a backdrop for the unrelated character draw slightly related character drama.
Scott: You know, even though cowboy bebop setting was less preposterous But perhaps also didn't have a such a built-in moral that was blazingly obvious.
Rym: I think preposterous is the right word because we mentioned it earlier But there's kind of the scale where there's cowboy bebop and then you take one step more toward preposterous Arity.
Scott: Yeah, basically while I'm watching that is this show while I'm watching Tosha content So I sort of alternate, you know It's like I'll be watching it and suddenly there'll be a scene Where my suspension of disbelief flies right out the window and I'm like, what the fuck.
Scott: this is the stupidest most ludicrous bullshit I've ever seen.
Scott: but then I'm like, but you know what?
Scott: I'll sit here for the next 30 seconds until this bullshit is over because then there's gonna be five minutes of the characters that I've grown to like suddenly.
Rym: and I really like the characters because again kind of like full metal panic there's like the characters aren't really stereotypical, but they're all really strongly cast and they're not.
Rym: they stand out and they're Interesting and I'm interested in all of them and there's kind of the same separation of character roles like full metal panic.
Rym: But full metal panic took all those character roles put them all to the extreme and made it dumb as a result.
Rym: Yeah, but I got to stop.
Rym: I'm just trashing full metal panic.
Scott: I know.
Scott: the other thing is though Is that some of the episodes the individual episode plots are sort of resolved often by you know?
Scott: Semi-deus ex machina things which are hard to believe but it works because it's early on.
Rym: Yes, a lot of those things I don't think they're really deus ex machina as in.
Rym: there's these parallels because the whole point I the real story of the show forget the library wars and all that is.
Rym: there's a girl a girl who?
Rym: loves books and she is trying to buy a banned book at a bookstore just as these M bison types busted and they take the book from her and she tries to defend it.
Rym: and then a knight in shining armor.
Rym: Well, basically one of these library core people saves her and saves the book and she looks up to this person wants to become like this person so she joins the library car and That's where the show kind of begins.
Rym: So you have these parallels.
Rym: where then this drill sergeant that she works with?
Rym: there's the same kind of relationship And then he's a lot like she was when she was young and this idealism playing through and etc.
Rym: etc.
Scott: It's that typical anime thing.
Scott: where oh, is that drill sergeant?
Scott: Is he the guy who saved her way back in the day?
Scott: or he's a lot like her, you know Cuz he never.
Scott: they never showed the guy's face and it's sort of like the horse.
Rym: This is the cycle of how people like this are born.
Scott: Yeah, and then they you know, it's like obviously they're supposed to get together But they don't.
Scott: and they some other characters in there like, you know, the cool roommate girl and the other Officers.
Scott: and then you know, they heard the person who's also on the same team as she is the Tezuka kid.
Scott: If they said Tezuka, I thought they were talking about Tezuka like when they first said his name.
Scott: It's about books, so I thought they were going to save a Tezuka book, but then I was like, oh wait No, this guy's name is Tezuka this new character.
Scott: They just introduced two seconds ago.
Rym: Okay, so the main character?
Rym: Well, I guess the real the super main character though This is one of those shows where there's kind of a core of mostly main ish characters.
Rym: Yeah, definitely Iku I really like her because she's not super stereotypical at all.
Scott: No, she did.
Scott: I can't really think of that.
Rym: many, you know She reminds me a little bit of Hitomi from Escaflowne in terms of personality a little bit a little bit She's.
Scott: she's a little crazier a little more energetic in the in the emotions at least.
Rym: She's also tall Athletic strong and kind of full of fights.
Scott: Yeah, she's also.
Scott: she's not stupid, but she's a little she you know.
Scott: They show her not be performing at peak in the mental tasks as much as the physical tasks Not right away, but what she does have are guts.
Scott: She's got plenty of guts.
Scott: That's for sure.
Scott: alright, so this show is Made by production IG.
Scott: Those are the people who make the ghost in the shell standalone complexes and such and As you would expect the animation is completely awesome and off-the-wall like super on model But they do a lot.
Scott: sometimes there's a little like there was one like I Guess and maybe in the later episodes like there's a few parts that are off model like they draw.
Scott: they drew her roommate.
Scott: I remember in one scene Like they just they drew it in such a way that she was really tall like way taller than she ever was before and I Was like what might not have noticed that was kind of distracted by you didn't?
Scott: I don't think you saw that episode?
Rym: I probably didn't.
Scott: there was also another one where like they animated the main character walking like a little weird.
Scott: It's like it seems like they got one bad animator on the team and like one scene in 20 will be a little awkward.
Rym: You hear that Takashi?
Rym: Yeah, she Tanaka Tanaka.
Scott: But otherwise, you know the the.
Rym: the graphical quality of this show is you know at production IG standards No, they slip away into kind of super deformed land a lot, but they do it in a in a stylistically More unique way than you usually see.
Scott: Yeah It's very.
Scott: it's very polished and shiny and the colors are really strong and it's obvious that these people have the animation skills and Technologies and budget.
Rym: it's definitely though.
Rym: One thing you'll notice is it's one of those thick lines shows.
Rym: There's a lot of everything's thick and there's thick lines and strong lines everywhere.
Rym: And that's that's how I would characterize it.
Scott: Yep The music is you know, the opener and closer are pretty much standard j-pop songs.
Scott: They didn't really catch me to catch you.
Rym: I didn't even notice him.
Scott: Yeah, they're just j-pop songs.
Scott: typical, you know, Sony music is I guess one of these sponsors, you know.
Scott: The other sponsor is who?
Rym: Pocky.
Rym: Oh I was expecting something related to books.
Scott: It's actually Glico, but they make Pocky.
Rym: Well, yes, they do.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I was watching it was like, you know, oh, okay.
Scott: Thank you.
Scott: They must you know.
Rym: sponsors Whatever now if you have any doubts as to where the show's loyalties lie I'll point out that the manga is published in Dengeki Daioh.
Scott: That is the same Manga anthology that publishes the Asa manga dial the Otsuba, etc.
Rym: Now it's ongoing as is the anime.
Rym: The anime is not done yet.
Rym: Yep, so, uh, I don't know I like it and I'm probably going to watch all of it.
Scott: Oh, I probably watch over.
Scott: That means better than a lot of other anime seen recently.
Scott: It's not some amazing, you know, perfect anime because there is still the absolutely Unbelievable universe that makes absolutely no sense and is really kind of painful at moments.
Rym: I will say one thing though The universe works partly because apparently the author of the manga hero Arakawa writes a lot about the SDF and military stuff and she knows what she's doing.
Rym: because The action scenes the military action scenes, which are actually a Not too bad Minority most of the show is just the characters hanging out and talking and doing their thing.
Rym: It's not like a super action show.
Rym: It's a. it's a lot of character stuff and then the action kind of comes in and punctuates what the characters were doing.
Rym: yeah, but the action is Very realistic in terms of military tactics and that sort of thing Like there's a lot of subtle like sniper tactics and squad tactics.
Rym: They're animated very much more properly than the average anime would animate them far better than those eyes eyes and Jotaro Animates them.
Rym: I don't think you can say it's hard to say better because you can't multiply by zero and get anywhere.
Rym: I Mean if this show had flat helicopters that come out of nowhere.
Scott: It has plenty.
Scott: actually the helicopters are really nice in this.
Rym: Yeah They are but like all the little details of squad tactics are there and you won't care about this unless you're a military otaku.
Rym: But if you care, it's there.
Scott: Yep, but the reason for the tactics is stupid.
Rym: It's not That stupid.
Scott: it's not that stupid because it's weird because you have this ludicrous completely off-the-wall Unbelievable premise.
Scott: yet the aesthetic of the premise is awesome And the moral of the premise is sort of obvious Fahrenheit 451 moral.
Rym: But it doesn't matter.
Rym: obviously you should not let books out that damage you and you should burn anything controversial.
Rym: Of course exactly and bison will help you.
Scott: But you can you sort of ignore the you know lack of belief in the premise because you like the aesthetic and the character Drama, and well, there isn't that much of the premise going around.
Rym: It's interesting we brought up read or die because if this show takes a step toward preposterity From something like cowboy bebop then of course read or die goes beyond the word preposterous to the point where it's so out there That you have no choice, but to take it completely at face value.
Scott: Well, I think the difference is right is that this world presented in Toshikan sense.
Scott: Oh is in every other aspect like the real world.
Scott: There's no magic or anything else crazy and people are generally smart and whatnot.
Scott: So the fact that this incredibly stupid thing would happen sort of doesn't fit Whereas in read or die is a totally fantastical world.
Scott: so they sort of make up their own rules.
Scott: You know it is and they're self consistent.
Rym: What I think worked so well it was that read or die was this completely fantastical group of characters and plot Sets in other than all these people a completely normal world.
Rym: Everything was normal except all the characters in the show.
Rym: It's weird.
Scott: It's like when you're doing any sort of story right the sort of like this line you cross to where like you know your fantasy Enough.
Scott: well first of all you always have to be self-consistent or else And you know it's always gonna be screwed up no matter how fantasy you are.
Scott: But it's like you become fantasy enough that you can do really weird things and have people believe them as long as they're self-consistent.
Scott: But if you're not fantasy enough if you're only a tiny bit fantasy and everything else is very much reality Then it becomes hard to accept that little bit of fantasy even if you know it's self-consistent.
Rym: Like DMZ I was about to say it's kind of like DMZ jinx.
Rym: yeah, but the only difference I would say is that I'm able to run with this a lot more easily than I was with DMZ.
Rym: I forced myself to go screw it.
Scott: I like actually actually I've run with DMZ a little more easily that I run with this.
Rym: well the thing is with with DMZ I think what I was able to do is I just I purposefully decided to not consider Anything, but the actual story of the guy and that was the only way I could get around it.
Rym: In this show I kind of I'm going with everything it presents me in the world and As a result every now and then I have the pangs of.
Rym: that doesn't make any sense But that's always supplanted by but it's totally fucking awesome.
Scott: Yeah, see in DMZ my lack of belief is sort of meta and that when I'm not reading it I think about what DMZ is and I say wow that's really unbelievable.
Scott: What while reading DMZ the lack of believability in the premise doesn't get in my face?
Rym: Met the rednecks at the tunnel is when my Ability to run with that setting got shot.
Scott: I don't know it didn't bother me.
Scott: But in Toshikansen, so you know for like a minute or two per episode when the premise gets in my face It kind of is like and I sort of just try to get through it to get on to the part where you know the characters And I can forget about the you know absolutely insane book thing.
Rym: But seriously the show is really fun, and it is fun.
Scott: You know what.
Rym: I hate to make a recommendation so open like this, but it's a. if you like anime It's just if you're an anime fan You would care not just.
Rym: oh I like specific anime.
Rym: as you know people like a lot of people like it.
Rym: well Everyone likes cowboy bebop, but not everyone likes cowboy bebop is an anime fan.
Rym: They might just be a cowboy bebop fan And then they like this other thing and that other thing like most normal people are.
Rym: But if you consider yourself to be an anime fan.
Rym: just in general.
Rym: you're the kind of person who goes to anime cons.
Rym: You're the kind of person who does all that.
Rym: you will probably really like this show.
Scott: Yeah, this is this is a very wide appeal show.
Scott: it has a lot of stuff.
Scott: You know it can appeal to a wide group of people the military otaku the serious sci-fi people.
Scott: a little bit You know the the people looking for the character drama the comedy people a little slice-of-life action Military otaku.
Rym: They don't bring it up.
Rym: But if you pay attention the uniforms and the badges and the ranks and them and all that stuff is perfectly self referentially consistent.
Scott: Yeah, it's got the shoujo relationship action going on.
Rym: I actually really like the relationships.
Scott: I do that actually that's my favorite part of the show just when when someone asks because it's sort of like antenna with the fairy tale But you know backstory yes plus with the but also when someone asks someone out I actually really thought that was funny.
Scott: That was it was pretty good.
Scott: It came out of nowhere, but it was alright.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's a solid show.
Rym: what more can I say?
Rym: you'll probably like it if you like.
Scott: you want something light if you can Get past and and you you can deal in your mind with the fact that the world makes no sense.
Scott: Then you can watch this show and you'll probably enjoy.
Scott: it won't be the best show ever But you'll probably like it.
Scott: at least you'll like six episodes worth.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.