Rym: It's Tuesday, November 11th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, why do we play the old games and not the new games?
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So I ordered this pizza stone from Amazon.
Scott: after, you know, I researched what was the best pizza stone.
Scott: Then I went on Amazon, I ordered it.
Scott: It was like the square one, which I thought was interesting.
Scott: But you know, who cares if they say it's the best is the best.
Rym: Well, I'm excited because this is part of the, uh, I was gonna say trifecta, but we're only buying two things.
Rym: My portion of this is.
Rym: I ordered a waffle maker, which is apparently, uh, no, no, but it's in my Amazon queue.
Scott: So the pizza stone arrived today.
Scott: I open it up and where is the stone?
Rym: Well, there's a stone.
Scott: I open, there's a box.
Scott: Inside the box is some crumpled, like brown paper and then another box.
Scott: And in the other box is the pizza stone, which has like a corrugated cardboard frame that sort of holds it in the middle of the box.
Scott: So it's not actually touching the box and it's not bouncing around or anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, um, I go in to take the stone out and, uh, there's two stones in there because it's broken.
Scott: It says on the inner box, it says fragile on the outer boxes is amazon.com.
Scott: So I go to Amazon to click, like returns, you know, damaged in shipment.
Scott: Right.
Scott: My pizza stone is broken and I get to the point where it says, you know, uh, print these out and put them on the package when you send it back.
Scott: And it, uh, I click print and then it crashes.
Rym: That's great.
Scott: So I go to Chrome, right.
Scott: Which is supposed to not crash or at least only crash one tab when it crashes, not 10 times per second.
Rym: Right.
Scott: I click it and it crashes all of Chrome.
Scott: And so it crashed Firefox and Chrome.
Scott: I'm going to try Internet Explorer after the show and I'm going to try Safari.
Scott: I'm going to try opera.
Scott: I think Amazon might've figured out some exploit.
Scott: They can crash all browsers or and they're just using it to prevent you from returning merchant.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: It's brilliant because I can recall stories from my early days of I.T.
Rym: of certain companies that may have, if a problematic customer was on the line, just, uh, just hang up on them because it'll probably take them a while to figure out to call back.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then they're going to wait in a long waiting queue again.
Rym: Good times.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So news is.
Scott: I don't know if you can handle my news.
Rym: I don't know if I can't either, but I'll say this.
Rym: When I got home, I saw that pizza stone box out on the porch and it was like open and on its side.
Rym: And it was in a pretty sad state.
Rym: So I can't say that I'm that surprised.
Rym: the pizza stone was broken.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I guess there's the one disadvantage to ordering the things online, but I'll be going to the post office this weekend.
Rym: Yeah, either that or worst case, charging back the credit card.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, no, they let you return shit.
Scott: Well, apparently they don't find out.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So you've been talking about the stupid news.
Rym: Well, what could you possibly have?
Scott: I don't know if I can explain this news without just reading the article, which I hate doing.
Scott: But let me I'll read the headline and then you tell me what you think this headline means.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'm game.
Scott: Von Hans is to star in Les Freres Corbusier's Dance Dance Revolution.
Rym: Are they making a French Canadian version of DDR?
Scott: There's going to be a play in the Ohio theater that is...
Rym: Wait, wait.
Rym: The Ohio theater in Ohio?
Scott: I must assume in Ohio.
Rym: No, it's got to be the thing.
Rym: Ohio was named after.
Scott: I don't know, but Les Freres will transform the Ohio theater into a fully immersive bombed out discotheque as it fuses Japanese rave music with sophomore comedy and a futuristic dance spectacular.
Scott: The show is inspired by the wildly popular video game of the same name.
Rym: This sounds kind of awesome.
Rym: You know, Emily and I were going to go to the opera, but fuck that.
Scott: Additional cast members will include person, person, person, person, person.
Scott: Prior works include Obie Award winning a very merry unauthorized children's Scientology pageant.
Scott: Boozy, Hell House and Head-A-Tron.
Rym: Head-A-Tron.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What is that about?
Scott: I don't know, but I kind of want to see a very merry unauthorized children's Scientology pageant.
Rym: I can say one thing, a bombed out discotheque.
Scott: Well, no disco T-H-E with an accent sign.
Rym: Yes, that's how you spell discotheque.
Rym: Q-U-E.
Rym: That's how you spell discotheque.
Scott: Some people spell it D-I-S-C-O-T-E-K.
Rym: Yes, they're wrong.
Rym: But bombed out discotheque gives me the Charles Barkley shut up and jam guide and vibe.
Scott: Japanese rave music with sophomore comedy fusion futuristic dance.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I get this like Japanese DDR equivalent of Charles Barkley shut up and jam guide and in a future post-apocalyptic world where DDR is outlawed.
Rym: Only sophomore comedy remains dancing and bombed out discotheques.
Scott: Well, we'll feature original songs by Gary Atler and Phoebe Kreutz.
Scott: The production will play the Ohio theater December 3rd through 20th.
Scott: Alex Timbers will direct.
Scott: This is from theater mania dot com.
Scott: I don't know what else to say about that.
Scott: For more information, visit lessfrayrares.org.
Rym: You know, I really kind of want to see it now, but I don't want to go to Ohio.
Rym: But then again, maybe the Ohio theater is not in Ohio.
Scott: Yeah, Hans is the star is best known for playing gay teen Luke Snyder on the CBS daytime drama as the world turns and appeared off Broadway last season in Die Mommy Die.
Scott: This is a high class theater production here.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: That's like we're talking.
Scott: we're talking Tony Award lock in.
Scott: This is going to run longer than cats, I guarantee it.
Rym: So if we don't get a chance to see this, I urge anyone within a radius of where bring in a video camera.
Scott: Get me some bootlegs.
Scott: Where is the CD audio in the soundtrack?
Rym: I implore you.
Rym: Please go see this and tell us what happens.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if it's the if the Ohio theaters in Ohio or not, but God damn.
Scott: I mean, we don't even have like Mario the musical.
Rym: Well, well, well, well, I'm sure there is.
Scott: Well, yeah, but not in a real theater define real at Ohio.
Scott: We're better.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So I want to talk about this just because there is a whole bunch of rambling on slash.
Scott: Just one more thing.
Scott: I went to.
Scott: I went to the Les Freres Web site here.
Scott: And here's here's a few things that must be read.
Scott: Ready?
Scott: So it's a futuristic dance, spectacular, fusing, unmerciful Japanese rave music with deeply regrettable sophomore comedy.
Scott: Oh, they've got more adjectives.
Rym: Those are good adjectives.
Scott: And then wait.
Scott: And a futuristic Orwellian society where dancing is illegal.
Rym: Oh, my God, it is Charles Barkley.
Rym: Shut up.
Scott: A group of local street toughs harbor.
Scott: no hope of overthrowing the fascistic.
Scott: no fun government until a mysterious dance prophet named Moonbeam Funk arrives.
Rym: Oh, my sweet Jesus.
Scott: I can't say anymore.
Rym: I've got to say click here to buy tickets.
Rym: We've got to say I clicked here to buy tickets, buy tickets, just find out smart ticks, then you'll find out where it is.
Scott: General admission seating.
Rym: Wait, general admission.
Scott: I guess you just go in and sit wherever you see.
Scott: Ohio Theater, Worcester Street, New York.
Scott: What?
Rym: What?
Rym: We're going.
Scott: Yeah, duh.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: The Ohio Theater is in New York, New York.
Scott: One oh one two.
Scott: That's right near my work.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: What bring in?
Scott: It's around the corner of my office.
Rym: When's it playing?
Scott: Just buy like December 20th, December 2nd through something sweet.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So like date and time.
Scott: Well, let me look at it again.
Rym: OK, all right.
Rym: I told you couldn't have been in Ohio.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I was thinking Ohio or France.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: Around the corner from my office, literally like like a block away.
Rym: I'm so excited about this.
Scott: Yeah, I work on the Lafayette and Prince Spring is one street south of Prince and Broom is like one or two streets.
Rym: OK, kids, we'll post in the forum once we've picked our dates.
Rym: And I hope any of you in the city will come and see the show.
Rym: And then afterward we will probably have 16 showings.
Scott: All of them are at 8 p.m.
Scott: on various days, Wednesdays, Thursdays, Fridays, Saturdays, Sundays, Tuesday.
Rym: Much like how theaters function and not Mondays, though.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Much like how theaters function.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: OK, good guy.
Rym: Well, we're going to that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, my news really doesn't live up now.
Scott: See, I told you my news was awesome.
Rym: I got to admit you were right.
Rym: But I got to talk about this because there's a lot of rambling.
Rym: But there was this article on Slashdot and the headline was, and I quote, vital parts of games as DLC.
Rym: Now, if you're not hip to the Internet, DLC means downloadable content, which I think is a stupid acronym.
Scott: Why do I much prefer the UGC to the DLC?
Rym: Why is there an L?
Rym: download is one word?
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But DC is people think DC Comics in Washington, DC.
Scott: So you need to do something different in this.
Rym: But DLC is not what you do.
Rym: I'm not sure what you do.
Scott: Downloadable content.
Rym: Maybe you just say downloadable content.
Rym: I don't think we need an acronym for that yet.
Scott: Why don't we just say, you know, I don't understand why when something is, you know, when you change the distribution mechanism, you need to call it something different.
Scott: Well, in this case, we kind of it's a video game, whether you download it or buy it on a disk.
Rym: But video games have always been in this really kind of interesting situation where the in every market, in anything you can buy and sell physical goods.
Rym: There's the primary market and the secondary market.
Rym: And then there's the black market.
Rym: There's also the gray market.
Rym: But anyway, there's this kind of gradations and, you know, people buy things in retail stores, but then they resell those things through pawn shops or to their friends or on eBay.
Rym: Sometimes people steal things or get, you know, off shelf merchandise from stores in weird situations to sell in the gray market or the black market.
Rym: But usually most of the commerce of something is in the primary retail market, at least in America.
Rym: That's the way things are.
Scott: There's a lot more sales of DVD.
Scott: if you compare sale.
Scott: I mean, DVD sales aren't that big except on certain things.
Scott: But if you compare DVD sales of new legitimate DVDs at Best Buy and Amazon and compare it to used DVD sales, used DVD sales has nothing.
Scott: If you compare like even CD sales and MP3 sales are down in the you're not that great either are a lot more than used CD sales, which are restricted to like tiny shops in random places.
Rym: But even at the height of the Napster paranoia, when the music industry suddenly collectively realized that they were completely screwed.
Rym: They weren't like they were always down on the secondary market, but that was such like.
Rym: basically it's like music got to the point where piracy came into existence and destroyed the industry long before the secondary market could kind of come in and do this.
Rym: But with video games, the secondary market, as far as I can tell, is getting to the point where it's almost bigger than the primary market.
Scott: Here is why you're ready for this.
Scott: This is the reason that the video game secondary market is so huge.
Rym: I think that the reasons for it are numerous.
Scott: No, it's really simply ready.
Rym: OK.
Scott: The people who buy video games are punk kids with no money.
Scott: They want to play a lot of different games, but they can only afford to actually buy one or two at the price of fifty dollars.
Rym: But at the same time, they could just pirate them.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But it's a lot easier.
Scott: You know, it's hard to pirate games for, say, the 360 or the PS3 or the Wii.
Scott: So when those kids want to play those games now, they get a couple for presents.
Scott: You know, maybe they buy one or two.
Scott: They beat them.
Scott: There's no replay value or they, you know, they'd much rather play a new game even if there is replay value.
Scott: So GameStop easily tricks these punk kids into trading their games in because kid doesn't have 50 bucks, but he's got 10 bucks.
Scott: She gives in his 50 dollar game and 10 bucks, gets a new game, gets another 10 bucks and does it again.
Scott: And he's effectively buying new video games for 10 bucks, which you can't afford to do where you can't afford the 50 dollars.
Scott: He just only has one video game at a time.
Scott: And but he could actually hold the game onto it until he beats it, which is preferable to, say, doing blockbuster game rentals where he might have to return the game before he's beaten the game.
Rym: See, but at the same time, I think there's a little more to it than that, because with video games, especially among the kinds of people who care about that sort of thing, having the game right away is important to these kids because you want to beat it and play it.
Scott: You can get a used game right away.
Rym: Well, not necessarily.
Rym: It depends on where you live.
Rym: I mean, we live in New York City where some kid will buy the game and beat it and return it that day.
Rym: But in a lot of places, you go to GameStop, they're not going to have the used version of the game for weeks now.
Scott: So you return your old game and buy, you know, and it becomes a used copy for someone else who's going to buy that.
Scott: And then you buy the new game new and then you return that later and you buy, you know, the other new game new, I think.
Rym: But there's more to it than that in that a lot of people I mean, movies, you could do the same thing.
Rym: And movies are even in many ways less kind of time dependent, because if you care about seeing the movie when it's current, you see it in the theater when it's actually current.
Rym: If you're going to watch it on DVD, then it really doesn't matter when you watch it to even like hardcore movie people.
Rym: But a lot of people buy movies and collect movies and you don't really have this secondary market for DVDs.
Scott: as much as the price of a DVD isn't fifty dollars.
Scott: It's like fifteen dollars.
Scott: If a DVD was fifty dollars, you would see the secondary market.
Rym: I don't know, because it seems like people who buy movies, buy DVDs, they hold on to them for various reasons because they're fifteen dollars.
Rym: Well, no, partly because I think they want to they feel like I'm going to use this again.
Rym: I'm going to show this movie to someone.
Rym: It's part of my collection.
Rym: I was fifty dollars.
Scott: They'd be doing that with a lot less of them.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: But at least video games, especially a lot of modern single player games, have basically zero replay value, like not like a movie that's only an hour investment or a two hour investment where, you know, I'll watch Star Wars again.
Rym: I'm glad I'm a million times.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Or I'll watch The Matrix one.
Rym: Well, the Matrix.
Rym: There weren't any other Matrix movies.
Scott: Well, you only saw one of the other two.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: And I knew better, you know, it's.
Rym: besides I do recall that you and several other people, the front row crew for quite some time not only insisted that I had seen the movie and that I was with you in the theater seeing the movie, but you argued this point against me for some time.
Scott: I think you could have been lying.
Rym: It wasn't until I proved with a pay stub that I, in fact, was living in Poughkeepsie and working at IBM at the time that you relented.
Scott: The point is, is I think, well, that's a tangent.
Scott: But I think the Matrix movie, the second and third Matrix movies, they weren't bad.
Scott: Well, no, they were bad.
Scott: They were bad movies, but they weren't super bad.
Scott: They were just regular bad and they got and they were treated as super bad because they were held in the light of the super great Matrix one.
Scott: And I think, you know, the second half of Death Note suffers from the same thing and many other, you know, a lot of things do.
Rym: But the other thing about the video game industry that's interesting is along with this kind of gigantic secondary market, there's this so-called hardcore gamer idea that they've got.
Rym: You know, there are the hardcore gamers and the people who are really into games feel like they're the base.
Rym: And they used to be true.
Rym: I mean, think about it.
Rym: Video games used to be a very niche thing and not that many people played video games.
Rym: It was kind of a weird side hobby.
Rym: But as video games mainstream, do they really mainstreamed?
Rym: I mean, video, everyone plays video games.
Rym: Some woman at my work bought a Wii today and she's like, yeah, I heard so much about these Wii games and bowling and stuff that I just bought one at the Circuit City.
Rym: that's closing.
Scott: Oh, good deal.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Was it 10 percent off?
Rym: I think so.
Rym: It was cheap.
Rym: She bought it just kind of on a whim while she was out at lunch.
Scott: Well, I mean, Wiis aren't that expensive to begin with, but if there's a little bit of discount on it, it's a big deal.
Rym: But as they mainstreamified, we've got to this point where it's much more profitable to either make a game that has a low barrier to entry and a recurring cost or a game that's just crap.
Rym: I believe all those games that have the name of an animal followed by the letter Z.
Scott: Yeah, you know, making software is pretty easy, especially if, you know, you only have to change, you know, a little bit of it.
Scott: You know, it's like, well, I'll make a game, you know, with a guy who jumps on bad guys.
Scott: It's a side scrolling game.
Scott: OK, I made one.
Scott: Now I want to make another one.
Scott: All I do is change the pictures on it, maybe redo some of the levels.
Scott: It'll take a few days.
Scott: I got another game.
Scott: It took you know, it didn't cost me almost anything.
Scott: And I can still sell it for 30 bucks.
Scott: And even if only a few people buy it, I'm in the money.
Rym: So the video game market is in this really difficult situation where the people who are into games now, I'm not going to try to make a value judgment as to what games are good or what games are not, other than the fact that pets is a bad game.
Rym: But the problem is the people who even a game who are really, really into games are also the ones who tend to not play the games that are mainstream and make money.
Rym: There's much more incentive to make the crappy game and sell it to the non gamers.
Rym: I mean, look, how much money is Fallout three going to make compared to how much money it costs to actually design that game versus like another Sims expansion or Burning Crusade or something?
Scott: Well, basically, you know, the video game industry is something out, something that started out as niche only, you know, because it was, you know, delegated to the, you know, the as a kid's toy and, you know, many other reasons, you know, throughout its history.
Scott: And it's still sort of backwards.
Scott: If you look at every other, you know, medium of, you know, artistic works in the U.S.
Scott: entertainment medium, right.
Scott: Big time money making movies, the blockbusters, the things that make the most money they spend the most money on.
Scott: and the ones that are for the quote hardcore are in the art house theater.
Scott: They cost less money to make and less people see them.
Scott: It's in balance there.
Rym: In the video game industry, the books that the art house game is usually more expensive to make.
Scott: Yeah, they the the hardcore video games are the ones they spend the most money on and make the least money on.
Scott: or well, not the least, but not enough money on.
Scott: And the game that costs almost nothing to make makes plenty of money, at least relative to the cost, you know, and sells a bajillion copies and doesn't appeal to the people who care about, you know, care the hardcore and appeals to just, you know, the masses.
Rym: So basically, but the video game industry still needs these hardcore people because while they don't make money necessarily from marketing games to these people, those people provide this kind of pseudo culture that is used to market video games.
Rym: like there's the subculture of video gaming.
Rym: And I feel like that subculture is used to market video games to people who aren't in that subculture.
Rym: Maybe we'll get to the point where the subculture doesn't actually exist anymore.
Rym: And the image of the gamer that you see in like the magazine is just completely made up.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I think that the the the main problem now, I think, with the image of the, you know, gamer is that the actual, you know, people who care about video games and, you know, games are a big part of their lives and they self identify as a, you know, video game player.
Scott: I think that those people have, you know, sort of balkanized in, you know, to the extreme to where you can't really say, well, what's a gamer?
Scott: Is it that, you know, guy who plays, you know, DDR at the arcade nonstop or is it that guy sitting there still playing Counter-Strike?
Scott: Is it, you know, is it the guy who's playing Smash Brothers in the tournaments?
Scott: You know, these are all like.
Scott: so, you know, to most people out there, those are all like the same person.
Scott: But when you really look at it, they're completely different people.
Scott: The guy playing DDR is never playing Counter-Strike.
Scott: You know, they're they're completely separate.
Rym: But here's here's the one thing that ties it all together.
Rym: I mean, we went to PAX, of course, and you look at the demographic of people who self identify as gamers and by and large, while a number of them tend to be young, poor punk kids in high school, it's also affluent 20 somethings, oftentimes tech workers, people who have a lot of money to burn and unless they're podcasters or something, have plenty of time to to play video games and they're into video games and games like Fallout and these kind of high production value games can make a lot of money if all those people who have this money buy it.
Scott: But there aren't that many of those people.
Rym: No, there are.
Rym: There are enough of those people for these games to be profitable.
Rym: if those are enough.
Rym: Well, no, there's plenty.
Rym: If the people buy the games at retail, but with the secondary market more and more, especially when more games are out there and there's more entertainment options available, even the affluent 20 somethings, I think, are willing to wait and buy a game used or hold off and not even pirate, but just use the perfectly legal secondary market.
Rym: And the gaming industry has to come up with a way to either have to give up on these people or come up with a way to get these people to have some reason to buy the game at retail as opposed to from the secondary market, giving the game store the money.
Rym: Now, Steam is a great way to do that because you cut out the game store entirely and you definitely can't sell a game you bought on Steam to anyone.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: But at the same time, that doesn't work for console games so much until now.
Rym: The point of the article was basically that one way around this and it's basically a loophole to get around the first sale doctrine.
Rym: What if you sell games for online consoles, but you take advantage of this downloadable content business to say, all right, you buy the game, you can play it.
Rym: I don't care where you bought it from.
Rym: But to beat the boss at the end of the game, you got to pay 20 bucks to get the downloadable content.
Rym: Well, you can't transfer that.
Scott: Well, people who don't realize this would be pissed and people who do realize it would never buy the game.
Rym: See, no, I don't know, because maybe the people who are really into gaming will just buy the game at retail, which of course includes all the downloadable content for free.
Rym: You only have to pay for it if you bought the bootleg secondhand copy.
Scott: Oh, is that how it works?
Scott: That's how it works.
Scott: How could you make that go?
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: How do you make it go?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Technologically speaking.
Rym: So I buy Mario eight on the Xbox.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And I buy the thing.
Rym: But when I put it in my Xbox, much like when I pick up an item and wow, it binds to my Xbox like that, it downloads the downloadable content.
Rym: once that copy of the game that I bought, that physical disk will never download the content again for free.
Scott: But what if I, you know, my Xbox dies and they get a new Xbox?
Rym: Well, you get the entitlements back.
Rym: So if you get a new if your Xbox dies, you can transfer the entitlements from your old Xbox to the new Xbox.
Rym: But if I buy a second Xbox, I can't have the entitlement on both.
Rym: If I sell the game to some dude on eBay, he can't get the downloadable content for free.
Rym: He has to buy it.
Rym: But it's only 20 bucks.
Rym: Basically, it's this really kind of underhanded way to completely cut out the secondary market.
Scott: And there's nothing illegal about it.
Rym: It's perfectly legal and it's not even that unethical.
Rym: And while this is not happening yet, I mean, we are seeing a lot of just sort of dickish.
Scott: It's not, you know, wrong, but it would work.
Rym: And I don't know if this is actually ever going to happen or not, because it's I could go 50/50 on whether or not the gaming community would just go to ease.
Rym: They would either suck it up and just buy the games and then GameStop might go out of business or they'll just freak out and pirate everything forever more and pull an RIAA reaction.
Rym: I mean, remember when the RIAA got really bad and people who were into music basically just said, you know what, we hate you.
Rym: We're going to pirate music just because until you go away.
Rym: And I feel like that could happen with video games.
Scott: I think I'm actually starting to you know, I know that early on in this podcast, you know, as in the early days of GeekNights, right, we were often, you know, crying.
Scott: You know, the death of the PC game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, PC game is dying.
Scott: PC gaming is done.
Rym: They were as far as I felt, but there's been a big comeback.
Scott: Well, it's not.
Scott: it's not just that.
Scott: there's been a big comeback.
Scott: I think and what I've realized is that I let's say I make an Xbox game, right?
Scott: Even if I make a game that appeals to the mass audience and not just, you know, the hardcore quote audience, the most copies I can sell is one per Xbox.
Scott: And there's a lot of Xbox is out there.
Scott: Millions.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's a lot more PCs out there.
Scott: And remember back in the day when like mist came out, even people who had no interest in video games or anything, just everyone had every PC had a fucking copy of mist.
Scott: Every single one is like every.
Scott: you could go over to someone's house if they had a DOS computer.
Scott: There was.
Scott: there was a mist box somewhere in that house that he was there somewhere.
Scott: And World of Warcraft is sort of the same way now.
Scott: Everyone's got computers.
Scott: The people with computers in World of Warcraft and no other video games whatsoever going on.
Scott: You know, and I think the companies in their quest for, you know, the money and realizing that, hey, these consoles, as cool as they are and, you know, the living room experience, whatnot, PC gaming is really the way to make the most money.
Scott: You make a game that appeals to an incredibly huge audience and there's no bigger audience than the PC audience.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you make it where you can only get it by downloading it or have some sort of subscription.
Rym: Well, look, they're doing the same thing with the market and you're like Rock Band and all these games, the downloadable content makes it to where they make all their money from that after the fact.
Rym: And I think that's going to work just as well, too.
Rym: But it worries me because I feel like the only way to make money in the long run, you know, in the kind of end game scenario of video games now is going to be either recurring costs because the game is online in some fashion, downloadable content that is tied to you or really, really crappy games with very broad appeal.
Scott: All three.
Rym: Well, yeah, that's the thing.
Rym: You can do those three things, but that means there's not going to be another fallout.
Scott: Well, no, eventually what's going to happen is the video game market is slowly but surely correcting itself to fall in line with movies and books and music and everything else to where all the really popular things that cost more to make are going to have really broad appeal and be really shitty.
Scott: And all the really high quality things are going to have a very small appeal and not have big budgets.
Scott: And that's how it's going to be.
Scott: You know, I mean, and, you know, the next natural selection is going to have a very small budget scraped together by a few guys out west.
Scott: And it's going to appeal to the very small audience of awesome people like us.
Scott: And we're going to play and be happy.
Scott: And they'll make, you know, spore two or whatever in a billion.
Rym: Of course, I point out this brings this brings up a much more interesting end game because.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So video games are going to hit the point where movies are now.
Rym: But movies have their own problem with end game because of movie rentals and all sorts of other things.
Rym: So what's going to happen with movies?
Rym: I mean, the end game for video games might hit after the point where movies and other mainstream media have gone beyond whatever comes next.
Rym: Well, really, the
Scott: main reason that movies and video games aren't in the same situation as music is because bandwidth is limited and eventually all of this will become moot because people have enough bandwidth to where trading a multi gigabyte video game will be as simple as trading an MP3 on the Internet and then everything will go to shit.
Rym: But video games will still have downloadable content.
Rym: Movies can't have that.
Rym: Well, they could.
Rym: They could.
Rym: I can envision that.
Rym: However, it horrifies me.
Rym: It really horrifies me.
Rym: I mean, imagine this.
Rym: Imagine the day where you can pay five bucks after you watch Star Wars to see Star Wars the entire thing again, except Yoda's naked.
Rym: Anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So Emily and I were looking at stuff on YouTube and we stumbled across this.
Rym: And I think it's pretty cool.
Rym: Basically, take make MIDI music, but make MIDI music in such a way that the notes you have constructed form pictures that are relevant to Mario Paint, to the video game that you are making the music from.
Scott: So Mario Paint, Bunch of Game Boys.
Rym: No, not quite.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: It's a lot more.
Rym: You're right.
Scott: The swan is the king.
Scott: Everything else sucks.
Rym: I don't really want to explain it, but it starts out pretty good with the Tetris pieces.
Rym: But the Gradius near the end and the entire Donkey Kong are masterpieces.
Scott: Yeah, the Donkey Kong and the Gradius really are sort of amazing.
Scott: The thing is, you won't understand the Gradius unless you know Gradius music.
Scott: But the Donkey Kong, anyone can understand.
Rym: Yes, it's a whole Donkey Kong.
Scott: People have no idea what you're talking about.
Rym: I know because it's hard to really explain the awesome of this without just watching it.
Rym: So watch my thing of the day.
Rym: It's cool.
Scott: So I'm a big fan of all sorts of quirky indie RPGs lately, and I like to look at them and buy some of them, but and never play them.
Scott: That's my.
Scott: that's my thing lately.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I got to really got to play more of these things.
Scott: But I found this one and this one's in particularly interesting because it comes on a single card.
Scott: It's like a trifold square card, right, with printing on both sides.
Scott: And it's called versus outlaws.
Scott: And it's three dollars.
Scott: And let's see.
Scott: It's a mini RPG of adventure in the Old West.
Rym: What kind of system does it use?
Rym: Tristad.
Scott: It's cool.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: All I know is that it involves hombres dispensing two fisted justice weights.
Rym: You haven't pirated this thing.
Scott: No, it's it's a card.
Scott: It's basically a game written on a piece of cardboard that folds in two places for three dollars.
Scott: But you look at the art on the on the.
Scott: you just look at the art on the cover of this cover of this card.
Scott: And yeah, you can't deny that this is some sort of awesome game.
Scott: And apparently they have also made a game called Versus Monsters.
Rym: Ooh, yeah, I'm holding out for pirates.
Scott: Well, it says here is a complete game to play.
Scott: You will need pencils, paper, a deck of playing cards and a fistful of friends.
Rym: You know, so actually I play.
Rym: I was playing NS tonight when I got home from work and I got home from work and I got a lot of stuff to do.
Scott: But buddy, buddy, buddy, buddy.
Rym: I ended up playing some NS and we had basically I thought, oh, I'll play a couple of quick games and then I'll get on to some business and then it's got to come home to do the show.
Rym: And I ended up only playing one game that did not finish because the Marines turtled the turtle and they had.
Rym: but they turtled in two places.
Rym: They had Marine Star.
Scott: Yeah, that's what happens.
Scott: And they had the hive directly opposite that, because if you could get the third hive, you could win, but you can't get it and you can't get Marine Star without the third hive.
Scott: So it's just it's it's.
Rym: we had the whole rest of the map and it was one of those maps where you could really lurk it up.
Scott: We had three, but it doesn't matter because they turtled and got heavies.
Scott: Your lurks don't do shit.
Rym: No, they didn't have heavies for a long time.
Scott: But if you don't get them before they get the heavies, you're stuck.
Rym: No.
Rym: So we were fine.
Rym: We had three fades and two lurks and we basically the fades ran in and we're just destroying them at Marine Start and really wrecking them.
Rym: And we were.
Rym: we were on the verge of victory.
Scott: Broke the turtle.
Rym: Yes, we were basically.
Rym: well, no, we almost broke the turtle.
Rym: We the lurks were perfect.
Rym: It was like it goes spore, spore, umbra, spore, umbra, umbra, spore.
Scott: Lots of umbras and spores.
Scott: We get it.
Rym: No, but we had a pattern.
Rym: Me and this other lurk.
Scott: Oh, I don't need a pattern.
Rym: Yes, you do.
Rym: Because remember, Umbra and Spore last a certain number of seconds.
Rym: So we had lurks on both sides of Marine Start in two separate hallways getting two opposite sides, protecting the onos and the three fades.
Scott: Oh, that's it.
Scott: It was brilliant.
Rym: It was working so well until we found out that one of the hives was under attack.
Rym: Someone, while we were focused on destroying and breaking the turtle, had ninja'd out, built two phase gates.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's the new strategy these days to build two phase gates.
Scott: That way, even if you rush in to take one down, they come in.
Rym: So we bust up the phase gate in the hive.
Rym: We totally pull it off.
Rym: We start to cheer and then they keep coming and they keep coming.
Rym: And then someone yells, oh, my God, there's another phase gate at four.
Rym: And it was over.
Rym: And the question remains, why am I playing NS when I own Fallout and the Left 4 Dead demo and the new Castlevania game for the DS?
Scott: Because it's better than all those games?
Rym: I don't know if it is better.
Rym: Basically, the point of this show, what we're trying to figure out here is what is wrong with us?
Rym: Why do I play NS and Counter Strike and all these old games?
Rym: I was playing Advance Wars on the train today.
Scott: Why is it that I've only watched a mere fraction of all the movies ever created and I've only listened to a mere fraction of the music ever created?
Scott: I've only ever read a mere fraction of all the things that have been written in the entire history.
Scott: But you watch Star Wars, Star Wars 10,000 times.
Scott: I'll watch it again.
Scott: I'll play the same video game over and over again.
Scott: I'll read the same comic book three times.
Rym: You know, I'll read Watchmen, like specifically video games like I mean, NS is even kind of played out.
Rym: I've been playing NS for a long time.
Rym: Like there is no secret in NS.
Rym: Nothing is going to be revealed to me.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The two phase gates have been sort of recent development, actually.
Rym: I don't think it's a recent development so much as a renaissance of tactics from the heyday.
Scott: Possibly.
Scott: Because we've got such a- Because a few weeks ago, I started playing NS again like weeks ago and a few weeks ago, people weren't doing the double phase gate.
Scott: But like maybe around a week or two ago, like the double phase gate has appeared like a few- like it feels like in my- the games I'm playing, the frequency is increasing.
Rym: So, uh- But it's not like I can say, oh, you know, the argument would be, yeah, well, new games are worse than old games.
Rym: or Rym is elitist and nostalgic and only plays the old games and decides that the new games suck.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: Fallout 3 is awesome.
Rym: I really, really like it.
Rym: When I got it, I played the hell out of it.
Rym: But after like four hours total of gameplay, I still think, wow, that game's really fun.
Rym: Man, I really want to bust into Tenpenny's tower and just fuck everything up in there because I don't like that guy one bit.
Rym: But I sit down in front of the computer and I open Steam and I'm about to click on Fallout and play like two hours of Fallout.
Rym: And then I click on NS instead, not even consciously.
Rym: It's like I want to play Fallout.
Rym: I end up playing NS and I feel more satisfied at the end of the NS game.
Scott: Yeah, definitely.
Scott: I mean, I got, you know, that Wario game, which is great, you know, but I've also got Mega Man 9, haven't played it at all.
Rym: I've been playing a lot of Mega Man 9, but that lends another point to the Rym's just nostalgic pool, because Mega Man 9 is just Mega Man 2 for someone who's played Mega Man 2 so much he's sick of it.
Rym: That's all it is.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I love it.
Rym: Mega Man 9 is great.
Rym: I'm about halfway through it.
Scott: But were you a Mega Man hater?
Rym: No, I was just never good at Mega Man and I didn't.
Rym: I didn't like Mega Man that much, but I didn't hate it.
Rym: I just I liked other games more like.
Rym: I like Metal Gear on the NES a little more than I like Mega Man.
Scott: No, you suck.
Rym: What?
Rym: Metal Gear.
Scott: So I don't like Metal Gear, right?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: See, why?
Scott: Let's see what?
Scott: Basically, it's like I'll just be sitting there and I want to play a video game and I got some free time.
Scott: and it's just.
Scott: I don't know that.
Scott: I don't even usually I have a logic to things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, there is a logic to the amount of time I spend playing video games.
Scott: You know, I don't.
Scott: I don't let my, you know, feelings sort of allow me to uncontrollably play video games for too many hours, you know, as opposed to doing shit.
Scott: You know,
Rym: I've actually broken that instinct because I enjoyed video games a lot more in college when it wasn't a matter of, all right, I'm going to play video games for an hour and then I'm going to do a podcast and then I'm going to braise some chicken to cook some dinner.
Rym: It was all right, I'm going to play Counter-Strike.
Rym: And there was no.
Rym: and then it was just I'm going to play Counter-Strike.
Rym: And at some point I would stop playing Counter-Strike.
Rym: fulfilled, sated.
Rym: I had finished.
Rym: Counter-Strike was now done.
Rym: The time for Counter-Strike was over.
Rym: Then I would turn to look at the clock and decide, well, it's now nine thirty.
Rym: What shall I do next?
Scott: Yeah, but my choice of what video game to play is usually just guided by some feeling, you know, it's like I'll just be standing there with all these games arrayed before me and like I just and as has like the feel like, yeah, that's what I want to play.
Scott: And the other ones don't entice me as much.
Scott: And I don't know.
Rym: Actually, I think I just realized I keep going back to games that I'm comfortable with.
Rym: and but this is strange to me because I really enjoy exploring in games like when I first got the new Castlevania DS, the first one, the one that was basically, yes, Symphony Knight was such a good game that we're going to make that game over and over again forever on the Nintendo DS.
Rym: And that game was great.
Rym: And I played it to the exclusion of all other activities until I beat it.
Rym: And then I played it again in Julius mode until I beat it.
Rym: And I just explored and explored and the novelty was great because I hadn't played a game like that in a long time and I love games like that.
Rym: But I don't know, I've played two of those games and I have the new Castlevania, haven't touched it, haven't even put it in my DS.
Rym: And while I know it's a great game, it's exactly what I want and it's comfortable to me.
Rym: But at the same time, I don't know, the novelty of exploring that kind of world is almost lost to me.
Rym: And even if like a new Advance Wars game came out, I almost feel like my desire to play in my comfort zone is coming from the fact that I want to perfect a game.
Rym: I want to take a game that has this kind of skill cap and reach that skill cap.
Rym: So I keep playing Advance Wars that I'm only 90% perfect at instead of playing the new game that I have no desire to ever be perfect at.
Scott: Well, I think there's something to that, you know, the for example, like when I play like the Castlevania games, right, like the first DS one, I just beat it and then I beat like the second ending and then the second one came out and I beat it.
Scott: But I didn't get the second ending.
Scott: And then I tried to play Symphony of the Night, which I never played before.
Scott: And I was able to beat, you know, the first half of the game and get to the upside down castle.
Scott: But then after getting a bit into the upside down castle, I sort of stopped playing.
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: there are certain, you know, they're good.
Scott: There's good gameplay.
Scott: Exploring a 2D world a la Castlevania, a la Super Metroid is good gameplay.
Scott: I kind of I like that kind of game.
Scott: It's a good kind of game, but there's only so much that I can replay that particular type, you know, gameplay type.
Scott: It's not so much now the where before a whole game would be, you know, replay value.
Scott: Now it's the type of gameplay that it is, is the replay value.
Scott: So it doesn't matter if it's a new one.
Scott: It's I'm doing the same thing as I was doing in the old one or doing the same thing that I was doing in level two as in level one.
Scott: So I can only take so much side scrolling 2D exploring before.
Scott: I don't want any more.
Scott: And there's something about certain games like NS or what other games can I go back to all the time?
Scott: I punch out.
Scott: Yeah, punch out where where even though this is gameplay that I have had a whole bunch of, somehow this type of gameplay tastes good every time.
Scott: Like you can only eat so much of one kind of food before you don't want that kind of food anymore.
Scott: But you can just eat steak, one hundred steaks, and you can still want more steaks like, you know, Wario.
Scott: It's like I'm rocking the Wario.
Scott: I'm probably going to beat it.
Scott: But it's like if I get to a part that's sort of hard, it's like I sort of want to stop playing.
Rym: But well, I remember you had that problem with the newest, newest advanced wars.
Rym: Once you hit that owl, you just had no desire to continue playing.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: I got to the owl and I'm just like, well, fuck this, you know.
Rym: I'll admit the only reason I got past the owl before I just said, you know what, this isn't worth it, was that I beat the owl on my first try with a B because you just suck at advanced wars.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: The owl just sucks.
Rym: No, the owl doesn't suck.
Rym: Believe me, you think the owl sucks.
Rym: The mission after it is a thousand times more annoying.
Scott: I could beat the owl.
Scott: It's just I didn't have the patience for it.
Scott: It's like I didn't want to sit.
Scott: It's like I knew what I had to do.
Scott: But I didn't want to actually sit there doing it.
Scott: That's actually a problem I have with a lot of my job is like when I'm making software, I really like, you know, designing software and trying to solve software problems and figure out how things work and figure out how to fix something.
Scott: But it's like once I figured it out, then you actually have to type in the code that makes that happen.
Scott: And that part doesn't really require thinking as much.
Scott: It's it's a different part of the brain.
Scott: It feels more like manual labor, like it's just, oh, you know, I already.
Scott: No, that I have to.
Scott: This is how it needs to be done.
Scott: Why should I have to actually sit here for an hour just moving my fingers up?
Rym: But at the same time, why do we play punch out over and over and over and over again?
Rym: I know how to beat everyone in the game.
Scott: I've played punch out, but you can't beat everyone in the game, can you?
Rym: I can get almost to the end.
Rym: I never I never legit.
Scott: I can get to the second Don Fomenko.
Scott: That's as far as I can get.
Rym: I've eaten him, but I've never gotten from the beginning of the game to Mike Tyson.
Rym: But I've beaten my ties and starting on my time.
Rym: When did you beat my days when I was a kid?
Rym: I used the code again.
Scott: Let's see you beat Mike Tyson now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know how I beat him?
Rym: I used the code to get to him.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And I'd someone told me exactly how to beat him.
Rym: And I remember I just played over and over and over.
Rym: I just played against Mike Tyson constantly until once I beat him just barely.
Rym: Yeah, it's actually not that hard.
Rym: He's easier than some other people.
Scott: There's there's like a second awful.
Scott: I can't second.
Rym: Don Fomenko is not harder than Mike Tyson, but he's not that much easier.
Scott: He's pretty rough.
Scott: You know, super macho man's also really tough.
Rym: But even then, like even if I could beat punch out without even trying, I feel like Bionic Commando.
Rym: There's an example.
Rym: The original Bionic Commando.
Rym: I can beat that game in like twenty five minutes without even like thinking about it, like without even expending effort.
Rym: And yet I will periodically put Bionic Commando into my Gameboy and beat it.
Rym: Like on the way home, on the train, I'll just beat Bionic Commando and then take a nap.
Scott: Well, you check this out, right?
Rym: I usually then again, is that like exercising?
Rym: or just is that my equivalent of mindless activity.
Rym: instead of, you know, playing the mindless Sudoku, I beat the mindless Bionic Commando.
Scott: That's just is.
Scott: I always make fun of Sudoku people, right?
Scott: Because I'm like, you know, what's the point of doing Sudoku?
Scott: I can write a computer program that solves any Sudoku.
Scott: trivially would take me like a few hours, you know, and I already know how it would be written.
Scott: It's so it's such a it's a solved problem.
Scott: It's like you already know how this thing is done.
Scott: You're just doing the work, just like I complained that, you know, typing in the code is doing the work, not solving the problem.
Scott: But, you know, Picross, I don't know if most people know how to play Picross, but it's really.
Scott: it's just a different kind of, you know, puzzle.
Scott: It's really not.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's not the same thing as Sudoku, but it's, you know, effectively the same kind of thing.
Scott: It's you figure out which squares to fill in and which ones not to fill in.
Scott: And a picture shows up at the end.
Scott: And, you know, I never was able to actually play Sudoku before just because I never had the patience to figure out exactly how to do it.
Scott: And then I got a puzzle book on the way home from Seattle.
Scott: I said, you know what?
Scott: I'm going to freakin do a Picross, not Sudoku.
Scott: I know how to do a Picross.
Scott: And I'm like, I'm going to do fucking Picross for for for reals.
Scott: And I did it.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, and there's something about even though, you know, it's busy work, I already know I can write a computer program to solve every Picross ever.
Scott: It's it's trivial.
Scott: I could do in a few hours.
Scott: But for some reason, my body likes doing Picross and I got Picross DS and I just keep solving Picrosses even though it's really easy and I can write a computer program to do it.
Scott: It's just busy work.
Scott: So how come I don't like doing the busy work of typing in code, but I love doing the busy work of doing Picross?
Rym: It's I don't know, but the thing is, I feel like this with Bionic Commando, it's not so much a mindless entertainment when I think about it.
Rym: It's like exercise.
Rym: It's like I've got to keep my skill alive.
Rym: Otherwise I'll lose it because I feel like I'm retraining that muscle.
Scott: But I don't feel like I'm retraining my Picross muscle.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: What do I need that for?
Rym: Maybe you just enjoy mindless entertainment.
Scott: But I usually don't, except for Picross.
Rym: See, the thing is, I don't like Picross at all.
Rym: I don't get the enjoyment anyone could get from it.
Scott: I don't know either, but I just I keep wanting to do it.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: I have no desire at all to do, but I don't want to do.
Scott: anything else is mindless except Picross.
Scott: I'm not even like, you know, excited to see the picture that shows up at the end.
Scott: I just go, yeah, OK, it's a squid.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Next picture.
Scott: Huh?
Rym: Maybe you're just crazy.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: See, I think at least I. there's two factors here.
Rym: I mean, when I play Advance Wars again, I've what I'm doing is I'm perfecting the game like I'm basically beating like the last three things that I don't have an S in just to get an S and to prove to myself that I am perfect at this game.
Rym: I'm actually I have this goal of being absolutely perfect at Advance Wars such that no matter when I play Advance Wars, at least the most recent iteration of Advance Wars, I can play it 100 percent perfectly and know that if I win, I won because I'm perfect.
Rym: And if I lose, I lost because it was impossible to win.
Rym: I feel like that's the only reason I'm playing Advance Wars.
Rym: And for some reason, I guess I value that more highly than the novelty of playing a new Castlevania game.
Scott: Well, I think actually, you know, novelty is a big part of it, because when you play something like, you know, NS, even though I've played a million NS games and I know how most of them are going to go, something about playing NS, it feels like constant novelty, just because the way the game is, you know, you don't fully know, you know, there could be a Marine in the vent.
Scott: There might not be, you know, it's the game, even though it's the same maps with the same people in the same strategies, it feels like constant novelty where even something like a new Castlevania game, even though it's full of novelty, I have no idea the shape of the map.
Scott: I don't know what the rooms are.
Scott: I don't know what the story is.
Scott: I don't know what the weapons are.
Scott: I know nothing about it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because I've played other Castlevania games, even the things in the new one that are novel and new don't feel novel because I've you know, it's like I've seen similar enough things enough times to where the novelty isn't novel anymore and I need some other kind of novelty for it to work.
Rym: But then again, I don't know.
Rym: It's hard to say.
Rym: I keep saying it's hard to say because I'm not 100 percent sure what drives my gaming motivation anymore.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: How come, you know, I'm still wanting to play board games.
Scott: You don't want to play board games anymore.
Rym: I want to play board games all the time.
Rym: We just need more people.
Scott: Regricola is a great two player game.
Rym: Yeah, but I have more desire to play Puerto Rico or T&E.
Rym: I could play T&E any time.
Rym: In fact, there has never been a point in my life where someone said, hey, you want to play T&E?
Scott: That is true.
Scott: But if they, you know, you have a choice, you don't have a choice between Agricola and Puerto Rico unless there are three people.
Scott: If there are two people, you don't have the choice.
Rym: But that's the thing.
Rym: I value that choice so highly.
Rym: It's kind of like how I want to play an FPS.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Tribes, too.
Rym: I can't play tribes, too.
Rym: Damn it.
Rym: I'm not going to play, I don't know, Half-Life 1 Deathmatch.
Rym: If that's the only FPS I can play, I'll just hold off until I can play Tribes 2 again or until someone makes a magical new game.
Scott: But then you're just not going to play anything.
Rym: Yeah, but that's my problem.
Rym: But see, there's the thing.
Rym: It's not like we're not playing games.
Rym: You can't say, oh, we're being jaded or anything because I'm playing more PC and DS games than ever right now.
Rym: I'm just, I'm playing Advance Wars and Natural Selection.
Scott: I think that the main thing about it that makes me feel really bad is there was a point at which every video game I owned, even though not as good ones, I had beaten, you know, relatively completely, you know, or at least beaten to enough satisfaction to where I didn't feel like, you know, I spent money on that game and then didn't get my money's worth because I didn't play the
Rym: whole thing.
Rym: Oh, that's the worst.
Rym: Lately, I've been getting about three quarters of the way through a lot of games and then just not caring.
Scott: Yeah, like Bioshock.
Scott: It's like I got pretty far in Bioshock, you know, and I even paid for it instead of playing Rimskopi and whatnot.
Scott: And I got to a certain point that it sort of stopped playing and didn't start playing again.
Scott: And it's sort of like, oh, I paid for that and I didn't.
Scott: It's like buying a fancy dinner and not eating at all.
Scott: It's like, oh, I didn't eat at all.
Rym: I guess once I beat a second Big Daddy, I just had there was no reason to play that game anymore.
Scott: Well, the thing I think the thing that got me is I went really far through the game and, you know, made some sort of some major plot things happen, you know, relative to what was going on.
Scott: And I barely killed any Big Daddies.
Scott: I'd somehow like there were tons of them all over the place.
Scott: I just like avoided them or, you know, use the thing that lets you control them and stuff like that.
Scott: And didn't actually I maybe got like the the Adam for maybe like two girls.
Scott: And that was it.
Scott: And it just wasn't working out for me.
Scott: And I was just like, eh, whatever.
Scott: And I just never had any desire to pick it up again.
Scott: But it it feels bad because video games are expensive and I do pay for them.
Scott: And if I don't play the whole thing, it's like, oh, that that's not it's not good.
Scott: I need to play the whole thing somehow because otherwise I'm wasting all this money all over the place.
Scott: But I think I'm just going to stop buying new video games.
Scott: Left 4 Dead is going to be it after Left 4 Dead and not buying any video games like beat everything I got.
Rym: It didn't help that I got really burned by Team Fortress 2.
Rym: I mean, I was looking forward to that game for a decade.
Rym: A decade.
Rym: It came out.
Rym: I bought it sight unseen.
Rym: It had maybe 10 hours of play.
Scott: You played it a lot more than 10 hours.
Rym: No, actually, look at my steam.
Rym: I didn't play it that long.
Scott: Yeah, you played it a lot.
Scott: A lot more than me.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: After the show, I'll go into my steam and I'll find out exactly how long I played it.
Scott: All right, we'll do that.
Scott: Be interesting.
Rym: I had it.
Rym: I had no more than 10 hours of good play and then a little bit of residual.
Rym: I have to prove to myself that I'm good at this game before.
Rym: I never play it again.
Rym: And then I just haven't touched it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Someone I am the other day is like Left 4 Dead demos out.
Scott: Why are you playing?
Scott: And I'm like, because it was a tiny demo.
Scott: I beat the whole thing two or three times.
Scott: I don't need to play it anymore.
Scott: Why should I play it again?
Scott: I can play NS, which will be as a full game.
Scott: That'll be, you know what, though?
Rym: Honestly, really?
Rym: The reason I play NS still, if I really think about it and I think back to why I've been enjoying it is that it's such a good game.
Rym: And but more importantly, it's not played out that in terms of novel content, there is still novel content because the community is so excellent that I have a new like meme or funny saying or weird conversation every time I play like the people are the innovative content.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I think that's why, you know, we're talking about DLC early in the show.
Scott: And I said I much prefer UGC, which is the user generated content.
Scott: And I think, you know, the games like Line Rider, which isn't really a game, but like Little Big Planet and games like that, where, you know, the players, you know, it's really less of a game and more of just a focused creative tool.
Scott: You know, I think that's where the business is at.
Scott: You know, it's not, you know, DDR, can you dance these arrows?
Scott: It's DDR, make arrows to your favorite song.
Rym: It's, you know, well, also the social aspect of DDR.
Rym: playing alone in my room, I really only do for exercise and practice.
Rym: But the real fun of DDR is playing on a boardwalk at an arcade with your posse, all your friends in public hanging out with the people.
Rym: And as wouldn't, I probably wouldn't really play NS that much if it weren't for the fact that I there's these great people to interact with and the gameplay itself is reliant on that interaction.
Scott: I mean, you know, that's a lot of people say about the wow and such is like, oh, it's all about, you know, the people.
Scott: It doesn't matter that the game is crap.
Scott: The thing is, I really think you just need both because the game is crap.
Scott: Even if there's people there, why am I?
Scott: I could go and do a different a good game and have people.
Scott: And that's I can't really think of any game that has the combination of both being good other than NS.
Scott: It has the people.
Scott: And at the same time, the game is amazing.
Scott: Everything else seems like have people with a bad game, like, wow.
Scott: Or maybe it's a great game, but it's a single player game like Fallout three or something.
Scott: There's no people.
Scott: What other game has the people and the great game?
Rym: The thing is, the people in NS, all the conversation in NS, all the interaction is within the context of the game.
Rym: There's never a meta conversation.
Rym: No one ever like you see people playing.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Or, you know, I just I'm hanging out.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I play NS and people are talking about Obama, but it's usually they're saying Obama while they're biting someone to the rhythm of their biting.
Rym: But see, that's still.
Rym: it's contextualized by the rhythmic play.
Rym: Like I've never heard the just generic conversation for playing.
Rym: Someone's like, yeah, so what do you want to do after the game?
Rym: Let's go get some food, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: It's like people are going to play bejeweled while I wait.
Rym: Most of the conversation in NS is in the game itself.
Rym: People saying funny things in the context of the game, yelling at other people for choosing OC as the tower.
Rym: Oh, see, oh, the game I was playing, we had an early fade like right away.
Rym: This dude killed a bunch of people.
Rym: So we fade right away, like so early in the game that it was ludicrous and there was no way we could lose.
Scott: I got next time.
Scott: So I got the strategy.
Scott: Next time, Alien, I'm just going to get the five reds and go look immediately.
Scott: I'm not going to wait around.
Rym: I do that almost every game.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I gorge right away and build the MC immediately.
Scott: That's what I've been doing.
Rym: I'm going to be a real good lurk.
Scott: I'm lurking.
Scott: All right.
Rym: But basically the guys like, could someone please drop an MC?
Rym: Could someone please drop an MC?
Rym: For the love of God, I'm afraid we can win this.
Rym: Drop an MC.
Rym: Fast forward 10 minutes.
Rym: Jesus Christ.
Rym: Someone drop an MC for the love of motherfucking shit.
Scott: Ten minutes.
Scott: Really?
Scott: You lost if it was 10 minutes.
Rym: No, we were just because as someone else pointed out, it's OK, man.
Rym: I dropped an OC.
Rym: I got you covered.
Scott: That's even funnier if you know.
Scott: the game is, you know, an OC cost the same amount of resource points as an MC.
Scott: So he could have built an MC instead of the OC.
Rym: But the game, I guess the game itself, interaction aside, is also not played out.
Rym: It's it's getting close.
Rym: It's definitely near the end of possible gameplay.
Rym: But there are enough turnabouts and enough different strategies and that the game on a tactical and learning level is not played out.
Rym: And as long as I feel I've never even commanded effectively, as long as a game, I guess, is not done for me tactically.
Rym: As long as I can learn something new in the context of the game, then a game is still worth playing.
Rym: And I can still learn things in NS.
Rym: I can still learn things in Advance Wars.
Rym: I can still learn things in Punch-Out because I could be better at Punch-Out and I can still learn things in Maena Commando because I could beat it faster.
Rym: I'm about eight minutes short of a legitimate speed run.
Rym: Legitimate, as in.
Rym: I could call it a speed run with a straight face.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I think a perfect speed run, I think, is like twenty five minutes.
Rym: So if I beat it in a half hour, that's pretty damn good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, Left 4 Dead seems like it's going to be the answer because for a while I've wanted to play a game.
Scott: Like Serious Sam, which is, you know, FPS is pretty.
Rym: That was the best part of the game.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: FPS is pretty much come in a few flavors.
Scott: You know, there's the.
Scott: but anyway, one of the flavors of FPS is the millions of bad guys everywhere hoes them down flavor, which is the Doom flavor and the Serious Sam flavor.
Scott: And Left 4 Dead seems to be in that flavor.
Scott: It's not like one of those creepy, crawly zombie games like Resident Evil.
Scott: It's a flood of zombies hoes them down without dying.
Scott: And it's just four person co-op.
Scott: And I feel like, you know, I played the demo and I'm definitely going to play through, which means I've already played the whole thing.
Scott: Well, actually, I think the demo is available today for everyone, even if you haven't paid for it.
Rym: But yeah, but I'm honestly I'm just going to wait for the real game.
Rym: The demo is the real game is just like, well, two levels of the rest of the game, because my worry is that once I play Left 4 Dead, I might play it out.
Rym: And then what?
Scott: Well, I think that's what's going to happen.
Scott: It feels to me like there is a multiplayer component, but I don't have a lot of confidence in it.
Scott: You know, even though I haven't played it, I think I'm just going to end up playing the entire, you know, single player thing, you know, with a four person co-op and just hosing down all the zombies in one go.
Scott: And then that'll be the end of that.
Scott: And then I'm going to not buy any video games until I beat all the ones I've got that I haven't beaten yet.
Scott: I'm going to go and beat the Bioshock and the Super Paper Mario and the Wario game.
Rym: But here's the thing.
Rym: Do you really want to beat Bioshock?
Rym: Like, will you enjoy it or you're going to beat it because you paid for it?
Rym: Will it be a chore?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think it'll be a chore because I fired up Bioshock again recently.
Rym: And while I was playing, I was like, wow, I'd rather be playing Fallout.
Rym: And then when I went to play Fallout, wow, I'd rather be playing Tribes 2.
Rym: I can't play Tribes 2.
Scott: As an example, you know, Bioshock really sort of felt the reason I stopped playing.
Scott: Bioshock is sort of the same reason I stopped playing.
Scott: I never beat Golden Sun 2, even though I love Golden Sun.
Scott: Is that I got to a point in Golden Sun 2 where I sort of had to manage all these items, just the chore of managing all those items was more was sort of unfun.
Scott: But the idea of restarting felt really fun.
Scott: And I feel like maybe I'll just end up restarting Bioshock and doing it, you know, better and actually trying to kill the Big Daddies, all of them or something, instead of, you know, just fooling around and dodging all of them and rushing through the plot.
Rym: Well, see, that's the one thing about Fallout that makes it a lot more fun than a game like Bioshock, even because it feels similar playing it.
Rym: But in Fallout, I don't feel this need to beat the game.
Rym: Well, I feel this need to poke it all the bits, not that I need to beat the game.
Scott: Well, it's that if you get to a certain point in the game, you know, you can and you haven't done things up then until properly.
Scott: Suddenly the game is bleh, where if you had done it a different way, the game would not be bleh at this point.
Scott: The game would still be rocking.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel I don't know.
Rym: Other games seem to pace that better such that I can't get myself into that situation.
Scott: Sort of like imagine if you were playing, say, Half-Life 2, right?
Scott: And you got to a certain point in the game and you just, you know, decided that in this part of the game you were going to just hose all the bad guys down with, you know, just use all your ammo.
Scott: Then the next part of the game, you don't have enough ammo.
Scott: Well, now it sort of sucks because you don't have used all your ammo and there isn't enough lying around.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is Half-Life was paced such that that never happened.
Rym: You'd have to really, really screw up to run out of ammo.
Scott: And that's what made it a good game that I could, you know, beat twice.
Scott: I beat Half-Life 2 twice because it was that good.
Rym: Of course, I haven't even beaten it.
Rym: I'm at the end and I just lost all desire to play because I'm playing NS instead.
Scott: Yeah, I think these games where it's possible to be in a situation where you put yourself in a way that you don't want to play anymore.
Scott: I think that's something bad about the game because it doesn't happen in other games like Portal or Half-Life 2 or whatever.
Scott: You just, you always want to keep going no matter how you've played up until now.
Scott: You're at this point and you still want to play ahead.
Scott: Whereas in a game like Bioshock, it's like, I would want to play forward if I had done something different previously and thus I could only move forward actually by starting again from the beginning and getting back to this point by following a different path.
Rym: Well, I feel like a part, it's just all the games I still play, there's some sort of competitive or social element independent of the tactical part.
Rym: Maybe not completely independent, but Bionic Commando, I play it partly because I can show off by beating it in front of other people and they go,
Rym: "Wow.".
Rym: NS, duh.
Rym: It's a multiplayer FPS with goals and it's asymmetric and it's great.
Rym: Bioshock, eh, there's no interactive component.
Rym: I'm never going to have a story or an anecdote to tell someone about the crazy thing that happened in Bioshock.
Rym: At least Fallout has that.
Rym: I mean, me and Daryl Surratt were swapping crazy, funny Fallout stories just because Fallout's a game that lends itself to that.
Scott: I think that's part of the user-generated content is not just you make something in a game, it's that when you're playing of a game, it's a unique experience.
Scott: As opposed to say, if I watch Star Wars and you watch Star Wars, our experiences are pretty much the same unless someone in the room does something silly.
Rym: But if I play Fallout once and you play Fallout once, I totally shot this dude and stole his gun and then blew up the mansion and you went into the mansion and made friends with the guy and raised an army.
Scott: It's like you have these completely unique experiences that are things that belong to you that you can share from the game.
Scott: It's all about those unique personal experiences.
Scott: that is the reason to play a game more.
Scott: If the game keeps churning out more things like that, you'll keep cranking it to get more things to come out.
Scott: Every time I play NS, there's something great that's going on, so I'll keep cranking it and cranking it.
Rym: Every time I play NS, something unexpected happens.
Scott: There's no story for me to tell about what happened when I was playing Wario Shake.
Rym: I could do a whole show on awesome things that happened in the last week of playing NS, like when we ambushed that Fade.
Rym: That was the most epic moment of NS I've ever had.
Scott: Or when there was a one hour long turtle deadlock and we quit.
Rym: We couldn't even finish it.
Rym: If we were in college, we would have stayed to the end.
Rym: You realize if that had gone all night, we would have been there.
Scott: But we just quit.
Scott: Imagine the server had crashed, but it didn't.
Rym: You know, the NS community being what it is, I can imagine everyone rejoining and purposefully like no one kills each other and we recreate the stalemate and then continue the game.
Rym: NS is a game where that would happen.
Rym: It could though, because things like that happen.
Scott: No, because even the peace knife gets no respect anymore.
Rym: No, I was in a game.
Scott: I had it respected a little bit, but eventually they get you.
Scott: They don't let you go on.
Rym: It was in a game on Saturday where we were playing and suddenly one of the Marines types all knives.
Rym: And sure enough, everyone had knives out and the skulks, they didn't respect the peace knife because it wasn't a peace knife.
Rym: But there was basically this jets versus knife fight in the street outside of Marine Start.
Rym: And then after this ended, everyone kind of went through separate ways and then the game continued.
Rym: I've never seen that happen again, but it happened.
Rym: This one unique thing happened.
Rym: It didn't happen to Scott.
Rym: It happened to me.
Rym: I have a weird story to tell.
Rym: That's never going to happen in Wario Shake.
Scott: But not only do you have a weird story to tell, but it was.
Scott: you had that weird story while you were playing a game that also made you think and had quality stuff going on in and of itself.
Scott: Also, you could you were trying to win at something that required you actually exercise parts of your brain and got the awesomeness on the side.
Scott: The dreaded combination of undefeatableness.
Rym: Yeah, I think part of it, too, I keep saying part of it, but another part, yet another, suffice to say, et cetera, and so on, is that when I play NS, there's there's so many people who are good at the game within the community.
Rym: Like the percentage of people who play NS, the percentage of those people who are good at it is very, very, very high.
Scott: Yeah, there's hardly anyone playing the game who's no good.
Scott: It's a complicated game.
Scott: It's hard for noobs to learn.
Rym: Like I could play T and E, you know, me and Scott and two noobs, and that could be fun, but it wouldn't be a test of skill.
Rym: It'd be a test of like teaching the game to someone effectively or making the game fun for these people.
Scott: And whether I win or Rym wins is pretty much who can take advantage of the noobs the most.
Rym: But NS has been around for so long and the people playing it have been playing it for so long that we've kind of, it's kind of like when, say I want to talk about movies with someone.
Rym: If we've both seen 10, not 10,000, a thousand movies and know like the full history of film, we can have a conversation entirely different from the conversation that we could have if a person in the room or the person we were talking to had only seen four movies.
Rym: And didn't even know, couldn't name.
Scott: like a single person in the room is an AI.
Scott: that's completely predictable and you know what it's going to do every time.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's going to say Casablanca was a great movie.
Rym: It amounted to a hill of beans.
Rym: Yeah, but, and as the conversation, and I mean this in the kind of high level sense, not in the I'm holding down V and talking sense.
Rym: The conversation I have in the context of the game between myself and the other players is very high level because we can assume that everyone knows how to play or that the majority of people know how to play.
Rym: That they're good at playing.
Rym: That if I drop sense first, the other players will react to that and the strategy of the game will be different.
Rym: It's kind of like the difference between playing chess with someone else who is your same skill level at chess versus playing chess with someone who's never heard of chess.
Rym: You have to, like you move your rook, but he doesn't understand the ramifications of that.
Rym: So all of your strategy goes out the window and you just beat him.
Scott: It also helps that, you know, when people in other games, you know, the shit cockery doesn't exist in the natural selection world.
Scott: I mean, you know, maybe once in a blue moon, there'll be a shit cock, right?
Scott: But for the most part, some people do exhibit shit cock tendencies, but they're always like in humor.
Scott: Like someone will start playing some music and it's like all mans and everyone is all mans.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Honestly?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Instead of, whereas in Counter-Strike, someone will start playing music and it's like, all right, just dude, shut up.
Rym: Fuck.
Scott: Racial slur, racial slur.
Rym: Yup, yup.
Scott: Whereas in NS, it's like racial slur on mans.
Rym: The cheese.
Rym: The cheese says everything about NS.
Scott: The cheese is the greatest.
Rym: But I don't know.
Rym: I'm going to keep playing NS unless something causes me to play another game.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what I'm going to do.
Rym: And maybe if we get, the only thing that could break this is if we get tribes two going, but again, old game.
Scott: And where are you getting a 40 people who are really good at it?
Scott: I know.
Rym: I mean, if we make a server of tribes two, pretty much what it's going to be is like 10 people, five on a team and a whole bunch of bots.
Rym: And if we're on the same team, we'll just win and it won't be fun.
Scott: And where will we, you know, it's not just the problem of getting enough people and getting enough people who are good, it's getting people who are willing to go to figure out how to get it to work technologically.
Rym: Not just that, but to play the game long enough to get to the point where the conversation we'll have inside the game will be high level.
Rym: I mean, the great part about tribes was when, you know, I'm flying strike backup for the transport full of heavies that is going to suddenly burst out of the clouds and descend upon the enemy base that Scott has just blown up the generators for.
Rym: That level of play, that level of coordination would require like four months of preparation and play of just all the people who have never played this game before learning the basics of the game.
Rym: We can't even have the high level conversation until they all have their own low level conversation.
Rym: And as because there's still a community around it, I can have the high level conversation faster than the time it takes to start a game of Civ 4.
Rym: I can snap my fingers, I'm in a high level game.
Rym: Oh my god, I want to play Anus right now and I think I should.
Scott: Well, we probably will, but I need to eat something or I'm going to die.
Rym: Alright, I think we're done here.
Scott: I still eat before I play a video game.
Scott: Stay tuned!
Rym: We're probably going to do a show tomorrow and Thursday to make up for the lack of shows last week, but don't hold us to that, stay tuned and we're done.
Scott: We'll see what happens.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution, non-commercial, share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.