Rym: It's Monday March 17th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Scott talks about what computer programming languages are.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know my car I'm not gonna.
Rym: I'll say this openly because if any police officers listen to this show and Happen to be police officers in a jurisdiction that covers me You're probably cool enough to not come after me or even care because we did something illegal.
Rym: I've done something illegal Continuously sin for about seven months now.
Scott: What do you been doing?
Rym: I've been driving an uninspected car.
Rym: Oh good job Yeah, but I did look it up.
Rym: The fine is like 20 bucks if they catch you and you have to go get the inspection which I renewed my car on time.
Scott: Thank you very much.
Rym: Well, the reason I didn't was that the last time I renewed my car.
Rym: I've told this story before but I went to the mechanic some shady mechanic and Yonkers cuz near my work back then and I was Hey, I need an inspection and he says you want me to actually inspect it or you just want the sticker.
Rym: and I said Yeah, and he inspect.
Rym: I told him to really inspect it and it passed.
Rym: but I know my front shocks are shot Mm-hmm, they're completely shot.
Rym: All right, but then again, I don't know exactly what it takes to pass a New York State inspection.
Rym: Nope, so I took my.
Scott: you could look it out.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know much about cars either.
Rym: I remember but way back when my front right control arm bushing was broken and I knew what a bushing was And I think I knew what a control arm was but I wasn't quite sure what the front right control arm bushing was and I tried to look under my car and I didn't even I Couldn't even tell what was broken and the guy was like, yeah, I have to fix this.
Rym: But then I learned what it was like, oh, okay, and it made sense.
Rym: I'm glad I got it fixed but my car is a lot of minor problems and I took it and I'm like it's kind of old.
Rym: I decided alright, my deal is unless it's a new car I'm gonna go find some shady mechanic because a shady mechanic who is certified and Gets business.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, if you inspect cars in New York You have to put this metal sign on your mechanic shop in plain view that says we are certified to inspect cars.
Scott: And this is big.
Scott: they got a big yellow sign and the big green sign was.
Scott: they say different things But if you see those signs on a building you can get your car inspected there.
Rym: Yep, now beyond all that pretty much what I've learned throughout my life is that you don't want to go to a scuzzy looking mechanic But you want to go to a kind of rough-and-tumble looking mechanic.
Rym: because those are the people who if they're still in business It means they know enough about cars to keep getting business And two people like that tend to be a lot more resource or they
Scott: have to be a great Location where the cars break down all the time like
Rym: the shitty one in Yonkers.
Rym: Yeah, but I needed to get this inspection.
Rym: So I looked in beacon and there's a bunch of you know mid-range not not scuzzy look and just you know Kind of like rough-and-tumble looking mechanics and I just picked one randomly the one that was in the most convenient location.
Rym: Mmm, and let me tell you that lady in there is one of those like badass mechanics and those kinds of mechanics.
Rym: Just a little hint for all you out there.
Rym: We'll always find a. they will tell you what it will cost to do fix something the quote unquote right way.
Rym: But they'll also tell you how to fix it the clever cheap way Which usually involves getting parts from salvage for an old car.
Scott: That's not a bad way to go.
Rym: old car for any car older than like four or five years.
Rym: That isn't a special car.
Rym: That's the way to go because a salvage switch is no different than a new switch.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Anyway, she Come in and remember I think because it was kind of a low-income area for a long time.
Rym: I was like, all right You know, I go in I go back and I'm like, so what's the damage?
Rym: What'd you find?
Rym: And she's like, well I had to fail your inspection and I got some bad news and I'm thinking shit The shocks are shot that would cost so much to replace.
Rym: I'm just got to throw the car away and buy a new one like this week.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: And she's like Everything's fine.
Rym: Except all these little things.
Rym: I fixed all those for free cuz whatever I'm like, okay and then that's also the cool thing.
Rym: mechanics like that will totally fix minor stuff for free cuz it's.
Rym: it's like I Replaced the light bulb on the back of your car.
Scott: Yeah pay me for the light bulb.
Rym: light bulb cost a nickel I'm not even gonna charge you.
Scott: sometimes are $2.
Rym: It depends on what kind of car?
Rym: what kind of light bulb?
Rym: You want that fancy light bulb or not?
Rym: Well Yeah, but she doesn't.
Rym: apparently I was missing a lug nut.
Rym: All right, and she showed me like yeah What the fuck did my lug nut go?
Rym: All right, I'm gonna take it and then she's like, but yeah the bad news.
Rym: It's gonna have to cost about a hundred and sixty dollars to replace the headlight switch because I can't find a Sunfire even close to yours in any salvage yard in this County.
Rym: Yeah to which I thought wow, my car must be pretty reliable and to 160 bucks, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, uh, all right, that's damage.
Rym: I don't think that's damaged pretty much as long as a car continues to run.
Rym: if you own it any repair There's less than a thousand dollars that's gonna last.
Rym: at least a year is worth it compared to buying a new car.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you don't care about having a newer car you guys you're willing to keep driving the old jalopy go nuts Plus.
Rym: it works as old a job.
Rym: It goes pretty damn well, and there's nothing wrong with it Except that one thing.
Scott: the thing is when you really think about it, you're paying a hundred and sixty dollars Instead of paying a $20 ticket, you're better off.
Scott: Just knowing the $20 ticket.
Rym: See the problem with that is that all right $20 ticket.
Rym: Also if I'm in an accident with an expired inspection It'll be real hard to claim no fault.
Rym: Even if I'm not a fault because I have a car that's not legal.
Rym: Yeah, and Whenever my Registration is due.
Rym: I can't renew it without a valid inspection.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Also, and you only need the expansion inspection once a year or every two years Do you need the registration every two years?
Rym: Yeah action every one year, man I remember in Michigan the registration lasts like five years.
Rym: the license lasts like 20 years.
Rym: My Michigan license still says it's valid.
Scott: great.
Rym: Anyway, I got that out of the way because that's pretty much the good thing that we have to talk about this morning because you see Getting up this morning It was a normal day going to work and I get on my train and I noticed that there's a freaking lot of people on the train and they're all wearing green and some of them are drunk.
Rym: and I'm note that I take a 532 Express train into the city a.m.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Yeah, did it cause any problems or was it just loud and annoying?
Rym: It was very very crowded To the point that it took a long time to get people on the train and my train got into the city like 20 minutes late.
Scott: See I took the 744 train.
Scott: I wanted to take the 728 but I slept And the 744 was ten times worse than that.
Scott: Basically, I saw at the train station.
Scott: I can't tell if they were college or high school.
Scott: if they were college They were the most immature college kids ever.
Rym: Oh I ran into a bunch of high school kids carrying around like a Tool leader that looked like it was full of coke and like I don't know some kind of liquor and they're all passionate around anyway Obviously 14.
Scott: they were in the second to last car.
Scott: So I got into the last car, you know Cuz I wasn't gonna run around to the front of the train or anything, you know.
Scott: and They basically everyone else is like they would look into that car and say I'm not going to that car.
Scott: as a result You had this entire train car full of rowdy punk kids.
Scott: I don't know if there was alcohol or whatever.
Rym: So there was.
Rym: I can say some of them.
Scott: I think there was like smoking going on in the vestibule.
Scott: It was it was out of control and basically the conductor is fed up with that shit and they were getting rowdy and whatnot.
Scott: So he stopped at Croton Harmon and was like I'm calling the police.
Scott: This train isn't going anywhere.
Rym: That would totally be worth it.
Rym: just to see the comeuppance.
Scott: yeah, and basically all that happened is some people went over and got on the.
Rym: the nice train that you know was like if my Train ever stopped in Croton Harmon and I was going into well the train was gonna stop there anyway.
Rym: Yeah, but if it like stopped there and there's any problem I would totally get on those other trains.
Rym: Well, the trains are great.
Scott: The other trains are real nice, but they it was gonna make a bunch of stops before Grand Central.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: there are some of those that are expressed from Croton to Grand Central.
Scott: Yeah, but not at the same, you know, basically this train is an express from Croton to Grand Central.
Scott: So why would they have another Croton Grand Central Express leave at the same time?
Rym: It's almost worth it though I mean if Amtrak is first-class and Metro North normal is coach.
Rym: Those are like second-class right there.
Scott: Yeah, they're okay.
Scott: But yeah, and I was already on the later train so I didn't wanna you know But I stayed on there cuz I was in my nice safe car in the back.
Scott: But yeah, the those rowdy kids got some comeuppance.
Scott: But as soon as that train pulled into Grand Central those rowdy kids got rowdy again.
Scott: Well, and then on the way home They were they there was still some rowdy ness and there was like a drunken fireman on the train and you can still lose stuff going on.
Scott: and I just got home.
Rym: and Yeah, there were a bunch of troubles on my train on the way home But they didn't involve me and I just sat there with my laptop.
Scott: So yeah, I was just like God these people God.
Rym: But the worst thing was I around lunchtime like man, I'm hungry.
Rym: And again, I forgot about this holiday.
Rym: So I just walk out of my building and I want Indian food and the only Indian place really near my work is in Grand Central.
Scott: good job.
Rym: So I go in there.
Rym: It's a pretty good place and I go down and pretty much there is basically a large sea of people in green loud Drunk spilling things.
Rym: I saw someone vomiting just in the middle of Grand Central.
Rym: It's like all over the floor I ran into.
Rym: I watched the police.
Scott: I like to go to work today?
Rym: Apparently not.
Scott: Hey everyone everyone in my work went to work today.
Scott: It's everyone.
Scott: I had one co-worker went to play golf, but everyone else is at work.
Rym: Well, everyone in my work went to work today, but that's because the stock market is very interesting.
Scott: Currently playing golf is Scottish not Irish.
Scott: So it's the wrong holiday day.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes, it is Scotland Island.
Scott: Yes more Island.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, st.
Rym: Patrick's Day.
Rym: I mean, I think kid the only like st Pat when I was a kid st Patrick's Day was I wear a green shirt to school or everybody fucking punches me because everyone's jerks.
Scott: I didn't do anything on st.
Scott: Patrick's Day ever.
Rym: I wore a green shirt.
Rym: That was it.
Rym: I didn't do anything until high school when I didn't do anything.
Scott: But yeah, I really think the problem is we.
Scott: we take a commuter train, you know, it's a people.
Scott: They want a nice quiet trip to work and home.
Scott: They want it to be fast.
Scott: They want to sleep They want to whatever.
Scott: but the train is allowed to be used by all, you know Including people on day trips and it's always day trip tourists people in groups who use the trainer like the second most common people To use the train if they use the train in a weekend, whatever.
Scott: It's the weekend train, right?
Rym: Yeah, we're pretty rowdy on weekend.
Scott: But if they use the train on the weekday, right?
Scott: It's like whoa You're the commuters are here.
Scott: You need to.
Scott: I really think they should that if there's like some sort of weekday group They should sort of like designate them to.
Scott: you know far away from the commuters or somehow that's crazy.
Scott: Like this is the quiet car.
Scott: absolutely no talking on this car whatsoever something like that.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I've noticed the conductor's usually just deal with it.
Rym: I mean like on the on the trains going home.
Rym: Usually they everyone's kind of talking and it's kind of loud.
Rym: it like that's super loud, but it's not like silent.
Rym: But in the morning the conductor doesn't even announce the stops because he knows no one cares.
Rym: Yeah, and a lot of times some of the cars have the lights off and they're not supposed to be off But obviously they were just turned off because people kind of want that.
Rym: Yeah, and if someone's like even talking quietly the connector be like sir, you need to be quiet Yeah, and they kind of just deal with it, but I mean you can't really segregate.
Rym: There's like the airlines all the people who cause problems on the airlines and people who don't fly off it.
Scott: Yeah, they should have family flights and business flight.
Scott: They're trying to do that in some entirely separate flights instead of separate sections.
Rym: Yes, because I'm sure that is economically viable Why not?
Rym: and also a good idea.
Scott: the family fights just be less often the family fights will be flights.
Rym: Yes I disagree with you.
Scott: I think it's a good idea.
Rym: I don't think it's a good idea.
Rym: freedom of transportation.
Rym: Besides I'm willing to put up with a tiny bit of annoyance.
Rym: plus, you know what I have earplugs There is it's.
Rym: you know how much it takes to actually bother me.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the earplugs protect me from plenty of noise.
Scott: It's that you know.
Scott: people Running up and down the train bumping in you possibly barging on you.
Scott: That's that's the truth.
Rym: Did any that happen?
Scott: Someone else?
Rym: it happened because if it happens the conductor deals with it.
Rym: Yeah It's hard to conductors versus like a whole car full of rowdy kids Yeah, but all they have to do is say well we've stopped and here come the police.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't do much.
Rym: I've been on a few trains.
Rym: The conductor will just like suddenly come out and say Effectively to anyone who has luggage on the seats removed here.
Rym: I'm kicking you off the train as soon as I see you.
Scott: Yeah, the other problem is it's like alright, you've got a whole car.
Scott: that's seemingly rowdy, right?
Scott: How do you know who is you know?
Scott: What if someone was sitting quietly and everyone else is being rowdy?
Rym: I've seen conductors do this.
Rym: They look in from the vestibule and they make note And then they identify those people when the police come.
Rym: I've seen that exact thing happen many times.
Scott: It's conductor procedure.
Rym: actually though the funniest thing was that most of the people on my train home didn't have tickets.
Rym: Wow didn't understand how it worked and Pretty much the conductor went person by person.
Rym: the conductor be like, uh, sorry Do you have a ticket is like no how much is it?
Rym: and she'd be like however much which is always some ludicrous amount.
Scott: It's like 30 bugs.
Rym: they check on this crazy surcharge if you don't have a ticket and you pay and especially on a peak train.
Scott: Yeah, you're supposed to buy tickets to the machines.
Scott: You can buy the ticket on the train But it costs a whole shit ton extra and most of the people didn't have money.
Rym: A lot of them didn't have IDs.
Rym: they wanted to pay with credit cards.
Rym: They balked at the price.
Rym: few people were like, I can't pay what are you gonna do?
Rym: Could I just like kick you off the train?
Rym: Yeah, as soon as we get to Croton Harmon Yep, and if I can identify you really make a note so we see you.
Rym: if you ever come again Yep, and the guy's like, uh, what do I do?
Rym: and she's like get off the train quietly in Croton Harmon.
Rym: Hope I don't notice you.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The thing is the conductors will always cut you a break if you're not a jerk Yep.
Rym: So all people who ever come to New York City if you screw up on the train Just be polite and they will totally cut you a break.
Rym: That is my advice to you.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: I did you read that milestones thing?
Scott: They give up.
Rym: I read that every time because it's always.
Scott: did you read what it said?
Rym: I always read it because it always is very kind of snarky in its seriously.
Rym: people be quiet in the morning.
Scott: Well, did you did you see what it said in the most recent one?
Rym: I'm not sure to what you're referring about the.
Scott: they're actually gonna give the conductors like handheld gizmos instead of the paper They've been using for a hundred years.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I think that's cool.
Rym: Yeah I was gonna wait till it happened and then I was gonna talk about it.
Scott: now you can pay.
Scott: you're probably gonna be able To pay with a credit card on the train instead of you know Punch a holes in a piece of paper and give you a piece and then file it in the office.
Rym: I'm really looking forward to that to be honest because that's like such a good idea.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: It's.
Scott: I'm surprised It wasn't implemented.
Scott: I don't know to five years ago when that technology was invented.
Rym: I don't even care about the paying part.
Rym: What I like is that now they'll get perfect accurate statistics of who is going where not just going to Grand Central But a lot of times they don't really know who is taking what trains when who's getting off at all those kind of in-between Stops when because a lot of a lot of like.
Rym: if you want to go from some stations to other stations Like when I was commuting to the Bronx from here, it's almost impossible.
Rym: But yet a lot of people do it and now they'll know exactly how many people do it And I think the train schedules are gonna become ten times better.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: All right, let's break through all these bunch of newses.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So, uh, what do you got first?
Rym: You see there's so much to talk about.
Rym: We both have a real news and a quickie news.
Scott: Well, here's my is my quick news.
Scott: Actually, I could talk about this a lot but basic I'm not going to.
Scott: there's a company called Japan steelworks limited And that has to be an awesome fucking place, right?
Rym: It's like heavy industry right there.
Scott: That is the heaviest of industries.
Scott: basically It's a giant steel mill in Japan where they make like the world's best steel or close to it.
Scott: And at the top of the mountain, there's a guy in an old-fashioned hut and he makes Swords right like the old-school way.
Scott: He makes awesome swords with their best steels for sword making but down in the steel mill is where the news is at Because I just wanted to point that out.
Scott: so, you know that it's the same steel mill that's making swords is making this.
Rym: Well, no that guy in the top actually makes those things by hand.
Scott: Yeah, but he doesn't make the steel.
Scott: you take the deal.
Rym: I was saying the thing that you're about to talk about.
Scott: Oh, no In fact, no No He does not make in the steel mill down at the bottom of the hill where they do not make swords.
Scott: So they make big things very big things.
Scott: They have a factory.
Scott: that is the only factory on the entire earth that is capable of Producing the core of a nuclear reactor in one solid piece.
Scott: every place else that makes nuclear reactor cores Makes two pieces that are half and half and then welds them together.
Scott: Now you might say oh well, you know What's why is that a big deal?
Scott: because it's a bajillion times safer than having the two separate pieces welded together.
Scott: So basically everyone who was building a nuclear reactor, which is hundreds and hundreds right is buying these things.
Scott: and the thing is They have to put down.
Scott: Well at first they can only make for a year.
Rym: So if a hundred people want them you're gonna be waiting a while, you know, that makes me realize, you know The enormity of the task.
Rym: I'm afraid from this point forward.
Rym: We can only make four gig nights a year.
Rym: We just can't really hand it.
Rym: Yeah, and two well, it would be if we did not edit.
Scott: like some people people who want these things Because there's only four a year.
Scott: They have to make a down payment of a hundred million dollars and this is considered like a sure bet like a like a great Investment like oh, of course.
Scott: Why wouldn't you spend 100 million dollars?
Scott: It's obvious for one big piece of metal.
Scott: So yeah, I think just think that's pretty amazing.
Scott: and I think if you read this article it talks about how they make the 600 ton ingot of steel and such.
Rym: and think about how normal that I said enormity twice for a reason 600 ton ingot 100 million dollar deposit.
Rym: Yeah, I put a five dollar deposit on my car repair.
Scott: I mean you go to a chip factory whatever.
Scott: still look at that Business.
Rym: yeah, I mean even tiny steel mills are awesome.
Rym: Imagine.
Rym: I'd love to see videos of just all the stuff.
Scott: I don't think they would let you in because then that would reveal the secret to the rest of the world and suddenly everyone be Making one piece nuclear reactor cores.
Rym: Yes, I'm sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Alright, so my quick I make one in my backyard my quickie news real briefly.
Rym: I just want to point this out.
Rym: According to some article this linked on slash shot.
Rym: It appears that six and only six botnets are responsible for approximately 85% of the world's spam.
Rym: I might have a lot to say about that but I think we should wait and do a show on botnets and spam or something like that because It would take a lot much more than the news.
Rym: But I have to point that out because there are debates along the lines of why don't we make secret evil?
Rym: Viruses that screw anyone who is infected by these botnets thus saving the internet.
Rym: Hmm, and there's a lot of any reasons why no one does that.
Rym: but I I just want to point this article out because If you're computer running windows and you think that your windows is fine and safe and there's nothing wrong with it You might want to double-check with some sort of third-party Firewall checking your own traffic.
Scott: You might want to get someone who knows something to check because obviously you don't because a large.
Scott: if you know how to check Then I can guarantee you you're safe because you know, but you might think you know and not know.
Rym: So, how do you know?
Rym: if you know or you just think you know you get someone who really knows.
Rym: But what if they just think they know then you're fucked.
Rym: or you could just ask us I don't know.
Scott: only you can only trust us cuz we know.
Scott: yes only I can only trust someone who is who is very Intelligent.
Rym: but what if we only think we know we know?
Rym: The thing is there's almost no way to tell.
Scott: there's an easy way to tell.
Rym: yes External outbound firewalls.
Scott: the wireshark can easily tell wireshark and eyeballs.
Rym: Well wireshark can tell.
Rym: but what if your TCP IP stack is compromised?
Rym: You can use the another computer with wireshark with a yes Like I said external monitoring external outbound monitoring is the only way to know.
Rym: Yes So now you know.
Rym: and if you thought something else you didn't know.
Rym: and now you know that you didn't know.
Rym: and now you know That you know, yeah.
Rym: Anyway, you know, you know, so I got a real news here.
Rym: So, you know, there's been this problem lately with the FCC kind of not saying what their regulations are but then suddenly someone says fuck on the airwaves and $100,000 fine your network's gonna be shut down.
Rym: all this business.
Rym: the FCC has wide and broad powers and Some of those wide and broad powers are important and I agree with them.
Rym: and some of those powers.
Rym: I'm of the mind that the FCC should have absolutely no regulation whatsoever over the content of what is on the airwaves.
Rym: I think that's that's they show.
Rym: but they should have full power to regulate how the airwaves are used exactly as in protocols as in companies having the right to use or not use them with such power and whatever as if people are preventing Shared technology spaces such as radio frequencies from working.
Scott: Then the FCC can step in.
Scott: if someone is using them for things which are legal Then they got it doesn't matter as long as they're not fucking it up.
Rym: There have been a whole bunch of Controversies and a whole bunch of problems with this in the u.s.
Rym: Lately.
Rym: I mean you might remember what happened at a Super Bowl a while ago, and there have been other incidents, but All the networks that have balls have basically stood up and challenged all these things And there have been a bunch of lawsuits going around because they
Scott: want porn on primetime TV And I'm all for it.
Rym: Or maybe it's more that they don't like the fact that an entity over which they have no say and no control Can.
Scott: well they have saying control.
Scott: They just send lobbyists with lots of money to say in control.
Rym: remember the FCC is largely independent of other governmental structures.
Scott: Yeah, but you can still send people with money over there and get what you want.
Rym: not so much you have not on paper I remember.
Rym: the FCC generally follows the guidelines put forth by a Ridiculous minority of the American population.
Rym: yeah pretty much and this minority actually has very little Lobbying power when compared to the lobbying power of the entertainment industry.
Rym: you get the entertainment industry Industry people like.
Scott: it's very hard to tell because you read the news right and you see news about different things.
Scott: you see news about sports.
Scott: you see news about Entertainment industry.
Scott: you see news about you know banks.
Scott: you see news about Technology industry.
Scott: right it But it's hard to tell because you sort of get the idea of how big things are based on the quantity of news.
Scott: like you See lots and lots of entertainment news and that sort of makes entertainment feel big, but if you really look at the numbers like Technology industry like Microsoft could buy probably the entire entertainment industry like all of it like every movie studio Microsoft could buy them all.
Scott: Probably it's that that's the size.
Rym: We're talking about him yep, but regardless This really came into stark relief here when there was a this problem where the FCC changes policy on so-called Bleeding expletives.
Rym: The biggest example was when someone at the Golden Globes three years ago caught five years ago Uttered didn't even say outright, but just uttered the phrase, and I'm gonna quote here fucking brilliant Mm-hmm.
Rym: and the FCC said well the f-word when used in any context is quotes Inherently sexual and connotation unquote.
Scott: all right even if it is what's wrong with that?
Rym: even beyond that Fuck you has no sexual connotations.
Rym: with me saying it now it means that I rather dislike you that I'm blowing you off that I disagree even if it does have Sexual connotations, what's wrong with sexual connotation?
Rym: ah ah well apparently I don't even know.
Rym: but the problem is the FCC has they changed their policy saying that they can enforce and Fine as a result of any network allowing expletives that are fleeting To be put forth to be on the airwaves?
Rym: and they protested this and a court said well You didn't really say why you changed your policy, and you didn't make your policy clear.
Rym: So your policy can't be enforced until you come forward with something and now they're appealing it And it's going all the way to Supreme Court.
Scott: Oh, it's the case of the century.
Rym: so the Supreme Court is Going to.
Scott: did they say yes, or did they just say no?
Rym: Well quote the Supreme Court on Monday stepped into a legal fight over the use of curse words on the airway.
Scott: Oh, what did the previous court say?
Rym: all the previous court was the court that said.
Rym: I already said, that's okay.
Scott: So the previous court was on our side.
Rym: yes, okay, and they appealed it all the way to SCOTUS, okay?
Scott: But if SCOTUS says we don't want to look at that then we win.
Scott: well I believe the news Scott as I pointed out was that they said they're going to look at well That's usually bad because that means there's a chance of losing whereas if they said no there'd be no chance of losing.
Rym: However, I'd rather them look at it.
Scott: well if they look at it, and then we still win.
Rym: That's like double-plus yes, and if they look at it and they rule otherwise I've learned that I now disagree with the Supreme Court on such a fundamental level because to paraphrase Seinfeld Freedom of speech and religion is the first one.
Scott: It is indeed so.
Rym: the case will actually be argued in the fall and This in my eyes is other than maybe the whole Torture thing is probably the most important Supreme Court case to be put forth in Recent memory.
Scott: this is going to be the most important case until we have the wiretapping case.
Rym: yes I want to point out that The wiretapping case you know a lot of people say oh the government can't do anything about that because blah blah blah blah blah Blah blah blah, and this is not big news yet.
Rym: But I point out that last week the house had a secret session for the first time in like two decades Which means that they're gonna debate something secret and obviously it was that and they voted to not give immunity.
Scott: It really seems like you know lately I mean like.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: maybe I just paid attention to the Supreme Court less earlier in my life But it seems like the Supreme Court like it's like every case is like the new case of the century.
Scott: It was like the Grokster case.
Scott: This is the public domain case.
Rym: there were a bunch of cases You didn't care about.
Scott: I know there were a bunch I didn't care about but it does seem like there's just it's.
Scott: Case after case.
Scott: every case is bigger and badder than the previous one.
Scott: I think like in five years is gonna be a case like so crazy It'll be like should we end the world or not?
Rym: Well, I think the reason if a case gets to the Supreme Court It has to be the case of the century because that means that no not always.
Scott: a lot of them are sometimes Just small.
Rym: things are relatively small means they're so contentious that it has become a federal possibly Constitutional issue.
Rym: we need the people who have the most authority possible to come down and deign to say what actually is going to be and No one can do anything about it except Andrew Jackson.
Rym: Yeah, and he's dead.
Scott: He's dead All right, so check this out.
Scott: I'm not exactly sure like I heard about this news on a podcast, right?
Rym: How great.
Rym: some guy on the internet love to it.
Rym: and well now you're hearing about this on a podcast that heard about it.
Scott: Well, they didn't hear about it from a podcast.
Scott: I heard about it from to it.
Rym: no, you're hearing about it from us And that podcast heard about it from.
Scott: So because I decided I wanted to talk about it I had to look for the article and I don't know.
Scott: maybe I just couldn't find the article but I found.
Scott: basically it seems like Twit made up a news.
Scott: That was the combination of two other two articles that Man Regardless.
Scott: basically twit said.
Scott: this is what twit said to.
Scott: it said that some Chinese company Made like routers and switches that were fake and put the word Cisco on them Sold them to the US but they had back doors in them.
Rym: now one buying a bootleg Cisco router with all the functionality unlocked.
Scott: Brilliant, absolutely brilliant.
Rym: selling an awesome Cisco router.
Rym: That's obviously bootleg with everything unlocked Along with a back door.
Rym: brilliant.
Rym: Yes brilliant again, like my head is off to everyone involved.
Scott: Well, except for the morons.
Scott: You don't realize they bought a router with the back door.
Scott: Like buying a router without a back door.
Scott: brilliant.
Scott: buying a router with the back door.
Scott: if you can find the back door and seal It up.
Scott: double brilliant God.
Rym: We just need someone to make an open-source router.
Rym: That isn't awful.
Scott: Yeah anyway anyway In looking for this news.
Scott: I found actually two other stories.
Scott: The first story is That there were bootleg routers made from China and sent to the US and Canada and that they confiscated bootleg routers Seventy million dollars worth of Cisco systems networking equipment.
Scott: That was bootleg.
Rym: I was right problem.
Rym: If I was using it for my own use I wouldn't be that opposed to a bootleg router if it worked.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Then I read another story that's basically says that PC Pro news in the you in the UK.
Scott: Right, I Said that it would be possible for Asian manufactured switchers and routers to have back doors.
Scott: I should watch about that.
Rym: that.
Rym: that see it's funny.
Rym: that sounds like a subtle change like it happened to.
Rym: it could happen but no that turned a Real article into nothing more than FUD.
Scott: and basically what I'm linking to here is an editorial by a guy on CNET Who says that that FUD is xenophobic and bla bla bla bla bla bla fuck you.
Scott: granted I agree with that guy.
Rym: if I were in China making bootleg Cisco routers in order to sell and make a gigantic profit You can bet you can Absolutely bet that there would be some sort of VPN back door credit card numbered password getting thing in there.
Scott: But that would be true for me.
Scott: making bootleg routers in any country Yeah, the fact that they were specifically being all racist against you know, the Asians who are known for their bootlegs There is no doubt.
Rym: but well, mostly China Korea.
Scott: Yeah, you know what I'm on the Southeast Asia mostly China Yeah, and the Philippines, but you get you get the drift here.
Scott: so The I haven't found yet a news article that shows that these two things have actually been combined into a true story.
Scott: But there are two separate things.
Scott: They're interesting and they're worth thinking about.
Rym: You know what a much better way to go about this if you are a Chinese bootlegger instead of going the whole I'm gonna make fake Cisco stuff sell it and put it back door in is I'm going to take the Cisco stuff sell it, but I'm not gonna call it Cisco.
Rym: I'm gonna call it sasco.
Rym: I'm gonna call it something sorry.
Scott: Oh, yeah, we'll go down to.
Scott: We'll go down to canal Street and right next to the verse H will be the sascoes.
Rym: It's a. it's a verse edge Disney cross over.
Scott: the guy will set a cross on the side.
Scott: I'll set up a table on the sidewalk.
Scott: He's like 24 foot switches 24 foot $10 with load balancing and a picks firewall.
Rym: I'll throw in a picks firewall picks firewall free without every purchase.
Rym: but what I would do is I'd make my own brand and I just it would happen to just be bootleg Cisco software and bootleg Cisco designs.
Rym: But I'd stand by my brand as in my brand is totally not full of bag doors.
Rym: Yeah, so that people are going to go buy bootleg Costco's are Totally gonna buy my bootleg Costco's.
Rym: and also now Cisco can't get me for trademark infringement.
Rym: They can only get me if they prove that I'm using their software.
Scott: We should be hard.
Scott: Yes, I don't think they even know what software they're using.
Rym: All I'd have to do is change some checksums here and there and oh man, oh man.
Scott: Yep Exactly.
Rym: So if I were a Chinese large-scale pirate, that is what I would do.
Rym: Yep Wow, we just killed that hole if I was a pirate episode.
Rym: Alright Rym if you tried if you ever tried one of those digital to-do lists in the past I had a PDA once and I put to-do lists on him On it and then I never looked at that to-do list again ever.
Scott: Yeah, you know I get it's weird.
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: there's all these productivity tools and they seem sort of obvious, right?
Scott: But you end up not really using them.
Scott: like Google Calendar is the only one I've kind of used But I don't really like.
Scott: I don't live by it like.
Scott: I use it a little bit.
Rym: I just Google Calendar and things like that to remind me like Does this convention overlap with this other convention before I try to do events at both of them?
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: It's like they have these tools designed where you can like live by them like a like a day planner like the day runner products or something, you know, and I feel like That's like a thing you need to have or do but I never.
Scott: Every time I try one, I don't I might.
Scott: you know, I had calendars that I just never used.
Scott: the Google Calendar I do use but I only use it a bit Like I. I feel like I should be using it hardcore like putting everything in there and but I feel like that would take more time.
Scott: it would just be a waste of time because I don't forget to do anything and Like I just don't do it.
Scott: and the same thing is a to-do lists like that.
Scott: You know, I've had to-do lists in the past and I sort of use them and not use them.
Rym: I just remembered when I first got my new moleskine.
Rym: I put a to-do list in there and I realized I haven't looked at my moleskine in a long time.
Rym: Yep, let's see what I got in here Email katsu-kan about panels.
Rym: did it email uncle yo about katsu-kan?
Rym: did it make an archival feed?
Rym: I didn't do that.
Scott: didn't do that?
Rym: Make C's.
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: but anyway I also did it to-do list of my moleskine and I kind of use it a little bit.
Scott: You know sort of like the same way as the Google Calendar like I don't live by it But I sort of use it some you know, and I look through it and I'm like, oh right I forgot about that thing, you know.
Scott: And sometimes like I'll come up with an idea and if I remember to write it down real quick then even if I forget that Idea later, it'll be in there and I kind of like that.
Rym: Yeah what I have used like things like that for is like whenever I'm in a bookstore if I see a book that I want I Write the name down in my notebook or something.
Rym: I see things I like useless doll for that, you know, like when I'm in the bookstore And I see a book Yep, and then I come home and I put it in Amazon and I buy it because it's always cheaper that way.
Scott: But anyway, if you're that kind of person, right I found here a is it?
Scott: you know There's a billion to-do lists on the on the web, you know, like oh we have a to-do list.
Scott: We have one, you know, there's one I found called.
Scott: Remember the milk remember the milk calm It's got this happy cow and he's kind of cute there.
Scott: and this to-do list Actually looks like it might have the potential to be a real to-do list.
Scott: It integrates if you have you know, Windows Mobile.
Scott: It works with that go.
Scott: Google Calendar works with that Got.
Scott: an iPhone or an iPod touch works with that got.
Scott: Twitter works with that got.
Scott: Gmail works at that.
Scott: It works with all your stuff.
Scott: It just integrates and it's a happy awesome to-do list.
Scott: This is how web applications need to be made people.
Scott: All right, you know, I was dealing today with like I You know Twitter pounce and jaku and I was trying to sort them all out and none of them was good.
Scott: They all sucked in some way and we're all good in some way and it was horrendously annoying.
Scott: But remember the milk.
Scott: even if it's you know, you don't end up living by it.
Scott: This is a to-do list where it's not a problem in the software.
Scott: if you're not, you know using it to the fullest It is the high quality.
Rym: So I had a much more meaningful thing of the day something I generate some discussion about.
Rym: I'll save that maybe for a Thursday, but instead This video.
Rym: there's a small chance.
Rym: It was staged But I would believe that it isn't because I have seen people do things this dumb and I know video using.
Rym: I've.
Rym: I've witnessed people in actual workplaces doing things like this.
Rym: All right, dudes taking a spool.
Rym: They got to get it up into another part of it.
Scott: I don't think everyone knows you mean by spool.
Rym: All right a spool of cable as in it's like five or six feet in diameter.
Scott: It's real heavy think a spool of thread but with giant heavy cable wrapped around it and it's big like as big as you Like.
Rym: the kind of thing a college kid will steal with when there's wired gone from it and make a table out of.
Scott: it's the kind Of thing you see on like the phone company truck with cable wrapped around it You know big wooden discs with a cylinder in the middle.
Rym: Well, these guys have constructed some sort of ramp to get these things up.
Rym: It looks like they're probably wiring this building for connectivity.
Scott: Why did they use an elevator?
Rym: There's a lot of reasons for that.
Rym: a lot of buildings make the mistake of not having service elevators if they're small buildings not in cities and then it's like normal elevators just can't deal with stuff like that.
Rym: or The elevators were broken or they wouldn't fit in the elevator or that floor was like a mezzanine that isn't supported by elevators.
Scott: It looks like it was sort of an open Lobby.
Scott: They could have used one of those like, you know lifting things.
Rym: Nah, how do you want how do you get that in the lobby?
Rym: You have to construct it in there because obviously there's no big way into that Lobby anymore.
Scott: Yeah, and also there will be soon.
Rym: Yeah, and also a lot of times like the floor.
Rym: There's a lot of reasons why they were poorly designed building.
Rym: There are a lot of legit morons.
Rym: No, there are a lot of legitimate reasons why I would be doing something like this.
Rym: However, there are certain Safety precautions you take to do this sort of thing Safely.
Rym: these people did not take those precautions.
Rym: What results is nothing more than sheer Absolute hilarity bonus points when the car alarm starts going off.
Scott: Yeah, that was like.
Scott: it's like you see some damage done from morons and then you there's like this two-second pause.
Rym: You're like, wow, and then there was more damage.
Scott: That was off-camera.
Rym: Like did it hit a car?
Rym: and sure enough you get to see.
Rym: yes it hit a car.
Scott: It was much off-camera damage.
Rym: I've no one got hurt.
Rym: So I don't feel bad about watching it Just laugh at the morons or the poorly designed building.
Rym: No the morons because the building there might have been a lot of legitimate reasons for what they were doing But when they designed the building they designed a stupid not necessarily there.
Rym: I don't want to get into this.
Rym: Yeah, there are a lot of legitimate reasons for doing what they were doing.
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: Yes I've.
Rym: the only problem here is that they were doing these things in an unsafe manner.
Rym: There's a safe way to do that.
Scott: You could have just kept the spool on the bottom floor and taking cable off of the spool as needed it.
Rym: No, that's really really inefficient.
Rym: All you do is have a winch at the top and you secure the thing.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Yeah, it's all you had to do anyway.
Scott: So I got to talk about programming again, right?
Rym: Yeah go now.
Rym: It's I'm gonna play Layton.
Scott: Oh great.
Scott: So last time I talked about what is programming right and you know, I talked a little about that and Basically programming is you tell the chip what to do, right?
Scott: But the next thing I was gonna talk about was programming languages and I was gonna go over like, you know Some of the big very popular programming languages of today and the past and talk a little about what each one does and how they're Different.
Scott: but I realized something I can't go talking about programming languages yet until I talk about What is a programming language?
Rym: So we're not gonna have the what's better visual basic or see we're not.
Scott: there's no such thing.
Scott: No language is better than any other language unless you have a specific situation in mind.
Rym: I would argue that some languages are overall worse.
Scott: But well some languages can be less useful can all?
Scott: there are some languages that are always less useful than some other languages for every Possible situation but that you know, they're not like a worse language.
Scott: That's that's just not a valid kind of.
Rym: I can submit a worse language.
Rym: I made it right now Anyway, it doesn't even work.
Rym: Anyway, go that's exactly.
Scott: this is what I'm talking about.
Scott: Is that before you understand that kind of argument you have to understand what is a programming language?
Scott: Well a program telling you what a programming language is is very simple.
Scott: a programming language is a language that's used for programming.
Scott: That's that's all.
Scott: there is The heart.
Scott: I already told you what programming was last week.
Scott: So the part you don't know is what a language is.
Scott: now you're thinking Oh, I know what a language is like English Spanish French Chinese.
Rym: It's just the thing that tells the computer what to do.
Scott: No a language.
Scott: and see there's the colloquial use of the word language.
Scott: You know English Spanish Spanish French Japanese Canadian right.
Scott: and then there's the sort of language theory use of the word language Which is a completely different meaning.
Scott: well actually it isn't super completely different but basically according to the Wikipedia because I couldn't come up with the super exact definition on my own even though I know a Language is a system of visual auditorial Visual auditory or tactile symbols of communication and the rules used to manipulate them.
Scott: so you have some sort of Symbology right and there are some rules governing the symbology.
Scott: that is what a language is.
Scott: so a programming language is a set of symbols rules governing the.
Scott: How do you manipulate those symbols?
Scott: and those manipulated symbols are used to program?
Scott: That is what a programming language is.
Rym: well simple.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: No.
Scott: We're not really done because people have no idea What the hell I just said do they?
Rym: some people might but if you do then you don't really you're not gonna learn anything today.
Scott: Most likely yeah, all right, so the thing is when someone says okay You know I kind of understand that.
Scott: well the next thing what you know every language right you say, okay?
Scott: A language is a set of rules governing the use of a set of symbols.
Scott: right well How do we describe those rules?
Scott: How do I how do I tell someone a language?
Scott: Well if I was gonna tell Rym about a language.
Scott: What those rules are called is the grammar.
Scott: you see oh you see where this goes?
Scott: The grammar yes, so the grammar is basically It's the set of rules that Tell you what the language is.
Scott: so Let's say here.
Scott: I'm gonna come up with a brand new language right now.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: My language is called a B. That's that's what the name of my language and the alphabet of my language alphabet being a keyword has two symbols.
Rym: You know it's funny that you chose a B because alphabet literally alpha beta a B.
Scott: I know anyway.
Rym: Yes, you see me I see that you're clever.
Rym: You're yes.
Scott: Yes, my language Maybe my language a B has an alphabet.
Scott: that alphabet has two symbols.
Scott: you see the alphabet is the set of symbols for the language a And B. I hope you know what those are.
Scott: I'm not gonna you know.
Scott: and they look like the letter a and letter B for the English alphabet and The way the rules of my language the grammar of my language is thus the language is comprised of Sentences.
Scott: all right You can have as many sentences as you want.
Scott: all right every sentence must begin with a a can be followed only by either B or the end of the sentence.
Scott: every B must be followed either by a B or an A. I Just made a whole new language.
Scott: you see that I made rules.
Scott: the rules make a language and now we can Take symbols and arrange them and then we can look at those symbols and we can say are those symbols grammatically correct?
Scott: Are they in this language or are they not in this language?
Rym: all right?
Rym: So you've got your language, and we know how to form things in the language correctly.
Rym: You know what the rules are.
Rym: so how what what does that get me?
Scott: What does that get you?
Scott: Well you see when you have a language like the English language you see the human brain is Sort of flexi, and it is very has the fuzzy logic and the fusiform gyrus.
Scott: Yes as things which computers right now Do not have.
Scott: so if you were to try to speak the English language to a computer which is a valid language It's a language just according to the definitions.
Scott: I just gave The computer.
Scott: it'd be very very difficult to make a computer that understood that right.
Scott: and like I talked about last week You know the chip in the computer it knows like an assembly language Which is just numbers and then we sort of replace some of those numbers with letters to make it easier to type in but really It's not any different.
Scott: It's incredibly difficult for a human to think in the way a machine does.
Scott: so I assembly language is difficult.
Scott: So it's incredibly difficult to tell a machine what to do because you have to think the way it does which is hard.
Scott: It's much easier to think in.
Scott: you know your native human language But it's very hard for the computer to understand that.
Scott: so what we do in the world of programming is We basically if you made a chip that on the lowest level where the assembly language was easy That ship would be very slow because the assembly language is determined by the actual hardware.
Scott: So we make the hardware where the machine language is very hard.
Scott: It's the assembly language right, but then we make another language That's a little bit easier for humans to read and then that language gets translated into assembly language.
Scott: you see and we make up these languages we make up grammars for these languages and Then you know we write we talk to the computer in these new languages that we just made up.
Scott: We can make up any language you want.
Scott: we could even make a B into a programming language if we wanted to and then we Arbitrarily decide right because a language the meaning has nothing to do with the language.
Scott: right?
Scott: what a means like a bbva End of sentence is a valid sentence in the a B language.
Scott: What does that mean?
Scott: Oh, that's nothing to do with the language what it means.
Scott: we arbitrarily decide what the things are going to mean outside of the language and What we do is we take a grammar we type in our programming language The computer looks at the grammar right it looks at the language And then it says aha that is in this language Or it is not.
Scott: if it's not that's how you get the syntax errors you see.
Scott: Because he says oh, that's not in this language that doesn't match up.
Scott: you put a b a b Which is wrong because a must either be followed by a or the end of a?
Scott: B or the end of a sentence and B must be followed by either a or B. So if B is followed by the end of a sentence is no good.
Scott: I Don't know this is getting confusing even for me.
Rym: Don't do what Donnie don't does dude anyway.
Scott: Yeah anyway What we do is you make up a language.
Scott: the language can be a rules for how the symbols are arranged.
Scott: You can arrange the symbols however you want as you know you when you're making up the language.
Scott: But once the language is made up you obey the language And then the computer will translate that language according to the arbitrary things you set up, so we decide okay?
Scott: Aba that means you know the computer.
Scott: do this and a bba that means computer.
Scott: do this other thing and We just come up with a language that is you know a B is hard for people to understand.
Scott: You know it's only got two symbols.
Scott: It doesn't mean a lot of stuff.
Scott: But if you come up a language like C. We can have things like printf if while do then return You know int x integer All sorts of.
Scott: you know things that mean something to a human being and we write rules for how we're going to arrange these things in a structured way that a computer can break them apart.
Scott: and Now you can tell a computer what to do in a language that makes sense to humans, but is still structured and According to a grammar that a computer can bust apart, and that is that is sort of a languages.
Scott: I didn't do the bad by planning on how to explain.
Scott: that was much better than my execution.
Rym: That's fine because my what is IT was.
Rym: I'm just filling time before I eat a bunch of food.
Rym: Let's just keep trying.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: I will clarify more in the form if anyone wants, but here.
Scott: I want to say one more thing though.
Scott: No, here's where this kind of stuff gets interesting, and this is the stuff that is like the the complex parts of computer science That you will learn if you go get a CS degree all right, so let's say I Want to write down on a piece of paper.
Scott: right a definition of my language?
Scott: I want to write the grammar down.
Scott: if I want to write the grammar down.
Scott: I need to write it in a language don't I?
Scott: So so we have languages for writing grammars.
Scott: We have one language in particular called back as an hour form or BNF.
Scott: most people just say BNF because back as an hour is hard to say And BNF is a language for writing down grammars.
Scott: It's really not that complicated.
Scott: if you look at it It's it's pretty obvious.
Scott: It basically says this this can you know?
Scott: This is that and this is that.
Scott: so you can say sentence equals and then after that you put you know the form of a Sentence and then you could even do like sentence equals a number of words.
Scott: a word equals a number of you know letters.
Scott: Letter equals a or B or C or D or E or F, and that's English right there.
Scott: You know.
Scott: it's not that complicated.
Scott: But what if I wanted to write the grammar of back as an hour form?
Scott: because back as an hour form is a language.
Scott: So you could actually write the definition of the back as an hour form language in back as an hour form.
Scott: Think about that.
Scott: So wait here, we're gonna get crazy.
Scott: Are you ready?
Scott: XML is a language.
Scott: It's a markup language not a programming language, but it's a language.
Scott: right XML is a language.
Scott: It's the extensible markup language.
Scott: in XML there is a subset of XML called a DTD.
Scott: a document type definition I believe is what it stands for.
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: I think it's a document type definition.
Scott: a DTD is a way is a subset of XML.
Scott: so all DTDs are XML but not all XML or DTDs.
Scott: and a DTD is a way of Writing a grammar for a language.
Scott: that is XM.
Scott: that is a subset of XML.
Scott: so Xhtml for example is also another subset of XML, right?
Scott: So I could write the rules for writing Xhtml in a DTD.
Scott: in fact there is one you can go look at the rules for X HTML.
Scott: There is an X HTML DTD that you can look at.
Scott: That's a set of rules for writing an XML document written in a subset of XML itself, so you can write.
Scott: get this.
Scott: You can write a document type definition because DTDs are XML.
Scott: right You can write a DTD for DTDs.
Scott: You have XML as a language.
Scott: within that language you have a sub language that can define a Subset of the language so you can define.
Scott: it's it the subset of the language with itself?
Scott: You're writing languages.
Scott: you're using languages to write rules for languages and therefore they can write rules about how to write themselves.
Scott: It's totally crazy, and I got an assignment to write the DTD for DTDs once and I didn't do well It was hard.
Rym: man never had to do anything weird like that in IT.
Rym: We're just like here's a router.
Rym: set it up.
Scott: Yeah, if you can write if you want to go a real challenge try to write a document type definition for document type definitions.
Scott: I'm in fact there is one.
Scott: you can probably just download it on the internet.
Scott: See what it looks like.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe I'll find it somewhere, but You know this is the kind of stuff that you know is like the core of computer science.
Scott: You know you have languages.
Scott: It's language theory how languages work.
Scott: You know different language structures.
Scott: You know because by restruck.
Scott: This is why we have so many different programming languages.
Scott: you think oh We'll just have one.
Scott: You know we'll just have a handful.
Scott: why do we need so many?
Scott: it's because you can structure languages in so many different ways and It's really it's not about the computer so much.
Scott: We you know the computer speaks assembly.
Scott: we can trans.
Scott: You know we just need to come.
Scott: when you're making a new language You just need to make sure that you can translate it into the assembly somehow somewhere right or you could even translate it into another Language that can then be translated to assembly.
Scott: like Python translates to C translates to assembly.
Scott: so as long as I can translate to C I'm okay now.
Rym: You might say that seems silly, but think about it.
Rym: It's really a lot easier to write Python than it is to write C.
Scott: Well depends on what you're doing.
Rym: well for me It is for non coder.
Rym: if I'm doing simple stuff I can get a lot of the performance of things that are written in C, but I only have to write them in Python.
Scott: Yeah, so you basically there's this whole science, and it is science is computer science of trying to work out languages working with languages and grammars to come up with languages that are Easy for people to understand and you know are structured in a way that you can use them to get different jobs done.
Scott: However, also you need to be able to get computers to understand these languages make sense of them understand them and Translate them into actual real assembly instructions that the chip in the computer you know reads and does something according to that and That's like the core of CS there.
Scott: that that's the hardcore shits.
Rym: Well, if you don't have anything else then I can tell you all that next Monday I'm gonna talk about a IT subject that is near and dear to a lot of people.
Rym: We're going to talk about the help desk and what that really is and what its purpose is.
Scott: Those are the most annoyed people at the company and all the morons call them constantly The people.
Rym: when your Comcast thing is broken you call these people Everything that goes right.
Rym: these are the people.
Rym: they're pretty much the interface between users and People who actually care.
Scott: and the big problem, but I'll talk about it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.