Scott: It's Thursday, May 15th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, Geek Profiles #1 with Thade.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Okay, so we told you in weeks past that on Thursdays we're gonna start to change it up.
Scott: And this is the first Thursday where we're gonna change it up.
Rym: Oh, snap.
Scott: Oh, snaps.
Scott: We have today a special guest on the GeekNights.
Scott: Introduce yourself special guest.
Guest: Good evening, everyone.
Guest: It's Thade.
Guest: Hopefully, this isn't an entirely unfamiliar voice.
Scott: No, well, I don't know.
Scott: People... Do you mind?
Scott: Like, it seems like people are starting to call like Friday Night Partyline, like GeekNights Friday.
Scott: Is that like upset you or what?
Guest: The last time that we did the show, though, we had really it was just you guys that were from the forum.
Guest: I mean, Friday Night Partyline originated before I even came to your forum and stuff.
Guest: I don't mind what people think about it, but it's not that.
Guest: And it's going in a different direction now anyway with the guests that we're adding.
Scott: Much like our Thursday show.
Scott: It's going in a different direction right this minute.
Scott: All right, so I think the general idea here is, at least my idea, is you know, sometimes you get a guest on a show who's like, you know, some sort of famous person and you have to interview them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, I figure, you know, I guess Thade, there is some special things about you and you're, I guess, semi-famous and talented in ways.
Rym: Well, you're so generous.
Scott: I am.
Scott: So magnanimous.
Scott: Look at, I am so benevolent.
Scott: Look, look upon.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That, you know, my idea is that we could do sort of like these like geek profile kind of things, you know, where we could like ask the same questions or similar questions to like a bunch of different geeky people.
Scott: And you can sort of look at all the different geeks around the world and how they're the same and how they're different, because that's sort of, you know, the core philosophy of GeekNights is that, look, all these people are geeky and geekiness is awesome and such.
Scott: And also, I think we're going to start it off.
Scott: I told you to get a news in the thing of the day.
Scott: But I forgot that we sort of wanted to can the news on Thursday, which is fine because.
Rym: Well, maybe not necessarily can it, but have bits other than, oh, my God, we talk about the news.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I kind of want to make, you know, obviously when we, you know, when you ever have a guest on the show, it always takes forever.
Scott: You know, it's going to be a long one.
Scott: And I kind of want to be able to cook and eat dinner before a reasonable hour, even though I know that's not going to happen because I'm looking at the clock already and it's upsetting.
Scott: But you had a very, very interesting news and it gave us an idea for a possible Thursday bit.
Scott: So tell us about your news and then we will discuss it.
Guest: My news, Scott, is about trains in India.
Guest: And the headline is Mumbai.
Guest: trains kill 20,000 in five years.
Scott: That's like an insane number, like.
Guest: Yes.
Guest: Well, you have to imagine what these trains are like.
Guest: If they have doors at all, it's unusual.
Guest: They have barred windows, but no glass.
Guest: And unlike in Japan, where everybody is really orderly in getting on the train, these trains are just a mob scene every day.
Guest: People are hanging off the roof, they're hanging out of the windows and they're jammed in way beyond any sort of capacity that the trains are designed for.
Rym: I mean, I've seen pictures of these on Fark.
Rym: I mean, they're often an object of ridicule on Fark, but you know that everything is ridiculed on Fark.
Rym: But you see these things.
Rym: And if you just see this picture without context, you would look at it and think, wow, that's a joke.
Rym: That is not an actual daily occurrence.
Scott: Yeah, it looks like one of those things where it's how many people can you cram in a phone booth, you know?
Guest: But here, I mean, 10 people a day are dying on these trains.
Guest: So if you think you have a bad commute or your train is messy or you're sitting next to a smelly guy, imagine being crammed in beyond what humans should endure and then risking your life every day.
Scott: I mean, in Japan, they pack them in pretty tight.
Scott: They actually have guys who will push the people into the train, you know, but it's nowhere near this bad, not even close.
Guest: Smell.
Scott: So, yeah, so like there's a lot of things I was thinking of that they could do to sort of fix this problem.
Rym: But that's very easy to say.
Rym: Oh, well, they could do this.
Rym: I know that because if they had the resources to do something effective, it probably would have been done.
Scott: I know that sort of it's sort of one of those things where, yes, they're obviously not going to do this because of, you know, realistic reasons like that.
Scott: But it's fun to try to, you know, think of solutions to something like this from like, you know, an engineering sort of nerdy standpoint.
Scott: Like I was thinking, well, why did they even have train cars?
Scott: Why don't they just have like, you know, like a big, long platform, you know, that that just moves around the tracks, like in a big circle, really slowly, constantly, you know, or something like that?
Guest: Like at the airport?
Scott: Yeah, sort of like at the airport.
Scott: or maybe like you have one train, you know, if you didn't have a big metal train car, if you just had, you know, one engine and like, say, you know, just seats on boards, you know, just something like that was much more open and you could weigh a lot less.
Scott: And that's one train engine could pull a lot more.
Scott: You could be spread out a lot more.
Scott: You know, maybe you could just I don't know.
Scott: It seems like that might actually be pretty cheap to do, you know, if someone actually thought of it.
Scott: I mean, the safety concerns, if you fall off, you could get run over by the train, but it wouldn't be moving that fast.
Rym: Well, I think the more fundamental problem is that if you look at the sort of governmental and civil infrastructure of nations like India, there's very little civic planning in most cases and a lot of corruption and such to the point that even if there was a good idea, I mean, how could you possibly implement it?
Rym: The trains are the way they are, partly because no one is effectively tried to make a solution.
Guest: And the huge population, I mean, we're talking about a rail system that ferries seven million commuters every day.
Scott: No, that's like more than all the people in New York City.
Scott: Right.
Scott: How many people are in the city?
Rym: Well, the thing is, we have a very extensive transit infrastructure in New York, but the population of New York grew a lot more slowly than the population in India.
Rym: There was a lot of time to adapt.
Rym: And also we have we have superhighways in the car culture and there's all these alternate ways of getting around.
Scott: I mean, there are cars in India, but you've seen that video.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Guest: Plus, you know, when you're making a couple dollars a day, you know, you're not going to be able to buy a car.
Rym: I mean, a lot of Americans can't even afford to have cars or they have cars, but really they'd be better off if somehow they're away where they could just use some sort of public transit.
Rym: I mean, the cost of ownership of a car in the U.S.
Rym: is staggering.
Rym: Our friend Conrad really he's desperate to find a way to just be able to get rid of his car and never own one again.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I take the train to work, but I still have to have the car.
Scott: It's like, you know, or else I'd be screwed.
Scott: I wouldn't be able to get groceries at the grocery store.
Scott: I wouldn't be able to go to my parents' house.
Scott: You know, it's it's.
Scott: It's really not fair.
Guest: Depends on where you live, too.
Scott: I mean, if I lived in in the city or in one of the boroughs, you know, Bronx, Queens, Staten Island, Brooklyn, I wouldn't need a car.
Scott: And it's actually difficult to have a car because I'd have to pay for somewhere to park it.
Rym: But remember, I grew up in the Midwest where there there were barely even buses.
Rym: I'd never seen a taxi in person until I got to New York.
Rym: It's just it's a totally different world.
Rym: There's no trains.
Guest: And you wouldn't take a bus in Detroit anyway.
Scott: I don't even take a bus in New York City, not because I'm like afraid of it or anything, but because I just don't trust.
Rym: Well, I think it's more because we tend to restrict ourselves to Manhattan and occasionally the Bronx where there's no reason to ever take a bus.
Scott: The subways go everywhere except the Javits or they go close enough for you to walk.
Rym: But if you're going to the airport or you're in any other borough, the buses are actually great.
Scott: Yeah, I guess if I was you know, if I had to go somewhere and the bus was like the only going anywhere in Brooklyn that isn't near a subway, just take the bus.
Rym: or if you live in Brooklyn.
Scott: Like my cousins live in Queens and they could go to the subway, take the train.
Scott: But they like the express bus is closer to their house and is, you know, faster.
Scott: But it's a little bit more expensive.
Scott: I think it's like five dollars.
Rym: Great.
Rym: So obviously then the solution is we just need to build subways in India.
Scott: It's not a bad idea.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Rym: It's a terrible idea.
Scott: Well, you got to build enough of them.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: even subways aren't long distance or even medium distance transit.
Rym: They can't go very far, at least by the way.
Rym: we design modern subways.
Rym: And considering that the part of the problem in India is that they don't have the money to build a more robust infrastructure, they're not going to build a depressurized underground super train.
Scott: I guess they're not going to make a super train, but, you know, I don't know, they could build sort of like an amusement park thing where there's just a constant like this string of like, you know, little two seaters that just this third constant is two seat or two seat or two seat.
Scott: You know, I don't know.
Guest: You have population density like that.
Guest: Human life has less value.
Guest: They don't care.
Guest: They don't care if 20,000 people die.
Guest: They're not going to change anything.
Guest: They're pouring as much money as they can into it now.
Guest: But it's not enough to keep up with the pace of population growth.
Rym: I mean, I think there's also the point of even if individual people care in the system, the system itself, I mean, you know, a bureaucracy gets to the point where it maintains itself.
Rym: And the system takes a lot more work to make it care than any individual person working within it.
Scott: It's depressing.
Scott: And, you know, I think the train like on Thanksgiving, sometimes our train will be filled up to the point where, you know, people are standing in the aisles.
Scott: But that's not crowded at all compared to this.
Rym: Of course, you look at a lot of people on that train and to them, it's the end of the goddamn world.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Imagine I should take I should print out pictures of the India train and like tape them to the walls on the New York train.
Rym: I mean, actually, today my train was delayed by about five minutes because there was rain and all this.
Scott: Well, they're doing something to one of the tracks up near Beacon.
Scott: I was I was delayed also.
Rym: Yeah, but it was also because of the rain which delayed the work with blah, blah, blah.
Rym: But we were delayed like five minutes.
Rym: And when the conductor announces like, I apologize for the delay, we're going kind of slowly due to rain and construction, we'll be arriving about five minutes late.
Rym: And this guy sitting a little ways down goes, Son of a goddamn it.
Rym: My tax dollars, Metro North, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: This is bullshit.
Rym: This is worse than Amtrak.
Rym: And he's just going on and on and on to himself.
Rym: And all I could think was, dude, not only is Metro North not paid for by your tax dollars and profitable.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: I mean, Amtrak, you can complain about if you're, say, you know, out in the middle of nowhere where it sucks, but you mean out in the middle of nowhere where they shouldn't be using trains, where buses and hubs would be much more efficient?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So things of the day, I'll admit this is quite a cop out.
Rym: This is one of those backup things today.
Rym: I kind of keep around for when I didn't see anything worthwhile on the Internet.
Rym: that wasn't already on CollegeHumor.
Rym: I'm not going to tell you how I found this.
Rym: It I will not admit that I was just sitting around looking up pictures upon videos, upon movies, upon everything I could find of puppies and baby foxes.
Scott: And that's your default.
Scott: Find the cute animals.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: But this one, Shiba Inu are incredible dogs.
Rym: They're incredibly, amazingly intelligent.
Rym: But as a result, they're really whiny and they're very talkative and they're very difficult for a lot of people to deal with because they're smart and they're obstinate.
Rym: And well, this Shiba Inu has encountered an intruder in his space and the way he reacts to it.
Rym: And of course, more so than that, the nature of the intruder is kind of epic.
Rym: I don't think I'll even let on to what the intruder is.
Rym: I think you should watch the video to get the kind of.
Scott: I'm feeling like I might want to spoil your secret, because every time I try to lead people into something and secret it up, you spoil it.
Rym: When was the last time I did that yesterday?
Rym: See, I have words about the way you were trying to review that show that for a Wednesday when I try to do a show on how to review a show.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Well, yeah, that's going to be a good show.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I'll do my thing today and then then you can go, Thade.
Scott: So my company, you know, last year we did some softball and it didn't go so well because you sort of like all this, all the sort of company sports leagues in the city, they require you to have like, you know, X players show up or else you lose.
Scott: And they require you to have like, you know, a mix of male and female players.
Scott: And that's that's all well and good.
Scott: Those are good rules that they have there.
Scott: But my company had very, very few people total.
Scott: So it was very difficult to get a whole softball team together, you know, on this, you know, the times and the schedules for the games.
Scott: And a lot of the games will be far away from our office, like way uptown.
Scott: And no one wanted to go, you know, so it didn't last very long.
Scott: But actually, we were looking around, you know, because some of us in the office still kind of want to do some sort of office sport of some kind.
Scott: And we found this really cool website, Zog Sports dot com, Zog Sports dot com.
Scott: And check this out.
Scott: This is way cool.
Scott: You they have basically, you know, sports leagues for, you know, amateur nonprofessional teams.
Scott: They let you play, you know, either like ultra casual, casual or, you know, kind of weak, actually caring about winning and losing, you know, playing.
Scott: all the money that, you know, you give to them to sort of join the leagues.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They use that to, you know, rent the fields and the equipment and all that stuff and pay the umpires or whatever sort of officials they need to to referee the games.
Scott: But the rest of the money all goes to charities and such.
Scott: And when you win.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If your team wins, the prize you get is a cash prize to the charity of your choice.
Scott: So winning is sort of like you get to pick the charity.
Scott: And the best part about this whole thing is that it's not just sort of your normal sports, even though it is.
Rym: They have volleyball in there.
Scott: Well, let me let me list some of the sports here.
Scott: We got touch footballs.
Scott: We got kickball.
Scott: We got wiffle ball and the rest are, you know, indoor soccer, outdoor soccer, volleyball, basketball, kickball.
Scott: I said kickball.
Scott: Oh, and dodgeball.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Oh, and coming.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: Dodgeball.
Rym: There's a lot of ways to play.
Scott: Coming soon, whitewater rafting, surfing and beach trip and wine tasting.
Scott: How about that?
Scott: So, yeah, it's good stuff.
Guest: Sounds like the Cleveland Sport and Social Club we had here a few years ago.
Scott: Yeah, I'm always wanting to do something like that, but it's not easy to get it together unless you you know, you live down there, because I mean, if I stay after work for like a kickball game.
Guest: It's covered.
Guest: You'd meet girls.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Scott: Maybe they said that, like, you know, after games, they like they pay for you to like go out and drink or whatever.
Guest: Well, there you go.
Guest: They could have some orange juice for you or something.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure.
Scott: All right.
Scott: You have a thing of the day?
Guest: Yes, my thing of the day is Muto, a wall painted animation by Blue.
Guest: And this is a short film by this guy named Blue who did it in Buenos Aires.
Guest: What he did, which must have taken I can't even imagine how much paint and how much time this took, but he did an animation like you would on paper on a wall with graffiti.
Guest: So he did this whole movie of this, this, this animation and this wall going inside, outside, down the street, into holes, all of these things.
Guest: At times it gets to be two or three stories tall.
Guest: The amount of labor that went into this is just, I mean, it must have taken months.
Scott: Are you sure it wasn't like digitally aided?
Guest: No, no, this is, this is, this is Buenos Aires.
Guest: I mean, this is, this is Latin America.
Guest: This is old school.
Guest: This is, you know, a camera and a guy with a lot of paint and a lot of time.
Guest: But, you know, the style of animation, I mean, you've seen, I guess I'd describe it as the human form going through various mutations, you know, people climbing out of their own skin and shapes for heads.
Guest: And I mean, the animation, I think we've all seen it before, but just the fact that it's done as graffiti and it's, and it's animated, I mean, the, the effort is, is stunning.
Scott: I was, I started to watch the video, but then I stopped and I haven't seen it, so I don't really know.
Scott: But, you know, I mean, it is posted on the internet, so there's obviously some, you know, don't like think, oh, it's somewhere that's, you know, I don't think about.
Scott: They don't have any technology because they do.
Scott: All right, so basically what I'm going to go for here is, is I'm going to, I'm going to ask you a bunch of questions.
Scott: You don't have to answer all of them if you don't want to, but I hope that this will take us somewhere interesting.
Scott: And this is sort of the experiment for the future.
Rym: Yeah, everyone out there for good or ill, this episode is mostly Scott, if you can't tell.
Rym: I'm kind of just chilling back.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: And so I want all listeners out there who are who are listening to this show to make comments on it, you know, because we're going to sort of try to continue this.
Scott: maybe or maybe not if you all hate it.
Rym: But hopefully it'll be good as long as you keep the energy up.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: I'm trying to keep the energy up.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the first question I'm going to ask you, right.
Scott: So you are a GeekNights listener.
Scott: Yes, obviously.
Guest: Yes, yes, I am.
Scott: How did you find GeekNights?
Guest: Oh, wow.
Guest: I don't remember.
Guest: It's been a while.
Guest: I was looking for a good podcast to listen to, and I was just going through, I probably did some searches, some indexes on technology related things.
Guest: And I don't know, I think that I just I would listen to a couple of shows and just weed them out.
Guest: And if the sound quality was bad, that I that just kills me immediately.
Guest: So you guys have always had good sound.
Rym: Well, well, you never heard the special episodes.
Guest: The ones that you won't tell people about on the forums.
Guest: They're out there.
Scott: I mean, even even the non, you know, the early episodes that weren't special, if you listen to those, they're really terrible compared to like what we're doing right now.
Guest: I mean, I was listening to Adam Curry when I first started listening to podcasts.
Scott: I did, too, and I don't anymore.
Guest: No, no, he's still doing it.
Guest: But I didn't know that or whatever.
Guest: I it's not.
Guest: But once you get you find shows that that cater to your interests, then, you know, you gravitate toward those.
Guest: And then I was interested enough to start doing podcasting.
Guest: And I think it was about the same time that I started.
Guest: Friday Night Partyline is when I started listening to your show.
Scott: So so why do you like our show?
Guest: Well, I think that it's.
Guest: you know, you guys obviously have a terrific sense of comic timing and you you work very well together.
Guest: But for me, it's probably the fact that you don't hold back.
Guest: You don't try to dumb it down.
Guest: My whole life, I have searched for people and through things that that aren't dumbed down because our society and our culture is geared toward the sixth grade reading level.
Guest: And and, you know, Rym is always people are always busting his traps about being elitist.
Guest: And my thought is, come on, you know, step up.
Rym: Jeez, it works for Barack Obama.
Rym: It'll work for me.
Guest: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Guest: I agree with you on so many things from except for for Mr.
Rym: Obama, but we'll have to have a little post show discussion.
Rym: I'm curious.
Scott: I wanted to start a lot of discussions, but I don't know if I want to start that one.
Guest: Yeah, I hate talking about politics on the Internet and on Twitter and all these people talking about their political views.
Rym: And I don't know, I think I'd like talking about politics with you on the show, especially because Scott will never, ever talk about politics and doesn't know anything and doesn't care.
Scott: So, you know, I care a little.
Scott: I just don't care that much.
Scott: And it's mostly, you know, over, you know, for the earlier part of my life, I didn't know, you know, right from left.
Scott: And then once I knew, you know, just discussing it was like, you know, at one point it was interesting.
Scott: But then lately it's just frustrating because everybody's crazy.
Scott: I just before we go out and everyone argues from emotion and everyone argues irrationally, everyone and most people, though, at least especially on the Internet, it's like it's very difficult to actually get a real political discussion focusing on, you know, because I always come at things you try.
Scott: I try to from like a political science standpoint, and most people sort of don't see that view.
Scott: And it's very difficult.
Scott: All right, anyway, so.
Scott: You've heard, you know, we've done like a bajillion GeekNights episodes, right?
Scott: Do you have an idea for for a GeekNights show topic that we haven't done that you would very much like?
Guest: Oh, Monday, Mondays and Thursdays are my favorite days.
Guest: So if you just take the technology stuff that you know and then really don't hold back, if you're something that you're interested in professionally, where you like in your coding, you were saying you were complaining the other day about not being able to parse something, if you if you could take something that that you see in your day or some philosophical aspect of of of computer programming and then really go into it in detail, pretending like we're all at your level.
Guest: And then that way, as listeners, we can work to understand what you're saying as opposed to just saying, oh, I can't get my brain around that.
Guest: I forget it.
Guest: I'm not going to listen anymore.
Guest: That's kind of what I appreciate.
Guest: But that probably puts me in the minority of listeners.
Rym: Yeah, well, you wouldn't believe the amount of feedback we got when we way back tried to do this whole how computers work thing.
Rym: And we started, I think, with like flip flops and like the basics of electronics.
Scott: And I'm going to have to redo this video now, I think.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the thing is pretty.
Rym: the emails we got were basically, wow, I'm stupid and I want it from a first grade level.
Scott: Yeah, but we also got emails saying, wow, that was really great.
Scott: And it's so half and half.
Scott: We don't know which way to go.
Scott: And with those shows, our goal is sort of to actually help people understand how computers work.
Scott: So it's if they're not going to understand it, then it's sort of like we're not achieving our goal.
Scott: You know, but on the other hand, we sort of you know, if people if we're saying things that are so dumb that no one's learning anything new, then it's also sort of not achieving our goal.
Rym: Well, it's tricky with particularly what I do.
Rym: I mean, I'm kind of apart from Scott and a lot of the other people we know technology wise and that everything I do is like enterprise level, like it's this totally different realm of computers and technology.
Rym: And it's it's something that has zero application in 90 percent of technology professionals lives and ninety nine percent of human beings lives like.
Rym: the topics are so esoteric and so specific and so just utterly, utterly I don't I mean, not necessarily difficult or beyond, but just not applicable in any way to people's lives.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Guest: And a big call for Emily to be in the show more, I think that if you can interject someone else who is dynamic and and smart and of course female, then people are going to like most of your audience is male.
Scott: Yeah, we have a lot of, you know, other front row crew people, but, you know, they're not always nearby or they're not always willing.
Scott: You know, I mean, on New Year's, I tried to get one of our friends on the show because he's like an expert on many technological issues, even more so than than we are.
Scott: But he was like talking about James.
Scott: Yeah, but he didn't want to.
Scott: He was like, no, I don't want to.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, because I kind of wanted to hear what he had to say, because he, you know, he knows a lot more than I do.
Guest: Not everybody is an attention whore like we are.
Scott: No, I guess not.
Rym: Yeah, we started young at that, though.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what other like podcasts or video internet shows do you listen to or watch frequently?
Guest: Oh, wow.
Guest: I could give you a more complete list if I had my eye.
Rym: You don't have to be complete, just, you know, actually, it's probably better this way because instead of going through the list, it's kind of what was on your mind.
Rym: I mean, there's shows I nominally listen to and I'm subscribed to, but I don't think about them on a daily basis because I don't like them that much, to be honest.
Guest: I've really tried to go out and look for some more recently.
Guest: You know, since we worked with Dr.
Guest: Kiki, I pretty much have followed everything that she's doing from This Week in Media to This Week in Science.
Guest: There's all of the Leo Laporte podcasts are pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, I mostly only listen to Twit and the Floss Weekly.
Scott: The Floss Weekly, that's the best one, I have to say.
Guest: Net at Night, I think it's called with Amber McArthur.
Guest: That's really Amber McArthur is very pleasant to listen to.
Guest: And the CNET podcast, Buzz Out Loud.
Scott: Yeah, I've heard of that.
Guest: That's very good.
Guest: I mean, Molly Wood is one of those unique personalities, very fun to listen to.
Guest: Of course, Extra Life Radio, Scott Johnson, who we may or may not have a connection with here in the short future.
Scott: Yeah, we got too many Scott Johnsons.
Scott: We got to find a way to separate them.
Rym: Yeah, our Scott Johnson is the one who actually knows about politics.
Rym: And I actually get to talk to him.
Scott: Well, we don't know that the other Scott Johnson doesn't know about politics.
Rym: He's in our crew.
Rym: Yeah, he understands politics enough to where?
Rym: if you make a political science argument, he understands it and responds with an equally valid political science argument as opposed to a but McCain.
Scott: But it will be expressed with not much eloquence.
Scott: Hey, it's true.
Scott: He knows it.
Scott: He doesn't care.
Scott: All right.
Guest: There's a couple others.
Guest: Maximum PC, just because it's it's hard to find a really good hardware show.
Guest: There's Maximum PC is good.
Guest: And there's another one.
Guest: I can't think of the name of it.
Guest: It's Extreme Tech.
Guest: That's an Extreme Tech podcast, both hardware related shows.
Guest: And that's really as far as computer knowledge goes.
Guest: That's my strong point.
Guest: It's from a hobbyist perspective anyway.
Rym: I'll actually admit that I used to be that way.
Rym: And then in recent years, like I'm so divorced from the PC world that I don't even I wouldn't know what video card to buy.
Rym: I don't I have to look up to figure out what processor goes with what motherboard or which one's fast or what Northbridge is good anymore.
Scott: It took me a long time to build that computer, much longer than it would have in the past.
Scott: That's for sure.
Guest: It all comes back to you, though.
Scott: It does.
Scott: But it's sort of like you have to relearn like what acronyms match up with what others and all that business.
Guest: Someone in your forum suggested Geeks On.
Guest: I went back and I listened to the Joss Whedon episode that they had.
Guest: That was outstanding.
Guest: But I started listening to their latest show and they got a couple of things wrong.
Guest: And that just it's almost like bad sound to me.
Guest: If you if you don't know what you're talking about, then you shouldn't be talking about it.
Rym: They were using the word schadenfreude.
Guest: And I may have even mispronounced it, but but I know that it's German and not French.
Guest: Thank you very much.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: OK, because I was going to say, like, you know, we get things wrong.
Scott: Sometimes we even know we get them wrong.
Scott: But we do a good job of I think at least I think we do a good job of pretending we know what we're talking about.
Scott: And it's convincing that we're not bullshitting.
Rym: That's a problem I have when I when I sell things to people or I do my stuff and I tend to it's very easy to talk around anything I don't know and make it appear that I know a lot more than I may actually know.
Guest: Well, and I'm not being fair at all.
Guest: But, you know, if you do get it wrong, everybody makes mistakes.
Guest: Then correct yourself.
Guest: Don't try to hide it.
Scott: You know, I mean, if people call us if people call me out and I'm wrong, I always say I'm wrong.
Scott: You know, I just you know, but it's surprising how many episodes, like, especially when we used to sort of do like reading Wikipedia episodes.
Scott: Oh, no one.
Scott: No one would call us out.
Rym: I remember there was one word way back where you're talking about programming.
Rym: And for like five minutes straight, you were talking about like object oriented and all these different kinds of programming and you just set them all backwards.
Rym: But no one noticed to this day.
Rym: I don't think.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Rym: Because we noticed it after the fact.
Rym: We're like, oh, man, we totally screwed that up.
Rym: But to this day, no one ever called us out on it.
Rym: And a lot of people listen to that episode.
Guest: I think podcasting is going through kind of a phase change right now.
Guest: People are trying to do innovative things.
Guest: If you look at Leo Laporte, he's doing twenty five hours of video now, he's trying to bring the world to Leo so he can stay in his area and then just not have to travel at all and people have to travel to him.
Guest: I, Justine from Pittsburgh and Alex Lindsay from This Week in Media, we're just out there and it's kind of interesting to watch him sort of go into video because the way he describes it, it doesn't seem to be like he has a real plan.
Guest: And for me, I don't consume much video.
Guest: I mean, very, very little because there's no time.
Guest: I'm too busy doing the things that I do in my life, whereas with audio, I can listen to it in the car while I'm doing other things.
Guest: So in terms of my own podcasting stuff, I'm going to continue to explore audio, but I'm only going to do video as sort of special things for work and maybe some computer stuff.
Rym: That's definitely the direction we're going in with the whole video thing.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely seems, though, like his video is pretty much just showing the people's faces while they're recording the otherwise audio show, you know, to sort of just add the, you know, you can see the person's face, you know, element and maybe also, you know, if they're talking about a particular device or something, they can actually show it to you.
Scott: But it seems like that's all he's really doing with the video.
Scott: Is he doing more that I don't know about?
Guest: Oh, and I mean, if he's looking to try to turn this into a company, he can sell like, you know, CBS buying CNET for one point seven, five billion or however much they bought it for today.
Guest: I think that someone like Kevin Rose is going to have a much better chance with revision three than he is with this.
Guest: I just don't know what you know.
Guest: How do you get advertisers for a thousand people that have nothing better to do but watch you do a podcast?
Guest: I don't get.
Guest: I mean, I don't understand where the model is.
Guest: I don't know.
Rym: At least we've avoided that whole pitfall by just not trying to make money at all.
Scott: Well, we're not trying to make money with the GeekNights show.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what I mean, we've already I'm starting to find ways, you know, because I always said the GeekNights show is sort of like, you know, let's get out there and then we can do other things and then we'll have sort of like an installed audience for other things that may or may not make money, you know.
Scott: So it's sort of like if I would have done a project before, like let's say I would have made something like a game.
Scott: You know, if I would have tried to sell that game, you know, it would be very difficult.
Scott: But now it's sort of like I have this this base and it's like if I do anything else, this base, I can easily draw their attention to it and sort of get off with like a little head start at anything I do.
Scott: So that's that's sort of what GeekNights is for.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah, for me, though, it's just to keep my audience, I'll go crazy if I don't have a lot of people listening to my voice every day.
Scott: Yeah, that, too.
Guest: Attention whore, yes.
Guest: I mean, I'm as guilty as you are, I love it as much as you do.
Rym: Even we got in some of the other front row crew people as they brush with GeekNights, they do stuff with us where there's crowds or there's fans or anything, and they always come back and they kind of say they usually say something along the lines of, wow, it's kind of cool being on the other side of that velvet rope.
Scott: I know you're going to say a velvet rope.
Rym: Can I can I be behind that velvet rope again?
Scott: It'll be like you can be behind as many velvet ropes as you want.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So you are.
Scott: you are quite a geeky person, obviously, if you're if you're liking the GeekNights.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So so what are your?
Scott: what are your primary geekeries?
Scott: Because, you know, we we're sort of got our hands on all the geekeries.
Guest: Right.
Guest: Oh, and you've you've opened my eyes to other things, geek related.
Guest: I was only kind of into anime and I'm still nothing like you guys or some of the listeners.
Scott: We're not even that much into anime as we used to be.
Guest: Or what's?
Guest: what's her name, Tenshi.
Rym: Oh, and Neforum.
Guest: Yeah, it's her own show, too.
Guest: She's really, really into the animes.
Guest: But no, computer hardware is my primary geek area.
Guest: If I shared with you some of the computer things that I've got going on here in my home office that we've nicknamed Michigan, Michigan, Michigan, Mission Control.
Guest: I have about 15 computers.
Guest: I Mac is the only non PC related.
Guest: I have a Ubuntu box and the rest of the stuff is Win 2K, XP and Vista.
Guest: But, you know, I just I'm playing with computers all the time, whether it's swapping out hard drives out of laptops or building machines from scratch or for other people, I just it's something that relaxes me.
Guest: I have a pretty stressful job and it's that's that's, you know, it's really.
Scott: Nancy, I was way into, you know, fiddling with the computers themselves for for a long time.
Scott: And early on, it was like a big, you know, learning thing like.
Scott: that's how I learned a lot of the stuff I know is just by putting computers together, installing operating systems.
Rym: I mean, you used to run Jentu and unlike me, you actually kept part of job today.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And that helped me learn a lot.
Scott: But then I sort of reached a point where I wasn't learning anymore.
Scott: And it was just, you know, it's I wanted to use the computer to do things I didn't want to.
Scott: You know, I found that I was spending all my time working for the computer and the computer wasn't working for me.
Scott: So that's why now it's just like install Ubuntu or install whatever the default OS is, use the default settings and just get work done.
Scott: You know, so.
Rym: But you got to got to tweak your kernel.
Rym: The kernel's got to be tweaked.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Guest: And that's more software than hardware.
Guest: You know, I just built a couple of FreeNAS servers and that that has been a lot of fun.
Guest: FreeNAS is a lot of fun to play with.
Guest: And, you know, one of them's a four terabyte server.
Guest: And I did a. I did a video about that.
Guest: And the funny thing as far as video killing podcasting, I think I have over 2,000 views on that video, whereas the average, you know, number of listeners for, say, the over 40 gamer podcasts that I was doing for a while, you know, I was getting 70 or 80 a month on that solo show.
Guest: So video is much more powerful.
Guest: No, it isn't.
Guest: And Friday Night Party Line's numbers are considerably, well, substantially higher.
Rym: I mean, I think the issue is with video, like the main thing we want to do with video is it seems like a lot of people just don't understand podcasting.
Rym: Even to this day, the vast majority of people I talk to have never heard of the word of no idea what it is that they and even if they own an iPod, they just like, oh, I don't know, is that some iTunes thing?
Scott: It's like a podcasting button in iTunes, but they don't notice it somehow.
Rym: They don't even know it's there.
Rym: Never, never even cross their mind to click on it.
Rym: So we want to make videos that kind of point out, hey, there's podcast.
Scott: We should definitely do a how-to podcast video.
Rym: You all commute.
Guest: Kevin Rose did one three years ago.
Guest: I mean, that helped me get into this show and get into this stuff.
Guest: I mean, the folks over at Revision3 have done a lot of the things that you're talking about and they're making a go of it.
Guest: But I have a feeling that their numbers on some of their shows are probably lower than GeekNights.
Scott: Well, some of it, yeah.
Scott: I mean, you know, some of the Revision3 shows, I mean, I know who Revision3 is just from listening, you know, to to Twit and formerly reading Dig and all that stuff.
Scott: But, you know, I only know about some of their biggest shows.
Scott: I mean, they have a lot of shows on there and most of them, I think most people just never heard of them.
Guest: If you can't tie advertising to it, though, it's it's it's not.
Guest: it's hard to sustain with the degree of quality that you'll need to compete with other things that are happening.
Guest: There are so many people that do podcasting and maybe do one or two shows and then then fade away.
Guest: But the number of good, consistent podcasts, I think, is actually shrinking.
Rym: I would have to agree.
Rym: I mean, I have an added new podcast to my repertoire and in a long time and I have it's not like I've stopped looking.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, sort of what I've had is I sort of found enough podcasts to sort of fill my daily routine.
Scott: So it's like, you know, I added recently that the John C. Dvorak's like Tech Five, you know, it's very short.
Scott: So I can just sort of listen to it in the morning really quickly, like I'm driving to the train station.
Scott: I can listen to the whole thing.
Guest: Well, that's what Grammar Girl does, too.
Guest: And Grammar Girl has that whole company of all, you know, legal lad and sales guy and all of these six minute podcasts that that have advertising in it, but give you a nugget of value in that six minutes.
Scott: Onion Radio News, I think, was the first podcast to really master that format.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So you said you're like primary geekery is like computer hardware, right?
Scott: But you weren't like born with a CPU hanging out of your mouth or anything.
Scott: So how did you like get into that?
Guest: Well, it just goes back to the beginning.
Guest: I'm old.
Guest: I'm two years old.
Guest: And, you know, so I mean, I played with Trash 80s.
Guest: I played with.
Guest: I had a Timex Sinclair computer.
Guest: I played with them since they became popular.
Guest: I still have my original IBM XT.
Scott: XTs are good for typing.
Guest: When you when you just play with something as a hobby for more than 20 years, you just learn really.
Guest: I mean, yeah, I'm a lawyer.
Guest: I'm not I'm not a computer guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I was just about to say, like, you know, with such an interesting computers, you ended up, though, as the lawyer, like how did did you did you?
Guest: Well, that's that's a fair question.
Scott: I you know, I mean, would you rather be a computer guy?
Guest: Oh, that's such that's I don't know.
Guest: I think that I'd rather do what you would rather do and be sort of independently wealthy and then do whatever it's like that day.
Scott: Well, you have enough money to feed both of us.
Scott: So let's both quit.
Scott: And we'll get on that.
Rym: Well, there was that period about a year ago when I was thinking about just giving up on I.T.
Rym: going to law school.
Scott: It's true.
Rym: Going the opposite direction.
Rym: Luckily, but I mean, that was all before.
Rym: I guess I was so disillusioned with I.T.
Rym: just because I had a pretty crappy job and I was making, you know, mediocre money.
Rym: And then suddenly now stock market gigantic.
Rym: Like I actually just got a fifteen thousand dollar raise out of the blue last week.
Rym: Like my boss said, hey, you want fifteen thousand more dollars?
Rym: And I was like, yeah, I think I'm going to stick around this place a while.
Rym: So I think I've given up on my lawyer dreams.
Guest: Well, you know, you're probably better off for it.
Guest: Law is extremely competitive.
Guest: I mean, my first seven years of practice, I didn't enjoy it at all.
Guest: And it was very, very difficult.
Guest: And then through a series of circumstances and through some things that I was involved in, I ended up at my current place.
Guest: And I like that a lot.
Guest: And it's been very rewarding, too.
Scott: So do you have any hobbies that, like, aren't geeky?
Scott: or I mean, is it just pretty much that we would argue that any any hobby becomes geeky?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Like if you told me that you liked, you know, say, snowboarding, I'd say, well, you're a snowboarding geek, but, you know.
Rym: Well, maybe not.
Rym: Maybe I've never seen a snowboarder actually snowboarding.
Scott: So that's yeah.
Scott: But do you have any hobbies that aren't, you know, popularly considered to be geek hobbies for a while?
Guest: I was a serial hobbyist.
Guest: I would go from one thing to the next to flying lessons.
Guest: I took oil painting lessons, drawing.
Guest: I still do a little pencil drawing.
Guest: I did collecting various things from stamps to coins to, you know, I don't even remember all the things now.
Guest: From Lego to robot building to I'm just sort of looking around now for the remnants, the vestiges of these hobbies.
Guest: And eventually my work got so time consuming that I really only had time for one or two.
Guest: So I still have the sports car and I still have all my computers.
Guest: But podcasting is probably, if you can call that a hobby, the only other thing that I do.
Guest: But that's geeky.
Scott: Yeah, I guess.
Scott: My friend's dad is a lot like that.
Scott: Like he would go and buy a bowling ball and then he would stop bowling.
Scott: He would bowl a whole bunch and then he would stop.
Scott: And then he would yeah.
Scott: Then he would go and buy something else and do that.
Scott: Like he bought a camera and he'd be taking pictures like crazy and then he would stop.
Guest: And I don't know, it's all part of discovering what you like to do.
Guest: I mean, when we on Friday night party line, we make fun of the idea of what what is it?
Guest: that's really fun.
Guest: If you're a happy person, like, you know, Rym is a happy person.
Guest: You can't make the guy unhappy, really, from what we see, at least in the audience.
Guest: I don't know.
Guest: Maybe he cries himself to sleep every night, but on the inside, maybe.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: As people are in, the crew can say it's actually scarier in real life than on the show.
Rym: I'm much less cynical in the real world.
Guest: So, you know, but there are other people, Scott and me, who are not like that.
Guest: And so you spend your life searching for something that is enjoyable, that you can put your time in and get something that's back, that's rewarding.
Scott: I don't need to search.
Scott: I just can't get.
Guest: Well, but it becomes a search after a while.
Guest: I mean, you remind me of myself from when I was younger, except I had a girlfriend.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: What do you want from me?
Guest: No, it's your rigid thinking, Scott.
Guest: You have so much rigidity in your mind and it stops you from doing things like dating.
Guest: That's all.
Scott: Well, you know, I don't think rigidity in my mind to stop me from dating so much as lack of free time.
Rym: Lack of rigidity in other places?
Scott: No, but I have plenty of rigidity in many places.
Scott: But I do recognize that there are a lot of things where, like, I come up with like an obvious answer to my problem and then I sort of refuse to execute on that because I feel like it's cheating or I feel like it's sort of wrong.
Rym: You know, you're like.
Rym: you're like what you're like me when I was a kid and I play video games and I'd run into a boss and it'd be super hard and I couldn't beat him.
Rym: Like, it'd be really difficult.
Rym: But then there'd always be like I'd see the really cheap way to beat the boss, like, oh, if I just go around the back and grenade and then he'll die.
Rym: And I remember never wanting to do that.
Rym: And as a result, I never beat video games.
Rym: And then I found out later that all these games kind of expected you to do that.
Rym: And that was, in fact, the only way to beat those bosses.
Scott: Yeah.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: All right.
Scott: So you are you're you're a fancy lawyer.
Scott: I don't even know what.
Scott: actually, you know, there's a lot of lawyers who listen and talk in the forums and are on Friday night party line.
Rym: Did you forget which ones which?
Scott: No, no, I just it's like I know what kind of lawyer all the other lawyers are, but I don't know what kind of lawyer you are.
Guest: See, I can't really go into that because I do want to keep this Internet schizophrenia going.
Scott: That's fine.
Guest: And I the type of law that I do is highly specialized.
Guest: So if I go into it at all, I'd be easily spotted.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: And that really is an exciting area of law, like intellectual property, or is it or is it lame to normal people?
Guest: I'm not a litigator.
Guest: I started out doing commercial litigation.
Guest: I can talk about that.
Guest: I hated it because basically it's combative all the time.
Guest: You know, four thirty in a Friday afternoon, motions are coming in over the fax machine designed to ruin your weekend.
Scott: Are you at least sending out to ruin other people's weekends at the same time?
Guest: Oh, yeah, sure.
Guest: Yeah, yeah.
Guest: And doing all kinds of things.
Guest: And it's give and take, but I don't want that.
Guest: I'm not the kind of lawyer that wants to fight.
Guest: So, you know, I'd rather have everybody agree.
Guest: And so litigation is not for me.
Scott: Well, I mean, this sort of like this, I don't know, sort of cliche, you know, like, oh, lawyers, they're like the bane of existence.
Scott: You know, they make the world miserable.
Scott: So being a lawyer, I guess, is it, you know, do you sort of feel that like, you know, I'm you're evil or what?
Guest: Well, it's it's my evil.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: OK.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's sort of like, you know, it's like my uncle's a dentist.
Scott: So it's sort of like people dread, you know, the dentist.
Scott: So it's sort of, you know, he doesn't care.
Scott: But other other, you know, there's there is a high rate of like suicide among dentists.
Scott: And that has something to do with it.
Scott: So I was wondering if lawyer, you know, what kind of feelings you had being in a, you know, a member of a somewhat despised profession?
Guest: Yeah, I mean, you get that a lot and you just have to go with it.
Guest: I mean, the idea, the joke about the post office coming out with a commemorative stamp for lawyers, but they had to discontinue it because people couldn't figure out which side of the stamp to spit on.
Scott: I never heard that one.
Guest: You get you get you get that.
Guest: But, you know, what I do is helping people.
Guest: It's it's not combative.
Guest: So I don't I don't internalize that.
Guest: And I can always blame the plaintiff's lawyers for being the real cause of the problem.
Guest: But you know what?
Guest: It's like an onion.
Guest: If you peel that back, it's not really the plaintiff's lawyers.
Guest: They're the guns.
Guest: And it's the people that are that are unhappy, that are willing to sue and go through the incredible inconvenience and hassle that a lawsuit is just to have vengeance or make money or what have you.
Scott: So, you know, I'm sort of speaking for myself here, but it really feels like lately, especially with all the, you know, the the ways law and technology have been interacting, that, you know, law has become more important for a lot of people in their everyday lives.
Scott: But it's also, you know, incredibly complicated.
Scott: You have to go to school for years and years to even, you know, understand it.
Scott: And sort of in a situation where, you know, every day people have like lots of questions they want to ask lawyers.
Scott: But in order to get an answer, you have to pay someone like it's not it's not free.
Guest: Right.
Scott: So it seems like people, they want to follow the law or know it, but it's not something they can understand.
Scott: And it's like it really feels like you have to if you don't have a lot of money, you can't even know what the law is to follow it.
Scott: Do you get what I'm saying?
Guest: I guess, but most people have a working knowledge of the daily laws that they have to not violate to stay out of jail.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm talking about
Rym: actually, I would argue that maybe it's just geeks and technology people, but a lot of the things that I do on a daily basis get very close to gray areas of the law where I'm not sure anymore, because a lot of laws that relate to these areas just aren't clear.
Rym: And even our company lawyers are like, I don't know, I just don't know.
Rym: And there's there's not enough body of case law to kind of have a precedent or anything.
Rym: And the judges don't understand.
Rym: And there's no way in hell a jury's going to understand.
Rym: And I mean, I guess I should be the one who's out there as the expert witness.
Rym: But then all I'm doing is explaining the technology.
Rym: And then the lawyer still has to tell me what I like, how to translate what I just said into what the law says.
Scott: If you haven't guessed, I'm pretty much taking advantage of the fact that you're a lawyer and you're on the show to save myself some money.
Rym: So you're planning to to possibly break some laws, apparently?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Is it is it against the law for me to just if you just answer law questions for me?
Guest: Well, I'm not licensed in New York state, so I can't give you legal advice on New York law.
Guest: But we can talk about hypothetically and generally speaking.
Scott: That's good enough.
Rym: So how do you feel about we do it?
Rym: I want to derail.
Rym: We won't go on too long about this.
Rym: But there's a story recently about a guy who is taking photographs and he wasn't violating any laws.
Rym: He was taking them in a public place.
Rym: But the police harassed him.
Rym: I think they eventually arrested him and all this business.
Rym: And in the end, it was determined that he was not violating a single law.
Rym: And yet because the police neither the police nor him nor anyone involved until it got to court even knew the law or knew that whether or not there was even a law that covered the situation, that this person could be arrested for committing absolutely no crime.
Rym: And there was no even evidence that he committed a crime.
Guest: That's not surprising to me at all.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I don't know.
Rym: I don't really have a question.
Rym: What do we do about that?
Rym: Because technology is making it more easy to run into these situations like with photography.
Rym: How many pictures are taken in public constantly?
Rym: And it seems like no police officer in this country understands that it's legal to take a picture from public place as far as I'm aware.
Rym: And I'm not a lawyer.
Guest: You guys talked about this, right?
Guest: You mentioned the standard of reasonable expectation of privacy.
Guest: Someone said that.
Rym: Yeah, that's one of my hot buttons.
Rym: So it's one thing I actually did.
Rym: as much research as a non-lawyer can do.
Guest: You know, Ray from Friday Night Party Line is an expert on this area of law.
Guest: He is nationally known on this point.
Guest: But basically it is that, that reasonable expectation of privacy.
Guest: But at the same time, the police have immense power and they can always arrest you.
Guest: Just because you haven't actually broken the law, that'll get figured out later.
Guest: Maybe.
Guest: And if you have perfect faith in the system and then you don't use a lawyer to defend yourself, you're probably going to get convicted.
Guest: Really it's a power system, not so much a system of justice.
Guest: It's, so, you know, some of the stories you've told, Rym, about how you've pushed the envelope with police officers.
Guest: I would cringe when I heard it because you were counting on your rights to be upheld.
Guest: And they're really not, it's just, it's almost happenstance if that's actually how it's going to work out.
Rym: Yeah, sadly I've gotten to the point now where I'm of the mind that I should carry surveillance on me at all times so that if I have an interaction, let's say, with the police, there's some sort of external record of it to vindicate me in the future.
Guest: Well, often they are recorded themselves and the fastest way to get arrested is to start videotaping a police officer.
Guest: And in fact, that might be a good way to get tased too.
Scott: Even though it's perfectly okay.
Scott: I mean, where would Rodney King be if we weren't allowed to videotape police officers?
Guest: But yeah, we're supposed to have this, the First Amendment and everything else, so theoretically you should be able to, but in some states it's not legal to do that.
Scott: Are there any particular things in law that are like really, like they really bother you a lot?
Rym: I mean, you can avoid talking about things that might reveal your secret identity.
Guest: And I wish I didn't have to do the secret identity thing, but you know, if you work for a place that might care and I go out of my way to try to do what you do, Scott, and do something that would embarrass me.
Guest: But I'm a human being and I might make a mistake.
Guest: So I have the pseudonym as sort of an extra layer of protection.
Guest: That way I can have fun, you know, this being one of the few things I consider fun in life.
Guest: But yeah, the things that bug me, I mean, the whole copyright thing is really hard to understand.
Guest: This mux tape thing that's out now where you can upload your songs, create a mix and have other people listen to them, I'm waiting for that to just blow up because basically you could buy a new CD, put it up track by track and that, and then anybody in the world could listen to that CD.
Guest: Why would they buy it?
Guest: You're just using the internet as a giant hard drive for everybody to listen to.
Guest: They don't have to download it.
Guest: They can listen to it when they want to.
Guest: So that's going to go down.
Guest: They're going to attack that.
Guest: The RIAA has, is, you know, some of the things they want to put in place in terms of federal laws, they want to have a copyright czar who's on par with the war on drugs czar.
Guest: I mean, that's crazy.
Guest: They want to break down people's houses and see if you happen to copy an old video tape from 10 years ago.
Rym: This is why I've actually been very interested in, and I've asked a lot of people about how to do this before because I really want to be one of those expert witnesses for all these cases because I think I would enjoy it because I like to expound upon things that might make other people angry.
Guest: Unless you like being sodomized by lawyers because that's what they do to expert witnesses.
Guest: You have to be, I mean, the expert witnesses you see on TV, well, if it's a big enough case, they'll hire private investigators to follow you around to try to dig up details in your personal life.
Guest: They'll look at everything you've ever said in public or in private.
Guest: Masturbation episode of GeekNights, exhibit A in your testimony after you're done.
Scott: But how is that relevant to my computer knowledge?
Rym: Well, what if it's a case about pedophiles or something?
Scott: I'm not going to testify in a pedophile case.
Rym: But that's the most common case on the internet.
Rym: It's either that or it's copyright.
Scott: I guess.
Guest: So they would have a field day with you.
Scott: No, that's that's the kind of thing that bothers me is sort of like this.
Scott: You know, why are they attacking my character when I'm just there to tell them how computers work?
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: if I know computers work, what does it matter?
Scott: if I'm you know, what else is true about me?
Rym: Well, my real interest is that, you know, you brought up the RIAA and copyright, but as a technology professional and ignoring the legal aspect of it, from everything I've read about these cases, they've never presented technological evidence that was even close to being useful ever in any of these RIAA cases.
Guest: It's what they're talking about.
Guest: So they can fudge it.
Guest: If you can get in a courtroom and most of these are small state courtrooms and state court, you know, you don't want to be there.
Guest: if you don't have to.
Guest: And you're not going to have the high level of expertise that you will in federal court.
Rym: And I feel like this is a big problem.
Rym: I feel like if it like, in addition to having a jury of your peers, you should have the right to at least have an expert witness who understands the issue at hand in any court case.
Scott: I mean, like, you know, you have a jury, but if the case is about, you know, computers and no one on the jury has ever used a computer, how are they?
Scott: I mean, how are they my peers?
Scott: They're not.
Guest: It's just that's just jargon.
Guest: There's no such thing as peers, but they're going to, you know, Rym's on trial.
Guest: They're going to go out and find people, you know, 12 people with IQs of 140 plus who have technology backgrounds.
Guest: Wrong.
Guest: They're going to find people who can't figure out how to get out of jury duty.
Rym: The sad thing is I wanted to serve on jury.
Rym: Every time I'm called, I really want to serve on the jury and I do everything right.
Rym: And I'm there and I'm always immediately dismissed.
Rym: As soon as they like, look at me, they kick me out and I'm done.
Scott: It's just no good.
Rym: In fact, when I worked at the hospital, I was told.
Rym: basically I said, yeah, I'm a technology professional for a hospital.
Rym: They said, oh, you don't have to serve on a jury.
Rym: And they let me go.
Scott: Oh, well.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Do I have any other lawyer-y questions?
Scott: Well, it is, you know, it's like there's a whole.
Scott: It's like, I kind of.
Rym: So what's the legal distinction between flotsam and jetsam if we're in international waters?
Guest: I'm not a maritime lawyer.
Guest: You should have Carney on, though, because his perspective as a prosecutor is different than mine.
Scott: Maybe we will.
Scott: It could be pretty cool.
Scott: But yeah, it's like.
Scott: lately I've actually run into like a few sort of like situations where it's kind of like I need a lawyer.
Scott: Like we sort of want to officially make like a business like front row crew studios or something.
Scott: And we also kind of want to like buy a house.
Scott: But since there's a whole bunch of us, we might need like a real estate lawyer.
Scott: You know, it's like, how do I like find a lawyer?
Scott: How do I know I'm not getting ripped off?
Scott: How do I, you know, I don't know how to do any of those things.
Guest: The Bar Association will probably have a referral service.
Guest: At the very least, you can try that.
Guest: Talking to lawyers who know other lawyers is a very good way to find people.
Guest: You guys do like to do a lot of stuff yourself.
Guest: And they're, you know, certainly with setting up an LLC, you can probably do that yourself.
Guest: You can learn a lot just by going to the website for the Secretary of State.
Guest: And it's not hard and it's not expensive.
Guest: I just set up an LLC that's going to own Friday Night Party Line and anything else that I do online now.
Rym: Because actually the worst thing is.
Rym: that's what I was thinking.
Rym: Like, all right, LLC, whatever.
Rym: And then we got advice from people who kept saying, no, you got to make a Delaware whatever thing and you got to do this and that and issue stock and blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Then we run into the fact that with my job, I'm legally barred from having control over investments or owning stock or anything like that.
Rym: And there's all this trouble.
Guest: Business entities are very flexible.
Guest: If it turned out that you do your LLC just for tax purposes and then later if someone wants to buy it or they want to invest in it and they're out of state and there's SEC issues, you can convert it into another entity.
Guest: There are many, many things you can do and they're all very flexible.
Guest: So start out with what you can do now.
Guest: Set up an LLC, get a tax ID number, get a business account, get a PayPal business account and then you're good to go for pretty much anything for the next few years unless somebody is going to pay you $1.75 billion like CBS did for CNET.
Scott: I mean, if I had $1.75 billion, I would probably buy like a sports team, right?
Scott: Why would you buy CNET?
Scott: I don't get it.
Rym: Depends on the sports team.
Scott: It does.
Guest: Why is CBS bought CNET?
Guest: Because they're afraid.
Guest: All of the newspapers in the world are declining.
Guest: Nobody watches TV and when they do watch TV, they time shift it or they don't watch it at all anymore.
Guest: When you can watch anything you want at any time, you don't watch anything.
Rym: Well, I just feel like there's, I mean, this is a topic for a whole separate discussion, but I feel like in the next, God, I want to live a time frame.
Rym: I'd say within the next decade, definitely, there's going to be a rapid fundamental shift in the way media is presented and consumed.
Rym: I think it's going to, I think the ramifications are going to be far reaching and longterm and frightening to a lot of people.
Scott: I think we're definitely, you know, we're sort of climbing the roller coaster now and in a few years we're going to be going over the top and then it's downhill.
Guest: But CNET, according, you know, CBS looks at CNET and they say, okay, they're doing internet TV, they're doing IPTV, we'll buy them and then we'll have IPTV too.
Guest: But you know, are they doing it very well?
Guest: Do they really have that strong of a presence?
Guest: to what kind of credibility do they have?
Guest: I don't know.
Scott: Well, they've got, they've got a name seen as a somewhat well known name.
Guest: They're well known.
Guest: And if you pump a lot of money into it, I mean, they do things on a shoestring.
Guest: If you start pumping money into them, maybe, maybe that it'll, it'll do for CBS what CBS wants.
Guest: And I think that ultimately when people can watch videos and TV shows literally anytime they want to, when they're on a bus, when they're, you know, and there, and there's no iPod necessary, you know, there's no storage media.
Guest: Everything is, anything you could ever want is immediately delivered instantaneously.
Guest: Then, you know, that's probably what you're talking about, Scott.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it gets, it gets really tricky then.
Rym: Cause I, I, I'm still debating if I want to write an article or something about it, but it's not just that you have to compete with the other media out there and even not even talk about monetization.
Scott: Oh yeah, this is a great idea.
Scott: I love this.
Rym: You can't, we also now, every piece of media we make has to compete with every piece of media that ever came out.
Rym: And I'm thinking of titling this little short book.
Rym: Like you can't compete with the past.
Rym: I mean, there are more movies that have been made in the history of movie making that are probably worth for me watching to where.
Rym: if movies were not made for the rest of my life, I don't think I would run out of movies to watch.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's because back in, like when I was a kid, right, it, it pretty much, it costs something.
Scott: It was difficult to get anything, especially if it was old.
Scott: I mean, if something was old, it was incredibly difficult to get.
Scott: The only real stuff you can get was new stuff.
Scott: So it's pretty much if new stuff didn't come out, you really couldn't see anything.
Scott: Cause you would just be sort of quiet.
Scott: But now with you, not only do I have access to like all, everything that's new, but I have access to pretty much everything that has ever existed.
Scott: I mean, there's old TV shows, old comic books, old radio shows, old movies, old music, old everything, you know, for as long as humans have had recording technology, photographs, everything.
Scott: So there's so much that already exists and there is so much being created at any one time that the value of something new is significantly decreased because the supply of things in total is just so large that it's like, I don't need new things.
Scott: I can live on the old or the current.
Rym: I mean, I haven't even finished reading Herodotus or Xenophon, let alone.
Guest: You need an Amazon Kindle that lets you buy anything you ever wanted right now, anywhere you are, because it has the free wireless.
Rym: Actually someone, I'm at this training for this gigantic like enterprise thing I bought for work and all week and down on wall street actually.
Rym: And three of the guys, they all have Kindles and I got to play with it for a while.
Rym: They had lent me to, you know, Hey, check this out.
Rym: It's cool.
Rym: And I'm probably going to buy one as soon as like the next revision comes out, like revision two.
Scott: Yeah, I definitely, yeah.
Scott: If there's a revision two of the Kindle, I might go for it.
Guest: But yes, cause how many times have you wanted to book and not been able to get your hands on one here?
Guest: You know, when you guys are talking about the Prince of Nothing, oh, okay.
Guest: Touch three buttons and I have the copy.
Scott: I think it's relevant to bring up.
Scott: Remember in the Prince of Nothing episode, I talked about, you know, I was thinking of setting up an Amazon Associates thing, right?
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Well, I did.
Scott: And you know, all the links to the three Prince of Nothing books were Associates links.
Scott: And you know, I'm not, you know, I don't want to like, you know, I'm fully disclosing here.
Scott: We made a lot of money from that.
Scott: Like a lot, like I get paid the Libsyn bill and then more so.
Scott: And like if we sell one Kindle through Associates, we get like $40 per Kindle.
Scott: It's like ludicrous.
Scott: And I sort of don't feel bad doing that because it's like, you know, you people who click on those links and buy products are not paying anymore.
Scott: It's just we're basically taking money.
Scott: Amazon would have had an Amazon pocket.
Rym: The only reason it becomes, it would become bad would be if we started purposefully talking about things we wouldn't otherwise talk about and hyping them up just to get the link.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not, I'm not going to hype up Kindles just because I'll make $40 off of them, you know, even though, you know, it is somewhat enticing, but there's no way that's going to happen.
Scott: But yeah.
Guest: I reviewed HGTV on my blog and I got mad hits on it.
Guest: If I would have done that, I would probably have made thousands of dollars.
Scott: And I started looking around and there's actually a lot of websites have like these Associates programs, like Newegg has one, Right Stuff has one, Fun Again, which sells board games, has one, you know, I don't
Rym: think I'd go with Right Stuff because, well,
Scott: no, we can go to Amazon.
Rym: But I'm saying even with the whole, even with Amazon, when DVDs, I feel like Netflix is killing the anime DVD.
Scott: Maybe Netflix has a thingy.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Everyone already has Netflix.
Scott: I know, I know, I know.
Guest: But if you produce content, you should make money on it.
Rym: Yeah, but it's tricky because like the anime industry is a good example of this where, you know, you can't compete with the past.
Rym: and so much anime is being released in the US and as someone aptly put it, they try to make all their money selling DVDs.
Rym: But that's like the Wheel of Fortune trying to make money off of selling DVDs.
Rym: Like it's this disposable medium.
Rym: These are shows that air once a week and like everyone watches them and then they forget about them and no one watches them again.
Rym: They're like these serial million episode monstrosities and they make a ton of money in Japan with TV advertising and, you know, merchandising and all that stuff.
Rym: But in the US, they've got this market of.
Rym: they try to sell these DVDs and no one buys them.
Rym: and as huge anime fan as I am, I really never buy anime DVDs and there's no reason to because I can rent them perfectly legally.
Rym: I don't even need to steal them.
Rym: But as a result, the anime industry is collapsing.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of sad.
Scott: All right, it's getting a little... Do you want to end it here?
Scott: Do you got anything else?
Rym: I guess we could wrap it up.
Rym: We've gone on a good hour.
Scott: No, that's good.
Scott: I can go eat dinner.
Scott: So, Thade, is there anything like you particularly want to like promote?
Scott: Anything you want to, you know, tell people?
Guest: Oh, just Friday Night Party line because, you know, you guys have been a part of it and I hope that you'll continue to be a part of it as we really ramp things up in the next few months.
Guest: I don't want to go through the list of people that we've asked to be guests, but some of them have been on Oprah.
Scott: So it's not Tom Cruise, is it?
Guest: No, that would be interesting.
Guest: But I mean, the plan for Friday Night Party line is to monetize it to an extent only really to satisfy my own hobbyist interests of being able to afford to get high-end guests.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I have the opposite take of like.
Rym: I haven't been on it nearly as often as Scott, but I always want to because I would... Making money or whatever, it's just really fun to be on that show.
Rym: It's a lot more enjoyable than doing GeekNights.
Scott: That's the reason I do it.
Scott: I look at that topic list and I'm like, oh, man, I got something to say about that.
Scott: Everyone's going to hear it.
Scott: Yeah, it was great.
Rym: We'd love to have you on more often.
Rym: I want to set up some interesting topical round table.
Rym: I don't want to step on Friday Night Party line's toes.
Rym: Definitely want to go with a different kind of format.
Guest: Yeah, these podcasts are so personal that even if you had the exact same setup, it wouldn't be the same show because of your personality.
Rym: And again, that it's very hard to get a word in edgewise.
Guest: Yeah, right.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.