Scott: It's Monday March 3rd.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: What is?
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I Got an announcement to me.
Scott: Oh an announcement.
Scott: I'm gonna say something that I've been waiting.
Scott: perhaps I don't know if it's exactly six months But around six ish months to say.
Scott: I haven't said this in six ish months But I'm gonna say it now what I'll bet.
Rym: I'll bet an amount of money that I can preempt.
Rym: what you're about to say.
Scott: Oh, well shall we say it on perhaps the count of three one two three?
Scott: warm today Warm yesterday even warmer today.
Rym: I think woman is retired until about January.
Scott: January I think it's.
Scott: I think it's retired till like October I don't know last year.
Rym: I mean this year and last year didn't really get cold until January.
Scott: yeah one thing I realized though I have to go and get rid of these snow tires now and buy regular tires.
Rym: Yes, you do.
Rym: yep I gotta get my seven months behind Car inspected well do it and I gotta buy new tires And I gotta get the headlights fixed and the horn fixed.
Rym: you want to go to the tire this weekend Maybe but Saturday, we're probably gonna go see a show.
Scott: so you can go see a show and then go to the tire on Sunday.
Rym: Yeah, but the make I gotta go to a regular mechanic and most mechanics Don't know the tire guy actually does all that.
Rym: You know how much he charges for?
Rym: Non-trivial mechanic II stuff.
Scott: you could do your inspection.
Rym: No, we can't cuz it won't pass the inspection until I get a mechanic to fix the things.
Scott: Well that that's a separate problem.
Rym: I busted old car.
Scott: I can't help you with that.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta go to a real mechanic as in a shady mechanic.
Rym: That's how I got the car fixed before I drove into shady mechanic in Yonkers and said all right, dude Well think about shady mechanic in shady neighborhood.
Scott: He deals with far worse cars than yours.
Scott: Yeah, he deals with those cars that are like dragging mufflers on the ground.
Rym: I remember I drove in.
Rym: I'm like all right that headlight doesn't work And I don't know why can you fix it for cheap, and he's like well Do you want it to work and you want it to work well?
Rym: And I was like I wanted to pass an inspection to which he said a real inspection.
Rym: or you know I said a real inspection.
Rym: He said oh all right hundred bucks.
Rym: What okay, and then $100 later He fixed everything.
Rym: I don't know what he did, but he replaced the whole assembly from some other Sunfire that duct tape and oily rags.
Rym: He had some other Sunfire that someone had smashed So he just took the whole headlight assembly out of it.
Scott: probably that's it doesn't?
Scott: I guess that's pretty easy if you're a mechanic.
Scott: a yeah All right, so yeah, no not much else besides that.
Rym: no weekend was nice and relaxing.
Rym: I played some half-life too since I was booted into windows.
Rym: I yeah, I also played with my laptop a lot.
Scott: What sucked today is that in the morning?
Scott: I had like a sweater and a coat and then on the way home.
Scott: I was like ah shit I'm gonna carry this shit But that's the end.
Scott: the sweaters are going in the closet, and they're probably not coming out.
Rym: That's the one benefit of the.
Rym: never wear long sleeves ever unless I'm going to a formal ball.
Rym: Yeah, except for the it'll get cold because and you know what it's not cold in the office And when I'm outside of the office or outside of my house, we're in a coat.
Scott: Yeah, I have a coat sometimes not enough to be fully warm, and you don't have a good coat.
Rym: my coat is excellent All right, so what are you on the news?
Rym: I don't really.
Scott: I don't really have news so much and it's not really a geek bite because I great because they don't really have The product to review it.
Scott: I sort of want to do like a general Informative thing about a category of product that you may or may not know exists.
Scott: Uh-huh, yeah, I've been looking into these recently for many reasons and also you know some other my co-workers are also looking into them for various other reasons.
Scott: and Basically you know when you buy a desktop computer on Newegg right the motherboard you get is ATX form factor.
Scott: most likely you know.
Scott: And that's you know that's that's a set of specifications about where the screw holes are how big the motherboard is Where the things on the motherboard are located the what kind of power supply connector etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: right well there are other choices besides ATX such as ITX and also Nano ITX don't forget AT AT the old one and also Pico ITX.
Rym: Now I remember a long time ago.
Rym: I used to make jokes about how yeah, we should make Pico ITX and they get.
Scott: well they have Pico ITX.
Scott: yeah, it's a real thing basically little.
Scott: what these are is their motherboards But they're full computers.
Scott: They they have a CPU a sound card a video card Storage you know IO Connections a battery a network card usually pretty much everything or at least you know some sort of stripped-down Limited feature version of what a normal desktop computer has but very very small.
Scott: so you can go out and you can buy for usually under $400 a Computer that is wicked small like wicked small we're talking like a few inches by a few inches right uses very little electricity Makes no noise because it has no fans Usually uses flash, but you can use like compact flash or even a little laptop hard drive if you want.
Scott: but that'll make noise and heat and whatever and Is usually powerful enough to do a whole bunch of computing tasks?
Scott: I mean you can't play games on it.
Scott: obviously well I guess you could play minesweeper on it, but you could play doom - it's all you need.
Scott: you could probably play doom - on it.
Rym: Yeah, I can play doom - on a 486 with 4 megs of RAM.
Scott: You usually won't use this as a desktop computer.
Scott: what you'll use this for is say you want to have a monitor Hanging on the wall somewhere in your office That's showing like graphs of real-time data or You want to have a kiosk in the mall that people will come up to and there'll be some software on it running that they can interact with.
Scott: or You want to have a server in your house that runs DHCP DNS?
Scott: Maybe a little web server, maybe a little SSH Maybe a firewall something like that stuff that isn't to you know processor or performance intensive.
Rym: You're not running the raid 5.
Rym: San off of this thing.
Scott: no no we're just talking about you know just Software that will run on pretty much any computer of any performance.
Scott: you can run it on a really tiny quiet relatively cheap Computer that you can just sort of hide away and doesn't use much electricity.
Scott: You know no reason to.
Scott: I mean you could scrap together parts and build like a $50 computer.
Scott: You know that's just.
Scott: but it'll be some old-ass giant desktop making lots of noise heat and using a lot of electricity.
Scott: so I Just want to make people aware that these products exist that there are.
Scott: There's actually there used to be.
Scott: these used to be really expensive and they used to be not a lot of choice.
Scott: and most Of them were for you know industrial purposes.
Scott: You know like use it in a factory, and it's in some case That's like wicked.
Scott: You know durable and invincible.
Scott: So you saw the factory explodes it'll be okay, or if acid gets on it.
Scott: It'll be okay, but now this you know more.
Scott: You know consumer type ones, and you can customize them for all sorts of uses and these will be useful for many people.
Scott: You can do Linux Windows pretty much any OS except.
Scott: I guess Mac OS.
Scott: That's not gonna work, but yeah be aware of these.
Scott: they may be good for you.
Rym: so in actual news There's a bunch of tech news last week, and I had to actually pick and choose.
Rym: There's a lot here.
Rym: There's also a lot of meat space news going on with the let's say the the fun with our friend You go Chavez down south save your meat space news for Thursday.
Rym: always a riot that guy.
Rym: Anyway, I will talk about that later cuz I actually got a lot to say about this and hopefully by Thursday We'll know if this leads to war in South America or not.
Rym: Yeah Nothing bad could ever happen with South American war.
Rym: Luckily, there's no chance of a CIA intervention or anything.
Rym: is there's not like we've ever done that before no CIA in South America intervening in some sort of Military operation possibly involving some sort of industrial complex?
Scott: I never heard of such a thing,
Rym: but this news might seem a little off the wall But I think it's warranted because we talk a lot about technology And I think we even did a show about how there are a lot of problems in the world that if you applied a little Bit of common sense and a little bit of properly put together technology these problems could be alleviated trivially.
Rym: There is a kind of annoying problem in the world, and I've run into this a lot.
Rym: I'm sure a lot of you fly have that it takes for fucking ever to get people onto a plane.
Rym: Yeah, an airport and they line people up but people don't line up and they call people up in certain orders and all this business.
Rym: and There have been a lot of studies about the fastest way to load a plane.
Scott: I think the number one problem right is that people get on the plane and they get to their seat And they don't step out of the aisle quick enough.
Scott: They'll stay in the aisle try to get their stuff in the overhead bins, which they're not good at at all.
Scott: Right, they have no skill at loading the overhead bins And then everyone basically who needs to get past them stands in the aisle behind them not moving and it takes forever.
Rym: Now wouldn't?
Rym: wouldn't an obvious way to get around this be to load the plane from the back to the front?
Rym: So there's no way anyone could be blocking they else.
Scott: they do this.
Rym: most airports Don't see?
Scott: when I when I get on it like a jet blue plane, right?
Scott: They'll say everyone is sitting in rows like 20 through 25.
Scott: Please come up right.
Scott: and the problem is of course someone in row 20 gets on before the 25 people right and is really slow at putting their luggage up or the person with the Window seat gets on before the person with the aisle seat.
Scott: I mean You know vice-versa.
Scott: so the aisle person keeps the window person out and then people have to get out and then back into their seats.
Rym: Well, I'll put it this way Two studies at least have shown that the the Average way that the average airline in the u.s.
Rym: Loads planes is close to the worst possible way You could do it in terms of efficiency Alrighty, and that the best way to do I never really.
Scott: I have flown maybe twice in my life on non jet blue So I don't know much about any other airline.
Rym: I've only actually flown jet blue once and if you're going somewhere jet blue goes and you're not a business traveler who wants some nice Like first-class whatever.
Rym: it's pretty nice and a lot of the problems of other airlines go away.
Scott: The only other airline I've ever heard that is very nice Is that is the Virgin Airlines and from what I've gathered to go to like if I was going to UK I'd probably take them.
Rym: from what I've gathered almost every airline that flies around Europe is awesome compared to most us.
Scott: Oh, yeah, like I always see like ads for Lufthansa and it looks so nice.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: That's like first class.
Scott: I saw I saw a YouTube video of the inside of first class of an airplane going to Dubai Man, yes, if they had more gadgets built into that first-class seat than we have in this whole house You know what?
Rym: I could imagine I wouldn't be surprised if I were to Bay.
Rym: I would simply state that you can't have coach and still fly into our airport because obviously those people can't afford to be here pretty much next up Monaco.
Rym: but no the Deal here is that they've pretty much determined that if you just force everyone to line up in order By row ahead of time before the plane is ready to be loaded or At least half the people load out like make them stand in line in order.
Rym: if you're not in the right place You have to wait till everyone else is on board punish him in that way and then just load people row by row seat by seat Strict order.
Rym: No one gets any say no one gets any sort of special treatment.
Scott: Well, that's another thing.
Scott: Is that a lot even on jet blue?
Scott: what they do and I think it's an FAA regulation is they say anyone who needs help?
Scott: Getting on the plane get on first, right and they take care of you like if you're an old person who can't walk or if you have a wheelchair or if you have a baby or something.
Scott: and Really when you think about it, it would be more optimal to have those last people unless put them on first.
Rym: Actually, I read an article that said just as much.
Rym: Yeah, because they go one else in the way.
Rym: No one moving.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much those people right?
Scott: It's it's tough to get them on it takes some time.
Scott: So what you do is instead of putting them on first forcing everyone else you can get on quickly to wait.
Scott: You let everyone get on real quick Then you get the slow people on and then you go and there's no there's no delaying the quick peep You know, there's no chance of the slow people holding up the quick people.
Rym: now sadly while this article is all like on all these Articles.
Rym: Yeah, you could really super efficient eyes.
Rym: I like that.
Rym: I'm gonna say that word more often.
Scott: There really isn't another word for that.
Scott: I needed to say if she buys Okay, no, but demise is close.
Scott: Well, you have to say optimize the efficiency, you know It's like a two-word saying optimize the efficiency just reeks of Utilizing the buzz and see ya maximize the okay.
Scott: Yes, so we need a new.
Scott: we need to efficient eyes.
Scott: I think has to be a word now the the real.
Rym: I mean this article like oh, yeah, we could do this, but The the studies do overlook one important thing
Scott: a human psychology the fact
Rym: that When you fly and I've seen this every time ever flown It seems that the majority of the people getting on the plane are Families who have probably never flown before or in the very least don't fly often.
Scott: Yeah a lot See, it's like Pete.
Scott: you can tell like it's the same thing like in New York City, right?
Scott: You can tell tourists apart from business people I remember there are.
Rym: when we say tourists we're using the derogatory term because there are people who technically are tourists who are not in fact Tourists,
Scott: right but you can tell like a businessman He goes whoosh right down the street walks right into the subway gets right on the subway car gets right off Goes in the right direction all the time.
Rym: He got he dodges around people and he just puts his bag up sits down.
Scott: He's asleep before you even seem that right.
Scott: but the tourists like they'll walk though.
Scott: They'll walk side by side blocking the sidewalk They'll walk down the street and then suddenly stop in their tracks.
Rym: So worse and behind the bumping into the words to the people in DC on those long-ass Escalators who'll just stand right in the middle.
Rym: Oh, you mean us.
Rym: You see luckily there were many people around now when we did that and we did it knowing that it was a bad thing to Do.
Scott: yeah, but you know It's in general people who are don't fly often get in the way of the people who do fly often just like people in New York City who aren't there often get in the way of me every day.
Rym: Yeah, out of my way.
Rym: The thing is flying if you look at it.
Rym: It's not like it's a cryptic thing I mean if you don't know how the New York City subway works Or even if you've never taken like a New York Metro North kind of train before No one's there to help you you kind of have to figure it.
Rym: I mean if you ask someone they'll tell you like oh, this is the train to blah blah blah and everyone's super nice.
Rym: but well if you just show up on a platform you just show up on this platform and it says This is the name of the platform and trains are coming in both directions and you know, which ones?
Scott: what you know What I think, you know Really the most efficient way to deal with the airplane boarding problem.
Scott: is that just?
Rym: it's not even something People consider have classes in high school to teach people how to get on a goddamn plane.
Scott: That would be I guess maybe help but no check this out.
Scott: when you go to an airport Right, you go through security and then the plane usually is already there at the gate connected to the gate, right?
Scott: And they make you wait there like out, you know in the airport terminal for a while Right, and it's just pretty much.
Scott: then they say okay now we're all gonna get on the plane.
Rym: Well, a lot of that is FAA regulations exactly cleaning the plane usually getting it ready Right, right, right, but basically they get you.
Scott: they don't start boarding the plane till like, you know a few minutes Maybe ten minutes at most before it's going to leave.
Rym: Usually the plane actually isn't ready until then even so a lot of times.
Scott: It's like it's just sitting there.
Scott: You know, it looks pretty ready to me.
Scott: You can sit in it while they're fueling it.
Scott: You can sit in it while they're all you can't.
Scott: why not?
Scott: There's rules against that.
Scott: I know there are rules against it But why actually there's rules against that?
Rym: on a lot of buses too.
Rym: Anyone who's taking a long bus trip in America has learned that if you get on the wrong bus They'll stop every time to get gas Wake everyone up make him get off and stand out in the cold While they drive the bus over and fill it up drive it back and let you back on.
Scott: Why can't you sit on it while it's fueling?
Rym: there's rules about that.
Scott: That's a rule that makes no sense.
Rym: Does it might blow up?
Scott: Oh, it's gave it has gas in it.
Scott: Anyway, it might blow up.
Scott: Anyway, it's not gonna.
Rym: there's no more risk of blowing up while fueling then Something and this is definitely not a blanket like this is not a truth of the world because there are people have legitimate uses for these things and there are circumstances where they're warranted.
Rym: but multiple people have pointed out on slash job and I've seen this sentiment elsewhere that the best way to make airlines more efficient would be to ban Anyone who shows up with wheelies on their baggage if the baggage is smaller than a gigantic bag.
Scott: I agree with that.
Rym: Like if the bag is smaller than your torso and it has wheels Just ban him from flying.
Scott: If your bag has wheels and you aren't checking it, then it shouldn't have wheels.
Scott: If it has wheels, it's not a carry-on.
Rym: If you can't carry it, it's not a carry-on.
Scott: and if you can carry it It shouldn't have wheels because you can carry it.
Rym: actually though I think pursuant to all that if you think about it another big problem You see a lot of people have carry-on that like I actually check like I look at the dimensions I make sure my carry-on is like within the legal.
Rym: like this is what you can bring.
Scott: I only ever carry on stuff I actually need on the plane.
Rym: Well actually before all these BS rules about can't have toothpaste or whatever I would never check bags when I flew because I didn't need that much.
Rym: I'd bring the two carry-ons I'm allowed.
Rym: one was full of all my stuff But if it within the thing and one was full of all my entertainment for the flight And then I didn't have to deal with bag check or anything in and out See thing is thing is you know.
Scott: after you know, because I flew quite often when I was in college But you know back and forth from Rochester Checking I would always check exactly one bag and carry on my backpack.
Scott: and that's what I would do.
Scott: the same exact thing every time Right, and it was always cake because I would just I knew exactly what to do.
Scott: I'd walk up I would just dump my check bag.
Scott: I'll give them my ID and my ticket.
Scott: They would go.
Scott: Yep Yep, they would ask me all the questions.
Scott: I would say yes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: No, right I would just walk over to the security go right through and get on the plane Get off the plane go wait on the little conveyor belt.
Scott: My bag would usually come out in like 10 minutes grab and go and that was it.
Scott: it was.
Rym: but then again I mean I flew a bunch of other airlines and I never had a problem with jet blue But I've only flown him once.
Rym: so I can't but a lot of times I'd show up and that the line to even check a bag would be like 45 minutes long.
Scott: There's sometimes there would be a line to check the bag But you got it, you know you get there early enough.
Scott: and the worst thing That's only really crazy holidays and really easy time blue.
Rym: when I flew to Arizona, right?
Rym: It wasn't.
Rym: it wasn't even a full flight.
Rym: I had a full row to just kind of sprawl out and go on the way home and everything.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: but yet when I got back to JFK I had to stand there for an hour before my bag showed up.
Scott: That's a long time.
Scott: Usually I've never had to wait that long.
Rym: Well, I've had to wait that long 50% of the times.
Rym: I have no jet blue Oh yeah, but I find this article interesting because basically the gist of it is just that there are more efficient ways to do this and Airlines by and large don't.
Rym: and the main reason they don't is because public perception is Kind of wrong and like people would like if you did it the intelligent way people would complain.
Rym: So they do it the way.
Rym: that's not intelligent but looks intelligent to people who are dumb and as a result Everyone's mildly angry, but I guess that's better than people being more angry But actually getting on the plane because you change anything people will be angry.
Scott: if it had been a different way This whole time, you know.
Scott: Then if you change it to the way it is now people would be angry.
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: it has nothing to do with the way it actually is.
Scott: Let's do it.
Scott: the fact that you're changing something.
Rym: Therefore people get upset no matter what you change, of course There's also the idea that if you just say alright go and let everyone just get on the plane willy-nilly It's still faster than the way they do it now.
Scott: So that's I'm saying they should just let everyone.
Scott: you know, as soon as the plane is ready Just let anyone get on the plane whenever they want and then the plane takes off at the scheduled time.
Scott: If you're not on the plane, fuck you.
Rym: Yeah, the problem with that however, is that a lot of times people are making a connecting flight and if the airline screws someone else over If your plane if your plane is delayed and you don't make the connecting flight.
Scott: Oh, well, that's your you know You bought a connecting flight.
Scott: You knew that that was a risk and you I just had to take the next plane.
Rym: Yeah, but the one time that happened to me that the flights were two hours apart and yet the plane still fucked me.
Scott: Well Hey, that's that's that's a risk you take when connecting flights.
Scott: get a direct flight.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes it's not a more for a direct flight to reduce risk.
Rym: I actually know a lot of times direct flights are cheaper if you get them early enough.
Rym: It was more that there were no direct flights.
Scott: Well, then what can you do?
Rym: Never fly to Detroit ever?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Can we move on?
Rym: I think we can.
Rym: so things of the day.
Rym: I'm sure Scott the other Scott will be pleased with this and I'm also pleased with this because I rather enjoyed it.
Rym: and even if you do not know anything about the subject at hand I recommend you take this quiz because by and large the second hint is always hilarious.
Scott: I I don't know much about the subject matter But the quiz gives you so many blatant obvious hints that it's really stupidly easy.
Rym: This is a pretty cool quiz though.
Rym: It is the booze test and I'll warn you.
Rym: I got almost a perfect score.
Rym: I don't know what that says about me.
Scott: I don't think it's that I mean I would have if I had taken the test.
Scott: I would have gotten close to a per.
Rym: no you wouldn't know because you wouldn't have gotten them all.
Rym: on the first question Basically you get four hints and there's a list of answers and You can either guess or get the next hints or guess or get the next hint.
Scott: So every time you get a hint here, you just not didn't get a perfect score.
Rym: Yeah, you keep going down All right.
Rym: So if you get a very high score on this, you're probably in the Rym realm of alcohol usage.
Rym: But I'll give you so I'll go through the Thunderbird wine.
Rym: This is it's a really fun really well done quiz like.
Rym: here's an example.
Rym: the first question clue number one I am made with the flowers and leaves a medicinal plant called wormwood.
Rym: now Anyone who drinks should know immediately what that is.
Scott: or anyone who reads I do not know I do not know what alcohol is is made of fermented wormwood.
Scott: I'll be honest.
Rym: now You should because it's all it's pretty cool.
Rym: Now.
Rym: The next clue is a picture of absinthe.
Scott: oh I guess it's absent.
Rym: Yes now that is only if you know That it is absinthe.
Scott: But how would I tell it?
Scott: What does it look like?
Rym: It's bright green with that special spoon.
Rym: anyone who's read anything about?
Rym: Bohemia or any?
Scott: I might.
Rym: that might be Moulin Rouge if you've ever.
Rym: you'll know.
Scott: a green liquid with a spoon might get me to Guess absinthe.
Scott: What's the next hint?
Scott: The next one is I'm illegal in the United States, which is not true anymore And that would have tipped me off immediately because I knew that that was an urban legend and I would I would complain and I Would get that.
Scott: and then I'm because it is multiple choice, right?
Scott: I don't have to type in absinthe absinthe one of the available choices.
Scott: Yes Yeah, so I would ease I would get that.
Scott: on the second or third one green fair.
Rym: now I think the best one is The kamikaze they drink.
Rym: and the first hint is like, you know, it's made of blah blah blah.
Rym: The second hint is a picture of a kamikaze attack from World War II and it's multiple choice.
Scott: Yeah, there's no way you can miss that.
Scott: or like if you do nothing about alcohol You couldn't miss the gin.
Rym: The first one is like, you know, I'm flavored with juniper berries.
Rym: All right, that's how I knew because I freaking love juniper berries.
Rym: number two is a picture of one of those beef eaters.
Rym: It's like okay talk about easy Yeah, but if anyone else gets a near-perfect score, my head is off to you.
Scott: Well, you just give them a bunch of answers.
Rym: They will not get a perfect score if they do not actually know about alcohol.
Rym: All right, if you say so This is pretty fun though.
Rym: Check it out.
Scott: Okay, so I recently discovered this little open-source project from Sun Microsystems no less.
Scott: Sun Microsystems actually Java's looking better and better every day.
Scott: I'll talk about that sometime in the future, but I'll leave it at that for now.
Scott: Sun is doing some good stuff.
Scott: They're sort of they're rebounding at least in my eyes.
Scott: Anyway, they have a project.
Scott: It's open source called project dark star.
Scott: Sounds pretty cool, huh?
Scott: Well, what now go on?
Scott: you don't think dark star is cool.
Rym: the name dark star is amazing.
Scott: All right, that's what I'm talking about.
Scott: So this project dark star The goal of this project is is basically the thing I find most interesting about it Is it doesn't seem to have any competition, right now?
Scott: Basically, what it is is it's an.
Scott: it's a multiplayer Game server engine.
Scott: So it's not actually a game engine.
Scott: It won't help you with you know, making your game or your 3ds or anything like that.
Scott: It helps you with making your game server.
Scott: So if you want to make a game, you know, most likely an MMO that's sort of what it's designed for.
Scott: Where any game where there are lots of players sharing, you know the same space the same resources.
Scott: this project dark star is a server framework that will allow you to easily develop and deploy a server that can handle that.
Scott: and you know It's still not you know production worthy yet But in the future it their goal is to have it be very scalable.
Scott: so you know making an MMO game is very expensive and one of the most expensive parts is making the server and getting all the servers up and whatnot.
Scott: and if there is sort of this, you know one really good platform for developing those servers and handling them then that could significantly decrease the costs of Making and running MMOs and maybe you could do away with like, you know The monthly fees or at least severely lower the the fees to the players.
Rym: or maybe someone awesome would take this sort of thing And make an MMO because we've hinted at this a little bit in the forums.
Rym: That is not an RPG or no.
Rym: No, maybe you see the problem.
Rym: Is that?
Rym: and memorpica, you know MMORPG and MMO and RPG have all kind of turned into very specific genres, even though originally I mean a role-playing game was a game where I play a role And it's kind of gotten to the point where role-playing games have so little role-playing and you're
Scott: heading.
Rym: you're heading to Tuesday territory Yes, but I mean it's relevant in science in computing.
Rym: One of the most important things is having a shared useful nomenclature.
Rym: I mean this is why we had the debate over Pluto and Scientists said Pluto is not a planet.
Rym: and anyone who disagreed with that statement who is not a scientist is a moron.
Rym: because basically Calling Pluto a planet makes the term planet useless.
Rym: because by if Pluto is a planet then there are hundreds of other things That are equally as useless as Pluto that also have to be called planets or else We've just diluted the term planet to be useless to scientists.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, well, you know if we decide that you know, it's like a meter is exactly this long.
Scott: if we decide Oh, well, that's a meter too for sentimental reasons.
Rym: Well now the term meter is useless in you know scientific discussions I feel like the term MMO is useless now because most people know MMO means a grind based Massively multiplayer stateful avatar game.
Scott: Do you really you really think so?
Scott: Cuz I think a morpiga is definitely, you know, but well, I think MMO.
Rym: I think common parlay parlance.
Rym: Most people say MMO to mean World of Warcraft I think.
Scott: I think you may be right there.
Scott: But I also think that if someone were to specifically say MMO FPS or MMO RTS or MMO something else that or MMO puzzle All right that people would you know not associate it with more paga?
Rym: Well, I guess I feel that if we don't change course soon that will no longer be true And MMO will be a genre in and of itself.
Rym: I think that I think as opposed to what it should be which is just a medium.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much Ah, it just does.
Rym: but it bothers me too that even mmorpg the word RPG is useless to describe a game nowadays.
Scott: Well, I think that the term RPG, you know The everything that is called an RPG has the common ancestor of Dungeons & Dragons and its ancestors.
Scott: But or you know Final Fantasy all these sorts right, but if you look something like Final Fantasy 12, what is Final Fantasy 12?
Scott: Well, it's a movie and you push buttons to see the next part of the movie and there's a little bit of exploring and such.
Rym: Yeah, we're not saying there's anything wrong with that but how is that?
Rym: the same as burning wheel or as a role-playing game where you play a character and There's a lot of dialogue based decision-making and reactions and you play a role in a story?
Scott: Yeah, they're completely different things yet.
Scott: You call them both RPGs.
Scott: That's like, you know if I have a Piece of paper and I have a bomb like a bowling ball can I just thought is something weird?
Scott: and then I call them both carrots.
Rym: It's like if I have an analogy and I just take as crazy as I possibly can go.
Scott: I have an analogy and I tried to make it silly.
Scott: But anyway, this this project dark star seems like it's pretty cool.
Scott: And I think it will encourage many people who you know Might otherwise veer away from developing MMO type games because of the difficulty in time and expense involved.
Scott: Now pretty much all you have to do is you get this project dark star.
Scott: you set your server up And then you can develop the client end of your game in sort of any platform you choose.
Scott: you know, you could take the unreal engine you could take the source engine, you know, whatever and You can make the client end.
Scott: So people you know who were formerly making like half-life mods or something.
Scott: if they take this It won't take much more work or at least add the amount of work It would take otherwise to make say an MMO source mod.
Scott: So we're gonna see a lot of I think quality MMO games coming out maybe if people recognize this project.
Rym: So I guess I'll introduce what's about to happen because we came up with something We've a long time.
Scott: We're gonna try this out do a little dueling new thing.
Rym: We're gonna do this for four Mondays in a row and then we'll probably take a break from it go back to our usual fair and then we'll try to come Back to this and hopefully we'll build up some other Monday fair in.
Rym: You got some I got some but anyway, the idea here is that for a long time?
Rym: We've been avoiding certain topics largely because either myself or Scott are an expert on it or know a lot about it But the other of the two of us doesn't know so much about it.
Scott: We've also been sort of avoiding these topics because we sort of always try to veer away from going too deep too technical and fear of scaring away some people who might not want to be so Technical, you know if I start talking about like the nitty-gritty of like different memory management algorithms
Rym: Start explaining exactly what the OID take trees are in SNMP.
Scott: Yeah, if I start, you know explaining, you know, why.
Scott: you know the big O scheduler in the Linux kernel versus You know that the new scheduler is one is better than the other.
Rym: I start explaining the intricate details of why it sucks to Synchronize time and a virtualized machine.
Scott: It's gonna be a snooze fest
Rym: yes, but I think we realize is if we kind of get away from this fear of Going into topics where really only one of us has a lot to say and the other person is kind of the passive voice And if we alternate it between CS and IT effectively We can probably get some really interesting shows out of this.
Scott: All right, we think we will.
Scott: it's worth a try, right?
Scott: It's It's it's a free show.
Scott: We're making here.
Scott: We can make it everyone's.
Rym: we're pushing 500 episodes here.
Scott: So I think we're running out of ideas Not terribly.
Scott: We just came up with a bunch of new ideas and this is one of them.
Rym: so yeah but I think also the I the fact that I think we can keep this interesting because we're gonna get into a lot of kind of Real like awesome detail and deep depth, but at the same time or relatively deep depth not gonna go too deep.
Rym: I think we can keep it interesting especially because there will always be one of the two of us who is not 100% together with all of this and might ask the questions that you at home are thinking What about blah?
Rym: Scott will say something about object-oriented something something.
Rym: I'll go.
Rym: was it was it?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So today we're gonna Scott's turn.
Scott: It's my turn.
Scott: basically, you know, I realize I'm Programmed for a living.
Scott: I've been programming computers technically Speaking since kindergarten when I was using logo, right?
Rym: Programming is always turn the turtle into a helicopter.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good one, but Programming computers is pretty much how I do.
Scott: That's how I make money is?
Scott: it's how I live.
Scott: I went to school for it And I've been taking classes on it for even longer than you know, I technically went to school for it.
Scott: I've been doing it for mad long and I've done how many episodes of GeekNights and we've actually only done one show on Computer programming yet and it was how to get into computer programming.
Scott: I didn't even actually talk about programming itself or anything like that.
Scott: So I figure what now I will do is I'm gonna do a show on what is programming because a lot of people are interested in it, but not many people really know.
Scott: even people who are Programming don't really understand what they're doing, you know conceptually and for reals.
Rym: Yep I mean, it's kind of I'll say this cuz.
Rym: I had a revelation Early on in my IT career when I was I was trying to learn some programming language to do some crap for a class Even this is back when I was working at IBM and I was still going to RIT and I was trying to program something.
Rym: I'm making this program.
Rym: It's getting bigger and bigger and it's complicated and it's frustrating and I'm having trouble with it.
Rym: and then I thought and Much like when I played initial D the arcade game and I was trying to drift and do all this fancy stuff and learn all The craziness and then I thought I was like, wait a minute.
Rym: All I really want to do is get down the hill as fast as possible.
Rym: Doesn't matter it.
Rym: I'm trying to do something.
Rym: Why don't I just do it?
Rym: then I looked at my code I said why don't I just do it?
Rym: and the end result is what I wanted?
Rym: and I did it.
Rym: and then I learned a Lot more by thinking about what I wanted to get done as opposed to thinking about anything else.
Scott: Yep Alright, so before I start talking about what computer programming is I gotta talk about what a computer is.
Scott: We may have talked about this before but it bears repeating because we if we did talk about it before is only once.
Rym: also I think Scott's going to talk about it in a in a way that will be very very I don't know.
Scott: I like how we're met in this episode because it's such a test.
Scott: Anyway, so Rym what do you think a computer is?
Scott: why a computer is a very complex machine that adds Are you purposefully giving the wrong answer or do you know the the right answer?
Rym: Let me get that.
Rym: I was.
Rym: is a very complex machine that the complexity exists solely to do a very simple thing Over and over again billions and billions of times.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: Yeah, that simple thing is to add a.
Scott: That's not a computer.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, that could be a subset of computer.
Scott: A computer is a device any device any.
Scott: it could be mechanical.
Scott: It could be electrical It could be anything into which you input some information.
Scott: somehow the machine then Processes that information and has a deterministic output based on that input.
Scott: that is what a computer for you.
Rym: fancy-fancy think.
Rym: wait But what about a?
Rym: no you're wrong because if you made it there was some initial input.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much and if there's no output it effectively doesn't exist, yep.
Scott: So yeah, you could have a computer that say well an abacus is not a computer.
Scott: An abacus is not a computer because there is no processing.
Scott: the abacus that you know It doesn't you?
Scott: you input you move the little guys around right?
Scott: I don't really actually know how to use an abacus.
Rym: I'm sorry and abacus is more like data storage for the brain that does the process.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you move things around But it doesn't actually Process anything.
Scott: there's no output.
Scott: It's like you move a guy up and the rest of the guys are down.
Scott: Well, that's it.
Scott: It's the end of the road.
Rym: What about say a clockwork mechanism to calculate where the planets will be in the sky?
Scott: That is indeed a computer.
Scott: you would you would input the you know, the time and the date right of you know when you wanted to what you know time and date you wanted the stars to look like and then You would push a button or crank a lever or something and it would move the planets and stars around and it would show You the output where the planets and stars will be on the given date and time, you know an astrolabe That's.
Scott: that is a computer I guess a Pocket calculator.
Scott: That's a computer, right?
Rym: Oh my computer.
Scott: Oh, yeah your computer your computer It's a computer.
Scott: right all these things are computers, right?
Scott: but many computers right are not Programmable computers.
Scott: for example, we just talked about a machine that would say, you know Do show you where these stars in the sky are.
Scott: or a pocket calculator, right?
Scott: Well a pocket calculator it does one thing it calculates, you know one plus one equals, right?
Scott: You can't change what it does.
Scott: It is programmed already to do one thing and only one thing.
Scott: You know, it might be do a complex thing like a pocket calculator or even a graphing calculator.
Scott: Of course many graphing calculators are programmable.
Scott: So that's that's sort of a bad point, but a scientific calculator not very programmable Really?
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: So What is the difference between a programmable computer and a non programmable computer?
Scott: Well, let us consider say a light switch, right?
Scott: You could almost say that a light switch combined with a light is a computer.
Scott: you have input switch up switch or switch up or down and Output.
Scott: the processing is just see.
Scott: the thing is there's no processing in a light switch.
Scott: It's just sort of direct, you know, which is what sort of rules it out.
Scott: But let's say you had two switches that controlled one light.
Scott: That would be a computer.
Scott: You know if you could be set to where you know.
Scott: It's only odd.
Scott: the light only turns on if both switches are up, right?
Scott: Okay, you hardwire that in.
Scott: you can you connect electrical wires so that two switches are up.
Scott: the light turns on any other configuration The light is not on.
Scott: that's a computer.
Scott: There is a tiny amount of processing the figuring out if both switches are up or not and the output the light turning on, right?
Scott: But let's say you want to have a programmable light switch computer.
Scott: well, and what you do is you add two more switches and What happens is those two switches?
Scott: basically, you can have it set where if the two additional switches are both up that means the light will turn on if the Original two switches are both up and if the two additional switches are down Then the light will only turn on if the two additional switches are down.
Scott: You have more inputs additional inputs and those additional inputs change the nature of the processing.
Scott: The processing can be modified with more input.
Scott: So you instead of just having input that is then processed and outputted you have input to modify the processing itself And then the input and then the output.
Scott: so you can have one machine that can actually Do different things because you can modify what it's doing.
Scott: You could say have a pocket calculator right and then modify it so that the plus button Actually is a minus button in the minus buttons a plus button.
Scott: You just changed the processing in the calculator.
Scott: Yet, it's still a computer and it's still computing but it's programmable because you can change what it does.
Scott: Now Let me go a little deeper into how we do this.
Scott: go deeper go deeper, right?
Scott: So you have your Pentium chips right now, how does the Pentium chips work?
Scott: Well, the Pentium chip understands instructions, right such as you could tell it to add.
Scott: You know inside of the chip is a very small amount of memory and registers.
Scott: But don't worry about I'm just gonna say registers.
Scott: if that bothers you It's just memory in the chip.
Scott: You could tell it to say take the data in register 1 and add it to register 2. right you could tell it to erase register 2. you could tell it to Look at the number in register 1 and that number is an address in the RAM.
Scott: Go to the RAM and get the data at that address and put it in register 3. you know you.
Scott: these are the kinds of instructions you can give to the chip and The way you give it these instructions is binary.
Scott: it for example the instruction to you know move Some data from one place to another right is actually, you know is like the move instruction is zero zero one zero one One zero one zero one.
Scott: I just made something up, but that binary string that number is the instruction.
Scott: So you input that number and the chip goes aha That number is the move instruction and then you tell it the next number that comes in and it goes aha that is what I am moving from.
Scott: and then the next number that comes in it goes aha, that's where I'm moving to and That's how you these chips work.
Scott: is there either?
Scott: You turn the chip over and there's all these pins.
Scott: right those pins take zeros and ones.
Scott: That's all they can go on those pins electricity or not electricity and the instructions are all you know.
Scott: If you have a 32-bit processor these instructions are 32 bits long.
Scott: You can have a lot of instructions because you can have 2 to the 32nd power.
Scott: different instructions you can have.
Scott: they don't have that many, but you could and These instructions are what we call the assembly language.
Scott: That is what you know.
Scott: people talk about assembly all the time And how it's so hard machine machine code because it's the code of the machine.
Scott: you're literally Talking to the processor.
Scott: It's as if the processor had 32 levers and you were putting the levers up and down and then pushing a button to send that into the processor and then Changing all the levers and then pushing another pushing the button again.
Scott: You're literally sending zeros and ones directly into the CPU and because of the way if you understand how the CPU is made There are books and you know any CPU you get that's programmable has a giant book that tells you everything it can do and all The instructions and how it works and what's inside.
Scott: all right?
Scott: You are directly controlling the CPU with zeros and ones now obviously writing any sort of large.
Rym: I mean imagine trying to write half-life 2 in Assembly code.
Rym: try to break that game down to move this bit here move this bit there move this byte here.
Scott: Yeah, that's not gonna be fun.
Scott: That's that's pretty much The definition of pain.
Scott: I mean people have written some pretty impressive programs in assembly language.
Scott: usually you know old in the olden days Before we had you know more advanced technology and also for very small devices.
Scott: We're writing in assembly is pretty much Necessary because when you write in assembly language the advantage is that you can optimize the code with your human brain To run very quickly on that machine and to take up very little memory.
Scott: so your iPod You know if someone writes the iPod operating system in assembly language that operating system will end up being much smaller and much faster Making the iPod cheaper because you have you need less storage space to hold the operating system so they can give you less flash memory you know and say make the device cheaper and Also, it'll be faster.
Scott: The problem is it'll be much harder to make so they'll have to pay the developers more money.
Scott: and not many people know how to Write assembly language anymore.
Scott: It's it's a pretty rare skill and every different kind of chip has a different language.
Scott: so knowing how to write.
Scott: You know assembly language for one chip doesn't mean you know how to do it for another.
Scott: you usually have to read the book to Learn the new chip and such.
Scott: but anyway So that is.
Scott: that is how programming chips works.
Scott: you you give instructions To the chips that tell them how to process and then you give the input.
Scott: Which is more it you know following the instructions of how to process and then the chips do the output right?
Scott: But assembly language is not fun, so we have programming languages.
Scott: This is where for even for me a long time.
Scott: It was a complete mystery.
Scott: You know it's sort of like how do you get from programming language like something like Visual Basic right?
Scott: Down to the assembly language.
Scott: in the zeros and ones it seems like there's like this big fuzzy gap.
Scott: They're like huh, how did we get from here to there?
Scott: How do you get from windows popping up on the screen to assembly language?
Rym: It's like you know to the electricity zooming around on the motherboard especially as a kid when I mean I was writing stuff in Q-basic, and I couldn't fathom writing something before.
Rym: you know I knew about a lot more computing.
Rym: I couldn't fathom writing like windows in that.
Rym: and then I thought how do I leave and load windows?
Rym: What's windows running?
Scott: Ah it's eat?
Scott: There's this big gap between the software world right which is which is all the the Instructions just in binary that you're gonna send to the CPU.
Scott: That's all software is it's Instructions to send the CPU.
Scott: you know zeros and ones.
Scott: you know conceptual zeros and ones they don't have to be real zeros and ones and the physical silicon in the chip that is going to take electricity into it and then Change the way it processes and then take more electricity into it and then actually process.
Scott: There's this big hole and how does that hole get filled?
Scott: well is how that hole gets filled right?
Scott: You have a thing that is called a compiler.
Scott: There's an alternative which is an interpreter, but I'll explain that as the all soon.
Scott: what a compiler does is It basically takes some.
Scott: it's a program itself right.
Scott: that is you have a. you have a program already running on a CPU right and that program tells the CPU right to process input in a certain way.
Scott: and What it does is it basically tells the CPU take this input and then output another program.
Scott: Think about that for a second.
Scott: you program the CPU To output a program based on some input.
Scott: That is a program itself could understand.
Scott: so a simple idea to try to get this across.
Scott: so you know what the hell I'm talking about.
Scott: I Could tell the CPU.
Scott: Okay, here are some instructions read from the memory in location number one in the RAM.
Scott: and Then you know make it equal to.
Scott: you know I don't know number 32 and then output that back into the RAM.
Scott: and then The next thing you should do the next instruction that you should interpret.
Scott: You know the.
Scott: you know because you when a computer is going at least a modern PC generally the way it works is there's a counter and that counter is a place in the RAM and it looks at that place in the RAM and That is where the next instruction is.
Scott: so Basically in the RAM you would have lined up see I starting with no address number one.
Scott: It's like if a guy's what I'm trying to explain this because it's really hard without a picture.
Scott: Okay, so you're walking down the street and every square on the sidewalk has a piece of paper on it, right?
Scott: And that piece of paper says do this and then you walk.
Scott: after you do that You go to the next square on the sidewalk and you pick up the piece of paper and you do what it says, okay?
Scott: So the RAM is the sidewalk and what's in the RAM are those pieces of paper.
Scott: and the CPU walks down the street doing What all the pieces of paper say?
Scott: What if one of the pieces of paper said?
Scott: Skip over the next two pieces of paper That's that's that happens.
Scott: Erase the next piece of paper in front of you and write this on it instead?
Scott: That is what we're talking about.
Scott: here is a program.
Scott: it tells the CPU to write a program for itself and That is how programming languages work.
Scott: You have something like C, right?
Scott: You write in C, which is if you look at go look at some C code online You can find plenty of examples.
Scott: if you just search for like hello world in C or something like that You'll find plenty of examples of what C code looks like if you've never seen it.
Scott: And there's a program called the C compiler and the C compiler is a program and the Input to that program is C code and the output of that program, you know with the CPU outputs is Assembly language it takes in.
Scott: you know text, you know the letter A letter B letter C in binary form.
Scott: it processes them the way the.
Scott: you know, the Compiler program has told the CPU to process and the output of that program is A bunch of assembly language instructions.
Scott: and if you were to feed those assembly language instructions back to the CPU it would Reprogram the CPU to now do what the program you wrote in C told it to do.
Scott: So if you write hello world the compiler right takes your hello world.
Scott: the word hello world you typed into notepad.
Scott: It sends it the CPU the CPU then outputs a bunch of instructions And then it walks down the street that it just wrote all the pieces of paper on the street.
Scott: Then it went back to the beginning and starts doing what those pieces of paper It just wrote say.
Scott: and it says write the letter H write the letter E. so it's like if you went to your refrigerator and you wrote down get eggs and Then later you went to the refrigerator.
Scott: You took the note off and it said get eggs and you got the eggs.
Scott: only it's a lot simpler to you know, the.
Scott: the difference is is That the sort of the human level of writing C code is much easier than writing the assembly code.
Scott: So it's like it's translating for itself in a way if that makes sense and this is what?
Scott: computer programming is.
Scott: computer programming is writing Instructions in sort of the higher level language, but also the lower level language, you know but in a language.
Scott: and then if you're not writing in assembly language a Another program that you could even program those programs it gets that crazy.
Rym: So I guess at this point where you gonna go with this the week after next where you gonna continue?
Scott: I'm gonna go over probably a bunch of different programming languages You know like and talk about the differences between them and which ones are useful for what because that's that's more of a real-world problem.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: one last thing I want to mention in this episode though is that you know compiling is one way but there's also interpreting and the way interpreting works is basically when you compile a program the way that works is you walk down and you give the program to the compiler and It writes all the pieces of paper on the sidewalk all of them and then it goes back to the beginning and then it does What all of them say with an interpreter?
Scott: It does it one at a time.
Scott: so it take it rewrites one piece of paper does what it says then writes the next piece of paper and does what it says.
Scott: and it's sort of it does things one at a time as it goes through and compiling and Interpreting both have advantages and disadvantages and and such.
Scott: but there are the two different ways of sort of that programming languages do.
Scott: But yeah, I wonder if that made sense.
Scott: Tell me if that made sense people.
Rym: Yeah, we'll find out.
Scott: we'll find out.
Rym: It made sense to me, but I'm an IT professional.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, so we'll see.
Rym: but speaking of IT professional where I'm gonna pick up next week is you know A lot of people use the word IT and a lot of people don't really know exactly what an IT department is.
Rym: I say a lot of people.
Rym: I mean a lot of companies too.
Scott: Yeah, mostly companies.
Rym: I'm pretty much gonna explain in in all the detail you'll ever want what IT actually is what IT departments actually do and I think it'll be pretty interesting.
Scott: actually Yeah, a lot of people are like IT is just you know, the helpdesk or IT is a. you know Those server admin gas.
Rym: IT is both more and less than all of that.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: But yeah programming it's telling dinner.
Scott: Yeah, it's telling the CPU how to process.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.