Rym: It's Wednesday December 17th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about Mamoru.
Rym: She's the sky crawlers.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I have bruises in places that I wish I didn't have bruises.
Scott: actually I have a bruise on my leg like last night.
Scott: I was laying in bed and Sort of randomly my like calf just like cramped like and it stayed Crammed and like I like.
Scott: it was so cramped I put my hand near it to like feel and like the shape of my leg had changed and would not change back.
Scott: And today it's like whenever I flex that muscle over there.
Scott: There's like obviously some sort of bruising internally.
Rym: So actually that's very common.
Rym: It's caused by a sedentary lifestyle.
Rym: No, I don't know.
Rym: go to a doctor that's that came out of nowhere.
Scott: or or just wait and it'll go away.
Rym: I was talking about how I went skiing yesterday.
Rym: Well, yes.
Rym: Yes today.
Rym: Well yesterday because the show doesn't come out until today.
Scott: Yes The way today is Tuesday.
Scott: Yes skiing on Tuesday.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: However for the listener Listening Tuesday night, it's GeekNights.
Rym: But this isn't gonna be uploaded until Wednesday night because it's a Wednesday show.
Scott: Oh fuck.
Rym: Yes You see what I was gonna do.
Rym: I was gonna forget.
Scott: It was a Wednesday show like So.
Rym: yesterday I went skiing.
Scott: I forgot it was a Wednesday show.
Scott: So I'm getting ready for Tuesday show.
Rym: So on Tuesday, whichever day that may be yesterday.
Scott: Hey, so today we did secret Santa at work.
Scott: I don't know I don't know what I got.
Rym: I Went skiing.
Rym: Yeah, and I learned something.
Rym: I learned something really important.
Rym: I learned that if if the website for a ski resort says frozen granular surface conditions That's a code actually and the code means rims gonna bust his ass.
Scott: Well, if it's frozen, that means it's gonna be hard which means you can fall down.
Scott: You're gonna hurt yourself.
Rym: Well, basically frozen granular consists of ice.
Rym: Well snow that became ice that has now broken up.
Rym: So you're skiing on like chunky hard pieces of broken snow.
Scott: It's awesome Mmm, so it's sort of like, you know when the snow freezes and you know You step on it and you sort of make like these holes in it and then but just people just step on all the snow And then it gets all crunched up.
Rym: It's kind of like skiing on pebbles like a sea of pebbles but pebbles made of ice Mmm, yeah, so I would try to do things that I was able to do proficiently last year and not succeed in my endeavors.
Scott: Damn those weather Required Sporting events.
Scott: I mean like, you know, I mean ice hockey sort of needs some weather unless you have an indoor ice hockey.
Scott: But even then it's like as long as it's less than 32 degrees and you got a Zamboni.
Rym: It's all good Yeah, but snow like it depends on the previous several days weather.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so I'm in a little bit of pain.
Rym: yesterday All right I skipped work.
Rym: I went skiing and that's it.
Scott: All right now I only have to work this week and I guess this is the last episode I have to do this week.
Scott: Yeah, next week.
Rym: No more work until next year up until Christmas Eve.
Rym: And then I'm not going back to work till the second.
Scott: I'm not going back to work until the fifth.
Rym: I'm going for a half day on the second.
Rym: I'm gonna pop in on the second and do work but to train rises a lot of time.
Rym: No, because you realize the whole crew is gonna go to the city and do stuff that day.
Scott: Is that what you want to do?
Rym: Well, that's what they all want to do.
Scott: We'll see what happens.
Rym: That's what's gonna happen.
Rym: then I rented.
Rym: I didn't rent it yet, but I'm gonna rent a One of the giant rooms in one of the good karaoke places and we're all gonna go do karaoke.
Rym: I'm not gonna do karaoke so you can stay home with it.
Rym: All the other lame people and the rest of us will go to karaoke.
Scott: You can do all the karaoke you want.
Rym: Oh, we will.
Rym: Oh, yes, we will.
Rym: This time I'm not wasting my money and time on such a thing have to print out Romanized lyrics to Japanese songs because My knowledge of katakana does not even consist of all of katakana or hiragana Let alone kanji, so I can't sing along to Japanese.
Scott: I know like three letters of one of the honors.
Rym: I can sing a couple of songs like the KO century beast opener.
Rym: I know it by now.
Rym: It's in English rock and roll bomber.
Rym: Yeah, well, it's not all in missus in English.
Scott: It's it's enough in English.
Rym: Oh, you know me.
Rym: Sorry, ooh, three two ones.
Scott: Yeah, the only word in there is The only Japanese.
Rym: No, it's a really easy word rock and roll bomber plus half the songs in Japanese.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Rym: Anyway only the rock and roll bomber part is in English, which is the majority of the song.
Scott: And like you said koi no misayalu.
Scott: It's that's no missile is English.
Rym: It's a missile of love.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Not so many.
Scott: and also there are many characters in the show who speak the English.
Scott: Oh Bud mint, I love you all the bird people.
Rym: So you got to the part with that Colonel Sanders, I'd forgotten about him.
Rym: We're not reviewing KO century beast yet.
Scott: No, we're not soon.
Scott: I watched I think Four episodes now, there's only three left.
Rym: That's a show that really I see it from this whole different perspective now than what I did when I first watched it.
Rym: Of course, I think part of it's that when I first watched it, it was like 3 a.m Yeah Definitely.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I've seen the show mostly the same as before.
Scott: It's actually more of a robot show than I remember.
Rym: Yeah, well I get more of it now like I get things they're referencing that I had no idea.
Scott: But I don't see that many references.
Scott: We it seems mostly I don't know.
Rym: There's a few.
Rym: There's a few that really stand out that I wouldn't have noticed like the whole thing with mahjong.
Rym: Yeah, the mahjong.
Rym: I didn't know about mahjong anime back then.
Scott: Yeah, that was pretty good All right.
Scott: Anyway, definitely one of the better scenes.
Scott: All right, it's a Manga comics night.
Rym: So is there any anime manga comics news other than the fact that Continuously the anime industry in America is in its death spot.
Scott: It's not news.
Scott: What's there to say?
Scott: Um, Usually the news I hate the most Right is all that.
Scott: oh my god You know.
Scott: movie five years from now news, right?
Scott: Cuz it's all bullshit.
Scott: You never know until the movies actually in the theater.
Scott: Yes, right.
Rym: I gotta check and see if there's any updates on the Temeraire movie.
Scott: Yeah, like a hundred years from now, you know, cuz I mean there have been in the past.
Scott: There have been movies that were made like fully made the movie is done Edited the whole thing that never saw the light of day there multiple times.
Scott: This has happened So I usually don't trust any movie news at all.
Rym: Oh, there's a minor update.
Rym: Peter Jackson said of Temeraire and I quote Blah blah blah, I particularly love fantasy and historical epic.
Rym: I can't wait to see Napoleonic battles fought with the squadron of dragons.
Rym: That is someone said is what I go to the movies for.
Scott: so someone says something Well, no Part of it was.
Rym: I want to make that movie.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: any option the rights, but yeah, but option meaning not set in stone what needs to be pointed out that that is a sentiment that Scott Johnson can also be behind.
Rym: that Is what he goes to the movies for it is indeed.
Scott: But anyway, I'm not talking about that movie.
Scott: who gives a shit about that.
Scott: I'm talking about this movie news, which Even though this is a movie that is gonna come out and when 2010 right It's set in stone enough it where I couldn't I would bet money that you know.
Scott: Everything that is here is going to come to be.
Scott: you know, it is.
Scott: it is a certain thing.
Scott: basically You know, I'm not really excited about any movies that come out these days really at all.
Scott: so much except I think this might be like the first one.
Scott: and the worst part about it is as Really don't like a lot of underwear pervert movies, especially the recent ones.
Rym: Well, I gotta say The recent Batman movies did not do it for no, everyone likes those.
Scott: I don't like those.
Scott: I like the 1989 Batman.
Scott: I like I guess I like that first spider-man one.
Scott: I didn't see the other ones.
Scott: I guess I didn't like any of the x-men move.
Rym: my problem with the Batman movies in particular.
Rym: Is that Everyone in them is awesome except Batman.
Rym: I mean Batman is such a static character in these and so just like I'm Batman.
Rym: I mean look at the Dark Knight Returns.
Rym: The reason it's good.
Rym: Is that Batman changes?
Rym: Everything changes.
Rym: people die people change.
Rym: the Joker was a. someone else actually pointed this out to me.
Rym: I didn't notice it, but the Joker Doesn't change.
Rym: Batman does.
Rym: no one changes in the new movies at all.
Rym: And also microwaves don't work that way.
Scott: Yeah, that really bothered me.
Rym: that bothered me enough that I stopped watching it.
Scott: No, but you know in 2008, right?
Scott: We saw the Iron Man movie.
Scott: I didn't see it.
Scott: Actually.
Rym: I didn't see it.
Scott: I don't really know if I want to see it, but that doesn't matter.
Scott: in 2009 there's gonna be the cats in America movie Right now.
Scott: if you if you know about underwear perverts or at least Marvel underwear perverts, you know where this is going, right?
Scott: It's the Avengers and the Avengers, you know has many characters in it that change over time but the three characters that are the Avengers and Marvel are Iron Man cats in America and Thor now.
Rym: are they making a Thor movie now?
Scott: I would not care about.
Scott: you know a Thor movie.
Rym: Here's what I want.
Rym: I've suddenly decided I want a movie that is just the Norse gods doing their thing.
Scott: Well, if you ever read actual, you know Thor comics like from Marvel.
Scott: a lot of them are just that it's mostly like when you see Thor and Avengers is me.
Scott: a lot of underwear pervert action.
Rym: Yes, but but I want that in movie form.
Scott: Well, you may or may not get that movie storm.
Scott: Have you heard like this?
Scott: I think I've talked about this once before.
Scott: you don't remember?
Scott: No, oh well then basically the.
Scott: Let me read to you the quotes from from the The director before I tell you who this director is.
Scott: Alright, I'm directing Thor or the mighty Thor as you might like to call it.
Scott: I think it will be Thor.
Scott: There has been lots of talk.
Scott: I sound like a politician, but we were too early.
Scott: at this stage We're getting the story and the visual effects together and all that is very exciting.
Scott: Someone sensational is going to play the part, but it is early days.
Scott: It's Akashi Mika Something about it's.
Scott: they're gonna concentrate a lot on.
Scott: you know the the.
Scott: you know cuz Thor in Marvel Comics is like a normal dude and he gets the hammer and then he turns into Thor and They turns the normal dude and they're gonna you know concentrate on some of the human story there.
Scott: and then in 2011 the year after the Thor movie there's gonna be Avengers movie, which is Iron Man Captain America Thor, right?
Scott: No, but you know, this is rumor ish before but now it's it's.
Scott: it's gonna be as long as Marvel doesn't fold or anything.
Scott: by 2011 all these four movies will exist.
Scott: No, but the director of Thor is Kenneth Branagh.
Rym: What I told you I Almost had a nerd gasping right there That the only thing that can make that better is if somehow Patrick Stewart had a role in it.
Scott: Kenneth Brad he has broken his silence about directing a film version cuz he had see it broke the silence.
Scott: So it was like.
Scott: it was like whisper whisper, but now it's like alright.
Scott: Yeah, I am directing Thor.
Scott: I think the mighty Thor as you might like to probably did tell.
Rym: tell me this but I probably just assumed it wasn't true and Thus forgot it.
Scott: Well now it is the true true.
Scott: You know, it is Wednesday and it's like normally, you know when you have a new movie news that's so far out you go.
Scott: Hey, right, but know that the superhero movies if are pretty much set in stone, you know They're gonna keep making these things is they keep breaking in the money and these are the ones they're gonna do and that's that I should say because it is a Wednesday night.
Rym: Oh, well, it's Tuesday technically since Scott broke the illusion.
Rym: Yeah, but if you don't know who kind of the brown owl is and why I went Mom his Hamlet is the second best Hamlet ever Mm-hmm, it's four hours long.
Rym: It has Billy Crystal in it and Robin Williams and Jack Lemmon and everyone else famous.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it is a masterpiece Mm-hmm.
Rym: I say second best because a Patrick Stewart's Hamlet is apparently also awesome.
Scott: Oh wait, actually I got the years wrong.
Scott: Thor is gonna open in theaters July 16 2010.
Scott: Iron Man 2 is on May 2010, so they're doing two movies at once here So we're gonna get to see these.
Rym: Quetzalcoatl is not gonna fuck it up.
Scott: Captain America Well, the Avengers movie will be in July 2011 and Captain America is in May 2011 So it's gonna be like Iron Man 2 Thor Captain America Avengers in 2010 2011.
Scott: So, I don't know what's in 2009.
Scott: Nothing, I guess.
Scott: I don't know, huh?
Rym: Yeah, I could be excited about that.
Scott: I'm only excited about the store.
Scott: Fuck all the others.
Rym: Thor is the only thing I care about.
Scott: Yeah, fuck all these other movies.
Rym: So speaking of things that may or may not be made only pretty much.
Rym: Ever since asa manga daioh was a huge success.
Rym: the manga and the anime Yotsuba has been like the one of the best manga out there.
Scott: Yeah, it was also one of the biggest selling manga outside of the Naruto's and things and it's fantastic.
Rym: I don't need to tell you it's fantastic.
Rym: I don't need to tell you you should be reading it but What everyone's been saying every anime fan pretty much since they first saw Yotsuba was When's it gonna be an anime?
Rym: When's it gonna be an anime?
Rym: And there's always rumors about oh, well, there's gonna be an anime.
Rym: Oh, no, there isn't.
Rym: Oh there is and it's gonna be directed by Moroshi.
Scott: Yeah, right Yes, it's going to be a Takashi Miike live-action Yotsuba.
Rym: That could be good.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: With that little squirt gun.
Rym: If only I could draw I would.
Rym: this is a. this is homework listeners who can draw.
Rym: draw me a bunch of four panels Like when Yotsuba had that squirt gun as if Yotsuba were directed by Takashi Miike.
Scott: No Just go and take pages from Yotsuba put that page up and then right next to it draw the same page Directed by Takashi Miike.
Rym: I want to make this a meme seriously?
Scott: Well, no, let's do the Takashi Miike and anything meme.
Scott: just take anything and then remix it as by Takashi Miike Anything at all?
Rym: Hey, I smell a panel a panel that could only be enjoyed by people who know their anime.
Rym: Anyway in the long string of stories as to why there will or will not or when or how be a Yotsuba anime You make one there will be.
Rym: the latest news is actually kind of interesting because asthma came out and Made statements about all this.
Rym: finally and he didn't make the statement.
Rym: I expected it.
Rym: He didn't say something like yes There's an anime.
Rym: No, there's not.
Rym: what he said was the
Scott: reasons
Rym: you all are saying For why there is not an anime are made up crap Mmm, and he said very simply I'm not gonna quote from the article or anything, but he basically Yotsuba just would not translate well to an anime to anything other than a comic and he can't come up with a way To make it an anime that would keep it funny for the reasons that it's funny.
Scott: On the one hand I can sort of see that but on the other hand You know, there have been lots of things that you know, we're sort of called untranslatable, but did really Came out just fine, but it's different.
Rym: when I was the author themselves say yeah, not gonna happen.
Scott: Well, I mean it might not get it might not be able to happen But just because he can't see a way to do it.
Scott: I think there are people who can make it happen.
Rym: I mean I can imagine it myself, you know Like one example he pointed out was like there's one where Yotsuba walks in and goes hello And everyone ignores her and all the rest of the panels are just no one reacting and then it ends.
Rym: And he was like all right like okay I could do that but it wouldn't be as funny if it was animated.
Scott: I know you just put like some cricket noises over it, you know, yeah, I don't know that that's just what I was gonna say.
Rym: I can't yeah, I can't impinge upon him.
Scott: No, the one thing about Yotsuba is that unlike every other popular manga that came out in the u.s.
Scott: This was actually published by ADV manga.
Scott: It was like the only thing they ever published.
Scott: besides well I think there was one of their manga they had that I liked but no one else liked.
Scott: but Yotsubana is a manga dire where they're only sort of successful manga ventures, you know, and then now ADV is DOA, right?
Scott: Well, I guess not OA because they've arrived a long time ago, but they're.
Rym: they're D But they're not MD.
Scott: no, they're M.I.A and So Yotsuba is also M.I.A even though it was wickedly popular and made lots of money.
Scott: But ADV kind of owns it doesn't own it.
Scott: what's going on?
Scott: We're waiting for all these volumes a bunch of volumes out in Japan But they're not out in English only because ADV sucks.
Scott: if like visit license this we'd probably have every volume already.
Scott: You know, if dark horse had licensed it we'd have every volume already.
Scott: It's only because ADV license it that were that everyone in the u.s.
Scott: Has to suffer even though this thing is very Popular and profitable.
Scott: So the other manga companies?
Scott: somebody got to snatch this shit up and I can't.
Scott: I can't imagine that They don't realize that this is going on.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: I imagine it's a difficult situation and someone's got a freaking.
Scott: No one has against the motivation to work it out Except for the fans.
Rym: What's interesting?
Rym: Is that some of these rumors are crazy like some people were saying there's no anime because him and some director had a falling out or That he doesn't get along with Tomoko Kaneda who is the voice of Chiyo-chan, but did he know?
Scott: No, how do you know these two?
Scott: How do you come up with that?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It's real easy if I want to spread a rumor, right?
Rym: All right Shit up and I'll go to a forum somewhere and I'll just be like, yes, so I heard Mamoru.
Rym: Oh, she is working with Osamu Tezuka to make a live action.
Scott: Tezuka's dead Evangelion spin-off call.
Scott: I mean if someone goes in a forum and says that the next post is how could you possibly know that?
Scott: No, it isn't.
Rym: the next post is OMG and then the next post is lololol buts It's the internet.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: So I guess it's time for things of the day.
Rym: I thought that I had seen every possible Funny thing on the internet involving a Leonidas face.
Rym: You know what I'm talking about that very specific set of faces of King Leonidas that so Perfectly encapsulates everything that I think is funny on the internet much like that face the yellow face looking up like It wasn't there.
Scott: a really good Leonidas are really.
Rym: Yes There's a good Leonidas everything.
Rym: But I thought I'd seen them all like I really did.
Rym: I thought that I had.
Rym: there was no one who was going to make one That was newest new enough or funny enough or different enough to make me go.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: I didn't expect that.
Rym: I Must have missed one.
Rym: So here we go.
Rym: What would you do with the drunken Spartan if you?
Rym: I don't know you might have all already seen this.
Rym: I don't know what you kids watch on the internet, but this was Unexpectedly funny and the fact that it's so long just makes it funnier.
Rym: I I don't know what I can say other than that There are about three or four points in this where the Leonidas face just does something.
Rym: Usually it's like there's one Leonidas face singing and there's another one like in frame not doing anything And then suddenly that one will do something and I'll lose it.
Scott: Yeah Is that it?
Rym: that's it.
Scott: that's it All right.
Scott: So I'm listening to me.
Scott: world orders right and in passing Daryl Surratt sort of mentioned some video game like an old video game that no one's ever heard of called metal wolf chaos.
Scott: Right metal wolf metal gear you basically just as metal of chaos something something everyone loves metal of chaos bla bla bla.
Rym: the end Right, that's a very Daryl Surratt statement.
Scott: I go and I ask him yo, what's that wolf thing?
Scott: He's like what wolf thing?
Scott: I'm like you said.
Scott: there's some video games like oh, yeah metal wolf chaos cuz I didn't remember the name, right?
Scott: So he's like, yeah was this game.
Scott: That was an Xbox one game not an Xbox.
Scott: That was Japan only.
Scott: yet the entire game voice acting and text was in 100% English Weird, huh?
Scott: And the game was only ever released in Japan.
Rym: now for the Xbox one The Xbox didn't do well and it was made.
Scott: it was made by the same developers that made What's it called?
Scott: Armored armored core and chrome hounds and those games right from whatever actually there's.
Rym: sorry.
Rym: I'm thinking of something else.
Scott: go on Yeah, so there's a game called the metal wolf chaos.
Scott: It's like this sort of unheard of game at least, you know by normal people.
Scott: So it's pretty obscure.
Rym: One up calm found out about it recently actually really and they they actually named it the quote most insanely patriotic game ever made.
Scott: all right, um, I Don't really want to give away with the games about.
Scott: I know Ruins all the humor of it.
Rym: I want to because I want to say funny things about it.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time you need to experience this video the way Scott Emily and I experienced it.
Scott: Because just watch the whole thing because even if it's not funny it gets.
Scott: They watch the whole thing.
Scott: Don't stop it.
Rym: It escalates.
Rym: Yeah, and every time you think you saw the funny bit it continues to escalate.
Scott: The thing is is that when I was a kid, I had this choose your own adventure book But it wasn't actually.
Scott: choose your own adventure book.
Scott: it was a TSR produced.
Scott: choose your own adventure book and it was almost exactly the same as Story as this.
Rym: I can say.
Rym: I'm gonna say one thing.
Rym: according to Wikipedia people Who have played the game or looked at the game?
Rym: Notice the relative eye level that the main character has.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil who the main character is In relation to everyone else and he must be 11 feet tall Which kind of works.
Scott: it totally makes sense Makes perfect sense.
Rym: This game is fantastic.
Rym: I don't know if it's actually good, but it's fantastic.
Scott: No, it's a third-person action shooter.
Scott: You know, it's.
Scott: it's probably it is what it is, but Watching it on YouTube You're gonna get what it's worth and if you wanted to you could probably easily go and download the game on some Torrance and then Burn it to a CD or DVD or whatever and put it in your Xbox or something like that and it would work.
Rym: Yeah, the the internet is my.
Scott: I don't know if you had to mod an Xbox.
Scott: I don't know how that shit works.
Scott: Definitely possible in some way.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: The Xbox modding was huge, right?
Scott: People installed all sorts of crazy shit on there.
Scott: I don't know What.
Rym: if Daryl Surratt is the cause of the resurgence or if he found out about it because of the resurgence?
Scott: But he said that like there was a panel at a convention He did recently where he was trying to do an anime and video game panel You know where he showed anime based video games that were good, but he just whipped this out You know because it's so great even if it's not anime.
Rym: Well, the thing is I'm looking around now and I'm finding a lot of very recent references to it where there were no references before Huh?
Scott: Well get it.
Scott: while it's hot people Metal Wolf chaos.
Rym: So we had the privilege actually Torrance will be rocking right now last weekend of seeing the New York premiere.
Rym: I don't know if it was the American premiere, but it was definitely the New York premiere of Mamoru Oshii's new movie Scott new animated movie.
Scott: Yes Scott.
Rym: Well, I think it's the newest movie.
Rym: He made possibly I'll check that but skycrawlers.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It was a Mamoru og animated movie, you know just like ghost in the shell or beautiful dreamer or the Pat LeBourne movies.
Scott: You know two plus something hours long Crazy high quality animation.
Rym: Oh my god the end.
Rym: We're gonna review it but we're not going to see.
Scott: I mean, you know, usually it seems like these days like, you know directors and just artists in general Sort of like trying to get away from their sticks, you know, well, he doesn't go away from his stick.
Scott: I mean that you showed me this movie.
Scott: I could have been like oh it was and you said who's the director?
Scott: like 10 minutes in.
Scott: I would have been like I was oh She.
Scott: yeah now as soon as you see like the freaking dog.
Rym: If I'd only seen the first I don't know 15 minutes and I knew the plot but I hadn't seen the rest I might have guessed that maybe shiro wrote it or something, but
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's a tough call and that kind
Rym: of but it's definitely oh she all the way that the one thing I noticed Is that we went with a whole bunch of people?
Scott: The thing is as soon as you when you think shiro in an anime you go to oh She because you know, he directed the ghost in the shell one and two and so it's like, you know It makes perfect sense,
Rym: but no shiro had nothing to do with this at all.
Rym: This is all.
Rym: oh, she adapted from a novel.
Scott: But yeah, what was the novel?
Scott: I forget.
Rym: Oh the not.
Rym: well get to that.
Rym: I'll get to the whole history of what this is and where it came from.
Rym: But we went with a whole bunch of people like we ran into uncle yo and a whole bunch of people I love living in New York at this showing like we didn't coordinate this.
Rym: It seems like every time there's an anime screening like a big one in New York City If we go we see like the same posse of people there every time.
Scott: I definitely saw a lot of people there that were also at the Satoshi khan thing and the cool thing was the same exact theater.
Rym: So, oh, she actually recorded a little short like a three-minute video of himself Really shabby looking in front of a wall.
Scott: Yeah, it's like he.
Scott: this is worse than a YouTube.
Scott: basically It's like you think a guy with all this, you know, like movie making skill would make a better video of himself.
Scott: It's like he was like wearing like a ratty white.
Scott: He looked like some nasty otaku who basically and he's sitting in front of this camera real close to his face That way it had heart.
Rym: It was like he's sitting down with you.
Rym: Like look I sent this movie over to you Americans.
Scott: It's like thanks for coming to the New York premiere.
Scott: This is my movie.
Scott: It's about this It's also about this and it's also about this.
Scott: Please stay until the end.
Scott: That guy got a lot of laughs because you know His movies are long and so it's sort of like we thought he was see.
Scott: we thought he was saying Please stay until the end because maybe it's long and you'll get bored.
Scott: It is over two hours long Yeah, but actually he was saying stay until the very end after the credits because there's more.
Rym: Yeah, there is more.
Rym: we Made a critic.
Scott: We didn't really need to see it because it's sort of it.
Scott: It's one of those things where after the credits they show you something.
Scott: now in some movies after the credits what they show you Is like game-changing?
Rym: Yeah, it's not like alien.
Scott: The whole show is in the credits.
Rym: Yeah, the whole credits are like, oh by the way, here's what happened Everyone and oh look, we killed a bunch of people.
Scott: the end in the credits the final craze less They.
Rym: I remember Gabby's screaming from the other room.
Scott: Yeah No But in that what happens after the credits in this movie is basically a visual confirmation of things you already know.
Scott: So if you were paying attention to the movie itself now, it's not too bad that you missed it.
Scott: one thing I noticed and I it's actually good that we missed it because we probably wouldn't have made the tree.
Rym: I would recommend that any anime fans see this movie But very specifically if there is any way for you to see it in a theater see it in the theater.
Scott: Yeah, normally, you know, obviously Movies in the theater are far superior, right?
Scott: But I'm usually not too anal about it.
Scott: It's like yeah I know the theaters better you get the big screen and the better sound.
Scott: But really if I want 90% of movies if you watch him in your home on a DVD player, it's good enough.
Scott: VHS isn't good enough, but a DVD with some speakers is good.
Scott: No, it depends.
Rym: I mean, is it a movie of people talking to each other?
Rym: Is it a movie of people shooting at?
Scott: You know while I'd rather watch Star Wars in the theater I can watch Star Wars on a DVD like a hundred times.
Rym: but no but it doesn't have the same effect though The one time I went and saw those Star Wars movies in the theater.
Rym: It was a different experience.
Scott: It was.
Scott: but but this movie like the theater Makes it anything is the theater we saw it in wasn't even like a really fancy digital theater with wicked sound.
Scott: It was sort of like, you know, it's like an auditorium at the you know, Juilliard the school.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: it's not that awesome a theater.
Rym: It's not like a screen wise because I've been to local theaters lately.
Rym: in the screen itself how big it is relative to where the seats Are it's fantastic.
Scott: It's alright, but you know, it's not like go into an An IMAX or well even like even like you go to like the Lowe's.
Scott: like, you know Super digital theater with the stadium seating is you know in is a lot better than this screen, but it's not a bad screen It's just not.
Rym: it's not a super screen is what I'm saying, but skycrawlers Seeing it in the theater would be a completely different experience because this movie is the first Animated.
Rym: this movie has a new standard for prop plane dogfights.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there are lots of anime with airplanes shit tons like a row.
Scott: so you got you know I'm not just you know jet fighters and prop planes.
Scott: I mean you got you know, all those Miyazakis with airplanes in an area 88 the blue skies.
Scott: You know the list goes on and on and on.
Scott: planes and flight are huge but in the anime.
Rym: But this movie took it to a level.
Scott: It's well over 29,000 in the CG era right with surround sound full length in movie theater theatrical anime, right There hasn't really been a big one with the planes.
Scott: I mean, I guess steam boy had a bit of flight in it kind of little bit not so much I mean what else.
Scott: what else really has there been recently in the theaters?
Scott: I Guess was oh, what was the one?
Scott: By Makoto Shinkai the oh, yeah I could look it up and like one plane right with the big tower the one that you like.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah, yeah place promised in early days place promise in one plane.
Scott: That was sort of a you know Anime movie.
Scott: but this is the first anime movie that I can think of in like the CG era to go full-on With the planes with the sound with the CG with everything it did
Rym: the blurry shaky cam super awesome Choreographed dogfights and because they were like man
Scott: cross zero macros plus you got nothing on this shit.
Scott: All right He did.
Scott: he basically said you know what every anime has done planes.
Rym: if I do planes I have to show everyone up times a million and he did and I think it really helps that they're prop planes because you get All those like s turns and maneuvers that don't really like modern fighter jets.
Rym: Don't really dogfight so much as shoot missiles at enemies who are over the horizon.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much but oh my god like if nothing else.
Rym: even if you hate this movie and you hate, you know two hour long introspective philosophical atmospheric movies.
Rym: Watch this movie for the dogfights.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: this is one of those movies where it's like.
Scott: sometimes you get something That's you know real intellectual and deep and slow and most people be bored by it.
Scott: But you know cool people will love it or whatever or pretentious people will love it depending, right?
Scott: But this is one of those ones that can be enjoyed on multiple levels Which is really what you want to go for right?
Scott: You can.
Scott: he's got this deep message going on that comes across really well.
Scott: He's got you know, like this great character development thing.
Scott: It's got this ongoing plot.
Scott: It's got a sci-fi plot, but on the surface level he's got his fucking action.
Scott: Just there you go.
Scott: If you if you don't get all that shit and don't care about it You will still love this movie for the fucking airplanes that are really loud with lots of explode.
Rym: However, do not forget that is a Mamoru Oshii movie because I think a lot of our friends who came with us a Lot of people didn't really like it when we got out of the theater.
Scott: and yeah I mean, it's not the greatest movie ever, but it's a good movie.
Scott: I liked it.
Rym: I thought it was good.
Rym: Yeah, it's in my top hundred.
Scott: Yeah, definitely.
Rym: It's easy to get into my top hundred.
Rym: It's definitely in there.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: It might be in the top 50, but maybe not.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I have to start counting.
Rym: Yeah, I'd have to count at that point, you know, it's a pretty.
Scott: it's pretty good.
Scott: It's like seven or eight stars out of ten.
Rym: if you're an anime fan first off.
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: there's that many anime movies you get to see that are new.
Scott: that's in America.
Scott: So any anime, I don't know if anyone's gonna get to see this in the theater in America besides us.
Rym: Yeah, maybe out in the West Coast, but yeah this movie I get after the movie.
Rym: What a lot of people said who didn't like it was that was really long.
Rym: That was really repetitive.
Rym: The the character development was weird.
Rym: It was all atmosphere and no plot and to which I said Yeah, it was directed by Mamoru.
Rym: She it's like.
Scott: have you not seen his movies before?
Rym: Exactly like this.
Rym: I went in expecting this and I got exactly what I wanted and I was very pleased I was.
Scott: quiet scenes lots of scenes where a character you watch characters like performing everyday actions in like real time Quietly and slowly.
Rym: Granted it's not to the level of the the cats on the train in space where I get to see him Slowly walk to a door slowly open the door walk through the door turn around slowly close the door turn around walk away.
Scott: quiet.
Rym: you Like my quiet in space I know but that that movie took you too far.
Rym: Though I have quiet in space as you can get I have this evil idea to take Odean and All any see.
Scott: hide it together with not in the galactic era any
Rym: scene that just shows space or like an atmosphere scene extend and extend and copy paste copy paste and Make it five hours long secretly and then run the who can watch this movie to the end contest late at night at a con
Scott: With the with these special elongated
Rym: cut.
Rym: I'll call it.
Rym: I'll call it the director's cut.
Scott: It's the elongated Rym cut the the on abridged version.
Scott: Yeah, I'll cut in some MD guys doesn't matter Just throw in some random shit towards the end.
Scott: I'll take losing it.
Rym: I'll just take all of MD guys and stick it in at the end like before Right before the credits just pay.
Rym: like they get near the end they find MD guys and then it's just MD guys from there.
Scott: That's most dangerous.
Rym: But anyway The movie I guess part of the reason it seems like people had a problem with it though was that being an oshi movie.
Rym: the form and structure of the film like the way it is put together and the fact that it's repetitive and the fact that they're the character develop my characters don't really develop is Critical to the message.
Rym: It's like if the movie were shorter or More like cut more finely or had fewer of these atmosphere scenes or had closure Not to spoil it but had closure.
Rym: that was expected.
Rym: Then it would have kind of betrayed what oh she was saying, you know Yeah, I mean in in.
Scott: I'll tell you because this isn't a spoiler because oh she told it to us.
Scott: You know indirectly before the movie started but he said the movie is about.
Scott: you know People who don't grow up and it's about You know whether living a life of daily routine is is worthwhile and such.
Scott: now, right?
Scott: So if you want to have this message of daily routine, you need to actually in the movie like show Routine and repetition and you know to deliver that and that necessarily at least, you know If your mom or oshi makes the movie sort of long and has lots of repeating things and routines That you get used to and then when the routines break that's when the movie goes.
Scott: Oh my god is typical, you know narrative technique there, you know.
Rym: but then the one of the big points was that even when the routines break also not a spoiler because Believe me you can watch this movie.
Rym: We're not gonna say anything where you're gonna go.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: No, I can't watch it Mm-hmm, but uh, even when routines break did they really break?
Scott: Yeah, I mean I walk the same road to work every day.
Scott: Well, I'll walk on the other side of it this time.
Scott: We're all look in a different direction this time and it talks I mean a lot of what we're thinking.
Rym: it's not just routines and how they affect people but the idea of immortality or aging or Being in a rut in your life or anything like that.
Rym: I mean if one day is no different than the next if you live Wednesday the same as Tuesday the same as Monday Then are you really living three separate days or was your life turning into just one big day?
Rym: Mm-hmm one day where nothing new happens.
Scott: So I think I'll give you a tiny Non-spoilery plot summary.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Well, I mean it was based on a novel written by Hiroshi Mori.
Rym: Actually, it's a set of five novels.
Scott: Ah, well, you know in Japan They always break the novels up into little volumes that we get a little ones.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but basically though This series is a deviation from his usual works in a big way.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Apparently he writes mystery novels.
Scott: Oh, I'd like to see.
Scott: I wish that more Japanese book books were translated to English, you know, and they kept him in that same tiny format, you know And and the same prices.
Rym: and well, yeah, he's a. he's a writer and an engineer who's famous for writing mystery novels in Japan.
Scott: I'd like to get me some of that.
Scott: and then out of the blue he wrote this stuff sweet all right, basically the story you have here is there's a guy and He I'm not gonna and he goes to work.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: I gotta go one step further with this guy.
Rym: He writes a very specific kind of mystery story.
Rym: He calls them Rakei mysteries science mysteries math mysteries, ah man Apparently maybe I should go buy.
Scott: that's like stupid rosette.
Rym: The perfect insider is quotes often criticized for its overuse of computer jargon.
Rym: No He responded by saying that is perfectly natural for people with a background Of knowledge and technology to better understand others.
Rym: Yeah, yeah jargon.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, so the movie Even oh man, I find it all these things.
Rym: He talks about how using computer jargon in a book with computers is no different than using Fantasy jargon in a book about fantasy.
Rym: It's just proper nouns.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, so the movie.
Scott: It's about a guy who goes to work at you know, basically a military base, but it's a military base That just has a few planes, you know, it's like a little Air Force base, you know tiny one.
Scott: They got a hangar they got a little building with some you know rooms to sleep in and a couple offices and a little eating room and whatever right up and he works for some company and There's some people at the base.
Scott: There's the the lady who fixes the planes.
Scott: There's the other pilots.
Scott: There's the Commander lady.
Rym: Yeah, there's obviously a whole command structure but at the beginning of the movie you get the impression that there's Some sort of war going on and that this company is a part of it in some way.
Rym: and they're either in providing the technology or It's not made clear immediately and it is made Crystal clear by the end of the movie.
Scott: definitely Yeah, you know they you know, he gets there and you know, you meet these characters and all the characters You know are sort of have mysteries about them.
Scott: just you know, they say very little, you know They're acting strangely.
Scott: this there things that are weird and are not fully explained You know and you don't even know why they're fighting or what happened before this or anything like that movie really feels Like a dream, which is also I mean remember.
Rym: Oh, she also did beautiful dreamer, which was about dreams directly.
Rym: Yeah And it had the same kind of its dream.
Rym: like scenes flow into each other like there's really no beginning or end It kind of starts in media res and ends in media res.
Scott: Yep So they go on all that, you know, they go on missions and they you know They fight and they do recon and stuff like that and you know They do things.
Scott: whether you know, it also shows you what they're doing when they're not going on missions.
Scott: You know going to the diner eating a meat pie, you know getting some hose that's or you know things that pilots do.
Rym: I actually really like the two prostitute characters.
Scott: Yeah, they're pretty cool.
Scott: They're actually some of the better characters.
Rym: Yes, but that but that that's very important to what he was saying.
Scott: I know right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, and then, you know, basically the movie just consists of you know time going by day by day you know things that happen and slowly things are revealed.
Scott: and as things are revealed and The characters learn more about each other and about you know things that are going on You know situations evolve as such and then you have a movie and you know by the end You learn everything you need to learn and it's it's what you do.
Scott: learn is pretty crazy.
Scott: the only thing that I had to say about it though is that There was the scene where they went to the diner for the first time and then afterwards they got in the car and he was Like, how was the meat pie?
Scott: And at that moment, I knew everything that was.
Scott: I knew the whole movie.
Scott: I already figured it out.
Scott: It was solved.
Rym: See, I figured it out a bit before that.
Rym: Well, everyone can say the scene if you.
Scott: basically it's like if you pay attention You can figure the whole movie out But at the same time you're not gonna figure out all the things.
Rym: Oh, she's trying to say because he makes a lot of points He makes like.
Scott: it's like he has like two or three big things to say and then he's got a lot of little things to Say throughout, you know, so it's like you can get.
Scott: the big plot thing is pretty obvious.
Scott: You can get real close to it or close enough to where.
Scott: it doesn't matter that you're not right on target.
Scott: But you know, you still watch the rest of the movie did all the little stuff, you know.
Scott: And I guess if you're not smart, you won't figure it out until the end and you'll go.
Rym: Oh shit The movie I don't know.
Rym: I thought this movie also the teacher.
Rym: oh my god the teacher.
Scott: I think the teacher might be my favorite.
Rym: Of course that thing on the side of his plane made me kept my reminding me of the Thundercats though I want to point out something interesting here because The movie was directed by oshi, but the screenplay was written by someone named Chihiro Ito.
Rym: Chihiro Ito is known for one other anime a very important anime.
Rym: You see he did the key animation for perverse investigations.
Rym: Key animation big deal perverse investigations also has the alternate title sex judge.
Rym: It's the only two things he's done.
Scott: unless yeah the I'm sure he's done something else that they let him write a screenplay.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: at least he's done nothing.
Rym: the same person Unless see I'm basing this entirely on the anime news network.
Rym: And
Scott: yeah He's probably done a lot of live action or something like that and it's probably it might even be a different person who did that Anime, you know
Rym: it is possible, but I was surprised to find that when I was clicking on the links of all the people
Scott: We had to go get a guy.
Scott: bet you know we should.
Scott: we don't own any hentai's.
Scott: You know I'm not really big fan of the hentai's even though if you like him.
Scott: That's that's your deal.
Rym: well I can say this.
Rym: I have somewhere it's found one of those hard drives a Downloaded copy of the first episode of elven bride.
Scott: great.
Scott: That was right as a comedy though.
Scott: It's not a.
Rym: well It's a sexy comedy.
Scott: yeah, but there was in a sexy comedy, and you know which is intended for humor But happens to be sexy and something that is intended for.
Scott: you know Titillation.
Scott: well yeah, he's viewed comedically.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: you say titillation because I think that was intended at least a little bit.
Scott: yeah Yeah, of course.
Scott: But I think if we're gonna on his quest to get the harpy you if we're gonna go and get some you know hentai for comedic purposes.
Scott: You know Sex judge sounds like a pretty good one to go for.
Rym: no just based on the title alone sex judge sounds like something Dave and Joel should review.
Scott: It just sounds so funny like I imagine.
Rym: It's not that funny.
Scott: Maybe not imagine, but the name I can.
Scott: I can.
Scott: I can imagine it being really hilarious based on the name.
Rym: Oh, there isn't even a description here.
Rym: It's voted.
Rym: one person said it was very good.
Rym: really only one person said it was.
Scott: that person is the sex-defendant.
Scott: The one person who said it was awful was the sex plaintiff.
Rym: 51 people on the animators network have seen it.
Scott: wow that said too many.
Rym: But anyway this movie one thing I want to say is that you know we talked about how you should see in the theater is Beautiful, but I can't stress enough this movie is beautiful.
Rym: It is absolutely beautiful.
Scott: It's a production IG 2008 movie.
Scott: what do you expect you know?
Scott: I mean, I guess sometimes the anime studios that have the big skills and the big money's you know put out something That's lower quality to save money and cuz they don't care, but yeah, they they put it all into this one.
Scott: You know it's like it's just got the.
Scott: you know It's the same people who you know who'd worked on like ghost in the shell to innocence.
Scott: That's the kind of high-quality amazing animation You're looking at now suppose newer than that.
Rym: even the the author of the book because this was such a big departure from his other Stuff he said that it would have been of any work He's written.
Rym: it would have been the most difficult to adapt to screen.
Scott: well And he never wanted including his computer jargon mister I guess.
Rym: but the only reason he gave consent to have this movie made was because he found out that oh She wanted to direct it.
Rym: Oh Which makes sense because for what the movie is only oh she could have done this.
Scott: Was it like I couldn't imagine?
Scott: like taking this plot and having it being done by like anyone else?
Scott: really it just wouldn't.
Scott: I Just wouldn't see it working like I try to imagine this.
Scott: you know the base.
Scott: I take the core plot of what this movie is and I think of it as directed by You know say like Takashi Mika.
Scott: No wouldn't work.
Scott: Well, I mean this directed by you know Anno.
Scott: No that would work.
Scott: the niche now.
Scott: It wouldn't work.
Rym: This is a movie.
Scott: however Miyazaki wouldn't work.
Rym: where?
Rym: The characters?
Rym: for most of the movie most of the characters do not have any character development at all.
Scott: and yet Well instead of as a poke because instead of doing the character development thing is the character revelation where they're already developed But you don't know them, and then you learn them.
Rym: well Yes, but what I want to say is that in many movies where this would be a flaw Oh She what he has done is made that like one of these Strongest points of the movie like the movie wouldn't work any other way.
Rym: hmm.
Rym: I mean I I'm trying to talk about everything very Circuitously because I don't want to spoil it.
Rym: this movie is fantastic.
Scott: Yeah, cuz this is like you know.
Scott: I'd like to you know discuss the movie in full, but nobody has seen it, so it's like Yeah.
Scott: Anyone who is pretty much on guarantee probably a hundred percent of the listeners except I don't.
Scott: maybe Emily you know it's gonna be spoiled.
Rym: if we say you know what I'm gonna do I'll uh I'll ask some of our friends at Otakon because I'm this is the kind of thing they should show in that 35 millimeter Room and we should oh, that's a good idea.
Scott: I'm gonna have millimeter Otakon sky crawlers.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna.
Scott: Oh, we got to make that app.
Rym: I'm gonna lean on anyone.
Rym: I can lean on to make that happen.
Scott: That's gotta happen.
Scott: That's the way to go.
Scott: well.
Rym: We've got some Special things in store for Otakon possibly next year, but I'm gonna see if that can be part of it.
Scott: We're gonna.
Scott: We're gonna try to make that happen so hard.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Am I?
Rym: emails are going out tonight?
Rym: That's right, but anyway one other interesting thing The people the people who made the ace combat series of games Which is basically for people who don't know.
Scott: katsu really likes those there.
Scott: if you're a fanboy about fighter jets fighting each other Ace combat is like this series long-running series of games in Japan for and I guess also the u.s Yes, you know for ps2 Xbox Xbox 360 etc.
Rym: They are making the sky crawlers game for the Wii.
Scott: Oh, yes, really?
Scott: Yes, really?
Rym: Honestly It's gonna be called sky crawlers innocent aces and Well, that's that's right on target there, okay, I gotta find out what's going on.
Scott: is the head boss the teacher?
Rym: No, this website says it's going to be released in October of 2008.
Scott: So maybe it's out in Japan.
Rym: I'll look into that because I want to play that game possibly.
Scott: Yeah, well you're gonna need a Japanese Wii.
Rym: Yeah, can I mod your Wii?
Scott: you can buy another weed?
Rym: But I don't want to say anymore without.
Rym: I mean eventually.
Rym: I do want to do a final thoughts like a full review.
Scott: the movie gets released on DVD in the u.s.
Scott: Then we'll do a thing.
Scott: Yes, because in fact, I'm sure it will be eventually, right?
Scott: It's a Sony classics and they put out paprika.
Rym: I do.
Scott: So why wouldn't they put out sky crawl?
Rym: I do want to start Suggesting to people kind of like we have the GeekNights book club.
Rym: That's going pretty well.
Rym: I want to warn people and then eventually do full reviews of anime movies because there aren't that many that are widely seen in the US and Reviewing a movie is difficult without spoiling it other than doing what we did now.
Rym: I mean the review.
Rym: it's great.
Rym: Go see it.
Rym: However, if you're not smart, or if you don't like very long atmospheric movies, then you won't like it.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, but this movie will probably be on DVD within 12 months.
Scott: I pretty much can guarantee that.
Rym: so but if you get a chance to see this movie in the theater do not pass that up.
Scott: Yeah, definitely seriously Just for like that, you know the the planes alone and they even in the middle of the movie They put like the biggest plane fight ever Just to have it.
Rym: When that bomber blows up while it's trying to bang It's trying to drop its bombs and then it blows up and then all the bombs blow up and then it blows up so big It blows up the other bomber flying below it.
Scott: They just because most of the you know the most of the fights in the movie air air fights are like a few planes and a Few planes and then the middle of the movie like, you know what?
Scott: a million planes and a million planes.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Also one thing I should point out.
Scott: It's so strange that a movie that has a partially anti otaku message right in a way Is also has is very much of a taco appeal it but then again trick him into watching make him feel bad like Ava.
Rym: Maybe Ava tricked people into watching and then the movie made them feel bad.
Scott: I guess it's like if I made a romantic comedy and then the moral was anyone likes romantic comedies is stupid.
Rym: But one thing I really should point out a good portion of this movie is in English.
Rym: Oh Yeah, which is fine.
Rym: Don't that's not what I want to talk about.
Rym: But there's this guy about that.
Rym: There's this one point where they walk into that diner and it's the same background and look at the animation because the same people are Talking
Scott: but
Rym: this time it's really quiet and this one guy with a really big head and a really big mouth is Saying something very quietly, but just because there was nothing else and because it was a theater and the volume was real high We all heard what the guy said in the background.
Rym: I'm not gonna say what he said.
Rym: Watch for it Listen to what I heard it and I defy you to not crack up his stare.
Scott: I didn't crack up hysterically, but I was like, huh?
Rym: He says it.
Rym: and well, I wouldn't have cracked up if if not for the fact that Did find anything.
Scott: though, you know you talked about that after we left the theater and I very much noticed it.
Scott: You know, it's what you know, you watch a big long movie like this.
Scott: I've only seen it once in the theater.
Scott: You don't remember every little detail, but that was a very small detail that I remembered.
Scott: a whole distinctly remembered it and the fact that Rym brought it up and was so Enthusiastic about it was like wow.
Rym: It wasn't just me.
Rym: the reason I laughed was I was like, uh, and I turned to the left.
Rym: I look at Emily and she's Simultaneously turned to look at me and we both meet eyes and realize we're looking at each other about the same thing.
Rym: Yeah and then we lost.
Scott: it's like everyone.
Scott: everyone noticed this one little thing that was like It couldn't even need to be in the movie.
Scott: It meant nothing for the movie at all.
Rym: Yeah, I I could not even stretch a meaning to place It's just.
Scott: it's basically just noise effectively Plus notable scenes.
Rym: I mean, of course all the dogfights Much like how spider-man had the upside-down kiss this movie has the Kissing along with guns.
Scott: Yep, and also it says right after the great series of scenes in the city Oh my god, the bowling alley.
Scott: Yeah, the bowling alley was great.
Rym: That was Fantastic.
Scott: bowling alley was awesome.
Rym: This movie is really really really.
Scott: the diner was also pretty great like that.
Scott: They're like three or four diner scenes.
Rym: I can't recommend this movie enough.
Rym: If you're an anime fan.
Scott: There's no reason I could recommend it enough.
Scott: It's not like the greatest thing ever, but it's great.
Scott: You definitely want to check this out.
Rym: Well, I think you should see it.
Rym: Anyway, because it's it's good enough to where even if it's not one of the greatest works ever made Anyone who calls himself an anime fan should have seen it.
Rym: There aren't that many anime movies you can see.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, definitely put it up there.
Rym: I Really enjoyed it.
Rym: and now I'm going to bed because it's Tuesday Mr.
Rym: Illusion breaker.
Scott: good.
Scott: I don't have to go and make a post.
Rym: Yeah, but you'll have to make it tomorrow.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I don't want to do anything else tomorrow.
Scott: It'll take like two seconds.
Rym: All right, we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.