Scott: It's Tuesday, September 16th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, PAX08 Part Deux.
Scott: Saturday.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Once again, it's a Tuesday night, and once again, we're talking about PAX.
Rym: What we would have done the previous week if I had not been ill, and what we would have done, I guess, right after PAX, if it weren't for the fact that it took us more than an hour just to talk about Friday at PAX.
Rym: Uh, it's just, we're not gonna do news, we're not, well, we're gonna do things of the day, but I think we really have to just get right into this.
Rym: All I want to say is that if we were doing news, I would talk about the crazy DRM in Spore, but we're not doing a news, so I'm not gonna talk about it.
Rym: We were talking about Saturday at the Penny Arcade Expo 2008.
Scott: So someone in our forum posted this really cool link to TIGsource.com, which is the independent gaming source.
Scott: If you like independent gaming, it's a site you should follow.
Scott: Anyway, they had a competition, the Bootleg Demakes Competition.
Rym: Demake?
Scott: Yeah, basically the idea of this competition was that you made a video game, and the video game you made was a demake of an existing game.
Scott: As, you know, normally, I mean, games these days get lots and lots of remakes and sequels, right, you know?
Scott: But this is a demake.
Scott: Take a game and make a shittier version of it.
Scott: So, like, the example they give sort of on the side is an Atari cartridge that says "Cogs of Conflict" instead of Gears of War.
Scott: Alright, so it's like, what if the new shiny game Gears of War was an old bootleg Atari game because of conflict, right?
Scott: You can download this torrent that has all the games in it, absolutely every one of them.
Scott: You need Windows for the vast majority of them.
Rym: Before any of you think, "Why would I want to download a bunch of joke and stupid
Rym: games?"
Rym: I'm gonna say one thing.
Rym: A lot of those games are actually really fun.
Scott: A lot of these are actually better than a lot of games that you pay for.
Scott: Alright, I mean, there's a game, it's like actually a real RTS, like, for reals.
Scott: You know, some of them are just jokes like "Auntie Falcon's Amateur Rollerboarder 5", which is a Tony Hawk, you know, parody and such.
Scott: But, like, "Advanced Set the Rope on Fire Cartridge" is better than "Set the Rope on Fire".
Rym: Well, it better be.
Rym: It's advanced.
Scott: "Buddy Bass 2" is a 2D Team Fortress 2.
Scott: It's actually really good.
Scott: "Corner's Shiny", right?
Scott: "Mirror's Edge" isn't even out yet.
Scott: They made "Corner's Shiny", which is basically 2D "Mirror's Edge".
Scott: But it's actually, like, a really good platforming, sort of "Ninja Guy" Danish kind of thing.
Rym: I mean, the way I would look at these is, remember "Passage"?
Rym: We talked a lot about it and how, you know, there's games that exist that kind of blur the line between, I guess, game versus art.
Rym: You know, a game that is not just a game or a test of skill.
Scott: Well, any game is art, you know.
Scott: It's like any movie is art, even a really bad one.
Rym: Games are primarily either tests of a skill or idle enjoyments, but then there are games... It's kind of like the difference between a film and a movie or a book and literature.
Scott: It's basically someone made a piece of interactive software for the purposes of artistic expression, you know, as their intent, rather than, you know, entertainment or occupying the brain or anything like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: My favorite one is, you only have to see the screenshot to get the joke, "General Sherman's Redemption".
Scott: Did you see the screenshot for it?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Oh, good God, yes.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, yeah, you definitely, if you have a Windows computer or even if you don't even have Windows, right, just go to the website and look at all the screenshots and the game titles.
Scott: And it's funny, if you actually have Windows, download the torrent and play as many of these as you can.
Scott: Some of them only take like a minute, but some of them are actually, you might keep playing for a long... Some of them have working, good multiplayer.
Scott: Good God.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, Emily turned me on to this, but you know, Japan will have their kind of memes where they'll do something like the caramel dance and where someone did something and then a million people will take like that thing, but replace all the characters in it with characters from something else.
Rym: This time, it's something really long.
Rym: They took this song, this kind of comedic song about going to the convenience store late at night.
Rym: And they basically will take this and take characters from something like you do and put them in it.
Rym: And all I want to say is, one, this video is hilarious.
Rym: Two, it has subtitles.
Rym: You can actually understand what the song is, which of course, it really doesn't make sense if you can't understand Japanese otherwise.
Rym: I don't know what I can say.
Rym: I find this hilarious.
Rym: This is one of the better, weird memes that come out of Japan lately, even though I'm surprised because it's really long.
Rym: The song is like three and a half minutes long.
Rym: It's not like caramel dance, which is just 12 frames of animation.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, this is, they took a song, you know, in the US we have songs like this.
Scott: There's songs that tell a story.
Rym: Like the Chainsaw Juggler.
Scott: Like Chainsaw Juggler.
Rym: You know, whatever happened to the Chainsaw Juggler.
Scott: Or some weird Al songs.
Scott: You know, any kind of Dr.
Scott: Demento kind of fair.
Scott: And there's a song from Japan that's up that alley.
Scott: You know, if there was a Japanese Dr.
Scott: Demento, he'd play that song.
Scott: And I wonder if there is a Japanese Dr.
Scott: Demento.
Rym: I'm sure there is, but it's, one, of all the ones, I'm linking to this on a Tuesday because, one, the anime people probably have already seen this.
Rym: You know, the Wednesday GeekNights listeners.
Rym: But two, they happen to take characters from Smash Brothers.
Rym: It's two link goes to the convenience store.
Rym: And I got to say, to the convenience store.
Rym: It fits really well.
Rym: It's pretty well done.
Rym: I'm not actually going to play the audio in the show for one reason, one reason alone.
Rym: It'll get stuck in your head.
Rym: It's been stuck in my head for like a week.
Scott: And we don't have time.
Rym: It's trivial to do that.
Rym: It's just, it'll get stuck in your head.
Rym: I'm going to warn you now.
Scott: Alright, let's PAX it up.
Rym: So, I can't believe, you know, Friday, all that happened.
Rym: We had more coverage for Friday at PAX than we've had about, I don't know, most conventions we go to.
Scott: And started at 2 o'clock.
Scott: There are conventions we go to at 8am on Friday that have less to say than we had to say about Friday at PAX.
Rym: Saturday, we wake up.
Rym: And, much like Friday, we had plenty of time.
Rym: The con didn't start until 10am.
Scott: I mean, you know, 2pm on Friday is pretty late, you know.
Scott: 10am on Saturday.
Scott: That's earlier than 2, a lot earlier, you know.
Rym: But still, cons we go to, the hotel cons, they usually have stuff starting at like 8 o'clock on Saturday.
Scott: Otakon opens at 7 or 8, right?
Rym: Uh, 9.
Scott: Even so, that's pretty, you know.
Rym: It's weird, all that extra hours.
Rym: Like, everything about PAX is just a little bit off from what I'm used to.
Rym: Most cons I go to, like PAX is just crooked slightly so.
Rym: Yeah, we open at 10, I know everyone else opens at 9.
Scott: By opening at 10, it's like they give you all this time to eat breakfast, and get your shit together, and hang out, and talk, and not do anything.
Scott: It's really weird.
Scott: But it was nice.
Rym: Now, actually Saturday, we spent probably the first time we actually had a chance to really just kinda wander around the con without any goal in mind.
Rym: I mean, there was no event.
Rym: at 10 we wanted to go to.
Rym: We just woke up, wandered over the con, and walked around.
Scott: Well, there actually was the, um, make a strip panel.
Scott: But we didn't make it to make a strip panel.
Rym: Basically, we said, well, we'll see.
Rym: We haven't had to line up for anything really yet to go in.
Rym: So, let's see about this.
Rym: make a strip.
Rym: And let me tell you, the line for the make a strip was frightening.
Rym: It was perhaps the most painful line in the entire convention.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, at the anime conventions, right, the masquerade gets this huge line and fills up the main events.
Scott: At, you know, PAX, they had main events filling events in main events, pretty much the whole con.
Scott: And that was everything most people wanted to do.
Scott: You wanted to go see the Q&As, you wanted to see the keynote, you wanted to see the concerts.
Scott: You know, you wanted to see the make a strip panel, all main events.
Scott: Every day there were at least two main events to go.
Scott: see, right?
Rym: But the make a strip just kind of transcended that.
Rym: I mean, I expected long lines, and we got into the concerts, you know, by the skin of our teeth.
Rym: And we really didn't have to wait in any lines, but there was no way to get into that make a strip for us.
Rym: There was just no way.
Scott: I figure I went to all the main events I wanted to go to, except for the make a strip.
Scott: I made out pretty well.
Scott: I was expecting, I was thinking I was going to be lucky going to one of them because of the insane lines required.
Scott: But I went to all of them but once, that's pretty good.
Rym: Yep, so pretty much we just kind of wandered around the con.
Rym: Now the thing that was really kind of cool was that because the convention center is really tall, there was basically this kind of long, upward angled throughfare where you'd go up escalator, escalator, escalator to all these different levels.
Rym: And then around on the corner on the other side there was the same thing kind of going back down.
Scott: Yeah, there was like a north lobby, there was like a north end of the convention center and a south end, and they were almost separate convention centers.
Scott: Like, to get from one to the other was like woooo, and then it started like the dark world and the light world almost.
Scott: And each side had a tower of escalators going up and down on multiple floors.
Rym: And this is really why I think why so many people could be at PAX and yet it didn't feel nearly as crowded as like Katsucon or Otakon or even ConnectiCon.
Rym: Well, Saturday, ConnectiCon, is that there was so much space associated with the con that just happened to be there.
Rym: Like, pretty much the whole ground floor, there was nothing con down there at all.
Rym: It was just like restaurants and the big mall area.
Rym: And the thing is, that was all effectively, as far as PAX was concerned, convention space.
Rym: If the con was just going on down there, even though PAX had nothing to do with it.
Scott: Yeah, it's just people all over the building, no matter what part of the building it was, except for the one part where there was another convention.
Rym: And there was just this constant stream of people.
Rym: It's kind of like every counter, people are walking, but there were just so many people going up and down.
Rym: The escalators were just a sea of people.
Scott: And the escalators worked the whole time.
Rym: I can't believe that.
Rym: They never broke at all.
Rym: I'm trying to figure out why.
Scott: Because they're modern escalators.
Scott: Things in the west are new, things in the east are old.
Scott: You know when our escalators were made?
Rym: Actually, they were all rebuilt not that long ago, at the BCC at least.
Scott: East coast escalator repairmen suck, that's all I got to say.
Rym: I think there's a little bit more to it.
Rym: I think the crowd and the dynamic of... Not bad?
Rym: No, definitely not bad.
Rym: I think what it is, is that anime conventions in general seem to have people move around more than they did at PAX.
Rym: Because there are more events going on all over the place at different times.
Rym: And at the same time, for many people, depending on what you're into, less to do at any given point.
Rym: So people tend to walk around and walk back and forth a lot.
Rym: But here at PAX, everyone who was walking was on their way somewhere.
Rym: And then when they got there, they stopped and did something.
Rym: You didn't see a lot of people just wandering aimlessly.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people at Rookon wander aimlessly to look at cosplay or to be in cosplay.
Scott: And I do think that cosplay has a lot to do with it.
Rym: Yeah, that's the other thing.
Rym: Remember, no cosplayers.
Rym: There were plenty of cosplayers.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: There was effectively no cosplay.
Rym: In that, when you were just walking around, there was no one getting in your way taking pictures.
Rym: No one would stop and go, "Oh my god, look at that
Rym: cosplay.".
Rym: So as a result, the crowd just moved.
Scott: Yeah, there were people in costume.
Scott: Plenty of them.
Scott: It wasn't the majority.
Rym: It wasn't even the minority.
Rym: It was like 5%.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Not even.
Scott: If you looked around at any given point in time, you would see one or two costumes.
Scott: Depending on where you were and how many people were around at the time.
Rym: I use that term loosely because a lot of the costumes were basically just a guy in a Captain Hammer t-shirt.
Scott: Yeah, but the costumes never got in the way.
Scott: The cosplay had no effect on the con.
Scott: None of the things that cosplay does to a convention were happening.
Rym: But I think part of that was just because there was so little cosplay.
Rym: If there had been a ton of people in costume and an equal number of people trying to take pictures of people, then PAX would have ground to a grinding, blistering, horrible halt.
Scott: Probably.
Rym: But there wasn't really, despite all these space that held people, there weren't that many places to go.
Rym: It seems like there were a small number of high quality places to be at any given point.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, where could you go?
Scott: You go to main events, right?
Scott: You can go to the exhibition hall.
Scott: You can go to the PC room.
Scott: You can go to the console rooms.
Scott: You can go to one of the four tiny panel rooms.
Scott: You can go to the annex.
Scott: You can go to the DS lounge.
Rym: Oh, don't forget, in the annex, on the third floor, we were mystified by this.
Rym: Remember, on level three, there's the Serpent Theatre.
Rym: And right next to it was the mystery space.
Scott: You want to talk about the mystery space?
Rym: We talked about it on the other show.
Rym: It was actually just kind of this lame... It wasn't really that lame, but it was a marketing ploy by someone.
Rym: You go and do these puzzles, and there was a guy chained up who looked like Jesus, answered like riddles and all these mini games.
Rym: A lot of the little kids were hanging out there.
Scott: Yeah, it was alright.
Scott: You know, that kind of thing.
Scott: If I was five years younger, that thing would have been awesome.
Rym: Well, the thing is, at the same time, I would have turned the mystery space into an idea we had that we're probably not going to talk about this show.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: We have an idea.
Rym: There's one thing that was lacking from PAX.
Rym: If you can't figure it out, you'll find out in a future episode.
Rym: But, you know, we got all these places, and we decided, alright, let's go check out every possible thing.
Rym: So we actually went over to the console free play area, which is something I never do at gaming cons.
Rym: For some reason, I just have no desire, when I'm at a gaming con, to walk into a room with a bunch of consoles and play Smash Brothers, which seems like that's what most people do.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, I can play Smash Brothers at home.
Scott: I have friends.
Scott: I own the game.
Scott: Why do I want to spend my precious convention time playing it against people ten thousand times better than me?
Scott: And I know I'm not going to build it.
Scott: It's not, you know, it's like, I'm not one of those people who does it.
Scott: Some people don't want to play against someone better than them because they don't like to lose.
Scott: I don't like to play against people that much better than me because there's no way I can build skill.
Scott: I just die immediately.
Scott: If there was a way I could get better by sitting there and playing and playing and playing, I'd do it.
Scott: But I can't, mostly because you can't just keep sitting there and playing and playing.
Scott: It's loser walks at a convention, you know, because everyone's trying to get more people want time on the machine than there is time on the machine.
Scott: So I don't tend to do those sorts of things.
Rym: Well, part of it, too, is that you walk into any average, you know, gaming room, and there's pretty much, there's like the consoles with the right games that just, there's a line and people playing them constantly.
Rym: And then there's always the other consoles with games people don't really care that much about.
Rym: They just kind of sit there.
Rym: One guy walks up, plays for like two minutes, walks away.
Rym: Someone else walks up, like pokes at it, walks away.
Rym: PAX, once again, has transcended and they did something that I never really see.
Scott: Well, first of all, I was amazed that the console free play rooms, there were a bunch of them, right, on two different floors, I think.
Scott: But they were very, very small.
Scott: I think if you took them all and put them in one room, it would have been smaller than Otakon's video game room.
Rym: By far, Otakon has ten times the console gaming of PAX.
Scott: Yeah, it was crazy.
Scott: I mean, KatsuKon has a lot more console gaming than PAX.
Rym: But yet, you know, you finally walk into these to see what the deal is, and I noticed that any console that's not being played, there's not only no one at it, there's no game in it.
Rym: So we realized that what they've done is you go to a table, you check out a game, and then you get friends, and you go play that game with your friends, and when you're done, you take the game back.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Brilliant!
Scott: It was brilliant.
Scott: And the thing is, the result was that all the rooms where you could check out a game were pretty quiet because no one who didn't have a game checked out was in there, looking around, walking around.
Scott: All the people who didn't have a game yet were in the "get a game" room.
Rym: Yeah, the LFGs.
Scott: Yeah, there were two LFGs, and the LFGs- Yeah, were there three?
Rym: There were three.
Scott: Okay, there were three LFGs, and there were a lot of people in the LFGs, because in there, they sort of did the normal thing, where they had, you know, eight TVs, you know, with games already on them, running all the time, that you could play while you waited for the game you wanted to become available.
Scott: You know, those rooms are a little bit crowded, but pretty much everyone in there was not playing those games because they wanted to play them, but because they were playing them to wait for the game.
Scott: they actually wanted in their number to be called.
Scott: And, you know, I heard that the number calling went a little slowly.
Scott: You know, some people waited, you know, a half hour, maybe an hour for it to actually have their number called after they said what game they wanted, you know, but they think they put a half hour limit on people playing in the console rooms and such.
Scott: So, you know, they pretty much, you know, move people as quickly as they could, you know, pretty well every console and every one of the console free play rooms is being used all the time, at least that any, as long as someone was wanting to use it.
Scott: And that was it, you know, not if everyone at the con wanted to play a console, it wouldn't have worked, but not everyone wanted to play.
Rym: But just this idea of check out a game, it's kind of like the board game area, which at most cons they do this, where you check out a board game that you want to play and get people to play it with you.
Rym: So there was this, the culture was just completely different and it was more a vehicle to meet cool people and hang out with them than it was a vehicle to see who's the best of Smash Brothers.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And the other cool thing about it was like, you could go and if like, if you met someone at the con and you were like, hey, you know, want to play some of this, you could just play some of that no matter what that was.
Scott: Pretty much no matter what that was.
Scott: I mean, I think they obviously didn't have every video game ever.
Rym: No matter what that was, because, you know, they had like the five or whatever console rooms on one floor, but on the other floor they had the two special free play rooms.
Rym: One of them was the leaderboard room.
Rym: They actually kept track of who was winning all these games.
Rym: There's this giant leaderboard.
Scott: You could win prizes, couldn't you?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I didn't even pay attention to that.
Scott: I never went in the leaderboard room, but there was.
Rym: no, it existed, but they had big monitors and they were keeping track.
Rym: It was really cool.
Rym: But they also had the classic console room.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Who was running that room?
Rym: I don't know, but it was right.
Scott: They had a sign run by so-and-so sorry.
Scott: So-and-so I forgot who you were, but what they did is they actually had hours on Friday and their hours and Friday were less than the hours of the con and their hours and Saturday also looked to be relative,
Rym: but it was crossed out in marker and rewritten until 2 a.m
Scott: And it exactly, they decided that they were so awesome that on Saturday they were going to forego their original plan of doing weak ass hours and do kick ass hours instead.
Scott: So mad props to those guys.
Rym: So Scott says, Hey, I wonder if they have kaboom.
Rym: And I said, there's no fucking way they have kaboom.
Rym: So we walk up there and you know, we were looking around and we see all these old consoles.
Rym: I mean, when they said classic, it was classic.
Rym: It was like every console you would have wanted to play.
Rym: I can say one thing, that room seemed more popular on average than the other rooms.
Scott: Well, cause I think it was a little easier in the other rooms, you know, you had less waiting.
Rym: Well, no, I think it's more that older games, a lot of those competitive old, like NES games are much more conducive to quick pickup competitive play.
Scott: Also that, you know, uh, those are games that you can't just play at home easily if you're some noob kid and you're not old school.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, NES roms easy, but some of that stuff, not so easy.
Scott: I mean, if you just had an Atari Jaguar, I'd say Katsu Kan, he just put it there with a game in it.
Scott: People would play it a lot just for the novel.
Rym: We did that.
Rym: We brought my Atari 7,800 to Katsu Kan last year.
Rym: We put it up to this gigantic flat screen TV, and there were people like in awe of it.
Rym: We had an ET tournament as a result.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But, uh, so we're walking around and we look in the corner and sure enough, there's the Atari 2,600.
Rym: Kaboom is in it.
Rym: And there's a bunch of people playing it and yelling at each other.
Scott: The only Atari 2,600, at least the only one I saw.
Rym: What are the odds?
Scott: So of course I walk over the moment we walk in there too.
Scott: Those guys weren't in there the whole con.
Scott: They were there at the time we walked in there.
Scott: The only time we walked in there looking for Kaboom.
Scott: The Kaboom guys happened to be there at that time.
Rym: Kaboom is not a well known and popular game.
Scott: It's well known and popular, but it's not at the top of the list.
Scott: It's like, you know, second or third tier of old school.
Rym: It's one of those games where people will meet and they'll be like you Kaboom.
Rym: I Kaboom too.
Rym: Let's Kaboom together.
Scott: So, of course, likes to Kaboom with you.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: So I walk over there and I'm like, I see you guys are playing Kaboom.
Rym: And they're like, yeah, yeah, we are.
Rym: And I'm like, I don't think you understand how fucking good I am at Kaboom.
Rym: And they all go and they look at the one guy and they're like, I don't think you understand how good this guy is.
Rym: And the guy's like, what's your highest score?
Rym: And I'm like 90,000 something.
Rym: He's like 100,000 something.
Rym: And we kind of stare each other down.
Rym: And I'm about ready to throw down.
Rym: This is going to be like the best thing ever.
Rym: And he says, we can't play.
Rym: These paddles are broken.
Scott: That's pretty typical for an Atari 2600.
Rym: This is the third set we've tried.
Rym: There aren't any more.
Rym: And I say, then he's like, you want to play anyway?
Rym: And I'm like, how broken are they?
Rym: He's like, you'll see.
Scott: Were they more broken than ours?
Rym: Let me put it this way, cause Scott watched this epic battle.
Rym: I was player two.
Rym: He was player one.
Rym: I've been known to play Kaboom for like a half hour straight.
Rym: And this guy might have even been better than me because his absolute high score was a little bit higher than my absolute high score.
Scott: I think his high score was way higher than yours if I remember.
Scott: 10,000 more?
Scott: No, I think it was a lot more.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, so he got like 130 and I got like 150.
Rym: They were so broken.
Scott: We really need to get some like Atari 2600 controllers in the box.
Rym: It was so sad.
Rym: It was like watching Wayne Gretzky play hockey against Wayne Gretzky, but he was given a one inch.
Rym: They were both given one inch long sticks and the net was smaller than the puck.
Rym: Yeah, that's basically what it felt like.
Scott: It was real sad.
Rym: But at least I shook hands with the only person I've ever met in my entire life, other than my father, who had a chance of beating me at Kaboom.
Rym: I was excited.
Rym: I didn't have a business card.
Rym: So Kaboom guy, if you happen to hear this at all, drop me a line.
Rym: I will totally make sure we have a tournament.
Scott: Some I see on eBay, this guy claims Atari 2600, quote, jitter free paddles.
Scott: Work fab.
Scott: Oh, whatever.
Rym: I figured out I actually cracked open a third party once.
Rym: I'm just going to buff that thing.
Rym: I think it'll work fine.
Scott: Here's another people.
Scott: New set of paddles.
Scott: Right.
Scott: New, they say in box.
Rym: But just think about the magic of packs.
Rym: What are the odds that I ran into the one awesome dude at Kaboom and his posse of shit talking friends when I am ready with my shit talking friends to bust out some Kaboom?
Scott: Yeah, it's good times.
Scott: If only Mega Man 2 was competitive.
Rym: We should make competitive Mega Man 2.
Scott: We should.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So I want to take a point because I said the serpent theater and, you know, our panel was in the Wolfman theater.
Rym: The theaters all had names, the Wolfman, the serpent, the.
Rym: I don't remember what the other ones were.
Scott: I got him.
Scott: Give me a second.
Scott: The raven and the serpent walrus, raven walrus, serpent Wolfman.
Rym: So, you know, I was curious about that because when we originally got our letter about, hey, you guys are going to do this panel.
Rym: It just said, you know, auxiliary theater or whatever.
Rym: And it gave me a room number.
Rym: And then apparently at some point the name, the rooms all got names.
Rym: And someone asked about that at the Q and A. And I believe the answer that Tycho gave.
Rym: when Gabe said, yeah, where did those names come from?
Rym: He was like, yeah, I kind of just decided they should have names.
Rym: So I kind of named them all at the last second.
Scott: Yeah, on his own.
Rym: So thus we got to perform in the Wolfman theater.
Scott: They should like put a big Wolfman up there or something.
Rym: I don't know, because to the geek, it's the Wolfman.
Rym: But to like the people in my office, when I told them I'm doing this panel, it was the Wolfman.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like Marv Wolfman.
Rym: I don't even know who that is.
Scott: That's a comic book writer.
Scott: He's not.
Scott: I don't like him, but other people.
Scott: Like Teen Titans and such.
Rym: Yeah, but panels, much like everything else being different at PAX, the panels at PAX were handled very differently from panels at any other convention.
Rym: I think we mentioned this, but they had a gap between every single panel, which was basically the time for the professional panelists to tear down their panel and leave.
Rym: Well, the incoming professional panelists set up their panels so that every single panel began with a crowd walking into people ready to roll.
Scott: Yeah, there was a 30 minute gap between every single panel and then they were staggered.
Scott: So two rooms, right, would have panels starting at one time.
Scott: And then a half hour later, the other rooms that have a panel starting and then a half hour later, the other panels would have a panel starting, you know, so that way it wasn't.
Scott: They all start at the same time.
Scott: And then if you don't like the one you're in, well, there's, you know, two others you can go to without missing the beginnings of them.
Scott: So if you went to say Warhammer Online Age of Reckoning at two thirty, I got the schedule open here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you didn't like it.
Scott: Well, you couldn't go to democratizing game development because that also started at two thirty.
Scott: But you could go get in line for movie nerdcore rising or make the world notice, you know, and you'd be all set.
Rym: Well, you might be except that for the maybe not the vast majority of panels, but for all the panels that were in any way popular.
Rym: If you weren't there 45 minutes or more before the event in line, there was no way you were getting in.
Scott: Well, some of the panel rooms like the Serpent Theater was actually pretty big and you could.
Scott: there was a lot of standing room in the back.
Scott: You know, like we all we were standing in the back that there was going to be the well beaten panel, but we didn't want to hang around.
Scott: So we left, but we could have stood in the back for that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But at the same time, those panel rooms, because they weren't in dedicated rooms, they were kind of loud and they're actually kind of difficult to hear the present.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There was the other.
Scott: What was the other theater?
Scott: Was it the Raven, I think, or the walrus?
Scott: that I think was the walrus one that had the.
Scott: it was sort of in a corner next to a D.S.
Scott: lounge.
Scott: Just open, completely open.
Scott: So you could just walk past it and see what was going on.
Rym: It was pretty much the worst panel room.
Rym: Like, I would have felt terrible if I was presenting in that room.
Scott: I'm real glad that wasn't the Wolfman Theater.
Scott: I would have been pissed.
Rym: Yeah, because the panel, of course, the panel I saw that were there looked like it would have been really awesome, except for the fact that it was kind of loud.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Panels need to be in closed rooms with doors.
Rym: Of course, at the same time, I think next next packs, they're going to have larger panel rooms because part of the reason they didn't have good panel rooms was that there was that other convention using the top floor of the convention center for no good reason.
Scott: Yeah, packs really needed those rooms, but they needed them badly.
Rym: I mean, by and large, the panels.
Rym: I mean, we didn't get to go, obviously, to any panels.
Rym: But what everyone said was that the panels were generally super professional and really, really, really awesome.
Scott: Well, I mean, if you look, the vast majority of the panels were run by industry people, you know, either by people who are pimping out their own games or people, you know, people from a bunch of different companies who all made the same kind of game or all were interested in the same.
Scott: You know, the topic in gaming and they all discussed it together, you know, and stuff like that.
Scott: There wasn't a whole lot of fan panels and stuff like that.
Rym: I mean, like democratizing game development, the art of the dungeon master, sex and video games, a comparative study, the giant bomb reunion.
Rym: Honestly, a lot of people were talking about that.
Rym: I'd never heard of the giant bomb in my life.
Rym: Me either.
Rym: And then when everyone explained to me what it was, I still really wasn't sure what it was.
Scott: Here, I'm picking a random panel here that actually has the people listed.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Video games and piracy issues for an increasingly complex world.
Scott: Panelists include Dennis McCauley, moderator.
Scott: OK.
Scott: Oh, and he's also the editor of GamePolitics.com.
Scott: Ah, that's a good site.
Scott: Jason Della Rocca, the executive director, International Game Developers Association.
Scott: Jennifer Mercurio Esquire, director, Government Affairs, Entertainment Consumer Association.
Scott: Chris Melissinos, chief gaming officer at Sun Microsystem.
Scott: So that's the kind of panel quality you're looking at at PAX, not like at even Otakon.
Scott: It'll be like, you know, yeah, the fan sub panel by some guys who've been doing it for the past few years.
Scott: The fans just like you.
Scott: It's just.
Rym: I got to say I wanted to go to the majority of these panels.
Rym: I couldn't just because I was doing other things and because you had to wait in line.
Rym: But other people like most of the people who were going to these panels were real excited about the panels.
Rym: And pretty much every panel had a lot of people excited about it.
Rym: And I don't know, in general, I feel as though other conventions could learn from this.
Rym: I mean, at first I was really dubious.
Rym: I thought this staggering meant, wow, there's going to be a lot fewer panels.
Rym: But no, all it meant was that the panels that were there were amazing and professional and great.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much perfect.
Rym: And I feel like every convention in the world could learn from this.
Rym: quality matters a thousand times more than quantity.
Rym: Half as many amazing panels is worth a lot more.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, if you have a billion panels at your card and everyone has something to do all the time.
Scott: Well, on the one hand, they start to feel worse after a certain point because they're not being able to do things they wanted to do.
Scott: People are much happier if they get to do the things they want to do.
Scott: And if you have less things, even if you have way too many people, we'll just have less things in bigger rooms and such.
Scott: People will feel a lot better if they can sort of plan out their day.
Scott: There's only one thing they want to do at any given time and they get to do it.
Scott: Rather than a million things to do, the quality is questionable.
Scott: If the quality is not questionable, then no matter what people's decision is, they'll be happy.
Scott: If people go to a panel and it's no good and they chose that over another panel, now they'll feel really bad because they chose something bad over something else that might have been good.
Scott: they don't know.
Rym: And the one thing I can say is that FRC people who didn't go to PAX, if this is any indication, these are people who by and large do not go to panels at conventions, seemed really interested and/or excited in all these panels and they wish they could have gone just to go to some of them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I'll admit, I really wanted to go to the panel right before ours, actually.
Rym: The Art of the Dungeon Master.
Scott: Had some Motzy peoples on it.
Rym: Yeah, we actually couldn't get into the room because that panel had a line similar to the line for our panel.
Scott: And it was completely full when we showed up and they didn't let us in until it let out.
Scott: And yeah, okay.
Scott: So of course, the biggest thing at PAX.
Scott: Oh, we should talk about this other thing first, right?
Scott: So even though we didn't really go to any panels, we were hanging around a lot.
Scott: Mostly near the Serpent Theatre, because it was just sort of open and near the tabletop gaming annex.
Scott: And in the Serpent Theatre, we happened to see parts of two early rounds of the Omega-Thon.
Rym: See, I had basically decided, and Scott agreed, there's so much awesome at PAX that we kind of had to pick and choose.
Rym: But it was picking between a bunch of awesome options as opposed to picking between a bunch of unknown quantities.
Rym: So we decided to generally not worry about seeing the Omega-Thon at all, except for the final round.
Rym: But we ended up accidentally seeing two of the rounds.
Scott: We didn't see the whole rounds, but we were standing there for a significant part of some of the rounds.
Scott: Two of them, specifically.
Rym: So, boom blocks.
Rym: All I want to say is that green guy got totally hosed and it totally wasn't his fault.
Scott: I know, I was basically watching this boom block start and I can't really tell exactly how it works.
Scott: I'd never played it, and I would buy it if it was cheaper, but it's still like $45, so fuck that.
Scott: Basically, the first player threw their block at green.
Scott: The next player threw at green.
Scott: Then it was green's turn.
Scott: Green, like, failed to throw somehow.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: if they didn't know how to play or if there was something with their Wiimote, I don't know.
Scott: But green failed to make a throw.
Scott: The fourth player threw at green.
Scott: And I was just like, "Oh, this isn't a game.
Scott: This is just a luck or skill.
Scott: It's a game of pick on one
Scott: person.".
Rym: Well, the thing is, the other game of boom blocks progressed in a similar way.
Rym: I'd wondered, I thought about this a lot, because I didn't try to be an omega naught or anything.
Rym: I wondered, how would I be if I was an omega naught?
Rym: Because part of me, when I play board games or video games or anything, especially when there's something on the line as opposed to just prize.
Scott: Yeah, remember, trip to Tokyo on the line.
Scott: Be evil.
Scott: You must be evil and you're not going to win.
Rym: Yes, it's not just I get to laugh at Scott instead of him laughing at me.
Rym: It's, "I get to go to Tokyo.
Rym: None of these people
Rym: do.".
Scott: Yeah, there's pretty much two equivalent game theory options in a situation like that.
Scott: Option number one, be a dick.
Scott: Do absolutely everything you need to win.
Scott: Don't give a shit.
Scott: Use your skill to your max.
Scott: Win, win, win, win, win.
Scott: Right?
Scott: The other equivalent strategy is trust that you have enough skill to win when you need to.
Scott: Act like you're not so great.
Scott: That way people won't gang up on you because you're not so great.
Scott: They'll gang up on the much stronger player and use your skill to always stay alive by a hair until the final round where you whip out your full skill.
Rym: Now, I'm not going to get into the game theory rationale behind this, but that particular round of boom blocks, the one Scott was referring to, even though the other one progressed almost the exact same way, was exactly as vicious as I would have been and it was so cold and calculating and it proved everything I know about game theory in the real world.
Rym: The first players chose green and said, I'm going to attack green and I'll bet they made a very calculated decision.
Rym: I'm not sure if they knew the other omega knots better than we knew the other omega knots, but the next players, the one who proved it because the next player looked at the situation.
Rym: And remember from the way this route, from what I gather, the way this round worked was four people play boom box blocks.
Rym: The top two go on.
Rym: The bottom two are kicked out of the omega thon.
Scott: Yeah, and there's basically two simultaneous games of boom blocks.
Scott: You had four people on the left, four people on the right.
Rym: You're not trying to win.
Rym: You are trying to make two other people lose.
Rym: So as a result, the strategy is make friends with someone, hopefully someone who actually you think sucks at the other games.
Scott: But someone who thinks that they're better than you.
Rym: And king make.
Rym: I lie up and if I had been up there, I would have turned to player two and said, I will attack green.
Rym: If you also attack green, then we will be able to move on together.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And that is what happened.
Rym: And it was so wonderfully.
Rym: game theory.
Rym: Delicious.
Rym: Everyone getting is.
Scott: if you have been player three or player four, you would have been S.O.L Yes.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: That is how game theory works.
Rym: Because you have to jump on the opportunity.
Rym: You have to be a dick.
Rym: If the dog is down, kick that dog, because if you all gang up on green, you've reduced your chances of being eliminated from the omega by half by a quarter.
Scott: Well, depending on what kind of chances of getting kicked out were two and four.
Scott: And now your chances of getting kicked out are actually one in three.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So that's why I was avoiding the statistics.
Rym: But suffice to say, the proper way to act is to seize upon weakness and be merciless.
Rym: And I was so proud of player two.
Rym: I want to find out who player two was in that round, and I hope it's my man.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So then the other game we saw played in the Omega Thon was Geometry Wars.
Scott: And they played the mode in Geometry Wars where the sort of invincible shields bubbles appear.
Scott: And basically Geometry Wars is Robotron, but really flashy with lots and lots of lines and vectors and all over the place.
Scott: And it's actually a game of skill.
Scott: One of the few skill games in the Omega Thon.
Rym: In fact, it was really the first game that was actually really a game of skill.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And basically these bubbles appear.
Scott: And if you go in the bubble, you're invincible.
Scott: So the basic idea with the game was go in the bubble, the bubble shrinking, get out of it before it kills you.
Scott: Go to another bubble that just opened up without dying on your way there and shoot as many bad guys as possible to get lots of points.
Rym: Now, let me tell you, because obviously they'd all practiced.
Rym: That was some epic Geometry Wars play like it.
Rym: There is nothing great.
Scott: You know, when the audience is watching a game and they go, oh, there was a lot of O's going on.
Rym: In video gaming, then playing or spectating among incredibly skilled players at a game.
Rym: If there are four people who are similarly skilled at a game of skill.
Rym: Well, I guess you couldn't be skilled at a game of chance.
Rym: And they are competing against each other and there's an audience who is knowledgeable about the game.
Rym: That is some really good entertainment right there.
Scott: Well, I mean, not everyone playing was as good as all the other guys.
Scott: There were, you know, clearly some people were better at the Geometry Wars than others.
Scott: I got to say this, but they're all better than me.
Rym: In the game we watched, the player who was yellow, that was some crazy.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: Yeah, yellow pulled off this crazy crazy.
Rym: Yellow is going to die.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Yellow just.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Yellow is good.
Rym: Yellow just avoided that.
Rym: Like yellow would be in the corner surrounded by bad guys about to die.
Rym: Suddenly everyone else is dead.
Scott: Yellow's left and yellow's left in a bubble.
Scott: And it's like, oh, it's all right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If you don't do other things at PAX, the Omega-thons, especially the later rounds.
Scott: It's worth your time to go.
Rym: Totally worth it.
Scott: I imagine I didn't go to the Jenga round.
Scott: I imagine the Jenga round would have been mad intense.
Scott: Just watching these people thinking it's going to fall, man.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: So I point out at this point that we had not yet been to the exhibition room.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Now, the exhibition room at PAX is much fabled.
Scott: You know, basically people act like it's the new E3.
Scott: It is.
Rym: It is the new E3.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But, you know, they act like it's this gigantic room.
Scott: You get all the big video game companies are there and they are.
Scott: And they all bring the games that in olden days they would have brought to E3.
Scott: Games that aren't out yet.
Scott: You know, games they really want to sell.
Scott: Big fancy booths, the whole thing.
Scott: And they do.
Scott: But really, the exhibition hall was about as big as the New York Comic-Con.
Scott: It wasn't really that big square footage wise.
Scott: You know, I wasn't like impressed by the size.
Scott: I was able to cover the whole room pretty much.
Scott: I wasn't able to play every single game because I would have had to wait in lots of lines at many of the booths and a lot of the games weren't worth playing.
Scott: But I saw every booth.
Rym: But at the same time it was concentrated awesome.
Rym: It wasn't like a dealer's room.
Rym: I mean, the analogy of the exhibition hall to any other con is that's the dealer's room.
Rym: But there weren't actually that many people selling things.
Rym: It was mostly exhibitions.
Rym: It was people showing things off.
Scott: Well, they were advertising.
Scott: They were selling them.
Scott: But they weren't selling them right then and there.
Scott: They were trying to sell you on them so that you would later go to GameStop and buy them.
Rym: Yeah, but the people were actually selling things.
Rym: Like PinkGodzilla was selling some stuff and there was like one...
Scott: Namco was selling their Pac-Man merch.
Rym: There was one anime dealer selling like anime stuff.
Rym: And oh my god, those people rake it in because they were the only people there.
Scott: The people who were selling the retro video game stuff.
Scott: That was about it.
Rym: Yeah, it was mostly Nintendo.
Rym: Play games that aren't out yet.
Rym: Play Fallout.
Rym: Oh my god, play Fallout.
Rym: Play Iron Jeff DS.
Scott: Play Left 4 Dead.
Scott: Oh my god, Left 4 Dead.
Rym: Play Starcraft 2.
Scott: Oh my god, Starcraft 2.
Scott: Play World of Warcraft expansion.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Probably the most sought after booth in this entire exhibition hall I think would have been booth 632.
Rym: The Fallout 3 booth.
Scott: Well, it's either the Fallout booth or the Left 4 Dead booth.
Scott: It's a tough call.
Scott: Tough call.
Scott: They both had long lines the whole time.
Rym: While they had similarly long lines, there were a lot more Fallouts to play.
Rym: So I think there were more people all told.
Rym: And also, the Fallout booth was the only way to get the Fallout puppet.
Scott: Not too many people got it.
Rym: Yes, the Fallout puppet was perhaps the greatest status symbol you could have at that con.
Rym: Other than an all access badge or an Omegathon shirt.
Scott: I was going to say, an Omegathon shirt is a pretty big status symbol.
Rym: The puppet was number 3 in terms of standing out in the crowd.
Scott: Pretty much, yeah.
Rym: Well, I guess number 4 was being me and Scott.
Rym: No, just kidding.
Rym: No, not even close.
Scott: No one noticed us at all except for our listeners and people at our panel.
Rym: Yeah, but all the people at the panel.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: So, the Fallout booth.
Rym: I don't think you understand the tonight.
Rym: There were people in that line.
Rym: There were people lined up well before the exhibition hall opened on all three days.
Rym: To get into the exhibition hall the second it opened in order to line up to then hours later play Fallout 3.
Scott: That's actually not a bad idea.
Scott: Because look, the exhibition hall opens pretty much when the con opens, right?
Scott: So, if you wait in line before the con opens, you're not really losing any con in that line.
Scott: If you are really early in that line and you get to be really early in the Fallout line.
Scott: You could play Fallout at like maybe 10.05, 10.10 in the morning.
Scott: And thus, you won't lose any of your con, any significant portion of it, and you'll get to play Fallout.
Scott: If you had tried to go play Fallout at pretty much any other time, you would have to wait for like an hour maybe.
Scott: Half hour to an hour.
Scott: A long, long time.
Scott: You would have lost a significant portion of con time to just play this game.
Scott: So, waiting in line before the con to play Fallout or Left 4 Dead or Starcraft 2 was a pretty good idea.
Scott: And the people doing it were pretty smart.
Scott: I just didn't want to play those games badly enough to wait in those lines.
Rym: But I did want to play them every time I walked into this room.
Rym: I didn't want to play them just that badly.
Rym: But I'd walk into the room and be like, "Oh my god, I want to play Fallout.
Rym: Oh my god, I want to play
Rym: Fallout.".
Rym: And then I'd see the line, and it's bigger than any line I've ever really wanted to stand in in my life.
Scott: Well, it's not that it was physically large.
Scott: I mean, it was pretty large.
Rym: Well, bigger in terms of how long it would take.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's because people are playing a game.
Rym: I'll put it this way.
Scott: And then they stop, and then one person goes and plays.
Rym: It's not even that it would have taken that long.
Rym: It's that the opportunity cost at PAX, what I would have had to ma- I mean, I waited four hours to ride a rollercoaster once, but I wasn't missing anything.
Rym: I was missing other rollercoasters that I'd already ridden.
Rym: At PAX, every second I wasn't doing something, and I was standing in line instead, I was missing something.
Scott: We paid a lot of money to go to Seattle and stay in a hotel.
Scott: You can't waste a single moment of that incredibly short trip that you used all your vacation days on.
Rym: But luckily, I will say this.
Rym: Every single person I talked to who played Fallout was so excited about Fallout that I- Hold on, three by the way.
Rym: Yes, Fallout, not Fallout 1, which was fun when I was young.
Scott: I tried to play it recently.
Scott: Let me tell a little story.
Scott: Fallout 1 is a game I tried to play a long time ago, and then I tried to play it again a year at RIT once.
Scott: And then I tried to play it very, very recently.
Scott: The last time Scott Johnson was over our house, he got it on GameTap for me with his account so I could try it again.
Scott: I did a little better this time, but that is a game that I just cannot play.
Scott: I just completely fail at that game entirely.
Scott: I need someone to really help me.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I just can't figure it out.
Scott: I just die immediately.
Scott: I can't figure out where I'm going.
Scott: It's too open-ended.
Scott: It's not my deal.
Scott: Maybe Fallout 3 will be a little better for me.
Scott: Fallout 1 was not.
Rym: But suffice to say, I am real excited about Fallout 3 because I feel like just based on the booth, if the booth is any indication, they know what it was that made Fallout good, and they know what parts of Fallout needed to go away and were just limitations of technology.
Rym: I think the game is going to be amazing, but I reserve judgment until I play it.
Scott: I am more excited about Left 4 Dead.
Scott: Oh man, Left 4 Dead.
Scott: I knew Valve was making a zombie game.
Scott: That's what I knew.
Scott: And I had seen maybe some videos and some screenshots.
Scott: I stood there watching people play a game of Left 4 Dead together, just seeing the people inside the door waiting at the door that they can't close for the final person to get in the door so they can close it.
Scott: That's some good gameplay right there.
Rym: Oh my god, I don't even want to get into it, but we saw game mechanics that made us drool.
Rym: What do zombie first person shooters need to be good?
Rym: They need objectives that don't suck.
Rym: They need zombies coming up to hell right now!
Rym: Prez!
Rym: They killed your parents!
Rym: Oh my god, did this game have that.
Rym: It had everything I want in a zombie game.
Scott: If you have a copy of Steam, and Half Life 2 works on your computer, and you don't buy Left 4 Dead, you're an idiot.
Rym: Because even if it sucks, this is the best chance zombie first person shooters have ever had.
Scott: It's pretty much going to be win.
Scott: I can almost guarantee it.
Rym: And if it isn't, well, I'm going to take that chance.
Scott: There were other games that were big, like Starcraft 2.
Scott: I looked at it a little bit, and I didn't really see enough of it to make any sort of judgement on it.
Scott: I can talk about Starcraft 2 videos that I saw online before the time.
Rym: I can say this, the people in line to play Starcraft 2 were Starcraft people.
Rym: You could look at them and be like "wow".
Scott: I was watching some videos online of Starcraft 2 and some of the things they're changing in it and whatnot, and I was actually starting to feel good about it, because I was like "yeah, yeah, yeah".
Scott: I think so too.
Rym: I feel like Starcraft 2, at least based on what I saw, because I stood over someone's shoulder and watched them play like 10 minutes of it, it might be another instance of knowing what it is that made the original Starcraft popular, and distilling that into modern technology.
Scott: Yeah, well that's all Blizzard does is distill.
Rym: Yes, but again...
Scott: I was reminded recently, there's a good RTS...
Rym: Oh, this is so sad.
Scott: There's an RTS in that bootleg demakes package.
Scott: that's actually a real RTS.
Scott: It's playable and has multiplayer.
Rym: Scott told me about this, but I'll just interject by pointing out that I did check this out, I played it.
Rym: This is pretty much, it is like, I would call it an RTS.
Rym: It is like the most generic, and this is the core of a basic RTS.
Scott: It's a baby RTS, basically.
Scott: I tried to play it, and I was playing it as well as I thought I could play it.
Scott: I tried real hard, real hard, and basically it was "alright, I've built a bunch of ships,
Scott: attack!".
Scott: They have a million times the number of ships I have, they killed me instantly, then they came and attacked me.
Rym: Oh my god, I got a fighter jet, let's go.
Rym: And they've got planets made out of fighter jets just waiting for it.
Scott: I just suck so much at RTSs.
Scott: It's just the building things fast enough, I just can't do it for some reason.
Rym: I've realized something, Scott, because you also suck at turn-based games.
Scott: I don't suck at turn-based games as much as real-time.
Rym: The thing is, turn-based games do not exemplify and bring out the flaws as much, because they're turn-based.
Rym: But when we play Advance Wars, you'll always be like, "Hey, Rym, I'm coming, I'm doing well, I'm doing
Rym: well.".
Rym: And then your one infantry gets to the middle of the map, ready to capture the cities in the middle.
Rym: And I've got four mega tanks sitting there, I've got 50 units maxed out, aircraft carriers all over the map.
Scott: I don't know how it works, I just can't figure out how to get things as quickly as people do in RTSs.
Rym: Or turn-based games.
Scott: Part of it is clicking fast, but there's something else, maybe my brain is just broken in some way.
Rym: Scott, it's a defect of the womb.
Scott: Who knows what it is.
Scott: And because of that, I think I might not end up buying Starcraft 2 or whatever.
Scott: But that's only a fault in me, not a fault in the game.
Rym: Enough speculation.
Rym: We shouldn't talk about games we didn't play.
Scott: Like LittleBigPlanet, which I didn't play?
Rym: Oh my god, do I want to play LittleBigPlanet, do I want to own it, do I want to touch it?
Scott: They had it on one screen on a dev console.
Rym: There was a crowd around that screen cheering and screaming, and oh my god are people into this game.
Rym: And you know what, it looks like it's really legitimate.
Rym: Anyway, games we played, Scott and I went over to the Nintendo booth and we decided, why don't we both play two different games in order to maximize.
Rym: So I went over and played the new Mario baseball.
Rym: All I want to say is Baseball Simulator 1000 is better than this game.
Scott: But, basically the pitch- You were saying better things about it at the con.
Rym: Well, no, it's fun.
Rym: The pitching is really good.
Rym: The batting is really good.
Scott: Is it better than Wii Sports Baseball?
Rym: Oh my god, yes.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: The fielding feels really, really, really automatic.
Scott: Oh, so there's basically no fielding.
Rym: Well the thing is, the guy running out and catching the ball, or getting to the ball, feels almost 100% automatic.
Rym: But the decisions of where to throw the ball when, and all the kind of strategic stuff, was really well done.
Rym: So, I don't think it's a buy when it comes out game, but I think it's a buy about halfway through its life cycle when it's $10 cheaper game.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is, Mario Golf for the GameCube was one of those games where I'm like, I'll buy this when it's $20.
Rym: It's still $50.
Scott: Well it's not, but I just never bought it.
Rym: Yeah, well I think the problem is that, while I like these games, we don't get enough play out of Mario Soccer, which is a fantastic game.
Scott: Yeah, we gotta play that some more.
Rym: We're gonna play that this weekend.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: We're playing it.
Rym: That, and we're playing Mario Tennis, because once again, there's no way anyone can beat Team Rym and Scott.
Rym: At least in the front row crew.
Scott: Mario Tennis is the epic win.
Rym: Oh my god, I love those games.
Scott: So yeah, I- So, while Rym was playing Mario Baseball, I mean they had other games there.
Scott: They had the new Animal Crossing.
Scott: They had some other games that weren't even made by Nintendo.
Scott: You know, I forget exactly.
Scott: The only game I cared about was Wario Shake It.
Scott: Now, I don't know if people realize, listening to this podcast, that I am like the Wario fanboy.
Scott: And I'm not talking about Wario where, you know, I'm not talking about, I don't know, like playing as Mario in Mario Party or Smash Brothers.
Rym: Those Wario games for like the Game Boy that were crazy awesome.
Scott: Here's some history knowledge that you should, people, it's important to know, right?
Scott: Super Mario Brothers, that's the old game on the NES that came with Duck Hunt, right?
Scott: Super Mario World, that is the game for the Super Nintendo with Yoshi.
Scott: Super Mario Land, Super Mario Land is that Game Boy game, original Game Boy game with the Sphinxes and the submarine and the helicopter, remember that one?
Scott: The original Mario game for the Game Boy.
Rym: That wasn't a helicopter, it was a tiny biplane.
Scott: Anyway, that's Super Mario Land.
Scott: Super Mario Land 2, the six golden coins, was a great Game Boy game.
Scott: It was a Mario game.
Scott: The boss of that game was Wario.
Scott: The first appearance of Wario was the boss of the six golden coins.
Scott: Super Mario Land 3 was called Wario Land.
Scott: It was Wario Land 1, right?
Scott: People don't realize that, that Super Mario Land 3 was Wario Land 1.
Scott: That's the one where you're Wario and is the genie and the whole thing.
Scott: Then there was Wario 2, one of the greatest platforming games to ever exist, ever.
Scott: It came out for Game Boy, but it was also one of those half Game Boy Color, half Game Boy games.
Scott: Then there was Wario Land 3, which was a Game Boy Color only game.
Scott: Then there was Wario Land 4, which is a Game Boy Advance only game.
Scott: Neither of those were really as great as Wario 2.
Scott: They were just sort of more of the same and kind of eh.
Scott: Wario Land 4, especially for the GBA, was pretty eh.
Scott: I think because they were eh, they held off.
Scott: Notice how they switched over on the GBA to WarioWare instead of Wario Land.
Scott: They stopped making Wario Land games.
Scott: I mean, it was a really crappy Wario game for the GameCube, but ignore that, right?
Scott: So where did Wario Land, the 2D platforming Wario go?
Scott: He went to the Wii and Wario Land shake it for the Wii.
Scott: This is a Wii game, a real Wii game.
Scott: You're going to have to pay 50 bucks to get it on disc, right?
Scott: Not some WiiWare action.
Scott: You're actually going to pay 50 bucks for a Wii 2D platforming game.
Scott: I played this game.
Scott: This game is worth 70 dollars.
Scott: I'm a Wario fan, so maybe I'm biased, but this is the return to the greatness that was Wario 2.
Scott: The addition of the Wii with the shaking of the Wiimote and such is not overbearing.
Scott: It's mostly hold it sideways, play a platformer.
Scott: It has all the greatness of, you know, the old Wario games.
Scott: You know, get the treasures, find the secrets.
Scott: It's really hard to die.
Scott: The whole, you know, figure out the clever ways to get from here to there.
Rym: And in addition, in addition, the style, the way the game is presented to you, the graphic design, is totally Saturday morning cartoon.
Scott: Well, it's totally Wario.
Scott: If you've ever played any Wario lands 2, 3, or 4, it's exactly like that.
Rym: Well, except for the fact that technology has allowed it to actually look like a Saturday morning cartoon.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: And it looks fantastic.
Scott: It's freaking awesome.
Rym: This is one of the first games on the Wii where I look at it and go, "Wow, that game looks
Rym: amazing.".
Scott: It has the mechanic from the older Wario games of go to the end of the level, then you sort of have to get back to the beginning level before the time runs out.
Scott: And as soon as you hit the end of the level, the level itself changes.
Scott: It's like you'll go through the level and there'll be unreachable areas, and you have to reach them on the way back.
Scott: But on the way back, you're in a hurry.
Scott: And that was a really good mechanic in Wario 3 or 4.
Scott: I forget which, I think in 4 they had that mechanic.
Scott: And I'm glad they kept it.
Scott: It was the only good thing in Wario 4.
Rym: Alright, we probably shouldn't spend a whole bunch of time like we did talking about all the other... There was so much in this room.
Rym: We should kind of...
Scott: Alright, let's talk about things really quickly.
Scott: Ready?
Scott: Here we go.
Rym: The rest of this will be an overview.
Rym: For one, there was a table covered in nothing but rub-on Bomberman tattoos.
Scott: There were rub-on, there were water-on Bomberman temporary tattoos.
Rym: Same thing.
Rym: They're little, you know, temporary tattoos.
Rym: All I want to say...
Scott: We grabbed a fistful of them and we applied them...
Rym: I have like 50 of them.
Rym: Let me tell you, these were some of the highest quality little tattoos ever.
Rym: If it weren't for the fact that I know tattoos look like crap after a relatively short amount of time being on a person, and they're also kind of indelible, I totally would have gotten the tattoo that exact same flamey on my bicep because they were really cool tattoos.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, the pink Godzilla booth, which we said is one of the booths selling stuff, sold these Japanese DS-like containers that hold all your DS games.
Rym: Best DS case ever.
Scott: Buy it.
Scott: I bought one.
Scott: It holds like 4, 8, 12, 16, a whole bunch of DS games in a really small amount of space.
Rym: There's never been a better DS case.
Scott: Nope, never.
Rym: Well, DS game case.
Scott: Not that I've seen.
Scott: Razer was there, the company that makes the mouses and such.
Scott: We used their mouses and they weren't as bad as I thought they were.
Scott: I think they had some of those games set on easy though because I was owning.
Scott: It's like I went to their booth and I was playing some FPS I never played before, and I was destroying everybody.
Scott: Everyone is getting their ass kicked by me.
Scott: I shot so many people in the back of the head and so many people from far away.
Scott: I refuse to believe it was the mouse.
Scott: I mean, it could have been.
Scott: I think they just, I don't know what it was, but I was killing everybody.
Rym: I'm kind of thinking about buying one just because...
Scott: Well, it is your kind of mouse.
Rym: It is my kind of mouse.
Scott: It's not my kind of mouse.
Rym: I'm very finicky about my mice.
Rym: Now speaking of mice, there was some other company and they basically were the "we're selling gimmicky mice" company.
Scott: They had this gun mouse basically.
Rym: It's basically shaped like a gun, like a handgun.
Scott: You hold it like your hand, you make a fist and you hold your fist just straight forward.
Scott: You don't turn your wrist over, you know, facing down.
Scott: Your palm faces to the left.
Rym: Like a gun.
Rym: But the thing is, you can also kind of tilt it and it's got buttons all over the place, but here's the thing that was interesting, because I thought I looked at it.
Rym: I stood there for like five minutes kind of laughing at it.
Rym: Well, chortling I guess, and going hee hee hee.
Rym: This thing is so dumb, just waiting for Scott to finish doing something so I could show it to him.
Rym: But then we both tried it and we realized that the sensor, because you can kind of whip it around and it has this long base going out in front to steady it.
Rym: The sensor is way up at the front.
Rym: So you can kind of whip it around like a gun and I actually decided to try it out.
Rym: It was surprisingly really easy to use and cool and I'd have to try it again, but all I want to say is it impressed me to the point that I'm willing to try it out again.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, at first you put your hand on it and it's like, eww, weird.
Scott: But then you start playing this FPS with it and you're like, Alright, this isn't as stupid as it looks.
Scott: I'm making something to this.
Scott: I'm dubious, but I wouldn't use it for everyday mousing, but maybe if there was an FPS that it worked well with, maybe if that's your thing and you got some money to burn.
Scott: It seemed to work.
Scott: It looked like the kind of thing that would never work, that was just a gimmick, but it had something to it.
Rym: Alright, so you know that movie Idiocracy?
Rym: No.
Rym: Well, in that movie, it's a movie that's up your alley, Scott, but there's an energy drink in that movie and they had samples of the energy drink to try and drink.
Rym: There's a booth that was basically just drink this energy drink and Scott knows.
Scott: Oh, the Brondo?
Rym: I am the person who will go up to any energy drink and try it.
Rym: and let me tell you, I didn't get to try it because they ran out right away.
Scott: Yeah, geniuses come to PAX with not enough product for people to drink.
Rym: But speaking of Idiocracy, there was a booth.
Rym: I'm not going to dignify the game by saying what game it was.
Rym: If you were willing to shave your head and have the name of the game written on the back...
Scott: No, they didn't write the name of the game.
Scott: They just wrote the word "hell" on the back of your head.
Rym: Oh, yeah, yeah, but basically if they shaved your head, they would give you a copy of the game.
Scott: Well, what they did is they gave you a pre-order for the game so that later you would get the game when it came out.
Rym: A surprising number of people shaved their heads for this game.
Scott: I think a lot of them are people who shave their heads anyway.
Scott: And basically they have a barber there.
Scott: You sat down, they shaved your head, and they put the word "hell" on the back of your head and then they gave you a pre-order for this game.
Scott: So you got the game for free.
Rym: From what I found out, the barber basically was paid to sit there all day shaving heads.
Scott: Yep, oh well, whatever.
Rym: And I heard that there was only one barber.
Scott: Yeah, there was that one booth I mentioned that sold really, really retro stuff.
Scott: They had some really, really retro stuff.
Scott: Like retro stuff the likes of which you will not see anywhere else.
Scott: And it was all for sale, which is unbelievable.
Rym: It was the kind of stuff that I usually see as like a museum piece.
Rym: But it was just there for sale for about what you would expect.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: What else is going on?
Scott: Oh, there's a booth that sells the PAX merch and all Penny Arcade merch.
Rym: It was gigantic.
Scott: Yeah, it was a pretty big booth.
Scott: And there were two lines, so you could go to either side of it.
Scott: We were stupid.
Scott: We saw a line for it.
Scott: We're like, "Yeah, we'll go back
Scott: later.".
Scott: We came back later, the PAX shirts were sold out.
Scott: They sold out of PAX shirts.
Scott: I was like,
Scott: "Fuck!".
Rym: Every single one of them in every size was sold out relatively early.
Scott: I think that they should just ask your t-shirt size when you get a badge and they should just give one to everybody.
Rym: Even if they raise the badge price.
Scott: And raise the price to make everyone pay for one.
Rym: I'd be fine with that.
Rym: That'd be pretty cool, actually.
Rym: And then make pre-registering the only way to get a shirt.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I found Iron Chef DS.
Rym: I played it.
Rym: It was kind of okay.
Scott: It was just Cooking Mama only with an Iron Chef America theme on it.
Rym: It was kind of fun.
Scott: I played a little bit.
Rym: Let me put it this way.
Rym: It was kind of fun, but the versus mechanic.
Rym: The mechanic of the game was very, very clever.
Rym: And I'll leave it at that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There was a Red Riding Hood DS game.
Scott: I don't remember exactly what it was.
Rym: Was it Kill Zombies?
Scott: It was like Shoot Zombies, You're Red Riding Hood or some crap.
Scott: It was fucked up.
Scott: I tried to play it and I couldn't figure out the controls.
Scott: They were so screwy.
Rym: And the person demoing it seemed to know there was a problem.
Rym: Because apparently a lot of people are having trouble with this.
Scott: She was like, do you need me to show you how to play?
Scott: And I'm like, no, I'm going to figure it out.
Scott: And no, it was not.
Scott: Don't buy it.
Scott: Don't bother.
Scott: Let's see what else is going on.
Scott: Oh, there's the animal boxing game.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Animal boxing is animal boxing.
Rym: It is humans versus animals.
Rym: The game is kind of okay for play.
Rym: Like I didn't play it long enough to say if it's a great game, but I can say one thing.
Rym: The game gets like 10 points for style.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't get any points for play.
Scott: I basically played it and I vigorously tapped the stylus on the animal and then it eventually fell over.
Rym: But at the same time, multiplayer against a human might be really fun.
Rym: There were Rock Band and Guitar Hero.
Scott: Well, Rock Band 2 and Guitar Hero 4.
Rym: Yes, obviously.
Rym: Stages set up, gigantic ones.
Rym: And like people were basically playing concerts.
Rym: And while I'm not interested in these games, people were really having a good time with that.
Scott: If you walked over to them at any point in time, there were people playing them.
Scott: And from what it seemed to me, it seemed like people liked Rock Band 2 a little bit better than they like Guitar Hero 4.
Scott: But there was some music in Guitar Hero 4 such as Van Halen that was not in Rock Band that people really liked and would, you know.
Scott: And actually, you know, Konami is coming out with their, you know, rock whatever, rock revolution or whatever they're calling it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I was actually reading some details about that today on the Internet.
Scott: And I'll talk about it more later.
Scott: But it looks like maybe Konami has the right idea and is going to go somewhere.
Scott: You know, the gods of rhythm games might, you know, we doubted them coming into this plastic instrument zone, you know, given that they had lost, you know, with their guitar freaks back in the day.
Scott: But I think they might have learned something.
Scott: And I would watch out for the Konami rock game.
Rym: While I was watching people play the Guitar Hero, I overheard a conversation from the people who were next up to play.
Rym: And one guy turned to, I guess it was a girlfriend or someone.
Rym: It seemed like girlfriend because they were totally making kissy faces at each other.
Rym: But he basically said, I'm something to the effect of, we'll see how this plays out, because after Guitar Hero three, well, I don't know anymore.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So there's in the way back of the exhibition hall, there was this Intel booth.
Scott: They basically had a trailer that you could go inside.
Rym: It was Intel Extreme Gaming, eight core monstrosities.
Rym: Check out the biggest, baddest things.
Scott: They had the craziest possible computers you could possibly get.
Scott: They were all Intel machines and they were all running all sorts of different games.
Rym: Now, this, you can make this shit up.
Rym: So we walk in and Scott stands in front of this kind of low powered like economy game.
Scott: It was like a fifteen hundred.
Scott: It said they had prices on all the machines.
Scott: It was like, here's a fifteen hundred dollar gaming machine.
Scott: So I got in front of it and I started playing whatever game was on there, some FPS.
Rym: And right next to it was the kind of the best machine they had.
Scott: This was like a four five thousand dollar game.
Rym: This was like this ludicrous gaming machine.
Rym: And we both hit, you know, start the game at the same time.
Rym: Scott's game loaded like ten times faster than mine.
Scott: My machine was just working just fine.
Rym: Mine was slow as shit.
Scott: Obviously, I'm not saying it's because of Intel hardware or anything like that.
Rym: Something was wrong with this demo.
Scott: Something was wrong with the software set up on the machine.
Scott: Maybe they had the software running two copies at once or something.
Rym: The fact that I was standing in front of what Intel is telling me is the best gaming machine money can buy.
Rym: And it really wasn't working.
Rym: Scott's in front of the economy.
Rym: Well, you can probably afford this one.
Rym: It was working great.
Scott: Yeah, it was just because the machine was set up.
Scott: poorly, obviously.
Scott: But it shows people running that booth weren't making sure the machines were reflecting their product well.
Rym: And of course, there was the voting and all the stuff for the Pax 10.
Rym: But I feel like we should talk about the Pax 10 after we have played all 10 Pax 10.
Scott: Basically, the deal is the Pax 10, they had a Pax themselves, right?
Scott: I guess Gabe and Tycho, I don't know, maybe some other people, picked 10 independent games that are the Pax 10.
Scott: And they had a booth there where you could play all of these 10 games.
Scott: And you could vote on which one was the best.
Scott: And the best one won something good.
Scott: And there were these 10 different indie games.
Scott: And we played a bunch of them, actually.
Scott: And some of them we didn't even realize are Pax 10 games.
Scott: And they were all, you know, the ones we played were all pretty interesting in one way or another.
Scott: And I guess we'll talk more about them in the future at some point.
Rym: Yeah, they definitely deserve a dedicated, at least a bit in a show, as opposed to an offhand mention here.
Scott: There was this one called Project Aftermath, though, that if we played that one the most of all of them, and Rym played it, actually.
Scott: And if they get the multiplayer on that game set up right, it could be something wicked awesome.
Rym: Yes, suffice to say, Project Aftermath is a game that I'm going to be watching with great interest.
Scott: I can't guarantee a winner, but it's something to keep your eye on.
Rym: If any game has a chance of pulling this kind of game off, and I point out that I've never seen a game pull this kind of game off.
Rym: I've seen very few people even attempt it.
Rym: Project Aftermath could be the game.
Scott: There was also a game that was made by a team of people from RIT, so go RIT.
Rym: Yes, but the one cool thing I want to mention about the exhibition hall is that it was up across this big skyway.
Rym: And you walk around outside the front of the con, there's this kind of big skyway above you, with glass windows and a glass roof.
Rym: That was like this hangout area between the exhibition hall and the rest of the con.
Rym: And there was cool stuff out there, like all the bands had their little booths to hang out there and meet after the concerts.
Rym: There were a whole bunch of sumos and just cool stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it was a good, nice and airy room that made it a comfortable space.
Scott: Like if you exited the exhibition hall, you could go "ahh" and not be crowded in.
Scott: And it made traffic in and out of the exhibition hall really smooth.
Scott: Whereas Otakon, where they're dealer's room, is sort of a narrow entryway and a narrow exit.
Scott: So they need to separate the entryway and the exit to keep it smooth.
Scott: But they were able to keep it smooth by just having a giant whole bunch of doors going into a giant empty room.
Rym: But all that aside, we did all these things and then eventually it comes around to 4 o'clock or so, we got ready to do our panel.
Scott: We had to do our Beyond D&D panel.
Scott: It was the same Beyond D&D panel we did at ConnectiCon, except I feel like we sort of ran out of material a little quickly.
Rym: I don't think so at all.
Scott: And we had to keep talking.
Rym: We had another hour easily of material.
Rym: We had to cut everything off pointedly in order to say the bare minimum things we wanted to say.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: I felt, because I was looking at the clock after we were starting to get towards the end of the slides, and we had like a half hour left.
Rym: Scott, at ConnectiCon, we got to the end of the slides at about the same point.
Rym: And then we just talked without slides for the rest of it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, it was alright.
Scott: It was a great panel.
Rym: In fact, it was paced almost the exact same way.
Rym: I don't know where you get this.
Scott: Anyway, it was actually the panel had this giant line forming, just as every other panel had a giant line forming.
Rym: Basically, most cons, we go to our panel room like five minutes before the panel, because we're doing a million panels.
Rym: But here at PAX, we only had one.
Rym: This was our only obligation.
Rym: So we got dinner, took a nap, got all prepared.
Rym: We came back over.
Rym: We walk over to the panel room a little over an hour before our panel.
Rym: And there are already a lot of people lined up for this panel.
Scott: I had a feeling like people were lining up for every panel at the con, and ours was not an exception.
Scott: People were definitely digging our panel.
Scott: You know, they read the description.
Scott: They saw the title.
Scott: They knew us for whatever reason.
Scott: They wanted to be there.
Scott: In fact, they ran it right after Art of the Dungeon Master.
Scott: And I think a lot of Art of the Dungeon Master people wanted to go to our panel also and couldn't, because they left that panel and then had to get in the line for ours immediately.
Scott: And some of them, you know, it just the room wasn't that big.
Scott: It would only seated like a hundred people, maybe.
Rym: It was kind of good, but also bad, because I feel like some of those WotC people from the previous panel might have wanted to be at our panel, because it was the WotC people talking about being a game master.
Rym: And then right after, some guys talking about why D&D is kind of poop.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I looked around online, you know, for feedback of our panel.
Scott: There was actually quite a bit.
Scott: And everyone was saying good things, but one guy said, "Yeah, you guys basically spent the whole time saying D&D sucks, but no, really, it
Scott: doesn't.".
Scott: Which we kind of did a little bit.
Scott: It's just we really tried to avoid doing that, but it's hard, because D&D is the reference point everyone has to go by, so you have to keep using it to compare to, and thus it seems like you're saying it's poop, but really,
Rym: we were
Scott: saying D&D isn't poop, it's different.
Rym: Well, what we said that it seems like most people got was that for role-playing, D&D really is poop.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If you want to role-play, there's no reason to use D&D.
Scott: Well, role-play as per the definition of role-playing, which we defined at the beginning of the panel.
Rym: If you want to role-play, as in play a role in a collaborative storytelling environment, D&D provides almost nothing for that.
Rym: But anyway.
Scott: Less than nothing.
Rym: That was our panel, and we did this panel, and the panel went over amazingly well.
Rym: We had Luke Crane and Jared Sorensen.
Scott: We had to get them in because they didn't show up early enough.
Rym: Yeah, basically, Luke Crane calls me, he's like, "Yeah, we're outside.
Rym: They're not going to let us in.
Rym: They're telling us that there's no
Rym: room.".
Rym: And I was like, I motioned to the staffer, and the staffer's like,
Rym: "Huh?".
Rym: And I motioned, and I'm like, "All right, tell them you're with me.
Rym: I'm waving to them right
Rym: now.".
Rym: And they let these two in.
Rym: We gave them seats at the front.
Rym: And there was nothing cooler than doing a panel that is so heavily influenced by two people who have so much to do with the indie role-playing game scene.
Rym: And there was a point of the panel where we said something, and they looked at each other, and one of them was like,
Rym: "Huh?".
Rym: It was like, "Uh, huh,
Rym: oh.".
Rym: And they started nodding and thinking like, "Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no,
Rym: no.".
Rym: I feel like we might have given them some minor insight.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Also, it's good when you start talking about a dude's game.
Scott: Because when Luke Crane talks about his own game, he does his little Luke Crane dance.
Scott: He's like, "Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
Scott: yeah.".
Scott: So when I was talking like, "Let's say you want to climb Mount Everest.
Scott: That takes eight dice.
Scott: Your climbing skill is four.
Scott: That means eight of your four dice need to show
Scott: up.".
Scott: You know, that's the kind of awesome thing there is in Burning Wheel.
Scott: And he starts doing his little dance, and I'm like, "Yeah, I made him do his little
Scott: dance.".
Rym: And when I said the words, "My aunt is an abbess,".
Rym: I think he about lost it.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: So you know you're doing good when you can entertain the guy who made something by talking about the thing he made.
Scott: I mean, imagine if you went and you were talking about Super Mario Brothers.
Scott: Miyamoto was sitting there, and you start talking about Mario Brothers.
Scott: And all the things you say, he's like, "Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: He's got it right.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: What's
Scott: up?".
Scott: Whereas I don't think Miyamoto would be like that.
Scott: He'd be like, "Oh,
Scott: oh.".
Rym: We basically, with one minute to go, had to say, "Oh, my God.
Rym: We're out of
Rym: time.".
Rym: We talked a whole bunch real quick and got a whole bunch more out there.
Rym: And then, basically, we took the entire crowd and said, "All right, kids.
Rym: You want more?
Rym: Follow
Rym: us.".
Rym: And the scary thing is, everyone tried to follow us.
Scott: Pretty much the vast majority of that room tried to follow us.
Rym: So thus, chaos ensued as me and Jared Sorensen have this gaggle of 20 people following us.
Scott: I have a gaggle, and Luke Crane has a third gaggle.
Scott: So we're- Three gaggles.
Rym: Basically, we got these crowds.
Rym: We realized, "Uh-oh.
Rym: We can't deal with
Rym: this.".
Scott: Because what happened was, the annex where all the tabletop gaming was going on, it had people the whole weekend.
Scott: But there were always plenty of open tables, and we figured we could just go over there and get some.
Scott: After our panel, it just happened to be the exact moment when every single table was full.
Scott: It just happened to be that time.
Rym: So we get in our three ragged gangs of ruffians to the annex, and we've lost about 40 people along the way.
Rym: But we still have a very large and very eager crowd, and we discover that there aren't any free tables, and it's just a giant clusterfuck.
Rym: So, while we're trying to figure out what to do, a Penny Arcade Enforcer walks over and says, "Alright guys, what do you
Rym: need?".
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And one thing led to another, and basically, the Penny Arcade Expo and the Penny Arcade Enforcers went above and beyond anything I have ever experienced at any convention ever.
Scott: Yeah, most conventions, they'd be like, "What are you doing with this crowd trying to make some shit
Scott: happen?".
Rym: Or they'd be saying, "What are you doing?
Rym: This is a fire
Rym: hazard.".
Rym: Or, most cons would be saying, "I don't know what to
Rym: do.".
Rym: Basically, all these PAX Enforcers converged, discussed, spread out.
Rym: The next thing we know...
Scott: They have us tables, and they gave us the Serpent Theater, which was no longer in use that night.
Rym: They gave us the Serpent Theater, they set up two demo tables on there, they set up the microphones, they set up crowd control, they set up line control.
Rym: They announced, they did everything we could have possibly asked, they did things I didn't even think of.
Rym: And three of these Enforcers hung around until our event, which went on until about 1.30 in the morning, ended.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This was hours and hours of maintaining a crowd that they did not expect, that we pulled out of the ether.
Rym: Oh my god, PAX, are you, like, I could hug all of you.
Scott: So basically what went down, right, is not everyone could play Burning Wheel demos all at once, and we couldn't run that many at once.
Scott: 'Cause Luke Crane didn't expect that much of a crowd, we didn't bring enough materials, there weren't enough, you know, it was pretty much, oh god.
Rym: So one, on the stage, Luke Crane and this other guy start demoing Burning Wheel, and while he's going...
Scott: That's eight people at a time.
Rym: I go up to Luke behind him, and I'm like, "All right, Luke, how many demos can you
Rym: do?".
Rym: And he said, "How long is this room
Rym: open?".
Rym: And I said, "The room closes at, like,
Rym: two.".
Rym: And he said, "I'll do demos until they kick me
Rym: out.".
Rym: And I said, "All right, are you
Rym: sure?".
Rym: And he said, "Yeah, of course I'm
Rym: sure.".
Rym: So I run around this room, getting people to sign up for Burning Wheel demos, and oh my god, the number of people who wanted to demo, like, it was frightening.
Rym: I had, like, two pieces of paper full of names, grouped up into groups of four, and, like, the groups had names, and it was crazy.
Rym: And Luke Crane stayed until everyone who wanted a Burning Wheel demo got a Burning Wheel demo.
Scott: Or left before their time came.
Rym: Yes, which was justifiable, because there was a large crowd, and it took forever.
Scott: But, in order to get people to not be bored while waiting, Jared Sorenson did something amazing.
Scott: He played Action Castle.
Rym: Well, first he comes over to me and says, "I can entertain the
Rym: crowd.".
Rym: And I said, "What are you gonna
Rym: do?".
Rym: And I said, "Can I have a
Rym: microphone?".
Rym: And the attention of the crowd.
Rym: And we said, "Yeah, we can do
Rym: that.".
Rym: And he got another microphone.
Rym: Again, Pax Enforcers, oh my god.
Rym: He stood there with a microphone.
Rym: Pax Enforcers set up a line, and at the front of this line was a microphone.
Rym: And he ran Action Castle.
Rym: I don't know if I want to get into what Action Castle was, I feel like I should dedicate, because we're running out of time here tonight.
Rym: I should dedicate a whole bit on another Tuesday about what Action Castle is.
Scott: Could we play Action Castle online, with some webcams or streaming or something?
Rym: We will figure this out, and we will talk again.
Rym: Let me tell you this.
Rym: I had a revelation.
Rym: Action Castle, I'm going to memorize it or something like it.
Scott: We should make up a different one.
Scott: We should make, like, Daring Dungeon, or Action Castle 2.
Rym: I will summarize.
Rym: The crowd loved it, and this is now what I'm going to do to entertain a crowd.
Rym: anytime I'm at a convention with an unruly crowd to entertain.
Rym: This is going to be, if I can pull it off, the official Keep a Line or Keep a Crowd Busy event.
Rym: Hell, you could run this as an event at a con, and it would be amazing.
Scott: Trademark Jared Sorenson.
Rym: Yes, Jared Sorenson is the freaking man.
Scott: Unless he got it from someone else, in which case, I don't know.
Rym: Regardless, Jared Sorenson, we're going to have an interview with him as soon as we have time to put it together.
Scott: So, after all that, it was still Saturday, the con was still rocking, and what do you do at a con that's PAX if it's Friday or Saturday night?
Rym: You go to the motherfucking concert.
Scott: You go to five hours of the best concerts at any convention in the United States.
Rym: After we left them to be, we said, "Alright, we're going to go to the
Rym: concert.".
Rym: And we said, "Aw, crap.
Rym: Wristbands.
Rym: What if this concert's overflowing?
Rym: What do we
Rym: do?".
Rym: And a PAX enforcer walked over and handed us wristbands.
Scott: Well, I think some of our listeners gave us wristbands also.
Rym: Yes, we actually had, like, five wristbands as a result.
Scott: People came through and gave us wristbands, which is awesome.
Rym: Like, one PAX enforcer gave me the crumpled up one that he took off himself.
Rym: Another PAX enforcer gave me an un-put-on one, a brand new one.
Rym: And listeners gave us some.
Rym: So thus on, we walked over to the concert, and once again, at PAX, you can pretty much just walk into any concert after it starts.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: You don't have to worry about getting the wristbands.
Scott: If you want to see the concert, you'll see it.
Scott: Even with that many people, even without you're going to see the concert, don't worry about it.
Scott: And we said that last time.
Rym: The secret, walk into the room, walk all the way around the back, all the way to the left, and then scooch in, and you'll be, like, right up front.
Scott: Yeah, at least, you know, if PAX is still in the same room layout next time.
Rym: Now, as you know, the previous night's concert was almost worth the price of admission in and of itself.
Rym: In fact, it probably was worth the price of admission in and of itself, considering what I've paid for other less satisfying concerts in my life.
Rym: But I was real excited about this one, because I had never heard two of these bands at all.
Rym: And I was a huge fan of the other two acts.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like, well, I love two of these, and I don't know two of these.
Scott: Alright, at the worst, it's half awesome.
Rym: So we wander into the beginning of Anamanaguchi.
Scott: Is that how you pronounce it?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Basically, these guys were no older than we were.
Scott: And they did the typical rock out video game music thing.
Scott: You know, that was done by such bands as Arm, Canon, Entertainment System, etc, etc, etc.
Scott: And they were pretty much right in line with that, and just as good as all the other ones.
Rym: Yeah, the crowd got really into it.
Rym: It was really fun.
Rym: I don't have much more to say, but you guys rule, and it was a good show.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't sitting there going, "Oh, get off the stage," which means good concert.
Rym: But while that was well and good, then comes forth from the darkness, the darkest of the hillside thickets.
Scott: Now, the name of the band is, quote, "The Darkest of the Hillside Thickets,".
Scott: end of name.
Rym: I'm not going to mince words.
Rym: They are a Lovecraftian-themed metal band.
Scott: You really don't need to say more than that, do you?
Rym: They're old.
Rym: They've been around for a while.
Rym: They've been performing since like Necro Wombicon.
Scott: Yeah, they played a lot.
Scott: They're an old, old band.
Scott: They've been around.
Scott: I've been around for a long time, and I've never heard of them until now.
Scott: I don't know why I've never heard from them until now.
Rym: You know, a lot of times, someone says, "Oh, we're a concept band," or, "We're a
Rym: Lovecraft.".
Rym: You know, something funny like that.
Rym: It's usually like, "Yeah, the concept's cool, but the band's kind of
Rym: mad.".
Rym: The band is super awesome, independent of their theme.
Rym: They fucking rock the shit.
Rym: They put on a great show.
Rym: They did the whole metal.
Rym: They were dressed in these costumes.
Rym: Look online.
Rym: You can find some video of their act.
Scott: Yeah, if you are a Lovecraft fan or a metal fan, or hopefully both, how could you not?
Scott: How could you not?
Rym: The level of energy that the lead singer put forth, and the lyrics.
Rym: Oh, the lyrics.
Rym: The crowd's screaming.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: I can't even.
Rym: I can't express it here.
Scott: Oh, that was the greatest.
Scott: Everyone was going, "Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Get through the
Rym: photography.".
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Get through the photography.
Scott: Oh, that's good stuff.
Rym: Basically, the concert on Saturday.
Rym: If the concert on Friday was just a really good concert, the concert on Saturday, one thing I can say is that the level of energy in the room escalated and escalated and escalated.
Scott: I mean, Friday.
Scott: Remember, Friday was fucking Jonathan Golden and such, and Freeze Pop.
Scott: Super, super energy amazing.
Scott: Somehow, even though I guess the star power of Saturday was a tiny bit less, the rocking was twice as hard.
Scott: I don't know how that could be, but it was.
Scott: Maybe it's because we were closer into the stage.
Scott: I don't know what it was.
Rym: Now, this is the concert I really want to talk about, because I liked MC Frontalot.
Rym: I love Nerdcore.
Rym: I've always liked MC Frontalot.
Scott: Actually, this is the second time I had seen MC Frontalot live.
Rym: See, I've only seen him live once.
Scott: Me and Emily actually went to these digital life things they have in the Javits Center that I always get into for free, because I refuse to pay for it.
Scott: It's basically walk around a room in the Javits where a bunch of tech companies have crap set up and whatever.
Scott: A lot of gaming action going on.
Scott: One of them, we happened to show up during MC Frontalot set.
Scott: It was really sad, because he was playing to all these empty seats and five kids sitting there.
Scott: He was way into his show, trying real hard, but there was no one there.
Scott: It was like the Javits at a trade show.
Rym: At least when I went and saw MC Chris.
Scott: I felt really bad for him, but I was like, "Oh, that's MC Frontalot, the bald dude.
Scott: All
Scott: right.".
Rym: I liked his music, and I liked this sort of thing, but seeing him in concert adds this whole new dimension to his music.
Rym: You want to talk about a performer who is into what he is doing?
Rym: The level of energy on that stage was powerful, almost painful.
Rym: The man is intense.
Rym: He is almost frightening.
Rym: It was fantastic.
Rym: And he did pretty much all his headlining songs.
Rym: The crowd was losing their shit.
Rym: Everyone was singing along with him.
Rym: He was just intense.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: I guess Scott's got nothing to say about MC Frontalot.
Scott: There's no words, because the amazingness was so, so off the charts.
Scott: What can you possibly say?
Scott: And that's not even counting, right?
Scott: I got nothing to say about that.
Scott: What can I possibly say about when he brought Joko out to play with him?
Rym: Jonathan Colton and MC Frontalot doing a duet.
Rym: This was, I don't know, amazing, spectacular.
Scott: And then after he, you know, they had a song that they played together, which actually is a song no one's ever heard before.
Scott: I went and listened to it again.
Scott: I liked that song a lot.
Rym: I also like that song.
Scott: Like way too much.
Scott: We should link to the song, maybe.
Rym: Yeah, we should.
Scott: And then Jonathan Colton hung around and played the drum for the last song.
Scott: He just played one drum.
Rym: Man, I love that dude.
Rym: Now, MC Frontalot was amazing.
Rym: The energy level in the room, like the crowd was really freaking worked up at this point.
Rym: And then, of course, like with every concert at PAX, we went through the charade of Go Away, Come Back Encore, and MC Frontalot's Encore, the fucking bomb.
Rym: But then the minibosses came out.
Scott: Now, the minibosses, right?
Scott: They're a band that I've known about for a long time.
Rym: They're an old standby.
Scott: Like since the year 2000, right?
Scott: In the year 2000, I got to RIT, I discovered the minibosses.
Scott: People who played video game music, but they rocked out.
Scott: They did the Mega Man and the Punch Out and all the goods.
Rym: Now, a lot of people play video game music.
Rym: I mean, the Anna Manigucci and all these bands, but the minibosses bring something a little different to the table in that the songs they play are not crazy interpretations.
Rym: They're not musical interpretations.
Rym: They're pretty much the truest to the original source material as you can possibly be while still performing something live.
Rym: And they're fantastic.
Rym: They're so true, and they sound so good and so nostalgic.
Scott: This is a band that I had known about and listened to for a very long time, always wanted to see live, never had a chance to, and they weren't super uber popular, so I didn't think they would be around that long.
Scott: But they do packs every year, I think, and they rock the packs every year.
Scott: And you can tell, because they came out acting like this is something they do every night.
Scott: They're like, "Hey, guys, what's
Scott: up?".
Rym: "We're going to do some Mega Man for
Rym: y'all.".
Scott: "I think they want
Scott: Excitebike.".
Rym: "No, they want Mega
Rym: Man.".
Rym: "Well, should we
Rym: play?".
Scott: "Ah, fuck it, let's just play
Scott: this.".
Scott: Every other band had their thing planned out and scheduled.
Scott: It was serious business.
Scott: They were like, "Yeah, we do this all the time.
Scott: It's like our fifth packs, whatever.
Scott: What do you guys want to
Scott: hear?".
Scott: "All right, we'll do that
Scott: one.".
Scott: And they had a DS on the stage, and they're like, "Hey, you guys, pick to chat this DS and write down what you want us to
Scott: play.".
Scott: And people did, and it was great.
Rym: Of course, there were a lot of penises in there, too.
Scott: There were quite a bunch of penises.
Rym: But this is where... I mean, you might say we were kind of hesitating, because now we have to talk about our shameful, I guess, conclusion to Saturday.
Rym: This is one of the most shameful things I've ever done.
Rym: This is a sign of my age.
Rym: But you see...
Scott: Well, the concerts on Saturday were... Remember, we went over there when they started, which was...
Rym: Now, the concert is four hours long, from 9.30 to 1.30, and the doors to the con close at 3 a.m Right, so the concert is supposed to end at 1.30.
Scott: Then we were going to go to bed.
Scott: So at 9 o'clock, 9.30, we went over there, stayed there until 1.30.
Rym: And I'm jumping up and down, and I'm headbanging.
Rym: I'm throwing up the horns.
Rym: I'm basically losing my shit and jumping around and pogoing.
Scott: This is right after doing a panel, right?
Scott: This is right after doing all that crazy stuff in the Serpent Theatre.
Scott: This is right after a whole lot of action.
Rym: This is after Friday!
Scott: We were standing up the entire time during this concert, right?
Scott: And every band during the entire concert, every single one, had one or two encores.
Scott: It was a shtick.
Scott: Just everyone did them, right?
Scott: M.C.
Scott: Prodlot even came out, and he was like... He came out for his encore right away, pretty much, leaving no suspense.
Scott: And he's like, "Oh, what gave it away?
Scott: The large number of encores already performed at concerts this
Scott: weekend?".
Rym: So I'm headbanging to the 11th or 12th song of the minibosses.
Rym: And I start to lose it.
Rym: I feel like, "Wait a
Rym: minute.".
Scott: It's like 2.30 in the morning.
Rym: I don't even know what time it is.
Rym: I'm thinking, "Whoa, I'm having an old man moment here.
Rym: I gotta go to bed.
Rym: Oh my
Rym: god.".
Rym: So I'm like, "Alright, the concert's gotta end
Rym: soon.".
Rym: And I look at my cell phone, and it says 2.30.
Rym: And I look at Scott, and I point at it.
Rym: He's like,
Rym: "Ugh.".
Rym: And neither one of us wanted to admit that we were losing it.
Scott: I could've stayed there the whole time.
Scott: I could've.
Scott: But really, I was in such a state where my brain wasn't processing the music fully.
Scott: I was not getting out of it what I should've been.
Rym: And at this point, we realized they're not stopping.
Scott: Yeah, they weren't acting like they're wrapping it up soon.
Scott: It was like they acted.
Scott: Their demeanor was like, "We're in the middle.
Scott: We're in
Scott: this.".
Scott: We didn't even start yet.
Rym: We were playing until you were kicked out with us.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, many times in my life, at anime conventions, at gaming conventions, at a Linux convention, at concerts, I have made the decision to leave an event, to leave a concert before it ended.
Rym: And it's usually an informed decision.
Rym: It is the decision of, while I could stay, I'm going to sacrifice the last hour, or last half hour, or last whatever, of this event in order to sleep so that I can do more the next day.
Rym: Like, it was always a decision, and I could've stayed.
Rym: At 2.32
Rym: a.m.,
Rym: well, I guess on Sunday morning, at the Penny Arcade Expo 2008, in the middle of the minibosses concert, I realized I could not go on.
Rym: I realized that I could not stay to the end.
Rym: I would've had to go to the back of the room and sit down and possibly fall asleep.
Rym: For the first time in my life, I was defeated.
Rym: This has never happened to me before.
Rym: I felt like I was a thousand years old.
Rym: And as I walked out of the room with Scott, and there were a handful of other people.
Scott: I just stayed, but Rym wanted to leave, and then I just sort of acquiesced.
Rym: Yes, basically, it's not like Scott was the trooper saying, "Man, Rym, fuck you, but we should
Rym: go.".
Rym: Scott was like, "It's kind of like the Jenga that's teetering, teetering, teetering,
Rym: teetering.".
Rym: And I looked at it, and I went, and it fell right over.
Rym: So we walk out, this walk of shame, and as I look back, the energy of the room has not diminished at all.
Rym: I am just older than I used to be.
Scott: Even though the average age of PAX is more our age than young punk kids.
Rym: But at the same time, as I walked out, I saw other people our age, and I saw one person who I'm pretty sure was younger than me, also on their way out.
Scott: Also, I point out, they have, one good thing about PAX is that the concerts are general admission.
Scott: If people don't realize this because they don't go to concerts and you're a bunch of nerds, I know some of you, right?
Rym: Yes, there are no chairs except in the very back.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: General admission just means it's the floor in front of the stage, and you walk out there, and you can just walk around except where there's people already standing, and then you can't walk there because of the laws of physics.
Scott: Seating means seats, right?
Scott: Well, at Otakon and such, the concerts have seats right up to the front, and it's sort of black.
Scott: because what can you do?
Scott: You stand up in front of your seat and you dance, and you sit down and you can't see, and then you stand up in front of your seat and you dance a little bit.
Scott: General admission is what concerts are about.
Scott: If your concert doesn't have general admission, that ruins even the best band in the world.
Scott: It kind of sucks.
Scott: Basically, at PAX, they have general admission, but they have seats in the back of the room, like two rows of seats in the way back, so you can sit if you want, and it works out.
Scott: Most of the time, those seats are about half full.
Scott: When I walked out of that room at 2.30
Scott: a.m.,
Scott: the seats were 100% full, 100%.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now, seeing that and seeing other people who also left the concert before 3 in the goddamn morning, I felt a little bit younger, but I still felt like I was 100 years old, and when I go back to that hotel room and I fell immediately to sleep, I mean immediately, like, I literally, like, laid down and I woke up, and it was the next day, and it was time to go back to the con, but I have never felt as old in my life as I felt walking out of the end of that concert.
Rym: I was defeated.
Scott: And I think at that point- Now, that's the end of Saturday at PAX.
Rym: Thus, Saturday.
Rym: I'll at least say this.
Rym: We're not going to do an entire dedicated Tuesday to Sunday.
Rym: We're going to talk about some other stuff the next time we talk about PAX, but- Next time we have a Tuesday episode.
Rym: I think our coverage of PAX is going to be three nights long.
Rym: There's no way to avoid it because I have a lot to say about what happened on Sunday.
Rym: I'm kind of excited.
Rym: I want to talk about it now, but we've been going a while.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.