Rym: It's Monday, June 16th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights Mondays.
Rym: Tonight, it's a Tech News round-up.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: You know what I did at work today?
Rym: What did you do, work?
Scott: No, I did actually work, but while I was working, I was watching Tiger Woods.
Rym: You know, I was working.
Rym: I had a lot to do and I was really busy at work, so I'm typing furiously and doing my thing.
Rym: There's a meeting.
Rym: My boss and my boss's boss and a bunch of other people are in the conference room, which I think I've talked about.
Scott: Has a satellite dish hooked up to a television?
Rym: Oh, no, no.
Rym: Well, yeah, but not for that.
Scott: Oh, because ours does.
Scott: We have Dish Network.
Scott: Well, I think we have DirecTV in our conference room.
Rym: But it's a conference room, but like I've said before, my entire office is one big room with all glass walls and glass doors.
Rym: It's really cool.
Rym: So, I noticed, like I kind of looked to see if they're going to be done yet, because I got to talk to my boss about something before I go and I see that they're all looking behind me and not talking about whatever they're talking about.
Rym: So, I look behind me and I see all the salespeople and the customer support people and they're all standing and it looks like they're all watching one guy's computer.
Rym: So, my boss's boss walks out and he's like, "What are you guys doing watching so-and-so do some work?
Rym: Maybe you could take a hint and
Rym: work.".
Rym: And then he comes like, "All right, guys, what are you really looking
Rym: at?".
Rym: And we're watching the sudden death whatever.
Rym: I didn't even know golf had a sudden death.
Scott: Well, see, here.
Scott: Oh, let me explain it to you, then.
Rym: Oh, I know how it works now.
Rym: Someone at work explained it to me and I was like, "Oh,
Rym: wow.".
Rym: And then I watched it because that golf was suddenly really interesting.
Scott: Well, see, here's the thing.
Scott: Golf as a sport, right?
Scott: Especially while, I mean, playing it can be fun.
Scott: You know, actually, I would play golf if, number one, it was significantly less expensive.
Scott: Number two, it took a lot less time to play.
Scott: Number three, I could just walk up and play and not have to call up and get a tee time and then wake up at the crack ass at dawn.
Rym: One, it is cheap to play if you use used clubs and play in crappy places.
Scott: Which is not worth playing because then the game sucks.
Rym: When it's raining.
Scott: It sucks even worse, then.
Rym: Two, it takes a long time on purpose because people play golf to get away from their real lives.
Scott: I know.
Rym: And most people who play golf seem to play just as an excuse to hang out.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Scott: I feel, though, like if we make, we could design a golf course, right?
Scott: In such a way.
Rym: Oh, I know.
Rym: You know, you designed a giant mini golf course.
Scott: Well, no.
Scott: What I would do is I would have normal golf holes, right?
Scott: But half the holes take you away from sort of the main base and the other half bring you towards it.
Scott: And then you could send people, like the first people who show up, you send them to hole one.
Scott: The second group that shows up, you send them to hole three, you see?
Scott: And you can sort of, and you make people play fast and you can...
Rym: Well, you've already lost every golfer.
Scott: Well, you lost people who are golfers now, but you might get a whole new bunch of golfers regardless.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Golf is not that interesting to watch.
Scott: The action of golf is not exciting, right?
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's not like a hockey game where you can watch a crappy high school hockey game, but the action will be awesome enough to entertain.
Rym: He's he's he's he's he punts.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It goes in.
Scott: Hey, he went in.
Scott: But because right of the the insane drama of who is playing and what the stakes and the circumstances were.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The just the drama in itself of who's going to win and who's going to lose is enough to make you watch.
Scott: And all it all.
Rym: The only thing that got me to watch was the fact that it was sudden death.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because then it was even worse sudden death than you think.
Scott: As I will explain, you see, Tiger Woods hasn't played golf, not at a tournament in like months because he was having some knee surgeries.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He said, I'm going to take off until the U.S.
Scott: Open because that's important and I want to win that really badly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the U.S.
Scott: Open is being played in Torrey Pines in San Diego, which is pretty much down the street from, you know, Navy golf, which is where Tiger Woods played with his dad when he was a kid.
Scott: And the tournament was on Father's Day weekend.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you see where this is going.
Scott: And Tigers is playing with a hurt knee.
Scott: So he plays through four days and he's actually doing pretty badly.
Scott: And at the end of the fourth day, he's tied with this other guy named Rocco Mediate.
Scott: And Rocco is actually a pretty cool dude.
Scott: He's not like an asshole or anything.
Scott: He's he's a really fun kind of guy.
Scott: He's like 45 years old.
Scott: What do you base that on?
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: Is that just like the media telling he's a good guy?
Scott: Well, no, you watch him play and you can see he's sort of having fun.
Scott: I see by his golf technique that he must be a good not his technique, but his demeanor when he's hanging out his putter.
Rym: Look at the way he holds his.
Scott: You can tell if you want to hate his mom.
Scott: If you watch golf, you're making this take too long.
Scott: If you watch golf, you can see how the you know, the the attitudes and the the emotions of the players as they walk around and, you know, stand there and whatnot, you can see what kind of people they are like.
Scott: You know that John Daly is just like a drunken bum, but, you know, whatever.
Scott: And Rory Savatini is an asshole.
Rym: Anyway, you already know more names of golfers than I've ever known.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You don't know Jack Nicklaus and Tiger Woods.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: OK, so so you have Tiger Woods, the greatest golfer to ever live, pretty much right.
Scott: And he's tied on the fourth day of the tournament.
Scott: So the U.S.
Scott: Open, unlike any other golf tournament, or at least most other golf tournaments, and they usually if you are you're tied on a golf tournament, they'll just make you play the 18th hole again.
Scott: And whoever you know, if you win, you win.
Scott: And if you lose, you lose.
Scott: And if you tie, you do a different hole until someone wins.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The U.S.
Scott: Open, if you tie, it makes you play another 18 holes on Monday.
Scott: Now, of course, no one can watch on Monday except the old people, because everyone's at work.
Scott: Smart, smart golf puts the golf on the Internet streaming live video for free.
Scott: Other sports take heed.
Rym: That is, in fact, how we were watching it at work.
Scott: I mean, if that wasn't like that, who would have watched?
Scott: Nobody.
Scott: Now, you might say, whoa, how are the broadcasters making money off of this?
Scott: Well, they have to work that out.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: Someone was making money off this.
Scott: You know who is very, very happy about this streaming live video of golf?
Scott: Well, first of all, golf was very happy, as I could tell by the comments under the video, it was creating new golf fans.
Scott: And to notice that Tiger Woods is wearing like Nike stuff all the time.
Scott: Notice how the other guy was wearing like Callaway stuff.
Scott: I think it's a living ad.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Those people, the sponsors and the the endorsers of the players would be very happy if if sports are streaming video on the Internet.
Scott: If I was an endorser advertiser type person, what I would do is instead of buying TV ads or something like that, I would pay to get my, you know, like my ad on like the football field or the ice hockey rink.
Scott: And then I would pay the broadcaster and I would say, you were putting this on the Internet for free so people can see my ad that's on the ice hockey ring and other sports need to take a lesson here because whatever sports do, this more are going to become more popular than the others.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I could I guess I could talk about how I went to buy a new mountain bike, but I think we should get to the news, the big news, the news that everyone's been.
Rym: It's a little passé now, which is good because that's good.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So we can't avoid talking about to iPhone news, can we?
Rym: I might get one.
Scott: I'm definitely going to get one.
Scott: There's no question about it.
Rym: It's about there's a 75 percent chance that I will get one.
Scott: There's 100 percent chance.
Scott: And I'm going to tell you why.
Scott: The iPhone, the new iPhone is by no means perfect.
Scott: It has its flaws for one.
Scott: It has many flaws.
Rym: Get podcasts by any usual or nice means.
Scott: Yes, that is a major flaw.
Scott: There are other major flaws.
Scott: It is very closed.
Scott: That is a problem.
Scott: I can't just do whatever I want with it.
Scott: I can't just like be making Skype calls on it yet.
Scott: At least that's not.
Scott: that's not you know, other phones can do that.
Scott: You know, there are many problems with it.
Scott: It is by no means perfect.
Scott: However, if you compare it to every other phone in existence, it is available the entire world, actually, I would say.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It is superior for these reasons.
Scott: Let's compare it to that.
Rym: That's a lot like the democracy is the worst possible form of government.
Rym: after every possible form we've already tried precisely.
Scott: Let's take a look at a good competitor, the Nokia and ninety five ninety seven, whatever it is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The phone that does everything.
Scott: The problem is the iPhone has a Web browser.
Scott: The Nokia and ninety five has a Web browser.
Scott: The Nokia and ninety five Web browser is usable.
Scott: The know the Apple Web browser is far superior.
Scott: It's actually a pleasure to use.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The Nokia and ninety five can play some MP3s.
Scott: It sure can.
Scott: It can also play some videos.
Rym: Yeah, I phone as I do.
Scott: It is an amazing music and video player.
Scott: And at top of the line, it is as good as a standalone MP3 player.
Scott: In fact, better than that, because it's also the phone.
Scott: And if the phone rings, it's very clever with how it will, you know, pause the music and all that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Those sorts of as the visual voicemail.
Scott: Now, there are not many other people have that going on.
Scott: But if you get a voicemail, you can just look at the text instead of having to see the dial and then listen.
Scott: That is a pleasure.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When you make text messages, it does the the threading like an I.M.
Scott: conversation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It is also a GPS, a high quality GPS.
Rym: So a lot of people were confused about this.
Rym: It's not the cell phone GPS that most cell phones have where they triangulate with cell towers, assisted GPS.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Which is better than regular GPS.
Scott: It is like the best GPS you can get is a consumer pretty much.
Scott: So basically, for the price of less than the Nokia, whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You're getting something that might be lacking a few features that the Nokia device has.
Scott: But the features it does have are actually usable, whereas in the Nokia and the other phones are less usable to the point.
Scott: I mean, in your Blackberry, it has a Web browser.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you wouldn't actually be Web browsing with that shit.
Rym: I do.
Rym: But the thing is painful.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: That's why the only side I go to is Google Reader.
Rym: And even then, it sucks.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But here on the iPhone, it has less features.
Scott: But the features it has are actually usable.
Scott: And this is why the thing is.
Scott: the same thing is true for Mac OS X. Mac OS X is less features than Linux or Windows, but they're more usable.
Scott: And that's a bad thing because on a PC, on a big honking machine, I want 100 percent features.
Scott: I want to be able to do anything.
Scott: But
Rym: on a portable device, especially with a small interface like that, I want to be able to do the few things I need to do as best as I can do them as quickly as possible,
Scott: because even on a PC where Windows or Linux are less usable than Mac, you know, I guess theoretically, they're still usable on the phones.
Scott: The unusable interfaces are unusable.
Scott: They are painful to use, you know, even where Windows or Linux suffers compared to OS X in terms of interface.
Scott: They're not impossible.
Scott: They're not painful.
Scott: They're just a little less slick.
Scott: The iPhone is a pleasure where the other phones are, I guess, I don't know, torture to try to get those features to happen.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So that is why I will get the iPhone, because for I can replace my phone, which sucks.
Scott: I can replace my iPod, which I guess is OK.
Scott: I'll be replacing it with a similar, better iPod.
Scott: And I won't have to go and buy one of those Tom Tom or one of those other company geo, you know, GPS thingies.
Scott: And I can get that all in one thing.
Scott: I can carry less things around with me, which is a huge thing that the other phones don't have going for them.
Scott: I can because like I bought the Nokia or something.
Scott: I still have to have my iPod because it's not a good video audio player.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And I'll need to carry one thing.
Scott: It'll be great.
Scott: I'll have three things in one, three things, which would have had to carry separately before.
Rym: And I mean, of course, 3G.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's that's as fast as it goes.
Rym: And granted, do be aware all of you out there that 3G will subs if you're using it, will substantially cut your battery life.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the point of 3G is that there is no Wi-Fi here.
Scott: I want to still be able to browse the web and I don't want to be painful.
Scott: But the 2G iPhone browsing the web and some such when there are no Wi-Fi access was painful, ludicrously painful because 2G, you know, wireless service is pretty much good for making phone calls.
Scott: Not much.
Rym: Just just so people are aware of the.
Rym: these are the stats as they have released them, which means that obviously the real world load is much less.
Rym: Ten hours of 2G talking, five hours of 3G talking.
Scott: That's still, you know, considering the fact that this is also going to be an MP3 video player and a GPS.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm going to be charging in my car.
Scott: I'll be charging it at work.
Scott: I'll be charging it at home.
Scott: I'll probably have it like I'll.
Scott: probably I'm actually getting the docks instead of just the cables.
Scott: that way, like at work, it can stand up and I can sort of poke at it while it's just standing there.
Scott: Maybe I can use it as like my clock radio at home, you know, wake up.
Scott: And there it is.
Rym: I'd probably have a dock at home and just a cable at work.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We'll see what I do.
Scott: We'll see what the prices on those things are.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the dock is really just a little plastic thing for the cable to go into.
Scott: You know, it's not special in any way.
Rym: Yeah, it depends.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: At work, it'll probably just be charging, but at home it'll be.
Rym: But the point I was getting to, you know, five hours of 3G, six hours of Wi-Fi.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Remember, when you want to use those things, you have a radio in there and you to turn this radio on with a large amount of energy to power that antenna and send out a radio signal.
Rym: like my laptop or any good laptop usually has a hard kill all the wireless switch, which is one for the.
Rym: you know, you're on a plane.
Rym: You can just kill all the wireless and be safe.
Rym: But we'll say from getting screwed by the airline if they find you.
Rym: But do it'll save a couple hours on your battery.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that's really, you know, the iPhone, as far as I know, is actually very smart about turning on and off the different parts of itself when it needs them.
Scott: I mean, from what I've heard, the GPS.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Will only turn on for like a little bit.
Scott: Get the coordinates and turn off.
Scott: It won't have a staying on sustained GPS because that would kill the battery like in 30 minutes, probably.
Rym: But then again, I'm sure certain applications like say you had it docked to something in your car with some sort of navigation thing.
Rym: Then you don't care.
Rym: It's being powered.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Another thing is that they've been taught they're talking about if you want to make a service that pushes right to the phone.
Scott: The thing is, if they just let people program that on their own, that would sort of they could kill the battery on the phone very easily if the phone is pulling a server somewhere or depending on the architecture of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Apple made this thing that people are sort of, you know, two ways about.
Scott: and there are two ways about it, where if you want to make an application that pushes data to the phones, you actually push your server's data to this Apple server.
Scott: And then the Apple server manages the pushing to the phones, which on the one hand, you know, sort of goes more towards that.
Scott: They've closed the platform.
Scott: They're limiting what developers can do and such and whatnot, which is, you know, not so great, but it's going to save you a lot of battery life.
Scott: And it'll actually be, I think, easier for people to develop applications that push to the phones rather than before, where, you know, they would have had to develop it on their own and they might conflict with people.
Scott: And I think it will make a smoother experience despite being yet another lacking of features and possibilities.
Rym: So I assume you're going to get the eight gig.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I might get the 16.
Scott: I got to think about it.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I am not sure.
Rym: I know a lot of people were complaining about the fact that there was no 32 gig.
Scott: I don't need 32 gigs.
Scott: I mean, I have.
Rym: I can understand why they would complain, because I can conceive of a lot of lifestyles where I would need that.
Rym: But I use a two gig nano right now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The reason I have a four gig nano and the reason I'm thinking about the 16 right is because only one hundred dollars more, which is not too bad.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I can afford it.
Scott: But in addition to the probably I'll be probably putting a lot more musics on it.
Scott: Because it'll be like my primary device and whatnot.
Scott: And I'm starting to organize my music and iTunes.
Scott: I'm already, you know, using more music on my iPod as it is.
Scott: But I'm going to be installing apps and things.
Scott: And who knows how much space they're going to take up.
Scott: So rather than wait around, I want to get the most for my money.
Scott: I mean, it'll cost the same amount of money to get this thing around holidays as well now.
Scott: So buying it earlier just means I'll get more for my money in terms of all those months of being able to use it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I can't wait for a bigger one.
Scott: So it might be a good idea to get the big one from the get go.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, the only reason I'm waiting, I'm probably going to get one, but I'm waiting a little bit, partly because the main reason I want to go with this is because it has kind of the Blackberry push and all that.
Rym: And my work, we're going to try to set that up and we've got to make sure that it's good enough to where I can drop my Blackberry.
Rym: Yeah, because if I don't need my Blackberry anymore, I'm all about having just an iPhone to carry.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Not not having to carry more than one device is quite amazing.
Rym: Of course, there's one benefit of having my current setup where I have the Blackberry and the crappy older in the Blackberry off and escape work.
Rym: No, because I could.
Rym: I could probably just not turn off notifications from the work stuff when I'm on vacation.
Rym: I imagine the trouble is I do a lot of sports like mountain biking today.
Rym: I was out biking in the pouring rain for like 45 minutes.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I bring my crappy cell phone with me.
Rym: Oftentimes I'll wipe out and that cell phone is in a lot of danger.
Scott: Well, you can get a little protective thingy for the iPhone.
Scott: Keep it, you know, like a little armband thingy or something like that.
Rym: It's not so great because the shocks alone, especially I mean, it would have to be a pretty sturdy piece of equipment.
Scott: I mean, as long as you don't scratch, as long as it doesn't hit the pavement and get scratched up, if you just shake it around, it's it's all solid state.
Scott: So it's not going to hurt.
Rym: But my phone is.
Rym: there have been many times where I've landed against a tree or something and pretty much straight on my cell phone.
Scott: Well, I mean, but it was in your pocket, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: See, I'm thinking someone should make something right.
Scott: That would be like maybe a little metal like sealed container, sort of.
Scott: that were like a strap.
Scott: So like, you know, if you're doing something heavy duty, you can bring it with you.
Scott: Yeah, I'll have to find something like that, like a plant, like a plastic shell, not just the kind that covers all of it, but the screen, but like a complete plastic shell that locks shut, you know, but is still has little tiny holes in it.
Scott: So like, you know, maybe it still wouldn't be waterproof, but you could hear it if it rings, you know, and you would just sort of be if you landed on it.
Rym: I'd rather have straight up sealed, waterproof, pneumatic.
Scott: Just so you get that, too.
Scott: And you wouldn't hear it ringing.
Rym: I don't care about that.
Rym: I only care the phone in case one.
Rym: I want to see what time it is.
Scott: Or you need to call an emergency.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Or usually an emergency for me is I ran too far and I can't get home before dinner.
Rym: Will someone come pick me up?
Rym: I'm somewhere in New Paul.
Scott: See, the only thing the the only reason I was before hearing all the news of the new iPhone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I was torn between the iPhone or waiting for the Android phones.
Scott: And the thing is, I'm a heavy user of the Google ads for domains.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Google is my thing for communications.
Scott: And the fact that they're doing this mobile me.
Scott: Well, first of all, if I wasn't using Google ads for domains and the mobile me thing was free, I would have gone for it right away.
Scott: But I'm not going to go for Google ads for domains is where it is.
Scott: Screw mobile me.
Scott: It's not worth the money, even if I didn't have Google apps.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the reason the Android phone was appealing, obviously, is because it would have had better integration with my Google apps and my Gmail's and my Google calendar and all that business, where the iPhone does integrate with that, but only on a mediocre level.
Scott: You know, it does basically the bare minimum integrating with the Google stuff.
Scott: And that's sort of sad and disappointing.
Scott: But the Google phone, even the Android, as good as it might have been or might as well, as good as it will be, because from everything I've seen, it is pretty awesome.
Scott: There's no way that that is a good enough MP3 player.
Scott: There's no way it's a good enough video player.
Scott: There's no way it's a good enough GPS.
Scott: I would have to have that and have other stuff.
Scott: I would have to have an iPod still.
Scott: I would end having fewer devices worth, you know, if if you tell me I have a choice, since there is no perfect thing option out there, if I have to choose between my Google interfacing is slightly mediocre or I have to carry a bunch of things instead of one thing, I'm going to carry the one thing and have a mediocre Google.
Rym: I don't trust Google to fully support my four domains because they don't support it for credit is to Google.
Scott: If people Google apps for domains, I don't know if people know about this.
Scott: We use it heavily is if you get a Gmail account rights at gmail dot com.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But let's say you don't really want to run a Web server because Web servers suck and it sucks to run them.
Scott: But you want to be a people to email you at your own domain dot com.
Scott: So for us, it's from recruit dot com.
Scott: But we don't want to run the mail server.
Scott: Well, Google run the mail server for you.
Scott: And it just looks like Gmail.
Scott: It is Gmail, but it's your domain.
Scott: So when you email us, we actually go to like Gmail and read those emails.
Scott: But it's not a Gmail account.
Scott: It's a front row crew dot com Google apps for domains account.
Scott: The thing is, they don't support.
Scott: It's like the people who use Google apps or domains, the hardcore Google users who actually run their own domain off of Google, we get the shaft.
Scott: We get less.
Scott: We don't have those Google Labs features that are in Gmail.
Rym: Not even that, like Google Reader.
Rym: I have the Google stuff doesn't work at all.
Rym: So I have a Gmail account and a Google Apps account.
Rym: Yeah, email account exists solely to use all the Google stuff.
Scott: The people with Google Apps or domains get the shaft.
Scott: So because of that, I can't trust, you know, without super confirmation that the Android phone isn't also going to shaft people who use Google Apps or domains as opposed to just regular Gmail.
Scott: So screw Google.
Scott: I'm still going to use Google Apps or domains is still the best.
Scott: But I'm going to just work through it with the shitty interface that I can, you know, going to the Web page in the Web browser, syncing with the icon, the calendar thing.
Rym: Well, I think my strategy for now is I'm not going to get the iPhone right away.
Rym: I'll let Scott get it and a few other people get it.
Rym: And by then, I'll probably know how well it's going to work with my work.
Scott: Well, I mean, I got my brother got an iPod touch and I was poking that.
Scott: And I was.
Scott: all I had to do is poke it for five minutes.
Scott: And I was like, yeah, all right, I'll get the iPhone.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It really just comes down to if I can support it with my work.
Rym: Because if I still have to carry that Blackberry, I'm not.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: if I still have to carry the Blackberry, I wouldn't.
Scott: If it didn't replace it, I wouldn't do it either.
Scott: The only other thing I can say about the iPhone is that as good as the multi touch is, these keyboard is not better than actual QWERTY button keyboard, which is why my boss refuses to get an iPhone.
Scott: But, you know, that's another tiny sacrifice I will make because the advantages are far away.
Rym: Plus, I'll point out I've seen this kind of often on the train.
Rym: I'll see a person with a Blackberry or something and plugged into it will be a full size keyboard.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Scary.
Rym: I mean, it could because if you're just typing emails, I guess it would kind of for a little email.
Scott: OK, but for a big email, you're much better off taking your laptop, tethering it to the Blackberry and opening outlook.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So 20 years ago at Michigan State University, a university that has much love for him because it's an awesome college town.
Scott: You didn't go there, though.
Rym: No, but I had a lot of friends there because you're from Michigan and my brother went there.
Rym: And let me tell you, there was no way.
Scott: it says Michigan State, not U of M, not U of M, Michigan State, Michigan State.
Scott: All right.
Rym: The green one with the Spartans.
Scott: OK, I didn't actually know it was green.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Green and white in Lansing, the capital.
Scott: All righty.
Rym: Anyway, so 20 years ago, a man by the name of Richard Linsky, a biologist and evolutionary biologist, took a strain of E. coli and he split it up and made 12 E. coli populations.
Rym: And for the last 20 years, he's been observing these 12 strains.
Scott: 20 years.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: That's quite a large experiment.
Rym: They've undergone over 40,000 generations.
Scott: That is quite the experiment of grandiose-ness.
Scott: Well,
Rym: in this time, I'm not going to get
Scott: I mean, I'm no scientist, but I would be I
Rym: even wore a lab coat and I would be
Scott: mighty bored if the if I like if I only worked on one software project for 20 years,
Rym: I imagine
Scott: I would be mighty bored.
Rym: I imagine he worked on other things.
Scott: I hope so, because God damn, that'd be so boring.
Scott: Well, one thing for 20 years, day 4008.
Rym: No change.
Scott: Good God.
Rym: So I'm not going to get into all of the details, partly because I want to talk about a lot of other news tonight.
Rym: And two, because Pete and Lisa and Scott Johnson will probably pick holes through anything I say beyond the kind of AP wire story we don't know we're talking about.
Rym: I know a little bit.
Scott: We know the more than most people, but not as much as people really know.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Rym: I'm going to first I'm going to paraphrase from this article, and then I'm going to summarize the article.
Rym: But sometime around the thirty one thousand five hundredth generation, something dramatic happened in just one of the populations.
Rym: The bacteria suddenly acquired the ability to metabolize citrate, a second nutrient in their culture that E. coli cannot normally use.
Scott: As in you squirt some oranges on it and it goes yummy, yummy, yummy.
Scott: Well, the other E. coli is good.
Rym: No, it was something that was already there.
Rym: OK, basically.
Rym: Now, this is why this is amazing.
Rym: The ability to metabolize citrate in this manner is one of these specific traits that is used by bacteriologists to distinguish E. coli from other bacteria.
Scott: So in other words, if you want to do a test to find E. coli, you put some citrates in there.
Scott: And if the citrates are not metabolized, then it's E. coli.
Scott: But if the citrates are metabolized, then then it may be a different species.
Scott: All righty.
Rym: But apparently that basically the gist of this is that these bacteria evolved a very complex and very specialized trait.
Rym: And we observe this directly.
Rym: Now, I don't think I need to preach to the choir here, but there has.
Rym: there has been a lot of evidence for evolution.
Rym: The theory of evolution.
Rym: There's really never been evidence against it.
Rym: This is I don't know how many nails there are in the coffin, but this is the biggest fucking nail I've ever seen.
Scott: I mean, we already had some like stakes right through the heart and stuff.
Scott: But this is like I don't know.
Scott: This is like the nail of heaven through right down the asshole and out the mouth.
Rym: To paraphrase a quote from Jerry Coyne, another evolutionary biologist.
Rym: He's from Chicago.
Rym: The thing I like most is it says that you can get these complex traits evolving by a combination of unlikely events.
Rym: That's just what the creationists say can happen.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: We have we watched it.
Rym: It happened.
Scott: Here it is on video through a microscope, microscope, video.
Scott: Watch.
Scott: See it.
Rym: I just think this is fascinating.
Rym: And I'm hoping that Pete and Lisa and Scott will have something to say in the forums about how amazing this is.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So anyway, before we get on with more tech news, round up a cop out Monday, it's not a cop out.
Scott: This is good stuff.
Rym: Yeah, there is this time in the past.
Rym: It has definitely been a cop out.
Rym: It's time for things of the day.
Rym: So I don't know how many of you are aware of this practice, but because a bunch of you were fooled in the forum, I have to bring this up.
Rym: There is a pass time on the Internet, a pass time that I love, that I adore, that I wish I had more time to try to get involved in called link baiting or news baiting.
Rym: Now, the idea here is that you make a similar to Rick Rolling.
Rym: Not really.
Rym: You make a fake news story and try to get the real news to pick up on it.
Rym: Or the very least happens a lot to fool a bunch of people.
Rym: And there was a story.
Rym: Our forum was talking about it, about a teenager who stole his dad's credit card and bought hookers.
Rym: And if you couldn't tell from reading the article, it was totally made up.
Rym: And here is the detailed explanation of who made it up, why they made it up, who paid them to make it up and how you're all too credulous for the Internet.
Scott: Credulity.
Scott: Learn it.
Rym: Well, no, credulity, avoid it.
Scott: Same thing you got if you learn about credulity, you won't have it.
Rym: You need to be incredulous.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: All right.
Scott: We're good.
Rym: That's all I got.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So you if you're listening to Tech Monday, you should know about twenty six hundred magazine.
Scott: It started out as sort of like.
Scott: Yeah, OK, it started out as sort of like this sort of zine of sorts, and you had to like go to a news group and send it, you know, self-addressed stamped envelope to get, you know, sort of get it and eventually became, you know, a real quarterly magazine that was professionally published.
Scott: And I think it's dead now.
Scott: Isn't it dead now?
Rym: I stopped reading it in the 90s.
Scott: I never actually read twenty six hundred, but it was always infamous.
Scott: It's like everyone knew what it was, whether you read it or not.
Rym: It'll totally tell you how to make a blotto box.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically.
Scott: it's basically the magazine for the hacks or is the real hackers?
Scott: like the whole history of, you know, what happened in technology like the 80s and 90s is all in twenty six hundred magazine.
Scott: We're talking about everything from the phone freaking guys, you know, to the to what caused the creation of the Electronic Frontier Foundation.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I mean, it's probably common knowledge to a lot of your techies, but knowing the twenty six hundred, the number is a very important number and not just because of the Atari.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And we're talking like, you know, the whole story of Kevin Mitnick was in there, the whole thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I posted this in the forums already, but it's got to be my thing of the day anyway.
Scott: They are making a hardcover bound book that is eight hundred and eighty eight pages.
Scott: That is the best of twenty six hundred.
Scott: So if you didn't have a chance to, you know, live nerd history, you're too young for that shit or you just missed out on it or whatever.
Scott: by this book, you can preorder on Amazon.
Scott: It's only like twenty six dollars and you'll basically have.
Scott: you know, it's not every every article and every two twenty six hundred ever.
Scott: But it's the best of twenty six hundred.
Scott: All the important stuff.
Scott: It's all of the history of how technology got to where it is today from where it was about like, you know, twenty, thirty years ago.
Scott: And it is if you're really if you're a tech person, you know, who's hip to the nets and whatnot, you're elite.
Scott: This is something you got to own.
Scott: You can't not have this.
Scott: You can't be out of the loop on this shit.
Rym: I mean, I feel in a way I'm glad I live when I do now because technology is just leaps and like it's accelerating at a point that I can barely even keep up.
Rym: But at the same time, there was a certain magic to the phone freaking error that was kind of the Wild West, like the wildest of Wild West's technology.
Rym: And we came of age and the fading days of it.
Rym: I mean, I red boxed a little bit and then it was over.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's like you have to you know, if you are someone who's in, you have to know where you came from.
Scott: You got to know the roots.
Scott: You know, this is if you don't get the twenty six hundred and you think you're a tech person, that's like if you're playing PS3, you never played any essence.
Scott: You know, you know, you don't know nothing about any essence.
Scott: You got to.
Scott: you got to know, you know, the shit.
Rym: So like we said, this is a tech news roundup, which means that we're just pretty much going to cover a whole bunch of tech news.
Rym: But we got a bunch of little things that we're not going to go into super depth about.
Rym: But mostly our opinions, I think, are what matters.
Rym: And if you don't know what the news is specifically are, you want the details.
Rym: There's a reason we link to things.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Go to the website, read the news article.
Scott: People seem to notice how we didn't go over what the features and what the announcement for the iPhone was.
Scott: We just sort of gave our opinion of it.
Scott: also because you go to engage it and read that shit.
Rym: People seem to like the one episode where we pretty much didn't hold back very much in terms of talking about tech.
Rym: So we're going to try to go along that line a little bit more than we used to.
Scott: But I'm not supposed to hold back.
Scott: I'll stop holding back now, at
Rym: least in terms of we're not going to explain what IP addresses are before we talk about the
Scott: I&I, the I&I, the
Rym: I&I, I&I, so there's
Scott: this
Rym: article on Slashdot,
Scott: you know,
Rym: there's something about that, that specific troll that I still crack up to this day.
Scott: It's a funny troll.
Scott: What can I say?
Rym: Anyway, there's this article on Slashdot that recommends an interview with John DeGose or Goays or Goays.
Rym: And basically the gist of it with the gist is what I want to talk about.
Rym: The headline says it all.
Rym: Open source killing commercial developer tools.
Rym: Quote, some developers would rather quit their job than be forced to use a new editor IDE.
Scott: Yeah, so let me get let me explain what this is very hard to sell these things as a result.
Scott: OK, so there is software in the world that is meant to be used by people like, for example, Microsoft Office is meant to be used by people.
Rym: Oh, I guess we're explaining.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: You want to I'm going to.
Scott: I'm going to explain only a little bit.
Rym: It's real simple.
Rym: These are things that developers use to make software.
Scott: It is software made by developers for developers.
Scott: Now, people often complain about open source software usually being bad for end users like the GIMP.
Scott: You know, as much as the GIMP is good enough for me, it's not good enough.
Rym: It's like being the GIMP.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You know, the software that is made by open source is usually not as usable for the average person because it is made by developers for they make it for their own sensibilities and being advanced users, you know, it's not going to be sensible to my grandma that as much.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, even like ReSound, I use it, but I defy a lot of people to even get ReSound to work in Ubuntu, whereas GarageBand nice and easy for those people, even those less features.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what's happened is developers, you know, they make software for other people open source, but they also make software for other developers open source.
Scott: And that software that is made for other developers by open source developers has taken over the world.
Scott: You look at stuff like Django, Ruby on Rails, all these development toolkits, all you know, the VIM, the Emacs, all these sorts of GCC, it can just go on and on.
Scott: All these developer tools made by developers have pretty much taken over the development world.
Rym: Now, this guy is I didn't read his whole interview, but basically he works for some company that makes this sort of software for money.
Scott: Yeah, like stuff like Microsoft Visual Studio and stuff like that, you know, competitors in that arena not doing so well because for free you can get the best stuff there is.
Scott: It's not like open source.
Scott: You can get it, but it's missing some features.
Scott: It's when it comes to developers tools, it's open source, better than everything else and free.
Rym: And now over time, what I want to get into the reason for this, really, I mean, people like this guy's article, it looks like he's just complaining about how it's really hard to compete in this market.
Rym: And the article is pretty much just a shill for his development thing.
Scott: Yeah, screw that.
Rym: Yeah, but basically I'm of the mind that screw that.
Rym: that market is dead and it should be dead.
Rym: I'm glad it's dead.
Rym: And the reason it's dead and the reason there's no point in making commercial software is that the main problem with most open source is that people know it's kind of like podcasting.
Rym: You might know about audio and podcasting, but do you know about something else that's interesting to make a podcast about?
Rym: A lot of audio software sucks because most people who write software don't know a hell of a lot about audio or don't care about it, where all these open source projects often aren't good at what they do because there aren't enough people with the expertise to code these things that are also interested in making that specific software.
Rym: There is very little, let's say, hospital management software that's open source because it's not fun to write hospital management software.
Rym: But if you're a software developer and something pisses you off about your development tool, you make it better because it's the thing you definitely know about.
Rym: You're writing code.
Rym: You can write code to make writing code easier.
Scott: You sure can.
Scott: And what happens over time is someone will get a job somewhere and that place will use some proprietary development tool.
Scott: Then they'll go somewhere else.
Scott: And that place used an open development tool of some kind.
Scott: And they can't use the closed development tool they were using before because someone had to pay for it.
Scott: And over time they'll go to the next job.
Scott: And even if that job uses a closed development tool, those open tools are still available for free.
Scott: So what happens is over time, if developers move jobs and change habits and do stuff on their own, they will always have the open tools available to them no matter where they go or what they work on.
Scott: Whereas the closed tools are only available when they work in the places that have them.
Scott: And thus, as developers continue on in their careers, their default set of development tools will always be an open set of tools.
Scott: And not only that, but the open set of tools are far superior in every possible respect.
Rym: Plus, if anyone made a commercial IDE or something that was I mean, there's an argument for visual based like Visual Studio is actually a pretty damn good idea if you're doing that sort of code.
Scott: But it's mostly the reason people use that is because it's the only way to make like Microsoft software is to use.
Scott: that is no there's no alternative.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But like in terms of if, say, some commercial company made an IDE that was like a thousand times better than anything out there, whatever concepts they used, even if the code isn't stolen or shared or whatever, any developer who looks at it and goes, oh, that'd be a good feature.
Rym: We'll just add it to their idea.
Scott: I mean, how many Visual Studio features are in Eclipse?
Scott: Most of them.
Rym: Man, Eclipse has come a long way.
Rym: I'll say this much.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if you're doing Java, Eclipse is the way to go.
Scott: You can use it for other things, but for Java, it's definitely it's worthwhile.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Granted, I don't write a lot of code, so I pretty much use notepad plus plus or VI to write my Python CV.
Scott: I made a text editor made by people who texted it all day.
Scott: They make VI with VI.
Scott: Think about that.
Scott: The VI is going to turn out real well if you make it with itself.
Scott: So today's what Monday?
Rym: It is Monday night, Monday, June, Monday, the 16th.
Scott: Two thousand and eight.
Scott: So last Friday was the 13th because even Monday the 16th, you have a Friday, the 13th.
Scott: And when you have a Friday, the 13th, you have a Thursday, the 12th.
Rym: Yeah, but you also have Wednesday, the 11th, Tuesday, the 17th.
Scott: Dum, dum, dum.
Scott: If anyone knows about the famous Ren and Stimpy episode with the bad juju, Tuesday, the 17th, which only occurs on their Friday, the 13th.
Rym: I wonder how intentional that was.
Scott: Very intentional.
Scott: Anyway, the Tuesday, the 17th, tomorrow is a very special Tuesday, the 17th, perhaps one of the most special Tuesday, 17th ever because Firefox three is going to be released, not just release.
Scott: candidate did the full deal.
Scott: It's going to be out, out, out, out, out for the real deal.
Scott: Time to upgrade.
Scott: Forget Firefox two.
Scott: Firefox two is dead.
Scott: It sucks.
Scott: Everyone knows it sucks.
Scott: It sucks a lot.
Scott: Firefox three.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Super awesome.
Scott: Not perfect, but a lot better than every other web browser.
Scott: And the Mozilla people, what they're going to try to do is they're going to say we want to have the most downloads ever of a software program in one day.
Scott: So the more people that download Firefox three, you are going to be part of a Guinness Book of World Record, which will hopefully, if that is achieved, provide additional stimulus and, you know, I guess advertising in a way to for Firefox, increase the word of mouth.
Scott: We'll get the word out there.
Scott: Some more.
Rym: I'm of the opinion that Guinness Book is pretty much just Pablo.
Scott: Oh, it is quite the pablum.
Scott: Regardless, it will still help the Firefox for this pablum regard.
Scott: And Firefox three, even if you don't want to upgrade to it tomorrow for the stupidity of the world record and whatnot, it should probably be used in Firefox three, no matter what kind of computer or device you are using.
Scott: If Firefox three is available, that's the browser you want to use, if possible.
Scott: Because let me tell you, I've been using it for a few months now.
Scott: It is a thousand times superior to every other web browser that I've ever used in my entire life.
Scott: I mean, the Firefox, two problems of crashing and running out of memory, gone, slow interface problems, gone, features missing, gone, fast, super fast, renders things nicely, perfectly.
Scott: Firefox three is where it's at, people.
Scott: You got to be upgrading tomorrow.
Scott: You're probably listening to this.
Scott: You listen to this on Tuesday because we do Monday, Monday night.
Scott: So right now, get Firefox dot com and download that shit.
Rym: Right, so there's this article here, I'm not going to get into the specifics once again, because it's an issue that I thought I weren't holding back.
Rym: Well, yeah, but the specifics of the issue itself and why it came up in the article are not that interesting.
Rym: What's interesting and what a lot of people seem to have questions about is the whole idea of a return to sender or sender receipts on an email.
Scott: Because isn't that when I send a thingy, but I want to get a notification that you opened it?
Rym: Now, I mean, a lot of commercial or like office things do that like exchange.
Rym: You can tell it to use a receipt and then whenever you open an email, it'll say, hey, do you want to send a sender receipt?
Rym: And most people click never and then check never, ever again.
Scott: Yeah, but the idea is that it gives you an a possible way, right, for you to send someone an email and then if they want to, they can let you know they got it.
Scott: That's all it is.
Rym: Granted, at least in corporations, I very much like and used a lot the idea that that is not an option and that you will know the second that anyone read an email that you send in the corporation.
Rym: And where I worked before at the hospital, it was set up that way.
Rym: And at IBM, it was set up that way.
Rym: And that was possibly the best thing ever when I would inform someone of something and then they didn't do it or they complained when their server got turned off, despite the fact that something 10 emails telling them I was going to turn it off and voicemails and that could point and say, well, on Monday you read the email that said that I was going to turn it off on Tuesday.
Rym: You read the critical high priority email that said I was going to turn it off.
Rym: You obviously did nothing.
Scott: Good times.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of people are really freaked out by this and a lot of people get really nervous about it.
Rym: And then these companies come along and say, ah, we've got a special technology where if you send someone an email, we can tell you when they read it, we can tell you how long they read it.
Rym: We can make it so they can't forward it to other people.
Rym: We can make it so it self-destructs.
Scott: You can do that.
Rym: Here's the deal.
Scott: Pretty much I can always copy paste the text out.
Rym: Well, the way are.
Rym: let's tackle these in order.
Rym: First off, the way most spam does that is they'll include an image, either an invisible like one pixel by one pixel, a little spliff of an image there or just the whole email will be an image.
Rym: And the image is not an embedded image.
Rym: It links back to a server somewhere and then they know if that image got downloaded.
Rym: So if you put this little one pixel by one pixel and you make the file name unique for each one in each email you send out, like some sort of serial number, then, you know, if someone visited and read that email because then their client went out and got that image.
Rym: Of course, Google and smart clients just don't allow images from untrusted clients explicitly allow.
Scott: You don't see the images in your email until you click a button that says display images so that that plan doesn't work.
Scott: Try try again.
Rym: So but the thing is, a lot of people just click that anyway or use clients where that's the default.
Rym: So it actually works pretty well to find out if someone read an email.
Rym: Now, the way they go one step further, let's say they want to know how long someone read an email.
Rym: This is so clever.
Rym: They'll embed another invisible image, but they'll throttle the rate so that it sends pixels at a time or bytes at a time.
Rym: And the email client, if it's stupid, which most email clients are, will slowly read this image as long as it's open and stop reading it once you close the email.
Rym: So you can pretty cleverly figure out how long someone read an email within a reasonable error of certainty or error of window of certainty or reasonable error.
Scott: Another thing people do is they send you an email, right, that's actually a big image, but they use some other magic and they can figure out exactly where you clicked on the email.
Scott: Like, did you click on this link or that link, you know, and all the different links on the email are actually slightly different.
Scott: So when you click on one link or another, they take you to the same place that the spam wants you to go to.
Scott: But because the links were named differently, their Web service is aha.
Scott: He must have clicked on that link.
Scott: So now they know which links in the email are getting clicked on more.
Scott: And then they adjust the way their spam looks to sort of get more clicks from people.
Rym: Now, a lot of people really freak out about this.
Rym: And one, I don't care at all.
Scott: I really don't care either.
Rym: I'm fine with people knowing if I read an email or didn't read an email, because let's be honest, if I don't, I'll just say don't send a sender a receipt this time.
Rym: The only reason to not want someone to know that you read their email is if you plan on avoiding them or whatever they tried to send you without having to tell them to their face.
Scott: Well, I also do it sometimes where I don't want people to think I read the email.
Scott: It's like a long time to reply.
Scott: I want people to think, but I read the email and then take a long time to reply.
Rym: I know it was there and I didn't read it purposefully.
Scott: I want to read the email.
Scott: I want people to think I read the email and replied relatively quickly, like within a day.
Rym: Yes, but obviously that's not true.
Scott: Well, it is most of the time.
Scott: It is true, actually.
Rym: You know, the email was there.
Rym: You just didn't respond to it.
Rym: I guess you saw it there and you decided like say you knew that there's an email, but he has left.
Scott: There's no receipt.
Scott: Then they might have some doubts that maybe I didn't read it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but that's the thing.
Rym: It's just you trying to pull the wool over on them.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I like to pull the wool.
Scott: I think the difference I'm pulling the wool without actually lying.
Rym: The difference in philosophy here can be summed up pretty easily because you saw this a lot in the early days of.
Rym: I am and I'm sure you still do.
Rym: I just don't pay attention anymore.
Rym: But I remember you always had the option of let other people know when I'm online or idle or don't.
Rym: let other people know when I'm typing or don't.
Rym: And I've always allowed people to have this information.
Scott: The only one I don't do is know what I'm typing because sometimes I'll type and then I'll say, oh, actually, I didn't want to say anything.
Scott: And then they'll be like, well, what are you going to say?
Scott: And I'm like, I decided not to.
Rym: I let it go anyway.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Google lets me know when you're typing.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I just, you know, it's.
Scott: Sometimes I want to, you know, I don't want if I can avoid going, oh, yeah.
Scott: And and what?
Scott: Never mind.
Scott: If I can avoid that, that's OK by me.
Rym: But pretty much just a final bit here about this news, a lot of these companies try to say something like, hey, we can send you an email that you can't forward or an email that you can't.
Rym: That's impossible.
Scott: That is impossible.
Rym: Absolutely impossible unless they set up some sort of proprietary system, which one.
Rym: you're just not going to use their system or some sort of active X. use the open GL driver to send something directly.
Scott: Here's what you can do.
Scott: I can send an email to them, right?
Scott: They take a screenshot of the email and turn it into an image.
Scott: They email the image to the other guy that I actually want to send it to.
Scott: Then they check to see when the images are requested and by who.
Scott: And then they check, you know, to see if that's actually the person the mail is mailed to in his cash.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if that email gets forwarded to someone, then it won't load the image and they won't see any email.
Scott: But that person can always just take the image, save it an email to someone or copy and paste or any sort of thing like that.
Rym: All these sorts of soft or fake DRM that are applied to otherwise open protocols or standards are just instill a false sense of security and are pretty much nothing but scams.
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: Yeah, there's a few problems in the world that you may not realize are problems.
Rym: The fact that I have to carry four power strips with me when I go anywhere.
Scott: That is a problem.
Scott: There is also the problem that many devices that you plug in and to charge will actually constantly, you know, take electricity out of the wall even when they don't need it.
Rym: You know, also the fact that a lot of different electronic devices use completely different plugs and completely different like adapters to get their power.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And in a way, that's good because every different device has sort of its own proprietary rechargeable battery, which is sort of bad in the proprietariness.
Scott: But it's good and that these batteries are custom for the devices that they're for rather than every device having to adapt to use double A's or triple A's.
Scott: You know, it's much more efficient that way.
Scott: And, you know, you can design batteries to be just strong enough for the device and have the charge for the correct amount of time and all that good stuff.
Scott: So someone has come up with sort of a solution, but the solution won't take off unless more people get on the bandwagon.
Scott: The solution is green plug thing now.
Scott: First of all, for the environmentally curious people, right, this thing will save a lot of electricity if people use it, because all that stand by electricity usage, that just won't happen with this thing.
Scott: It's designed to not let you use electricity when you don't need it.
Rym: This is the kind of thing that has been a long time coming.
Rym: The idea that you can I mean, we have two way communication with almost every piece of electronics.
Rym: I mean, printers used to be one way a lot of times, but now the printer can talk back and say, hey, I didn't print that.
Rym: Why can't my cell phone tell the adapter, hey, stop powering that transformer?
Rym: I'm done.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So what this green plug thing is, is it's a universal plug.
Scott: Their goal is that I guess as many electronic devices as possible, perhaps every electronic device, you know, iPods, cell phones, Nintendo DS's, PSP's, you know, your Bluetooth earpiece, you know, anything that needs charging, right, that you have.
Scott: your laptop will instead of, you know, like my laptop has a power cable.
Scott: My DS is different power cable, right?
Scott: That instead, everyone will just use their power cable, the green thing, the green bug, whatever it's called,
Rym: and no
Scott: one will use any other kind of power cable and everyone will just make their device to use this thing, which is a great idea, because, first of all, you just have to carry one of these bad boys around.
Scott: You can charge everything and you won't have to worry about carrying separate shit.
Scott: That's great, too.
Scott: We could actually like build these things into the wall.
Scott: If, you know, if it's just universal, why not?
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: Well, the thing is, even way back when I was thinking about, hey, I should buy a house, I toyed with the idea of having some DC for all the servers and things we have.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And number three, this thing does the two way communication with your device.
Scott: So you look at the plug and it will tell you which devices that are plugged into it are charged, how much they're charged, how much electricity you've saved, how much you've used, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: And you could actually price set options on it.
Scott: There's a lot of possibilities there and they've only really scratched the surface with the kind of stuff that you could do.
Scott: Like, you know, like you could tell it, hey, you know, only charge my laptop up or, hey, you know, forget everything else.
Scott: I need my laptop charge really quickly or all kinds of good stuff like that.
Scott: And if more companies start using this instead of using their own personal proprietary cables for every single different device, then the world would probably be a lot better place overall and a lot more convenient for everyone who uses electricity and has portable device and convenience aside.
Rym: I mean, I know environmentalism, not just from a from all and there's all these different perspectives on it, but there's a very practical element here, regardless of your feelings and all these things to conserving electricity, because energy is becoming the rarest and most important commodity in the world.
Scott: You know, actually, even more than saving electricity by using this device, you know what the biggest impact on the environment is going to be?
Scott: The fact that instead of having a hundred different factories around the world making all sorts of different plugs, there'll be one factory making the same exact plug over and over again, which is a thousand times more efficient.
Rym: I didn't even think of that.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: And that's the kind of thing that the people don't think of that anyway.
Scott: If you want to save energy, factories are the place to save the most energy.
Rym: There's there's zoom out economy of scale.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: That's why electric cars are in many ways a good idea, because then you've separated the you can do the conversion to electricity much more efficiently.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of factors.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there's a lot there.
Rym: I could I could talk for hours about that.
Rym: The point is, Westinghouse, which is not the biggest player, has decided they're on way to quote the article, but quote someone from Westinghouse, we're not the biggest player.
Scott: I didn't I didn't read the article.
Scott: I didn't read that, but we're the first.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: They've their first company on board with this.
Scott: And I hope that maybe we can get, say, I don't know, Sony on here.
Scott: Maybe that would help.
Scott: No, you realize what's going to happen about Fujitsu.
Scott: Have a Samsung.
Scott: Samsung, you help us out.
Rym: No, you realize exactly what's going to happen.
Rym: So what?
Rym: Samsung is going to jump on board with this right away.
Rym: And so is Microsoft, like for whatever things they sell, then Google will put put on their Android.
Scott: Where are you at?
Scott: But then Nokia.
Rym: But then Sony is going to release blue plug and blue plug is going to be one percent faster at recharging.
Rym: But it turns out you can only plug it into Sony products.
Scott: That's just fantastic.
Scott: I mean, it's like if they did that, even if they had a universal plug for each company, like the Fujitsu plug, the Sony plug, that would still be a thousand times better than I guess now.
Rym: I would only need the Apple slash Nintendo plug.
Scott: I know right now, but I hope that this happens and we should.
Rym: This idea is not just for portable consumer electronics for everything.
Rym: The idea of a universal plug
Scott: TV
Rym: for LCDs, for my Marantz, for every piece of electronics, because one of the biggest things where we waste electricity and power and energy in the modern world today is the inefficient distribution of power, the inefficient management of power, the wiring in most houses in this country.
Rym: Is atrocious.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And vacuum cleaners and TVs and all these things, if we just manage everything has its own power supply and they're all different and the power system in your house knows nothing about these power supplies.
Scott: If the if there was more communication between the power in the house and the grid and the actual power you need to use, we could distribute it a lot more efficiently, a lot more.
Rym: We can't make end to end intelligence.
Scott: In fact, that's ludicrous.
Rym: I mean, there's there's been a long standing argument both in telecommunications and in power transform, transfer.
Rym: I was going to say transferring transmission and I was also going to say transformation, but I meant transmission.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: But the idea of do you make the network dumb and the nodes intelligent or the nodes dumb and the network intelligent and their arguments equally in both direction?
Scott: You could make the whole thing intelligent, but that's ludicrous.
Rym: But I'm ambivalent on the issue.
Rym: But I think the best place to start is at the end point level with power, with consumer technology.
Rym: And then from there, with houses, I envision the day where regardless of what happens with the grid in the future, there is the demark point to my house and then my house will have a computerized intelligent power distribution system.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, think about it right now.
Scott: The actual devices themselves are as intelligent as they're going to be.
Scott: The next step is to make between the devices in the wall because that's the step we're looking at now.
Rym: The house is stupid.
Scott: And once if we get to that point where everything is powered by with the same green bug thingy, then we can make the house intelligent and then we can work our way up from there.
Scott: You know.
Rym: All right.
Rym: But I think we have to get on to our other big news, because while I really want to talk about Verizon dropping all net, which I don't care about, but I'm sure some people do not actually that hungry.
Scott: I'm hungry.
Rym: And I really want to talk about this Wall Street becoming a Linux stronghold article, because it's totally true.
Scott: It's totally true.
Rym: And there's a lot of reasons for that.
Rym: And I really, really, really want to talk about how the EFF won that case about first sale in terms of promo CDs, because first sale, if nothing else, mark my words, the doctrine of first sale is going to become one of the biggest fucking issues in the next three or four years.
Scott: I say the next one or two years, it's going to be huge.
Scott: And I think it's actually going to be settled.
Scott: And I'm predicting now be settled in our favor.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: If it is not settled in our favor, we still win, but we'll talk about that.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right, people, for the next Monday show, do you want cyber warfare or do you want first sale doctrine for a sale?
Scott: That shouldn't even really a Monday.
Rym: I think the technology, the technology issues surrounding it alone.
Scott: It is.
Scott: We could do that.
Rym: It could be a Thursday.
Rym: All right.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: So instead, we have to talk about this big news of metering.
Scott: By your eyes, please.
Rym: Now, this is such a complicated issue that we cannot do it justice in, I don't know, the last 20 minutes of this show.
Scott: Are you really going to die over 20 minutes?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: But I think what the fundamental issue is, the core, if we go all the way down to the bottom, we get as far down as we can go, is that the ISPs in the United States, pretty much since the beginning of broadband, have been lying.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They have been saying to people, look, unlimited, here's the speed we give you up and down.
Rym: In the best case, we will give you unlimited bandwidth and it costs X per month.
Scott: Use it all day.
Scott: Use it all night.
Scott: We don't care how much you use it.
Scott: We're going to set the speed on you.
Scott: But that's it.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The only reason that was viable back then was there's a little secret.
Rym: The dirty secret of the Internet was because they assumed, much like Jim's, that 99 percent of users would use maybe one percent of that capacity.
Scott: I posted this whole thing in the forum.
Scott: But yeah, if you go to like a workout gym, like Gold's Gym or New York Sports Club or Equinox or whatever kind of gym you have near you.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I'm thinking about getting a gym membership, actually.
Scott: New York Sports Club isn't bad.
Rym: You can take a shower.
Rym: In the winter, right?
Rym: In the summer, I don't care because I do all this stuff.
Rym: But in the winter, one, there's one right next to Grand Central.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And two, I can shower.
Rym: So, yeah, I'm thinking about then I could bike to work where my pajamas on the train.
Scott: If I lived in the city, I would get one.
Scott: I won the head of pool.
Scott: It's like a swim.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, of course, if I lived in the city, I'd live in a building that had a pool.
Scott: Yes, that, too.
Scott: And so with my millions and my diamond shoes, we get this one pool building in Brooklyn.
Scott: I know we can afford, but the pool is small anyway.
Rym: And also, as much as I like Brooklyn, I would rather live in either Manhattan or I don't know, on the Hudson line.
Scott: I'd like to live anyway.
Scott: So metering the Internet's right.
Scott: What was I saying?
Rym: I didn't even get to my my my point.
Scott: So much like gyms, the way gym membership works, like if you own a Gold's gym, the way you make your money is you have a membership drive around New Year's.
Scott: You get all the fat people to sign up for your gym.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you say, come on, lose weight, people.
Scott: It's only like 30 bucks a month.
Scott: And they go woo and they sign up.
Rym: And let me tell you, if you're a member of a gym, pretty much the three weeks after New Year's are hell because there's a million people who have never been to a gym before.
Rym: Half of them don't even have gym clothes, desperately trying to use the treadmill and maybe the Stairmaster.
Rym: Yeah, because they're afraid of everything else.
Rym: And then there's all the other people who think they're going to lift weights, but don't know how.
Rym: And then none of those people will be back.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And but those people, you know, they don't cancel or they you know, it's sort of like World of Warcraft.
Rym: They realize they can't cancel.
Rym: There's usually a fee that do.
Scott: So these people keep paying and paying and paying, but they're not using the facilities.
Scott: And that's how gyms make all their money.
Scott: If gyms actually had that New Year's traffic all year, they would go out of business because they couldn't afford to buy all of those workout machines to have all those people.
Rym: But at the same time, that would mean there's enough demand that they could just raise their prices or their gyms.
Scott: That, too.
Rym: But that's not how it is.
Scott: That's not how it is.
Scott: They have they they make money.
Scott: They make good profits because they can have less facilities available.
Scott: They don't have to actually supply to meet the potential demand of the customer.
Scott: And the ISP is the same way.
Scott: They could have a thousand customers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And only actually have enough real bandwidth available for like a hundred of them because only 10 percent of the people are actually using it at any one time.
Rym: I now now here is the rub, if you will.
Rym: The Internet is that times a hundred billion billion.
Rym: I mean, let's cut back in the day.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Way back, I happen to live in a place where I had a cable modem.
Rym: when I was in early high school, like ninth grade, I had a cable modem.
Rym: And my friends had a cable modem.
Rym: And like our area, we all got cable modems and everyone was like, oh, snap, cable modems, fast Internet all the time, cheap, whatever.
Rym: It was this trial rollout.
Rym: So we all had them and they advertised unlimited speed.
Rym: And I looked and realized, wait a minute, I can upload and download as much as I want.
Rym: My computer can be on 24/7.
Rym: My computer can be on the Internet when I am not on my computer.
Rym: And I started downloading things and pretty much I maxed out my pipe from the moment I got my cable modem until the moment I turned off the computer before a thunderstorm like three months later.
Rym: And I'm pretty sure that I personally accounted for a significant percentage of the bandwidth used in that trial period.
Rym: There are a lot of people like me nowadays and a lot of people aren't just downloading.
Rym: They're uploading.
Rym: The Internet cannot stand as it is.
Scott: Yes, for ISPs to be able to handle all this bandwidth, you know, as much as people are yelling at their ISPs thinking they're up to evil or lying, they're not.
Scott: To be able to handle all this bandwidth of all these YouTube people and BitTorrent people, you know, BitTorrent people, they're going to have to buy a lot more cables.
Scott: People talk about the dark fiber, you know, much it takes to turn on dark fiber.
Rym: Plus, a lot of that dark fiber is useless.
Scott: Yes, they're going to have to spend.
Scott: if you're an ISP and you actually want to be able to handle all this new bandwidth that people are using, you're going to have to spend so much money on laying new cables, getting new routers, the whole thing.
Scott: It's it's going to be insane.
Rym: So wait, wait, wait, wait, because that's not 100 percent true.
Rym: The evil part, because this is what bothers me.
Rym: All right.
Rym: The ISPs basically have been lying forever and saying unlimited bandwidth, even though it's not true.
Rym: And now because people are smart enough to use that capacity and there are ways to use that capacity that are things that normal people would be doing.
Rym: I mean, in the early days, it didn't matter.
Rym: Only people like me or Scott or half of you listening were using all that bandwidth.
Rym: Most people weren't.
Rym: But now a lot of people are using peer to peer.
Rym: A lot of people are YouTube, a lot of people are running servers and all this business.
Rym: So because the ISPs were lying, they've kind of painted themselves into a corner where if they stop lying, all the people who still lie will get all the business, at least early on.
Rym: And to even if they all stop lying, consumers are going to be really mad about how they lost this thing that they had before.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, usually, you know, service is supposed to get better, not worse.
Scott: You can't be offering me less than before for more money.
Rym: And that's what the ISPs are offering in replacement for this.
Rym: The so-called metered Internet is not the solution.
Rym: It is not a true metered Internet.
Rym: It is basically bullshit.
Scott: A true metered Internet would have disadvantages, but it would also have many advantages that make it very desirable.
Scott: It would be for the ISPs and for the customers.
Rym: You know what it would be like?
Rym: It would be just like how you pay for your electricity.
Rym: Now, I used X kilowatt hours, a kilowatt hour cost.
Scott: Maybe there'll be a flat base fee, you know, to sort of well, I was about to get to that.
Rym: I pay X dollars per Y kilowatt hour.
Rym: I also pay N dollars per month for the wires that connect to my house and give me the privilege of buying that power.
Rym: If the Internet were like that and I try, I don't know, a dollar a gigabyte and maybe five dollars a month for the privilege of the wire.
Scott: Now, the thing is, there's a problem there with a dollar per gigabyte.
Scott: Is that OK?
Scott: A dollar per gigabyte now.
Scott: But what about a year from now when bandwidth is even getting crazier to keep that dollar per gigabyte price when the Internet gets faster?
Scott: We're going to be paying off the nose.
Rym: That's why it's not a terribly analogous situation, because the price of gas and the price of electricity is not going to be going down.
Rym: My electricity is not going to be cheaper next year.
Rym: My electric bill is double not my electric bill.
Rym: My electric bill is actually less.
Rym: My gas bill is double what it was last year.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Bandwidth is getting cheaper at a rate that is ludicrous.
Scott: So if they actually metered the Internet the way they metered water, they would have to keep charging less and less and less over time to sort of make it so that the average person, you know, they would look at the average usage.
Scott: so that way the average person like we pay 50 bucks.
Scott: So they would have to keep changing how much it costs per gigabyte.
Scott: So the average person would be paying around 50 bucks.
Rym: Now, what they do, nothing.
Scott: users would pay less than the crazy users pay more.
Rym: What they could do, which would be fair, is what most oil people people use fuel oil.
Rym: The way they sell it is you'll buy oil, fuel oil.
Rym: You'll you'll negotiate or pay for a rate.
Rym: And that rate is good for one year.
Rym: And you sign a contract.
Rym: So say I sign the contract for the next year, I pay one gigabyte, one dollar a gigabyte total per month.
Rym: And then at the end of the year, it gets renegotiated based on the current market prices.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And that's probably a safe, fair way to do it.
Scott: That is a safe, fair way.
Rym: But the ISPs don't want that because that would be too good.
Rym: What if they pull the cell phone model, the cell phone model of you pay X dollars for one minute and then you pay a fee for minutes above that, because then you either have to buy more bandwidth than you need or not buy enough and get fucked.
Scott: It's like I buy 200 minutes and I only use 10.
Scott: Great for my grandma, who only uses it for five minutes.
Scott: Yeah, she gets ripped off.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or me.
Scott: I need a bajillion minutes.
Scott: Well, you're going to pay a bajillion dollars.
Scott: Oh, great.
Scott: Thanks.
Scott: Even though I went to vacation this month, you know, I didn't actually use it.
Scott: I still have to pay the bajillion because the use I needed next month.
Rym: Now, the thing is, I don't know where I want to go with this, because on one hand, I feel as though a truly metered Internet is probably the only way forward in the medium term.
Rym: But in the long term, bandwidth is getting cheap and also wireless technology is getting better.
Scott: in the is even with something like Wi-Max, the Wi-Max would go to an antenna, which would go to a pipe that is not big enough to handle the Wi-Max.
Rym: So in the as a movie in long term, I foresee that ad hoc wireless everything transmits and receives will make this a moot point.
Scott: And this is the fundamental problem here is that the Internet is designed as a Web, your ISP at that level of the Internet compared when looking at all the other ISPs and not the individual people.
Scott: It is a Web.
Scott: Everyone's connected to everyone else all over the place.
Scott: It's a big mesh.
Rym: And all the routers are agreements with all the people.
Rym: you're connected to pairing agreements and you have agreement like you're not connected directly to some people.
Rym: So you have agreements with other people in between to get between the networks and everyone.
Rym: So it's like everyone owns a bunch of a bunch of bridges.
Rym: And we all let each other use each other's bridges and we all charge each other tolls.
Scott: Yeah, but us with our DSL and our cable modems, we're not in the Web.
Scott: We are actually hanging off the side in a hierarchy.
Scott: And at the top of our hierarchy is our ISP.
Scott: And as a result, the ISP owns us.
Rym: Your ISP, all of you out there, unless you have something awesome, which none of you do, maybe the places you work at do, but you do not.
Rym: Most likely your ISP in like.
Rym: if you zoom out to the telco level or the like Internet level, your ISP is like this little thing kind of hanging off the end.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, the real like the peering in the real high tier Internet server, like you go to XO and you get your circuit to the Internet and that's a whole different.
Scott: Or you get like a direct to the Sprint link or something like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or you go to AT&T and you say, hey, AT&T, I've got these I got these, you know, server farm here.
Scott: I'd like to throw a couple of DS threes your way.
Scott: How about that?
Rym: Yeah, like you'll peer to the Internet through RCN or XO or something, but none of you have that.
Rym: So the Internet is in most ways a hierarchical hierarchy.
Scott: Are there any other kinds of hierarchies that are non-hierarchical?
Rym: Oh, I want to design a non-hierarchical hierarchy.
Scott: Perhaps it would be an acute obtuse angle.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think we're done.
Scott: The point is metered.
Scott: Internet could be good, depending on how it's implemented.
Scott: Something has to change.
Scott: The false advertising is no good.
Scott: But the bullshit metering is also no good.
Rym: I feel as though the ISPs are not being 100 percent truthful and are making a slightly unpleasant situation out to be far worse than it is.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: But also the users are basically, you know, overreacting, saying ISPs are evil.
Scott: Everything you say is a lie.
Scott: Give me unlimited, which is unreasonable.
Rym: At the same time, the ISPs have a lot of people, a lot of very powerful interests, have a vested interest in you not having cheap available bandwidth.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: The media producers, the media distributors, the cell phone companies, all these people do not want you to have cheap bandwidth.
Scott: You know who does want you to have cheap bandwidth?
Scott: Actually, Google podcasters.
Scott: Yes, podcasters want you to have cheap bandwidth.
Scott: How many people in Australia?
Scott: Because Australia only has one or two international links.
Scott: They have super limits on all their Internet.
Scott: They can't download the Ignites.
Scott: I mean, that's that's what it could be if they meter it the bad way.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.